<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a style of sports culottes has become popular on social media What is surprising is that this &quot;fairy skirt&quot; is neither Lululemon, a must-have for the middle class, nor well-known brands such as Nike and Under Armor, but Decathlon, an old friend of straight men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Decathlon, which has always been known as an affordable paradise and a favorite among straight men, why did it rely on women to get out of the industry this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data shows that since 2022, the number of notes about Decathlon on Xiaohongshu has reached 100,000+. With the surge in traffic, it has also driven the sales of its women&#39;s products. Sales, according to the top 5 sales of its Taobao official flagship store, the lowest-ranked women&#39;s yoga pants have sales of up to 30,000+. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Decathlon’s annual sales will reach 14 billion euros, and China has become one of the largest overseas markets, among which women’s demand is the most dazzling. In Decathlon’s official store, Women&#39;s products account for about half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is closely related to the development of China&#39;s outdoor economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China&#39;s outdoor products market will reach 315 billion yuan in 2020, and is expected to reach 599 billion yuan in 2025. Compared with European and American countries, the scale of my country&#39;s outdoor economic market is still Larger development space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A survey shows that the groups participating in outdoor sports in China are mainly young women in the front line and new front lines. They spend more, buy more, and save more to become contemporary women. The three major characteristics of tourism consumption have gradually set off a niche movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, Decathlon has seen the development potential of &quot;female consumers + niche sports&quot;. Today, &quot;Know&quot; will take you to explore Decathlon&#39;s transformation secrets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0 &quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945 &quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4. jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img -id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img -title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省卫健委党组书记、主任朱宏接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260404]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:55:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision: Zhu Hong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law. He voluntarily surrendered and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Hong’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Hong, male, Han nationality, born in September 1966, with an on-the-job postgraduate degree, started working in September 1982, and started working in March 1986. Joined the Chinese Communist Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as member of the Party Committee and Vice President of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, director of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Academic Exchange Center, secretary of the Party Committee of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, and secretary and director of the Party Leadership Group of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探索宇宙中相互竞争的隐秘力量：欧几里得望远镜发布首批照片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 09:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 7, 2023, Beijing time, the European Space Agency released the Euclid Telescope (Euclid) The first 5 full-color pictures taken. These images are the result of scientists&#39; preliminary processing of the first batch of data obtained by the Euclid Telescope, but they have already demonstrated the powerful observation capabilities of the telescope - no telescope has ever obtained such clear images across such a large area of ​​the sky before. image. They believe that this telescope is ready to create the largest three-dimensional map of the universe in history, helping us gain insights into the nature of dark matter and dark energy in the &quot;dark&quot; universe, thereby revealing the hidden secrets of the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclid is a famous ancient Greek mathematician and is known as the &quot;Father of Geometry&quot;. His &quot;Elements of Geometry&quot; has been passed down to the world and laid the foundation for the development of geometry for more than two thousand years. Foundation. Scientists now realize that the density of matter and energy is closely related to the geometry of the universe and determines its future. Therefore, the European Space Agency (ESA) decided to name the telescope that explores the structure and evolution of the universe after Euclid to commemorate the pioneer of geometry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Key Questions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the current mainstream cosmological theory, only 5% of the visible ordinary matter in the universe is , the remaining 95% includes 25% dark matter and 70% dark energy. Therefore, understanding the nature of dark matter and dark energy has become one of the most important issues in science today. The Euclid telescope is expected to play an important role in research in this area over the next decade and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a range of up to 10 billion light-years, Euclid will observe billions of galaxies in more than 1/3 of the sky, creating a picture of the large-scale structure of the universe. picture. Scientists hope to study five key issues in cosmology by exploring the composition and evolution of the &quot;dark&quot; universe: the structure and evolutionary history of the cosmic web (matter in the universe is arranged in a huge network), what dark matter is, and the nature of the universe. How expansion changes over time, what the nature of dark energy is, and whether we really fully understand gravity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2007, researchers proposed two research plans in response to the European Space Agency&#39;s space exploration plan from 2015 to 2025, namely the &quot;Dark Universe Explorer&quot; (Dark Universe Explorer). DUNE) and the Spectroscopic All Sky Cosmic Explorer (SPACE). Both proposals propose complementary techniques to detect dark energy. After a period of evaluation and demonstration, the two plans were merged, and this became the later Euclid Telescope. In October 2011, the European Space Agency&#39;s Science Mission Committee selected the Euclid Telescope; in June 2012, the telescope project was officially established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than ten years of demonstration, design, construction and testing, the Euclid Telescope is finally ready for use. On July 1, 2023, the Euclid Telescope was successfully launched from the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Site in Florida, USA, on board the Falcon 9 rocket of the US Space Exploration Company (SpaceX). At the end of July, the telescope flew near the Sun-Earth&#39;s second Lagrange point, about 1.5 million kilometers away from the Earth, and successfully entered its working orbit. The European Space Agency&#39;s Gaia telescope and NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope are also in orbit around this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic illustration of the workings of the Euclidean telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope is about 4.7 meters high and 3.7 meters in diameter. It consists of a service module and a load module composition. Among them, the payload module that performs the detection function includes a 1.2-meter-diameter telescope and two scientific instruments: the visible light band camera (VIS) and the near-infrared band camera (NISP); the service module mainly includes power generation and distribution, attitude control, data Devices for handling, propulsion, thermal control, remote control and telemetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Space Agency has high hopes for the Euclid telescope. &quot;Dark matter pulls galaxies together, causing them to spin faster than visible matter itself can explain; dark energy is driving the accelerating expansion of the universe. For the first time, the Euclid Telescope will allow cosmologists to study these competing forces simultaneously Dark mysteries,&quot; European Space Agency science director Carole Mundell said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website. &quot;The Euclid Telescope will help us make leaps in understanding the entire universe, and these beautiful images show that , the mission is poised to help answer one of the biggest mysteries of modern physics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Amazing Images&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The first five images released by the Euclid Telescope are the Perseus Cluster of galaxies, the spiral galaxy IC 342, the irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822, the globular star cluster NGC 6397 and the Horsehead Nebula. Picture of (The Horsehead Nebula). The field of view of the telescope for observation is very large, reaching 0.5 square degrees, which exceeds the sky area occupied by the full moon. It took less than a day to shoot the five images released this time. From bright stars to faint galaxies, the Euclid Telescope relies on its powerful observation capabilities to create exceptionally clear visible and infrared images. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perseus is one of the largest known structures in the universe, located 240 million light-years from Earth. This image of the Perseus Galaxy Cluster shows the 1,000 galaxies that are part of the cluster, along with more than 100,000 more distant galaxies in the background. This is the first time astronomers have been able to capture so many of the Perseus Galaxy at such a high level of detail in such a large image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Perseus Galaxy Cluster photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of these faint galaxies have not been observed by astronomers before because some of them are very They are so far away that it took 10 billion years for their light to reach us. Astronomers have shown that galaxy clusters like Perseus could only form if dark matter was present in the universe. They will observe many galaxy clusters like Perseus through the Euclid telescope and map the distribution and shape of the galaxies in them to learn more about how dark matter binds these galaxies together to form galaxy clusters and shapes us The universe as seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in orbit, the Euclid Telescope will image billions of galaxies, revealing the invisible effects of dark matter and dark energy on them. Among the first galaxies observed by Euclid, one was nicknamed the &quot;Hidden Galaxy&quot;. This spiral galaxy similar in shape to the Milky Way was officially numbered IC 342, also known as Caldway. Er number 5. Thanks to the infrared capabilities of the Euclid Telescope, astronomers have discovered key information about the stars in this galaxy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The spiral galaxy IC 342 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early universe, most galaxies did not look like the typical spiral shape of the Milky Way. Not only are they irregular in appearance, they are also small and form the building blocks of larger galaxies like the Milky Way. We can still find some such galaxies in the relatively nearby universe. Among the images released by the Euclid Telescope, there is an irregular dwarf galaxy numbered NGC 6822, 1.6 million light-years away from the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope also photographed the globular star cluster NGC 6397, which is the second closest to Earth globular star cluster, about 7,800 light-years from Earth. Globular star clusters are collections of hundreds of thousands of stars held together by gravity. Currently, no other telescope other than Euclid can see an entire globular cluster in a single observation and identify so many stars in the cluster at the same time. These faint stars can tell us about the history of the Milky Way and the location of dark matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Globular star cluster NGC 6397 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the celestial objects for which the Euclid Telescope released images this time, the Horsehead Nebula is the closest One, also known as Barnard 33, is part of the constellation Orion and is about 1,500 light-years away from Earth. In this image of the Horsehead Nebula, we can see not only the spectacular panorama, but also the fine details. In new Euclid observations of the stellar cradle, scientists expect to find many faint, never-before-seen Jupiter-mass planets in their early stages of formation, as well as young brown dwarfs and baby stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Horsehead Nebula taken with the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Six years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;continuous observation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although only 5 pictures were released in the first batch, these pictures already reflect the tremendous efforts of the scientists and engineers behind the development of the telescope to create these masterpieces. Euclid project manager Giuseppe Racca said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website: &quot;Our high standards for this telescope have paid off. There is so much detail in these images, thanks to Special optical design, perfect manufacturing and assembly of the telescope and instruments and extremely precise pointing and temperature control.&quot; said René Laureijs, Euclid project scientist Comment: &quot;We have never seen astronomical images like this before, with so much detail. They are more beautiful and clearer than we could have hoped for, showing us much that has never been seen before in the known regions of the nearby universe. Characteristics. Now we are ready to observe billions of galaxies and study their evolution throughout the history of the universe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The debut of the Euclid Telescope has inspired the astronomical community, and many people insist that Have the same opinion as Rene Laures. The images demonstrate the extraordinary capabilities of the Euclid Telescope&#39;s various instruments, which allow astronomers to study the distribution of matter in the universe and its evolution on the largest scales. Based on a large number of high-quality observations covering large areas of the sky, they will show us dark and hidden parts of the universe. And beyond the realms of dark matter and dark energy, these images show how Euclid can help astronomers create a treasure trove of information about the physics of individual stars and galaxies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclidean Union director Yannick Mellier said: &quot;Over the next few months, Euclid Union scientists will analyze these images and develop A series of scientific papers are published in the journal &lt;em>;Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics&lt;/em>;, as well as papers on the scientific objectives and instrument performance of the Euclid mission.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the months since the Euclid Telescope was launched, scientists and engineers have been testing and calibrating the telescope&#39;s science equipment. The team is currently making final fine-tuning in order to begin regular observations in early 2024. As the mission progresses, data obtained by the telescope will be released annually and open to researchers around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, the Euclid telescope will carry out observations for six years, after which the possibility of extending the mission will be evaluated based on the remaining amount of cryogenic gas used for propulsion. In the next six years, we can expect that the Euclid Telescope will continue to bring us new surprises and use more wonderful pictures to show us the hidden charm of the universe. The analysis of observational data will last longer, and astronomers will carefully search for clues to unravel the mysteries of dark matter and dark energy in these data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[万亿特殊再融资债券：云南、内蒙古、辽宁超千亿，北上广未发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260402]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73412&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70221&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG211250367208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan , ranking first in the country. Visual China/Picture&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257853&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan, Ranked first in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All creditors have been notified to settle their arrears.&quot; A grassroots official from a western province told a Southern Weekend reporter that the funds for the special refinancing bonds issued this time have been received and are being paid. Complete government debt. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, various regions began to issue special refinancing bonds on a large scale. According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, as of November 5, 25 provinces (municipalities and autonomous regions) have issued a total of 1.13 trillion yuan, equivalent to Gansu&#39;s GDP in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special refinancing bonds are issued by provincial governments. For municipal and county governments, they are equivalent to an extra amount of low-interest debt repayment funds, which can replace high-interest debts and lengthen the repayment cycle. Compared with refinancing bonds issued in ordinary times, special refinancing bonds do not list specific bond information for repayment. According to past issuance history, it is mainly used to repay implicit debts in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A number of local financial system officials revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that this special refinancing bond has two main investment purposes, one is to replace high-interest non-standard debt, and the other is to repay the debt owed by government departments to enterprises. accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of this round of special refinancing bonds, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on July 24, emphasizing the need to effectively prevent and resolve local debt risks and formulate and implement a package of debt reduction plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Zhang Qingsong, deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, said at the International Financial Leaders Investment Summit that &quot;a few provinces may face debt repayment pressure, and most of the debts of the relevant provinces are backed by real assets. Add A package of market-oriented plans has been formulated, and I believe that with the implementation of targeted policies, some local government debt risks will gradually be reduced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, and Liaoning issued over 100 billion yuan&lt;/p>; h4>; &lt;p>;According to the issuance information of this special refinancing bond, as of November 5, the top three provinces by issuance amount are: Yunnan (107.6 billion yuan), Inner Mongolia (106.7 billion yuan), Liaoning (100.6 billion yuan) . The region with the least issuance is Shanxi, with only 2.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt/GDP)*100%, in 2022, the debt ratios of the above three places will rank first among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions (excluding Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). Nine, tenth, twelfth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, only six regions including Beijing, Guangdong, Shanghai, Zhejiang, Hainan and Tibet did not issue special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Guangdong, Zhejiang, Shanghai, and Beijing have low debt ratios and developed economies. The government debt of Hainan and Tibet is not large. In 2022, Tibet&#39;s government debt balance is only 56.8 billion yuan, ranking last among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions. Hainan’s debt balance is 348.7 billion yuan, ranking fourth from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of issuance structure, as of November 5, among the special refinancing bonds issued, the scale of general bonds was 759.4 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%; the scale of special bonds was 368.6 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%. 32.7%. General bonds have a wide range of uses for funds, while special bonds have limited investment options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this round of special refinancing bond issuance, no department has yet explained the quotas for each region. However, judging from the issuance situation, funds still flow more to the central and western provinces with relatively low fiscal self-sufficiency rates, as well as regions with larger debt scales and higher debt ratios. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The province requires us to deal with high-interest non-standard debt first.” A financial system official in a northern province told Southern Weekend reporters that after issuing special refinancing bonds, his prefecture-level city obtained With more than 10 billion yuan in funds, arrangements are currently being made to redeem non-standard products. Since the beginning of this year, there have been many non-standard defaults in the local area, which has put great pressure on repaying principal and interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to debt replacement, another important purpose is to pay off the government&#39;s debts to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the bond issuance information disclosed by Inner Mongolia showed that it plans to issue 66.32 billion yuan of refinancing general bonds, and the funds raised will be used to repay the arrears of corporate accounts that the government is responsible for repaying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, the above-mentioned bond issuance materials were updated, and the purpose of the funds was adjusted to repay existing debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Audit Work Report on the Budget Implementation and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures of the Autonomous Region in 2022&quot; previously released by Inner Mongolia showed that the policy of clearing up the accounts of small and medium-sized enterprises owed to private enterprises has not been implemented, and 62 companies are owed 111 million yuan. . In addition, at the end of 2021, Inner Mongolia&#39;s temporary payment balance was as high as 47.055 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, Premier Li Qiang chaired an executive meeting of the State Council. The meeting pointed out that the provincial government should take overall responsibility for the settlement of arrears in the region, promptly solve the problem of government arrears on corporate accounts, and untie the &quot;chain&quot; of mutual arrears between enterprises, and central and state-owned enterprises should take the lead in repayment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Every creditor is now required to complete the procedures first.” The grassroots official in the western province mentioned above said that for example, in the past when building a road, the company had to complete a complete set of procedures for completion acceptance and submit it to the province for review and approval before releasing the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some regions have begun to offer discounts to repay accounts owed to companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Wuxi Delinhai Environmental Protection Technology Co., Ltd. (688069.SH) issued an announcement stating that the company, Yuxi Water Conservancy Bureau and Dali Erhai Protection Investment and Construction Co., Ltd. had receivables for some projects. The accounts receivable reached a debt restructuring plan, and the above-mentioned accounts receivable totaled 160 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement, Delinhai agreed to give the debtor a certain discount and is expected to recover 120 million yuan through this debt restructuring. Industrial and commercial information shows that Erhai Investment Company is a state-owned enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement explains that there are two backgrounds for this debt restructuring. First, the above-mentioned National Council meeting requires that the problem of corporate account arrears be solved; second, the Yunnan Provincial Government strives to resolve the existing hidden debts and implement hidden debts. The policy of clearing sexual debts was implemented and the implementation of a number of debt reduction measures was implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issuance of special refinancing bonds is undoubtedly an important part of the debt reduction measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73413&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70222&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG1515.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2266&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257854&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Faster and higher than the previous two rounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, there have been two peak issuance periods of special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that from December 2020 to September 2021, a total of 627.8 billion yuan of special refinancing bonds were issued, mainly used for the pilot program of implicit debt resolution in incorporated counties. Immediately afterwards, from October 2021 to June 2022, a total of 504.18 billion yuan was issued, mainly for the pilot program without hidden debt in the entire region, concentrated in Beijing, Shanghai, and Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Luo Zhiheng, president of the Guangdong Securities Research Institute, the proportion of local government bond renewals from 2018 to 2022 were 81.3%, 87.3%, 87.2%, 86.3% and 86.1% respectively, all at the The higher level is mainly to repay bonds issued in 2015-2017. From January to August 2023, the renewal ratio will increase to 90.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maturity renewal ratio = (refinancing bonds - special refinancing bonds) / maturity size. Generally speaking, after local government bonds mature, in addition to issuing refinancing bonds, fiscal funds, etc. will also be arranged for repayment. In other words, as the tight financial balance of local governments intensifies, they rely more on issuing bonds to renew maturing debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the previous two rounds of special refinancing bonds issued, this issuance is faster. In just over a month, the issuance amount exceeded one trillion yuan. The amount of this issuance is also close to the sum of the previous two rounds, and it has not yet ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after refinancing bonds replace implicit debt, it will increase the government debt balance. According to current regulations, local government debt (general debt and special debt) is subject to limit control. The difference between the debt limit and the debt balance is the maximum issuance amount of local special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the main issuance of general bonds as an example. As of November 5, seven regions including Inner Mongolia, Tianjin, and Guizhou have exceeded the local maximum issuance quota, that is, the debt ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Laicheng, a professor at the Central University of Finance and Economics, told Southern Weekend reporters that the issuance of special refinancing bonds in some places may exceed local debt limits. To this end, the Ministry of Finance will make overall adjustments and increase the debt limits of some regions on the basis of the local debt limits approved by the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the &quot;Report on the 2022 Municipal Budget Adjustment Plan (Draft)&quot; released by Chongqing City in September 2022 mentioned that the Ministry of Finance requires that the balance limit of special debt should be approximately 70%. It is retained by each province (autonomous region and municipality) and recovered by the central government at a proportion of approximately 30% for overall deployment among provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as a special means, special refinancing bonds can only relieve local government debt pressure in the short term, and the issuance amount is limited, which cannot completely solve the hidden debts of various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An executive of a county-level urban investment company in the north told Southern Weekend reporters that his province issued tens of billions of special refinancing bonds this time because the company had successively experienced non-standard overdue incidents this year. Due to heavy debt pressure, he reported to higher-level government departments to apply for bond funding support, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, after the issuance of trillions of special refinancing bonds, the financing demand of local urban investment platforms remains strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of a financial leasing platform in Shanghai told Southern Weekend reporters that several provinces he is responsible for have issued special refinancing bonds, but it has not affected business development. Several urban investment platforms he has recently contacted, Liquidity is still urgently needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花都华侨农场访问记：海外中国人筚路蓝缕，在国内也同样熠熠发光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent weekend, I took my son to wander around Ersha Island in Guangzhou and accidentally stumbled into the Guangdong Overseas Chinese Museum. , the overseas Chinese farm in one of the exhibition halls aroused my strong interest. As a teacher engaged in sociology, I came up with the idea of ​​visiting the overseas Chinese farm. I searched online and found out that there is an overseas Chinese farm on the outskirts of my city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were no classes on November 6, so early in the morning, I made an appointment with a colleague to go to the destination - the overseas Chinese farm located in Huadong Town, Huadu District, Guangzhou City. Huadu Overseas Chinese Farm has an area of ​​14.55 square kilometers and a registered population of more than 5,200, including residents from 13 countries and regions including Indonesia, Vietnam, Malaysia, Thailand, Japan, Singapore, Cambodia, India, Laos, New Zealand, Madagascar, Hong Kong, and Macau. There are more than 4,800 returned overseas Chinese and their family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The past and present life of Overseas Chinese Farm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After an hour&#39;s drive, we arrived at the &quot;Overseas Chinese Farm&quot; bus station. After briefly consulting an aunt at the canteen, we went to Qiao Xingyuan Community across the road. She said that many returned overseas Chinese live here. The community is not small, with nearly 30 houses together. Half of the houses have an elevated first floor, and there are some privately built houses scattered on the mountain behind. On the empty platform on the first floor of a house, we met two aunties who were busy packing mobile phone cases. They were returned overseas Chinese from Vietnam. My colleagues and I chatted with them while helping to install mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They returned to China in 1978, when they were only 10 and 8 years old respectively, and were placed here together. At that time, the management of the farm separated men and women, and they lived in collective dormitories. Even if they are a family, they must be spread out and cannot live together. The dormitory at that time was made of mud bricks, with rows of bunk beds inside. Due to the large number of people, the space was very small. Later, because too many returned overseas Chinese were accepted, the dormitories were not enough, so they had to live in ancestral halls in nearby villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of agricultural production and livelihood, the farm is similar to the surrounding villages. They are also divided into several production teams. In addition to planting rice, vegetables, peanuts, fruits, oranges, lychees, and mangoes, they also cultivate On the hillside, tea plantations are planted. It is reported that as early as the late 1970s, the Overseas Chinese Farm was the most important tea production base in Huadu. The tea industry was once prosperous, and the tea produced was well-known throughout the province and sold at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of planting tea in the mountains is still vivid in my mind. An aunt said that everyone used axes and hoes to open up the densely forested hills and turned them into tea planting bases. Without machinery, they carried small tea seedlings to the mountains with bare hands to plant them, and then carried buckets of water for watering. Gradually, a lush green tea mountain was formed in the Qifengtian and Wan Gongtang areas, covering an area of ​​several hundred hectares. At that time, we had to work on time every day. We usually got up at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning to pick tea, because the dew was thick at that time, which was the best time to pick tea. Although the conditions are difficult, everyone is very motivated. During the lunch break, everyone will gather together and listen to one of them reading the day&#39;s newspaper aloud, and sometimes someone will take the lead in singing...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is , all returned overseas Chinese who settle on farms can enjoy the same benefits and treatment as urban residents, including food stamps, cloth stamps, meat stamps and other material supplies. Now, after they have retired for many years, they can also enjoy retirement salary benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the aunt told us that rural people in eight villages within ten miles are proud to marry their daughters to the farm, because the daughter will immediately become an &quot;employee&quot; who can &quot;enjoy benefits&quot;, and her personal destiny will be A major turnaround could occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, the local government decided to implement a housing renovation project for Huaqiao Farm, investing 130 million yuan, with a total construction area of ​​more than 70,000 square meters, and built new buildings such as Qiaonan Garden, Qiaogang Garden, and Qiaoxing Garden. In residential areas, employees only need to pay a small amount of money to live in spacious and bright houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aren&#39;t the surrounding villagers envious of you?&quot; I asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That was true at the time, but it&#39;s different now. We envy them very much.&quot; said an aunt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government of Huadong Town, where the overseas Chinese farm was originally located, has taken advantage of its proximity to Baiyun International Airport in recent years and is committed to building an aviation logistics industry cluster, an aviation maintenance industry cluster, an e-commerce industry cluster and a temporary logistics cluster.空先进制造业集聚区，对华侨农场及附近村庄进行高强度的开发，华侨农场因为本身就是国有土地，属于政府内部不涉及产权置换的土地开发与利用行为，到农场职工手上的可见性福利寥寥，而附近村庄则不一样，很多村民因为被征地得到了数额不菲的补偿款，有的甚至只需增缴几万块就可以直接住上各种综合配套齐全的楼宇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿姨们包装手机壳打零工，一天可以赚个80-100块，反正在家闲着也是看手机，就做点事，人也舒服。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位阿姨的原话是，“我很小的时候，我妈就教育我要勤劳，现在退休了，但身体还算硬朗，就找一点事来做，我心里踏实。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一些人退休就知道打牌，刷手机，但我不喜欢。打牌输钱，我心疼；老看手机看坏眼睛，我不舒服，还不如做事。”另外一位阿姨这样说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;归侨的作用&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;接近中午12点，阿姨们要回家吃饭。同她们道别后，我们便去马路对面的侨南苑找吃的。在一家餐厅，我们邂逅了一家印尼归侨在聚餐。与她们简单打个招呼，说明来意，不想她们非常热情，竟邀请我们与她们同吃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;席间闲聊得知，阿姨姓温，在家中排行老四，上面有一个哥和两个姐，下面有一个妹，她于1960年回国，那时候她6岁。如今，老母亲已98岁高龄，神志依然清晰，精神依然矍铄。温姨说，她爷爷早年远赴印度尼西亚，算是“下南洋”的首批队伍，他们先后养过猪、做过豆腐，在当地成家、安定下来。她父母也继承祖辈基业，主要靠在印度尼西亚西南部小城市或小城镇做豆腐、卖豆腐维持生计。很显然，他们没有选择去竞争更激烈的首都或大城市落脚或谋生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;勤奋、节俭、做小本生意，在艰难与逆境中前行，可不能小觑这些特质，这些特质给温姨这一代人从小打下了脑子活、懂经营的基础。回国后，温姨及其家人相继经营起了豆制品厂、制衣厂、木材加工厂及饭店。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;需要说明，这些所谓的“小微企业”并非私营，而是归农场所有，生产出来的产品都需上缴农场，经由农场统一销售或其他处置。相比附近终日务农的村民，温姨一家及其他像温姨一样长期在国外打拼过的人的思维与想法明显更胜一筹，他们很大程度上推动了农场的全面转型与升级，为农场的产业多样化经营闯出一条路来，倚靠他们的先知先觉与身先士卒，农场拉开了产业化的序幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从更大范围讲，温姨及一帮人率先推动了花都地区的农村工业化进程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就温姨个人而言，她胆大、外向，善于社交，18岁就拿到了A类驾驶证，成为1980年代农场司机班里唯一的女司机，经常开着长挂车全国各地跑，自然见多识广，才思敏捷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温姨还是一位地道的美食制造家，每逢过节，不论是中国的节日，还是印尼的节日，抑或是街坊邻里有人结婚、有家里添丁、有孩子升学或参军办宴时，她都会提前一周准备各种食材，有时甚至专程去香港购买，制作各类极具印尼特色的精美点心，譬如千层糕、曼煎粿、宝塔饭、巴东菜、发酵黄豆块、加多-加多等，供亲友及乡邻品尝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毫无疑问，归侨身份让各国特色美食在华侨农场得以传承与光大，乡邻们在品尝各国美食过程中进行着跨文化交流，这样的朝夕共处与频繁交流，无疑营造了一个多样丰富文化的社区氛围，对于化解社区矛盾与争端、构建社区发展共同体、提升社区自组织能力、增进社区治理效能产生积极作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;归侨身份亦对后代的发展产生垂范作用。席间还有温姨的侄子，他饭后便欲启程去香港，继而转机去印尼。原来，他父母很早就定居香港，他小学及中学是在香港念的，大学及研究生在美国完成，目前在印尼巴厘岛一家地产公司上班。不难看出，祖辈或长辈们的跨国经历，对后代的受教育水平及人生际遇产生深远影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温姨告诉我，农场有数量不少的第三代跨国移民，多少得益于或受益于祖辈们构建起来的跨国联系网络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的感想&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;下午3时许，我们请温姨带我们去她曾经“战斗”过的一些地方走走、看看，她欣然应许，我们相继去了五队、六队和九队。一路上，我们发现从前的临时农场管理办公室、茶厂、制衣厂等早已改头换面，原址上已建起了很多涉及新能源与高科技等领域的新型企业。道理至简，华侨农场属国营单位，管理方式较大程度沿袭计划经济体制，很多传统产业难以跟上新的发展形势，不少企业纷纷破产，取而代之的是新项目纷纷上马，新企业纷纷进驻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到曾经劳作的地方，只有少数厂牌孤独地伫立在那里，温姨露出了遗憾与无奈的表情。时代在改变，华侨农场也在转型，这是无法阻止的客观规律。未来，华侨农场将继续深度融入都市化与现代化。在这一过程中，我以为有关方面可以尝试开展下面几件事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，应该鼓励大学老师、相关研究人员或学生群体开展针对归侨及其后代的口述史研究，做好各年龄层次人口的采访与调查，成为花东镇乃至花都区地方志的重要组成部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，通过政府与民间合作的方式，成立华侨农村博物馆或展览馆，让华侨文化与华侨精神发扬光大，将其打造为花都旅游中的特色与亮点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，积极申报建设省级或市级国际化社区，华侨农场是实实在在与真真切切的国际化社区，有关部门在升级改造与后续规划过程中不能或不宜一味地“去农场化”，华侨农场作为一种地方性特质早已成为花东镇或花都区地方性知识的重要组分，有关方面需要充分尊重地方，尊重地方原真性，让上述地方在新时期国际化社区营建过程中得以体现与绽放，这无疑很大程度助力地方营销（place marketing），进而成为招商引资的重要社会资本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系广州大学社会学系教授）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弄虚作假？二次污染？85亿元苏钢“毒地”疑云]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:53:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257847&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On March 18, 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. There was a red alert at the gate. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Plot snapped up for 8.5 billion&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;actually&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;contains&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;poison&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;cannot be put into operation after development and construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Listed Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lujiazui)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Requirements&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Go to court&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, Lujiazui issued an announcement to Jiangsu Province due to soil pollution problems. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;the following&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Abbreviation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and a number of Suzhou government agencies and institutions initiated litigation and claimed 10.044 billion yuan from Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. At present, the Jiangsu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court has filed the case and has not yet opened a hearing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;before &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Lujiazui sold it at a high price&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;former site&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;17 plots of land,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;with a total construction area of ​​over 1 million square meters&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui is in&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The announcement issued on September 29, 2023 stated that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;02&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;of which 2 Lot No.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;has been&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;built into a school&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;apply at&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;School License&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&#39;s&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; ;&quot;>;Process&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;One ​​after another, including the &amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp; plot Many plots of land are polluted&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>; Since&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Multiple&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;announcements,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;express&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation revealed that a total of 14 pieces of land were polluted, and the area and degree of pollution far exceeded what was disclosed during the listing. 2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2022, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;related&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Songti&quot;>;Plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; was named by the central environmental protection inspector, and the local government commissioned a third-party investigation and found that the pollution exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui stated in the announcement that the &quot;regulatory changes and transfer process of this land&quot; In the case, each defendant committed a series of violations, committed fraud, and failed to perform their duties in accordance with the law. &quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Release&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement 6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;天&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Later,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On January 10, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group issued a situation statement, saying&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_ GB2312&quot;>;We are actively responding to the lawsuit and putting the health of the people and the legitimate rights and interests of home buyers first. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Indicates&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Yifang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;In 2019, we have&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;learned that Lot 2 does not meet environmental protection requirements&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;but &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>; was not completed in accordance with the law Soil pollution investigation and remediation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;launched the project Land project construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;and&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;During the development and construction period&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Existence&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Secondary pollution caused by irregular construction operations&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Situation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; &quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter’s interview found that Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The plot is a typical industrial land redevelopment case, with soil investigation and evaluation, restoration and land transfer development and utilization spanning the &lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Seven&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, during which our country The laws, regulations, technical specifications and standards for soil pollution prevention and control have been continuously improved from a few to many. The different assessment results before and after may be due to repeated changes and tightening of soil pollution assessment standards, and the rich water system in the south of the Yangtze River, which makes pollution easy to migrate. In this kind of situation, who is responsible for pollution remediation is also a legal problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Buy &quot;poisonous land&quot; at a high price? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2016, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will establish a wholly-owned subsidiary&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank Real Estate Development Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; (hereinafter referred to as &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;) 95% equity is listed for sale, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;’s core assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; are 17 pieces of state-owned land. The land is located to the north of Sutong Road and east of Sugang Road, Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone. It was originally the production plant of Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. After 222 rounds of fierce bidding competition, Lujiazui became the winner of the land with 8.525 billion yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee .png&quot; data-key=&quot;257848&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Suzhou Steel History. Suzhou Steel Group official website/picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The announcement disclosed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;information about Suzhou Iron and Steel Group’s listing in August 2016,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The soil in the non-scorched area of ​​the plot under its name and groundwater are basically not polluted and can be redeveloped and utilized; the pollution in the coking area is mainly concentrated in the local area of ​​No. 4 plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; stated in the announcement released on April 14, 2022, &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Based on the public market equity listing information Trust, and reasonable reliance on the administrative actions of government departments&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;Bidding&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;equity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Situation Description&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Disclosure&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;,&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;When transferring the equity in 2016, our company has truthfully disclosed the existence of land under the name of Suzhou Green Bank to a third-party professional agency The investigation results and full text of the report on partial pollution, and the asset assessment report clearly stated that some plots in this area were originally steel coking production areas and may have soil pollution risks.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The &quot;Memorandum on Equity Transactions&quot; signed between Lujiazui and Suzhou Iron and Steel Group shows that the two parties agreed &quot;about the existence of soil pollution in some plots of land&quot; Regarding the matter, according to the relevant investigation and evaluation report filed with the Suzhou Municipal Environmental Protection Bureau, there are no technical obstacles to soil environmental treatment. After the treatment is completed, it will comply with national and local environmental quality standards and can be carried out in accordance with the requirements of existing planning documents. Development and construction. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will provide environmental management matters for&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Green Bank Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Provide coordination and support&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to the plan, Lujiazui will build the first million-square-meter city in Suzhou High-tech Zone here A regional complex project, the project was launched in May 2017, and the development cycle is planned to be 8 years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In addition to building commercial buildings and &quot;Splendid Lanshan&quot; residential buildings, Lujiazui also introduced Suzhou Reading School, a nine-year consistent international school jointly built by Suzhou Lunhua Education Group and Reading School in the UK, is located on Lot 2 of the project. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Unexpectedly&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The school was built, but it could not recruit students smoothly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, in 2021, Suzhou Reading School is applying for a school license During the certification process, according to the requirements of the Environmental Protection Bureau of Suzhou High-tech Zone, Lujiazui commissioned a third-party agency to investigate The soil pollution status of the land where the school is located was found to be seriously polluted and it could not be put into use through environmental impact assessment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default &quot;>;Mentioned in the fact sheet:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2019&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Lujiazui Yi&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;fang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;know&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_ GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. does not meet environmental protection requirements and has not been completed in accordance with the law&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;The soil pollution investigation and restoration treatment of plot No. =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; started the project construction of this plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; year, due to failure to pass the environmental impact assessment acceptance Failed to enable. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; The Lujiazui announcement in Song Dynasty also showed that the Suzhou Municipal Assets and Planning Bureau restored plot No. 2 to industrial (research and development) land, and the Reading school project objectively failed to complete comprehensive acceptance. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot; >;In March 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; A year later, the &quot;poisonous site&quot; was named by the Central Environmental Protection Inspection Team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In April 2022, Jiangsu Province announced the &quot;Second Central Ecological Environmental Protection Supervision &quot;Processing Status of the Sixth Batch of Letters and Calls Transferred to Our Province&quot; mentioned that the test results of the third-party testing agency showed that many plots of land in the Suzhou Green Bank Project&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The soil&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;benzo[a]pyrene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and naphthalene seriously exceeded the standards and did not meet the land use standards. At the request of the Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee, Lujiazui has suspended&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Related development, construction, and sales work, and implemented strict management of the above-mentioned contaminated land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Inspector&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The report&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;shows that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee attaches great importance to it and has established a special work class&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation report obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that in 2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;In August 2019, the People&#39;s Government of Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone entrusted the Nanjing Environmental Science Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment to conduct detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; According to the &quot;Song Dynasty&quot; investigation, 7 plots of land exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;The situation statement mentioned&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;these 7 plots&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312 In 2016, Lujiazui Party and Su Gang agreed to commission a third-party professional organization, the Nanjing Institute of Environmental Science and Technology, to conduct a detailed investigation of the pollution situation in the land. Coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;3&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;5&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;No. and non-coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; plot (of which only &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song _GB2312&quot;>;plot has been developed and constructed) and can be safely used after treatment and restoration. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Already occupied by residents&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;14&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No., developed and constructed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;8&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;13&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;16&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot and undeveloped construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;11&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;17&lt;/ span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. is a land that can be safely used. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>; Land planning diagram. Lujiazui Announcement/Picture (Editor’s note: Because the picture is tilted, the plot number and plot location are not completely aligned.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Based on Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The number of contaminated plots is more than 7 pieces&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;20&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; &quot;>;Over the past 22 years, Lujiazui and various environmental investigation agencies have determined the name of Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The next 14 blocks of land are polluted. Lujiazui filed a complaint against Suzhou Iron and Steel Group, the Suzhou Environmental Science Institute and Suzhou Suzhou Environmental Technology Co., Ltd., as well as related parties, the Suzhou National High-tech Industrial Development Zone Management Committee and the Suzhou Natural Resources and Planning Bureau. Go to court&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;宋体&quot;>;As&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;the third party in the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters called the plaintiff and third party in the case, and multiple staff members said Regarding the case, you need to ask the Lujiazui Group’s Board Secretary’s Office. On November 9, the Board’s Secretary’s Office responded, “The group has a unified voice and does not accept interviews.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Based on&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Two&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;EIA announcements,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Environmental Science Institute and Environmental Impact Assessment&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Responsibility&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Party&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Relevant personnel of Suzhou University of Science and Technology&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;neither got in touch or&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; refused to be interviewed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Different reference standards lead to different test results&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The development and utilization of contaminated sites requires strict environmental monitoring, assessment, restoration, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;process&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, why are the houses already built? /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The outside world says there is&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;pollution&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The Central Environmental Protection Inspectorate mentioned two pollutants that exceeded the standard:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Comparison&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;These two pollutants are in 2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014-2022 Numerical values ​​in multiple reports&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;can reveal the hindsight of the &quot;poisonous land&quot; of the Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. , it is possible that the pollution does exist, but the standards used in the assessment are different, resulting in different&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;different results&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; 2014&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;Divide the land into non-coking areas and coking areas&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>; (heavy pollution),&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty &quot;>;Entrust a third-party environmental company to conduct soil surveys separately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc.&quot;>;Environmental protection organizations&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. Line&quot;>;Guangzhou Green Network Environmental Protection Service Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;applied to the Suzhou Ecological Environment Bureau for disclosure and obtained the &quot;Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Old Areas (Except for Unclosed Areas)&quot; Preliminary Soil Investigation Report&quot; &quot;Preliminary Investigation Report on Site Pollution in the Coking Area of ​​the Old District of Jiangsu Sugang Group Co., Ltd.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Site Pollution in the Coking Area of ​​the Old District of Jiangsu Sugang Group Co., Ltd.&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Details&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Investigation Report&quot; and &quot;Coking Area in the Old Area of ​​Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Soil and Groundwater Human Health Assessment Report&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation scope of the four reports covers &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;non-coking areas and coking areas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Benzo[a]pyrene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;It is a type of carcinogen that is also produced during barbecue and is a semi-volatile organic compound&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;is between volatile organic compounds and semi-volatile organic compounds. A soil survey was conducted in the non-coking area in January 2014. Benzo[a]pyrene was not detected at any of the 35 sampling points&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene was not detected in most sample points (34). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;At that time, the investigation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Songti&quot;>;The standard based on is the &quot;Exhibition Land Soil Environmental Quality Evaluation Standard&quot; (HJ350-2007) (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Exhibition Land Standard&quot;), which is an industry standard formulated by the former Ministry of Environmental Protection.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;No&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;It is clear that these two pollutants require mandatory testing&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In other subsequent reports, such as&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Notice from the Central Environmental Protection Inspection Team in April 2022, announcements issued by Lujiazui,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In August 2022, a survey commissioned by the Suzhou High-tech Zone and the Nanjing Environmental Science Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment showed that benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene also exceeded standards at some points in the non-coking area. At this time, the reference standard is the national standard &quot;Soil Environmental Quality &amp;nbsp; Soil Pollution Risk Management and Control Standard for Construction Land (Trial)&quot; (GB36600-2018) (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Construction Land Standard&quot;) implemented on August 1, 2018. Previously, Benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene, which are not required to be measured, have been required to be measured. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;equiline&quot;>;&quot;Possible contamination of benzo[a]pyrene and naphthalene in non-coking areas It has always existed, but it was not discovered because there was no detection before.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. line&quot;>;Green Network&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;etc. line&quot;>;Work Personnel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei guessed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;And the parts found in the coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Pollutants,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;are included in each&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;phase report&lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;detection&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, but &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;may be due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The limits in the new standards have been tightened, resulting in compliance with the standards before but exceeding them later. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene is like that. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014, 2015&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Soil&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot; >;The survey results show that only&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;sewage treatment area and crude benzene workshop&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; &amp;quot;&quot;>;(That is, part of the No. 4 plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; mentioned above&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;is contaminated, and naphthalene in other areas does not exceed the standard. The reference at this time is the &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;Exhibition Land Standard&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;B-level standard,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The limit value of naphthalene is 530mg/kg. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;And in the subsequent &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Detection&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Reporting&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Not just&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Plot 4, there are&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;many&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and other pollutants &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Exceeds the standard. Subsequent&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;naphthalene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;limits for reporting reference have been tightened,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;respectively&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;25mg/kg(&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Type I land&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;70mg/kg (&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Second type of land)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, which are far lower than the previous standard&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;530mg/ kg. &quot;The previous standards were too broad, and the existing standards are based on factors such as human health and are more scientific&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The evaluation is relatively strict.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Guo Lei&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;257851&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;A summary of key pollutant detection results in various reports and notifications on Suzhou Iron and Steel’s “toxic sites”. Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou and Huang Siqi&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Compiled by Southern Weekend intern Xi Lijie&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Conservative principle&quot; in testing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Although there is no mandatory testing list in the 2014 soil pollution testing requirements, there is a &quot;conservative&quot; in the industry&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;性&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;principle&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In February 2014, the former Ministry of Environmental Protection issued the &quot;Technical Guidelines for Site Environmental Investigation &quot;Principles&quot; (HJ25.1-2014) mentioned that &quot;testing items should be based on the principle of conservatism&quot;: Optional testing items for general industrial sites include semi-volatile organic compounds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;This means that semi-volatile organic compounds such as benzo[a]pyrene are based on Based on the principle of conservatism, it is recommended to test.但郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;指出&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，苏钢委托的第三方环境公司并未&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;采纳，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;非焦化区没有检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;介绍，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;半挥发性有机物是钢铁厂地块土壤中的常见污染物，它们在焦化、燃煤过程中的热解和不完全燃烧过程中释放，排放到大气中，又沉降到附近的地面，进而污染土壤，“不只非焦化区，甚至厂区外的土壤也可能会超标”。其他&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;钢铁厂&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也曾&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发生过类似情况&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“苏钢地块是典型的工业用地再开发的案例，它的土壤调查、土地转让和开发跨越了我们国家土壤污染防治领域的法律法规、技术规范和标准从无到有、从少到多的过程。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在2014年苏钢地块开展土壤调查的时段&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，我国土壤污染防治的相关法律法规、标准、技术规范&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也才&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;刚刚起步&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;直至2014年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;上述技术导则才诞生&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；直至2017年7月1日，污染地块土壤环境管理办法才施行；2019年1月1日，土壤污染防治法才施行。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在此之前，仅有原环保部等部门出台的几项部门通知，并不具备较高的法律效力。一位&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤修复行业人士向南方周末记者回忆，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年左右，行业非常混乱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;重庆市生态环境局、规划和自然资源局于2021年发布《关于进一步加强建设用地土壤污染分类分级管理工作的通知》曾表述&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“早期土壤污染状况调查的认识不到位，相关技术导则规范不健全，调查技术手段受限等原因，导致部分重污染行业建设用地地块调查结果失真，修复不到位……部分建设用地土壤污染调查、风险评估、风险管控及修复效果评估报告编制质量不高、专家评审把关不严，对从业企业、评审专家缺乏约束管理。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“且不论弄虚作假等，光上述因素就会造成土壤调查精度不高，导致调查结果跟实际情况间可能有较大差距。”郭磊称。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;二次污染？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;焦化区域的污染主要集中在4号地块，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴一方在交易时即知晓，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;也曾编制修复方案和治理。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;2018年9月，《苏钢地块老区焦化区域污染场地修复工程环境影响评价报告表及专项评价》公示，建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;单位为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州绿岸，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;内容&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;为土壤原&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;位和异位修复。公示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;原网页环评报告链接已经失效，但网传有一份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;97&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;页的同名称环评报告（以下简称环评报告）。南方周末记者联系环评承担方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州科技大学&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;技术&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;人员确认，未获得&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;回应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告提到了苏钢老区焦化场地，自2015年启动初步调查、详细调查、修复方案等历时三年多，每一环节均经过专家评审，符合当时的环保要求，但是土壤修复中萘的修复目标值不符合新标准要求，修改后符合&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;GB36600-2018）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;。评价适用标准中，修复后规划为商业用地，土壤参考也是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”第二类&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;，萘的标准为70mg/kg。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257852&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;红色为曾进行土壤修复的大概位置。黄色为2022年新发现的4块污染地块。绿网公众号截图。 &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告显示，4号地块将进行土壤修复。但2022年后的多份检测报告显示，4号地块仍然有污染。有土壤修复业内人士向南方周末记者提醒，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;焦化厂污染是疑难杂症，非常难治理。在江南地区的水文地质条件下，还需要特别注意污染迁移”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;雷丁学校所在的2号地块也被多次报告污染，地图显示，2号地块和4号地块相连。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;苏钢的情况说明提到：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;方在开发建设苏州绿岸地块期间，没有按照有关要求建设地下水阻隔墙及采取其他防护措施，存在扰动地下水、搬运土壤造成部分环境交叉污染的行为和施工作业不规范造成二次污染的行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;对此&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，陆家嘴还未有回应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2022年7月&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;被苏州生态环境局处罚1.88万，原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违反土壤生态环境管理制度&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违法&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;事实对应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤污染防治法第四十二条第三款&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;风险管控、修复活动完成后，需要实施后期管理的，土壤污染责任人应当按照要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;023年1月10日发布&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;公告表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，苏州生态环境局作出该项处罚的原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸在之前依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏钢集&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;披露的污染区域对&amp;nbsp;4&amp;nbsp;号地块土壤修复后未按要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;汇业律师事务所合伙人、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;环境资源与能源专委会执行主任张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;向南方周末&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;记者&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，如果&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;施工作业导致污染扩散，应对生态环境损害的扩大部分承担责任。但不能&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;排除苏钢集团是否需要对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;号地块的污染负责，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;其中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;可能涉及多因一果的共同侵权，依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;民法典&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;第1231条的规定，在责任大小认定上需要结合污染范围、程度，以及行为对损害后果所起作用等因素确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;毒地修复责任归谁&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;根据已有材料，目前难以断定苏钢集团在交易时是否有所隐瞒、场地调查过程中是否存在不规范行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;出让了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;标准更迭加严，应该由谁来承担土地污染修复责任？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀告诉南方周末记者，评价交易双方的土地污染修复责任，关键看土地交易交割时期的标准，尤其是强制性标准。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;如果交易前，场地调查已有明确的国家标准，出让方不存在未披露风险情形，在企业存续期间也做到了合法合规达标排放，即使倒查，也无法追究其历史上生态环境损害赔偿责任，交易后的土壤污染风险&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;应由继受人承担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;如果土地交易时&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;缺乏&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确的标准，双方也没有遵循保守性原则严格排查，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;那么&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;现有土地使用权人&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;就&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;具有土壤污染风险管控和修复的义务&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，在本案中，也就是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;这在一定程度上归因于受让方在交易前缺乏独立严谨的环境调&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为现有建设用地使用权人，具有对土壤污染的风险管控和评估义务，应承担土地污染修复责任。至于修复费用的追偿问题，有两种途径，一是行政途径，通过土地污染责任认定程序&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;二是通过民事诉讼途径，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;基于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;投资并购交易合同。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;介绍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;月，生态环境部会同自然资源部制定了《建设用地土壤污染责任人认定暂行办法》，规定建设用地使用权人可以向有管辖权的生态环境主管部门提出土壤污染责任人认定申请。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不过，张秀秀认为陆家嘴与苏钢集团的责任认定存在较大难题。主要原因是目前国内土壤污染责任人认定办法出台时间短、实践案例少，推行阻力较大。 “很多地方的主管部门对于受理申请、启动认定程序非常犹豫，因为可资借鉴的案例很少。如果不被受理，使用权人只能通过交易合同关系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;去&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;追究历史的污染责任人。但一般的合同关系里，如果双方对于土壤污染的约定不明确，受让了污染场地的一方就会比较吃亏。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者查询发现，陆家嘴目前的公开披露信息中，未明确提及是否启动土地污染责任认定程序。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀表示，该起环境污染责任纠纷案件的启示意义在于，土地交易中买受人应注重环境法律风险的排查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;首先，买受人要深度了解土壤污染状况和历史用途，如果地块历史用途或周边涉及污染，应重点关注土壤污染的风险。其次，买受人应对地块的调查保持一定的独立性，对于既有的专业报告、评审结论保持警惕性，不可轻信结论，如有必要，可以聘请第三方开展更详细的土壤调查。最后，基于投资的通盘考虑，愿意承担一定环境法律风险的交易，应对土壤污染治理成本进行评估，就土壤污染状况、风险转移及可追溯的相关法律责任，在交易合同予以明确。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家金监总局三定方案： 健全金融消保者保护制度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 21:18:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家金融监督管理总局职能配置、内设机构和人员编制规定&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第一条&lt;/strong>; 为了规范国家金融监督管理总局的职能配置、内设机构和人员编制，推进机构、职能、权限、程序、责任法定化，根据党的二十届二中全会审议通过的《党和国家机构改革方案》、第十四届全国人民代表大会第一次会议审议批准的《国务院机构改革方案》和《中国共产党机构编制工作条例》以及党中央对金融工作的有关要求，制定本规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局是国务院直属机构，为正部级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第三条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局在中国银行保险监督管理委员会基础上组建，将中国人民银行对金融控股公司等金融集团的日常监管职责、有关金融消费者保护职责，中国证券监督管理委员会的投资者保护职责划入国家金融监督管理总局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定确定的主要职责、机构设置、人员编制等，是国家金融监督管理总局机构职责权限、人员配备和工作运行的基本依据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第五条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局负责贯彻落实党中央关于金融工作的方针政策和决策部署，把坚持和加强党中央对金融工作的集中统一领导落实到履行职责过程中。主要职责是：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）依法对除证券业之外的金融业实行统一监督管理，强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管，维护金融业合法、稳健运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）对金融业改革开放和监管有效性相关问题开展系统性研究，参与拟订金融业改革发展战略规划。拟订银行业、保险业、金融控股公司等有关法律法规草案，提出制定和修改建议。制定银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等有关监管制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）统筹金融消费者权益保护工作。制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划，建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度，研究金融消费者权益保护重大问题，开展金融消费者教育工作，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行准入管理，对其公司治理、风险管理、内部控制、资本充足状况、偿付能力、经营行为、信息披露等实施监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行现场检查与非现场监管，开展风险与合规评估，查处违法违规行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）统一编制银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的监管数据报表，按照国家有关规定予以发布，履行金融业综合统计相关工作职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）负责银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的科技监管，建立科技监管体系，制定科技监管政策，构建监管大数据平台，开展风险监测、分析、评价、预警，充分利用科技手段加强监管、防范风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行穿透式监管，制定股权监管制度，依法审查批准股东、实际控制人及股权变更，依法对股东、实际控制人以及一致行动人、最终受益人等开展调查，对违法违规行为采取相关措施或进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）建立除货币、支付、征信、反洗钱、外汇和证券期货等领域之外的金融稽查体系，建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制，依法对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证、处理，涉嫌犯罪的，移送司法机关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）建立银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的恢复和处置制度，会同相关部门研究提出有关金融机构恢复和处置意见建议并组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）牵头打击非法金融活动，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议，按要求组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）按照建立以中央金融管理部门地方派出机构为主的地方金融监管体制要求，指导和监督地方金融监管相关业务工作，指导协调地方政府履行相关金融风险处置属地责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）负责对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等与信息技术服务机构等中介机构的信息科技外包等合作行为进行监管，依法对违法违规行为开展调查，并对金融机构采取相关措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）参加金融业相关国际组织与国际监管规则制定，开展对外交流与国际合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）完成党中央、国务院交办的其他任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第六条&lt;/strong>; 职能转变。加强和完善现代金融监管，转变监管理念和监管方式，坚持既管合法又管非法，持续提升监管的前瞻性、精准性、有效性，强化中央和地方监管协同，消除监管空白和盲区，加强金融消费者权益保护，加大对违法违规行为的查处力度，牢牢守住不发生系统性金融风险的底线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强金融监管内部治理，强化对权力运行的有效制衡，规范政策制定、市场准入、稽查执法、行政处罚、风险处置等工作流程，强化对重点岗位和关键环节的监督制约，打造一支政治过硬、专业精湛、清正廉洁的监管铁军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第七条&lt;/strong>; 与其他部门的职责分工：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）打击非法金融活动职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立打击非法金融活动工作协调机制，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。2.国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会、国家外汇管理局依据各自职责对相关非法设立金融机构、从事特许金融活动等组织调查认定，采取相关措施或予以取缔。3.教育、养老、房地产、商贸服务等行业主管部门在职责范围内开展本行业本领域非法集资等非法金融活动的防范和配合处置工作。4.互联网信息内容管理部门、电信主管部门、市场监督管理部门等相关职能部门在职责范围内开展非法金融活动防范和配合处置工作。5.地方政府负责辖内非法集资等非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展风险排查、案件查处、善后处置和维护稳定等工作。6.对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，国家金融监督管理总局负责提出相关工作建议，按程序报批后组织实施，并及时采取应急措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）金融消费者权益保护工作职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局统筹负责金融消费者权益保护，牵头建立金融消费者保护工作协调机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。2.国家金融监督管理总局统筹制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划、建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度、开展金融消费者教育等工作，中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会予以支持配合。3.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立统一的金融消费者投诉举报流程和标准体系。国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会按分工落实或督促相关机构落实投诉举报处理主体责任，依法查处侵害金融消费者合法权益的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制。1.国家金融监督管理总局与公安部、最高人民检察院建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接工作机制，实现案件信息共享、协同办理。2.国家金融监督管理总局发现违法行为涉嫌犯罪的，按照有关规定移送公安部，同时抄送最高人民检察院。公安机关经调查发现依法需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由公安部向国家金融监督管理总局提出建议。3.检察机关决定不起诉的案件，需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由最高人民检察院向国家金融监督管理总局提出检察意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第八条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局根据本规定第五条所明确的主要职责，编制权责清单，逐项明确权责名称、权责类型、设定依据、履责方式、追责情形等。在此基础上，制定办事指南、运行流程图等，进一步优化行政程序，规范权力运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第九条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设下列正司局级内设机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）办公厅（党委办公室）。负责机关日常运转，承担信息、安全、保密、信访、政务公开、新闻宣传等工作。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委办公室日常工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）政策研究司。承担金融业相关改革开放政策研究与组织实施具体工作。对国内外经济金融形势、国际金融监管改革及发展趋势、监管方法和运行机制等开展系统性研究，提出相关监管政策建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）法规司。起草相关法律法规草案。拟订相关监管制度。承担合法性审查、法律咨询服务、行政复议、行政应诉等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）统计与风险监测司。拟订监管统计制度。承担监管报表编制、信息披露、数据共享以及行业风险监测分析预警等工作。统筹非现场监管工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）科技监管司。拟订相关信息科技发展规划和信息科技风险监管制度并组织实施。按分工承担网络安全、数据安全、关键信息基础设施监管等工作，推动数字化信息化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）公司治理监管司。拟订公司治理监管制度。开展股权管理和公司治理监管等工作，承担金融控股公司、保险集团等机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）普惠金融司。督促金融机构落实普惠金融政策要求，拟订监督管理的规章制度并组织实施，指导金融机构开展对小微企业、“三农”和特殊群体的金融服务工作，规范普惠金融秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）金融机构准入司。拟订银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的准入制度，研究结构布局，对机构及其业务范围实行准入管理，审查董事、高级管理人员等任职资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）大型银行监管司。承担政策性银行、开发性银行和国有控股大型商业银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）股份制和城市商业银行监管司。承担全国性股份制商业银行、城市商业银行、民营银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）农村中小银行监管司。承担农村中小银行机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）财产保险监管司（再保险监管司）。承担财产保险机构、再保险机构、保险中介机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）人身保险监管司。承担人身保险机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）资管机构监管司。承担信托公司、理财公司、保险资产管理公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）非银机构监管司。承担金融资产管理公司、企业集团财务公司、金融租赁公司、汽车金融公司、消费金融公司、货币经纪公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十六）银行机构检查局。拟订银行机构现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十七）保险和非银机构检查局。拟订保险业机构、金融控股公司及其他非银行机构的现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十八）机构恢复与处置司。拟订相关高风险机构风险处置制度、标准、程序，对出现严重风险、难以持续经营的机构开展风险处置等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十九）金融消费者权益保护局。拟订金融消费者权益保护发展规划和制度，开展金融消费者教育工作，承担相关金融产品合规性、适当性管理工作，组织调查处理侵害金融消费者合法权益案件，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十）打击非法金融活动局。建立非法金融活动监测预警体系和公开举报渠道，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展相关宣传教育、政策解释和业务指导等工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议。拟订小额贷款公司、融资性担保公司、典当行、融资租赁公司、商业保理公司、地方资产管理公司等地方金融组织监管制度，指导和监督地方金融监管部门相关业务工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十一）稽查局。拟订稽查工作制度。组织对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证，提出处理意见；涉嫌犯罪的，提出移送司法机关的建议。指导、检查金融机构安全保卫工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十二）行政处罚局。承担行政处罚案件审理等工作，提出审理意见，组织听证和集体讨论，送达行政处罚决定并执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十三）内审司（党委巡视工作领导小组办公室）。拟订系统内审和巡视工作制度、办法，监督检查系统贯彻落实有关重大决策部署情况，组织开展系统内审和巡视工作，对发现的问题及责任人提出处理建议，指导、监督、检查系统内审和巡察工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十四）国际合作司（港澳台办公室）。承担外事管理、国际合作和涉港澳台地区相关事务。承担外资银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十五）人事教育司（党委组织部）。承担机关、派出机构和直属单位等的干部人事、机构编制、劳动工资、教育培训和离退休干部管理工作。指导行业人才队伍建设工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十六）财务会计司。承担财务管理工作，负责编报系统年度财务预决算。依法强化对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等财会监督工作的督促指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十七）党建工作局（党委宣传部）。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委落实全面从严治党主体责任相关工作。承担系统党的建设工作，指导系统基层党组织建设、党员队伍建设、党风廉政建设和反腐败工作。负责系统党的宣传工作。领导系统统战、群团组织工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;机关党委。负责机关及在京直属单位党的建设和纪检工作，领导机关群团组织的工作。机关党委设立机关纪委，承担机关及在京直属单位纪检、党风廉政建设有关工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局机关行政编制910名。设局长1名，副局长4名；司局级领导职数114名（含首席风险官、首席检查官、首席律师、首席会计师各1名，机关党委专职副书记1名，机关纪委书记1名）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十一条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设立稽查总队，作为直属行政机构，正司级，负责相关案件的调查、取证，提出处理意见等。稽查总队的编制和领导职数另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局对派出机构实行垂直管理。国家金融监督管理总局地方派出机构、所属事业单位的设置、职责和编制事项另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十三条&lt;/strong>; 本规定由中央机构编制委员会办公室负责解释，其调整由中央机构编制委员会办公室按规定程序办理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据机构编制管理权限，由国家金融监督管理总局党委决定、报中央机构编制委员会办公室备案的机构编制事项，按照有关规定执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定自2023年10月29日起施行&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《漫长的季节》文学策划考编上岸：反思“铁饭碗”的人为何拥抱“铁饭碗”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一则“作家考编”的新闻引发关注。 2023年武汉市文联所属事业单位芳草杂志社公布了专项招聘名单，青年作家班宇、陈春成、王苏辛、淡豹（刘雪婷）在列。此事再次引发网友“宇宙的尽头是考编”的感叹。公示名单显示，班宇、陈春成与王苏辛“成功上岸”，淡豹则不幸名落孙山。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这则新闻的话题热度虽逊于去年的“明星考编”事件，但也提出了一些值得深入探讨的议题。此次“作家考编”之所以引发热议，还是因为在人设与选择上出了问题，让外界产生了强烈的违和感，这一点值得特别加以辨析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班宇曾被称为“东北文艺复兴三杰”之一，著有小说集《冬泳》，也是悬疑剧《漫长的季节》的文学策划。这部以上世纪末东北下岗潮为背景的热播剧，一大主旨就是对“铁饭碗”的反思，尤其是展现了其对人的束缚与异化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;淡豹拥有社会学与人类学学习背景，她的文学作品关注性别、阶层议题，也专长于非虚构写作，长期以来以“关注现实”的面目示人，怎么看都与“编制”扯不上关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无怪乎有网友评论道，看到这则“作家考编”新闻，颇有一种“孙悟空考上天宫编制”“《冬泳》终于上岸”的感觉，其中淡豹还喜提了“申公豹”的网络绰号。原因无他，只因作家之前的作品与“人设”，与考编的行为出现较大反差，让读者产生违和感。对比淡豹曾在访谈中“一个人怎么写，他就怎么活着”的说法，“作家考编”的短短四个字已经让“怎么写”与“怎么活着”互相矛盾了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说作家本人完全隐身于作品之外，并不希望读者“像吃了鸡蛋还要认识老母鸡”一样了解自己，那么“作家考编”就不会引发多么大的争议，比如那些深居简出、极少抛头露面也不搞营销的作家。问题在于，如今的文化界已经高度市场化，青年作家对外出售的除了文学作品，还有各种线上线下的访谈、演讲、见面会、分享会构筑的“人设”，也将这种鲜明的“个人IP”作为一种文化商品出售。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次考编的青年作家里，或多或少都在经营着市场化的人设，这种人设也帮助他们取得了作品的成功，甚至还有作品之外的成功，花钱买书的读者购买的就不止是作家的作品，也包括他们营销包装的“人设”，以及蕴藏其中的价值观与生活方式。读者期待他们实践人设，并对未能言行一致表示失望，这种失望也恰如其分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平心而论，没有任何一条法律法规禁止这几名青年作家考编，自由开放的现代社会当然也允许一个人实践他的价值观与生活方式，但他们这种“华丽转身”也未免有些“突如其来”，自然难逃外界乃至追随者的疑问：他们为什么要去考取编制？编制又能给这些已经取得不小成功的青年作家带来什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，武汉市文学艺术理论研究所（芳草杂志社）是武汉市文联所属二级事业单位，业务范围主要是各项文学学术研究、编辑出版发行《芳草》文学期刊。官网公示的招考条件显示，报考者除了年龄要在40周岁以下之外，还需要满足“三项条件其中一项”：作品获得省级期刊文学奖项，在中文核心期刊或是省级以上出版社发表过30万字以上作品，作品入围过几个特定的文学排行榜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次编制考试的招考条件可谓相当之高，三项条件恐怕就刷掉了绝大多数“普通做题家”。而从公示的成绩表与录取名单显示，此次“入编考试”分为专业能力评审、面试成绩两大类，最后依照综合成绩排名，并没有笔试环节，可见有别于普通的“考公考编”，称得上是为“青年作家”这个群体量身定做。试问，一家文学期刊为何拥有如此之高的招考要求，又为何可以吸引多名青年作家报考？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些青年作家本已在市场取得了成功，也没有逃避竞争去“吃皇粮”的迫切需要，在体制内期刊从事文学理论或是编辑工作多少有些大材小用的味道。因此比较合理的推断是，编制带来的好处不是明面上的“铁饭碗”，而是可以为这些市场化作家提供更好的社会地位，或者说某种身份标记，青年作家之所以要求得一官半职的傍身，大约是可以把两头的好处都占了，这自然符合“理性经济人”的决策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“学院憎恨天才，犹如修道院憎恨圣徒”早就是业界的共识。文学作品本就应该交给市场判断、交给读者选择，而不是一定要作家博得某个“盖章认证”，或是有一官半职傍身，其作品才能通行于世。几名青年作家遭遇的群嘲，也说明了这一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师手机被扣：一天后法院院长送还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[受贿超9.795亿元，中信银行原行长孙德顺一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260353]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 18:26:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;5413&quot; height=&quot;3371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257805&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月10日，山东省济南市中级人民法院公开宣判中信银行原行长孙德顺受贿一案，以受贿罪判处被告人孙德顺死刑，缓期二年执行，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产，在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释；对孙德顺受贿犯罪所得及其孳息依法予以追缴，上缴国库。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4634&quot; height=&quot;3338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257806&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明：2003年至2019年，被告人孙德顺先后利用担任工商银行北京市分行副行长，交通银行北京市分行行长，中信银行副行长、行长等职务上的便利，为有关企业在获取贷款等事项上提供帮助，非法收受财物折合人民币9.795亿余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市中级人民法院认为，被告人孙德顺的行为构成受贿罪。孙德顺受贿数额特别巨大，犯罪情节特别严重，社会影响特别恶劣，使国家和人民利益遭受特别重大损失，论罪应当判处死刑。鉴于孙德顺归案后如实供述罪行，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，受贿所得财物及其孳息已全部查扣到案，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其判处死刑，可不立即执行。同时，根据孙德顺犯罪的事实和情节，决定在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释。法庭遂作出上述判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[女性省级党委专职副书记增至6名丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月7日，河南省委副书记孙梅君在兰考县调研。（河南卫视截图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/62eee4c512.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;595&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/62eee4c512.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月7日，河南省委副书记孙梅君在兰考县调研。（河南卫视截图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月4日，河南日报客户端报道，中共中央批准孙梅君任河南省委副书记。此前，她曾任北京市委常委、组织部部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;孙梅君到任后，女性省级党委专职副书记又增加一名，达到6人，另5人分别是江苏省委副书记沈莹，安徽省委副书记程丽华，江西省委副书记吴忠琼，吉林省委副书记吴海英，四川省委副书记施小琳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;其中，吴忠琼兼任赣州市委书记，吴海英兼任吉林省委统战部部长、省政协党组副书记，施小琳兼任成都市委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;河南省委副书记已空缺&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;个月&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此番履新的孙梅君58岁，四川开江人，长期在中央机关工作。1986年起，先后在国家统计局、国务院研究室、国务院食品安全委员会办公室、国家食品药品监督管理总局、国家市场监督管理总局历练，曾任国家食药总局副局长，国家市场监管总局副局长。2020年12月，孙梅君赴任地方，历任北京市委常委、统战部部长、组织部部长等职，直至此番履新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;孙梅君到任前，河南省委副书记已空缺5个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年6月，时任河南省委副书记、省委政法委书记周霁升任中央港澳办分管日常工作的副主任、国务院港澳办分管日常工作的副主任（正部长级）。此后，河南省委专职副书记一职一直空缺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2004年9月召开的中共十六届四中全会要求，必须“减少地方党委副书记职数，实行常委分工负责，充分发挥集体领导作用”。2006年开始的全国各级党委集中换届中，全国大多数地方党委均建立起了“一正两副”的领导班子架构。2015年12月印发的《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》正式将“一正两副”作为地方党委领导构成模式。但该条例也明确，个别民族自治地方需要适当增加副书记职数的，由党中央决定或者省级党委根据中央精神审批。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此后的多数时间，除新疆、西藏两个自治区是“一正四副”的班子架构，其他省份均为“一正两副”。即一位党委书记、两位党委副书记。两位副书记中，一位同时担任省级政府行政首长，另一名则为专职副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》对省委副书记的职责有明确的界定:担任政府正职的党委副书记主持政府全面工作，组织政府党组活动；不担任政府职务的党委副书记主要协助书记抓党的建设工作，同时可以根据需要协调和负责其他方面工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;值得注意的是，《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》第八条规定，常委会委员名额，省级为11至13人。孙梅君赴任后，河南省委常委已有11人，但省纪委书记自2023年9月起空缺，省委政法委书记自2023年6月起空缺。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;人曾在国家部委工作&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;宣布孙梅君任河南省委副书记的前一天，2023年11月3日，沈莹获任江苏省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;沈莹和孙梅君同岁，也生于1965年。6名女性专职省委副书记中，最年轻的是施小琳，生于1969年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;从任职经历看，6人中，有5人曾在中央部门工作，即孙梅君、沈莹、吴海英、程丽华、吴忠琼，都有部委工作经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;沈莹是河南罗山人，本、硕均毕业于北京大学，先后在财政部直属的出版社、国家国有资产管理局、财政部统计评价司等部门工作，官至国务院国资委副主任。2018年12月“空降”黑龙江省，先后任副省长，省委常委、组织部长，直至此次转任江苏省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;吴海英是浙江义乌人，先后在中国科学院京区党委、中央国家机关工委、中央纪委机关党委、中央纪委国家监委驻生态环境部、中央纪委国家监委驻国家税务总局等部门工作。她曾任中央纪委机关党委常务副书记、中央纪委国家监委驻生态环境部纪检监察组组长、中央纪委国家监委驻国税总局纪检监察组组长等职，2022年5月，吴海英开始到地方工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;程丽华也曾在中央部委工作。她1984年进入青海省财政厅工作，2013年从青海省财政厅厅长任上升任青海省副省长，后来又跨省调任天津市委常委，2018年任财政部副部长，2021年4月调任安徽省委副书记，是二十届中央委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;吴忠琼曾在中国国际工程咨询公司、国防科学技术工业委员会、国家国防科技工业局工作过22年，在2010年组织的中央和地方干部交流中，赴辽宁省任科技厅厅长，此后任鞍山市市长、辽宁省发改委主任。2018年1月，吴忠琼跨省升任江西省副省长，此后历任江西省委常委、赣州市委书记，2022年11月，吴忠琼获任江西省委副书记后，继续兼任赣州市委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;施小琳有丰富的地方工作经验。她是浙江余姚人，长期在上海市工作，曾任上海市民政局局长、上海市普陀区委书记。2017年5月，施小琳升任上海市委常委，兼任统战部部长，当时她是上海市委常委班子中唯一的女性。2018年5月，施小琳首次跨省交流，任江西省委常委、宣传部部长。2021年8月，施小琳再次被跨省交流至四川，任四川省委常委、成都市委书记，2023年7月获任四川省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;在省级常委班子中，还有两位担任行政首长的女性副书记，分别是内蒙古自治区党委副书记、自治区主席王莉霞，黑龙江省委副书记、省长梁惠玲。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;人事动向&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中央台办迎来一位新任副主任】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央台办、国务院台办官网“办领导”栏目更新信息显示，仇开明已经出任中共中央台湾工作办公室副主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;公开资料显示，仇开明生于1964年10月，法学博士，此前曾任海峡两岸关系研究中心主任、中央台办研究局局长等职务。目前，中央台办、国台办有1位主任、3位副主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中央金融办、中央金融工委多名领导亮相】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央金融工作会议召开后，多名中央金融委员会办公室（简称“中央金融办”）、中央金融工作委员会（简称“中央金融工委”）领导已陆续亮相。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国人民银行主管的《金融时报》11月6日刊发的报道显示，国务院副总理何立峰已任中央金融办主任、中央金融工委书记，王江任中央金融办分管日常工作的副主任、中央金融工委分管日常工作的副书记，夏先德任中央金融办副主任，秦斌任中央金融工委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;王江曾任中国光大集团股份公司党委书记等职。夏先德此前曾任财政部党组成员、副部长等职。秦斌此前曾任中央第七巡视组组长等职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【淮河水利委员会新“掌门”到任】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;日前，水利部淮河水利委员会召开干部大会，宣布水利部党组关于淮委主要负责同志任命的决定，杨锋任淮委党组书记、主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;公开资料显示，杨锋生于1971年1月，浙江杭州人。他曾任水利部淮委规划计划处副处长、处长等职，于2020年11月任淮委副主任、党组成员，至此番履新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;淮委是水利部直属事业单位，是淮河流域水资源综合规划、治理开发、统一调度和工程管理的专职机构，总部位于安徽省蚌埠市。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;反腐纪事&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中国工商银行原副行长落马】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央纪委国家监委网站2023年11月4日通报，中国工商银行原副行长张红力涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;生于1965 年1月的张红力，在加拿大获遗传学硕士学位，在美国获工商管理硕士学位，在外资银行工作将近20年，先后任英国施罗德国际商人银行董事兼中国业务主管、德意志银行环球银行全球管理委员会委员、亚太区总裁等职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2010年，张红力出任中国工商银行副行长，成为当时内地从外资银行引进的最高级别高管，2018年“因家庭原因”辞任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中粮集团原副总经理被查，曾深耕地产领域】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月8日下午，中央纪委国家监委网站发布消息：中粮集团有限公司原党组成员、副总经理周政涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;周政生于1963年3月，早年曾在航空航天部第609研究所工作，后长期在中粮集团工作，先后任中粮南方包装有限公司总经理、中粮发展有限公司副总经理等职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2008年6月至2010年12月，周政任中粮地产(集团)股份有限公司总经理，2010年12月任中粮地产(集团)股份有限公司董事长，2012年1月任中粮集团有限公司副总裁，2013年2月任大悦城地产有限公司董事会主席、执行董事，2013年12月任中粮集团有限公司党组成员。2021年3月，周政辞去在大悦城的职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【湖南益阳纪委痛批7人“酒瘾难除”】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月9日，益阳市纪委监委网站发布消息称，益阳市纪委监委深入核查市司法局原党组成员、副局长罗俊伟酒后驾车问题线索，严肃查处了7名领导干部违规吃喝问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年2月26日至3月3日，益阳市委举办市管干部学习贯彻党的二十大精神集中轮训第四期研讨班。罗俊伟违规组织同期参训的大通湖区管委会常务副区长练世宏，南县人大常委会副主任孟祥胜，南县人大常委会副主任张红君，南县人大常委会副主任陈国奇，南县政协副主席王金辉和未参训的市人大农业委副主任委员谢建军，7人一同在益阳高新区某私营企业内部食堂聚餐，其行为系“吃心不改”“酒瘾难除”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;部委信息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【民政部：鼓励有条件地区因地制宜研制婚俗礼仪标准】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月1日至3日，民政部在浙江舟山召开全国婚俗改革暨婚姻登记“跨省通办”工作推进会。会议鼓励探索将婚姻登记与公益事业联系起来，积极举办有特色的集体婚礼、慈善婚礼、绿色婚礼等。鼓励有条件的地区因地制宜研制婚俗礼仪标准，加大倡导推广力度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【人社部：坚决防范化解规模性失业等重大风险】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;新华社11月6日消息，人力资源和社会保障部部长王晓萍接受采访时表示，人社部将全力加强就业监测预警。注重兜底保障，完善重点群体就业支持体系，着力促进青年特别是高校毕业生、农村劳动力特别是脱贫人口、就业困难人员等重点群体就业，切实兜住兜牢民生底线。坚决防范化解规模性失业等重大风险，确保就业形势总体稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【应急管理部：20个考核巡视组进入各省份】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;应急管理部网站11月7日消息，国务院2023年度省级政府安全生产和消防工作考核巡查正式启动。由国务院安委会有关成员单位部级领导带队的20个考核巡查组陆续进驻31个省级政府和新疆生产建设兵团，对2023年度安全生产和消防工作开展考核巡查。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;法治播报&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【最高检发布假释监督指导性案例，明确法律适用规则】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;最高人民检察院2023年11月6日消息，最高检以“假释监督”为主题发布第四十九批指导性案例，这也是最高检发布的第一批关于假释监督的指导性案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【《办理海上涉砂刑事案件证据指引》出台】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;最高人民检察院网站11月7日消息，近日，最高人民检察院办公厅、公安部办公厅、中国海警局执法部联合印发《办理海上涉砂刑事案件证据指引》。《指引》从犯罪主体、犯罪主观方面、犯罪客体、犯罪客观方面、量刑情节等五方面分别规定了这两类海上涉砂刑事案件需要重点收集的证据，为审查办理该类案件指明方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【公安部：假章假证犯罪呈现三大新特点】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月9日，公安部在北京召开“公安心向党护航新征程”主题新闻发布会，公安部刑事侦查局副局长陈士渠在发布会上通报，2023年以来，全国共立案侦办假章假证犯罪案件7700余起，抓获犯罪嫌疑人1.1万名，收缴各类假章假证1200余万枚（本）。此类犯罪呈现出犯罪链条产业化、制假种类多元化、销售渠道网络化的新情况新特点，全国公安机关将持续保持高压严打态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【最高法：未同意加装电梯业主补交出资后有权使用电梯】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月8日，最高法举行老旧小区既有住宅加装电梯典型案例新闻发布会。最高法有关负责人表示，未同意加装电梯业主补交出资后有权使用电梯，其他业主如认为阻碍电梯加装行为给其造成损失，可另案主张权利，但不能以此拒绝业主在补交集资款后使用电梯。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;地方政情&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【内蒙古：将积极申请设立中国（内蒙古）自由贸易试验区】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月9日，在国新办举行的新闻发布会上，内蒙古自治区党委常委、宣传部部长郑宏范表示，内蒙古将积极申请设立中国（内蒙古）自由贸易试验区，提升互市贸易区、综合保税区等平台功能，深化与蒙古国、俄罗斯在农牧业、能源矿产、基础设施、生态环保等领域合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【河北：雄安新区承诺优秀应届本科生入职5年内每月发1000元】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月7日上午，雄安新区在打造创新高地和创业热土聚集新人才政策措施新闻发布会上推出了各类人才引进及重大平台落地奖励等16条政策措施。高校优秀应届毕业生来雄安参加求职应聘考试免费入住“人才驿站”；入职后5年内，每月按博士生3000元、硕士生2000元、本科生1000元发放生活补贴，让人才在雄安安居乐业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【广东：广州拟对电动自行车实行累积记分制度】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;广州市公安局近日在官网发布公告，公开征求公众对《广州市电动自行车管理办法（征求意见稿）》的意见。针对电动自行车，《征求意见稿》提出公安机关交通管理部门可以参照机动车驾驶证记分管理模式，对电动自行车驾驶人违反道路交通安全法律、法规，除依法给予行政处罚外，实行累积记分制度。累积记分达到相应分值，驾驶人应当接受道路交通安全法律、法规教育。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中国人民银行行长潘功胜：5%的增长已经是一个不低的速度】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国人民银行行长、国家外汇管理局局长潘功胜11月8日在2023金融街论坛年会上介绍，今年前三季度，我国GDP增速5.2%，全年5%的预期目标有望顺利实现，“5%的增长已经是一个不低的速度。我国经济需要合理的增速，但更重要的是实现高质量、可持续的发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; text-align: justify;&quot;>;（综合新华社、央视新闻、澎湃新闻、《广州日报》《福州日报》等报道）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>