<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[更能提供情绪价值？网购冲击下，实体店靠什么活下来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258228]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The rise of e-commerce platforms has had a big impact on offline shopping. Coupled with the increase in consumption in recent years, After downgrading, many users, including me, have to shop around online before placing an order, and even start shopping on some platforms that are famous for their low prices, and they still find it really delicious. With such an unstoppable consumer trend, I thought that physical stores would definitely not be able to open. However, after observing my parents’ consumption behavior, I understood how physical stores can maintain a competitive advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown has a newly built self-built house with many rooms and toilets, so there is no one-time renovation. I took advantage of the e-commerce shopping festival to buy a bathroom cabinet for the restroom. This is the product I ordered after reading countless posts on how to choose bathroom ware online. After it was delivered to my hometown, I made an appointment with the installer, and nothing went wrong in the process. The only question came from my dad. In addition to expressing his dissatisfaction with the price, he also asked me a soul-searching question: &quot;Why don&#39;t you go to a store near home to buy it? I know you, it will be easier to repair in the future.&quot; I can&#39;t answer this question, because The reason for online shopping is to pursue cost-effectiveness, but my prices are uncompetitive in front of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I returned to my hometown, my dad couldn’t wait to take me to the bathroom they used and asked me to guess how much the bathroom cabinet in front of me cost. I said I couldn’t guess, “500 yuan!” With a proud look on his face, I could even see his inner monologue: &quot;See if I&#39;m very good. Online shopping is just a cloud!&quot; He explained to me: &quot;This is a sample from the boss&#39;s clearance, and I took it away. &quot;Of course I know that there is a difference between three-no products with nothing and brand-name products. The most direct reflection is the price, but the low price really shocked me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Misfortune never comes singly. After I went home and used the newly installed bathroom cabinet several times, I found that the sink and water pipe connections were not tightened, causing water to seep and drip onto the floor. There was no hexagonal wrench at home, and my dad was sarcastic to me again. If there was something wrong with his bathroom cabinet or water heater, he could just walk a few hundred meters and call someone to repair it, but I could only figure out a solution on my own. So, that bathroom cabinet is still seeping water, and the sound of water dripping on the tiles is my dad’s accusation against me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, it seems that physical stores rely on price wars to win online shopping. In fact, this is not the case. It’s just that my dad’s consumption concept makes him choose low-priced products. In essence, physical stores still rely on their touchability. The excellent after-sales service earns consumers&#39; dependence and trust on it. What’s even more amazing is that it also allows users to pay by providing emotional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One summer night, my parents went shopping to enjoy the cool air. When they came back, they brought a water purifier and a staff member. They also carried a complimentary air purifier and juicer upstairs. I was worried that the two elderly people had been deceived, so I quickly dragged my dad aside and asked him what was going on. The thing is that they were &quot;bewitched&quot; and immediately bought a water purifier. The price was less than 5,000 yuan, and it also came with two gifts. The brand is a regular brand, the store is a regular store, and the staff accompanying me also wear polo shirts with the brand logo printed on them. I subconsciously used my mobile phone to open the brand&#39;s online store and looked for the model my dad bought. After searching to no avail, I consulted online customer service. It turned out that the online and offline models were different. I didn’t buy fakes, but looking at the two gifts, I knew they must be expensive. I still don’t understand the reason why wool comes from sheep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My dad is a person who likes petty bargains, but buying a water purifier is not because it is cheap or because of the two gifts, but because the staff really win people&#39;s hearts. They are not robots in online shopping malls that use text to express intimacy. The guy who came to my house to install a water purifier, after being in contact with him for a while, I thought I might not be able to help but pay for him. During the installation process, he patiently explained the knowledge about use and maintenance to my parents. After completion, he was not in a hurry to leave, but opened the packaging of the juicer and demonstrated how to use it. I was standing aside at that time, knowing how to operate the juicer without reading the manual, so he could leave and get off work. But he asked my mother for bananas and milk, put them in the cup, pressed the button, and explained the operation at the same time. The juicer made a sound like an electric drill. My parents stood beside him quietly, watching with smiles. After the juice was finished, he poured two glasses and handed them to my parents. The three of them were talking and laughing. I was at the other end of the living room, watching this scene, and it felt like they were a family of three. Do you think it&#39;s worth the money? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the emotional value that online shopping is difficult to provide. In addition to a large number of middle-aged and elderly people who cannot use smartphones and shop online, there is also a group of people who firmly believe in physical stores and that only tangible products in the store and face-to-face sales staff can bring a sense of security. The e-commerce economy is booming, but many physical stores are not only surviving, but doing well. I think this is also a little bit of the needs of contemporary people who are prone to emotional emptiness. They need companionship, comfort, real touch and face-to-face communication. Only such care can make cold materials have extra value, and can Be willing to pay for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an employee of a state-owned enterprise in Hangzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独家专访诺贝尔文学奖委员会主席安德斯·奥尔森：“他能让沉默和停顿在剧场中说话”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 12:28:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/09/kha3TeOrTYWc4gmxLBcept2eoPt61ZczTcDWmib1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/kha3TeOrTYWc4gmxLBcept2eoPt61ZczTcDWmib1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, the Swedish Academy awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature to Norwegian Drama Author Jon Foss, whose plays are the most performed of any contemporary European playwright. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, 2023, Mats Malm, the permanent secretary of the Swedish Academy, called Jorn ·Fosse, 64, was driving in the village of Bergen, a city on Norway&#39;s west coast, when he called. Fosse had been carefully preparing for this call for ten years—after all, he had been part of the hot debate about the Nobel Prize in Literature for ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was surprised, but at the same time, in a sense, I wasn&#39;t,&quot; he told Swedish public broadcaster. Fosse promised to drive home carefully. He is the most famous living playwright in the contemporary era and his works have been performed the most. He also writes prose, novels, poetry, children&#39;s literature and translation works. His works have been translated into more than fifty languages. After receiving the Nobel Prize, he complained that there would be no more big prizes to win in the future, &quot;Everything will go downhill from now on!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jorn Fosse was born in 1959 in Haugesund, a small town on the west coast of Norway. De, who made his debut in 1983 with the novel &quot;Red, Black&quot;, began drama creation when he was around 35 years old and completed 40 plays including adaptations in 20 years. According to The New Yorker, after a very successful and busy period working almost exclusively as a playwright, in 2012 Fother converted to Catholicism, gave up drinking, remarried, and rarely wrote plays again, &quot;writing another The idea of ​​a script no longer entertains”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, John Fosse published his most important masterpiece of novels in recent years, &quot;September&quot;. This series of seven novels is written in the form of a monologue, nearly a thousand pages of stream-of-consciousness narration, with sentences never interrupted. According to the New Yorker, the narrator of &quot;Seven Parts&quot; is a painter named Asle, a convert to Catholicism who is mourning the death of his wife Ales. On Christmas Eve, Asler discovers his friend, a painter of the same name, unconscious in a Bergen alley, dying of alcohol poisoning. &quot;Their memories overlap, repeat, and gradually merge into A single voice, a vague consciousness capable of existing in many times and places simultaneously.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After winning the Nobel Prize, Fosse said in an interview that after completing &quot;Seven Parts&quot;, &quot;this announcement was expected to a certain extent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse always insisted on writing in Nynorsk, a language spoken only in the western and central regions of southern Norway. Nynorsk, also known as New Norse, is a written language formed by a linguist who collected dialects from rural areas of Norway in the mid-19th century. Compared to Norway&#39;s other official language, written Norwegian, Nynorsk has a small footprint. In Norway, the first language in which students are taught is supposed to be decided by referendum in each school district, but as of 2016, only 12.2% of primary school students accepted Nynorsk as the main written language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ninosk is a language that Fosse, who was born in the West Coast countryside, learned as a child. He attributed the award to the language itself, which he believed brought a sense of freshness. He is good at turning blank space and silence into speech, and even believes that &quot;Oriental audiences can best understand my works.&quot; Anders Olsen, chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature, mentioned in the Swedish Academy’s biography of Fosse that after completely simplifying the language and dramatic actions, Fosse used the simplest everyday language to touch human anxieties and emotions. uncertainty, and provide a profound experience of proximity to the divine. This brought him extraordinary public recognition and established him as a major innovator of contemporary theatre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anders listed several of Fosse&#39;s writing qualities. One of his key themes is to show, through minimalism and fragmentation, the harrowing transformations of critical moments of indecision. For example, a young mother left her apartment to take out the trash but locked herself out while her children were still inside. She needs to go get help but can&#39;t do that because she can&#39;t abandon her child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fosse presents situations that are immediately recognizable from our own daily lives.&quot; While in the 1995 play &quot;The Name,&quot; a pregnant young girl awaits the father of her unborn child, He was delayed. &quot;A tension is immediately built here due to this sense of uncertainty and the resulting fragmented sentences. Furthermore, these interruptions create a gap between the girl&#39;s desire for a new life with her child and her anxiety about being abandoned by her father Gully.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Death Variation,&quot; a one-act play about a suicidal girl, Fother tells the story backwards from the girl&#39;s death. It is written in brief, staccato language by six nameless people from different eras, both living and dead. The play ends with the girl giving a moving speech from the other side of the grave, expressing a fundamental uncertainty about whether her decision to end her life was the right one. Jon Fosse considers his writing difficult to categorize, &quot;You don&#39;t read my books for the plot. But it&#39;s not because I want to be an incomprehensible writer, I never try to write in a complicated way. I always It’s about writing in a simple and—I hope—profound way.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anders Olsen is the chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature. After the 2023 Nobel Prize in Literature was announced, Anders Olson Si received an email from Southern Weekend reporter as scheduled. He said he was happy to be interviewed and responded within a day. However, he remained tight-lipped on some issues, such as whether the jury&#39;s decision to award the award to Jon Fother went smoothly and whether there were any other strong contenders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is an exclusive interview with Anders Olsen by a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The strongest and deepest emotions are contained in silence and pauses&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past ten years, John Fosse has been regarded as a strong contender for the Nobel Prize in Literature. When did his name enter the Nobel committee&#39;s short list? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For confidentiality reasons, I cannot answer this question. All I can say is that Fosse has been is a globally renowned author whose works have been widely translated since the 1990s and have been with us on the theater stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On what writing qualities does the Swedish Academy pay attention to Jörn· Fother? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Fosse wrote in a wide range of fields. He was a playwright, novelist and poet, especially his scripts and long or short narratives capture our attention. But in all this he was a poet, as he preferred to be called. You can feel it in his language processing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What works of Jon Fother are the main basis for the award? work? Which work does the jury consider to be his most important work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We think (and Fox said so in the review) that after Fox completed his After releasing three volumes of his masterpiece, The Septology - a well-deserved achievement, this award couldn&#39;t come at a better time. This novel and more of his essays, and of course his highly innovative plays from the 1990s, are decisive for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From a personal perspective, you like him Which works? What strikes you most about his writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He can make silences and pauses speak in the theater, and it is in silences and pauses that the strongest, The deepest emotion, that struck me. &quot;Somebody is going to come&quot;, &quot;Death Variations&quot; and &quot;Dream in Autumn&quot; are all wonderful plays. And in his prose, I was completely immersed in &quot;The Septology,&quot; but I especially loved &quot;Morning and Evening,&quot; a book about life written in sparkling and extremely sensitive prose. Short stories of coming and passing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Give voices a special status”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Nobel Prize for Literature was awarded to Jon Fosse: &quot;His innovative drama and prose give voice to the ineffable.&quot; Where does the jury think his innovation lies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Fosse is good at using silence, interruption and postponement of action to evoke deep anxiety in people. This is a striking feature of his drama. In his prose, his use of repetition and evocation is more typical. In both cases, something must be expressed that cannot be easily said. Fother does this in a very touching way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The word voice in the award speech , also seems intended to emphasize Fother&#39;s contribution to literary language. How do you see the connection between Fosse&#39;s literary achievements and his use of the Nynorsk language? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is the first Nynorsk-language writer to win the Nobel Prize for Literature. I think his work should be read in his native language if possible, it has an unpretentious beauty and is not difficult to translate. Compared to written Norwegian, Norway&#39;s other official language, Nynorsk is more traditional, less urban and more closely related to Old Norse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are reading the Nynorsk version ? Are there any good translations to recommend? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I read Fosse in Nynorsk, and it is highly recommended. I don&#39;t have much experience with translations, and both Urban Andersson and Lars Andersson&#39;s Swedish translations are excellent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to understand the &quot;ineffable&quot; in Fosse&#39;s works What does it mean? He introduced his own writing ideas and quoted two sentences, one is Wittgenstein&#39;s &quot;Where there is no words, one must be silent&quot; and the other is Derrida&#39;s &quot;What cannot be said, one can only write&quot;. He thinks the latter is closer to his own ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think both statements can be linked to Fosse&#39;s writing. In Wittgenstein&#39;s Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus, &quot;unsayable&quot; refers to the realm where we cannot formulate propositions, and it is also the realm where we can call it &quot;true&quot;. But literature, ethics, and religion do not use propositions; they belong precisely to the realm of the unsayable. Derrida does not have the same strict standard of truth as Wittgenstein. On the contrary, his &quot;saying&quot; gives writing a special position, which coincides with Fosse. Paradoxically, Fother&#39;s writing gave voice a special status, especially in his dramatic works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Eon Fother believes that he has the greatest influence His writers include Tarje Wessos, the Austrian poets Georg Trakl and Samuel Beckett, and the ones he most admires are Kafka and Knut. Knut Hamsun. How do you think these writers influenced him? What were Fosse&#39;s own innovations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s hard to give a short answer. Fother has a negative worldview in the Gnostic sense (Gnostic (ancient Greek philosophy, which believes that the material world is evil and can only be saved through &quot;spiritual knowledge&quot;)), which is very close to Beckett. The most important thing is the use of negation and questions. Fosse&#39;s play bears a striking resemblance to Waiting for Godot, but this does not lead him to nihilism. There was in Fosse a faith that Beckett did not have and a kind of passive mysticism, like that of Meister Eckhart, which appears in the Heptalogy. 》 is very obvious. I won’t talk about other writers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“It’s very difficult to give a great Fosse performance”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You think the uniqueness of Fosse&#39;s writing lies in the fact that after completely simplifying language and dramatic actions, he uses simple daily life scenes to express human beings&#39; strongest anxiety and powerlessness. A lot of writers can do this, what’s so special about Fosse? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A certain strange confidence, almost childlike self-confidence, and a gentle humor in the negativity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the interview after the award, you said you were blessed Ser&#39;s work touches on common human &quot;anxieties, insecurities, and thoughts about life and death.&quot; This is easily reminiscent of the unease that pervades the world. Are there any practical considerations in awarding the award to Fosse at this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You are always influenced by what is happening in the contemporary world, but I don’t think it is the decisive factor. Fosse is always with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you seen his plays on stage? ’s performance? How is it different from reading a script? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It needs to be pointed out that Fosse&#39;s dramatic works are extremely readable. But this is not always the case. In addition, due to Fosse&#39;s special language and less stage scenery, it is very difficult to give a wonderful Fosse performance on the stage. Please read his work first and then perform your own mental show! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is the award given to a playwright? Although Jon Fosse is one of the most well-known playwrights in the contemporary theater world, compared with the popular candidates in the eyes of the outside world, such as Salman Rushdie and Margaret Atwood, this choice will not be the same. Will there be some niche? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For us it is of course important to focus on drama. Harold Pinter received this honor over twenty years ago and I think now is the time. Interestingly, Fosse also translated Pinter&#39;s work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2014, Fother accepted an interview with the British &quot;Guardian&quot; &quot;In an interview, he said that the Nobel Prize in Literature is usually awarded to very old writers. &quot;You will get it when it does not affect your writing.&quot; Coincidentally, Fosse rarely writes for the theater now. Last year, he told the New Yorker that he wanted to take a break after writing &quot;Seven Parts&quot; and that he is now very interested in literary translation. Does winning the award at this time confirm his previous views? Is this a &quot;lifetime achievement award&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it can be regarded as a &quot;lifetime achievement award&quot;, just like Peter Handke (2019 Winner of the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature) won the same award. Of course, this isn&#39;t always the case. In both cases, it is also important to note that they achieved great things before winning the award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year Chinese writer Can Xue ranked in the British bookmaker Nicer It ranked first in the odds list on the Odds website, attracting enthusiastic attention from the Chinese people. How did the jury respond to the possibility of Can Xue winning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For our confidentiality reasons, I cannot answer this question. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In my opinion, the Nobel Prize for Literature Giving to the so-called unpopular outstanding writers is a promotion of literature. Do you think that influence is declining? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 12:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[706名缅北电诈犯罪嫌疑人分三批移交我方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258285]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 11:26:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In view of the severe situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Yunnan Public Security Bureau continues to strengthen its cooperation with Myanmar-related local law enforcement departments border police cooperation and continued to carry out multiple rounds of crackdowns. Recently, based on the remarkable results achieved in the previous work, the crackdown has achieved another major result. 497 telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to the Lincang Public Security Bureau in two batches, and 209 telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau. Among them, online There are 26 people at large, which has effectively dealt a blow to the arrogance of overseas fraudsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since September this year, the public security agencies in Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er and other places in Yunnan have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar. A large number of overseas fraud dens have been successfully eradicated, and a large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects have been successfully eradicated. The person was handed over to us. In order to continue to build momentum and advance the crackdown in depth, under the command and deployment of the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau further expanded its results. 209 telecommunications network fraud suspects were successfully handed over to us on October 1. At the same time, Lincang Public Security Bureau&#39;s border police law enforcement cooperation has made significant progress. The relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar handed over 497 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us in two batches on September 25 and October 7 respectively. This is another important breakthrough made by the Yunnan public security agencies in border police cooperation, following the Xishuangbanna and Puer public security agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, relevant criminal suspects have been detained by public security organs in Inner Mongolia, Heilongjiang, Zhejiang, Anhui, Fujian, Henan, Chongqing and other places involved in the case. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all the facts of his crimes, and while cracking down on fraud crimes in accordance with the law, they will also dig deep into related crimes such as black and gray products in the country to ensure that the entire chain is cracked down and severely punished in accordance with the law. After continuous and effective crackdowns, 2,317 suspects of telecommunications and cyber fraud in northern Myanmar have been successfully captured and handed over to us, including 23 behind-the-scenes &quot;financiers&quot;, organizational leaders and backbones, and 94 online fugitives, a powerful squeeze This has reduced the living space for overseas fraudsters, and the number of telecom network fraud cases across the country has recently shown a significant downward trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency stated that the telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar mainly involve fraud types such as bill rebates, fake online investment and financial management, fake reseller logistics customer service, fake online loans, etc. The general public is advised to be careful Be vigilant, enhance your ability to detect and prevent fraud, and beware of being deceived. The public security organs will continue to keep a close eye on telecom network fraud criminal groups in northern Myanmar, continue to deepen border police cooperation, continue to organize special crackdown operations, make every effort to clear out fraud dens, arrest fraud personnel in accordance with the law, continue to expand the results of operations, and resolutely protect the people. Property security and legal rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突再起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258274]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On October 7, Palestinian armed groups in the Gaza Strip launched a large-scale rocket attack into Israel. Israel immediately declared a state of war. The conflict between the two countries has resumed, and geopolitical tensions have escalated. More than a thousand people have died.</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙志洋任广州市副市长、代市长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258283]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 11:10:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 9, the 19th meeting of the Standing Committee of the 16th Guangzhou Municipal People’s Congress decided , accepting Guo Yonghang’s request to resign as mayor of the Guangzhou Municipal People’s Government, Sun Zhiyang was appointed deputy mayor and acting mayor of the Guangzhou Municipal People’s Government. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山东省政协原党组成员、副主席孙述涛严重违纪违法被开除党籍和公职]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258281]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 10:20:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Sun Shutao, former member and vice chairman of the Shandong Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, for serious disciplinary violations Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Sun Shutao lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original intention and mission, was disloyal and dishonest to the party, deceived the organization for a long time, resisted organizational review; violated the spirit of the eight central regulations, accepted gifts and consumer cards in violation of regulations, and accepted possible Recuperation arrangements and banquets that affect the fair execution of official duties; failure to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, illegally seeking benefits for others during the selection and appointment of cadres; obtaining high financial returns through private business owners, using authority to benefit relatives’ business activities, and engaging in Trading in power, sex, and money; distorted views on political performance, and falsifying economic data in order to seek personal advancement; wanting to be an official and getting rich at the same time, engaging in power and money trading, and taking advantage of one&#39;s position to benefit others in business operations, job adjustments, etc. , and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Shutao seriously violated the Party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and being suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Party. , is serious in nature and has a bad impact, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Sun Shutao from the party; by The National Supervisory Commission dismissed him from public office; terminated his qualifications as a representative of the 12th Party Congress of Shandong Province; confiscated his illegal income; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“诗可以怨”：谈谈《诗经》中的吐槽]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258074]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of the new semester, the history department of a university made a joke. I wrote an article about an interview with a girl who quoted a poem called &quot;The Book of Songs: Biyang&quot; to express her desire to work hard. But there is no poem called &quot;Beyond the Sun&quot; in the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;. The forged poem is all homophonic. It is written in seemingly elegant words, but when read out it is full of swear words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This editor has probably not done any real interviews or face-to-face conversations. The swearing in this poem is so obvious that you can hear it right away. However, if you think of looking for materials in the Book of Songs, this idea is correct. The function of the &quot;Ode&quot; part in &quot;The Book of Songs&quot; is traditionally believed to be &quot;to describe the beauty and virtue, and to report success to the gods&quot;. Although the gods no longer believe in them today, the Book of Songs is still the highest example of how to declare success, speak solemnly but not rigidly, and be elegant but not pretentious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, although &quot;Beyond the Sun&quot; is fake, and it only plays homophonic jokes, it is not considered clever, and it is &quot;joking and sadizing&quot;. But the poem seems to mean one thing, but actually it means another thing. It is also within the cultural context represented by the Book of Songs. There are so-called &quot;changing style&quot; and &quot;changing elegance&quot; in &quot;The Book of Songs&quot;, which pays great attention to this technique. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Daya·Dang&quot; repeatedly emphasized, &quot;King Wen said to consult, and the daughter of the Yin Shang Dynasty was consulted.&quot; King Wen of Zhou couldn&#39;t help but sigh. What he sighed was the fate of the Shang Dynasty, and then he mentioned Shang Zhou in the poem. The various atrocities committed by the king were listed in detail and criticized repeatedly. The last sentence of the poem is the famous &quot;Yin Jian is not far away, in the time of Queen Xia&quot;. Shang Zhou wanted to know his own ending, and the mirror was at hand, it was Xia Jie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have always emphasized that Shang Zhou was vilified by the Zhou people. The reason is that subsequent dynasties must vilify the previous dynasty&#39;s subjugated king, otherwise it will not be enough to establish their own legitimacy. It cannot be said that this reason does not exist, but the poem &quot;Dang&quot; was obviously not written for this purpose. This poem was written during the Western Zhou Dynasty. The author was clearly criticizing Shang Zhou, but his actual intention was to criticize King Li of Zhou. Firstly, the artillery fire was not directed at King Li of Zhou Dynasty, but was rebounded by Shang Zhou; secondly, it was not the poet who fired the artillery fire like this, but King Wen of Zhou Dynasty. The foundation of this dynasty was created by King Wen. As a descendant of King Wen, can you still oppose him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Book of Songs&quot; initiated this tradition of borrowing from the past to satirize the present. Confucius especially emphasized to his disciples that they must study &quot;The Book of Songs&quot; carefully. Naturally, later generations of Confucian scholars played this trick very well. Why did Qin Shihuang burn poems and books? Just because &quot;Poetry&quot; is indeed an excellent teaching material that reflects the past and the present. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author of &quot;Dang&quot; was probably an important minister in the Western Zhou Dynasty. Traditionally, it is believed that he was Duke Zhaomu who pointed out that &quot;it is better to guard against the people&#39;s mouth than to guard against the river&quot;. At least it is reasonable. Most people can&#39;t talk about such advanced topics, but they also have a technique for venting their resentment through poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who have not read &quot;The Book of Songs&quot; have probably heard that &quot;under the sky, is it the king&#39;s land, and on the shore of the land, is it the king&#39;s ministers&quot;, and then judging based on intuition, they will also think this sentence The majestic praise comes from the official propaganda of the Western Zhou Dynasty. It cannot be ruled out that this sentence was originally propaganda. However, we can read this sentence today because the author of &quot;Xiaoya·Beishan&quot; was a small civil servant in the Zhou Dynasty. These four sentences are followed by two sentences: &quot;Doctors are not equal.&quot; , I am engaged in being an independent scholar.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The six sentences strung together mean: The world is the king&#39;s land, and the land is the king&#39;s ministers. The leadership is really unfair, and the burden is heavy on me. ——Xian means more. It probably means that those who are capable work hard, and the boss assigned all the work to the author. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following section of &quot;Beishan&quot; elaborates on how uneven the work of this department is: some people &quot;sleep in bed&quot;, which is a more elegant way of saying &quot;lying down&quot;; some people &quot;don&#39;t know how to call&quot; , no matter how miserable the people are, it’s none of my business, I’ll just do it if I can; some people are “Qi Chi Yan Yang” and will definitely be late for work and will definitely leave early after work; some people are “Zhan Le Drinker” and indulge in drinking and having fun; &quot;Come in and out of the discussion&quot;, and the reason for going to work is to talk loudly. If there are more people like this, the work will naturally be particularly miserable. He &quot;does not do anything extravagantly&quot; and is &quot;miserably afraid of blame.&quot; The more he does, the more blame he will bear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poem pursues the effect of a majestic slogan that seamlessly connects with the fly camp and the dog dog below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you turn two pages back in &quot;Beishan&quot;, you will read another song called &quot;Xiao Ming&quot;. ——There is a poem in &quot;The Book of Songs·Daya&quot;, the first sentence is &quot;Mingming is down&quot;, and there is a poem in &quot;Xiaoya&quot;, the first sentence is &quot;Mingming is going to heaven&quot;. So the song in &quot;Daya&quot; is called &quot;Da Ming&quot;, and the song in &quot;Xiao Ya&quot; is called &quot;Xiao Ming&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Ming said: &quot;I have passed away in the past, and the sun and the moon are gone. Will the clouds return? There will be no clouds in the year.&quot; I came to work after the Chinese New Year. When can I go home? In the blink of an eye. It&#39;s the end of the year. &quot;I miss me alone, and I am a common man. I am worried, and I am afraid that I will not have enough time.&quot; I miss me alone, and the more things I do, the more busy I am. I feel really sad, and I am afraid that I will never be able to finish my work. “念彼共人，睠睠怀顾！岂不怀归？畏此谴怒。”想我家里人啊，那是真想啊。 “岂不怀归？畏此谴怒”，是我不想回家吗？怕领导骂啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《小明》最后一章，尤其展示了把怨气转化为官方语言的技巧：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“嗟尔君子，无恒安息。”其实说的是你们这些管事的啊，可别太舒服啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“靖共尔位”，好好留在你的位置上吧，言下之意是我汇报工作要你拍板的时候，可别找不到人啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“好是正直”，你要做个正直的人啊，其实是说做人厚道点，该批的你就批了吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“神之听之，介尔景福”，神也在观察着你啊，你别为难人，会有福报的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好吧，两千多年了，小明还是小明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国光大集团原党委书记、董事长李晓鹏被“双开”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258279]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 10:07:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;经中共中央批准，中央纪委国家监委对中国光大集团股份公司原党委书记、董事长李晓鹏严重违纪违法问题进行了立案审查调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经查，李晓鹏丧失理想信念，背弃初心使命，对党不忠诚不老实，对抗组织审查；无视中央八项规定精神，违规收受礼品礼金、接受宴请；违反组织原则，不按规定报告个人有关事项，在干部选拔任用等方面为他人谋利；违规借用管理和服务对象钱款、持有非上市公司股份，利用职权为亲属经营活动谋利；泄露尚未公开的干部选拔任用事项；治家不严，家风不正；既想当官又想发财，长期以权谋私，“靠金融吃金融”，利用职务便利为他人在贷款融资、业务承揽等方面谋利，并非法收受巨额财物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓鹏严重违反党的政治纪律、组织纪律、廉洁纪律、工作纪律和生活纪律，构成严重职务违法并涉嫌受贿犯罪，且在党的十八大后不收敛、不收手，性质严重，影响恶劣，应予严肃处理。依据《中国共产党纪律处分条例》《中华人民共和国监察法》《中华人民共和国公职人员政务处分法》等有关规定，经中央纪委常委会会议研究并报中共中央批准，决定给予李晓鹏开除党籍处分；由国家监委给予其开除公职处分；收缴其违纪违法所得；将其涉嫌犯罪问题移送检察机关依法审查起诉，所涉财物一并移送。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被质疑的苹果，难表达的“碳中和”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/nHIDfd2bNTsJ64eVDpNfavQc80QVApMfkzXL2MOn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/nHIDfd2bNTsJ64eVDpNfavQc80QVApMfkzXL2MOn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年4月17日，世界地球日前夕，成都太古里苹果体验店的苹果Logo小叶子变成了绿色，员工工作服也变绿。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专业词汇“碳中和”正日益出圈，但打上“碳中和”的标签并不容易，一不小心就会招来质疑，哪怕是走在碳管理前沿的苹果公司也不例外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间2023年9月12日，苹果在美国加州推出首批碳中和产品Apple Watch。但9月22日，环保组织公众环境研究中心（IPE）发布《苹果产品碳中和疑云》（以下简称《疑云》），质疑苹果对碳中和产品的清洁电力使用、碳抵消等信息没有作出充分的披露和说明，且未能推动供应商披露工厂层级碳数据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月28日，苹果回复南方周末记者，承诺分享战略和进展，并对一些细节做了回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“碳中和”标签争议由来已久。碳中和简而言之是指排放的温室气体能被抵消。企业在自身节能减排之后，常通过购买“碳信用”（如森林碳汇）进行碳抵消。但近期雀巢、Gucci、易捷航空等企业宣布退出碳抵消市场，第三方咨询公司碳信托（Carbon Trust）从2023年9月起不再提供碳中和标签认证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;争议的背后，是越来越普遍的“漂绿”——企业夸大自身环保行为，并误导消费者信以为真。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要防止漂绿，多位受访者向南方周末记者表示，核心是“公开”。但目前碳中和产品信息披露的颗粒度尚未形成共识，有待标准统一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲已先行一步。法国对“碳中和”相关的宣传提出了信息公开的强制要求。欧盟在2023年9月19日达成了临时政治协议，如果不能提供证明，“气候中和（climate neutral）”“大自然的朋友（nature&#39;s friend）”“可生物降解（biodegradable）”和“生态（eco）”等标签将被禁止使用。这一协议如通过，将在2026年生效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者采访的六位业内人士观点较为一致，既肯定了苹果首款碳中和产品的信息披露可圈可点，同时认为也有提升的空间。对于IPE的质疑，有一半受访者认可苹果需要进一步公开清洁电力使用和碳抵消的信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“苹果对供应商的数据管理和公开水平在全球范围内领先，但仍需充分证明它实现产品碳中和是否用尽全力。”气候未来创始人、《碳中和时代》作者汪军说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/jM1wpQhW07Op9WGsVGUG1fvHbtcFiggO5v2c38y6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/jM1wpQhW07Op9WGsVGUG1fvHbtcFiggO5v2c38y6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年9月12日，美国加州，新款Apple Watch展出。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;首款碳中和产品披露了什么&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Apple Watch如何实现碳中和？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在宣布产品碳中和的元年，苹果在发布会和社交平台播放了《自然之母》（《Mother Nature》）创意广告——苹果CEO库克等向“自然之母”汇报了环保工作。最新产品的环境报告也在官网公布，披露了碳中和Apple Watch的碳足迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以Apple Watch Ultra 2碳中和款为例：基准碳排放为63.2kg，碳减排81%后降至12kg。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;81%的减碳从材料、电力、运输等方面着手：回收材料重量占比超过30%；100%清洁电力的使用；50%及以上产品物流采用非空运。剩下的12kg排放，利用Restore Fund项目的碳信用抵消。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/hPC956MeD0XOs6ChYcF3UQgWM84eRnMypDAreBcP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;928&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/hPC956MeD0XOs6ChYcF3UQgWM84eRnMypDAreBcP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Apple Watch Ultra 2碳中和款的碳排放数据。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（苹果官网，IPE编译/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从苹果获悉，苹果在大幅削减产品排放后，为处理现有解决方案尚无法避免或减少的排放，才会使用基于自然项目的高质量碳信用额。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港大学中国商业学院ESG中心主任施涵向南方周末记者表示，苹果采用了清晰严格的产品减碳方法，优先降低产品生命周期中三个最大的排放源——电力、材料和运输。但他也建议，苹果可参考科学碳目标倡议（Science Based Targets initiative，SBTi）对于设定企业净零标准的要求，在其开展产品碳中和过程，也争取实现不低于90%的碳减排，再寻求碳抵消的途径。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在各项全球应对气候变化的相关倡议中，SBTi以严格著称，与《巴黎协定》努力实现1.5℃的温控路径一致&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（详见南方周末报道&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258230&quot;>;《百余家企业被“公开除名”，科学减碳有多难？》&lt;/a>;）&lt;/span>;。南方周末记者查阅发现，苹果也加入了SBTi。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;81%提到90%并非没有空间。汪军向南方周末记者表示，苹果虽然说明了材料、电力、运输三方面的减排进展，但缺乏和同行业的比较，也未能论证这是否到达自身减排的极限，比如50%非空运物流和30%的回收材料，比例为什么不能更高？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何证明&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;100%&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;使用清洁电力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;苹果的碳减排路径中，清洁电力贡献最多。如何确认苹果产品生产过程100%使用清洁电力，是《疑云》的第一个疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPE通过不同渠道收集到的数据显示，苹果供应商的碳排放量有的仅有小幅下降，有的甚至仍在增长。 《疑云》提出，担心这些供应商实际使用的清洁电力比例非常有限，出现重复计算（double-counting）——宣称将清洁电力分配给苹果，但实际上又分配给其他品牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;环境可持续发展咨询公司Quantis首席可持续发展专家廖勋同样认为，电子产品的供应链涉及多层供应商，对一级供应商要求相对容易，但二级到四级供应商很难管控，在可再生能源比例未经披露的情况下，很难证明各层级供应商都使用100%清洁电力生产苹果产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，南方周末记者从苹果获悉，苹果每年都会密切监控、审查和验证供应商提交的数据，并聘请第三方对供应商清洁能源计划的方法进行独立审查，以跟踪和验证供应商清洁能源的贡献，并为报告的数据提供保证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对重复计算等采访问题，为苹果提供碳中和认证的第三方公司SCS Global Services（以下简称SCS）向南方周末记者表示，“不会向媒体提供我们客户的非公开信息”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《疑云》还认为，根据苹果披露的数据，已承诺使用可再生电力生产苹果产品的250多个供应商中，24%无法通过现场可再生电力或可再生能源采购等方式实现清洁电力替代，需要购买可再生能源证书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公众环境研究中心（IPE）创始人马军表示，代工厂清洁电力使用和采购状况相当复杂，其中很多并非直接接入可再生能源，而是通过购买绿电或绿证来实现碳减排。在这种情况下，有限的绿电如何在其不同的产品线上分配，成为关键。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苹果回复南方周末记者称，新加入承诺的供应商需要一些时间来获取清洁能源解决方案，因此Apple Watch供应链中已经承诺的一些清洁能源尚未投入运营。在此期间，苹果使用自己的可再生能源项目来缩小差距，将制造Apple Watch的电力足迹降至零。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/oPvV6ckNV7gVCA15OIB0hUt2r2x56wnMeiu6J5MY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/oPvV6ckNV7gVCA15OIB0hUt2r2x56wnMeiu6J5MY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年9月27日，丹麦，苹果首席执行官Tim Cook（右）与苹果可持续发展主管Lisa Jackson（中）、欧洲能源公司首席执行官Erik Anderse，背后的太阳能电池板为苹果位于欧洲的数据中心供电。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;资源集中在一个产品线&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;供应商往往服务多家客户，即便供应商将清洁电力都分配给了苹果，《疑云》的另一层疑惑则是“掐尖”（cherry picking）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，《疑云》提出，对比苹果公开数据，新推出的128GB版本iPhone 15 Pro的碳足迹总体比iPhone 14 Pro高约1千克二氧化碳当量，而生产环节则高了大约2千克二氧化碳当量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/NcT0AMj0oNtPP11kFxaplOhnTHvnaaPAoJNVGWMz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/NcT0AMj0oNtPP11kFxaplOhnTHvnaaPAoJNVGWMz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;128GB版本iPhone 15 Pro的碳足迹比iPhone 14 Pro 高。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IPE报告《苹果产品碳中和疑云》截图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新一代苹果主流产品碳足迹相较上一代不减反增，令马军产生怀疑：“理论上讲，企业通过掐尖的方式把清洁电力等指标、资源集中到一个产品线上，是可能让小众产品更快实现碳中和的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，苹果向南方周末记者强调，并不存在掐尖问题，没有将分配给iPhone或其他产品的电力用于Apple Watch。 iPhone 15 Pro的排放量比基准减少了28%，其中大部分减排来自可再生能源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但苹果没有明确回复iPhone 15 Pro的碳足迹为何比iPhone 14 Pro增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从业内人士处了解，可再生能源项目投入运营需要时间，可能会反映为个别环节的碳足迹起伏。苹果《2023年环境进展报告》显示，2022财年的总排放量比上一财年减少了260万吨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马军认为，为避免“数字搬运式”碳中和的情况发生，苹果需要有更多信息披露以供验证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;碳抵消项目详情待公布&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《疑云》提到，苹果关于碳抵消的信息披露也不够透明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如苹果在Apple Watch Ultra 2碳中和产品环境报告中称，减排后剩下的12kg利用Restore Fund项目的优质碳信用进行抵消。但未对项目作出详细说明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苹果在2023年4月发布的《2023年环境进展报告》显示，Restore Fund基金由苹果和保护国际基金会、高盛公司在2021年联合推出，第一阶段的工作重点是培育可持续管理的森林，产生优质碳排放权，主要项目包括对巴拉圭和巴西的优质生产性森林和原生生态系统展开修复和保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去远方买一片森林的固碳量，如何保证这片森林不被砍伐、山火烧毁或是重复计算，碳抵消项目正遭受着争议&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（详见南方周末报道&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/257762&quot;>;《多家企业放弃，森林碳汇为何不香了？》&lt;/a>;）&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位业内人士向南方周末记者表达了类似的观点。施涵认为，苹果的首款碳中和产品报告中没有透露其使用的碳补偿项目的具体细节，如项目类型、位置、数量及价格等。这使得外界难以评估其碳补偿的质量和有效性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月28日，南方周末记者从SCS获得了Apple Watch表带和手表的六份碳中和证书，证书显示了每款产品的碳排放、碳抵消数量、参考国际公认的SCS -108和ISO14067碳中和认证标准，但不包括碳抵消的具体信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SCS营销副总裁Karen Righthand及苹果公司向南方周末确认，以上证书可面向社会公开，公众之后可以在苹果官网及苹果发布产品次年的年度环境进展报告中查询。 10月6日，SCS绿色认证产品平台已上线证书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5kGm4JJ1bSIjPJm0bfUoKqIF4f7p3fWviLERgMgJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5kGm4JJ1bSIjPJm0bfUoKqIF4f7p3fWviLERgMgJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Apple Watch Ultra2（配高山回环式表带款）的碳中和证书。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（SCS/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者获悉，碳信用的具体信息通常在项目结束后公示。目前Apple&amp;nbsp;Watch碳中和产品所对应的Restore Fund碳信用项目可能尚未结束。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在苹果《2023年环境进展报告》的附录页中，可查询到用于清偿苹果2022年公司运营排放足迹的两个碳抵消项目信息，分别是位于秘鲁亚马逊地区的Alto Mayo森林保护项目和位于肯尼亚东南部的凯乌鲁山地区REDD+项目，包括项目的基本描述、年份、清偿量和项目在第三方碳信用核查机构Verra的注册链接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于Restore Fund，Verra官网上目前可查询到一个已完成项目——Forestal Apepu的位置、规划、起始时间等具体信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马军表示，苹果回应诉求，向社会公开碳中和证书，是值得肯定的一步。但目前的碳中和证书仍缺乏碳信用的具体信息，既然已经始宣传和营销碳中和产品，也应及时向社会披露碳抵消项目更详细的信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《疑云》援引了依据英国标准协会（BSI）发布的PAS2060碳中和标准，企业向核查机构提交碳中和验证申请时，应该提交碳抵消的量、种类、签发时间、有效期、注销日期等。虽然PAS2060标准并未要求企业向社会公开以上信息，但马军认为目前国际上对于碳中和产品存在较多争议，有必要审视并完善当前的标准，提高数据披露的要求，构建可以公开验证的证据链。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;数据披露&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;颗粒度&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;之争&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;马军认为，解决争议的最佳途径就是全面向社会披露碳数据。但《疑云》提出，苹果“在环境信息公开的立场上出现倒退”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年起，IPE陆续推出“绿色供应链CITI指数”“企业气候行动CATI指数”，以评估品牌在华供应链环境管理表现，苹果连续多年名列前茅，成为CITI“卓异品牌”之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，IPE碳披露平台正式上线，企业需要改变提交碳数据的方式，IPE多次就其披露政策的改变与苹果确认，希望苹果推动供应商填写披露表单，而苹果向IPE表示，“不会要求供应商向社会披露工厂层级的碳数据”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据此，IPE怀疑苹果“出现倒退”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苹果与IPE进行了几轮沟通，《疑云》公开了苹果回应IPE的邮件，苹果表示“对供应商向苹果报告碳排放的要求没有倒退”，“我们继续鼓励供应商公开披露其范围1和范围2排放，参与IPE的倡议，并倡导透明度”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者多方了解发现，IPE和苹果双方都支持供应商信息公开碳数据，分歧在于披露的颗粒度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPE鼓励企业公开工厂级别数据。 “部分供应商集团下属工厂众多，有些甚至全球分布，如果只是公布供应商集团层级的数据，无法对应到具体的工厂，就无法清晰地判断实际代工工厂的减排进展。”马军解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而苹果鼓励供应商披露公司层级而非工厂层级的碳数据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苹果回复南方周末记者称，供应商为应对气候变化可以采取的最有影响力的行动是向可再生能源过渡。由于（供应商获取可再生能源）这种积极影响跨越地区并可能跨越许多厂区，因此最好在公司层面进行衡量，可再生项目是附加的，并本地化到发生制造业务的同一电网。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“工厂层级”数据还涉及是否为商业机密的争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综合性双碳服务商广州捷碳科技有限公司总经理管维佳向南方周末记者表示，碳数据关联很多核心机密数据，对于这类数据的披露和分享，企业有权也有必要进行权衡，有些数据存在空白可以理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若只有第三方机构才能获取、核查企业碳中和产品数据，其他相关方就很难验证。马军认为，苹果在宣传碳中和产品的过程中，不应将其披露责任“外包”给无权披露的第三方机构，除非授权第三方机构代为披露，“污染和碳排放数据不应被归入商业秘密，公开是原则，不公开仅应是例外。遏制气候漂绿的起点，必须是，也只能是全面和完整的信息披露。在碳中和概念广受争议的当下，我们希望看到市场上涌现出经得起公开验证的碳中和产品”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“需要承认的是，目前对于精准盘查制造业碳排放数据的依据和标准仍然不够严谨和完善，受到质疑很正常，质疑也有助于促进整个碳行业的发展和进步。”管维佳说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;要不要先打造一款碳中和产品？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;要不要先打造一款碳中和产品，也有争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;施涵认为，企业选择一款产品实现全生命周期的碳中和，是逐步实现全部产品碳中和的关键起步。但他也提出，消费者在购买Apple Watch时，可能不清楚哪些搭配才是碳中和——因为只有选择特定的手表和表带组合时，才能满足要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪军也持类似观点，通过Apple Watch的碳中和试点示范，苹果可以跑通流程，有利于实现2030年全线产品碳中和目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;廖勋则持反对意见。他认为，内部跑通流程无可厚非，但不宜在现阶段营销“产品碳中和”的概念。企业进行碳中和实践和宣传产品碳中完全不同，前者是企业出于社会责任的行动，后者则是直面消费者的市场行为，“在碳中和各项标准尚未完善的情况下，企业自主宣称的碳中和没有实际意义，还会面临&#39;漂绿&#39;的风险”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马军表示，碳中和的标签在国际上存在争议，为此一些利益方已着手制定更加严格的要求。在相关标准需要完善的条件下，给产品贴上碳中和标签的企业，有责任通过全面的信息披露，来支撑绿色营销，以免误导消费者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苹果碳中和绿色标识是五片醒目的绿色树叶，但也有企业表示放弃碳中和的标签。比如2023年5月，依云在其网站上发布消息称，依云对其获得的碳信托认证感到自豪，但不会寻求全球范围内的再认证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，碳信托也宣布不再提供碳中和标签认证。碳信托总部位于英国，有超过20年的咨询和认证经验，曾在2007年发布全球首个基于产品碳足迹认证的碳标签。碳信托中国区总裁赵立建告诉南方周末记者，“碳中和标签在全球依然有很高的需求，取消碳中和标签并非因为依云或其他公司不再继续使用”，而是因为“市场在不断地发展，需要提供更具雄心的碳标签来配合”。更新标签已经过深思熟虑，并非仓促取消。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵立建称，消费者希望企业采取更积极而透明的气候行动，碳信托更新后的碳标签不再强调碳中和，避免消费者误以为产品没有碳排放或零排放，而是重点关注碳减排和产品碳足迹比较。比如减碳标签会展示通过减排措施，产品碳足迹比以前减排了多少；低碳标签会列举：此产品的碳排放较同公司类似产品更低；或此产品的碳排放较市场上同类产品更低。标签还通过网址/二维码展示更全面的信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们应该更谦逊地面对碳中和问题，认识到圆满达成碳中和背后的复杂性，正视其中的困难。”马军说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[钱伟长 最厉害的偏科生丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[把家庭财产、公司财产洗为个人财产？拆解三种洗钱类型]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258204]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 23:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;北京电视台《法治进行时》栏目有报道这么一个案例，从免费到高额收费，年过六旬的陈女士在北京市海淀区一家医疗美容机构里，禁不住一次次的“忽悠”，短短10个月内进行了370笔转账，总计花费在美容方面的资金达544万元，甚至有一天单日消费就达79万元，花光了全家的积蓄和老伴儿的救命钱。该新闻引发了热议，有网友称，“如此反常之举是否涉嫌转移家庭资产？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从报道来看，一方面该医疗美容机构先以免费为由，一步步将陈女士引入收费项目，销售顾问甚至称可“先帮忙垫付”部分费用并且无法提供相关病历，确有违规之嫌，但另一方面，陈女士明知丈夫身患癌症，居然将治病费用及全家积蓄全投入其中，其行为也有令人感到蹊跷之处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家里的钱，不是夫妻一方想怎么用就随便用。 2022年，北京市房山区人民法院曾审理一起离婚案件。妻子酷爱美容等高消费，将60万元家庭存款挥霍一空。法院经审理认为，涉案60万元存款属夫妻二人经营所得，为夫妻共同财产。夫妻双方对共同财产有平等的处理权，但夫妻一方在行使处理权时应秉承节制、理性及审慎的原则，合理、规范使用，切不可挥霍浪费，不能损害配偶方的财产权益。本案中，妻子行使合理处置权的部分，法院予以保护，过度高消费的部分，因未征得配偶方的同意，非以家庭日常开销为目的，且有挥霍性质，属侵害配偶方财产权益。最终法院判定该女子给付前夫存款补偿款20万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以此推理，陈女士将500余万家庭积蓄及老伴治病费用拿去“天价美容”，同样涉嫌损害丈夫财产权益。值得注意的是，上述报道中还提到一个细节，“医美机构给出了一份消费明细。其中，总消费金额、消费记录与银行调出的转账明细中多处存在出入”，实际支出与账目不符，相关资金究竟是用于美容开支，还是以美容为名转移家庭资产？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着有关部门对于“反洗钱”宣传力度加大，公众对其概念有所了解。洗钱，本质上是非法资产或其他不属于个人的资产通过各种方式掩饰、隐瞒、转化，使其在形式上合法化的行为，大致可分为三种类型：将家庭资产洗为个人资产，犯罪团伙或贪官黑钱漂白，将公司资产洗为、化为己有。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在上述“天价美容”案例，看客为当事人“千金一掷为美颜”的贪痴愚而感慨。或许某些人的反常之举，不过应了那句老话“别人笑我太疯癫，我笑别人看不穿”，以大额消费为名，将家庭财产转为个人财产，一旦后续婚姻关系生变，也就为财产切割做好了准备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将家庭资产“洗”成个人资产，方式还有很多。比如，用夫妻共同资金购买贵重首饰，归到自己名下；定期给父母家一大笔“红包”，后续再让父母家将钱打入自己账户；等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将来路不明的资金漂白，常见于贪官、犯罪团伙等。贪官以投资企业、购买艺术品甚至定期给儿女巨额生活费等途径，将贪污所得洗干净。公职人员利用境外公司，在进口设备和原材料时，高报进口价格，再从其手中拿巨额回扣，然后将非法所得留存国外，如此不仅将公款化为己有，而且还实现了资产向境外转移。公职人员还可借助“白手套”设空壳公司境外投资，即先在国外设空壳公司，然后利用手中职权给予各种便利，最终将境内所得以对外投资的形式汇到境外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;犯罪团伙则通过投资影视剧、虚拟货币交易等，让非法所得洗为合法收益。有犯罪团伙与赌场勾连，在赌场中将现金兑换成代币，再将代币直接交付给洗钱的受益人。再由他去将代币兑换回现金（通常需要5%左右的手续费），在外可声称在赌场内赌赢的。这样可以避免透过纸钞上的编号直接追查到洗钱的受益人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了以上两种洗钱方式，富豪通过在境外购买自己公司发行的境外债券然后利用职权优先兑付等方式，完成公司资产到个人资产的转移。比如，公司因经营不顺债务累累，面临破产。富豪作为公司实控人，让公司发行美元债券，年利率高达百分之十几甚至更高，然后富豪大量认购。如此操作，富豪作为公司实控人理论上只在股权范围内承担有限责任，公司还不上债是公司的事儿。这样通过“正当程序”掏空公司，金蝉脱壳，将公司资产转为个人资产，然后本人携家人、子女去境外安享后半生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>