<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[专访编剧芦苇：好的电影都有社会意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257491]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1460&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp . jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, &quot;Alive&quot;, &quot;Tuya&#39;s Marriage&quot;, etc. written by Lu Wei The film won awards at international film festivals such as Cannes and Berlin. The picture shows a still from &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Wei is 72 years old. He never uses social media. His daily contact is only through the phone. Over the years, he has become accustomed to I write with pen and paper and write one movie script a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October 2022, he said goodbye to his relatives and friends in Xi&#39;an and took a flight to the United States via Guangzhou. In addition to visiting his son whom he had not seen for a long time, during this trip, he also had to collect information for the next script. &quot;One advantage of writing scripts in the United States is that it is quiet and no one disturbs me. Unlike here, for example, if there is an event, you can&#39;t go even if you don&#39;t go. They are all acquaintances and friends. If you don&#39;t go, people will feel presumptuous, and it is easy to give people a A misunderstanding occurred.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1415&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei poses with Zhang Yimou, Lu Le, and Zhao Jiping (from left to right). As screenwriters, directors, cameramen, and musicians, the four of them are top-notch actors in the industry. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among China&#39;s professional screenwriters, there are few who have the same connection with three generations of film history as Lu Wei The directors have all worked together and witnessed the ups and downs of Chinese cinema over the past four decades. In 1988, his first work as a screenwriter, &quot;The Price of Madness,&quot; became the box office champion of the year. Since then, a series of works such as &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, &quot;Alive&quot; and &quot;Tuya&#39;s Marriage&quot; have won awards at international film festivals such as Cannes and Berlin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before his departure, his study was a little messy. The walls and table were covered with large and small paintings and photographs. There was a note nailed to the wooden board against the wall, written in Lu Wei&#39;s handwriting: &quot;Make up your mind to write &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot;! This is a key battle to fulfill your long-cherished wish. Go all out and never give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The multinational big-budget movie &quot;Wolf Totem&quot; released in 2015 After that, Lu Wei spent more of his creative energy on low-cost films, which gradually made him move away from the center of capital. In his view, movies have no big or small size, only good or bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is no retirement in the job of a screenwriter. Now I only write what I like and don&#39;t consider anything else.&quot; He told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Although the remuneration for small-cost films is low, it is not about money. Problem, the advantage is that there is no burden, and there is great freedom of choice. The level of attention is not a matter for me to consider, I only care about my script.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1402&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1995, Lu Wei and Jiang Wen (right ) during the filming of &quot;Song of Qin&quot; in Xi&#39;an. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Wei&#39;s latest screenwriter&#39;s Tibetan story &quot;Lausang Family Affair&quot; has not yet been released. I have finished writing a new martial arts-themed script &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot;, and then I want to put the story of &quot;Barefoot Doctor&quot; Sun Lizhe on the screen to reflect the past of the &quot;educated youth&quot; generation. &quot;Sun Lizhe went to the countryside in northern Shaanxi from Beijing and saved many people by learning medical skills. Since it is difficult to see a doctor now, I wrote about Sun Lizhe as a way to look up to him. I hope that all Chinese doctors can become people like Sun Lizhe. The Chinese people will be blessed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to his creations, Lu Wei’s public statements are also eye-catching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, on the occasion of the 100th anniversary of the birth of Chinese cinema, Lu Wei and his friend Wang Tianbing held a dialogue titled &quot;When will Chinese cinema grow up?&quot; and sharply criticized films including Zhang Yimou, Chinese directors including Jia Zhangke and Lou Ye think they don&#39;t know how to write stories and their themes are confusing. He was an outspoken critic of &quot;The Promise&quot; and parted ways with his old friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Lu Chuan&#39;s &quot;Nanjing!&quot; Nanjing! &quot;The King&#39;s Feast&quot; was severely criticized by Lu Wei. However, in 2013, when he attended the press conference of Lu Wei&#39;s new book &quot;Secrets of Film Screenwriters&quot;, he said: &quot;I was very confident at one time. I wrote the script according to the logic of commercial feature films and shot it.&quot; At that time, I was thinking about subversion. Fortunately, I met Lu Wei at the crossroads of my life. After having an in-depth chat with him, I felt that I was wrong at the time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; won gold After receiving the Palme d&#39;Or, director Chen Kaige (left) took a photo with Lu Wei. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/11/17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1281&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11 /17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1992, Lu Wei and Gong Li (right) in &quot;Farewell&quot; Ji&quot; studio. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luwei is greatly influenced by Hollywood movies and values ​​the watchability and social significance of movies. , has been working as a screenwriter for more than 30 years. He talks about the &quot;genre&quot; of movies more than the &quot;art&quot; of movies, and believes that there are no secrets to screenwriting. In the recently published book &quot;Film Screenwriters Have No Secrets&quot;, Lu Wei disclosed for the first time the detailed inside story of writing the script of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;. What surprised some fans is that this film is currently the only film to win the &quot;Palme d&#39;Or&quot; award at the Cannes Film Festival. Lu Wei&#39;s requirements for the scripts of Chinese-language films are that they must be &quot;typified&quot; and the stories must be good-looking, reasonable, and true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said: &quot;The title of the first book talks about the &#39;secrets&#39; of film screenwriters. I don&#39;t like it. I think there are no secrets for film screenwriters, they are just rules. The new book published this time I I just want to tell everyone this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, Southern Weekend reporters interviewed Lu Wei in Xi&#39;an. At that time, the most important &quot;National Day&quot; prime period of the year did not achieve the expected results. In terms of box office results, the Chinese mainland film market has rarely experienced a severe &quot;film shortage&quot; with only five new films being released in the entire month, and only three new films scheduled for release in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked about his views on new Chinese movies, he said: &quot;There are not many Chinese movie scripts that are qualified. Some movies are obviously script-problems. They require a lot of investment and effort, but the foundation is not good.&quot; Okay. The script is the foundation of the movie. If this foundation is not solid, the movie will definitely not be exciting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I finished college in a movie theater&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You used to study art. You first entered Xi&#39;an Film Studio as an art artist. How did you later transform into a film screenwriter? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the beginning, I did not prepare to be a screenwriter in my life plan and ideals. Later I came into contact with movies and also worked in film art. One day I suddenly realized that script writing is also a kind of plastic art, which is connected with fine art. I used to paint with colors, but now I paint with words. The principle is the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was completely by chance that I entered Xiying Film Factory. When I was recruiting workers, I was told that there was such a company that was recruiting people, but the job type was probably a cook. Although I was not willing to be a cook, I thought this unit was good and related to art. I didn’t know anything about movies at that time, but I just thought I could get in touch with art, so I joined. I thought to myself that even if I was a cook, I would still have a chance in this unit. As a result, I didn’t even work as a cook for a day. People knew that I could draw. After seeing my paintings, they said, “No problem, you can become an artist.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To do film art, it is inevitable to have to deal with it. to a movie script, because the content of the script determines the content of your work. If you do a lot of art, you will be able to see the problems in the script, how the script should be written, and how to write it is interesting. At that time, there was a so-called youth film crew. All the creative staff, including art and photography, would meet together to discuss the scripts. I often gave comments to some scripts. Later, I made many comments, and sometimes the director used them to provoke me. Fa said, &quot;Then you write and say that this is not good and that is not good, then you can do it yourself.&quot; So I really did it myself. They also felt that the script that was written was better than the original one. This also gave me confidence that the original script could be written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first work for which you were signed as a screenwriter was &quot;The Price of Madness&quot; directed by Zhou Xiaowen &quot;Well, this film was a sensation at the time and was the box office champion in 1988. But this is not the first time you have participated in screenwriting work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first one was &quot;They Are Young&quot;, but it failed. Wu Tianming was the director at the time, and he knew that I could write scripts. , pay more attention to me. Later I wrote &quot;The Last Madness&quot;, and that movie was somewhat well-received. It sold for a lot of money. Then I wrote &quot;The Price of Madness&quot;. At this time, I signed my name as the screenwriter. Wu Tianming was very supportive of me. I said, &quot;If you want to be a screenwriter, I will transfer you to the literature department. If you want to be a director, I will transfer you to the directing team. You can tell me what you want to do and I will support you.&quot; After hearing this, I felt that the director of the factory was treating me so favorably. I was very grateful to him, and I said I&#39;d better write a script. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you choose the screenwriter and director? Screenwriter, what&#39;s the difference between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I know a lot about screenwriters, but I don’t know about directors. I think the screenwriter is the designer and the director is the construction engineer. It often happens that the engineer can&#39;t understand the designer&#39;s creativity, so he will change your drawings to what he wants, so the final product may be different from what the designer imagined. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been a director and made a film called &quot;The Long Road to Xixia&quot;. I won the Golden Rooster Award for Best Director&#39;s Debut that year and also won several international awards. But I don’t think I’m a good director, and my directing business is not good. My nature is not suitable for being a director, and I really don&#39;t like to direct people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, with the progress of the film industry, the importance of screenwriters has Sexuality has gradually come to the fore. In addition to screenwriting majors offered in colleges and universities, screenwriting classes have also begun to appear in society. When you were young, there were few dedicated places to learn screenwriting. How did you improve yourself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just watching movies. Movies are different from other things. For science and engineering knowledge, it is best to receive systematic training. Movies are a very intuitive art. You can learn it by watching movies. Through analysis and research, you can become an expert. There is no need to learn. Not to mention attending a film college, I didn’t even have a complete education. I went to the countryside to work as a farmer in a mountain village in Baoji in the second grade of junior high school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am lucky because my father works in the People&#39;s Building in Xi&#39;an, which is a reception unit. He is the captain of the automobile team and is responsible for receiving some foreign experts and senior cadres. , so I had the opportunity to watch some foreign movies very early on, such as &quot;Quiet Don&quot;, &quot;Nights of Kabylia&quot;, and &quot;The Bicycle Thieves&quot;... In fact, the cinemas in the 1950s and 1960s were relatively abundant. Yes, it was not until the mid-1960s, when the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; was about to begin, that films began to be &quot;one size fits all&quot;. It was not until the late period of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; that some North Korean films began to come in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was making movies, it was still very difficult to watch movies. It gradually improved after 1980, when some foreign movies gradually came in, and it became easier to learn movies at that time. In addition to the convenience of working in the West Film Studio where you can watch some movies, Beijing has begun to hold events such as American Film Week and Spanish Film Week. At that time, a ticket cost about 25 cents, but it didn’t matter that you couldn’t buy it. I could only buy black market tickets, and some movie tickets could be sold for ten yuan. The salary at that time was very low, only thirty-six yuan, but I still wanted to see what I really wanted to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many movies that impressed me deeply, such as &quot;General Patton&quot;, &quot;The Dark Horse&quot;, &quot;Guess Who&#39;s Coming to Dinner&quot;, &quot;Into the Wild&quot;, etc. At that time, I had to take a train from Xi&#39;an to Beijing, and there was no I had extra money to stay in a hotel, so I settled in a friend&#39;s house, and then bought black market tickets every day. &quot;Dark Horse&quot; directed by Ballard is about the friendship between a child and a black horse. I liked it very much and watched it five times in one go. At that time, watching movies was mainly about learning the look of the movie, writing down my thoughts, and building an understanding of the composition of the movie. I completed my college studies in the cinema. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reading is equally important in your career. In this special era, you You participated in a book club. What was the atmosphere like at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1973, we started to organize a reading group, which can be regarded as a reading club. There are more than ten like-minded friends. The conditions for joining That means you have to have a certain level of education and be interested in theory. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have no organizational form and no name. We just conduct a learning exchange in the name of a gathering of friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We read theoretical books, such as &quot;Dialectical Materialism and Historical Materialism&quot; by Ai Siqi. We used it as an outline, discussed it chapter by chapter, and then summarized everyone&#39;s opinions on it. Use your insights. This book was an orthodox book at the time, and there was no danger in studying from it. After the &quot;September 13 Incident&quot;, the central government advocated the study of theory and designated several Marxist-Leninist classics, which we have all systematically read, such as the introduction to &quot;Das Kapital&quot;, &quot;Anti-Dühring&quot; and &quot;Ludwig &quot;Feuerbach and the End of German Classical Philosophy&quot; and &quot;The Communist Manifesto&quot;. In fact, at that time we had already begun to have our own thinking about the social situation and felt that some changes were about to happen. We just didn&#39;t know where this change would lead, so we thought Relying on reading to figure out some problems is our motivation for learning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At that time, you were trying to clarify some confusions about your future. How is it judged? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just know that I have hobbies and think that I must work hard to achieve my pursuit, but I don’t have any idea how to achieve it. I was studying and studying art at the same time. In order to find books, I also went to the libraries of various universities to steal books. I was discovered later and was detained at the police station for three days. Fortunately, we were lucky. The director was very kind to me. I always felt that the kid who stole the books was because I love reading and asked me to write a promise and go home. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We were in an era of information poverty, an era of extreme blockade, with no information at all. Today is an era of information explosion. Both are abnormal, one is hungry and the other is too full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei spent more than a year writing the movie script of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, most of which was spent doing various research. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;You cannot write &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; as a pure art film&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Going back to the book &quot;Movie Screenwriters Have No Secrets&quot;, you seem to have special respect for Hollywood movies because of the 1980s. Do you mainly watch American movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It exists in all countries, but it is undeniable that Hollywood has the greatest influence around the world, and American movies are a good learning object. Because their film composition is the clearest. This may also be a characteristic of Americans, who are relatively simple and direct. After studying, it comes to actual combat. Writing scripts means writing one after another, constantly moving towards new goals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have repeatedly emphasized that &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; should be written Genre film, does this have anything to do with its huge investment? When you talked about this movie in your book, you also emphasized that the script is for directors and investors, and the simpler the better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Screenwriters have to create based on cost, and this must be the case, because I am a professional, and the investment in &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; is It was a huge sum of money at the time, and I felt that it couldn&#39;t be turned into a purely artistic film. I remember when I first started writing the script, Wu Tianming told me how much a certain play would cost and not to overwrite it. Later, Peter Chan asked me to adapt Ha Jin&#39;s &quot;Waiting&quot;. My first question was how much to invest. This is a habit of mine. Later, he said there was no limit, so I started writing. Although the story is a small story, my The background is a big scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; is also adapted from a novel. In this book, you and Wang Tianbing analyzed the differences between the novel and the script, and you still think that the original novel is second-rate. Why do you think so? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think this is a classic novel, just a common romance novel. Chen Kaige once came to me In a letter, he talked about his wish for us to read the text of the novel again. The original author later published a new version of the novel based on the movie. Even so, the movie and the novel are still different in many places. The ending is very different, and many characters are newly added by us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Cheng Dieyi and Duan Xiaolou in the novel We finally met in Hong Kong, but your ending was that Cheng Dieyi committed suicide. Why did you change it that way? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This may be related to the experiences of many Peking Opera artists. I hope that every detail and scene in the movie &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; Provenance. For example, the character Yuan Siye, when he was shot at the end in the movie, he walked towards the execution ground with dramatic steps. That was the real story of the execution of a &quot;drama tyrant&quot; named Gao in Wuhan. The scene in which Cheng Dieyi was criticized comes from the past when people from the literary and art circles paraded through the Imperial Academy in Beijing during the Cultural Revolution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How long did you prepare for this script? Are you satisfied with the finished film? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It didn’t take long to write. It was mainly research, which took more than a year. For research, I had to travel everywhere, including the reference room of the Northern Kunqu Opera Theatre, the Opera Research Institute of the Chinese Academy of Arts, the library of Peking University, and the Beijing Library (now the National Library). I rented a room in a hotel next to the library. I went to the library every night and took a notebook to copy information. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movie was shot very well in the end. The regret is that some details can still be refined and some academic research can be done. There are also some performances that can be better, such as the old eunuch’s final performance. , I also felt that it was too pretentious and my understanding of this character was wrong. Of course, this cannot shake the final quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1450&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei (first from left), Ge You (middle) and veteran artists on the set of &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Alive&quot; is adapted from Yu Hua&#39;s masterpiece. Which one do you think is more difficult than &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Alive&quot; is very difficult, because this novel is well written, so it is not easy to change, so be careful when making changes. fear. When I wrote &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, my spirit was free, and I felt in my heart that it should be based on mine, and the novel was wrong; but when adapting &quot;Alive&quot;, I wanted to try not to touch the novel as much as possible, but of course I still had to touch it. , after all, they are two carriers. For example, in the novel &quot;Alive&quot;, Fugui&#39;s son died by drawing blood. In reality, this is too rare. There is a problem with the audience&#39;s acceptance. The writing is a bit cruel and beyond our life experience, so I changed it to a car accident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Judging from the ending, &quot;Alive&quot; finally gave People hope that it is not as cruel as the original work, and seems to be more tender than &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This movie is about family life. The style is a little different, but the quality of the two is the same. I should have written &quot;Alive&quot; shortly after I finished writing &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;. The origin is that I previously collaborated with Zhang Yimou on a film about Shaanxi shadow puppetry, and he also went to pick up the location. Later, he saw &quot;Alive&quot; and told me to do this first. I also liked this novel, so I agreed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I made a documentary about old Shaanxi artists performing shadow puppetry. Zhang Yimou liked it very much and found it particularly charming. He watched the film at my house and was very excited. He stayed at my house that night. , we chatted all night and said that we must put shadow puppetry on the screen, and then we put this element into &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let him become a living person&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Do you think that period was considered a better time for Chinese films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course, the policy is relatively loose, and the filmmakers also have a very fighting spirit. Everyone was willing to unite and make a good movie. At that time, personal demands seemed to be gone, and they just wanted to make a good movie. The desire for fame and fortune is relatively weak, and the movie has not begun to be marketed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the filming of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; was completed, Chen Kaige asked me to go to Beijing, so I went. He said that he had set up a company. I&#39;m a little skeptical about this, because when you set up a company, your motives are not necessarily so pure, and you have pressure, unlike in the system. I said something that maybe he didn’t understand. I said, “I don’t think so if you run a company. I think you’ll be hurt.” In fact, I meant that doing art wouldn’t be so pure in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, I am willing to continue to cooperate with him after that. He was going to shoot &quot;Feng Yue&quot; and asked me to be the screenwriter. When I saw that it was about the &quot;Demolition of the White Party&quot; in Shanghai, I decided to do it. I went to Shanghai to do research and wanted to find out what was going on. After I went to the Shanghai Research Institute of Literature and History to read the information, I found that there was no &quot;explosion of the White Party&quot; in history, so I was unwilling to write this script. Only if I believe it can I write a script. If I don&#39;t believe it, I can&#39;t write it. After I talked to Chen Kaige, he asked me if I could fictionalize it, and I said I couldn&#39;t do that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, I persuaded him at the time that &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; had been successful. Could we make a movie with a small investment but that we really wanted to make? But he still made &quot;Feng Yue&quot;, although It was basically the original cast of Farewell My Concubine, but it was a box office failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have also criticized the fifth generation directors for not being able to write scripts, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I mean they are not very good at telling stories. They are relatively unfamiliar with drama. What they study in school are all works of art and they admire It is also a work of art, and no effort has been made to the plot. The film school seems not to pay much attention to the plot, emphasizing the artist&#39;s style and the artist&#39;s personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many directors have made masterpieces, but later The works are becoming more and more disappointing. What do you think of this problem?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is normal. For example, athletes may create creative works when they are in good condition. World records, when the state is not good, that is, at an average level, they also have to face failure and the result of being eliminated. Filmmakers are the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You and many directors will have disagreements. , such as &quot;Red Cliff&quot; and &quot;White Deer Plain&quot;, what is the reason behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am not unhappy with John Woo. He and the producer approached me to write a red cliff story. Later, he didn&#39;t use the script I wrote. He used his lover&#39;s script, and I published my version as a book. The main reason is that my understanding of &quot;Red Cliff&quot; is different from his. I think Red Cliff is a battlefield and a struggle, while he thinks the theme is peace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had a very unpleasant quarrel with the director while filming &quot;White Deer Plain&quot;. He did not understand the theme of &quot;White Deer Plain&quot; and thought it was the relationship between man and land. But I think this book is about the father. The struggle with Zi is a conflict between two generations. What&#39;s more, his focus is not on movies, so some people say that this version of &quot;White Deer Plain&quot; is &quot;The Biography of Tian Xiao&#39;e&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are there any scripts that you have written but have not yet been filmed? Do you feel regretful? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; I just finished writing a script about the history of the Hetao area. It is a story about a swordsman from the Qing Dynasty, called &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot; . I have always had a special liking for martial arts films, and I also like Hetao folk songs. I just wanted to make a martial arts film with singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have always paid attention to new films, and you have often done so before. Review some new movies. What do you think of the recently released domestic films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was good to shoot &quot;The Myth of Love&quot; in Shanghai, but it also had its problems. For example, the three female characters are all too beautiful, and they don’t look like people from the market. They look like movie characters at first glance. There is also a problem with the image of the male protagonist. He is a good old man, too conceptual, and a bit simple. From my understanding of good old people, they are not that simple. These take away from the dramatic power of the film, but the story is good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you create movie characters, how do you let them A more believable character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You have to understand him and put the character into a real life scene. Don’t conceptualize, don’t simplify, don’t flatten, let him be a living person, a person with emotions, a soul, and emotional appeal. We often have misunderstandings when photographing heroes. Heroes all have emotions and desires. Truth, goodness and beauty, only truth can be good and beautiful. Some movies always make people unconvincing, but they are just not true. Such movies cannot be made by sycophants. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, theme-themed movies have once again become an important movie phenomenon, can you write the main melody movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have written two. There is also a main theme in the greatest movie of all time, namely Eisenstein&#39;s &quot;Battleship Potemkin&quot;. This is the Soviet main theme and was later regarded as the masterpiece of montage theory. I have never been convinced. In fact, my parents are both old Eighth Route Army soldiers. I think the main theme can be filmed. Unfortunately, the two films I wrote myself were not filmed. I still want to film them if I have the opportunity in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among the recent movies, you seem to be very optimistic about &quot; &quot;I&#39;m not the god of medicine&quot;, what&#39;s the reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It has far-reaching social significance. Difficulty in getting medical treatment is the common aspiration of the whole society. This movie happened to reveal this problem, so I think it has social significance. From an artistic point of view, this movie can continue to be refined, but this movie has extraordinary significance. Good movies, such as &quot;The Crow and the Sparrow&quot; and &quot;Small Town Spring&quot; have profound social significance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天成奇峡：云蒸霞蔚的“世外密境”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“失去对身边美好的感知”：社交媒体还是我们自己的问题？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258048]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Yan Fei, a professor of sociology at Tsinghua University, said: Social media brings people far away, but we But I lost my perception of the beauty around me. This remark triggered a lot of discussion, with both praise and criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One criticism says that experts from the pan-humanistic society tend to fall into reflection on &quot;new technologies&quot; and &quot;new trends&quot;, giving people a sense of criticizing for the sake of criticizing. However, this does not mean that Yan Fei’s statement has no value. Whether it inspires resonance or triggers refutation, it shows that it has touched many people and must be right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has social media brought to us? Is it empowering us, allowing us to better control our lives, helping us contact and discover the larger world, and achieving better selves? Or is it going too far and consuming us, and we are being included and swallowed, becoming this &quot;superorganism&quot; &quot;Human flesh input and output terminal, everyone produces fragments, and is fed fragments? The answer may be different for everyone. Different views on a technology can reveal its different aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a positive perspective, social media has indeed reduced the cost of communication. You can establish links with strangers in distant places without leaving home and just inputting and clicking a few times, sharing your opinions with each other and getting timely feedback; Moreover, in the online world, everyone can take off the mask they wear in real life and reveal their true self without worrying too much about offending others with their honesty. Some people will unite into a community based on common knowledge background, values ​​or hobbies, find an ecological niche that suits them, and find the meaning of survival. For those who feel lonely and out of tune with the people around them offline, it is also a kind of happiness to find that &quot;I am not alone&quot; online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, with the deepening popularity of mobile Internet and smartphones, more and more freelancers can work from home or even anywhere, especially for knowledge workers. For these people, social media is already an infrastructure for doing work, or a productivity tool. Others’ criticism and reflection on social media are just clouds and noise to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, barring a massive catastrophe, it is impossible for us to return to the state of things before social media for long. In this sense, all criticisms and reflections on social media are irrational and fleeting, while those that are reasonable can at best promote the improvement of social media. Of course, each of us is free to choose, and can independently decide the frequency and type of social media use, and the appropriate proportion and time of online and offline life. Therefore, we cannot treat our mental weakness and disability as Blame it on social media or something else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this general premise, we may admit that Yan Fei’s statement sees a problem.当然，表面上是社交媒体的问题，实质上是我们自己的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位网友对此话“于我心有戚戚焉”，Ta说，自己很爱看视频拍出来的草木黄昏之类，但现实生活里的就没太想去看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摆拍的生活或加了滤镜的生活当然不是真的生活。你是有选择的，你可以放下手机，去远足看一次日出，也可以在阳台上看一次日落，与真实的世界、与真实的人建立联系，感受身边的美好，也可以手机不离手，算法就会根据你的需要与欲望不断向你推送，让你一直很嗨，直到头昏脑胀、筋疲力尽，事后有消耗感与空虚感。当然，你也可以有节制地使用手机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本来，你要陪伴孩子，以增进亲子之间的了解与感情，或者与家人朋友周末一起去户外，安享恬淡的时光。但你拿起了手机，化身为社交媒体的英勇斗士，挥斥方遒，那你可能真是忽略了身边需要关爱的人，“失去了对身边美好的感知”。但只要你抽身离开，社交媒体对你只是一个死物，一个负责任的人不会推卸自己的责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一位网友反驳道：如果身边有美好，还有时间用社交媒体吗？大家不就想摆脱身边那一地鸡毛，才从社交媒体找自己幻想的世界吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;适当地从现实生活抽离、放松放空自己是无害有益的，文武之道，一张一弛。不过，逃避现实生活是不可取的，你不可能一方面在现实世界中过得很失败，另一方面在虚拟世界成为不世出的大英雄。现实世界“弃疗”的，也很难在虚拟世界“满血复活”。虚拟世界如果成了你逃避现实生活的麻醉剂，那只会放大与加剧你在现实生活中的失败，每一次你下网、回到现实的那一刻会面临无尽的精神空虚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毋庸讳言，现实生活意味着柴米油盐，意味着责任与压力。我们可以暂时抽离压力，但最终还是得面对。晚面对不如早面对。绝大多数父母无法养你一辈子，“全职儿女”之说只是自欺欺人。一个人的成长，一个人从精神上成长为一个合格的成年人，根本在于，激发自己内在的动机与勇气，使用自己天赋的才智与习得的能力，认领自己的责任，自己的事儿自己扛起来，报偿是做成事情的那种无与伦比的成就感，及一个精神上更强大的自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对绝大多数需要在现实世界拼搏的人来说，社交媒体应该是佐剂与点心，而不该是麻醉剂与正餐。从接受有效信息的角度看，也不应该对社交媒体全身心交付。某些社交媒体刻意制造“信息茧房”已经到了登峰造极的地步，同样一个新闻事件或热帖，给男性与女性看到的评论区都可以完全不一样，以精准迎合你的心思，或者说精准操控你的认知，岂可不惧？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，社交媒体给你带来什么，你是主宰它，还是它主宰你，根本上取决于你的自主选择，取决于你如何使用它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从卖寿衣到“古装大佬”，它凭什么抢占了半壁戏服江山？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257711]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;曹县一直以来生产棺材和寿衣，垄断了日本90%以上的棺材市场。2008年，曹县碰上线上火爆的戏服销售市场，当地居民开始转行卖戏服。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;纵观曹县整个汉服产业发展史，接地气、不抬杠、缺啥补啥、虚心请教……成为它显著的发展标签，在这个过程中，曹县将山东人实在的品质，体现得淋漓尽致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“知道”跟你谈谈，从寿衣到戏服，曹县是怎么转型的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72816&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69684&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; img-title=&quot;曹县1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;5863&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252254&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72817&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69685&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; img-title=&quot;曹县2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4530&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252255&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72818&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69686&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; img-title=&quot;曹县3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4875&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252256&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72819&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69687&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b3e2c3432d.png&quot; img-title=&quot;曹县4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;3435&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b3e2c3432d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252257&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[私搭浮桥18人获罪案启动再审：“原判决适用法律确有错误”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258058]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月，吉林洮南，即将建成的便民桥。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;881&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，吉林洮南，即将建成的便民桥。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾引起广泛关注的私搭浮桥18人获罪案有了新进展。2023年9月27日，吉林省白城市中级人民法院作出再审决定，认为原判决适用法律确有错误，符合再审条件，决定由白城市中级人民法院提审。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洮南市人民法院刑事判决书显示，2005年至2018年，黄德义伙同他人在洮南市瓦房镇振林村至白城市洮北区平安镇安全村洮儿河河道私自建船体浮桥，拦截过往车辆收取过桥费，收费标准为小车5元，大车10元，共计52950元。因犯寻衅滋事罪，黄德义获刑二年，缓刑二年，另有17名亲属获刑一年至拘役三个月不等，均为缓刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位接近案件的法律人士告诉南方周末记者，“按照我国的司法实践，法院启动再审是非常慎重的，通常经过很严格的审查。”该法律人士分析，纠正原判决有两种可能，一种是无罪，另一种是减轻量刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;再审决定书。受访者提供&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252967&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;再审决定书。受访者提供&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“是否强拿硬要”或是再审焦点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;再审决定书中提到的“原判决适用法律确有错误”，上述法律人士分析，根据最高法的司法解释，构成寻衅滋事罪必须具备一定的流氓动机和强拿硬要的客观行为，且破坏社会秩序。案件再审的焦点将围绕黄德义的相关行为是否构成寻衅滋事罪展开，即黄德义是否具有寻衅滋事罪的主观故意以及强拿硬要的客观行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“因此，再审的争议焦点可能会在黄德义是否有强拿硬要的客观行为，具体而言就是，黄德义是否强迫他人过桥。”该法律人士认为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，黄德义在接受南方周末记者采访时，解释之所以修建该座浮桥，是因为自家在河对岸有地，同时，祖上都是摆船的。黄德义称，“小车5元，大车10元”的收费标准是与过桥的村民商量决定的。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;详见南方周末报道《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252355&quot;>;涉黑村霸、破坏车道、返还过桥费？搭桥获罪者再回应争议&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于黄德义自称无强制收费的说法，在此前媒体报道中有不同声音。2023年7月，与振林村只有一河之隔的安全村村支书谷天福在接受媒体采访时表示，黄德义曾故意挖断河道，让往来村民不得不从他的桥上走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一审判决认定的收费金额52950元，有多名村民此前接受南方周末记者采访时，称不止这个数额，一位也曾在洮儿河上搭建过浮桥的村民估算，黄德义搭建浮桥收取的费用或多达上百万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收取金额的认定是否会对再审判决有影响，上述法律人士分析，再审决定书说，原审是法律适用错误，再审阶段应聚焦法律适用问题。“本案不是数额犯，黄德义是否构成犯罪以及量刑，与数额没有绝对的对应关系。”同时，刑诉法解释第469条规定，除人民检察院抗诉以外，再审一般不得加重原审被告人的刑罚。“从这方面看，再审给黄德义加重量刑的可能性不大。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据洮南市人民法院刑事判决书，黄德义除了搭建浮桥外，还组织亲戚17人排班守桥。若参与守桥的其他涉案17人中有人存在强拿硬要的行为，是否会对该案及黄德义产生影响？上述法律人士称，若其他人存在强拿硬要，他本人或也不构成犯罪，因为没有共同犯罪的故意，但前提是黄德义本人对此行为不知情。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;新桥10月底建成通车&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;因“浮桥获刑”引发关注的，除了案件本身，村民出行需求也引起当地重视。2023年7月，“洮南发布”发文称，计划在原浮桥附近建一座便民桥，将在秋收前建设完成。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;详见南方周末报道《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252709&quot;>;争田、渡河与拆桥：“私搭浮桥”案背后11座非法浮桥的困局&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者了解，该座便民桥选址并不在原浮桥附近，而是建在下游约十公里处的福顺镇榆树村。9月30日，榆树村村支书王左相告诉南方周末记者，之所以便民桥选在榆树村附近修建，是因为该段河面比其他地方的河面要窄，洮儿河上其他河面都有四五百米宽，“咱这儿二百多米宽”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅河面窄容易修建桥梁，还因该处处于“中心点”。洮南境内共有两条河流，分别是洮儿河和蛟流河，约67个行政村分布在两条河的两岸。在新的便民桥建成之前，全长156公里的洮儿河仅有三座大桥，分别为一号桥、满洲岱桥和镇西桥。王左相称，“桥设我们这，南北基本上都能够得着。桥修好后，离满洲岱桥约20公里，离镇西桥约35公里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该项目公示牌显示，&lt;a>;&lt;/a>;&lt;a>;新修建的便民桥为钢板材料，桥长327米，桥宽5米，投资685.2万元，计划完工时间为2023年10月31日。&lt;/a>;王左相称，每年10月中旬，当地开始秋收。“现在咱们洮南这边基本上修完了，已经铺装桥面了。”但因便民桥所架的洮儿河是分界线，一岸是洮南市，另一边归属白城市洮北区。9月30日，王左相告诉南方周末记者，“洮北区那边有个河汊子，大概50米宽，还没修，现在这桥属于断头桥。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洮南市委宣传部一位工作人员告诉南方周末记者：“我目前掌握的情况是他们在加速往前推进建桥，桥梁主体已经基本建设完成，&#39;断头桥&#39;是对岸的引桥，在我们桥梁建设过程中是必须保障的，那个工程要启动实施的话，两三天就能建完，不是多复杂。桥的事肯定是没有问题的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王左相认为，便民桥建成后，肯定会方便两岸的老百姓。但是他又有了新的忧虑，他认为，等桥建成后，来往车辆会非常多，而他所在的榆树村距便民桥仅3公里左右，进出车辆“净走我们屯”，会压坏村里4米宽的水泥路，而且村民出行危险系数也变高了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他希望相关部门将来可以修复村里被压坏的道路，同时，在便民桥周边的路口设置标识，比如标明十字路口，或T型路口。“我是一村之长，这事我得对村民出行安全负责。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[规避现代认知框架的陷阱：读葛兆光老师序言有感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhWQU0xWSXD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhW QU0xWSXD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Gangsheng has two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had time to read Teacher Bao Gangsheng’s new book &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot; (Guangxi Normal University Press, 2023), just after reading the preface by teacher Ge Zhaoguang, I felt that this book must be very interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have read Bao Gangsheng&#39;s &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; (Peking University Press, 2015) and his works on democracy. I do not study political science, but am interested in discourse analysis, so the so-called Reading is just a superficial reading out of curiosity about political science discourse, especially the cognitive evolution of terminology and the presentation of discourse. Bao Gangsheng’s academic foundation and keen awareness of issues are absolutely top-notch. Just because I read his &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, I am full of expectations for his new book, but I also have some mixed thoughts about what Teacher Ge said in the preface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is positive about Bao Gangsheng’s approach to the history of ancient thought from the perspective of modern political science, and believes that this is promoting the dialogue between Western theory and Eastern thought. He believes that it is meaningful to re-examine ancient thoughts from the perspective of modern political science. I completely agree with this, but I feel that in doing so, we must avoid the traps of modern cognitive frameworks. Cognitive frames have many functions, one of which is what William James called &quot;selective attention.&quot; One consequence of selective attention is that we pay too much attention to the similarities or differences between the objects being observed, ignoring the fundamental differences or similarities between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Give an example. When Bao Gangsheng introduced China&#39;s political outlook in &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, he mentioned three different political outlooks, one is modern, one is ancient, and there is also the Soviet model, that is, class rule. Let&#39;s not talk about this for now. . In the words of Bao Gangsheng, in the ancient political view, &quot;politics&quot; &quot;is most commonly understood to refer to the activities of the monarch and his ministers in ruling the country and governing society.&quot; Simply put, it actually means &quot;monarchy.&quot; According to Bao Gangsheng’s explanation, the modern political outlook is “the Chinese translation of English politics” and is a foreign concept. He quoted Sun Yat-sen&#39;s view that &quot;the management of people&#39;s affairs is politics.&quot; There is another sentence before: &quot;Government is a matter for everyone.&quot; Therefore, the politics in Sun Yat-sen&#39;s mind is &quot;administering political affairs by the people&quot;, which is the so-called &quot;democracy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to teacher Gao Quanxi in the book &quot;Modern Western Political Thought&quot;, the ancient Western monarchy is completely different from the ancient Chinese monarchy. If Bao Gangsheng’s summary and Gao Quanxi’s statement hold true, “monarchy” politics and “civil rights” politics are different concepts and belong to different cognitive frameworks with essential conflicts. Western &quot;monarchy&quot; theory and ancient Chinese &quot;monarchy&quot; or &quot;royal power&quot; also belong to different cognitive categories. According to the most basic assumptions of discourse analysis, terms generated by different cognitive frameworks and categories belong to different semantic fields and form different semantic relationships with related words. Two questions arise: 1) Is it appropriate to use different cognitive frameworks to explain political concepts expressed in the same text? 2) Is it appropriate to use words with different semantic relationships to explain the same term? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why I have such doubts is because there are many such examples in &quot;Political Science&quot; that I think are specious. For example, &quot;Confucius believed that politics should be upright. If the king above is upright, the people will be upright.&quot; When commenting on the concept of Confucius, Bao Gangsheng mentioned &quot;The Wealth of Nations&quot; and &quot;Theory of Moral Sentiments&quot; written by Adam Smith. He seemed to think that &quot;virtue&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; are synonymous with Confucius&#39; &quot;rectitude&quot;, as if It is said that Confucius&#39; &quot;benevolent government&quot; and &quot;ethics&quot; are highly similar to Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook. Is it really like this? Is Confucius&#39;s moral outlook centered on &quot;royal power&quot; and based on the differential order pattern the same as Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook based on the concept of equality centered on &quot;civil rights&quot;? If traditional ethics are virtues, then why did Lu Xun think that ethics cannibalize people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example, &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; is based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;The master of the Ming Dynasty guides his ministers with only two handles. The two handles are the virtue of punishment. What is the virtue of punishment?&quot; Killing is called punishment, celebrating reward is called virtue.&quot; This passage makes the following judgment: &quot;The principle here is close to the management philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organizations, that is, organizational management should pay attention to clear rewards and punishments.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t understand the philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organization management. Is such a simple principle of clear rewards and punishments the fundamental principle of modern industrial and commercial organization management philosophy? Are the premise of this principle for industrial and commercial organizations to be the same as Han Fei’s? What are the standards of modern principles? What are its basic assumptions? Do the two involve the same semantic relationship? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same section, the author draws this conclusion based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;If a person does not die, the coffin will not be bought. Love does not mean hating people, but benefits from people&#39;s death&quot;: &quot;In fact , Han Fei had a perspective similar to Adam Smith more than 2,000 years ago, and he had elaborated the &#39;economic man&#39; hypothesis and the methodology of individualism to a certain extent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;As an economic concept, doesn’t “economic man” have different basic premises and presuppositions? Is the core semantic term of &quot;individualism&quot; as an ism just &quot;profit&quot;? Are their semantic fields the same as Han Fei&#39;s? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw Teacher Ge’s high-level summary of some of the book’s viewpoints in the preface, such as “summarizing Taoism using methodism, weakness, inaction, and abandonment of wisdom.” Based on past readings, I even had the idea You shouldn’t have unreasonable doubts if you haven’t read the original work. I don’t know how the discussion of the book unfolded. Taoism&#39;s &quot;following the Tao, being weak, doing nothing, abandoning wisdom&quot; all have their own specific historical context and intertextual relationship. Is the &quot;wisdom&quot; mentioned in &quot;Qi Zhi&quot; a general sense? In terms of semantic relationship, can &quot;abandoning wisdom&quot; be separated from &quot;extreme sage&quot;? Although the political thought of Taoism is mentioned in academic circles, those who do not talk about &quot;governance&quot; but pursue &quot;governing by doing nothing&quot; and do not talk about &quot;law&quot; but hope for &quot;a world of supreme virtue&quot; generally use &quot;quan&quot; as the core meaning. Xiang’s “political thought”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Teacher Ge’s perspective in writing the preface is different. He criticized that &quot;some people always want to advocate &amp;nbsp;&#39;interpret China by China&#39;&quot;, meaning that these people attempt to study ancient Chinese thought in isolation from the world&#39;s modern pluralistic knowledge system. I totally agree with this. I think of Takeuchi&#39;s &quot;Asia as Method&quot; and Maruyama Masao&#39;s &quot;China as Method.&quot; The methods they advocate do not exclude the world&#39;s diverse knowledge systems. They just hope to use China&#39;s historical experience and traditional thoughts as one of the world&#39;s cognitive systems and methods. The reason why those advocates of &quot;explaining China in terms of China&quot; are problematic may be because they want to break away from the world&#39;s diverse knowledge system and develop a system that only they (here, they themselves) understand, and cannot communicate with others because they ignore consensus. The mystical explanation system of dialogue; or because its purpose is not to explain China in terms of &quot;China&quot;, but to explain China from the perspective of traditional &quot;rulers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is right in criticizing that these people always want to &quot;advocate going back to ancient times&quot; to find a &quot;whole must and tail&quot; explanation system. If these people have any basic respect for common sense, they should know that they cannot go back after receiving modern education. According to the basic assumptions of pragmatics, the context on which cognition is generated is not reality, but a construction, which is the result of selecting specific parameters. The so-called ancient context is actually a modern construction they made for a special purpose and based on their chosen cognitive framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, what Teacher Ge said: modern concepts and re-division and integration, &quot;allowing the originally chaotic ancient culture to present an understandable face&quot; should refer to allowing ancient culture to be understood in the modern cognitive environment. However, any contemporary &quot;rediscovery&quot; of ancient documents is actually a cognitive reconstruction of ancient times based on modern knowledge or experience. Therefore, how close this understanding is to the original face of the research object also depends on different perceptions. Know the choice of framework. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I am not opposed to re-examining ancient ideas from the perspective of modern political science to present different modern understandings. I just want to say that the premise of this kind of review is that we cannot ignore the historical semantic fields and semantic relationships of various conceptual systems, and we cannot cut them off to suit their needs. What cannot be forgotten is that the reason why we can find modern elements in ancient concepts, that is, the so-called &quot;ancient concepts&quot;, is more because we have replaced the cognitive framework and placed related concepts in different semantics. field, a new semantic relationship is constructed based on the new semantic field. But because the words are still words from the past, it is very easy to mistake our construction for the original semantic items of these words. This is what I think is the trap of modern cognitive frameworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book &quot;Political Science&quot; actually has a clear understanding of the differences in historical semantics. As the book points out, ancient Greece, the source of Western political science, had a fundamentally different view of politics: “In the eyes of the ancient Greeks, politics was the governance and management activities in which citizens of the city-state participated. The concept of politics at that time itself included citizen participation. The meaning of city-state affairs. Only the participation of citizens in the governance and management of city-state affairs can be called politics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, although the political words of &quot;royal power&quot; and &quot;civil rights&quot; have not changed, they Do they belong to the same semantic field? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had the chance to read &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot;. &amp;nbsp;These are at best a record of random thoughts caused by reading the preface of the book posted online. I will wait until I have time to read it. , be sure to read the original work carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 18:25:27 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[哪些孩子需要课外培训？我在高考大省的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258018]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 16:57:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Professor Shen Yan of Peking University HSBC Business School published a paper in Economics (Quarterly) entitled &quot;Education Burden Reduction, Family Education Expenditure and Educational Equity&quot; paper. The author uses the China Family Panel Study (CFPS) survey data of 14,960 households in 25 provinces, municipalities, and autonomous regions across the country from 2010 to conduct empirical analysis on a total of 42,590 individuals to evaluate the overall impact of burden reduction policies on students&#39; academic burden and family financial burden. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the results of the paper, students from families with incomes in the bottom 10% have an average probability of entering high school that has dropped by 9.3%, total education expenditures have dropped by an average of 21%, and weekly study time has dropped by an average of 9.19 hours. . For students from families with incomes in the upper 10%, the probability of entering high school has increased by 5.3 percentage points on average, total education expenditures have increased by 67% on average, and study time per week has increased by 10.37 hours on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall conclusion is: first, the previous burden reduction policy has brought about the differentiation of educational output, increasing the probability of students from high-income families entering high school, while the probability of students from low-income families declining; Second, the burden reduction policy has also led to the differentiation of education investment: on the one hand, the education expenditure and student learning time of high-income families have both increased, while the low-income families have experienced a decrease; on the other hand, families with high investment in the early stage will reduce their family education expenditure. And low-investment families will increase their education expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This conclusion is simply that children from high-income families invest more in educational expenditures and educational time, and the results are better. Children from low-income families, on the other hand, experience a decline in financial resources, time, and effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be said that this research is basically consistent with my observations around me. I live in Shandong, which is a province with a large population and a high level of college entrance examination. The difficulty of the college entrance examination also falls into the &quot;hell mode&quot;. In such a general environment, it is impossible to be completely &quot;flat&quot; on education issues. Parents attach great importance to education and examinations, and basically spare no effort in investing in education within their capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an English training institution downstairs from my house. Although it is not as well-known as New Oriental and Xueersi, the management is generally quite formal and the student pool is decent. Many children have signed up there. The &quot;double reduction&quot; policy was introduced and business resumed after a period of suspension. This kind of reopening is also compliant, because the &quot;double reduction&quot; has a series of clear requirements for off-campus training, as long as you fully cooperate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, except for those places in the country where the college entrance examination is in the &quot;easy mode&quot;, many places are facing the pressure of competition for higher education. In these places, even people in the education authorities are also faced with the education problems of their own children. They still have some understanding of the actual situation at the grassroots level, so with a pragmatic and people-oriented attitude, some management aspects that are more humane can play a certain buffering role during the implementation of the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reopening, prices have generally increased. For old customers, with various discounts, prices are basically the same as before. For new customers, the price has increased compared to before. Moreover, if you choose to pay fees for one year before, you can enjoy certain discounts. However, according to the latest regulatory requirements, you can only pay fees for one quarter at a time, and the discounts are no longer available. In fact, it is also a disguised form of payment. Price increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My eldest child is 11 years old this year, and my second child is 6 years old. One is in sixth grade and the other is in first grade. My child&#39;s classmates have previously enrolled in various cram schools, including mathematics, English, composition, etc. Of course, there are also those who don’t enroll in any classes. The overall situation is that those who used to enroll in various classes are still enrolling now, and I haven’t heard of a decrease. I used to rush to events on weekends, but I still rush now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of &quot;double reduction&quot; is to reduce the burden on families and children. However, the specific situation in each province and each region is somewhat different. In a province with a large population like Shandong, the pressure of competition in the college entrance examination will be passed down through the layers. Although parents also hope that their children can develop in an all-round way, they do not dare to take the scores lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents of several children get together, the focus of the chat will easily fall on the issue of future studies. Not only the college entrance examination, but also the previous high school entrance examination, high school and junior high school school selection and other issues. A very real problem is that although academic performance is downplayed in policy, most parents still focus on performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not all children who need tutoring are suitable for tutoring. Top academics are never taught. Academic champions generally have strong self-learning ability and self-motivation. They don&#39;t need to make up lessons, and it can even be said that their level may be better than the teacher&#39;s. It is a waste of time and money for top students to make up lessons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, &quot;stupid students&quot; do not need to make up lessons. The diversity of this person and society must be recognized. Just as not everyone is suitable for scientific research, many children are not suitable for learning book knowledge and Test taking. Of course, this does not mean that they are really stupid, but it means that learning book knowledge is too difficult for them. There is not much difference between making up lessons and not making up lessons, so there is no need to spend money and time on it. . Those who are at the middle level and have the motivation to make progress will see results after just a little supplement. This group of students needs supplementary lessons the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, it is to improve grades, and on the other hand, it is to let children know that grades can be improved by working hard, and work can be done well by working hard. In my opinion, the learning process is also a process of building self-confidence and responsibility. Improving grades is important, and self-training and self-growth during the learning process are also important, or even more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我与白塔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257994]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/bs57e1x4IQJ6KraNGzDhWuiQBUA9SVAGzsL5VDqO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/bs57e1x4IQJ6KraNGzDhWuiQBUA9SVAG zsL5VDqO. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children feeling the winter snow under the white tower&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaaaaa;&quot;>;Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a person from a small town in the northeastern border, I have a close relationship with the White Tower in Beijing What&#39;s the fate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who has lived in Beijing for a long time has his or her own feelings and memories about this city, and more or less longing for it. That year, when the lease of my studio in Wangjing came to an end, I tried to find a house in the alleys of the old city, thinking that this would be closer to the nobility and wealth of the city and would be conducive to new development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NyevBw1waDLo7t2WNXaMdLMLJsSEndluWYr07jat.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NyevBw1waDLo7t2WNXaMdLMLJsSEndluWYr07jat.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Vendors chatting at the door of the Gongmenkou wet market&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correct In the middle of summer, I wear NB993 running shoes that are unchanging in all seasons. Because of Steve Jobs, this pair of shoes has a symbolic meaning for me that goes beyond practicality. I bought three pairs in one go and rotate them around. With the blessing of shoes, the scorching sun and showers are no longer unbearable, and the road to dreaming in a foreign land becomes easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I first went to Houhai and Huguo Temple, then searched Dongzhimen and Dongsi. After several twists and turns, I came to Baita Temple and finally found a suitable house. The agent and the landlord have agreed on the price, and I want to go back and think about it before making a decision. As soon as I turned around and hadn&#39;t gone far, the landlord suddenly came out and stopped me, saying that the old man at home wanted to chat again. It turns out that my uncle accidentally heard me talk about his hometown, where he was sent to work as a teacher when he was young. The uncle&#39;s expression reflected the special meaning of that experience to him. I saw in his eyes a trace of sadness at meeting an old friend in a foreign land. The old man took me and asked me in detail about the current situation in my hometown, big and small, and took the trouble. Because of this unexpected fate, the house was settled quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, the place where a person first starts will give life a background and determine certain choices in life. Some passes cannot be forcibly reversed by manpower alone, and trying to do so is mostly in vain; but if you let nature take its course and take things as they come, you can see the bright future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, my fate with the White Tower began, and the White Tower in my heart gradually became clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/jEn7Z0GY4C23HpNmcwD6YDqlDfw3Kaj5egrhQCDq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/jEn7Z0GY4C23HpNmcwD6YDqlDfw3Kaj5egrhQCDq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gongmenkou Hutong under renovation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times , I walked around the tower alone. I try to slow down and move forward with a calm and quiet mentality. It seems that it is easier to meet happiness this way. However, as time goes by, wrinkles creep up to the corners of the eyes, and white hair grows on the head. The happiness in the longing for is like a bird perching on the treetops. It seems to be close at hand, but it spreads its wings and slips away. Between movement and stillness, the tall and pure white tower always stared at me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The studio is on the second floor, and the windows face the White Tower. When the sun rises, it covers the window sill with gold; when the sun sets low, it casts the shadow of leaves on the screen window. There is a statue of Venus with a broken arm in the house. According to the uncle, it was left by a tenant painter from the Academy of Arts and Crafts. The statue and the white tower often appear in the same picture, with light and shadow flowing between them, chanting the changes of the four seasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6NdsISkOezbywy1NFtuk6TR9j6tOavRRu9rtt8LO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6NdsISkOezbywy1NFtuk6TR9j6tOavRRu9rtt8LO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Golden Dome of the White Tower under the winter sunset&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5dSDq00pAPdQZpEhhpiok1M8MxLyyb0yKUCvEC5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5dSDq00pAPdQZpEhhpiok1M8MxLyyb0yKUCvEC5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pigeons flying around the tower&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is windy in spring. When the wind blows, the alley is no longer filled with yellow sand and dust, but the gentle airflow makes pedestrians hurry. Spring brings hope, and people want to do something quickly, maybe they can seize a chance and fly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is rainy in summer. Unlike the continuous drizzle in the south, even in the rainy season here, the rain is cheerful and warm, and stops in a flash. Sometimes while walking, a sudden rain shower occurs. The huge raindrops make the leaves rustle and the roof tiles crackle. Pedestrians start running in panic, looking for shelter from the rain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Autumn is so nice. Only in autumn does her beauty fully show here. Every alley, every doorway, balcony, and both sides of the door are filled with various flowers and plants, embellishing a colorful picture against the blue sky. Perhaps only Mr. Lao She&#39;s &quot;Autumn in Peiping&quot; can fully explain that scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Winter is another scene. A heavy snowfall seems to bring time back a hundred years ago. It is difficult to distinguish north, south, east and west in the vast whiteness, but you can vaguely see the Beiping where masters gather. People stayed behind closed doors, but I ran into the wind and snow to capture this time-traveled black and white world with my camera. After the snow, the ice subsided, Lu Xun’s home turned back into his memorial hall, and I returned to reality, under the White Tower in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/T3moYVA9HC1x8ARXk9h7C6nvofjUhGIKDPF7LT9Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/T3moYVA9HC1x8ARXk9h7C6nvofjUhGIKDPF7LT9Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Residences shaded by vines and green plants&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/14Fkgiv03oPupBxYvfvRmNzScD7CZPGKsD0zSdW9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/14Fkgiv03oPupBxYvfvRmNzScD7CZPGKsD0zSdW9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;The dog taking a nap in summer&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still remember the Xuji Shaobing Shop in Anping Alley. Big, every morning the aroma of burning pasta wafts out, and people come here to queue up to wait for the sesame seed cakes to be baked. The small tables and chairs at the door are always full of diners, and the crowd is buzzing. The crispy sesame seed cakes paired with a bowl of fragrant bean soup is a delicious treat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Master Bao at the entrance of the palace is always crowded. The Xingyuan Restaurant opposite is a time-honored state-owned restaurant, and the food is quite affordable. Walking west along Fuchengmen Inner Street, you will find Xinchuan Cold Noodles near Fuchengmen Subway Station. In the summer, a big bowl of it, paired with a bottle of ice-cold Arctic Ocean, is so refreshing. There is also a shop selling salted duck eggs downstairs from the studio. The supply is rationed every day, and each one peeled out is full of red oil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MpHQqXlXcavItT0RBSUSyhmc4sTUy7jzEVt8E7er.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MpHQqXlXcavItT0RBSUSyhmc4sTUy7jzEVt8E7er.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Uncle drying birds under the warm winter sun&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/LdvXPQc344shLwXqCY1sMvQQRuQmYmGOwk3chv83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/LdvXPQc344shLwXqCY1sMvQQRuQmYmGOwk3chv83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On a summer night, people enjoy the cool air while playing with their mobile phones&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The alleys around Baita Temple The name is both vivid and interesting. The most impressive ones include Qianchaoshou Hutong, Houchaoshou Hutong, Dachaye Hutong, Xiaochaye Hutong, East Langxia Hutong, West Langxia Hutong, and Cuihua Street - but there is no pickled cabbage stewed vermicelli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FbCZeRXvpWtyF9fUfvj4qeSm0tiNpzQ9dzZAVyOZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FbCZeRXvpWtyF9fUfvj4qeSm0tiNpzQ9dzZAVyOZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Xun on the wicker chair and pedestrians passing by the memorial hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MFCr0OuOwUR9HrBOKgBUVTEeKW7rWwX56uceOZtn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MFCr0OuOwUR9HrBOKgBUVTEeKW7rWwX56uceOZtn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;Barber shop in dimly lit place&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the night under the White Tower was not It is lively, without the frenzy and passion of small bars in Houhai Hutong, but with the gentle blooming of street fireworks in the dark night. My restless heart during the day gradually calmed down as the night fell. I don&#39;t know why I feel a little sad at this time, maybe because I feel a little unwilling to see another day pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/gYOquSrzn0vxzsOINRIPLeN3C02i0PESSM7JDaFn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/gYOquSrzn0vxzsOINRIPLeN3C02i0PESSM7JDaFn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Baita people who stick to the door god&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later slowly Discovered that everyone has his own white tower in his heart. Maybe I have never arrived at this tower, maybe I have never taken anyone to it. But it has always been there, standing majestically, like a god calling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5s88RDyn7jAfo7CYfy6mQdIOt2FLrHUVbxzhunJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5s88RDyn7jAfo7CYfy6mQdIOt2FLrHUVbxzhunJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Boy chasing bubbles&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/awM4nnKe7WF850Yn8ukCNK5J5I67EvrqZTjc6OEd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/awM4nnKe7WF850Yn8ukCNK5J5I67EvrqZTjc6OEd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252399&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The old man cleaning up the snow under the White Pagoda&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I left the White Pagoda Temple before the child was born. However, the white tower in my heart has never been far away. I have always kept in touch with my uncle, and I often go back to visit him. In between coming and going, I have walked around the tower again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the way, Baita Temple has another name - Miaoying Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被份子钱暴击后，这年头结婚连喜糖也卷麻了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258052]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;What is it like to have 7 friends get married during the 8-day National Day holiday? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone on Weibo complained about the weddings that were held during the National Day, which instantly sparked a heated discussion on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, when the guests were bombarded with &quot;red bombs&quot; such as molecular money, the bride and groom were also entangled in the wedding candies and cakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, #carefully selected wedding candies are said to be bad# has become a hot search topic, and the topic of how to prepare wedding candies has aroused heated discussions. Some netizens carefully prepared their favorite snacks, such as kisses, konjac jelly, etc. as wedding candies, but were criticized as being too bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know when it started, but the &quot;happy&quot; wedding candy headed towards the involution track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, China&#39;s wedding candy market is in close conflict with each other and the two factions are divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One group is companies focusing on the wedding candy field, such as Aidoduo, etc.; the other group is traditional candy companies, such as Dove, Hsu Fuji, etc. Companies focusing on wedding candy focus on customization and packaging, while traditional candy companies focus on nationality and cost-effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the weddings of grandparents in the past, which were mainly fruit candies and milk candies with simple packaging, high-end wedding candies are now the choice of contemporary couples. For example, they will choose Godiva chocolate for 5 yuan a piece. Demonstrate taste - Today, customization, personalization and high-end have become the keywords of wedding candy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by wedding candies, happy shops have also developed rapidly in recent years. Currently, there are more than 22,000 happy shops across the country. The happy shop culture is prevalent in the south, accounting for 60% of the country&#39;s total, while in the north, happy candy is customary. In terms of purchasing from candy wholesale markets, hypermarkets, and online, Xipu still needs to be developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the crowds of weddings are the &quot;red bombs&quot; that have been bombing one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that the average income per person in Shanghai, Zhejiang and other places is 1,000 yuan, while the average income per person in Guangdong, which has always been just about getting lucky, is only 100 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One side is spending thousands of gold on gifts, and the other side is spending tens of thousands of dollars on a wedding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, nearly 90% of Chinese couples will spend more than 50,000 yuan on their wedding, and 0.4% of couples will even spend more than 500,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, personalized weddings, such as &quot;material sorrow&quot; weddings and carbon-neutral weddings, have also become new choices for young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk to you about the sweet worries of weddings about wedding candies and share money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/831b80df1d8aa019cd150056d5435eb1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/831b80df1d8aa019cd150056d5435eb1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/95c2f4acac0bd5d935b7e41ee70742e4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/95c2f4acac0bd5d935b7e41ee70742e4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/1f28cfb09adb79f1b577f5f6dbc2fe7e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/1f28cfb09adb79f1b577f5f6dbc2fe7e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/6899c96a2a3cc79f52ab82a571ba38d0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/6899c96a2a3cc79f52ab82a571ba38d0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252953&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/f9209ae4d2f9444cf823fcddca744dce.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/f9209ae4d2f9444cf823fcddca744dce.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252954&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/a841ff40895bd7c611637dac01109292.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/a841ff40895bd7c611637dac01109292.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/d58a01e5fbb6bb084b06423bea502775.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/d58a01e5fbb6bb084b06423bea502775.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:55:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“成年人的奶嘴儿”：人人索要的“情绪价值”究竟是个啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258008]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 13:09:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Li Jiaqi tells you to work hard&quot; incident that made a lot of noise some time ago has provided netizens with entertainment and conversation topics after dinner. In addition, it also triggered the topic: In my country, the world&#39;s largest manufacturing country, the largest informatization country in globalization, and the world&#39;s largest online retail country, why does there still exist such a gap between producers and sellers? The &quot;cyber peddler&quot; class is both ancient and modern, and occupies a huge share and decisive influence in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explanation I put forward in the previous article is: just like the eloquent salesmen in the old society, in the process of walking around the streets, they can make potential customers buy or not. Feeling relaxed. In modern society, &quot;cyber salesmen&quot; like Li Jiaqi provide their fans with more than just eyebrow pencils, powders and lipsticks, but also emotional value, which is even more important than the actual goods. (Create a link: &quot;Before the &quot;best friends&quot; said bad things to each other: How can &quot;cyber peddlers&quot; like Li Jiaqi succeed against the trend?&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, after always using &quot;all girls&quot; as the opening of the live broadcast, use The &quot;bestie&quot; who held consumers in the palm of his hand and coaxed them into the clouds with his &quot;bestie voice&quot; suddenly broke out in his fatigue. When he began to &quot;struggle to educate&quot; consumers, he himself was &quot;cut off&quot; by the emotional value of the consumer. It is also an expected result that they are pushed into the whirlpool of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that &quot;emotional value&quot; is not only the key element for Li Jiaqi from the clouds of the business empire to the center of the whirlpool of public opinion, but also the root of the survival of the &quot;cyber peddler&quot; profession in modern society. In fact, this concept has already surpassed the live broadcast e-commerce industry and has spread in all fields of this society. We should talk about &quot;emotional value&quot; in the workplace, &quot;emotional value&quot; in love, and even in family life. Let’s talk about “emotional value”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is this &quot;emotional value&quot; that everyone wants and is more important than the commodity itself in commodity trading activities? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spiritual pacifier of the adult world&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Contrary to the intuitive impression of most people, emotional value (Emotional Value), a term that looks very much like a psychological term, is actually a complete term. The marketing concept itself refers to the difference between emotional benefits and emotional costs in the marketing process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it simply, in a shopping trip, regardless of whether the transaction is finally concluded, as long as the positive emotional experience provided by the seller to the consumer is greater than the negative experience, the consumer will obtain positive emotional value. This is a right Favorable results for the seller. On the contrary, if consumers gain negative emotional value, it will be an unfavorable result for the seller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sales industry, emotional value theory is often used to design and optimize sales processes, guide sales staff training, provide customers with a better consumption experience, and convert and fix potential customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as mentioned above, in today&#39;s society, both the concept of &quot;emotional value&quot; and the theory of emotional value itself have been greatly abused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In almost all fields of social and interpersonal communication, people’s demand for “emotional value” is becoming more and more urgent and intense. On a popular social APP, you can see everywhere that the emotional value requested is not as good as expected. Various complaints are raised: the boss cannot provide emotional value, colleagues cannot provide emotional value, love/marriage partners cannot provide emotional value, parents cannot provide emotional value, and even strangers who occasionally meet cannot provide emotional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, &quot;emotional value&quot; has changed from a marketing concept to an ability, an ability to use language to make people feel &quot;comfortable&quot;. Regardless of whether this language is the result of rational thinking, or whether its rhetoric is consistent with objective facts, as long as it can make people feel &quot;comfortable&quot;, it has the ability to &quot;provide emotional value.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People who are accustomed to asking for &quot;emotional value&quot; from others in life have a common characteristic, which is that regardless of whether they have this ability, they must require the other party to have this ability. While refusing to give in in public life, he complains that others cannot provide enough emotional value. This kind of mentality that is both strong and fragile, and wants to take but is unwilling to give, has formed one flammable and explosive tinderbox after another in social and public life, which can explode anytime and anywhere the moment they lose their pacifier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is an obvious fact that in modern society, while information technology and communication technology connect individuals more and more closely, the continuous disintegration of communities also makes individuals become more and more independent. Alone, people end up becoming what Hannah Arendt called &quot;atomized individuals&quot; - they may be very closely packed but at the same time isolated from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of &quot;noisy loneliness&quot; makes atomized individuals usually place material enjoyment in a very high position in order to alleviate and comfort the spiritual loneliness. Correspondingly, this kind of individual is psychologically lonely. Vulnerability also drives them to endlessly ask for the so-called &quot;emotional value&quot; from the outside world. Therefore, the overwhelming emotional value in modern society has long since changed from a marketing concept to a spiritual pacifier in the adult world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A paradise of clever lies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Just like in the business empire built by &quot;Cyber ​​Merchant&quot; with &quot;family members&quot; and &quot;queens&quot;, the emotional value is more important than the product itself. The &quot;emotional value&quot; that pervades other areas of society also exceeds reason, logic and objective facts themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the discussion of public affairs, the rhetoric of &quot;putting aside the facts, isn&#39;t XXX wrong?&quot; that can be seen everywhere is an excellent example of this kind of mentality, completely regardless of objective facts. Regardless of whether there is a problem with your own thinking logic (or no logic at all), as long as the other party makes you feel subjectively uncomfortable, it means that you have not provided &quot;emotional value&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an individual regards &quot;emotional value&quot; as the highest goal of social life, excessive and excessive emotional pursuit will inevitably consume and destroy their ability to think and express based on reason and logic. . The so-called &quot;thinking&quot; has become an animal conditioned reflex of &quot;if there is no pacifier, I will make a fuss&quot;. The so-called &quot;expressions&quot; are all the catharsis of accumulated emotions, and people cannot have any meaningful discussions, because all fact-based discussions will deviate from their original track and end in a hysterical mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A society full of such individuals must be a kindergarten composed of &quot;children aged 6 years and 256 months&quot; where &quot;everyone is fragile and needs to be coaxed&quot;, and it will naturally become a place where all kinds of clever words and tricks are Liars are at home in this paradise of lies. For some people, the sweet-talking online opposite sex in the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; can obviously provide higher &quot;emotional value&quot; than the &quot;low emotional intelligence&quot; partner in reality. For the elderly, the health product sellers who hang around them every day and talk about &quot;Mom and Dad&quot; obviously provide more &quot;emotional value&quot; than their own children who come back once a month and become impatient with a few words. Ultimately, a society where &quot;there is always someone to trick you&quot; will inevitably become a society where &quot;there is always a liar that suits you&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ability to regulate one&#39;s own emotions is the basic ability of adults living in modern society. It is normal for people&#39;s emotions to fluctuate under the influence of others, but if an adult&#39;s emotions are completely provided and controlled by others , then he can only be an adult in the physiological sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of social modernization is irreversible. Problems such as individual atomization, mental loneliness and vulnerability, and psychological immaturity that arise in the process of social modernization cannot be solved by reconstructing the pre-modern society where &quot;chickens and dogs hear each other&quot; solve. The ultimate solution to the problems caused by modernization is modernization itself. From the perspective of &quot;emotional value&quot;, we see a &quot;crisis of modernity&quot; that needs to be faced squarely and urgently resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“陪拍”爆红，出租自己的工具人生意也火了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257709]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>