<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[把家庭财产、公司财产洗为个人财产？拆解三种洗钱类型]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258204]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 23:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Beijing TV station&#39;s &quot;Rule of Law in Progress&quot; column reported such a case, from free to high fees, over the New Year Ms. Chen, who was in her sixties, couldn&#39;t help being &quot;fooled&quot; again and again in a medical beauty institution in Haidian District, Beijing. She made 370 transfers in just 10 months, spending a total of 5.44 million yuan on beauty care, and even some The consumption in a single day reached 790,000 yuan, which consumed all the family’s savings and the life-saving money of my wife and children. The news triggered heated discussions, with some netizens asking, &quot;Is such an abnormal move suspected of transferring family assets?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the report, on the one hand, the medical beauty institution first claimed that it was free, and then gradually Ms. Chen introduced a fee-based item, and the sales consultant even said that he could &quot;help advance payment&quot; of part of the expenses and was unable to provide relevant medical records. This was indeed a violation of regulations. However, on the other hand, Ms. Chen knew that her husband was suffering from cancer, so she actually transferred the medical expenses and the entire family&#39;s expenses. He invested all his savings into it, but his behavior is also strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The money at home cannot be used by either spouse as they wish. In 2022, the People&#39;s Court of Fangshan District, Beijing heard a divorce case. My wife loves beauty and other high-end purchases, and has squandered all the family savings of 600,000 yuan. After trial, the court held that the 600,000 yuan deposit involved in the case was the husband and wife&#39;s business income and was the joint property of the husband and wife. Both spouses have equal rights to dispose of common property, but when exercising the right to dispose of common property, one spouse should adhere to the principles of moderation, rationality and prudence, use it reasonably and standardizedly, and must not be squandered or damage the property rights of the spouse. In this case, the court protected the part where the wife exercised her right of reasonable disposal. The part where excessive consumption was done without the consent of the spouse, was not for the purpose of daily household expenses, and was squandering, which infringed upon the property rights of the spouse. In the end, the court ruled that the woman should pay her ex-husband 200,000 yuan in compensation for her deposit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this reasoning, Ms. Chen spent more than 5 million yuan in family savings and her husband’s medical expenses on “exorbitantly expensive beauty treatments”, which is also suspected of harming her husband’s property rights. It is worth noting that the above report also mentioned a detail, &quot;The medical beauty institution gave a consumption details. Among them, there are many discrepancies between the total consumption amount, consumption records and the transfer details transferred by the bank.&quot; The actual expenditure It is inconsistent with the accounts. Are the relevant funds used for beauty expenses, or are they transferring family assets in the name of beauty? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As relevant departments intensify their publicity on &quot;anti-money laundering&quot;, the public has become aware of its concept. Money laundering is essentially the act of disguising, concealing, and transforming illegal assets or other assets that do not belong to individuals in various ways to make them legal in form. It can be roughly divided into three types: laundering family assets into personal assets, Criminal gangs or corrupt officials use their money to launder and turn company assets into their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above-mentioned &quot;sky-high price beauty&quot; case, the onlookers lamented the greed and foolishness of the person involved in &quot;spending thousands of dollars for beauty&quot;. Perhaps some people&#39;s abnormal behavior is just in response to the old saying &quot;Others laugh at me for being crazy, but I laugh at others because they can&#39;t see through it.&quot; In the name of large consumption, they convert family property into personal property. Once the subsequent marriage relationship changes, , and preparations are made for property cutting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many ways to &quot;launder&quot; family assets into personal assets. For example, use the joint funds of the couple to buy valuable jewelry and put it in their own names; regularly give a large amount of &quot;red envelopes&quot; to their parents, and then ask their parents to transfer the money into their own accounts; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whitewashing of funds with unknown future is common among corrupt officials, criminal gangs, etc. Corrupt officials clean up their corruption gains by investing in companies, purchasing art, and even regularly giving their children huge amounts of living expenses. Public officials use overseas companies to inflate the import price when importing equipment and raw materials, then receive huge kickbacks from them, and then keep the illegal gains abroad. This not only makes public funds their own, but also realizes the transfer of assets overseas. . Public officials can also use &quot;white gloves&quot; to set up shell companies to invest overseas, that is, first set up shell companies abroad, then use their powers to provide various conveniences, and finally remit domestic income abroad in the form of overseas investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Criminal gangs launder illegal gains into legitimate gains through investments in film and television dramas, virtual currency transactions, etc. There are criminal gangs that are linked to casinos, convert cash into tokens in casinos, and then deliver the tokens directly to the beneficiaries of the money laundering. Then he will exchange the tokens back into cash (usually requiring a handling fee of about 5%), and he can claim to have won the money by gambling in the casino. This avoids directly tracing the beneficiary of money laundering through the serial number on the banknote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the above two methods of money laundering, rich people complete the transfer of company assets to personal assets by purchasing overseas bonds issued by their own companies abroad and then using their authority to pay them first. For example, a company may be in debt due to poor business operations and face bankruptcy. As the actual controller of the company, the rich people let the company issue US dollar bonds with annual interest rates as high as ten percent or even higher, and then the rich people subscribed in large quantities. In this way, the rich man, as the actual controller of the company, theoretically only has limited liability within the scope of equity. It is the company&#39;s business to pay off its debts. In this way, through &quot;due process&quot;, the company was hollowed out, Jin Chan escaped from the shell, converted the company&#39;s assets into personal assets, and then took his family and children to enjoy the rest of his life abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子持刀列车上杀人，广铁集团通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258276]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After review by judicial authorities, it was found that on the evening of May 4, passenger He used a black folding knife (blade) About 10.5 cm long) was hidden behind a belt buckle. At Hengshan Station, he avoided the security check and entered the station, boarded the K435 train, and suddenly committed a murder with a knife at 21:50. He was later arrested for intentional homicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, Guangzhou Railway Group, based on the review conclusions of the judicial organs and relevant regulations, punished Hengshan Station Director Hong, Deputy Station Director Qin, and security inspectors for failing to perform their duties due to poor performance of their duties. Kuang Mou and other relevant responsible persons were investigated for responsibility such as dismissal and removal from office. At the same time, all units are mobilized to carry out case education, learn lessons deeply, comprehensively strengthen the training and management of security personnel, continuously strengthen security inspections at stations, and make every effort to prevent similar incidents from happening and ensure the safety of passengers&#39; lives and property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列突遭强袭：当地华人“感觉一天打的炮弹比以往一整年都多”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258269]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 22:51:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/Pj6tPDxRrzd6saqBbkQYslHO50FGTzFGere6eAyA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Pj6tPDxRrzd6saqBbkQYslHO50FGTz FGere6eAyA. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From the apartment window, Zhang Feng could clearly see the white trajectory of the artillery shells streaking through the air. . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, 2023, local time, dense rockets suddenly pierced Israel Air defense alerts were sounded in the southern and central parts of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Israeli city of Rehovot, after hearing the siren, Chinese chef Zhang Feng (pseudonym) squeezed into the small bullet shelter at the stairs of the apartment with five Chinese colleagues and local neighbors. From the apartment windows, the white trails of shells streaking through the air could be clearly seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The shelling lasted from 6 o’clock to 9 o’clock. It felt like the amount of shells fired in one day was more than in the previous year.” Zhang Feng has been in Israel for more than two years and has experienced many attacks, but “it feels like Not as powerful as this time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces declared on the 7th that the attack was carried out by the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement (Hamas) and that the country &quot;has entered a state of war.&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said that the Israeli military&#39;s response must make Hamas &quot;pay a huge price.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2007, Israel has imposed a strict land, sea and air blockade on the Hamas-controlled Gaza Strip, strictly prohibiting the import of military weapons. Hamas, on the other hand, has secretly broken through numerous blockades and frequently attacked Israel through small-scale attacks, attracting international attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She Gangzheng, director of the Overseas Security Research Center at Tsinghua University, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that although Palestinian-Israeli conflicts have occurred from time to time in recent years, large-scale attacks that attack the Israeli mainland and cause triple-digit deaths are rare. It broke the previous relatively stable and balanced situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the Israeli side is likely to take this as an opportunity to launch large-scale retaliation against Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“This time is different from before”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Feng is from Hengyang, Hunan, and currently works as a chef in an Asian restaurant in Rehovot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhang Feng first came to work here two years ago, he received a kind reminder from the restaurant manager - &quot;When the alarm sounds, run to the air-raid shelter immediately, and put down the pot when cooking.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhang Feng, many houses in Israel are equipped with bulletproof rooms or underground air-raid shelters to deal with emergencies. In April 2021, Zhang Feng encountered the first air defense alert. At that time, he was resting alone in the dormitory and was about to run outside in panic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he ran to the stairwell, a local man in his thirties caught him. &quot;He spoke English, which I couldn&#39;t understand. Then he pulled me into the bulletproof room.&quot; Zhang Feng sighed, &quot;He has indeed been trained.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a long-term conflict situation, The Israeli people responded to emergencies &quot;in an orderly manner&quot;. Even so, the attack on October 7 took many people by surprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I started hearing the sound of artillery shells being fired around 6 a.m. on the 7th, and it lasted for several hours.” Zhang Feng said, “This time the sound was particularly dense. It was like boom, boom, boom. The sound was different. It was like setting off firecrackers during the New Year, dozens of them were fired at once.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack, the three-story apartment building where he and his colleagues lived was &quot;almost empty,&quot; and many Local people drove their families to the air raid shelters for safety. Compared with bullet shelters in apartments, air raid shelters are stronger and safer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack on the morning of the 7th, Zhang Feng and his colleagues were still discussing how to go to work in the restaurant. Looking out the window, the usually crowded lanes are becoming deserted. However, they soon received a holiday notice from the restaurant headquarters, &quot;No need to go to work, no need to go out.&quot; In order to explain the situation clearly, the headquarters specially arranged a translator who knew Chinese to explain it word for word during the voice call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This time is really amazing, different from before.&quot; Zhang Feng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;big battle&quot; Zhang Feng felt was a &quot;rare&quot; moment experienced by this region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli military claimed that on the morning of the 7th, Hamas fired about 2,200 rockets from the Gaza Strip to attack Israel, and armed gunmen also crossed the border and launched ground attacks in southern Israel. For a time, air defense sirens continued to sound in the southern and central areas of Tel Aviv, the former capital of Israel, and explosions were heard over multiple Israeli towns close to the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the Israel Defense Forces issued a statement declaring a state of war and recruiting tens of thousands of reservists to launch attacks on multiple Hamas targets in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sudden escalation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict shocked the world. On the 7th, many Western countries, led by the United States, condemned Hamas for launching a &quot;terrorist attack&quot; on Israel, while many Arab countries called for an immediate ceasefire between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, when answering a reporter’s question on the escalation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated that China is deeply concerned about the current intensification of tensions and violence between Palestine and Israel, and calls on all parties concerned to remain calm and restrained. , cease fire immediately to protect civilians and prevent the situation from deteriorating further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/GTkhYNgPyEqsEAmhI6hxnZzeInzbQ1goeFtlhDLa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;533&quot; height= &quot;877&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/GTkhYNgPyEqsEAmhI6hxnZzeInzbQ1goeFtlhDLa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the explosion, the ground was in a mess. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Israel was unprepared”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After a day of fighting between Palestine and Israel, the number of casualties has exceeded 3,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Palestinian health department on the 7th, the Israeli air strikes on the Gaza Strip have killed 232 local people and injured about 1,700 people. According to a statement from the Israeli Ministry of Defense on the evening of the 7th, various attacks that day killed more than 200 people and injured more than 1,000 people in Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this raid, Israel, known for its intelligence and military strength, acted passively, triggering a lot of speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is difficult to describe how unprecedented today’s situation is.” The BBC reported on October 7 that this may be Israel’s “most serious intelligence failure” since the 1973 Yom Kippur War. It has the most powerful intelligence agency in the Middle East, but there was no early warning of the attack that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the US &quot;Capitol Hill&quot; news on October 7, former US Secretary of Defense Mark Esper bluntly stated in an interview with US media that Hamas&#39;s attack was &quot;surprising and made Israel &quot;There was no preparedness on the part of the Israeli side,&quot; he said, adding that this was an intelligence error on the part of Israel. He also believes that Israel’s mistakes will trigger chain reactions in many aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, in the first round of attacks by Hamas, Israel has been quite &quot;slow&quot; in its response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to rocket attacks, videos released by Hamas showed that Hamas armed personnel were heavily armed and used homemade simple gliders to infiltrate into Israel. Videos and pictures that appeared on social media showed Hamas militants also entering Israeli-controlled areas in pickup trucks and motorcycles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 7, local time, the Qassam Brigades, an armed faction affiliated with Hamas, issued a statement saying that dozens of Israeli officers and soldiers were captured during military operations that day. The men are currently being housed in a &quot;safe location.&quot; This news was also confirmed by the Times of Israel report. The media quoted Israeli military sources as saying that &quot;soldiers and civilians were indeed captured by Hamas and kidnapped to the Gaza Strip.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Israel&#39;s &quot;Jewish Chronicle&quot;, photos released by Hamas show that its armed men captured Israeli Major General Nimrod Aloni and many other Israeli soldiers. It is reported that Aloni served as the commander of the Israeli Army&#39;s &quot;Gaza Division&quot; and the commander of the &quot;Depth&quot; force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She Gangzheng believes that Israel has been in a state of guarding against surprise attacks for a long time, and the relative stability in recent years can easily lead to laziness and paralysis. This sudden large-scale attack by Hamas caught Israel by surprise. In addition, Israel has fallen into political chaos in recent years and has long lacked leading power. The judicial reform led by the Netanyahu government has further paralyzed the original political consensus, and all parties are busy fighting among themselves. This is also one of the factors behind Israel’s slow intelligence and military response this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 7th local time, the Israeli Political and Security Cabinet held a meeting. Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu stated in a statement that Israel’s goal is to “eliminate Hamas’ threat to and harm to Israel for many years to come. the capabilities and desires of citizens”. He also added, &quot;The decisions taken by the cabinet include stopping the supply of electricity, fuel and commodities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We have started offensive mode and will continue without reservation and without breath until the goal is achieved .&quot; Netanyahu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;16 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;open-air prison&quot; under blockade&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;According to CNN, Hamas military commander Mohammed Dave said on October 7 that the operation was in response to Israel’s “attacks on women, the desecration of the Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem, and the The ongoing siege of Gaza.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The so-called &#39;reasons for action&#39; put forward by Hamas, although relevant incidents did occur, are more of a rhetoric to defend the legitimacy of its actions. However, Israel&#39;s blockade and siege of Gaza This has been one of the deep-seated conflicts between Hamas and the Israeli authorities for a long time,&quot; She Gangzheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the unilateral withdrawal of Israeli troops in 2005, Gaza has become the Palestinian sphere of influence. Since 2007, Israel has regarded Hamas, which controls the area, as a major security threat, and has begun to implement a comprehensive sea, land and air blockade of the Gaza Strip, with strict restrictions on the entry and exit of goods and personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, incoming and outgoing goods are subject to security inspections, personnel need to hold a permit to enter and exit, and fishing areas accurate to kilometers are set up in coastal areas. In order to prevent the construction of military facilities, Israel once banned any steel bars, cement and other materials from entering Gaza. It was not until 2010 that Israel narrowed the list of prohibited items to &quot;weapons and materials for military use.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the implementation of the blockade, Israel has claimed that it will not let Hamas obtain any weapons. But judging from the results, despite spending a lot of manpower and material resources, Hamas still has various channels to import weapons .&quot; She Gangzheng believes that since Israel&#39;s unilateral withdrawal in 2005, the Gaza area has been basically blocked by Israel, showing a stable and continuous state. On the one hand, Israel provides corresponding support to the Gaza Strip, such as electricity supply, allowing some Palestinians to enter the country to work, and releasing humanitarian relief supplies. On the other hand, millions of Palestinians are confined to this small area, where people&#39;s lives are restricted and often subject to humanitarian criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, the current population of the Gaza Strip exceeds 2 million, which is approximately one-fifth of Israel’s total population, but the area is less than one percent of Israel’s land. The Gaza Strip is small and densely populated. The blockade has hindered the development of the Gaza region. People&#39;s daily life, health system, and infrastructure have gradually deteriorated. A large number of residents rely on relief from international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s comprehensive blockade, the Gaza Strip has become an isolated &quot;enclave.&quot; Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas once described the Gaza Strip as a giant &quot;prison.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 7, local time, Israeli Energy Minister Katz announced that in response to the conflict, he had signed an order requiring the Israeli Electric Power Company to cut off power supply to the Gaza Strip. It is understood that about two-thirds of the electricity in the Gaza Strip depends on Israeli supply. Israel&#39;s announcement of &quot;cutting off supply&quot; is likely to further exacerbate the energy dilemma in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Fan Hongda from the Institute of Middle East Studies at Shanghai International Studies University believes that as long as the Palestinian issue cannot be properly resolved and as long as Israel&#39;s current position on this issue does not change, conflict between the two sides will be inevitable. Hamas may launch similar operations at any time it sees fit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Hongda also pointed out that this conflict is significantly different from the past conflicts. The Gaza armed forces have entered Israel and captured some Israeli hostages, including soldiers, which will bring consequences to the Israeli people. A real sense of fear. Next, Israel will intensify its attacks on the Gaza armed forces, and it will be a heavier blow than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is foreseeable that the situation of the people in the Gaza Strip will be even more difficult in the future.&quot; Fan Hongda said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突升级 当地华人亲历“一波一波地炸”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258273]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 23:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[走不一样的路，刘清漪成为了亚运冠军]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258265]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/z1fLaqhsT7kZRweauhtytjsffUhiVXSTIKZ8LQv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;616&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/z1fLaqhsT7kZRweauhtytjsffUhiVXSTIK Z8LQv2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Liu Qingyi competed&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, the final day of the first break dance event of the Asian Games, after several rounds of dance battles between contestants , the Chinese national breakdancing team won two &quot;first&quot; medals: Qi Xiangyu won the third place in the men&#39;s category, the first medal in the breakdancing event in the history of the Asian Games; Henan girl Liu Qingyi won the championship in the women&#39;s category, the first women&#39;s breakdancing event in the history of the Asian Games gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four national team members who participated this time all performed very well. Qi Xiangyu and Shang Xiaoyu won the first and fourth place respectively in the individual qualifying competition. Unfortunately, Shang Xiaoyu stopped in the top eight. Liu Qingyi and Zeng Yingying successfully advanced to the semi-finals. Zeng Yingying lost to Japanese player Ayumi Fukushima (2023 World Breakdancing Championship Champion) in the bronze medal match and finished fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through this gold medal, Liu Qingyi qualified to participate in the break dance event of the Paris Olympics. At the post-match press conference, she said she was very happy, &quot;Thanks to my coaching team and my motherland for giving me this opportunity, and to myself for persevering.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the first batch of national teams such as Liu Qingyi and Qi Xiangyu For the team members, they have witnessed the transformation of break dancing from folk subculture to the highest sporting event. Their original intention of practicing break dancing may not be for honor, but their efforts will eventually be lived up to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/ppzyBbipfV265K5IZiwt4E3xCSbROxKcltM4nQSf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;649&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/ppzyBbipfV265K5IZiwt4E3xCSbROxKcltM4nQSf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Qi Xiangyu was in the bronze medal match. He defeated Japanese player Isshin Hisikawa 2-1 and won the third place &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From civilian to palace&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before being included in sporting events, breakdancing, a dance that originated in the New York neighborhoods of the 1970s, had always been popular among young people. It not only requires a certain degree of skill, but also integrates many action elements from Brazilian war dance, gymnastics and Chinese martial arts. It can also strongly express personal style and is highly musical and ornamental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The International Olympic Organizing Committee has taken a fancy to the influence of break dancing. The ratings on the first day of the official events of the Rio Olympics in 2016 dropped by about 28% compared with the London Olympics. The continued sluggish ratings forced the International Olympic Organizing Committee to turn its attention to the broad group of young people and pay attention to their popular preferences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 7, 2020, the Executive Committee of the International Olympic Committee held a meeting and agreed to add four major events including breakdancing, skateboarding, surfing, and rock climbing to the 2024 Paris Olympics. The breakdancing event falls under the &quot; sport dancing&quot;. Nine days later, the Olympic Council of Asia announced that breakdancing would become an official competition event at the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movements of break dancing can be divided into 4 parts, rock steps, leg movements, air freezes and overall movement. Compared with other hip-hop forms, the advantage of break dancing as a sporting event is that a large number of moves can be measured and scored using standards. However, according to the rules customized by the World DanceSport Federation, judges will not only pay attention to the skill and diversity of the movements, but also the integrity, musicality and even personality of the performance as the judging criteria. Movements that only have difficulty and technique will not receive high scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the four members of the Chinese team participating in the Asian Games, the only one with martial arts skills is 18-year-old Qi Xiangyu. He started practicing martial arts with his father when he was 5 and a half years old, and officially started hip-hop dancing at the age of 8 and a half. In terms of movements, Qi Xiangyu will repeatedly practice difficult movements, such as the Thomas Pivot - this movement requires supporting the ground with both hands, and using waist strength and inertia to drive the legs to swing. The 9-year-old Qi Xiangyu practices 200 times a day, which is a full exercise It takes half a year to become proficient. In terms of music, Qi Xiangyu will also understand it repeatedly. His father Qi Liying said, &quot;I can&#39;t teach him music. He will listen to a song until he understands the melody and emotion thoroughly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Qi Xiangyu first came into contact with break dancing, Chinese street dance was still a folk subculture. In 2018, two variety shows &quot;This!&quot; &quot;It&#39;s Street Dance&quot; and &quot;Hot Blood Street Dance Company&quot; brought street dance into the public eye. When break dancing entered the Olympics and Asia, the project moved from the folk to the palace and was recognized by mainstream culture. Learners, practitioners and training institutions sprung up like mushrooms after rain. The &quot;China Hip-Hop Industry Research and Development Report&quot; released in 2023 shows that there are currently nearly 3 million hip-hop practitioners nationwide, there are over 10,000 hip-hop training institutions, and more than 10 million people across the country choose to learn hip-hop every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese National Breakdancing Team was born through a selection competition on January 8, 2023. There are 4 male and female players each. The 17-year-old girl Liu Qingyi was selected with her rich, diverse and explosive dance. During her teenage years, dance practice was lonely and full of controversy. There were few female hip-hop dancers in China, and she was the only girl in the club. She was once considered by her friends and relatives as not doing her job properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Qingyi&#39;s attitude is &quot;less talk, more action&quot; and &quot;prove everything with strength.&quot; The gold medal in breakdancing&#39;s Asian Games debut is the best response to all the praise and criticism in the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BzTpgRXjGw6zyQaHnXD2JJgseJvx5hTRoM5P4LuW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BzTpgRXjGw6zyQaHnXD2JJgseJvx5hTRoM5P4LuW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Zeng Yingying competed in the bronze medal match of the women&#39;s break dance event. She lost to Japanese player Ayumi Fukushima 0-3 and finished fourth &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;The stage is my life&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have just finished competing in the World Championships and preparing for the Asian Games, which is a physical and psychological challenge for me.&quot; Recently, two major international competitions in break dancing Held in succession: From September 23 to 24, Liu Qingyi participated in the 2023 World Breakdancing Championships in Leuven, Belgium, and immediately started preparations for the Asian Games after returning to China. The intense preparation experience made her feel the limits of her body and mind, but she persevered. Liu Qingyi unfortunately stopped in the quarterfinals at the World Championships. Half a month later, she reached the top of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to break dancing, the young Liu Qingyi never thought of giving up, &quot;I am the kind of person who will &#39;die&#39; when encountering problems. Since it is my choice, You have to do it to the end and do it well, and don’t give up when you encounter some problems. This is a ‘slap in the face’.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, 10-year-old Liu Qingyi saw a street dance performance on the street, which was so cool Her movements gave her a visual shock and &quot;felt very handsome&quot;, so she joined the hip-hop club. Liu Qingyi showed athletic talent in her early days, and just two months later she won the runner-up in a hip-hop competition. At that time, not only were there few female dancers, but due to physical conditions, they were generally weaker in terms of strength and technical difficulty. Liu Qingyi prefers more energetic movements, such as Thomas pirouettes, 360-degree spins, etc., &quot;I want to be different from others, and I like to meet challenges.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wanting to be different&quot; also made Liu Qingyi decide From amateur to professional athlete. In 2019, in order to prepare for the break dance competition of the National Games two years later, Liu Qingyi was selected as an alternate member of the Henan hip-hop team. Should you join the provincial team and say goodbye to your ordinary school career, or should you give up break dancing and apply for college normally? Liu Qingyi made a choice: &quot;In the end, I still feel that taking a professional path in hip-hop dance is an opportunity for me. I think there are many paths to take in life, and not everyone is the same.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/XGTNiGD3bCG6uHZ9t7GFvPXMUYyF3ClJyW9CMoZ5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;697&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/XGTNiGD3bCG6uHZ9t7GFvPXMUYyF3ClJyW9CMoZ5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese player Shang Xiaoyu (right) and Kazakhstan&#39;s Dolet Analbekuly competed in the men&#39;s round-robin group match&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the Henan Provincial Team, Liu Qingyi received more professional training and grew rapidly through large-scale events. The first international competition she participated in was the 2021 World Championships in Paris. She failed to advance to the quarterfinals, but she refused to admit defeat. &quot;Go back and practice hard and come again.&quot; In 2022, she began to make a name for herself around the world: breaking into the World Games He reached the semi-finals, won the championship in Outbreak and World Battle, two top events, became the first Chinese player to win the international break dance competition championship, and won the runner-up in the World Championship that year. Liu Qingyi used her strength to show the world the level of Chinese break dancing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My stage is my life.” Liu Qingyi believes that the most attractive thing about break dancing is that when she dances, no one can restrain her, “I can do what I want. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Independence and individuality, perhaps this is the reason why emerging sports such as break dancing have become popular. They represent the pursuit of a new generation of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[回顾近13年国庆档票房成绩单，2023年仅为2019年六成丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258267]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“雅思组合”蝉联亚运金牌，剑指巴黎奥运欲补遗憾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258242]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy32xlLgoLs1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy3 2xlLgoLs1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong (right) Group photo at the award ceremony&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which event is the most stable for the Chinese badminton team? The list includes men’s singles before Lin Dan retired, Ge Fei/Gu Jun, Gao Ling/Huang Sui, Yang Wei/Zhang Jiewen, Du Jing/Yu Yang, Zhao Yunlei/Tian Qing, Chen Qingchen/Jia Yifan’s women’s doubles, Zhang Ning , the women&#39;s singles during the Xie Xingfang period...and the Chinese mixed doubles before the 2018 to 2021 Tokyo Olympics and the 2022 to 2023 World Championships: a pair of Chinese pairs once dominated the world and became the absolute king among many mixed doubles pairs. The Badminton World Federation ranking points have exceeded an unprecedented 110,000. They are Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong, known as the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2017, the Chinese badminton team made adjustments and split the top two mixed doubles players Zheng Siwei/Chen Qingchen and Lu Kai/Huang Yaqiong into a new combination of Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong. The two formed a team to compete in November 2017. In the first half of 2018, they broke into the top ten in the world and reached the top of the world in August of the same year. In the 2018 season, he won 9 mixed doubles championships, broke 4 world records in 5 months, and ranked first in the world with a huge points advantage. In 67 games in 2019, they were 59-8. In the past two years, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; has won the World Championships championship, successively won the All England Open, Asian Games championship, year-end finals and other championships. With an undefeated record, it helped the Chinese team win the International Badminton Team Championship Su Diman Cup, becoming the most dominant mixed doubles combination in the Tokyo Olympic cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (top) and Huang Yaqiong (bottom) defeated the Japanese combination Watanabe 2-0 Yongda and Higashino Arisa won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2022, Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong will be paired up After regrouping, they won 7 consecutive season championships within 5 months, including the third world championship. After that, they won three championships in the second half of the year, including the Badminton World Tour Finals, and were awarded the &quot;Best Group of 2022&quot; award by the Badminton World Federation. The two set a record of 38 consecutive unbeaten games, with a winning rate of 96%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the 2023 season, the old rivals of the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;, the Korean combination Seo Chenjae/Cai Yujing, have made rapid progress. When the two sides meet, it usually takes three games to determine the winner. In the last two matches (the 2023 World Badminton Championship final on August 27 and the 8-4 match at the China Badminton Open on September 8), they defeated the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; consecutively and became the latter&#39;s current extremely important opponent. In the badminton mixed doubles semi-finals of the 2023 Hangzhou Asian Games, the two pairs met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past month, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; encountered some controversy due to two consecutive losses. In the comments on the game video, you can often see fans questioning the two&#39;s decline in form. For the third time in two months, the result was particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (first from left) and Huang Yaqiong (second from right) and the runner-up Japanese combination Yuta Watanabe （左二）、东野有纱（右一）赛后相互握手致意&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在2021年到2022年，雅思组合曾经历过更严峻的“至暗时刻”。东京奥运会前后也是“雅思组合”共认的混双职业生涯以来最艰难的阶段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一年，郑思维24岁，黄雅琼27岁，对于运动员来说，身体正处于巅峰状态。东京奥运周期内，他们一骑绝尘，拿下了除奥运会外几乎所有混双比赛的冠军，气势昂扬，剑指武藏野之森的冠军领奖台。然而事与愿违，他们在奥运会决赛中负于队友黄东萍/王懿律，获得银牌。回国后，又在全运会决赛中再次输给对方。二人在接下来的苏迪曼杯中休整，但整装待发后却迎来2021年世锦赛次轮（首轮轮空）负于名不见经传的香港组合张德正/吴永瑢，爆冷出局。一时间球迷们议论纷纷，无法接受这样的落差。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄雅琼表示，东京奥运会前后感受到的是两种不同的压力：赛前是由于搭档伤病无法正常训练，但又想在奥运赛场上拿到好成绩的焦虑；赛后则是比赛失利造成状态低迷，又不知道该从哪个方面下手的迷茫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家队教练组经过研究，决定先将“雅思”拆对。黄雅琼回忆，拆对前，教练曾找她促膝长谈，让她仔细想想，“下一届奥运会时就30岁了，你自己有没有勇气坚持到那个时候？”她坚定回答：“我想打。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，杭州亚运会羽毛球混合双打半决赛，韩国组合徐承宰、蔡侑玎（右）在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二人分别搭档张殊贤和欧煊屹进入冬训。新赛季开始前，郑思维/张殊贤拿到队内循环赛第一，但在赛季首站德国公开赛中“一轮游”。循环赛中发挥一般的黄雅琼和欧烜屹进入决赛，拿到亚军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于新组合排名低、不具备报名参加高级别巡回赛的资格，雅思组合在2022年3月的全英公开赛短暂重组。首轮面对实力并不算强的法国选手，二人苦战三局收获了胜利。赛后，雅琼对思维说：“怎么打得有点紧？”思维坦诚地回答：“我觉着有点信心不够。”几番努力后，他们闯进四强，和王懿律/黄东萍再度会师，但还是未能实现突破，以1:2告负，无缘决赛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄雅琼认为，她能明显感觉到老搭档总是差一口气，没有信心。 “很少在场上看到思维是这个状态。他以往都是阳光积极、在场上去主导比赛的，第一场我就察觉出他没有以前那么笃定了，出球也不是轻易就能处理好，不像他一贯的风格。”郑思维感受到了黄雅琼的变化：“当时我的信心很差，但雅琼和以前很不一样，她主动站出来鼓励我，能完全稳住场上的局面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全英赛结束后，郑思维伤病复发，走路都不是很方便。 “我这个打法很耗身体、耗能力，现在腿不行，还怎么打？要打下去势必要提升（状态）、要保持（实力），更要多练。可是，多练又跟伤病冲突，就感觉天要塌下来了。”他回忆面临的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教练征询他们对亚锦赛配对的报名意见，郑思维说：“我还是选雅琼，从那个时候，我们就已经确定配回来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后就是大家熟悉的30连胜剧本。到2022年世锦赛之前，二人一度焦虑会不会把好运气都耗在了前面的公开赛上，怕到大赛就变差了。因为此前有过“一轮游”，心里多少有些阴影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们在此次世锦赛首轮轮空，初次登场时遇到泰国年轻组合苏帕克/苏皮萨拉的猛烈阻击，以19比21输掉第二局。决胜局一度以13-17落后。黄雅琼赛后接受采访时说：“在13-17落后时我们拿到了一分，追到14-17。当时轮到我发球，感觉自己的心定了下来。赛后，思维也跟我说，他就是那个时候感觉到心中很稳，我们没有问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终他们一路过关斩将，拿下了第三个世锦赛冠军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;596&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，在杭州亚运会羽毛球混合双打半决赛中，中国组合郑思维（左）、黄雅琼（右）以2比1战胜韩国组合徐承宰、蔡侑玎，晋级决赛&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在教练杨明眼中，重组后的“雅思”到了另外一个高度：“分开一段时间对他们来说是好事情，两个人再次联手，都比之前有了成长。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄雅琼回忆，二人此前有分歧会争论不休，最后也没有结果。现在郑思维会听听她的意见，一起试试谁的方法更有效。郑思维认为黄雅琼“更能扛了”。 “我们组合的主要特点和得分在于我，以前她会受到我状态不好的影响，一起失误，出现一连串的消极反应。但现在，无论我怎样，雅琼都能兜得住底。我好，她更好；我差，她能挺身而出……可能是从合作之后，我们始终是顺境大于逆境，没有太多调试过在逆境中如何解决问题。如果当初那三个月我们没有分开，还继续憋在一起发力，可能是负效应。这种事情，好像在一起反而解决不了。等我们在新的环境、新搭档中渡过了这种情绪，回来的时候或许不需要特别去解决。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了这样一次从谷底到巅峰的过程，球迷们尽管对二人两连败有焦虑，但依然对他们充满信心。因此，本届亚运会半决赛，对徐承宰/蔡侑玎是胜是负，成为“雅思组合”能否跨越心理关卡的重要一役。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比赛开始，“雅思组合”没有找到节奏，也没有行之有效的得分手段，以13-21输掉了第一局。第二局，“雅思”积极调整，通过主动挑球进入防守，在多拍相持中寻找反击机会，以21-15扳回一局。决胜局，“雅思”先以2-6落后，但在11分之前就实现反超。之后，“雅思”打得更加坚定，将压力全部抛给了对手，对手越打手越紧，发球下网、杀球出界等失误接连不断。 21-16，他们终于得偿所愿。拿下制胜一分后，郑思维情不自禁地连声怒吼。比赛中，郑思维不再只是强攻，而是增加了进攻的变化；黄雅琼则提升了网前的盯球和跟进速度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253361&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年7月30日，在2020东京奥运会羽毛球混双决赛中，中国组合王懿律、黄东萍以2比1战胜队友郑思维、黄雅琼&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛后，郑思维说：“我们就是跟他们扛，跟他们打多拍，主动起球与他们打攻防，其实对手想攻死我们的概率也不高的。”比赛中，每得一分，“雅思”都要大喊足足三声。郑思维说，打到最后已经不单纯是技战术的较量，更多是心理的比拼。如果每得一分只喊一声，那对手就不会感觉到压力，必须再大喊两声，“到最后，他们确实也会发怵，发球也下网了。”黄雅琼则说：“其实我也有过不坚决的时候，决胜局11分间歇后，我有点精力下降，但思维一直在鼓励我，我也通过大喊来调动自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了这场胜利，雅思组合气势如虹。在2023年10月7日进行的亚运会羽毛球混双决赛中，以2:0（21-15/21-14）战胜日本组合东野有纱/渡边勇大，蝉联亚运会混双冠军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果打下去，我的目标就是奥运会，就是巴黎。”那次谈话后，黄雅琼说。现在，距离这个目标不到10个月。重回巅峰的“雅思组合”能够补上东京奥运会的遗憾吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新的中东战争爆发？以色列的猝不及防和犹太社区的自发秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月7日清晨6时30分，“第四次中东战争”50周年之际，哈马斯发动了对以色列的突然袭击。曾被认为是最精良的以色列情报系统完全失察，对对方大规模战备竟没有察觉；以精锐著称的以国防军，更是完全没有准备，被打得措手不及；而曾行之有效的以社会“民兵制”（寓兵于民）也未能充分发挥前几次“中东战争”时快速反应作用，大量平民伤亡。一整天下来，双方打得难解难分，又一个火药桶开始冒烟，人类社会真是多灾多难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚餐时，接到一位远在加拿大的朋友信息：因这场冲突，他所在犹太社区将募捐约1360多万加元，用于援助犹太同胞，他家将摊到近55万加元（约折合290万人民币）。好吓人！怎么会要这么多钱？经过一番沟通，才了解到当今犹太社区的一些小秘密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位朋友与犹太女性结婚，生了三个孩子，被接纳为犹太人，入住了加拿大一个由98户犹太居民组成的犹太社区。犹太社会规则很特殊：他们以母系血统为依据，外族男性与犹太女性结婚生育的孩子，被接纳为犹太人。而外族女性与犹太男性婚育所生的孩子，则不被认为是犹太人，而只是有犹太基因的外族人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入犹太社区的新家庭，包括与其婚配的外族男性，都可享有该社区福利，同时也要承担该社区的公约义务，包括：基建维修、清洁卫生、夜班执勤、安保服务、学童教育、奖学金、宗教服务、心理帮助、困难救助等等。朋友说：他家孩子，每年都能从社区得到几万加元的奖学金、各类福利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，羊毛出在羊身上。这些福利并非加拿大政府给的，而是他们这个小小的犹太社区自筹，具体说：该社区每个家庭每年每户要缴纳16.5万加元的份子钱（约折合87.5万人民币），每年1600多万加元，是该社区的共同基金，以提供社区的存续运营、修葺更新、安保服务、互帮互助。相当于业主自办物业、保洁、保安、社保、教会、教辅等诸多机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这笔社区共同基金，由犹太拉比管理、支付，所有账目对全社区所有家庭、每个成员公开，在社区会议上做出决策，因此从无贪腐、浪费。这是精于理财的犹太族群几千年形成的传统和本领，每个个体都精明地看住自己的钱财，不被权力侵占，才能确保整个群体和社会财富避免被偷盗和腐蚀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;犹太社区的共同基金还有个高价值内部资源：教辅。不是补课，而是学校教学之外的思维课程，有犹太族群“智者”主持对孩子们的价值观养成、思维方式培养、方法论锻炼……其中《塔纳赫》《塔木德》相当重要。其结果是犹太子弟在学术和商业方面具有很大优势，印度裔擅长做职业经理人，犹太青年则更长于尖端高新科技、金融界精英及始创型公司Boss。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该社区犹太人户户都是高收入，住带大院子、游泳池的独栋House，但即便如此，也不是每户每年都能足额缴纳这16.5万加元。社区的办法是：有钱的出钱、有力的出力、有人的出人，折算为一定工作量，来承担上述社区服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那位朋友的老丈人、小舅子，在澳洲西部的珀斯扩建新的犹太社区。在这次突发事件中，属于既没出力，又没出人，因此由朋友出三份钱约55万加元。以后，他们自己怎样算账，那是他们的家务事了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于文化基因与历史原因，犹太人崇尚基于对犹太宗教和文化传统认同的自治。因此，这个仅98户、不到500人的小型社区，竟然有自己的自卫队。十几岁到二十出头的年轻人，大多喜欢舞枪弄棒，在枪械管理松懈的加拿大，他们装备真枪实弹。除了各家各户自备的枪支以外，社区的共同基金里，每年都有部分安保基金，用于添置长枪和弹药，朋友给我看的照片里，甚至还有12.7mm“巴雷特”重狙。社区每年都组织青年们进行军训，但这部分威力较大的长枪，平时被锁在军火库里，以防出现意外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个小小的犹太社区不到500人，却有400多条枪，短枪、长枪、霰弹枪……接近人手一把，而且每年都在增加，他们开玩笑道：谁再敢屠犹，来试试看？话虽这么说，但朋友说在社区会议上，争议最大的话题仍是安保费用，很多家庭认为自卫能力有些就够了，现在毕竟不是战争时期、加拿大也不是战争地带，没必要每年家家户户都出很多钱，让几十个愣小子、疯丫头每年都噼噼啪啪发射几万发子弹，那太浪费了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这些民间自发练武并非完全无用。 10月7日清晨的突袭发生后，美国、加拿大、澳洲等地许多犹太社区的青年，在当晚即乘航班飞往以色列，准备参战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;犹太是数量极少的族群，算上混血的仅2500万人，在当今全球人口占比仅3‰。由于其文化传统特质，喜好金融行业与学术行业，这个族群又太过富有，且还不是“富不过三代”，而是所养育的一代又一代孩子，在学术和商业上太过成功，占据了太多高职、高薪、高利润，那么点人口又无法建立大帝国，无法组建百万雄师保护自己。所以，当今犹太社区摸索出来的生存智慧与组织秩序，即哈耶克所谓“自发秩序”，是群体和个体存在于世界的适应性选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[决赛直落三局，中国女排击败日本队第九次登上亚运冠军领奖台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258263]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排队长袁心玥在比赛中击球。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253420&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排队长袁心玥在比赛中击球。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月7日，杭州亚运会女排决赛在杭州师范大学仓前校区体育馆举行，中国女排直落三局横扫日本女排，以整个亚运会期间六战全胜、不失一局的战绩，成功卫冕女排冠军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，王媛媛在比赛中击球。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，王媛媛在比赛中击球。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;决赛首局比赛开场阶段，日本队一度领先3分，但随后中国队连得10分，并在后半段依靠有效拦网和高质量发球扭转场上态势，并通过连续得分以25:15拿下首局；第二局，日本队通过调整状态紧咬比分，一度将分差缩小到2分，比赛节奏紧张激烈，中国女排一直保持着比分上的领先，并以25:21锁定胜局；第三局，日本队加强了拦网，打得极为顽强，两队一路缠斗到9:9，最终中国女排球员吴梦洁把第三局比分锁定在25:21，终结全场比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排队员在比赛中拦网。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排队员在比赛中拦网。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排队员在比赛中击球。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排队员在比赛中击球。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排球员在比赛中庆祝得分。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排球员在比赛中庆祝得分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从1974年首次参赛至今，中国女排在亚运赛场占据着绝对的统治地位，球队在13届亚运会当中总计取得9金3银1铜，是夺冠次数最多的球队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排姑娘们庆祝决赛获胜。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排姑娘们庆祝决赛获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，决赛结束后，中国女排队员向观众挥手致意。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，决赛结束后，中国女排队员向观众挥手致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国队主教练蔡斌认为，队员们的努力得到了回报：“这次亚运会从第一场直到最后一场，队员们的心态起伏其实很小。把心态放得更平，把每个过程做好，这个结果就是自然而然的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月7日，中国女排球员在颁奖台上展示五星红旗和金牌。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国女排球员在颁奖台上展示五星红旗和金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女排横扫日本队成功卫冕，队长袁心玥渐入佳境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258252]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BLywMWeLWuvv0jb5ynmTl7P9CVr6ielltPKqn680.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BLywMWeLWuvv0jb5ynmTl7P9CVr6ielltPKqn680.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队球员在颁奖仪式上合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月7日晚，杭州亚运会女排决赛场上，中国女排的姑娘们以3-0完胜日本队，再次在亚运会夺冠。本次亚运会中国女排6战全胜，顺利拿下队史第9枚亚运金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整场比赛，队长袁心玥的进攻成功率非常高，打出了巅峰状态，22扣17中1拦拿到了18分。在赛场上比分紧咬、局势焦灼的时刻，她担当起进攻重任，拿下两局赛点，与队友李盈莹、刁琳宇、龚翔宇、王媛媛等人共同合作，一举夺下金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次亚运会是女排姑娘们在奥运会资格赛失意后的首场重大比赛。赛后，袁心玥接受采访时说：“我们奥预赛打完后就一直在调整状态和心态。训练中我们互相之间更多以鼓励为主，我需要把我自己先做好，再和队伍一起商量解决遇到的问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/SIbZ6wm7hqpZTFQELnM3zUR9xe7oDEAHY5kwtUK2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/SIbZ6wm7hqpZTFQELnM3zUR9xe7oDEAHY5kwtUK2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队球员袁心玥（上右）在比赛中拦网&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;担任队长一年有余，袁心玥对这一身份及其职责越来越熟稔了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年5月，中国女排宣布由袁心玥担任队长。彼时，经过近4个月的选材、备战与磨合，全新的女排队伍刚刚组建。由于朱婷仍在养伤，刚上任的主教练蔡斌决定将队长袖标交给袁心玥，“从进入国家队的时间、大赛经验以及在这次集训中的表现等各方面看，袁心玥很胜任队长这一角色。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实也的确如此。在当时公布的16人名单队伍中，丁霞、金烨、王唯漪、王云蕗、刁琳宇等队员都比袁心玥年长，可要论入选国家队的时间、随队参赛的经历，无人能及后者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年是袁心玥加入国家队的第10年，“我觉得（今年）和以往最大的不同是身边多了更多新队员，也有几位之前一起战斗过的队友。”过去10年，她见证了女排队友的更迭以及成绩的起落。如今身为队长，她给自己定下的目标是：“希望自己在队里把老队员的角色担当好，为中国女排做出更大的贡献。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;27岁的袁心玥从小跟着在校队做女排教练的母亲练习排球，由于先天条件不错，她随后被父母送入八一女排集训，孤身一人去了北京。2013年，不满17岁的袁心玥身高就已接近两米，被时任女排主教练郎平选中，越级进入国家队。同年，她所在的中国国少女排在U18世锦赛决赛中击败美国队夺冠，她以出色的表现获得“最有价值球员奖（MVP）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/A3EePMPbGSsHlwjMPllgOZyVOjNKJyRsXFPkswN3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/A3EePMPbGSsHlwjMPllgOZyVOjNKJyRsXFPkswN3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队主教练蔡斌（右二）在比赛中指挥&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，在意大利举行的女排世锦赛中，由于老将徐云丽意外受伤，初出茅庐的袁心玥替换上场。那场比赛她8次进攻得到7分，凭借出色的发挥，成为球队晋级的重要力量。这是她第一次参加世界顶级大赛，“挺兴奋的，球队安排很紧，没什么时间胡思乱想。只要我一有空，丽姐就马上给我补课，以至于半决赛前那个晚上，我做梦都是比赛。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/C3iY5niN71dtcadh64c59MWkgCI2MYJl4aD0ZXds.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/C3iY5niN71dtcadh64c59MWkgCI2MYJl4aD0ZXds.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队球员袁心玥（上）在比赛中进攻&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央视解说员田宗琦对袁心玥当时出众的表现印象深刻，并将她与侯玉珠（1984年洛杉矶奥运会女子排球金牌得主）作比，“作为17岁的小将，她把队友从集体梦游的状态唤醒。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其后几年，女排大小的国际赛事中，观众都能看见袁心玥的身影，熟悉她的粉丝们也因为她稚嫩的脸颊而喊她“小苹果”。表现不凡的“小苹果”从国家队的一位年轻选手，一跃成为和朱婷、张常宁并称“朱袁张”组合的女排骨干球员，并与队友们一起经历了2016年里约奥运会中国女排重回巅峰的荣耀时刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但她常常觉得自己还不够出色，“因为有朱婷、有张常宁、有（李）盈莹，她们就能够支撑起几点的攻守，帮我分担、牵扯对方拦网人的精力。等到没有她们的时候，我自己应该怎么去打，这种能力我觉得应该再提高一些。”袁心玥一直在队里担任主力副攻，拦网是副攻手的主要职责之一。有一段时间，她曾因拦网能力较差饱受质疑，“我觉得拦网还挺难，因为它既是一个被动挨打，也是一个主动去找节奏、时机的项目。”意识到拦网是自己的短板后，袁心玥下决心通过苦练提升自己的拦网技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年女排世界杯比赛，中国女排在与巴西女排对决时，副攻手袁心玥拿下26分，个人拦网得到7分，与朱婷一同成为当场比赛的得分王。她创造了自1999年1月排球比赛实行每球得分制二十多年来中国女排副攻在世界大赛单场得分的最高纪录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/CeQQzOmeOjYPatJMASWqi3dK8K47549kdSWwI0Gn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/CeQQzOmeOjYPatJMASWqi3dK8K47549kdSWwI0Gn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，在杭州亚运会女子排球决赛中，中国队以3比0战胜日本队，中国队球员王媛媛、高意、袁心玥（左至右）在赛后庆祝夺冠&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2013年重新执教中国女排之后，郎平先后率领女排姑娘们夺得2015年女排世界杯、2016年里约奥运会和2019年女排世界杯冠军，袁心玥都参与其中并做出了不小的贡献。尽管后来女排姑娘们无缘东京奥运赛场，但中国女排在过去40年间的数度浮沉都完美诠释着女排精神。正如郎平所说：“女排精神不是赢得冠军，而是有时候知道不能赢，也会竭尽全力。哪怕一路走来摇摇晃晃，但站起来抖抖身上的尘土，依旧眼神坚定，只要你打不死我，我就和你拼到底。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年上映的电影《夺冠》记录了郎平重新执教国家队、女排时隔12年重返奥运巅峰的坎坷历程。影片完整还原了女排姑娘们在里约赛场夺冠的一幕，袁心玥也参与了电影的制作。她记得，在拍摄重头戏中巴对决时，导演担心效果出不来想用些辣椒水，被她拒绝了，“一会就能哭起来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/hn9usGsqAEfBocw5yB1tF7OEz8ZTOS7qU1BYKqMQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/hn9usGsqAEfBocw5yB1tF7OEz8ZTOS7qU1BYKqMQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队球员袁心玥在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚运会前几个月，女排姑娘们刚走过奥运预选赛三连败的曲折历程。“队长的身份会让我在困难的时候，告诉自己更应该站出来。”袁心玥做到了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾中国女排2023年的比赛历程，虽然无缘直通巴黎奥运会让人颇为遗憾，但在杭州亚运会上卫冕成功以及在世界女排联赛中力克一众强手拿到亚军，都让球迷看到了这支处于新老交替期的中国女排队伍的进步和成长。我们相信在不久的将来，那支战无不胜、攻无不克的中国女排一定会重回世界之巅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考资料：新华网、澎湃新闻、新京报等。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[枪击案后，赴泰旅游会否再陷困境？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258250]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Iscf507cfHf8z9z7Oc7csxC72ETxATEcO5Qk2ZDA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Iscf507cfHf8z9z7Oc7csxC72ETxATEcO5Qk2ZDA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年10月7日，一名遇难者的母亲在泰国农磨兰普府发生枪击事件的保育中心外哭泣。当地一所保育中心6日发生枪击事件，造成至少36人死亡&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间2023年10月3日下午16时20分左右，泰国曼谷市暹罗百丽宫购物中心发出多声枪响。14岁的嫌犯用一把改造过且装有实弹的训练用空弹枪射击，导致2人死亡5人受伤。受害者中有两位中国公民，其中一位不幸罹难，另一位受伤，仍在重症监护室接受救治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在9月25日，泰国内阁为中国游客提供的为期5个月的免签政策，才正式开始生效。新冠疫情前，中国是泰国国际旅游的第一大客源国。据泰国官方统计，2023年前8个月，泰国的中国游客总数为210万，不足2019年中国赴泰游客总数的五分之一。推出免签政策，旨在刺激泰国旅游业恢复活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泰国旅行社协会名誉秘书长阿迪估计，这一政策将会为泰国在2023年最后一个季度多吸引50万—70万中国游客。泰国政府发言人乃猜表示，免签政策生效后的两天内，就有超过2.2万中国游客进入泰国。携程数据显示，截至9月12日，今年黄金周假期携程平台上的泰国旅游预订量同比增长5706%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事态似乎正向着好的方向发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，百丽宫的枪击事件，为中国游客重燃的赴泰热情浇上一盆冷水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/xmr5dhNn1X0xBRW6Hzg61gaQAuYIm15QW1Q2cLHp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/xmr5dhNn1X0xBRW6Hzg61gaQAuYIm15QW1Q2cLHp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月25日，泰国总理赛塔·他威信（前排右）在曼谷素万那普国际机场迎接中国游客。自25日起，泰国对中国游客实施为期约5个月的免签政策&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;旅行变得惴惴不安&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;枪击事件发生后，在一些自由行旅客的心中，曼谷从行程表上的重头戏变为不可久留之地。“再也不会来泰国了。”这是无奈踏上泰国土地的Kark的想法。和许多游客一样，Kark被泰国新近的免签政策带来的便利所吸引，将其选为国庆假期的目的地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kark原计划10月3日从香港飞到曼谷，住在离案发现场不到两公里的酒店，下午去百丽宫购物。只因在香港临时和朋友聚餐而把行程推后一天，Kark躲过一劫。“之前准备3号下午在百丽宫买包，后来看媒体报道，凶手就是在那家店旁边的厕所开了第一枪。这是老天的信号，告诉我这个国家不要去了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到新闻时，逗留香港的Kark陷入焦虑和恐惧：危险离自己也许只有一个巧合的距离。当他向旅行平台申请退票时，被航空公司以“非不可抗力影响”为由拒绝。为了不让三千多元的往返机票打水漂，Kark采取折中方案：4号落地曼谷后，立马转飞普吉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kark坦言，旅行变得让人惴惴不安。枪击案发生之前，Kark还能保持冷静：舆论夸大了泰国诈骗犯罪事件的概率，父母的极力反对也不能阻止他游览泰国的脚步。现在，身处人流稀落的素万那普国际机场，他感到危险如影随形。身体在泰国，心灵却渴望逃离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;类似的烦恼也出现在李平身上，同样是在申请机票退订碰壁后，他取消了在曼谷停留两天的计划，5日到达曼谷机场后径直前往芭提雅。在这个以热闹夜市闻名的度假胜地，李平晚上6点后就一直待在酒店，“想去玩但担心人身安全，不敢去。”白天出门，听到周围有很多人讲中国话时，他才感到安心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/KXTm6Ii5XcR5YJlHn8S7HbnjGqU0PgDsABqQf3My.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/KXTm6Ii5XcR5YJlHn8S7HbnjGqU0PgDsABqQf3My.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，泰国曼谷，警方突击搜查了一处住宅，一名法医正在查看陈列的枪支零件&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;失控的枪&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;出境旅行的安全问题，成为许多赴泰游客心中超越性价比的重要考量。百丽宫的枪击事件，暴露了泰国在枪支管制方面的漏洞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《曼谷邮报》报道，当地警方透露，14岁的嫌犯所用的武器，是一把经过改造的空弹枪——原本多用作体育竞赛的发令枪，被改造为装有子弹的真枪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方发现，嫌犯通过网络联系到非法出售枪支弹药的商家，花费17000泰铢（约合3259人民币）从对方那里直接购买空弹枪和9毫米真弹。尽管空弹枪和BB枪可以通过更换枪管被改造为致命武器，但由于它们被当作“仿真枪”，按照泰国法律规定，持有这类枪支不必像持有真枪一样需要申请注册。由于缺少监管，仿真枪流通比真枪更为便利，很容易就能从网上买到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/kM2XN3crvGbSAomd8X24a49CuuXiQcBSGDbkpmQT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/kM2XN3crvGbSAomd8X24a49CuuXiQcBSGDbkpmQT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，警察在泰国曼谷逮捕一名枪击事件嫌疑人。曼谷市中心知名商场暹罗百丽宫当天发生一起枪击事件，一名中国公民不幸遇难，另有一名中国公民受伤&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据泰国国家网报道，泰国警察总署署长多萨透露，近年来泰国进口了大量空弹枪，其中大多数被改造后用于犯罪。在7月的一次清缴行动中，警方缴获了2000个空弹枪管、超过10万发弹药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，泰国也是枪支持有大国。据研究报告指出，泰国有超过1030万支枪，平民的拥枪率为平均每100人10.5支，这一比例在亚洲国家中排名第二。2019年泰国涉枪死亡人数为2804人，枪支凶杀率为10万分之3.91，这一数据也排在东盟国的第二位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泰国颁布的《火器、弹药、爆炸物、烟花和仿真枪法》对非法持枪行为设置了较为严厉的惩罚：最高达10年的监禁、2万泰铢（约合人民币3930元）的罚款。但是，法律落实的力度有限。在泰国所有的枪支中，仍有40%的枪支属于非法持有，没有注册登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《纽约时报》的采访中，曼谷风险评估公司PQA联会的首席执行官夸利亚表示，泰国的枪支管制就像“不存在”一样，“注册枪支根本不需要费什么力气。泰国的问题在于枪支泛滥。无论合法还是非法的，枪支都可以畅通接触，容易获得。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;枪支泛滥和监管不力的现状，对泰国社会的公共安全构成威胁，百丽宫枪击案悲剧发生后，加强枪支管制已成为泰国官方、民众、游客的共同呼声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，经过多日商讨，泰国内政部公布了收紧枪支持有、交易、进口的13项计划。其中，短期计划包括：禁止批准新的仿真枪进口许可证、新增针对仿制枪持有的登记要求、停止颁发新的枪支经营许可证等。长期计划包括：强制要求持枪申请人提供精神状况的健康证明、将空弹枪和BB枪等排除在仿制枪类别之外、要求持枪人对子弹信息进行登记等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/QDHytCZBdmWPy9xG360HZwJ3qRPzYKTylg88R6Do.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/QDHytCZBdmWPy9xG360HZwJ3qRPzYKTylg88R6Do.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，警察在泰国曼谷商场暹罗百丽宫的案发现场发现一支手枪&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;旅游业冲击&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;枪击事件发生后，泰国总理塞塔向中国驻泰大使道歉、探望中国伤员，泰国王室也慰问帮助，其官方积极安抚中国游客的努力不可谓不诚恳。但泰国方面似乎也意识到，此次袭击或许会对后疫情时代刚复苏的泰国旅游业造成无法避免的冲击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据泰国星暹传媒报道，泰国旅游营销协会主席基蒂指出，考虑到枪袭案对中国游客的心理影响，10月将会有一半以上的中国客源流失，原本预计的70万游泰华人，或将减少到30万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较于泰国方面对旅游业的担忧，针对此次枪击案是否严重挫伤泰国游业务的问题，中国国内旅行社、线上旅游平台有更乐观的看法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;众信旅游市场部某负责人指出，枪击案和自然灾害、罢工等事件一样，会让游客因更警惕目的地安全问题而做出权衡，但疫情后出境旅游市场恢复的更大影响因素是签证和交通。从中国到泰国的航班数量，与疫情前相比仍存在较大差距，泰国旅游业务的恢复，是一个更长期的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;携程负责组团社业务的工作人员透露，截至10月5日，她收到因发生枪击案而要求退订泰国游的申请并不多，“大概10个里面会有一人提出这种诉求。”据她估计，11、12月到泰国的游客量会出现一定降幅，但这之后，这种影响会逐渐消散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，中国旅游研究院国际研究所所长杨劲松解释，此次枪击案属于偶发性事件，“它并不像大规模暴动、战争、疫情等系统性风险一样，大家会立刻做出反应，采取措施应对。枪击案的影响有滞后性，就像“噶腰子”传闻，逐渐累积，让泰国留下负面印象。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨劲松认为，泰国要改善在中国游客心中的形象，一方面需要向游客提供更多切实的安全保障，例如加强建设公共场所的安检系统、推动两国警方的联合执法工作；另一方面，要做好安保方面的宣传工作，主动向游客告知本国的避难场所、求助设施、警力配备，减少他们心中的不确定性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中Kark、李平均为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>