<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[阿奇霉素上热搜，广东儿科专家紧急提醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the topic &quot;azithromycin&quot; became a hot search on Weibo. At the same time, the increase in children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in the respiratory departments of many hospitals across the country has also caused concern. Huang Huarong, director of the Department of Pediatric Respiratory Medicine at Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University, revealed in an interview with Southern+ reporters that about 90% of the patients she currently treats have respiratory infections, and about 80% of them are Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;593&quot; height=&quot;457&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254629&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As for the use of azithromycin, Huang Huarong said that it is indeed the main drug currently used clinically to treat Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. However, there are many clinical types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. Therefore, it is not recommended to take it by yourself, let alone trust the so-called &quot;strategies&quot; on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is azithromycin the main drug for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, macrolide drugs such as azithromycin, clarithromycin, erythromycin, and roxithromycin are the most popular clinical drugs. The drug of choice for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. New tetracycline antibiotics such as doxycycline and minocycline or quinolone antibiotics can also be used for treatment, but caution should be used in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, azithromycin is the main treatment drug for Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. Take azithromycin once a day, with three days as a course of treatment. It will take effect quickly and relieve acute symptoms. In addition, azithromycin is convenient to administer, can take into account children&#39;s medication compliance, and is conducive to improving the therapeutic effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Under what circumstances is it more appropriate to use azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Patients diagnosed by doctors as having Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can be treated with azithromycin. Generally, patients with mild symptoms will experience relief after taking medications. But that doesn&#39;t mean azithromycin will always work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, different children may have heterogeneous manifestations such as different symptoms, different onset conditions, and different physical indicators. The choice of drug needs to be determined by the doctor based on the specific situation. For example, children with mycoplasma pneumonia are more suitable for treatment with erythromycin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, if severe symptoms such as persistent high fever, wheezing, shortness of breath, and difficulty breathing occur, it may be severe or cause other complications. At this time, just using azithromycin is far from enough. It needs to be combined with other drugs and other treatment methods for comprehensive treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, patients may develop unresponsiveness to macrolide drugs due to self-drug resistance, abnormal immune-inflammatory response, and mixed infections. That is, taking azithromycin cannot be effective, and other drugs need to be identified, added, or replaced in a timely manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can I buy my own medicine and take azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Azithromycin is an antibiotic drug and is a prescription drug. It should be used under the guidance of a doctor. It is not recommended to take it by yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Clinically, there are many types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. In particular, children&#39;s physiques are different from those of adults, and some children have an excessively strong immune-inflammatory response and their condition progresses quickly. If the drug is not suitable for the disease, the best opportunity for treatment may be missed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When using medicines for children, special attention should be paid to the safety, rationality and effectiveness of the medicines. The doctor will determine the dosage, course of treatment, usage, etc. of the drug based on the child&#39;s weight, physique, age and other characteristics. Only by rational use of medication under the guidance of a doctor can children recover faster and reduce complications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many parents are worried about the sequelae of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, children with Mycoplasma pneumonia who receive reasonable and timely treatment rarely have sequelae. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to avoiding sequelae lies in early identification and diagnosis of intra- and extra-pulmonary complications. Some children may have intrapulmonary complications such as plastic bronchitis, pleural effusion, and acute attacks of bronchial asthma, as well as extrapulmonary complications such as damage to the nervous system, circulatory system, blood system, and skin and mucous membranes, and require prompt medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254628&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for the prevention of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly spread through droplets, and the pathogen is carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing and runny nose. Try to avoid going to crowded closed places as much as possible, and wear a mask when necessary. Pay attention to washing hands frequently, ventilating frequently, strengthening exercise, and improving physical fitness. Children with the disease should pay extra attention to rest and improve their immunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, people have been wearing masks for a long time, which has reduced the occurrence of respiratory diseases and also caused people&#39;s &quot;pre-existing immunity&quot; to various pathogens to deteriorate. This is also one of the reasons why there are more infections with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and various types of bacteria and viruses today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents find that their children have persistent fever, cough, headache, sore throat and other symptoms, they should seek medical treatment promptly and do not blindly abuse drugs. Do not relax your vigilance after receiving treatment. You must continue to pay attention to the child, pay attention to severe warning symptoms such as persistent high fever and difficulty breathing after treatment, and return to the hospital in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老无所依丨昼夜有时]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbbQAs4OG6XJf5uUgM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbb QAs4OG6XJf5uUgM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon her pufferfish deflated with a &quot;pop&quot;. He looked sick and hopeless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first she would still think about us, feeling sorry that her sister was not married yet and that I had no children. When staying at her eldest sister&#39;s house, she would ask her eldest sister to invite her father over for dinner. She was afraid that he didn&#39;t know how to take care of herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later she could only think about her own affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She wants to live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to porcupine dates, she also believes that Bentong ginger can cure her gallbladder cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m so lucky to see this by chance.&quot; One day, she showed me a report about ginger&#39;s ability to cure diseases. She soon found a woman selling ginger powder nearby. The woman ground Bentong ginger into powder and put it in capsules. My mother bought five or six bottles of ginger powder capsules and gave me one as a gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then there are the leaves of the durian. We heard at the hospital that the leaves of the solanum pomegranate have miraculous effects. Some people boiled water with it and drank it for a few months, and their cancer was cured. So my father collected a bunch of durian leaves. He stored the leaves in her tailor shop. Day after day, they look fragile and pale in the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most ridiculous thing is the father’s idea. He brought back a brochure from Yiyo, claiming that he had met a Reiki master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pink and purple brochure has a photo of a middle-aged man printed on it. The man was wearing a black tunic suit and was serious in speech. He raised his hands in front of his chest as if he was pushing an invisible thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A gentle natural treatment that brings out the best in your mind, body and soul. When health shines, wealth grows.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also on the brochure are Reiki treatments and Reiki Masters Introduction and testimonials of “reiki benefactors”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father went to my eldest sister’s house carrying a bucket and several empty water bottles. He and the Reiki master agreed to treat his mother at his eldest sister&#39;s house the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Just believe me once, just this once.&quot; He said on the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t know.” My mother said when I repeatedly asked her what she thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe she didn&#39;t dare to say &quot;no&quot; to her father, like before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t know.&quot; She used to say this with fear or impatience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result was that we children rejected the Reiki master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last two weeks, my brother took time off to go home and take care of her. At that time, she could no longer walk. Suddenly her will to live returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I must get better, I must be able to walk, and I cannot let Axiang hold me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We bought various health products for her. Her brother also took her to Kuala Lumpur to see a nutritionist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why did you delay it until now?&quot; the nutritionist said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They brought back a bunch of bottles and cans. We don&#39;t care whether they work or not. But soon she couldn&#39;t swallow the pills anymore. After her death, her brother returned them to the nutritionist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She then survived on morphine. The nurse said morphine is a painkiller. When she was feeling uncomfortable, the eldest sister fed her morphine with a syringe, increasing the dose. All the doctors could do was ease her pain. Administer morphine, pump out ascites, and inhale oxygen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her will to survive is so strong, unlike me, who wants to give up at every turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end I couldn’t see the light either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three days before her death, I had a video call with her on the plane to Tokyo and found that her eyes were so empty. There is no light and no sadness. As if indifferent. She looked at me and said nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;God loves you. I pray for you.&quot; I didn&#39;t let her see my tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why would I say that? Things I’m not even sure I actually believe. In the church, this is what middle-class believers say. Now I am like them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She looked at me blankly and said nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is she tired? Fear? What was she thinking? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those last few days, we were almost scrambling to find explanations for our actions. We found “palliative care,” deliberately avoiding the word “hospice.” We are not preparing for her death, we are living with her illness, and it may be a long, long time, we comfort ourselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact is that we can only care for, accompany and comfort her. We can only watch her in pain and watch her die away bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors know better than anyone else. He called his eldest sister and asked her to invite relatives to visit his mother in the ward. &quot;The more people who come, the better,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The words suddenly came to my mind - &quot;Sometimes healing, often relief, always comfort.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her younger siblings arrived. They came one after another and sat by the bed to talk to her. Her spirits suddenly improved, she was in high spirits, and she talked a lot. At that time, no one thought that maybe it was a comeback. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just a few days ago, she would suddenly become confused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One night on the phone she told me loudly that she had five children and named them one by one. Then she asked me why she couldn&#39;t see her children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No. No, no, no. Why no?&quot; She said to me in Hokkien. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. Didn&#39;t see it. Why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I told her I would go back to see her soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eldest sister told me that she only remembered that the person she had just spoken to was me after hanging up the phone. &quot;That was Ah Hong just now.&quot; She murmured to herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her last days, although her husband and children took turns taking care of her, she also got a maid as she wished (people seem to like to judge a person&#39;s happiness in his later years), her The scene, her appearance, and the photo of her sitting alone on the hospital bed that I have buried deep in my heart always remind me of &quot;No Country for Old Men.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From beginning to end, she struggled alone, carrying her suffering and loneliness alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago, she once asked me what &quot;No Country for Old Men&quot; meant. She told me that a neighbor said that she and her father were homeless because three of their five children were abroad and no longer around. The woman said this in front of everyone while they were doing morning exercise at a nearby gym. My mother wrote down the four words &quot;no place for old people&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, when I watched &quot;Nowhere&quot;, I was no longer thinking of her. I was thinking about Natsuki and myself. Occasionally I would secretly lament that because of her and Xiamu&#39;s illness, I was thrown into such a fate and had to face a distant and unknown future early on. It’s as if our future has already arrived. We stumble, sometimes at a loss, sometimes patient, sometimes unmoved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe I should comfort myself in this way. On the last day, she was not sad or in pain, but had something to look forward to. At two o&#39;clock in the morning, she got up from the bed and told the maid Yuni that she had dreamed of her father and that she was going home. She said this without any sadness or fear. She wanted to go home, she always wanted to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She left during the day. She went to places unknown to us. Maybe she thought she was finally home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Nowhere&quot;, Jessica once asked those homeless people on wheels if they had ever thought about their future. Sylviane said the only thing she could do was to keep going and drive over the cliff like Thelma and Louise in Thelma and Louise. Alice says her body will remain in the desert forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know where my mother went. I don&#39;t know where we will go either. We never knew. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nomadland&quot; also has another name - &quot;Nomad Life&quot;. A long time ago, when talking about nomadic people in class, the teacher said that they &quot;lived in pursuit of water and grass.&quot; Wherever there is water and grass, that is their home. This is a life of constant searching, testing and trying. This is how people live, and so does mother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[联合国“近东救济工程处”：“加沙正被推向深渊”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258857]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原消失的海滩女童事件：警惕海滩的各种“隐形杀手”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258910]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 16:12:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[碧桂园辟谣“创始人父女已离境”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258869]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022701523769&quot; data- media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;da5905d728f643fbae16817a69ac3075-ld-nbv1.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/5619700d55766 78022701523769/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0. jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/5619700d5576678022701523769/MLInLoiOiu0A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src =&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/5619700d5576678022701523769/MLInLoiOiu0A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;October On the morning of the 19th, Country Garden issued a statement saying that the company was concerned about rumors that &quot;the founder&#39;s father and daughter may have left the country.&quot; The rumors were posted on multiple online platforms with ulterior motives, causing a negative impact. The founder of our company and the chairman of the group&#39;s board of directors are currently working normally in China. In addition, on the evening of October 18, Country Garden’s official Weibo tweeted that on October 17, Cao Jianglin, Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Agricultural Development Group Co., Ltd., and his delegation visited Country Garden’s headquarters for inspection and exchange, and had a meeting with Yang Guoqiang, founder of Country Garden Holdings Group comminicate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上级检察院如何调用下级检察官？ 告别程序争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258851]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/F1rLuuMtXWdBWiMsht0c1wkLK6ROo21DlVVvzOlj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/F1rLuuMtXWdBWiMsht0c1wkLK6ROo2 1DlVVvzOlj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, 2020, at the Zigui County Court in Hubei Province, the prosecutor who appeared for public prosecution Officials charged 12 members of an evil criminal group involved in &quot;routine loans&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can he appear in court on behalf of the municipal procuratorate to support the prosecution when he is obviously a prosecutor from a district or county? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, the Xinxiang Intermediate People’s Court in Henan held a pre-trial meeting for a bribery case. Wang Xing, a defense lawyer from Beijing, questioned the identity of one of the prosecutors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, according to the system of calling prosecutors from different places (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;abbreviated as &quot;referred to as &quot;remote prosecutors&quot;&lt;/span>;), the higher-level procuratorate can Prosecutors from lower-level procuratorates within the jurisdiction are called to handle cases on behalf of the court, and the called prosecutors can also be assigned to other lower-level procuratorates to handle cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem is that according to relevant laws, Chinese prosecutors have regional attributes, and the prerequisite for performing their duties is to be appointed by the standing committee of the local people&#39;s congress. For example, if the municipal procuratorate wants to transfer an prosecutor from District A Procuratorate to District B Procuratorate to handle a case, it should first remove the person from being a prosecutor from District A Procuratorate through the Municipal People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee, and then appoint him or her as an prosecutor from District B Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous practice, higher-level procuratorial organs often directly called prosecutors from lower-level procuratorates without going through the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The common feeling among lawyers is that when they raised objections to the identity of the prosecutor transferred from another place, the prosecutor either ignored it or said, &quot;It is under the dual leadership of the superior procuratorate and the local congress standing committee, so the superior The court has the right to invoke&quot; as a defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this time, the attitude of the prosecutor opposite Wang Xing was obviously relaxed. He made it clear that he would abide by the new rules to resolve the identity issue. &quot;If the appointment process of the local congress standing committee has not been completed by the time the court opens, he will not speak in court.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new rules refer to the highest The &quot;Regulations on Several Issues Concerning the Unified Dispatch of Prosecutorial Personnel from the Jurisdiction to Handle Cases by the People&#39;s Procuratorate at Higher Levels&quot; issued by the People&#39;s Procuratorate on September 5, 2023 stipulates that if the transferred prosecutors want to perform their duties as prosecutors, such as appearing in court to support public prosecutions, they need to In accordance with the law, the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress at the same level shall be asked to make appointments in accordance with legal procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The promulgation of this regulation means that the &quot;war of words&quot; between academic and practical circles over the off-site inspection system has come to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Legal Identity&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As early as December 28, 2022, the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress reported on the 2022 filing review work situation that the prosecutors were called from other places. It requested that “relevant appointment decisions must be made by the Standing Committee of the People’s Congress at the corresponding level” and stated that “research opinions have been submitted to the relevant formulation agencies and it is recommended that they be considered.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the nine months since the new regulations were promulgated, some local prosecutors’ offices have accepted lawyers’ objections to the use of off-site inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Wang Xing also met two prosecutors from districts and counties at a pre-trial meeting on a fraud case prosecuted by the Yibin City Procuratorate in Sichuan Province. The prosecutor wanted to express his opinion, but Wang Xing told the judge directly: &quot;If he disagrees, don&#39;t let him speak until the issue (their qualifications) is resolved, so as not to invalidate the pre-trial conference.&quot; April 19, 2023 , the Standing Committee of the Yibin Municipal People’s Congress publicly appointed these two people as prosecutors of the Yibin Municipal People’s Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;boot&quot; was launched, a prosecutor from a municipal procuratorate in the southwest region told Southern Weekend: &quot;New regulations have been introduced, and (offsite inspections) must follow the regulations in principle. If they do not comply, once the lawyer proposes When it comes to the identity of prosecutors, the procuratorate will be very passive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, the new regulations stipulate the applicable circumstances for the use of off-site prosecutors, that is, when there are a large number of people involved in the case and the case is particularly serious and complex, And when the case handling capacity is difficult to bear, the superior court can uniformly call on prosecutors from the jurisdiction. Among them, prosecutors from higher-level courts can be sent to lower-level courts to handle cases, and prosecutors from lower-level courts can be transferred to higher-level courts, or to lower-level courts within their jurisdiction for support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most important thing is that the new regulations standardize the calling procedures for remote inspections. Article 7 stipulates that once the case is settled, or the higher court terminates the call, the prosecutor will be removed from the aforementioned duties according to procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new regulations also take into account some exceptions. If a prosecutor from a higher court is transferred to a lower court within its jurisdiction; or if a higher court transfers a branch of its own court or dispatches a prosecutor from the procuratorate to its own court or another branch of this court or dispatches a procuratorate, it does not need to perform the prosecutor appointment procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A grassroots prosecutor told Southern Weekly that before this, when a higher court issued a transfer order, he had to go to the brother court at the same level to handle the case. The transfer period was usually three months, and he also I knew that &quot;the case investigators were seconded elsewhere and were not appointed by the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, so I actually had no legal status.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the National People’s Congress Standing Committee usually only arranges a meeting every two months, it may not be able to meet the prosecutor’s time limit for handling cases. The remedy provided by the new regulations is that before the local Congress Standing Committee makes an appointment, the prosecutor who is called can assist in handling the case as an assistant prosecutor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case of Chen in Honghe, Yunnan, who was suspected of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, the Honghe Prefecture Procuratorate transferred all six prosecutors at one time to assistant prosecutors to assist in completing court proceedings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the opinions of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate expert group, the biggest difference between prosecutors and assistant prosecutors is that important court duties such as reading out the indictment, interrogation, interrogation, cross-examination, defense and issuing opinions in court should be performed by the prosecutor. The former performs it in person; while the latter can only follow instructions and engage in supplementary and auxiliary work such as reading out evidence and assisting in multimedia demonstrations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Repeatedly caught in the whirlpool of public opinion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before the filing and review opinions of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress were made public, &quot;off-site inspection&quot; has repeatedly fallen into the whirlpool of public opinion in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the gang-related case of Wang Yongming in Baotou City, Inner Mongolia put the focus on off-site inspection. During the first trial of Wang Yongming&#39;s case, the defense lawyer reported in court that a prosecutor was suspected of soliciting bribes. Subsequently, the case was assigned jurisdiction by the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region High Court and transferred to the Wuda District Court of Wuhai City for trial. During this period, the Procuratorate of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region mobilized 18 prosecutors and assistant prosecutors from across the autonomous region to form a public prosecution team. Some skeptics pointed out that the practice of prosecutors from the autonomous region procuratorate joining the public prosecutor team and appearing in court to support the prosecution would lead to an imbalance in prosecution and trial and violate procedural justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the Wang Yongming case, in the &quot;Fraud Case of Xie Liuqing and Other 63 People&quot; in Wuhu, Anhui, the procuratorate also formed a &quot;public prosecution team&quot; to appear in court. Because 42 of the defendants were found not guilty in the first instance of the case, the Wuhu Fanchang District Procuratorate filed a protest. In October 2021, during the second trial of the case, the list of persons appearing in court from the Procuratorate was circulated online. Among the public prosecutors, in addition to personnel from various grassroots procuratorial systems in Wuhu City, they also include personnel from the procuratorial systems in Hefei City, Tongling City and other provinces, totaling 11 prosecutors and 2 clerks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This approach has caused great controversy. &quot;Whether the off-site inspection system is legal and constitutional&quot; has once again been put in the spotlight and has become an issue that cannot be ignored by relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Xing’s impression, in some major difficult or gang-related cases, it is “common” to use inspections in other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evolution of off-site prosecution first started with the unified calling of outstanding public prosecutors in the jurisdiction. The &quot;Opinions on Further Strengthening Public Prosecutions and Strengthening Legal Supervision&quot; issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate in June 2005 mentioned that &quot;the People&#39;s Procuratorate at a higher level may select and deploy outstanding public prosecutors or business backbones to handle major and complex cases based on the needs of case handling.&quot; In 2011, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate promulgated the &quot;Regulations on Deploying Excellent Public Prosecutors to Handle Major Public Prosecution Cases (Trial)&quot;, which stipulates that if necessary, outstanding public prosecutors in the jurisdiction can be deployed to handle cases. The newly revised &quot;Organic Law of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; in 2018 officially clarified the off-site prosecutorial system in the form of legislation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of many legal scholars such as Long Zongzhi and Han Xu of Sichuan University, the off-site prosecutorial system is designed to meet the needs of prosecutors and case handling. First, after the reform of the quota system, prosecutors who have the power to handle cases The number has been significantly reduced compared with the past. On the other hand, with the frequent occurrence of major, difficult and socially sensitive cases, it is difficult for grassroots prosecutors to complete their charging tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Zhang Jianwei, a professor at Tsinghua University Law School, the introduction of this system is in response to new changes in the form of defense: in major and sensitive cases, as well as in many corruption or anti-gang cases, out-of-town defense The involvement of lawyers has increased, especially the number of well-known lawyers taking on defense roles, which requires procuratorial organs in various places to respond with a higher level of public prosecutions; on the other hand, lawyers have formed teams to defend co-defendants involved in the case, breaking the past tradition of each acting independently and acting independently. The form of defense brings great challenges to grassroots procuratorial organs. In order to improve the level of public prosecutions and cope with new changes in the prosecution and defense situation, the procuratorial organs have deployed elite soldiers to undertake public prosecutions in the future, thereby ensuring the quality of public prosecutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no dispute over the rationality of using off-site inspections. The disagreement lies in how to use it. There have always been voices within the prosecution system that hope to refine the regulations. Long Zongzhi, a professor at Sichuan University Law School, mentioned in an article: During the revision of the &quot;People&#39;s Procuratorate Criminal Procedure Rules&quot; in 2019, many provincial procuratorates hope to clarify the scope, procedures and prosecutors&#39; responsibilities of unified calls. However, the author believes that &quot;from the current point of view, further experience needs to be summarized on how to call it specifically.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/19/YvHZdv9yPLrNkeO1GlGgHfunUjzyC8A8h76MYB01.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19 /YvHZdv9yPLrNkeO1GlGgHfunUjzyC8A8h76MYB01.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued &quot;About the Higher People&#39;s Procuratorate&quot; on September 5, 2023 Provisions on the unified deployment of prosecutors in jurisdictions to handle certain issues in cases.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are different opinions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Han Xu&#39;s view, the new inspection regulations for remote use The introduction of the law is not unrelated to the supervision of the National People&#39;s Congress, the voice of the academic community, and the review suggestions raised by lawyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year before the prosecutor in the second instance of Xie Liuqing’s case was determined, lawyer Gan Weidong wrote a letter to the Supreme People’s Procuratorate. He quoted at the beginning the second paragraph of Article 9 of the “People’s Procuratorate’s Criminal Procedure Rules”: The decision to call should be made in writing, and the prosecutor who is called can perform various procuratorial duties such as appearing in court to support public prosecutions on behalf of the People&#39;s Procuratorate handling the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think this provision is both unconstitutional and has no basis in superior laws.&quot; He wrote bluntly in the letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Doing so means that prosecutors can break through the jurisdiction of the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee to handle cases in non-appointment jurisdictions, which directly undermines the People&#39;s Congress system.&quot; Gan Weidong told Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 4, 2020, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate 12309 Procuratorial Service Center gave a detailed reply to Qian Weidong, clearly stating that when higher-level procuratorates call prosecutors from lower-level procuratorates to handle cases, they can indeed go to the local congress standing committee. appointment procedures, but in practice it is often difficult to meet the needs of case handling, and even leads to case handling being overdue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, some local prosecutors appointed transferred personnel as assistant prosecutors of the court. This temporary status belongs to the prosecutor, but does not need to be appointed or removed by the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. With the advancement of the reform of classified management of prosecutors and the reform of the prosecutor quota system, the position of assistant prosecutor has been eliminated, and the transfer of prosecutors to perform their duties in other places has become a problem. In order to solve the legality of using prosecutors in other places, when the Organic Law of the People&#39;s Procuratorate was revised in 2018, it was clearly stipulated that the People&#39;s Procuratorate at a higher level &quot;can uniformly call prosecutors in the jurisdiction to handle cases.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xu said that the unconditional &quot;remote inspection&quot; does not have legal legitimacy. However, since laws and judicial interpretations have established this system from the institutional level, &quot;off-site inspections should be used as little as possible and should not become the norm but only the exception.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 2021, during the second trial of Xie Liuqing’s case, lawyers Wang Xing and Shen Yachuan submitted a request to the National People’s Congress Standing Committee to review the legality of the off-site prosecution clause in the “People’s Procuratorate’s Criminal Procedure Rules”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the alleged violation of the provisions of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress at all levels on the appointment of prosecutors, the two lawyers also mentioned that the use of prosecutors in other places also violates the principle of criminal trial level jurisdiction and leads to the provisions of the Criminal Procedure Law. Avoid problems such as the inability of the system to be implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a year after receiving the filing and review suggestions, the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress responded to the lawyers’ suggestions in the filing and review work report released on December 28, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A scholar with knowledge of the situation revealed: “After the opinion of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress on the need for the approval of the appointment of the National People’s Congress Standing Committee for the deployment of prosecutors came out, there were different opinions, but the Legal Affairs Committee insisted on moving to another location. Appointments must be approved by the local People’s Congress Standing Committee.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to solve the remaining problems? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;With the introduction of new regulations by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the procedures for using inspections in other places are no longer controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question that practitioners are most concerned about now is how to deal with cases that have previously been handled by prosecutors without following the opinions of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;two highs&quot; also noticed this. On September 15, 2023, 10 days after the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued the new regulations, the &quot;two highs&quot; jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Issues Concerning the Unified Dispatch of Prosecutorial Personnel from the Jurisdiction to Handle Cases by the People&#39;s Procuratorates at Higher Levels&quot;, which clearly mentioned that for cases that have taken effect Judgment: If the complainant files a complaint on the grounds that the prosecutor who was transferred has not been appointed by the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress at the same level, and does not meet the circumstances that require a new trial under the Criminal Procedure Law, the complainant must be persuaded to withdraw the complaint; if he persists in the complaint, he shall be notified in writing. turn down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice also stipulates that for cases that have entered the second instance procedure, the second instance court shall not revoke the original ruling and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the prosecutor called during the first instance was not appointed by the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xu still has questions: Who will lead and supervise the prosecutor who was called? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He noticed that some prosecutors from higher-level procuratorates who were transferred to other places may have a higher rank than the chief prosecutor of the local procuratorate. As a result, it would be difficult for the chief prosecutor of the local procuratorate to lead the prosecutors of the higher-level procuratorate. . He has researched prosecutors who participated in &quot;off-site prosecution&quot; and found that in practice, there are indeed situations where &quot;higher-level procuratorate prosecutors who are transferred to lower-level procuratorates do not dare to supervise or have lax supervision because of their higher rank.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, when the called prosecutor is not suitable to continue participating in the case, who will make the decision to recuse himself? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new regulations mention that if it is discovered during the handling of a case that the prosecutor being called has circumstances that require him to recuse himself as required by law, the prosecutor being called should recuse himself, and the parties and their legal representatives have the right to request that they recuse themselves. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the Criminal Procedure Law, the chief prosecutor should be responsible for the recusal of prosecutors. However, prosecutors who are transferred from other places are usually decided by the superior prosecutorial agency. In this case, whether the recusal of the transferred person is decided by the prosecutor general of the superior procuratorial agency or by the prosecutor general of the prosecutor&#39;s office where he is transferred? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jianwei&#39;s point of view is that because the call is often decided by the superior procuratorate, if there is a situation where the prosecutor needs to recuse himself during the call, then &quot;whoever dispatches the prosecutor will decide to recuse himself&quot;; but if the prosecutor is called When personnel have begun handling cases on behalf of the procuratorate to which a specific case belongs, &quot;for the sake of efficiency, the issue of recusal should be decided by the chief prosecutor of the procuratorate handling the case.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether relevant departments will issue more detailed judicial interpretations or corresponding regulations for off-site inspections in the future, Zhang Jianwei, who once served as deputy director of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, expressed his expectation, but has not yet done so. Hear about the plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[警方通报男子当街性侵醉酒女子：网传信息不属实]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/lREj0mw3STng0v2EnzvQY0D3hMsQdkBAAiocNZ9O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2008&quot; height=&quot;4631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/lREj0mw3STng0v2EnzvQY0D3hMsQd kBAAiocNZ9O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老年相亲的奇观，“等你老了就明白了”｜记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258792]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73058&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69896&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c79f0bdf96.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;a0567795b9e103e6d94ea8797e82c17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 2023, Shanghai, IKEA restaurant Elderly people inside. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/18/c79f0bdf96.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254344&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Shanghai, Seniors in the IKEA restaurant. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/258371&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;>;In Shanghai’s senior dating site, regulars don’t talk about love&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/a>; p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before I walked into the IKEA restaurant for the first time, I ordered a cup of coffee.深呼吸，努力想扭转自己疲惫的状态，打起精神去跟一个新的群体打交道——一群老来单身的上海人，想必会无聊寡淡。但让我惊喜的是，他们可比我想象的有意思得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;先是一个年过六十的墨镜男迎上来跟我打招呼，他以为我来找伴，毕竟有不少年轻的女性来这个地方“钓鱼”。得知我是记者后，他神秘兮兮地告诉我，自己最近在写一篇《爱的迷茫》，他仰起头开始感慨，“一个人有多少时间可以去等你的爱情呢？这个社会是没有后悔药的，上了60岁，就跟爱情越来越远。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;墨镜男胳膊一挥，指着他背后乌泱泱的老年人，我眼里模糊的背景板即刻变得清晰，个体分明。 “现在往往是不谈精神层面，主要是为了房子，轿车，好多人没有找到伴，走了，黯然失色。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;的确，开门见山是这里的特色，每个人都把条件摊开来讲，包括经济条件、身体情况、生理需求等等，几句话下来，对方到底是图什么，都清清楚楚了。 68岁的洪建明说，该到什么程度，大家心里都明白。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪建明说，这里水深得很，男人图女人漂亮，女人图男人有钱，“你看我长这么帅，都没找到伴，因为她们知道，我养不起她们的”。我在宜家餐厅待了四个下午，遇到的大多数人都跟我形容，这里是一片凶险的江湖，陷阱五花八门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这里流传不少“骗子”的故事，最容易中招的，就是年过八旬的上海老年人。 “有个三四十岁的女人，专门来这里骗七八十岁的老人，越老越好，死得快嘛，她就这样拿了几套房子。”几个女人围着我讲起了女骗子们常用的伎俩——年轻貌美的外表先让老人“上钩”，结婚是瓜分财产最关键的一步，频繁性爱可以加速老人的衰亡，步步稳准狠。旁边一个涂抹浓重黑色眼影的女人插嘴，“漂亮的都是骗子，会把老头害死的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;求偶的男人们也深信这套阴谋论，他们一方面要尽可能做到财气外露，来吸引女性的目光；另一方面又要保持时刻提防，以防坏人得逞。同样，男人中也有另有所图的“骗子”，通过夸大自己的财力“钓鱼”，只为了跟“上钩”的女人睡觉。时不时还有为争一个女人在餐厅里大打出手的男人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管如此，他们还是会雷打不动地一头扎进宜家餐厅，因为“名利场”只是这里的冰山一角。前几年，宜家餐厅的工作人员几次试着将这群大声喧哗的老人赶出这个地盘，都没能成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“老年人太孤独了，我们现在来的这些人，还都能走路，再过几年就不知道了。”洪建明说这话时，我们面前正经过一个白发苍苍的老人，拄着拐杖一小步一小步地挪动，“你看这种老人才稀奇古怪，他来这里干嘛，就是无聊，听听看看”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;宜家餐厅带给他们的，何止是有个地方听听看看。每个礼拜二和礼拜四下午，会有人组织大家一起吃晚饭，尤其钟爱周二有优惠活动的饭店。比如有家饭店会在周二送一盘价值138元的爆炒牛肉粒，那是在一个光洁的长方碟一端，精致地摆上十几颗牛肉粒，为了这盘免费的招牌菜，他们已经来过几十次。人多了，菜多了，还便宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月19日，我第三次来宜家餐厅，得知在这里，有人曾组织大家一起去外地旅游，每个人出点钱报个老年团，彼此照顾；也看到了他们在这里大胆地谈论性与爱，甚至谈到令讨论的人面红耳赤的地步，但出了门，谁也不认识谁。没了那个氛围，有些话再难说出口。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这天晚饭后，一直很幽默的洪建明突然语气沉重地跟我讲，他时常在凌晨1点多从牌馆出来，白天就在宜家餐厅和人民公园走一走，跟人唠唠嗑。他心底其实瞧不上眼前这群嘴里只会念叨鸡毛蒜皮的老人，这跟他以前工作的同事无法相提并论，可是人老了没办法，他退休了，生病了，就要退到老人该去的地方，到老人堆里去寻求认同感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最让洪建明失望的是，儿子嫌他了，“他没有明说嫌我，但我是他老子啊，我还不知道他在想什么？装没用。”儿子每拎着东西来家里看他一次，俩人就重复上演一幕情景：儿子时不时看一眼手表，很快找借口离开，“我说那你走吧，他立马就走了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;儿子的嫌弃体现在方方面面，洪建明都看出来了。儿子从来不会主动打过来电话问问；他打给儿子的电话很少接通，儿子会隔很久时间突然打回来问他，“爸爸什么事，我前面在忙，没听到。”永远是这样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这样的例子，在宜家餐厅多得数不过来，我陆陆续续从几个人讲述中了解到，他们生儿育女，最终到了暮年，还是落得自己一个人生活，手里的房子和退休金，就是最后的底气。而宜家餐厅不过是老年群体的一个缩影，这里之外的现象可以想象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月21日，我最后一次去宜家餐厅，直到晚上9:30，还有四位老人留在餐厅里聊天。他们说，回去也睡不着，聊聊天挺好的。他们说，我还年轻，不懂得推着时间走向尽头的感受多么无力，我听过几次这句话：“等你老了就明白了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我确实不能感同身受，只觉得话题沉重。反过来说，尽管在他们口中，80岁的宋小飞是个糊涂人，把8000块钱的退休金都交给一个40多岁的外地女人，就为了让她陪自己；78岁的老张也是个糊涂人，每天花300块钱买年轻的女人来陪是糟蹋钱。但在我看来，或许是难得清醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;毕竟，人到暮年，剩下的时间不多了。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[视频教你坐地铁：面向全国数亿人的“社会生存学”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258812]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Uncle Chen has been working in Guangdong for more than ten years and almost never takes the subway. If the new construction site hadn&#39;t happened to be near a subway station, Uncle Chen wouldn&#39;t have walked in, even though it was Tiyu West Road, the largest subway station in Asia that handles nearly a million passengers every day. Because he still hasn&#39;t understood the rules of taking the subway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally arrived at the platform of Tiyu West Road Station. Uncle Chen was carrying a bag of quilts in one hand and a bucket in the other hand, which contained towels, shower gel and other daily necessities, and asked the strangers around him for directions. ——He was going to take the subway to work near Shipaiqiao subway station, which was just one stop away. Uncle Chen is from Hubei. He and his wife rent in Fushan Village, Huangpu District, more than 30 kilometers away from the center of Guangzhou. He usually works as a temporary worker at construction sites in Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Zhuhai and other places. The nearest subway station is 3 kilometers away from his residence. When he goes to work, he usually takes a bus or a taxi, even though the former is a long journey and the latter is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t ride the subway for long, and it’s very troublesome to go around in circles.” Uncle Chen said. His two daughters worked outside the home, and no one taught him how to confirm the route, transfer trains, or find the station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZOmMx5fvos11SE1narzVKAxCdNCwHi2GycsiJY95.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZOmMx5fvos11SE1narzVKAxCdNCwHi2GycsiJY95.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, at Xiuyi Station of Suzhou Rail Transit Line 11, citizens were checking the subway line map and buying tickets by themselves. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Heng, who is studying urban rail operation management at an engineering college in Hunan, is about to graduate. Just took the subway for the first time. In the first month of college, the teacher asked in class if any students had never taken the subway. There were 42 people in the class, and one-third of them raised their hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Out of surprise, the teacher asked a girl who had ridden the subway to share her feelings. The girl said that the subway was fast, comfortable and convenient. &quot;I was very envious at the time. I had never seen this thing before,&quot; Zhou Heng said. In his hometown and the city where he goes to school, public transportation is not very developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, teachers still asked the same questions in class from time to time, but almost no one raised their hands anymore. &quot;At that time, I was actually too embarrassed to admit it,&quot; Zhou Heng said, &quot;After all, I learned this by myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time Zhou Heng walked into a subway station was when he traveled to Nanchang with his classmates in his sophomore year. He found that the subway was a little different from what he imagined. It was not as quiet and comfortable as the girl described. It was very crowded during rush hours, the carriages vibrated obviously, and it was very noisy while driving. But he was still very interested and curiously paid attention to the layout of the station and the location of the escape routes. After arriving at the station, they remembered the subway driving process they had just learned in class, and stayed on the platform for a while, waiting to see the driver come out of the cockpit after the door closed, get out of the car, check, and then return to the car. They also took photos. Send the video to the teacher. &quot;The teacher praised us for being studious,&quot; Zhou Heng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You are 20 years old and have never taken the subway. Are you a failure?&quot; This is one of the most popular comments on David&#39;s video. He made a short video of the process of taking the subway and taught others how to transfer and find the station on social media. There are many &quot;traffic bloggers&quot; similar to him. Search for &quot;subway riding tutorial&quot; and the city name on the short video platform to find subway teaching videos in various cities. If you still don&#39;t understand, you can ask questions in the comment area. , and received precise answers from bloggers and enthusiastic netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type &quot;how many people in China have never taken the subway&quot; in the search engine, and the answer is &quot;900 million&quot; (Editor&#39;s note: As of September 2023, the 2022 permanent population of all cities in mainland China with subway access The total is 499 million). What does a subway mean to the silent majority? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Those who have never ridden the subway know nothing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many people who have never ridden the subway, the first thing to break through is the psychological barrier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ronaldiner works in Chengdu, and his parents have been working in Aba Prefecture, Sichuan for a long time. During the Chinese New Year in 2023, Ronaldinho asked her mother to accompany her from Chengdu to Chongqing. When she proposed to take the subway to the high-speed rail station, her mother refused and asked for a taxi. Ronaldinho didn&#39;t understand that taking a taxi was expensive and crowded, so he argued with his mother. In the end, her mother was a little embarrassed and said that she had never taken the subway and didn&#39;t know how to take it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ronaldiner said simply: &quot;Then I will teach you.&quot; The mother was stunned for a moment, as if she was surprised that her daughter did not laugh at her. The dispute ended with Ronaldinho convincing his mother to accept the instruction. The two rehearsed the entire process at the entrance. The mother asked many questions: how to apply for the bus code and how to use it; water bottles, sunscreen spray, fruit knife, red wine Can I bring a bottle opener? The two of them squatted on the ground and took out the items in the suitcase one by one and counted them. &quot;I was shocked at the time. My mother really didn&#39;t understand this aspect at all. I felt like I didn&#39;t even understand her life.&quot; Ronaldinho said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting on the subway, my mother became taciturn. When Ronaldinho explained the details of the ride to her, he just responded with a &quot;hmm&quot;. &quot;She would have a lot of questions before getting on the bus, but when she got inside, although she wanted to ask, she was too embarrassed to ask, so she didn&#39;t speak.&quot; She silently sent a text to Ronaldinho on WeChat, asking when and when she got off the bus. How to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After scanning the QR code and exiting the station, my mother opened Alipay and found that only a few yuan had been deducted. She was surprised and said that taking the subway was so much cheaper than taking a taxi. &quot;I won&#39;t take a taxi anymore. I&#39;ll take the subway from now on,&quot; my mother said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/PwLFZSK0QQPfaNPb6iyu10WhveY0jy4sUqGYM6xm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/PwLFZSK0QQPfaNPb6iyu10WhveY0jy4sUqGYM6xm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The earliest subway in the world was the London Metropolitan Subway in 1863, which has a history of 160 years ago. The picture shows the first phase of Lanzhou Rail Transit Line 2 in trial operation in June 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They don&#39;t know how to look up the map.&quot; He Jingtao said. He works at a travel agency in Guangzhou. In the two months since he created city subway guides on social media, He Jingtao has become half a &quot;traffic help blogger.&quot; He estimated that in the past two months, he had replied to more than 700 people in the comment area alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of the people who come to him for help come from other places to study or travel in Guangzhou. They don’t know that they can check the subway lines on the map because they don’t need to use mobile phone navigation in the local area. Therefore, the question he is asked the most is how to take the subway from the train station to a certain place or business district, or from one district to another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaojun is one of them. When asking He Jingtao for help, she only sent him the name of the school, but she was confused about how to take the subway from the train station to the school: She was from Huizhou, Guangdong, and was about to go to Guangzhou to study at university, but she had no idea where to go or how to get there. go. She told He Jingtao: &quot;The school admission brochure only said that you can take Line 6 to the Botanical Garden Station, and it didn&#39;t mention the distance before that at all. I took the train to Guangzhou Railway Station, and there will be no more.&quot; Next, Xiaojun asked How to get from the train station to the subway station, how to buy subway tickets, how to take the bus, etc. During the summer vacation, He Jingtao received a lot of similar requests for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many tourists traveling to Guangzhou face the problem that the place name of the destination is different from the name of the subway station. If they don’t know how to read navigation and don’t ask others for help online, they won’t know that to go to the famous scenic spot Shangxiajiu, they need to take Guangzhou Metro Line 6 and get off at the “Cultural Park” station; if they want to go to Beijing Road Pedestrian Street , you need to get off at &quot;Park Qian&quot; station. Aware of this, when He Jingtao was doing the &quot;subway tutorial&quot;, he mapped the common attractions he had compiled to each line, station and exit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ticket buying process is also a challenge. Xiao Wu, a self-media blogger, is from Baotou, Inner Mongolia. Only one city in Inner Mongolia, Hohhot, has access to subway. Once when he was on a business trip to Hohhot and taking the subway, he met a mother with her child who didn&#39;t know how to operate a ticket vending machine. There was a long queue behind her. She was also very anxious. &quot;The more anxious she was, the more mistakes she made.&quot; Xiao Wu bought the ticket for her. This little incident became the inspiration for choosing the topic. Xiao Wu made a similar short video &quot;Tutorial on taking the subway&quot;, using a first-person perspective with narration to show the whole process of taking the subway. The video wasn&#39;t complicated to create, but it gained unexpected attention, with many people saying it was &quot;very helpful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Wu remembers that the first time he took the subway was when he was traveling to Beijing after graduating from high school and took the Beijing Subway Line 1. When he walked into the subway station, he was at a loss. He didn&#39;t know where to buy a ticket. There were many people in the station. He was embarrassed to stand by and learn how others operated, and he was embarrassed to ask passers-by who were in a hurry. Although I had made a guide online in advance, when I came to the subway station alone, I was still &quot;afraid of making mistakes and showing my cowardice&quot;, so I finally asked the staff for help. He realized that many people were going through similar situations and &quot;found there was a huge demand for this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/yE7gJXewJ6pBDtDtFVhPCSJhntOn8EWVnmtyrhy3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/yE7gJXewJ6pBDtDtFVhPCSJhntOn8EWVnmtyrhy3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;According to the official account of the Ministry of Transport, in September 2023, a total of 55 cities in mainland China had 299 urban rail transit lines in operation, completing a passenger volume of 2.49 billion. The picture shows passengers waiting for subway trains at Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport in July 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;David also mentioned the issue of buying tickets. Among the requests for help he received, many people were wondering why the subway did not buy tickets first and then get on the bus like buses, high-speed rails, and airplanes. So when should the money be paid? Someone once asked him in a private message, &quot;If I need to transfer and buy a ticket at a self-service machine, can I buy the ticket directly to the terminal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the biggest difficulties for help seekers? David thought about it for a long time, and his answer was &quot;They can&#39;t think of these problems.&quot; He also felt confused: he occasionally had trouble with troublesome questions such as directions, transfers, and finding the station, but he was rarely asked about it. Most people often just reported two place names and then asked how to get there. Many people also asked in the comment area: &quot;What software did you use for the route map?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Anyone who watches the video and asks questions really has friends from dozens of cities outside the subway. They. Those who have never sat in it just don’t know anything.&quot; David said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Improving social exclusion in transportation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On social media, there are many bloggers like David and Xiao Wu who create life tutorial content and use short videos to teach people How to go to the cinema to watch a movie, stay in a hotel, send express delivery, etc. They are called &quot;social survival&quot; bloggers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the feedback they received, the most frequently mentioned word was &quot;social fear.&quot; Xiao Wu once received a private message from a girl, saying that she went to school alone in the city and her parents were working in other places. She felt a little anxious and depressed, and wanted to go to the hospital, but she had never been to a hospital alone, didn&#39;t know the process, and didn&#39;t dare to tell others, so she had to ask Xiao Wu for help. Later, Xiao Wu shot a video specifically for this purpose, &quot;How to See a Doctor in the Hospital for the First Time.&quot; Another girl said she suffered from severe depression and that her memory began to blur due to electroconvulsive therapy. Because she was afraid of being embarrassed in public, she began to be afraid to go out and stayed at home for two months. After watching Xiao Wu&#39;s video, she said: &quot;I think you not only warmed me, but also many friends who came out of the countryside for the first time and didn&#39;t know the various procedures.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let Xiao Wu The feedback that impressed me the most was &quot;Do you need to teach me about this?&quot; He was once troubled by this. After the video was posted, many people questioned him and said he was &quot;simplifying traffic&quot;: &quot;Why don&#39;t you teach me how to eat for the first time and how to eat for the first time?&quot; One drink of water?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone thinks that young people should know a lot, but they don&#39;t know everything. Today&#39;s lifestyle is too complicated.&quot; Xiaojiang said. Her content is positioned as &quot;Guidelines for College Students&quot;, teaching newly independent college students various social survival skills. The most popular ones are tutorial videos on taking the subway, high-speed rail, and airplanes, which have hundreds of thousands of likes. Before going to college, Xiaojiang had never used taxi-hailing apps. Her parents would help her call a taxi. Her parents often asked her to go out to buy meat, but she couldn&#39;t tell the difference between various types of meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most college entrance examination candidates can only worry about studying.” David once received a private message from a mother saying that her child would fly from Tianjin to Chongqing to take the art exam and asked if he could help. Arranging transportation, because the situation was complicated, David added her WeChat for step-by-step guidance. The other party asked a lot of questions, ranging from whether I could catch up with the exam in the afternoon after landing in the morning, how much transportation time I had to reserve to rush to another city after the exam, and whether I could take paints and drawing boards with me on the plane or subway. She also asked a friend in Chongqing to take care of the entire transportation of her child. &quot;She arranged the whole process. Faced with such a complicated matter, I think this mother is quite methodical.&quot; David said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She was very happy after she actually entered the pits, and I was also very happy.&quot; Ronaldinho said. Ronaldinho&#39;s mother likes to hear the &quot;beep&quot; sound when swiping the subway code when entering and exiting the station. She was very interested in everything in the subway. After leaving the station, her mother wanted to eat the grilled fish advertised on the subway. When she took the subway again in Chongqing, she was curious why the advertisement in the carriage changed to milk tea. As soon as she got out of the station, she wanted to eat. Ask Ronaldinho to take her to drink the milk tea in the subway advertisement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole trip turned into a subway trip. Once, because Ronaldinho had an appointment with a friend and needed to get off the subway in advance, he asked his mother, &quot;Can you take the subway back alone?&quot; Her mother calmly said no, &quot;no problem.&quot; During that journey, her mother took pictures of her every once in a while: &quot;Look, I still remember it.&quot; Later, Ronaldinho asked her if she got home smoothly. Her mother said that she had arrived home, and when she left the station, &quot;I really couldn&#39;t find it.&quot; She asked She asked the subway staff, who enthusiastically pointed her to the exit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Completing the task of leaving the station alone gave her mother a great confidence. She said: &quot;It turns out that taking the subway is so easy.&quot; After returning home, she showed off to her father that she took the subway today and wanted to go there in the future. When going shopping on Chunxi Road in Chengdu, her father does not need to drive her. She can take the subway by herself. Dad said, let Ronaldinho teach him too. After learning how to ride the subway, her mother recorded all the procedures that Ronaldinho taught her on her mobile phone, and even took her colleagues with her when she went shopping. Her colleagues praised her, &quot;We can&#39;t even play with these things, but you can play so smoothly.&quot; My mother was very impressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When returning from the trip, her mother asked Ronaldinho to teach her how to use 12306 to buy high-speed rail tickets. Ronaldinho sent her a high-speed rail instruction video. Later, my mother bought a high-speed rail ticket and went to Xi&#39;an to visit her old classmates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a tourism practitioner, He Jingtao can understand the importance of transportation issues. &quot;Tourism consists of five aspects: food, accommodation, travel, shopping, and entertainment, and transportation is one of them.&quot; But he admitted that he was surprised after his first subway riding tutorial became popular. “I didn’t know so many people needed it before I made it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Wang Shijun of Tongji University pointed out that in the context of rapid urbanization, some groups in urban transportation should receive more attention, that is, those with poor mobility in space and the inability to travel freely and conveniently. Destination groups, such as low-income groups, urban migrants, disabled people, elderly people who cannot use smartphones, etc. The lack of mobility in urban transportation not only leads to social differentiation and the formation of marginalized circles, but also affects all levels of social participation such as employment, schooling, and health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the possible consequences of this unfair situation is the social exclusion of transport disadvantaged groups. Professor Wang Shijun believes that the main factor leading to social exclusion in my country&#39;s urban transportation is that the current urban transportation is still in the stage of pursuing efficiency and maximizing traffic capacity, and less consideration is given to social equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, China&#39;s first underground railway, Beijing Subway Line 1, started construction. It took more than ten years from preparation to opening. In the 20th century, only four cities in mainland China, Beijing, Tianjin, Shanghai and Guangzhou, had urban rail transit lines. Entering the 21st century, opening up to the outside world and economic development have driven a boom in subway construction, because building subways can promote the flow of population resources and optimize land allocation. There is a popular slogan among the people: &quot;When the subway rings, there is a thousand taels of gold.&quot; From 2010 to 2020, China&#39;s urban rail transit construction has been booming for ten years. During these ten years, 29 cities across the country have opened subways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the subway has become an indispensable part of the daily life of many urban residents in China. Rail transit operation data for September 2023 released by the Ministry of Transport shows that 55 cities in mainland China have opened urban rail transit lines, and the subway mileage ranks first in the world. The total passenger volume in 2022 will be approximately 22.42 billion. In the new round of subway construction applications that will be launched in July 2023, more than 30 cities may apply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shijun believes that various official and private tutorials equipped with new media media are social innovation measures and are conducive to improving social exclusion in transportation, because an important aspect of transportation exclusion is the inability to obtain high-quality Transportation and travel information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this stage, the guidance services provided by the subway mainly rely on platform services and volunteers. Professor Huang Xiaoyan from the Northwest Land and Resources Research Center of Shaanxi Normal University also pointed out that the form of content, the platform on which it is released, and the target group are all important. Many transportation disadvantaged groups are limited by their own human capital and do not have access to this information. &quot;Now it may be necessary to consider both the macro and meso levels, as well as from the perspective of inclusiveness, fairness, and refined governance, in order to do this matter better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Heng recently I passed the campus recruitment interview and am preparing to do an internship in the subway system at the end of the year. He felt that it was a pity that the professional internship that was supposed to be completed in his freshman and sophomore years was delayed by the epidemic and did not start until close to graduation. Therefore, he did not know much about his future job. He only roughly knew that he needed to maintain platform order, pick up and depart trains, and serve passengers. . If he passes the internship assessment, he will become an official subway station attendant. He found that many people &quot;didn&#39;t seem to understand and didn&#39;t ask&quot; at the subway station. &quot;When you go in (you should) look for the staff first. This is their job.&quot; Zhou Heng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Uncle Chen, Zhou Heng, David, Xiao Luo, Xiao Wu, Xiao Jiang and Xiao Jun are pseudonyms)&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[什么是中国足球该有的样子？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258730]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 12:25:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In March 2015, the &quot;Overall Plan for the Reform and Development of Chinese Football&quot; was promulgated. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;For more than eight years, Chinese football has continued to move in the direction guided by the football reform plan and achieved certain results, but there are also problems such as poor implementation and deviations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former senior executives of the Chinese Football Association, many former middle-level officials and football practitioners were suspected of corruption, which caused setbacks in the reform and development of Chinese football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 16th, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held. Chinese football should take this opportunity to reinvigorate its spirit, reflect on itself, sort out the past, and illuminate the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6190e8eea893942bda1db0d9faaf0054.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6190e8eea893942bda1db0d9faaf0054.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254224&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 16, Song Kai (first from left) spoke at the conference. On the same day, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held in Beijing. The meeting elected a new executive committee, chairman and vice-chairman. Song Kai was elected as the new Chairman of the Chinese Football Association, and Sun Wen, Yuan Yongqing, Yang Xu, and Xu Jiren were elected as the Vice Chairman of the Chinese Football Association. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Jia Haocheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency reporters recently interviewed dozens of football practitioners and experts. They pointed out the current problems of Chinese football and gave insights. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Football reform shows results&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Football Association &quot;decouples&quot; and takes the first step towards the association&#39;s physicalization One step&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, the &quot;Football Sports Management Center&quot; was cancelled, and the Chinese Football Association and the State Sports General Administration were &quot;decoupled&quot; and became a corporate legal person. &quot;Two brands, one team &quot;The organizational structure became history. After the &quot;decoupling&quot;, the Chinese Football Association has autonomy in industry planning, institutional setup, personnel recruitment, foreign affairs visits, finance and market development. This also provides reference for the materialization of other sports associations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The China Youth Championship has been successfully held for two years&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Youth Championship hosted by the Ministry of Education, the State Sports General Administration and the Chinese Football Association The Youth Football League has been running for two years. Teams from schools, sports schools, club youth training echelons, and social youth training institutions can participate. This event is an important achievement of the integration of sports and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Chinese women’s football team won the Asian Cup again after 16 years&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the Chinese women’s football team won the Asian Cup for the ninth time Won the Asian Cup championship and stood on the top of Asia again after 16 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at the 2023 Women&#39;s World Cup, the performance of the Chinese women&#39;s football team highlighted the gap between them and the world&#39;s women&#39;s football team, and there is still a gap between them and the goal of &quot;women&#39;s football returning to the world&#39;s top teams&quot; in the football reform plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Chinese team won the 2023 East Asian Football Confederation U15 Men’s Football Championship, becoming a highlight of Chinese youth football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Rural football blooms with vitality&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rural football represented by Guizhou’s “Village Super League” blooms with vitality and opens up to the outside world It conveys a spiritually rich and happy emotion, and is a &quot;window to observe Chinese modernization&quot;. It is a new story of China&#39;s rural areas in the new era while promoting national fitness, realizing a comprehensive moderately prosperous society, implementing rural revitalization, and starting a new journey of Chinese modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, although my country&#39;s county football has encountered difficulties such as lack of funds, lack of venues, and lack of talent, it has generally shown a positive development trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/22b9d172e4d70b9b4f047171f6a5d378.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/22b9d172e4d70b9b4f047171f6a5d378.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254225&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This is the scene of the &quot;Village Super League&quot; finals taken at night on July 29 (drone photo). Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ou Dongqu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Football venues continue to increase&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;National sports venues in 2022 Statistical survey data shows that there are 135,900 football fields across the country, including 31,200 eleven-a-side fields, 43,200 seven-a-side fields, 61,400 five-a-side fields, and 140 beach football fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The goal of &quot;building two new national football training bases&quot; proposed in the football reform plan has been achieved - the China Football (South) Training Base and the China Football (North) Training Base were unveiled in Haikou and Dalian respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Football professional talents continue to grow&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese Football Association became the second professional-level coach in Asia in 2019 National association that certifies qualifications. According to data from the Chinese Football Association, there are currently 3 A-level coaches and lecturers in China, 11 B-level coaches and 37 C-level coaches. There are 80,000 registered coaches across the country, of which about 70,000 are C- and D-level coaches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The policy system to support the reform and development of football has initially taken shape&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the football reform plan, the &quot;Medium and Long-term Development of Chinese Football Planning (2016-2050)&quot; &quot;National Social Football Field Facilities Construction Special Action Implementation Plan (Trial)&quot; &quot;Opinions on Deepening the Integration of Sports and Education to Promote the Healthy Development of Youth&quot; &quot;China Women&#39;s Football Reform and Development Plan (2022-2035)&quot; With the release of football-related documents and supporting documents from local governments, football development will have an increasingly complete policy support system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Confusion and problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Low social recognition&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Junqing, chairman of the Inner Mongolia Football Association, said that the implementation of the football reform plan is not thorough, and there are many shortcomings in reform and development. It is common for local administrative departments to not list football as a special reform task. Inner Mongolia’s recognition of the value of football education and culture is not high enough. There is a general situation of insufficient attention to the development of football culture and ineffective measures. The industry development goals and the expectations of fans and society cannot resonate at the same frequency, and the continued deepening of football reform is restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such situations also exist in many places in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The construction of local football associations is weak&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An official of a provincial football association believes that he hopes that the Chinese Football Association will do more to reform the local football associations. Effective support. At present, football associations at all levels are top-heavy, with smaller living spaces as they go down, and they lack hematopoietic ability. Most of the city and county-level football associations have no entity and only have a brand name, making it difficult or even impossible to carry out their work. Football has a strong urban attribute. Some city football associations are strong but provincial football associations are weak. The latter&#39;s position is awkward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Junqing said that the reform of some local football management systems is struggling. Some grassroots football associations and football organizations generally face problems such as insufficient market development resources, insufficient comprehensive coordination, unstable income sources, and lack of professional talents; many grassroots football associations and football organizations generally face problems such as insufficient market development resources, insufficient comprehensive coordination, unstable income sources, and lack of professional talents. The Football Association has not formed a fixed model in terms of its own construction, work operations, and guarantee mechanisms, and is generally less enthusiastic and proactive; grassroots football development is mostly initiated by passionate football enthusiasts; administrative department support is weak; as a social organization, the Football Association is recognized The degree is generally low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The development of the professional league has encountered a bottleneck&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investor in a professional club said that if the league does not develop well, the national team is Rootless water; at present, clubs generally lack blood-forming ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, many clubs still have serious problems with wage arrears and historical debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Pei, a professor at the School of Sports Science at South China Normal University, said that many football clubs have become platforms for the exchange of public resources (mainly land). When public resources cannot be obtained through clubs, some parent companies decisively get rid of this burden. This is also the main reason why dozens of football clubs have disbanded or withdrawn in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by &quot;Jinyuan Football&quot; and the transfer market has been dominated by several brokerage companies and individuals for a long time, player prices have been artificially high for a long time. The various systems for football agents, including registration, are not perfect enough, which to a certain extent contributes to the &quot;false fire&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The utility of youth football still exists&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Junqing believes that young players are “prematurely specialized” and training goals Problems such as &quot;one-dimensionality&quot;, &quot;adultization&quot; of training and management models, and emphasis on competition and neglect of techniques and tactics still exist; &quot;championshipism&quot; still dominates youth competitions, leading to the contradiction between &quot;leaders want results and organizations want talents.&quot; There are occurrences; the integration of sports and education is insufficient, and the connection between campus football and professional youth training systems is not smooth; most clubs do not have a complete youth training echelon, and there are gaps in football talent training; there is a large gap in grassroots football talent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Allen Renard, director of youth training at Allen Football Academy, talked about three issues: First, the phenomenon of youth training clubs poaching from each other is rampant, and some even poach people across the country, which damages the players’ enlightenment. Club Benefits. Second, most of the competitions organized by football associations at all levels are tournament-based, and there is a lack of high-quality competitions. Third, there are few venues suitable for social youth training clubs, the procedures for building new venues are cumbersome, and the operating costs are high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investor in a professional club said that the youth calendar is confusing and repetitive, disrupting children’s training, learning, and life rhythms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the youth training compensation mechanism and joint mechanism compensation are not implemented well, which damages the interests of youth training institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Pei said that going to college is the ultimate goal of many football teenagers. They achieve this goal by obtaining a grade certificate, but their football careers often end after obtaining the certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Shijun, a physical education teacher at Wansongyuan Road Primary School in Wuhan City, said that there is a youth league at the national level, but the grassroots competition system still needs to be improved; children who play football cannot keep up with their cultural studies, and children who study have no time. To play football, it is urgent to improve the talent training system; due to the lack of a coaching training system, although many students from normal sports departments participate in campus football promotion after graduation, they do not have the qualifications of football coaches, and their knowledge structure cannot meet the needs of campus football development; due to the lack of fixed In competitions, referees generally lack a training platform and have low standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ec24a71b0a92685fcda5da59eaf1f969.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ec24a71b0a92685fcda5da59eaf1f969.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254227&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This is July 10, 2022, in the first China Youth Football League (Zhejiang Division) Boys’ Primary School U11 Group Competition , Yang Haoyuan (second from right), a young player from Hangzhou Pujia Primary School, and Zhao Yirui (first from right), a young player from Zhejiang Ostrich Football Club, fight for the ball. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Jiang Han&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Chinese men’s football team has missed the World Cup for five consecutive years&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, The performance of the Chinese men&#39;s football team is disappointing and they have missed the World Cup for five consecutive years. Their ability, style and performance are far from the people&#39;s expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Corruption sounds an alarm bell&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many practitioners are suspected of corruption, which sounds an alarm bell for Chinese football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a football association in a northern city believes that Chinese football is lacking or imperfect in employment mechanisms, evaluation mechanisms, supervision mechanisms, etc., causing chaos in the industry and providing space for corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;What football should be like&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Establishing correct football values ​​&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Football professionals say that the overall football values ​​​​of Chinese society are lagging behind. They often only recognize the honor value brought by it in international competitions and lack sufficient understanding of its overall value. There is insufficient understanding of the long-term, systematic and arduous nature of football, resulting in some short-sighted behaviors. Competitive performance is actually the objective result of football developing to a certain stage. Through the educational function of football, people&#39;s all-round development can be improved. Young people&#39;s participation in football should not be for the purpose of assessing grades and gaining points for higher education, but to enjoy fun and achieve the purpose of cultivating people through happy education. Only with correct values ​​can we build correct rule systems and other systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Chinese Football Association has established a good system&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Leishi, executive member of the Guangxi Football Association, said that the Chinese Football Association should clarify its own Our positioning is to provide good football services and do basic work, such as improving the league, youth training, coaching, refereeing and other systems. For example, he said that although there are now Chinese Super League, Chinese League One, Chinese League Two, Chinese Champions League and other leagues, the provincial, city and county league system is not perfect. Football powers have as many as a dozen or even dozens of leagues, which form the basis for sustainable development. ; At the same time, the Chinese Football Association should be more down-to-earth, establish a working system with the Football Associations at all levels, and have good business connections; the Football Association&#39;s departmental settings should be scientific; decentralize power and better play the role of the executive committee and member associations; Football Association affairs at all levels It should be transparent and open. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/7580afae56cc4e3400db8366b860feec.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/7580afae56cc4e3400db8366b860feec.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254226&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On July 7, Tianjin Jinmen Tigers fans cheered for the team. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Sun Fanyue&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for how to connect the Chinese Champions League with the amateur league, Huang Shenghua, chairman of Shaanxi Changan United Football Club, said that a &quot;double pyramid&quot; that is independent of each other but connected in an orderly manner can be considered system, that is, professional leagues, semi-professional leagues, and amateur leagues each construct independent league pyramid systems, and the two systems are connected through event results and access regulations. On the one hand, the &quot;double pyramid&quot; system gives cities, clubs, investors, and players interested in the development of professional football an upward path; on the other hand, amateur leagues with independent &quot;pyramid&quot; systems pass competition rules, team review, etc. Prevent too many professional, semi-professional players and professional club-related teams from sinking into the amateur league, prevent too many teams from investing huge sums in order to be promoted to the Chinese Champions League, and avoid affecting the enthusiasm of ordinary football fans to participate in the amateur league. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Improving the construction of national teams at all levels&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professionals said that the selection mechanism of team members should be improved to select players to serve the country Excellent players with strong aspirations, first-class will and quality, good ability and style, and reasonable age structure will enter the national team; build the national team talent pool and strengthen the scientific selection; unify the technical and tactical play styles of the national teams at all levels; establish a training monitoring and evaluation system to achieve National team members at all levels train in clubs and conduct daily monitoring and evaluation of competition data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Increase high-quality youth competitions&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Shijun said that the construction of grassroots competition systems such as city and district levels should be strengthened. For example, the &quot;Wan Chao League&quot; in Jianghan District, Wuhan City runs throughout the school year and has become a platform for the growth of young players. Through school district integration, Wansongyuan Road Primary School will share its space and teachers with other primary schools in the district. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also suggested exploring a training model in which students from physical education departments in normal colleges and universities obtain coaching qualifications (grassroots, D, C and even B levels) during college, which will partially solve the problem of campus football teachers; vigorously train students referee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reynard suggested that football associations at all levels introduce a third-party event operation system, encourage regional youth events to be graded and held continuously throughout the year, and provide venue policies and financial support for social forces to participate in youth training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of youth training compensation, professionals suggest that when conditions are ripe, a third-party account can be set up and relevant rules can be established. Transfers can only be made after completing the corresponding training compensation and joint mechanism compensation, so as to improve youth training. Institutional enthusiasm. At this stage, supervision is being strengthened and clubs that default on youth training compensation payments will be punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Improve the mechanism for the integration of sports and education&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the integration of sports and education, Li Pei suggested: First, clarify the sports and education department responsibilities and rights. The education department is responsible for popularizing youth football in the compulsory education stage, and the sports department is responsible for further improving competitive levels. The second is to establish a supervision and evaluation mechanism. The education department needs to improve the evaluation indicator system for various campus football projects, strengthen the construction of internal supervision and evaluation mechanisms, strengthen the audit and performance evaluation of special funds, allocate resources based on the evaluation results, and supervise and rectify or disqualify units that fail the evaluation. The Chinese Football Association has the power to assess the levels of referees, coaches and players. It must not only strengthen internal supervision and evaluation, but also introduce a third-party supervision and evaluation mechanism. The sports department should establish a database of youth coaches, referees and team members, conduct supervision and evaluation based on competition performance, and serve as the basis for talent selection and promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Anti-corruption should be institutionalized&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the corruption phenomenon in Chinese football, Zhou Ming, a partner at Beijing Weiheng Law Firm, said , the decision-making mechanism of the Chinese Football Association must be more transparent, and at the same time introduce an external supervision and restriction mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zhenghang, a lawyer at Jingsh Law Firm, suggested strengthening the prevention mechanism before the incident and the rapid rectification mechanism after the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that it is recommended that each club establish an internal supervision system. From a legal perspective, it is an anti-fraud mechanism in corporate compliance construction. Fraud here mainly refers to counterfeit gambling matters. The system construction includes the club&#39;s internal reporting mechanism, internal review mechanism and post-verification handling and reporting mechanism. It is also recommended that the Chinese Football Association establish a match-fixing supervision and inspection mechanism to conduct independent investigations and accountability for incidents that may be suspected of match-fixing discovered during complaints and reports or through arbitration committees, disciplinary committee hearings, penalties, etc., and to cooperate with the internal supervision of the above-mentioned clubs. The system is connected, and suspected crimes are directly transferred to the relevant investigation departments for further processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people in the legal profession said that the Chinese Football Association should establish a normalized cooperation mechanism with the Ministry of Public Security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The chairman of the Football Association of a southern province said that football reform should be carried out unswervingly and in accordance with the overall direction, requirements and path proposed by the football reform plan. If it can be solidly advanced and all departments can coordinate well, how can we What if I can’t do it well? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都2岁女童遭恶犬咬伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258847]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;A 2-year-old girl in Chongzhou, Chengdu was attacked by a vicious dog. She suffered multiple bites all over her body, contusion and laceration of her right kidney, and fractured ribs on her right side. . It is reported that the black Rottweiler that injured someone has been captured and is a banned dog in many cities. The dog owner, Tang, has been criminally detained by Chongzhou police in accordance with the law.</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>