<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国庆长假火车票正式开抢，你有多久没坐过绿皮火车了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256725]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 15, train tickets will officially go on sale on the first day of the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday. This year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday runs from September 29 to October 6. According to the 15-day pre-sale period for railway tickets, return train tickets for the last day of the holiday will go on sale on September 22. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While tickets to many popular destinations are hard to come by, there are also many trains and lines that are quietly withdrawing from the public eye. With the development of high-speed rail networks, the popularity of private cars and the expansion of air routes, regular-speed lines have ceased operations in recent years. For example, at Shantou Station in eastern Guangdong Province, all regular-speed trains have been suspended. The surrounding Jieyang South Station and Chaozhou Station have already closed their passenger transportation services, which have nothing to do with passenger travel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In neighboring Japan, this phenomenon is even more obvious. With the aging of the population and the outflow of people to big cities, a large number of local railway lines in Japan have been abandoned and stations removed. Not only is the travel of local residents in towns and villages affected, but many beautiful scenery along the railway are also difficult to see again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How long has it been since you took a green train? Are you interested in trying it out during your vacation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“一带一路”十年，国税总局局长谈如何共同优化税收营商环境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256714]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/ZVGm5aPxEWJIMD9smLx05hWAVWPHbsYSc1b7XvmE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ZVGm5aPxEWJIMD9smLx05hWAVWPHbsY Sc1b7XvmE. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation of China, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a keynote speech. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the State Administration of Taxation that on the afternoon of September 11, 2023, Beijing time , Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation of China, attended the opening ceremony of the 4th “Belt and Road” Tax Collection and Administration Cooperation Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The forum was held in Tbilisi, the capital of Georgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Members attending the forum include heads of tax departments from 32 countries and regions, representatives of 10 international organizations such as the United Nations and the International Monetary Fund, and representatives of some multinational enterprises, totaling more than 300 people. During the three-day forum, participating parties conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as optimizing the overall planning of the tax business environment, tax rule of law and transparency of tax collection and administration, reducing tax burdens, simplifying tax compliance, and building a dispute resolution mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun introduced in his keynote speech that in recent years, China&#39;s tax authorities have continued to optimize the tax business environment, and have carried out the &quot;Spring Breeze Action for Tax Convenience&quot; for ten consecutive years, and have launched a total of 620 tax service measures. Gradually realize that 96% of tax matters and 99% of tax declarations can be processed &quot;online&quot; or &quot;handheld&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of implementing a series of preferential tax and fee policies, Wang Jun said that from 2018 to 2022 alone, the cumulative number of new tax cuts and fee reductions and tax rebates and fee deferrals exceeded 11 trillion yuan, becoming one of the policies to help enterprises bail out. It is the policy measure with the most “gold content” and the most obvious benefits for business entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun also mentioned that China’s tax authorities continue to improve the new tax supervision system based on “credit + risk” to maximize supervision efficiency, minimize supervision costs, and minimize interference to business entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, China’s tax authorities are deeply involved in the formulation and adjustment of international tax rules, providing multiple cross-border tax processing channels for cross-border investment and trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to optimize the tax business environment and jointly build the &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot;, Wang Jun proposed three initiatives: First, embrace the digital trend, accelerate the in-depth integration of digital technology and tax business, and further promote internal and external tax-related data Gather China Unicom and organically connect online and offline to improve precise collection and management capabilities; second, give full play to and expand the role of taxation functions, which can not only provide all-round, full-cycle, and full-chain tax support for technological innovation, but also create new business formats, The tax business environment for the development and expansion of the new model; third, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; tax collection and administration cooperation mechanism will play a &quot;bridge and link&quot; role to help the world economy recover for the better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;The “Belt and Road” tax collection and administration cooperation mechanism was initiated by China and was established in April 2019. It currently has 36 members and 30 observers and has become an important influence under the “Belt and Road” initiative. A powerful multilateral tax cooperation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun said that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has gone through ten years. The holding of successive &quot;Belt and Road&quot; tax collection and administration cooperation forums has effectively promoted the tax authorities of various countries to deepen exchanges and mutual learning and continuously improve transparency. , efficient, stable and predictable tax cooperation mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[丰子恺：无宠不惊过一生丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 10:45:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家统计局：8月份各线城市商品住宅销售价格同比有涨有降]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256720]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 09:54:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In August 2023, the sales price of commercial housing in 70 large and medium-sized cities decreased. The number of cities increased, and the number of cities in all tiers decreased. The sales price of commercial residential buildings decreased month-on-month, but increased and decreased year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1. The sales price of commercial housing in first-tier cities dropped month-on-month&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of new commercial housing, in August, the sales price of newly-built commercial housing in first-tier cities decreased by month-on-month. Last month was flat but fell by 0.2%, with Beijing, Guangzhou and Shenzhen falling by 0.2%, 0.3% and 0.6% respectively month-on-month, and Shanghai rising by 0.1% month-on-month; the sales price of newly built commercial residential buildings in second-tier cities fell by 0.2% month-on-month, the same as last month. ; The sales price of newly built commercial residential buildings in third-tier cities fell by 0.4% month-on-month, and the decline expanded by 0.1 percentage points from the previous month. From the perspective of second-hand housing, in August, the sales price of second-hand housing in first-tier cities fell by 0.2% month-on-month, and the decline narrowed 0.6 percentage points from the previous month. Among them, Beijing increased by 0.4% month-on-month, and Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen decreased by 0.3%, 0.6%, and 0.6% month-on-month respectively. 0.2%; second-hand residential sales prices in second- and third-tier cities fell by 0.5% and 0.4% month-on-month respectively, with the same decline rates as last month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, among the 70 large and medium-sized cities, the sales prices of newly built commercial housing and second-hand housing increased month-on-month in 17 and 3 respectively, a decrease of 3 from the previous month. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;2. Sales prices of commercial residential buildings in first-tier cities increased and decreased year-on-year&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August, the sales prices of newly built commercial residential buildings in first-tier cities increased by 0.6% year-on-year. The increase dropped by 0.4 percentage points from the previous month; the sales price of newly built commercial housing in second-tier cities increased by 0.3% year-on-year, an increase of 0.1 percentage point from the previous month; the sales price of newly-built commercial housing in third-tier cities fell by 1.4% year-on-year, and the decline narrowed 0.1 percentage point from the previous month. percentage point. In August, the sales price of second-hand housing in first- and second-tier cities fell by 1.6% and 3.0% year-on-year respectively, and the decline was 0.2 and 0.3 percentage points higher than the previous month. The sales price of second-hand housing in third-tier cities fell by 3.5% year-on-year, and the decline was the same as last month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, among 70 large and medium-sized cities, the sales prices of newly built commercial housing and second-hand housing increased year-on-year in 25 and 3 cities respectively, a decrease of 1 and 2 respectively from the previous month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Note: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Real estate price statistics of 70 large and medium-sized cities are divided into first, second and third tier cities: first tier cities refer to Beijing and Shanghai , Guangzhou, Shenzhen and other 4 cities; second-tier cities refer to Tianjin, Shijiazhuang, Taiyuan, Hohhot, Shenyang, Dalian, Changchun, Harbin, Nanjing, Hangzhou, Ningbo, Hefei, Fuzhou, Xiamen, Nanchang, Jinan, Qingdao, Zhengzhou, Wuhan, 31 cities including Changsha, Nanning, Haikou, Chongqing, Chengdu, Guiyang, Kunming, Xi&#39;an, Lanzhou, Xining, Yinchuan, and Urumqi; third-tier cities refer to Tangshan, Qinhuangdao, Baotou, Dandong, Jinzhou, Jilin, Mudanjiang, Wuxi, Xuzhou, and Yangzhou , Wenzhou, Jinhua, Bengbu, Anqing, Quanzhou, Jiujiang, Ganzhou, Yantai, Jining, Luoyang, Pingdingshan, Yichang, Xiangyang, Yueyang, Changde, Shaoguan, Zhanjiang, Huizhou, Guilin, Beihai, Sanya, Luzhou, Nanchong, Zunyi, Dali Waiting for 35 cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“网红”老人们，把沉重的生死问题拍成段子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256687]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[子女对父母谋夺财产、实施家暴岂止是“不孝”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When many people mention domestic violence, they will immediately think of the grievances between husband and wife. The typical image of a domestically violent man created by Feng Yuanzheng in the TV series has endured for a long time, and it has also made people regard &quot;domestic violence&quot; as a &quot;patent&quot; for men. But in addition to beating people hard, life also teaches people very patiently to grasp those seemingly unpopular facts - for example, domestic violence does not only occur between husband and wife, but also occurs between men and women, parents and children, and women against men. and children to parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Statistics from the All-China Women&#39;s Federation and the National Bureau of Statistics in 2018 show that 22.9% of women and 19.9% ​​of men in China have suffered domestic violence. It shows that there is not much difference between men and women experiencing domestic violence, which is very different from a certain stereotype. As for domestic violence by children against their parents, it is relatively hidden and is generally regarded as a family scandal. Parents who suffer domestic violence would rather swallow their anger than &quot;ruin&quot; their children&#39;s future. This is pitiful for parents in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Guangdong Provincial Higher People’s Court announced a typical case of domestic violence against an elderly man by his daughter because he was unwilling to rent out his house. In this case, Feng and Liu had a mother-daughter relationship. In early 2020, Liu forced Feng to move into his home in order to rent out Feng&#39;s house. After that, Liu went to Feng&#39;s residence many times to threaten, abuse and intimidate him, smashed items in the house with a hammer, and asked a moving company to remove Feng&#39;s appliances and furniture and change the door locks, making Feng unable to enter. residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng applied to the court for a personal safety protection order, and sued Liu to return the items and restore Feng’s possession of the house. The People&#39;s Court of Xiangzhou District, Zhuhai City believed that the evidence submitted by Feng showed that he was indeed in danger of domestic violence, so it made a ruling the day after Feng applied for a habeas corpus order, prohibiting Liu from beating or threatening Feng. For violent behavior, Liu is prohibited from harassing, following, and contacting Feng, and Liu is prohibited from entering Feng&#39;s residence. Subsequently, the court presided over the mediation between the two parties, and Liu voluntarily vacated Feng&#39;s house within a time limit, returned Feng&#39;s belongings, and did not interfere with Feng&#39;s normal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I saw the results, I couldn&#39;t help but sigh. After suffering inhuman treatment, the last thing a mother can do is the so-called &quot;reconciliation.&quot; How can the pain involved be covered by a piece of paper? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the private sector, it is not uncommon for children to force the elderly to give up their houses and intervene in the disposal of the houses in advance to lock in their &quot;deserved inheritance&quot;. In the eyes of these children, it is almost destined that their parents&#39; property will belong to them sooner or later. Therefore, once they go to war to control the possession of the property, it cannot be regarded as unfilial and rebellious. On the contrary, this is a kind of &quot;smartness&quot; that is carefully laid out for its own &quot;rights&quot;. I believe this is what this daughter thinks. If the mother had not been forced to litigate, and if the court had not supported her, the outcome of this matter would have been even worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, people have been easily confused by the interdependent and unbreakable relationship between parents and children, and thus are unwilling to connect the dark things in human nature with this relationship, even if there is a strong conflict of interest between parents and children. , is also likely to be regarded as a common household chore by the world. When I was young, I witnessed other people’s sons and daughters-in-law rushing into my old mother’s house with tools, quarreling and fighting. The old mother screamed in agony, unable to do anything. The villagers who were watching only regarded this matter as &quot;a slap in the face that can&#39;t make a difference&quot;, and had no idea that this behavior was a kind of domestic violence from below to above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, domestic violence between parents and children also involves &quot;top versus bottom&quot;. It is common for parents to abuse their children for a long time, and to severely control their children&#39;s bodies and minds even when they grow up. Those who are accused often defend themselves under the guise of &quot;disciplining children.&quot; This is also confusing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why people &quot;cannot see&quot; domestic violence between parents and children, so that they turn a blind eye to it, is fundamentally because they trust too much in the ethical and moral foundation of the parent-child relationship, or they look at the parent-child relationship through filters. The contradictions in the family relationship are gradually resolved by trying to minimize the big problems and look for the best in everything. However, the unwillingness to admit the &quot;evil&quot; in the parent-child relationship and the unwillingness to expose the &quot;family scandal&quot; between parents and children has caused us to lose many opportunities to say &quot;no&quot; loudly and intervene in such domestic violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only from the perspective of rights can we better understand the confusion of such views in the past, and can we suddenly understand the harmfulness of &quot;parent-child domestic violence&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, the media reported such a case: The Procuratorate of Qiubei County, Yunnan Province accused Wang of being held criminally responsible for intentional homicide. However, it also pointed out that the victim had often beaten his parents in recent years. In view of the fact that the victim had It is a serious fault, and Wang has the circumstances of surrendering. The circumstances are relatively minor. It is recommended that the court impose a prison sentence of not less than 3 years but not more than 5 years. The Houqiubei County Court sentenced Wang to 3 years in prison, suspended for 5 years, for intentional homicide. The key word in this case is of course &quot;domestic violence&quot;. The domestic violence against the parents by the &quot;rebellious son&quot; has reached the point where the victim cannot bear it, which is the root cause of the tragedy of murder. Murderers should be punished by law, and the lessons of domestic violence should be remembered by the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An unavoidable question is why some children are so cruel to their parents that they are willing to violate ethics and morals and be nailed to the pillar of shame? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are indeed many reasons. Many parents dote on their children so much that they develop domineering and extreme personalities. If they are not satisfied, they will have violent outbursts, causing &quot;backlash&quot;. But this is only a general reason, and we can find the &quot;inducers&quot; of &quot;parent-child domestic violence&quot; from the details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the case of a daughter’s domestic violence against her mother as an example. The daughter’s coveting of her mother’s property was the ideological beginning of a series of extreme behaviors. According to the daughter&#39;s principles of dealing with things, if the mother obediently obeys without any resistance, domestic violence is unlikely to occur. But this kind of calculation is not in line with the righteousness of the world, nor is it in line with legal principles. By extension, using various decisive means to make the elderly lose control of their residence is domestic violence with deprivation of property as its core feature. This is where special attention should be paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, one of the acts of domestic violence committed by children against their parents is on the physical and mental levels. It is not just forcing parents into a corner over property issues, but also forcing them into a desperate situation. Such domestic violence is of a nature Especially bad. And this kind of thing is often regarded by some people as a way to make a fortune. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, in November 2021, such a case occurred in Nanjing: In order to drive their mother out of the house and monopolize the property they lived with, the couple actually staged a &quot;three knots and two divorces&quot; to transfer property. Drama, but fortunately the court ruled that the transfer of property was invalid. The judge emphasized that children have the obligation to support their parents and should ensure that their mothers have a place to live when they grow old. This is a simple truth, but it has been trampled on by some greedy children. Parents who have lost their financial security are like floating ducks in the world. You can imagine the physical and mental shock they suffered. This kind of domestic violence is even worse than physical violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comprehensively sort out the types of domestic violence, be more rational and keenly aware of the characteristics, harmfulness and deception of &quot;parent-child domestic violence&quot;, and curb this type of domestic violence in accordance with the law. This is to reshape the parent-child relationship and advocate A major premise of ethical order. We should not only show goodwill to the &quot;harbor&quot; in life, but also be vigilant about the truth about domestic violence that is obscured by routines, excuses and illusions. Only in this way can we truly create a normal atmosphere for ourselves and our family, without falling into a trap under the appearance of warm relationships and self-sacrifice, or even making ourselves a &quot;price&quot; in the calculations behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中科院博士讲述缅甸遭遇：因高薪被骗，坦言与学历无必然关系]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a doctor from the Chinese Academy of Sciences who was rescued a year after being deceived into Myanmar appeared and once again attracted attention. Nandu and N video reporters talked with the person involved, Mr. Zhang, and listened to his account of the twists and turns in the past year. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Mr. Zhang, last year, he faced financial difficulties due to the illness of his parents and girlfriend, so he chose to go abroad to seek job opportunities, but was lured to a fraud park in Myanmar by the so-called &quot;job in Thailand&quot;. They worked 18 hours a day under strict supervision, were punished corporally if they failed to complete their performance, and were severely beaten if they were found to have &quot;leaked secrets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The news was spread online and received continued attention. Finally, with the efforts of many parties, Mr. Zhang was able to return to China. In his view, being defrauded has nothing to do with academic qualifications or experience. &quot;Fraud takes advantage of the weaknesses of human nature, and anyone can become a victim.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0429ed8e0e9d65c317ac8f76739cd70c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;490&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0429ed8e0e9d65c317ac8f76739cd70c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250752&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Zhang. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Targeted” because of his good English and broad knowledge&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“PhD from Chinese Academy of Sciences” and “Myanmar Fraud Group” are two things that were originally difficult to connect. Words make Mr. Zhang’s experience incredible. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether a person is deceived actually has nothing to do with academic qualifications or experience. Scams take advantage of the weaknesses of human nature, and anyone can become a victim.&quot; Mr. Zhang told a Nandu reporter . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he set out to go abroad in August last year, he expected that his new job abroad would alleviate the financial pressure he was facing at the time. Previously, he worked at the Lushan Botanical Garden of the Chinese Academy of Sciences in Jiangxi. At that time, his parents I have a chronic illness and my girlfriend has early-stage breast cancer. This caused him to face great financial difficulties and had to look for new job opportunities. However, finding a job in China was not smooth. More than ten resumes came to nothing. &quot;He had no choice but to look for job opportunities abroad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled to Nandu reporters that he first learned through an intermediary online that a company in Singapore was recruiting customer service staff and promised a monthly salary of 15,000 yuan. At this time, the overall process seemed to him relatively formal. However, due to the impact of the epidemic at that time, Singapore&#39;s entry process was relatively complicated, and since he had not been vaccinated, the visa application was delayed, which delayed him for more than a month. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the trap has been set at this time, waiting for him to enter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang told Nandu reporters that the recruiter told him that their company has a branch in Thailand and suggested that he go to Thailand to work for a period of time and wait until Singapore’s immigration policy is relaxed before transferring there. Mr. Zhang agreed. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After visiting several cities such as Hong Kong and Bangkok, in mid-August last year, he arrived in Mae Sot, Thailand, a small town on the border of Thailand and Myanmar, across the river from Myanmar. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“They never mentioned the word ‘Myanmar’ to me from beginning to end.” Mr. Zhang recalled to the Nandu reporter that the process was very short, only ten or twenty minutes. When they realized something was wrong, they had already taken them to the Myanmar side.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/c85dbc0d58ca784422614c900a7d7580.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;456&quot; height=&quot;482&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/c85dbc0d58ca784422614c900a7d7580.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250753&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Zhang introduced his experience of being deceived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, he sent a message telling his girlfriend that he did not want to stay in Myanmar because it was not safe, but he had lost his personal freedom. He also tried to escape, but found himself heavily guarded and had to give up. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that while the news on the Internet that &quot;a doctor from the Chinese Academy of Sciences was deceived into Myanmar for a year&quot; has attracted widespread attention, at the same time, three men from Guizhou have repeatedly tried to smuggle themselves into Myanmar for telecommunications network Fraudulent activities, but due to low literacy and inability to type, the fraud company refused to accept them. Not only did they not make a fortune, but they were also sentenced to prison terms. Cases were also exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang analyzed to Nandu reporters that the main reasons why he was targeted by the fraud gang include his advantage in English and his broad knowledge. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Being beaten to the point of being unable to stand for &quot;leaking secrets&quot;&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the fraud in Myawaddy in eastern Myanmar mainly targets overseas groups. The one is &quot;European and American disk&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My job is to disguise myself as a woman and chat with the deceived through social software.” Mr. Zhang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Nandu reporters that there will be a &quot;salary&quot; in the first month after entering the fraud park, about 6,000 yuan. After that, the income will depend on performance commissions. If there is no performance, you will not get any money, and you will have to Accept corporal punishment. The corporal punishment includes running, push-ups, planks, frog jumps, squats, etc. If you do it continuously for more than an hour, someone will supervise you with a wooden stick from behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang revealed that he has never made money through performance. &quot;This situation is very common, and most people may not make any money in a year.&quot; Because now people are aware of the scams, fewer and fewer people are being deceived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The park is very taboo about &quot;leaking secrets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang said that the park allows him to call his family at intervals. &quot;Because someone was monitoring my phone calls, I couldn&#39;t tell the truth. In many cases, people who defrauded the park would deliberately threaten me to reveal false information to the outside world.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for a long time, , the family did not know his true situation. Later, Mr. Zhang discovered that he could install a mobile phone simulator on his computer and send emails in this way to get rid of surveillance, so he sent an email to his family in China asking for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On another occasion, he secretly contacted his girlfriend through chat software and talked about the company&#39;s fraud model, rules and regulations, corporal punishment methods, etc. &quot;Usually I delete the chat history after chatting with her, but that time I was negligent and didn&#39;t delete it in time. People from the company found out, which led to my arrest later.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang still remembers that they The people were beaten with wooden sticks as thick as shins. &quot;I was beaten until I couldn&#39;t stand normally at all, and I could only lie on my stomach when sleeping.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was detained from the end of April to the beginning of August this year. In the &quot;Army Station&quot;, it is similar to a private prison in the park. Later, he was moved to a dormitory, where he usually could only eat one meal a day, and it was irregular. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He once sent an email to tell his family that he was being monitored for 18 hours a day and that his escape was far away. He hoped that his family could rescue him. The park required a transfer of 120,000 yuan before releasing her, but after the transfer, her family found that their account had been frozen and they could not make the transfer. In early August, he was transferred to another company in the same group. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;After attracting attention, he became a &quot;hot potato&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Later, Mr. Zhang’s family chose to call the police . The news that &quot;it has been a year since a doctor from the Chinese Academy of Sciences was deceived into traveling to Myanmar&quot; was also disclosed and continues to attract attention. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After the media reports, many people in the park knew about me. The company leaders thought that keeping me in the park would bring them trouble, so they decided to lower the ransom.” Mr. Zhang He told Nandu reporters that his family contacted Aaron, a volunteer who helped with the rescue, and negotiated with the park through him to finally determine the ransom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Mr. Zhang’s family paid the ransom of 59,000 yuan, he was able to regain his freedom. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, before leaving the park, he was required to acknowledge that he entered the park voluntarily by signing, videotaping, etc. &quot;I was eager to leave the park at that time, so I could only pretend to agree to their request.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 26, the Chinese Embassy in Thailand reported in the early morning that on the evening of the 24th, the Thai police successfully found Zhang. The Embassy in Thailand and the Consulate General in Chiang Mai are closely coordinating with the Thai police to arrange for his return to the country as soon as possible. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/16ac446e4ff21da9b26edf828295a912.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/16ac446e4ff21da9b26edf828295a912.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250751&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Zhang appeared on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than ten days, no relevant news came out. Late at night on September 11, Mr. Zhang spoke out on Weibo and introduced the current situation, which once again attracted attention. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He revealed that he returned to China on September 5 and has been unable to publish due to cooperation with the investigation and personal illness and discomfort. In line with his responsible attitude towards the public and himself, he will explain some issues that everyone is concerned about in the future. The next morning, he posted again describing his encounter in more detail. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang revealed to Nandu reporters, &quot;The police investigated me on September 5, and I also provided them with the information that I was deceived.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; From the time the incident unfolded to the time I returned to China, I overcame numerous obstacles, and my rescue was the result of joint efforts from many parties.&quot; He said that this would not have been possible without the efforts of relatives and friends, including the assistance of official departments such as the police and the embassy, ​​as well as the private sector. The support of volunteers and media reports also played a very important role. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talking about the current situation, Mr. Zhang said that his parents&#39; condition is relatively stable, and his girlfriend has recovered from early-stage breast cancer. He hopes to do his best to repay society in the future and prevent more people from falling into the same trap. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Recognize your own character weaknesses”&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since this year, cases of Chinese people being deceived into Myanmar fraud gangs have been exposed frequently. Recently, Nandu reported on the case of Mr. Chen, a 20-year-old Chaoshan boy who was deceived into Myanmar and then rescued. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that with the support of the police, many Chaoshan chambers of commerce participated in the rescue operation. Zheng Chucheng, president of the Harbin Guangdong Chaoshan Chamber of Commerce, told Nandu reporters that the rescue work was not easy, just like finding a needle in a haystack. Another person familiar with the matter said that to carry out rescue work, it is necessary to first determine the location of the victim. In this process, the victim&#39;s active self-rescue played a big role. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0a43abf7ea56bcb259d265379813e61f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;508&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0a43abf7ea56bcb259d265379813e61f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250754&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Chen was rescued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After losing contact for many days, Mr. Chen privately found an opportunity to send a message to his family, describing in detail the environment surrounding the fraud park where he was at that time. The personnel involved in the rescue quickly determined their location by integrating information from multiple parties, which provided important guarantee for subsequent rescue work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Zhang also told Nandu reporters that it is very important to ensure one&#39;s own safety during the process of self-rescue, especially to ensure that the distress signal is not discovered by people in the fraud park. &quot;I asked for help from the outside world through email, which is less likely to be exposed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the many cases of being deceived into Myanmar, Zheng Chucheng reminded, &quot;The pie will not fall from the sky. Looking for a job People should not believe in the temptation of high salaries, and business people should not fall into the trap of huge profits.&quot; The above-mentioned insider also said, &quot;Believe in the police&#39;s anti-fraud propaganda, support anti-fraud work, study hard, work hard, and don&#39;t believe in the so-called &quot;High salary.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To avoid being deceived, on the one hand, you must recognize your own character weaknesses, and on the other hand, you must often learn and update your anti-fraud knowledge.&quot; Now that he has finally escaped, Mr. Zhang has a lot of emotions. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All parties are also intensifying their efforts to combat fraud gangs in Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that in response to the current serious and complex situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Ministry of Public Security has deployed public security agencies in Yunnan and other places to continue to promote crackdowns. Recently, the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau of Yunnan Province has actively carried out border police cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar. 1,207 fraud suspects from northern Myanmar were successfully handed over to us, including 41 fugitives online. This is after the previous capture of 269 fraud suspects from northern Myanmar. After the suspect was arrested, the crackdown achieved another major result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Public Security stated that the public security agencies will further strengthen border police law enforcement cooperation and continue to organize and carry out operations to crack down on telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar. Their determination and intensity will not decrease and they will continue to crack down on fraud. dens, arrest those involved in fraud in accordance with the law, and resolutely curb the high incidence of such crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Mr. Zhang, who has returned to China, told Nandu reporters that working as a journal editor or science popularizer is his interest and specialty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I hope that through this kind of work, I can make some contribution to society.” He said. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多地突发“雷暴哮喘”：半小时内发作，蒿属花粉或为元凶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:55:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[央行年内二度降准：释放中长期流动性超5000亿，效果将脉冲式持续释放]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256718]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 23:00:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/FNOA6veUr0UsCJ1nZEs8PhzPpQl XyAcy20uy4Nsu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 14, 2023, the People&#39;s Bank of China issued an announcement and decided to lower the deposit reserve ratio of financial institutions by 0.25 percentage points on September 15, 2023 (excluding the implemented 5% reserve ratio for financial institutions). This is the second time in 2023 that the central bank has lowered the deposit reserve ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that with the successive efforts of fiscal, taxation, real estate and monetary policies, market expectations have improved significantly in the near future, and the potential for economic stabilization is increasing, but the flexibility of economic recovery still needs to be enhanced. . This RRR cut will release more than 500 billion yuan of medium- and long-term liquidity to the market, further releasing a positive signal to protect the market and supporting the stabilization of the economy and the stability of liquidity in the financial system. This is another important benefit that reflects the regulatory authorities&#39; push for economic recovery after the &quot;big move&quot; of cutting interest rates and optimizing real estate and financial policies. However, this RRR cut is not a &quot;flood&quot;, nor does it exceed market expectations. It is expected that the policy effects of two interest rate cuts and two reserve requirement ratio cuts this year will continue to be released in a pulse-like manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The RRR is lowered on the eve of payment, why is it so urgent? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to relevant regulations, commercial banks should hand over deposit reserves to the People&#39;s Bank of China in three installments on the 5th, 15th and 25th of each month, depending on changes in their deposits. What is the purpose of this new policy of lowering reserve requirements, which was announced on the eve of the payment of deposit reserves by financial institutions on the 15th? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the just-released macroeconomic data is an important background for the &quot;flash&quot; launch of the new policy of lowering the reserve requirement ratio. This Monday, financial data for August was just released. Among them, the increase in social financing in August reached 3.12 trillion, a significant rebound from July. However, the broad money supply (M2 for short) increased by 10.6% year-on-year, and the growth rate was still slightly lower than that at the end of July and the same period last year by 0.1 and 0.16 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the balance of RMB loans issued by financial institutions to entities in August was 230.24 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 10.9%. The growth rate is recovering, which shows that investors&#39; confidence in the future has increased. Combined with the previously released August CPI and PPI data, various important economic indicators showed signs of bottoming out around August. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to promote the macroeconomic stabilization and improvement as soon as possible, since August, a combination of macroeconomic policies has been continuously launched, and fiscal, taxation, real estate, and monetary policies have been launched one after another. Among them, monetary policy is particularly eye-catching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of September, the central bank adjusted the existing mortgage interest rates, aiming to ease residents’ mortgage repayment pressure and stabilize real estate market confidence. The information on this adjustment to the deposit reserve ratio of financial institutions was released on the eve of the payment of deposit reserves by financial institutions on the 15th. The policy benefits were transmitted to the real economy at a rapid speed, and various financial institutions (excluding the 5% deposit reserve that had been implemented) Financial institutions (financial institutions) generally lowered the reserve requirement ratio by 0.25 percentage points. The intensity is consistent with the first reduction in March. The policy has both continuity and stability and the signal is clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What goals does the RRR cut in mid-September reflect? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the central bank chose to lower the reserve requirement ratio at this time for the following three main purposes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, seize the opportunity to consolidate the recovery of the real economy. A good trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;August data shows signs of bottoming out, which is a critical moment for economic recovery. The central bank decisively cut the reserve requirement ratio again, releasing more than 500 billion yuan in medium- and long-term liquidity. This move injects real money into the real economy through financial institutions, which may encourage financial institutions to further increase their investment in entities. Macroeconomic indicators will show more positive changes, and the sustainability of the steady economic recovery will be further enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to promote a moderate recovery in price levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maintaining a moderate level of inflation is more conducive to economic development. In the first half of the year, as CPI and PPI data continued to fall, concerns about deflation and recession continued in the market. Against this background, the central bank seized the opportunity of recent positive changes in inflation, especially when the year-on-year CPI turned from negative to positive in August and the year-on-year decline in PPI converged for two consecutive months, it promptly lowered the required reserve ratio to continue to enhance the potential of financial support to expand domestic demand. It is conducive to further giving full play to the early leading role of financial resources and supporting the continued moderate recovery of inflation indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to maintain reasonable and sufficient liquidity in the banking system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that in mid-to-late September, under the intertwined influence of factors such as local bond issuance, tax season peaks, and regulatory assessments, the liquidity pressure in the inter-bank market will increase significantly. Among them, local government bond issuance is accelerating. Following the issuance of 1.2 trillion yuan in August, more than 1 trillion yuan will be issued in September. Subscription payments by financial institutions will draw out a large amount of liquidity; the tax payment peak around the 15th of each month will cause market liquidity pressure in stages. Increase; September is still the end of the third quarter, and the needs of financial institutions for liquidity index assessment and other aspects will also increase significantly. After the superposition of multiple factors, the market&#39;s short-term capital supply and demand have increased. The central bank has chosen the time when the demand for liquidity is most urgent, taken timely measures, and played a significant role in protecting the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that this RRR cut is moderately forward-looking, which can not only alleviate short-term liquidity needs, but also continue to supplement credit growth, cash injection, and third-party payment institution preparations in the future period. The demand for medium- and long-term liquidity such as payment and back-up payment reflects the positive signal that the central bank is replenishing blood for banks accurately and appropriately and carefully protecting market liquidity. However, judging from the magnitude and pace of the RRR cut, this RRR cut did not exceed market expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How will the effect of continuous interest rate cuts and reserve requirement ratios be reflected? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, the central bank has cut interest rates twice and cut reserve requirements twice in a row, and the potential for active monetary policy continues to grow. In the future, how will the effects of relevant favorable policies be reflected? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the continuous &quot;relaxation&quot; of monetary policy has a direct effect on the continuous decline in financing costs of the real economy. This effect has been achieved. According to central bank data, corporate loan interest rates have dropped to historical lows from January to August, and personal housing loan interest rates have also dropped by 0.95 percentage points year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this move will promote commercial banks to further benefit the real economy. With the introduction of policies such as the central bank&#39;s interest rate cuts and existing mortgage interest rates, commercial banks&#39; net interest margins have narrowed significantly since 2019. As of the end of June, the average net interest margin of the 19 largest A-share listed banks was 1.83, a decrease of 30 basis points or 14% from the end of 2019. The overall profit margin of banks continues to shrink. This time the central bank lowers the reserve requirement ratio again, it will help reduce the cost of funds on the liability side of banks, further open up the downward space for loan interest rates on the asset side, promote the steady and steady decline of corporate financing and residents&#39; credit costs, and may further enhance the ability of financial institutions to transfer profits to entities. It is conducive to stabilizing investment and employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, with two consecutive interest rate cuts and two reserve requirement ratio cuts, monetary policy, fiscal policy and industrial policy have continued to exert their efforts. Factors conducive to the stabilization and improvement of the macro economy are increasing, and market expectations are quietly rising. changes occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant people close to the regulatory authorities told researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center that the central bank’s confidence, determination and ability to implement prudent monetary policies accurately and effectively will be further reflected, and the effects of relevant policies will be continuously released in a pulsed manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[庄稼地丨云间夜话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256556]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/o7vtcUwzK3dRQHvG13YrMqzZUdMvWxRwVhkXDkao.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/o7vtcUwzK3dRQHvG13YrM qzZUdMvWxRwVhkXDkao. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Crop field&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every morning in the community, there is always an old farmer walking out of the door among the endless flow of office workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His standard equipment is a broken straw hat and a rusty hoe. Of course, it is not only incompatible with the white-collar workers around me, but also particularly dazzling. At first I thought it was the landscaping engineer of the property, but later I found out that it was Tony&#39;s father, Lao Tan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tony drives a Rolls-Royce to work every day. But his father goes out with a hoe every day. I couldn&#39;t help but follow him on my bicycle and found that he had indeed entered the crop field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the 50 acres of crop land is a well-known large wasteland nearby. Who knows what the project was, but it was rotten anyway. Soon after it became wasteland, it was planted with crops by all kinds of people, so it was called crop land. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, Tony is so rich, what is Lao Tan doing? &quot;I can&#39;t help it.&quot; He said to me. If I can&#39;t smell the smell of the land for a day, I can&#39;t eat or sleep, and I can&#39;t stop yawning. As soon as I arrived at the crop field and smelled the familiar atmosphere, I felt energetic all over. Call me cheap, what can I do? When I first came to Shanghai, all the illnesses I had all over my body were cured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this matter, Tony had quarreled with him countless times, saying that it would seriously damage his image. But Lao Tan ignored him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The principle of crop land is that whoever opens it can plant as much as possible. Everyone has a playful mentality. The land is still deserted anyway, and the developers may come to work at some time. Only Lao Tan admitted the truth. In order to improve the quality of the soil, he collected dog excrement from all over the street and fermented it in a large vat. Even though he sprinkled maggot killers, the smell was still unbearable to the neighbors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also made his own &quot;vegetable fertilizer&quot;, which was another big vat. He filled the big vat with discarded fruits and vegetables from his own family and neighbors, bought compost strains, and pickled them like pickles. A big lump. Afraid that the soil would become hardened, we even brought in black &quot;soil loosening essence&quot; and spread it everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyway, the nice villa was turned into a toilet by him, and Tony vowed to leave him all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But you have to admit that Lao Tan is a good at growing crops. You can tell whether the soil is alkaline or acidic by looking at it, by tasting the water, you can tell whether it is too hard or too soft, and by looking at the pests and diseases, you can tell by looking at them: inchworms, armyworms, cabbage caterpillars, cutworms, root maggots, and mustard scale insects. , corn borers, rice planthoppers, red spider mites... For a while, &quot;green ecology&quot; was advocated in the crop fields. A few radicals did not use any medicine, saying that they would rather look ugly than be ecologically organic. The problem is that the insects are ruthless and will eat all the vegetables in just a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone invited Lao Tan to dinner and asked Lao Baoshi why the garden was still green without him spraying medicine. Who said no medicine? Lao Tan&#39;s throat suddenly straightened. What&#39;s going on? ! What I took was Chinese medicine. You can’t imagine this! For example, when I was a kid, I used Baibu to wash my hair and kill insects. One kilogram was only 12 yuan online. I brewed Baibu tincture in a big pot, sprayed it and poured it in, and it swept away all the germs and pests! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, he waved his big hand fiercely, looking very tall at that moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, despite being looked down upon in the community, when I arrived at the crop fields, it was like Napoleon of Elba returning to France, and my ears were filled with greetings one after another - &quot;Old Tan!&quot; &quot;Master Tan!&quot; !&quot; Some even call him &quot;Dad Tan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Tan felt very useful at this time. He sat on the small horse, took out the dry tobacco pipe he brought from his hometown, puffed for a while, and smiled, his face full of furrows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, good times do not last long as usual. Gradually, news came out that the developer would be back at work soon. Lao Tan was so worried that he sat in his vegetable garden in a daze every day. He smoked dry tobacco for a while and then reached out to touch the soil. I advised him that it was just temporary, so don’t take it so seriously. He looked towards me. not talking. Just kept rubbing the soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the large machinery came in, he was still sitting there every day. Let me put it bluntly, since you love the land so much, first, why bother leaving your hometown; second, you can still go back now! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He didn&#39;t speak for a long time. Then he said softly, &quot;I only have a son. My wife has died long ago. If I don&#39;t live with him, who will I live with?&quot; Second, let me tell you, the land in my hometown has long been gone, why don’t I still care about the “crop land” here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He suddenly cried. Tears flowed freely. Crying with a Hunan accent. I panicked and didn&#39;t know how to persuade him. He sat alone until it was completely dark before returning. Then for a long time, there was no trace of him. Tony&#39;s face looked very ugly. I know they were having a heated argument again. Lao Tan even beat his son, so I was embarrassed to ask about Lao Tan&#39;s whereabouts. I guess I should go back to my hometown. I think. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the beginning of winter, I rode an exercise bike and passed by the town of Sijing, 10 miles away from home. The fields were green and white with dew, and the fields in early winter were empty. On a remote road, a tent struggling in the north wind could be seen. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No, it is just a shack made of large plastic sheets tied with ropes. People in southern Guangdong call it &quot;Liao&quot; and people in Shanghai call it &quot;Pi&quot;. An old man was wrapped in a quilt and huddled there. Next to his head was a pile of foam bowls with traces of a lunch box. At his feet was a bottle of leftover &quot;Wuliang Chun&quot;. The food was in a mess. In front of the floor was a pair of mud-stained shoes. , a pair of socks with fuzzy fabric hanging on the uppers of his shoes, the street light shining on his exhausted face, and he was snoring like thunder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I coughed slightly, and he woke up and quickly raised his head. I was stunned for a moment, isn’t this Lao Tan! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can I become a homeless person if I can’t live in a nice villa? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I cooperate with others to grow rice. He smiled reluctantly. Didn&#39;t I tell you that my life is cheap? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do I have to stay here all night?&quot; I asked. Could anyone still steal? After all, it&#39;s the beginning of winter, and the chilling north wind is making the plastic shack rattle, huddled inside, and it&#39;s like being in the open air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old Tan sighed and said, you city people don’t understand many things. First, the most fearful thing about harvesting rice is rain. When it rains, even in the middle of the night or early in the morning, I must urgently &quot;gather the rice&quot;, pile it into a pile, and cover it with a tarpaulin. Second, the rice is drying here, and we are most afraid of being crushed by cars. We only dry half of the road, but there are too many heavy vehicles coming from the &quot;crop fields&quot;. Late at night, everyone came to stop temporarily. My ears were pricked all night long, and the sound of road pressure could be heard far away. I had to wave the signal light to ask them to &quot;raise your hand&quot;, so that at least less rice could be pressed...&quot; Chapter Third, keeping vigil does prevent theft.&quot; Lao Tan said, don&#39;t be surprised, some people steal rice - chickens, ducks and geese, they gain weight when they eat rice, and their egg production also increases, so rice thieves are all motor vehicles, and they shovel run. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rice he is guarding is called &quot;Nanjing No. 46&quot;. The seed fee is 1.6 yuan per catty; the charter fee is 500 yuan per mu; the fertilizer is 200 yuan per mu; and the manpower and machine farming fee is 105 yuan per mu; Pesticides are 115 yuan per mu; electric irrigation fees are 50 yuan per mu; harvesting fees are 100 yuan per mu. In order to ensure a fragrant and soft taste, organic fertilizers such as chicken manure must be applied per acre, as well as threshing and rice milling fees... In this way, the cost of rice per kilogram is more than 3 yuan, and our commercial grain price is 4 It costs 20 cents per catty. In fact, you can’t even earn 1 yuan per catty. With 26 acres of leased land, you only earn 10,000 to 20,000 yuan a year. The cost is so high, so you have to keep vigil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell, he said he would have to work hard for another four days before returning to the community. His son has made peace with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the bad news came on the fourth day. That morning, he just got up to pack his things and prepare to go home, but he fell down. Cerebral hemorrhage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heavy machinery in the crop fields is still roaring. But at the entrance, someone drew a circle and burned a lot of paper money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鄂尔多斯重大高压气体泄漏事故致10死3伤，国务院安委会挂牌督办]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256691]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Major production safety accident Notice of Investigation and Punishment of Listing Supervision&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Safety Committee Supervision [2023] No. 11&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot; >;People&#39;s Government of Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, a major high-pressure gas leakage occurred at Yiding Ecological Agriculture Development Co., Ltd. in Ordos City, your district, causing 10 people died and 3 were injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;According to the &quot;Measures for the Supervision of the Investigation and Handling of Major Accidents,&quot; the State Council Safety Committee decided to implement the supervision of the investigation and handling of this major accident. Your district must, in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Reporting, Investigation and Handling of Production Safety Accidents&quot; and other relevant laws, regulations and rules, promptly organize and carry out accident investigations, quickly identify the cause of the accident, and strictly study and propose handling opinions in accordance with the requirements of accident investigation regulations. Before the accident is closed, the accident investigation report (unfinalized) must be submitted to the Office of the State Council Safety Committee. After review and approval, your district will be responsible for approving the closure of the case and announcing it to the public. After the case is closed, the accident investigation report and the implementation of the accident handling decision must be reported to the Office of the State Council Safety Committee for record in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Contact person and phone number: Huang Yong, 010-83933559. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: right;&quot;>;State Council Work Safety Commission&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: right;&quot;>; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;September 12, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>