<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[宥予：有些人注定是要写小说的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257452]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/z2DTi4OKE6uUTaEyvrlo58LJTfCh1LJHcKpJ9pbj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/z2DTi4OKE6uUTaEyvrlo58LJTfCh1 LJHcKpJ9pbj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Cao Jiaxuan/Picture)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Puncture the membrane of life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After watching &quot;The Sky&quot;, you will have an illusion. You would think that those salesmen you meet in a noisy restaurant who are engrossed in eating with their colleagues, wearing short-sleeved white shirts day after day, and thinking about which shared bicycle monthly pass to buy when they leave, behind the lean and ordinary appearance In fact, they are all experts at experiencing life. They absorb everything around them delicately and keenly, and when they return to their shared home, they all become Kafka. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Crashing into the Sky&quot; is a novel published in August 2023. The protagonist in the book is a clerk working in downtown Guangzhou. The pen name of the person who wrote it is You Yu. He is in his early 30s and is naturally also known as I think I have had similar experiences. Of course, he also took some classes that were neither salty nor bland, and also ran a restaurant selling braised chicken. But when he started writing this novel with a rich sense of place, it had only been two or three years since he moved to Guangzhou, and he had only a few encounters with the streets that appear repeatedly in the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With no intention of finding a job, he decided to come to Guangzhou to live a low-cost creative life with the money he earned from opening a restaurant. After inspecting several district libraries, and taking into account the environment, the flow of people, and the rent, he rented one at the terminus of the subway line and went to the nearby Huangpu District Library from nine to five every day to write. According to the air-conditioning vents in the four seasons, The scenery outside the window changes the favorite seats in the museum, listening to Bach&#39;s unaccompanied cello suites, and constructing the life of office workers 30 kilometers away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is completely different from the type of novelist who needs to be rooted in a strange environment for a long time before he can write confidently. In his eyes, the external life that others try to figure out is like being covered with a tight and difficult-to-remove plastic film. Transparent and fragile bubbles that pop when poked. While shopping, he felt that his brain was uncontrollably breaking through physical boundaries, spreading and landing on everything around him. Buildings, chairs, and even the moving light spots on a small leaf were all sending information to him in a steady stream. . It is so abundant that it can even become a burden, causing you to almost collapse every time you go home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After starting to write, he finally found a way to release. Occasionally speaking about this &quot;trouble&quot;, he seemed to tentatively wipe the dust on the cabinet wall with his index finger. Only when he saw a clumsy and obvious trace did he realize, oh, it turns out that other people are different from me. Critic Li Jing fully felt his &quot;idiosyncrasies&quot; and described him as being like a radar, always in a state of sensing the situation around him. &quot;And he seems to be completely unable to ignore any kind of information or any kind of situation. He can react in his mind at any time, and express this reaction in a particularly precise, poetic language.&quot; She called him &quot;The opposite of Medusa&quot; means that wherever he looks, all solid objects dissolve into living, liquid or gaseous objects, becoming music, birds, and life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you think back, this &quot;special ability&quot; seems to have nothing to do with location. He could not escape this experience in his hometown in Henan when he was studying and in Shanghai when he was working. The division in time is even more obvious. &quot;The moment I learned that my mother died in a car accident, my hearing seemed to be different all of a sudden. There were dozens of people around, and everyone was talking, but I could hear them all. What are you talking about? I cried all of a sudden, but actually I didn’t feel sad in my heart. What happened to death? Many people around me praised me for being sensible and knowing how to cry. Instead, they gave me a kind of encouragement and made me cry. Even harder, letting me know that I should cry even more. Before, as a child, the entire adult world was actually surrounded by a wall, but after that, you will feel that the dam collapsed all of a sudden, and it poured directly into my body like a flood ( (in front of me). I have personally experienced the changes in every relationship, not only with family members, but also with anyone in the surrounding environment. Everything is changing. This change made me particularly clearly aware of how to come up with a relationship that is consistent with the situation. Everyone is expecting it, but in fact I know in my heart that I am performing for everyone to see.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For fear of disturbing others, his already low volume was lowered. From the first floor to the second floor, we changed seats three times, but we still couldn&#39;t escape the fate of being overwhelmed by the sound, other people&#39;s conversations, and the static of the coffee machine. With an anxious mood, I struggled to salvage his weak response - I had sold insurance, managed the Tmall flagship store of a pet company, had outstanding performance in after-sales work at a software sales company, and had to deal with endless abuse from customers. He was very patient, but when his boss promoted him to lead the team, he resigned decisively. He regards work as a mechanical performance, &quot;I just don&#39;t believe in evil and still have to do it. In fact, I am just avoiding writing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When faced with questions, he rarely responds directly, with a novelist&#39;s narrative The rhythm is not as simple as taking a small detour, but going straight to a completely unrelated route, suddenly braking when you are not sure whether you will come back - &quot;I&#39;ll tell you from the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;Avoid writing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have wanted to write a long time ago ? Have you thought about it before going to work in Shanghai? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Tell the truth, it’s really the truth. I have loved reading since I could learn to read, but at that time we couldn&#39;t afford books. Apart from textbooks, I read wherever I can see words, such as fertilizer bags, ingredient lists on pesticide labels, and opening paper balls. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I read a book was probably after my mother passed away. She passed away when I was in the fourth grade of elementary school. My sisters were in junior high school at that time, and they brought books back several times on the weekends, including &quot;Wuthering Heights&quot; and &quot;Jane Eyre.&quot; At that time, I didn&#39;t understand much about romance and didn&#39;t remember the specific plot. After watching it, I felt that these people were weird and interesting, and they were different from the people around me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you still remember the feeling of reading a book at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The clearest feeling is &quot;War and Peace&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I entered junior high school—I lived on campus at that time—I would ride a few kilometers to the school in the town every Sunday evening. In the beginning, I had to use meal tickets to eat at school. I had to carry a bag of wheat to the flour mill next to the school and give it to the cooperative flour mill. I then took the note to the accountant and exchanged it for meal tickets. When I was in the second grade of junior high school, the price of food seemed to have gone up a bit. My dad did some math and thought it might be more cost-effective to give me money, so he gave me only 10 yuan a week. But he didn&#39;t realize that I was growing stronger and my appetite had increased. (I) was hungry every meal. I knew it was very difficult to make money at that time, so I didn’t say anything. Occasionally, I can have a good meal at my aunt&#39;s house, so now that I see my dear aunt, I still feel full and feel very at ease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once we entered a bookstore, there were pirated books by Li Liang and Gu Long everywhere, while those by Tolstoy and Hugo were shivering in the corner. I definitely couldn&#39;t afford it at that time, not even more than one yuan. After all, I wouldn&#39;t even have enough to eat. I don’t know how I saved a few dollars in the end. Maybe a few months later, I bought two books before the summer vacation. One was &quot;War and Peace&quot; and the other one I really can’t remember. After I bought it, I opened it and found that the first page was densely packed with words and a lot of French. At that time, it rained continuously and the sky was covered with rain. The ground is covered with yellow water, branches are sometimes blown off, and the sound of rain is mixed with the sound of the last cicadas in late summer and the screams of young birds after their nests are blown away. Under these sounds, I watched &quot;War and Peace&quot; on the lounge chair in the main room without realizing it was dark. My dad came out of nowhere and said it was so dark it was ruining his eyesight. Because the wires were broken at that time, I moved to the porch at the door until I saw that there was no light at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I woke up the next morning, I could see the words again. It took me three or four days, during the heavy rain, to finish reading &quot;War and Peace&quot;. It’s hard to say what impact it had on me. From then on, there will be a feeling of another space in my brain, including everything around me, including plains, woods, and rain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did you also want to write something after reading it at that time? Did you start writing? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No. When I was in high school, I wrote an essay, and the Chinese teacher in charge of my class asked, &quot;Do you have any interest in writing in the future?&quot; I thought at that time, I don&#39;t want to develop on this dead-end road, and I think it will definitely be difficult. It was only when I thought back a few days ago that I realized that many people had realized that I must be doing this kind of thing (writing), but I myself had been avoiding it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you had the conditions to write before? Can I just write without going to work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No conditions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yes, so it can’t be said to be an escape. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s true. After working several jobs, opening a restaurant, and saving some money, I realized that I had no real interest in going to work. Everything I do is like this: when a task comes, I will handle it as well as I can handle it. There is no problem in execution, but I have no motivation (to continue). When I was a teenager, I realized that I was not motivated and had no motivation at all for the kind of life my father expected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After opening a restaurant and coming to Guangzhou, Are you looking for a job? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t read for a long time after graduation. After I arrived in Guangzhou, I found some books to read and thought it wouldn’t be difficult. If you want to write, then I’ll give it a try. Once I write, I find it’s quite difficult. The rhythm of language, narrative perspective, entry angle, and which point in time a story is more powerful are all explored bit by bit. Usually after the changes are made, it is quickly discovered that it is still a pile of garbage. Revise it over and over again, and every week you have to go through that ultimate pulling process from when you think it is rubbish to when you think you have written the best work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At most, a work will be revised several times version? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There was an article that was just finalized two days ago—in fact, I have been reluctant to finalize it. When I was a child, my grandmother would make yellow yeast and dry it in the sun. Every time she makes it, a piece of dough will be dried and concentrated in the dough vat. The next time she goes to ferment, she will take out the dough and use it. There are two novellas that I have been reluctant to finalize, and they are my two little noodle pieces. I didn&#39;t let go until I realized that there was no trace of me in that person anymore, and he really became himself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You also changed &quot;Chong Kong&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; I also changed it, but I am not satisfied with it. One day when I decided to write it, suddenly, a man from the north Man&#39;s life (comes) with all those things from his past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WDfJrEvipkrXfZii1aweShnFjJYxiZ8ypyM652QC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1441&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WDfJrEvipkrXfZii1aweShnFjJYxiZ8ypyM652QC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 3, 2023, Beijing Code Character Bookstore, You Yu communicated with readers at a dialogue on the new book &quot;Crashing into the Sky&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xiaowu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;From hypocrisy to disgust, from panic to sincerity&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The protagonist of the novel, He Xiaohe, still has a lot of your shadow? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, at least there is the experience of death. His mother, he is also drifting in Guangzhou, the food he likes to eat...many things are indeed mine. But I&#39;m different from him, and I was particularly vigilant when I wrote &quot;The Sky&quot;. Because it is so close to us, it is easy to write the self-pity of a frustrated person accidentally, to write a kind of romance that seems to have been added with artificial cream, and a kind of overflowing warmth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I didn’t dare to love any of them when I was writing. One eye was always staring at myself. Whenever I feel that I am getting emotional while writing, I will stop, walk around the library, and check again to make sure that my emotions are not involved before continuing to write. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What views and feelings of He Xiaohe on things are different from yours? the same? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are many, and I can’t summarize and analyze them. I think he will restrain himself. I am a little more hypocritical than him in dealing with people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He is already very hypocritical. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am more hypocritical than him. I&#39;m not afraid when I need to express something publicly, but after I say it, I hate every word I say. Because I clearly realized that when I spoke, there were four me at work, one was the me I expected, one was the me I wanted others to see, one was the me I thought I was, and there was another A more authentic me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if I know what I am more fundamentally, I can’t erase who I think I am, and then I can’t stop being the me that I want others to see. . During the whole process, I realized that my vanity, my hypocrisy, my pretense, as well as my sincerity and calmness actually existed at the same time. Perhaps when these four unite to become a complete one, that is truly true. If this were the case, I might not hate myself so much. I don’t know if other people feel this way, do you feel this way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I may not have so much to hate what I said . In your previous work experience, did you often need to speak to the public? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I sell insurance, I also have to host morning meetings and annual meetings. After writing, I didn’t think people would need me to talk about myself. Maybe they just needed to talk about how I wrote. The last time I was in Foshan to promote Peng Jianbin&#39;s new book, I met them and realized that they would be curious about me. Why was this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially at that time, it was the first time I really met readers and looked at their faces. Before, I had been writing alone in the library. After the conversation, a girl came to me and asked me. She said that she was also writing, but was a little confused. At that time, I realized that although my answer might not have that big an impact, it might have a small impact. This thing makes me feel quite panicked and scared. I tried my best to tell what I was sincere about, so that I would not be so panicked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I didn’t actually love literature before. The reason why I wrote it was because it was indeed a way I could find for me to get along with the world, others, and myself. I met (Luo) Danni, (Wang) Jiasheng (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Chong Kong&quot; editor&lt;/span>;), Jian Bin and the others , I found that they really love this thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ZZhNQSFgRSF3aW6SyYg1ZYul5DeG8Hz4D6AbvSxY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1247&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ZZhNQSFgRSF3aW6SyYg1ZYul5DeG8Hz4D6AbvSxY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you feel stressed among them? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Youyu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am not under any pressure, but I will be a little touched. I often felt that literature was useless, especially when I heard many people using the term &quot;Sister Xianglin&quot; to sarcastically refer to others. Many books clearly understand people so deeply, so why do people still use such simple terms? way to understand people? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I felt quite empty at the end of &quot;Crashing into the Sky&quot;. At that time, I thought of a long theme, and wanted to write about a person&#39;s 20 or 30 years in a chronological style, but I was When I was sorting through it, I found that there was a person in it who seemed to be a good novella. Then I started writing that, but during that time the library was not allowed in, so I wrote in my room. At that time, I was suffering from rhinitis all the time, and later I was infected with the new coronavirus. I had a fever for five days and died in pain. During that process, it took maybe two or three months to finish writing the novella, which was about 40,000 words. In fact, it’s something I don’t want to publish, and I don’t want to show it to others. After I finished writing, a friend happened to ask me. She said she just wanted to read something and asked me if I had any. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She goes to work, doesn&#39;t write anything, and hasn&#39;t watched &quot;The Sky&quot;. I showed her the novella with mother and daughter as the main line. It was posted in the afternoon, but she finished reading it in the evening and said that she felt very blocked and uncomfortable. After that, she called her mother, and the two cried bitterly on the phone for the first time. For the first time, she heard her mother talk about her youth, her love and her emotions when she was simply a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t think my writing was very good, or that it really played such a big role. Maybe it gave her an opportunity at that point in time, and she was finally willing to have that kind of communication with her mother. If what I write has a little effect on such a specific person, I will feel a little comfort in my heart. She and her mother have maintained relatively good communication since then. We have mutual trust and support, and I am very happy thinking about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You also wrote a story about a father and his daughter. What is the protagonist? Choose a woman from Xiguan, Guangzhou? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was not written as &quot;a woman from Xiguan&quot; in the beginning. It started with a dream. I dreamed that there was a place called Serisi Dragon Cave in the African desert. There was a dragon in it. The people there made a living by drinking dragon milk. After I woke up, I slowly wrote a poem. A man lives in Guangzhou, but when he closes his eyes, he will have another identity, a story about going to Saili Shilong Cave. After I finished writing it, I realized that it was just a man&#39;s self-pity and pretentiousness. Taken alone, at least for me, I couldn&#39;t accept it and it was untenable. Eventually I found myself rewriting the entire story from his daughter&#39;s perspective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many other novels may also be inspired by dreams Coming? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Youyu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After I woke up, I jotted down a lot, but this is the only one I wrote down, because I don’t have enough energy now to write anything. Much. I am going to write a long novel in the second half of this year. Many characters in this article have been popping up in my mind since the end of last year. From time to time, I see them there, what are they thinking, struggling, and saying? . Occasionally, a new character will appear. He may say a few words, and I can see his childhood and his entire path at once. They were still happening when I was writing other novels. It is a story that takes place in the second half of 2022, which is also very recent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you inspired by real life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excuse me: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. But I won’t write about many major events directly. I do the same when dealing with many short and medium stories. I don’t think it’s interesting to write about this matter directly. I still like to write about an event that may have been a long time ago, but how it played a role in someone’s entire life. of. It&#39;s like every time you throw a stone on the water surface, the water waves rise and then dissipate. Is the water surface still the same as before? What did that ripple mark leave behind? I&#39;m still more interested in digging into these things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西北师大“保研事故”：失误还是失信？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258072]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some students from Northwest Normal University who had obtained the list of postgraduate qualifications were disqualified during the publicity period. , the incident quickly attracted public attention. On September 29, the official website of Northwest Normal University issued a notice stating that the school’s “serious work errors by staff” resulted in “the number of announced postgraduate students being recommended for exemption exceeds the quota for the recommendation plan.” After discovering the problem, the school withdrew the quota for the excess exemption plan and explained to the affected students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Yong (pseudonym), the student involved, said that the publicity period was from September 20th to 29th, and they were only informed of the &quot;recruitment for postgraduate qualifications&quot; on the afternoon of the 28th, the day before the end of the publicity period. got canceled&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Insurance Research Incident” and “Research Qualification Cancellation” have become the hot search titles of this incident. However, there are still many factual details that need to be clarified in this incident, and it cannot be simply classified as an &quot;accident&quot; or even a &quot;shady incident.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recommended exemption from examination&quot; and &quot;successful admission&quot; in postgraduate studies are two completely different concepts. This point was intentionally or unintentionally blurred in media reports, which also made the direction of the incident somewhat out of focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, senior students seeking postgraduate study must first seek exemption qualifications from their own school before they can apply for pre-admission qualifications from their own school or other schools. At the same time, there are still divisions in the admission methods of the postgraduate entrance examination such as &quot;summer camp&quot;, &quot;pre-recommendation exemption&quot; and &quot;nine recommendation&quot; (exemption in September). In terms of acceptance units, there are also &quot;internal protection&quot; (our school) and &quot;external recommendation&quot; (other schools). ) difference. The priority of summer camp and pre-recommendation exemption is higher than that of &quot;nine promotions&quot;, and &quot;internal protection&quot; is more certain than &quot;external promotion&quot;. These are subdivided tracks in the &quot;protection research world&quot;, and each competition The rules of the Tao game are also different and cannot be generalized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this &quot;recruitment accident&quot;, the &quot;disqualified&quot; students participated in the &quot;September Exemption&quot;, which is referred to as the &quot;Nine Promotions&quot;. According to the &quot;Notice on Recommending Excellent Fresh Undergraduates to Study for Master&#39;s Degrees Without Examination in 2024&quot; released on the official website of Northwest Normal University on September 16, the timetable for this promotion is &quot;Students apply on September 17, 9 From September 17th to 20th, the college will recommend, and the school will review it on September 20th.&quot; Then it is &quot;from September 20th to 29th, the school will publicize the list of proposed recommendations, and the publicity period will be 10 days.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the general exemptions, Northwest Normal University’s notice on September 16 also announced other types of “September exemptions”, such as the “Bachelor-Master Integration” special program, “Counselor Program” &quot;Special Program&quot;, &quot;Rural School Education Master Teacher Training Program&quot; (referred to as &quot;Agricultural Master&quot;), &quot;Graduate Education Support Team&quot; special program, etc. are recommended to exempt enrollment plans. Among them, the recommendation work for “counselor special projects” is the responsibility of the Student Affairs Department of the Party Committee and belongs to the “Administrative Research Guarantee in Colleges and Universities”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Zongpan News&quot; quoting the student involved, Xiao Hong (pseudonym), more than 100 students were affected by this &quot;accident&quot;, and they mainly applied for the &quot;Undergraduate and Master&#39;s Integrated Excellent Middle School&quot; There are two promotion projects: &quot;Teacher&quot; and &quot;Counselor Special&quot;. China News Network’s report also showed that the two students interviewed applied for the “Counselor Special Program” and were subsequently disqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice shows that the &quot;Counselor Special Program&quot; is recommended by the Party Committee&#39;s Academic Affairs Department, and the academic system is &quot;1+Basic Academic System&quot;. After graduating from senior year, students must be full-time counselors for one year; &quot;Bachelor and Master&#39;s Integration&quot; The selection process is limited to the college and the receiving major, and a training agreement needs to be signed. The academic system is &quot;3+1+2&quot;, that is, three years for undergraduates, one year for transition, and two years for the master&#39;s degree in education. At least judging from the literal meaning of this document, the school has greater discretion and decision-making power over the admissions of these two internal postgraduate programs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pushing the issue to this point, based on the existing information, it is not difficult to conclude that there is indeed a possibility that the school made a mistake, that is, the school staff &quot;slid&quot;, allowing two &quot;internal graduate protection of the school&quot; projects The announced number of graduate students recommended for exemption exceeds the number of places in the recommendation plan, resulting in an excess quota. The key lies in how the planned quota of the disqualified postgraduate program is calculated, whether it is included in the total quota, and whether the school has the right to cancel it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A &quot;Boya Database&quot; published by Northwest Normal University on September 16 released the &quot;2024 Excellent Fresh Undergraduate Graduates Recommended Master&#39;s Degree Distribution Table&quot; shows that Northwest Normal University&#39;s &quot;2024 Class of There are 702 postgraduate positions, which is a significant increase from the previous session (641 people).&quot; Among them, 35 people are planned to be admitted to the &quot;Counselor Special Program&quot; and as many as 100 people are planned to be admitted to the &quot;Bachelor-Master Integrated Special Program&quot;. And these 702 people do not include the &quot;counselor specialization&quot;. Can it be said that the &quot;counselor special project&quot; itself is somewhat &quot;supernumerary&quot; in nature, so the school has the right to handle it flexibly? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quotas for the &quot;Counselor Special Program&quot; and &quot;Bachelor-Master&#39;s Integrated Program&quot; last year were 40 and 60 respectively. It can be seen that this year, the number of places for the &quot;Counselor Special Program&quot; has decreased while the number of places for the &quot;Integrated Bachelor&#39;s and Master&#39;s Program&quot; has increased. After the &quot;accident&quot;, Zhao Qin (pseudonym) said in an interview with China News Network that &quot;it was the middle part that was disqualified&quot; because &quot;Nongshuo has signed a contract and the deal is done, so we can only cancel ours.&quot; Han Yong also said that &quot;all counselors in our college who have been specially guaranteed for postgraduate study have been disqualified.&quot; This detail also shows that the contract signing time and formal enrollment for the &quot;Counselor Special Program&quot; are later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At what point in time did the mistake of &quot;excess public announcement of personnel&quot; occur? Why is there overstaffing? On what basis were the personnel quotas for the two affected research protection projects determined to be &quot;excess&quot;? Are the only over-subscribed projects the “counselor specialization” and “undergraduate and master’s degree integration”? Or could it be said that the school does have greater discretion over the two &quot;internally guaranteed postgraduate programs within the school&quot; and has the right to cancel or change the enrollment plan during the list publicity period? The answers to these questions will determine whether the nature of the &quot;accident&quot; is just a work error or a procedural breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the school should answer the specific details of the &quot;excess number of students found&quot; and announce to the outside world the specific rules of the several &quot;our school&#39;s postgraduate protection&quot; projects affected this time. In this way, it will be clear at a glance whether it is a mistake or a breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[指定居所监视居住，不能走样变形丨法眼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/04/uhg2cLvAxVLP9h2Z4iB0ZrIzgaZpOHEBlp6IYrBu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/uhg2cLvAxVLP9h2Z4iB0ZrIzgaZpOH EBlp6IYrBu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 14, 2023, on the first floor of Xinle Hotel, Xinle City, Hebei Province, there are The four walls of the room are all soft walls. The father of Bao Qinrui, the &quot;resident&quot; person, said that they had been placed under residential surveillance here. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Qian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance in a designated residence (hereinafter referred to as &quot;residence&quot;) is a criminal coercive measure. Recently, an unfortunate incident was linked to this coercive measure, making people rethink this system:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of July 7, 2022, the police removed 33-year-old Bao Qinrui from Shijiazhuang, where he lived. He was taken away from his home in Yuhua District. Soon, his wife was informed that Bao Qinrui was living in Xinle City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Shijiazhuang) on ​​suspicion of picking quarrels and provoking trouble. Thirteen days after &quot;Zhiju&quot;, Bao Qinrui passed away. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see the Southern Weekend App report on September 19 &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/256978?source =131&quot;>;The person who was &quot;accused&quot; passed away, and the police said that the other co-defendants &quot;should not pursue criminal responsibility&quot;&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of Qinrui&#39;s death will be revealed here Putting it aside and focusing on the accusation of violence against Qin Rui - how this criminal coercive measure is carried out and how it should operate is worthy of re-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Residential surveillance, divided into two&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;my country&#39;s 1979 Criminal Procedure Law stipulates five coercive measures - summons, release on bail pending trial, residential surveillance, There has been neither an increase nor a decrease in detentions and arrests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance was originally a milder form and was not considered a &quot;custodial measure&quot; at first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residential surveillance stipulated in Paragraph 2 of Article 38 of the 1979 Criminal Procedure Law is very simple, &quot;The defendant under residential surveillance shall not leave the designated area. Residential surveillance shall be carried out by the local public security police station, or by an entrusted The people&#39;s commune and the unit where the defendant works shall be implemented.&quot; At that time, suspects and defendants were collectively referred to as &quot;defendants&quot;, and residential surveillance measures did not distinguish between &quot;residences&quot; where they lived. Judging from the application of this measure, residential surveillance is a non-custodial measure. Although the scope of activities of suspects and defendants is restricted, their personal freedom is not deprived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1996, when the Criminal Procedure Law was revised, residential surveillance measures separated a &quot;residential residence&quot; from the residential surveillance that restricts personal freedom, and was used for suspects and defendants who &quot;have no fixed residence&quot; The suspects and defendants are required to &quot;not leave their designated residence without approval&quot; and the scope of their personal freedom is narrowed to &quot;the designated residence&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the semantic point of view of the legal provisions, &quot;not leaving without permission&quot; is a restriction on the person who is &quot;designated to live&quot;. The suspects and defendants still have personal freedom to &quot;leave&quot; the designated residence. The possibility, that is, not being completely deprived, probably belongs to a kind of &quot;house arrest.&quot; However, in practice, being &quot;resident&quot; is no longer the original meaning of &quot;residential surveillance&quot;, but has become a kind of detention, which is just different from being detained in a detention center like detention or arrest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, the Criminal Procedure Law was revised again, and the conditions for release on bail pending trial and residential surveillance were separated. Only those who meet the arrest conditions and legal circumstances can be released on bail pending trial. Article 73 of the law stipulates: &quot;Residential surveillance shall be carried out after the crime has been committed.&quot; The execution may be carried out at the residence of the suspect or defendant; if there is no fixed residence, the execution may be carried out at a designated residence. For suspected crimes endangering national security, crimes of leaving terrorist activities, or particularly serious bribery crimes, execution at the residence may hinder the investigation, after the previous With the approval of the People&#39;s Procuratorate at the highest level and the public security organ, enforcement can also be carried out in a designated residence. However, it cannot be carried out in a place of detention or a special case handling place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the legislation has tacitly approved the use of residential surveillance in a designated residence as a form of surveillance. This hidden meaning can also be seen in the practice of various detention measures, and the applicable conditions for residential surveillance are closer to the conditions for arrest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, residential surveillance has changed from a non-custodial measure to a custodial measure, and the suspects and defendants who have been &quot;residenced&quot; are deprived of their personal freedom. Not only that, the place of residential surveillance has also become a place of interrogation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Become &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; a temporary “case handling place” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Article 73 of the Criminal Procedure Law stipulates that “it shall not be used in places of detention, specialized It is not prohibited to turn a residence under designated residential surveillance into a temporary &quot;case-handling place&quot;. In fact, the measure of residential surveillance has become an investigative measure to obtain confessions due to the designated residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This combination of detention and interrogation means that for the case-handling agency, the interrogation conducted at the designated residence is subject to few external constraints, and the interrogation process is conducive to the control and regulation of the case-handling personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interrogation is conducted in a confined space outside a detention center. If the rights of criminal suspects and defendants are not to be infringed, they must submit obediently and provide the confessions expected by the investigators on a tap; or the investigators must comply with the interrogation. Standardize and consciously restrain the inertia and impulse of illegal evidence collection. When criminal suspects and defendants are not docile and actively cooperate, torture, torture, and corporal punishment and abuse can easily occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the place of &quot;residence&quot; is also a temporary &quot;case handling place&quot;, the case handlers in the pre-trial stage also become caretakers. Therefore, eliminating outside interference has become an inevitable choice. Not only are close relatives of people under such residential surveillance not allowed to meet with them, even lawyers are not allowed to meet with them, and they cannot even know where the criminal suspects or defendants are designated to live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defense lawyer complained that the accused residents’ rights to lawyers were not even as good as those of criminal suspects and defendants when they were detained in the detention center, because criminal suspects and defendants could still meet with their lawyers in the detention center. , but they are not allowed to meet him while under residential surveillance, creating a reality that is obviously disproportionate to the principle of proportionality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the close relatives of the accused resident are not informed of their designated place during the pretrial proceedings. Article 161 of the Supreme People&#39;s Court&#39;s &quot;Interpretation on the Application of the Criminal Procedure Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; Paragraph 2 stipulates that the close relatives of the parties should be notified of the reason and location of residence. This is because after investigation, review and prosecution of the case, it is no longer necessary to obtain confessions from the defendant outside the court. Therefore, the details of the coercive measures taken have also changed. The accusation without the function of obtaining confessions is undoubtedly closer to the essence of residential surveillance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The non-custodial nature should be returned&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the name, if &quot;resident residence&quot; is still a &quot;residential surveillance&quot; measure, it should be related to the custodial measure. Essentially different, not just a formal and meaningful difference in the form of a place of detention. In other words, people under residential surveillance should have a certain degree of personal freedom. If this freedom is completely deprived, it is a measure of detention rather than residential surveillance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although nothing can be seen from the provisions of the Criminal Procedure Law itself, in actual case handling, residential surveillance at a designated location has indeed lost its essence of residential surveillance and has become a detention measure. During the Republic of my country, the Criminal Procedure Law of our country already included &quot;residential surveillance&quot;. This measure existed as an alternative to detention, or as a measure to release from detention. The current residential surveillance is slightly different from the word order, but the nature of this measure is originally the same. Confusing residential surveillance with detention measures, even though there are differences in detention places, is still a flaw in the design of the criminal justice system or an act that exceeds legal boundaries in judicial practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Personal freedom is a basic human right second only to the right to life and health, and is guaranteed by the solemn commitment of the Constitution. Personal freedom is not absolute. Personal freedom can be restricted or deprived for the needs of social defense, the need for litigation and evidence preservation, the need for the personal preservation of the person being prosecuted, and as a penalty measure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, deprivation of personal freedom—whether as a social defense measure, a litigation safeguard measure, or a punishment method—needs to go through legal due process, that is, it is decided by the judicial authority, which leads to the judicial monopoly of the power of imprisonment. Sexuality and inalienability, non-judicial authorities may not deprive personal liberty for the above purposes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the deprivation of personal liberty stipulated in the Constitution as a protective measure appears with the word &quot;arrest&quot;. &quot;Arrest&quot; in the Constitution cannot be understood as an arrest in various coercive measures in criminal proceedings. It should be understood in a broad sense, that is, any arrest substance, no matter what the name is, will be regarded as an &quot;arrest&quot; in the Constitution and must be carried out in accordance with the Constitution. The prescribed restrictions are implemented - approval or decision of the People&#39;s Procuratorate and decision of the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deprivation of personal freedom as a protective measure in our country ignores the broad nature of &quot;arrest&quot; in the Constitution. In addition to arrest, there are many personal freedoms that have the same essence as arrest but do not appear in the name of arrest. Deprivation measures have caused the constitutional guarantee of personal freedom to become undistributed in practice. Zhiju refers to a detention measure that is not in the name of &quot;arrest&quot; and is not held in a detention place but has the same essence as arrest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The death of Bao Qinrui gives us the opportunity to examine the custodialization of residential surveillance and let us think: we should return residential surveillance to its non-custodial nature and avoid confusing its essence with custodial measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[史上首次，美国“三号人物”被投票罢免]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 19:26:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021854946024&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;For the first time in history, the &quot;No. 3&quot; figure in the United States was voted out of office.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/543d88ee5576678021854946024/sampleSnapshot /sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/543d88ee5576678021854946024/bJQdQltDrtQA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height =&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/543d88ee5576678021854946024/bJQdQltDrtQA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[全红婵 陈芋汐：神仙姐妹交相辉映]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258068]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/04/ssInabNEeMfdv7wu3WdauUzBwGZTGEBjjefNE7g7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/ssInabNEeMfdv7wu3WdauUzBwGZTGEBjjefNE7 g7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final of the diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games , the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right) and Chen Yuxi (left) at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the women&#39;s single 10-meter platform final of the Asian Games held on the afternoon of October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan reproduced the &quot;splash disappearing technique&quot; and won the championship with 438.20 points. Her partner Chen Yuxi was only 2.55 points behind Falling behind, he won the runner-up spot in the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fierce gold medal match between the two, Quan Hongchan made a mistake when doing 207C (backward somersault three-and-a-half-week knee-tuck, difficulty coefficient 3.3) in the fourth jump, and the score was temporarily behind. Chen Yuxi then overtook on the last jump. The whole process was full of ups and downs, fully demonstrating the charm of competitive sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A similar plot happened two months ago, but the results were slightly different. In August, in the 2023 FINA Diving World Cup Super Finals held in Berlin, Quan Hongchan made a mistake in her most difficult to conquer 207C movement and unfortunately won the silver medal. Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with 420.30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Tokyo Olympics, Quan Hongchan became one of the most watched athletes in the Chinese women&#39;s diving team, and the peak showdown between her and Chen Yuxi became a highlight in major events. But in the past two years, Quan Hongchan has faced difficult development hurdles, the &quot;curse&quot; of 207C, and the running-in with &quot;novice coach&quot; Chen Ruolin. Her results have not been stable, while Chen Yuxi, who has overcome the development hurdles, is getting better and better. Calm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/tJ4KWr8GuO11z5iDnb42G8Dk7r9N1hqqMGaZE7au.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;688&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/tJ4KWr8GuO11z5iDnb42G8Dk7r9N1hqqMGaZE7au.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 5, 2023, in the women&#39;s 10-meter platform finals of the 2023 FINA Diving World Cup Finals in Berlin, Germany, Chinese player Chen Yuxi (left) scored 420.30 Winning the championship with a score of 408.10 points, Chinese player Quan Hongchan (right) won the runner-up with a score of 408.10 points &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The 207C Curse of &quot;Genius Girl&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she won the women&#39;s single 10-meter platform championship at the 2021 Tokyo Olympics, Quan Hongchan was only 14 years old, and she happened to meet the requirements of FINA Required minimum age limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous year, with the postponement of the Tokyo Olympics, Quan Hongchan made her debut in a major domestic competition at the Olympic trials in October 2020. After three trials, she ranked first in points. Selected for the national team and qualified for the Tokyo Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Tokyo Olympics in the summer of 2021, Quan Hongchan relied on her outstanding performance-she scored 3 perfect scores in the 5 actions in the women&#39;s 10-meter platform final. The full score for all actions totaled 477 points. She won Scored 466.2 points - the highest score in the history of the women&#39;s 10-meter platform. She became famous in one fell swoop and was called a genius girl by the outside world, attracting much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next two years, her performance went up and down, and she lost to her partner Chen Yuxi in many international competitions. According to media reports, one of the movements that hindered the talented girl was 207C - she made frequent mistakes in this movement, which was almost a curse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;207C requires athletes to hold their knees and flip back three and a half times after taking off, then unfold and enter the water. The completion time of a series of actions is less than two seconds, requiring athletes to have extremely strong strength and the ability to control their bodies. At the same time, although it is not the most difficult move for female athletes, players with their backs to the pool need to overcome a certain amount of fear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/6xssjomGH9bawX8CsI8oVJTFRhyNcL7HghvXiswL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/6xssjomGH9bawX8CsI8oVJTFRhyNcL7HghvXiswL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252996&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, in the women&#39;s 10-meter platform final of the diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Quan Hongchan won the championship with 438.20 points&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;207C is not actually a difficult move. Quan Hongchan has always danced very well before. The problem is that she has grown taller and her position For female divers, development difficulties must be faced.&quot; He Weiyi, Quan Hongchan&#39;s head coach of the Guangdong Provincial Team, analyzed in a post-match review. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the two years since the Tokyo Olympics, Quan Hongchan has grown 7 centimeters in height and gained weight, which is a difficult problem for divers. Zhou Jihong, the current leader of the national diving team, once pointed out that the women&#39;s 10-meter platform has extremely strict requirements on the height and weight of athletes. Among all diving events, this is the one with the most frequent and cruel personnel iterations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps the most typical positive example is Quan Hongchan’s current head coach and former Olympic diving champion Chen Ruolin. Beginning in 2010, 18-year-old Chen Ruolin began to diet in order to prevent her physical development from interfering with her diving career. She only ate one full meal a day all year round and persisted for 6 years until she retired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Tokyo Olympics, He Weiyi once expressed concern about Quan Hongchan, &quot;Her natural sense of strength is fully capable of helping her through the growth period, but the premise of all this is: she needs enough Self-disciplined and using very strict standards to control her weight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the title of &quot;genius&quot;, He Weiyi does not agree, &quot;People on the Internet praise her too highly. Only through hard training can Only those who have survived development and injuries, as well as physical, psychological, technical, tactical and physical difficulties, can be called a &#39;genius&#39;.&quot; And this is what he expects from Quan Hongchan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fxA4lGMXHXNDbrmGM8CbzbvnJ7hAs2rdHpuA1UOC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;619&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fxA4lGMXHXNDbrmGM8CbzbvnJ7hAs2rdHpuA1UOC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Chinese player Quan Hongchan competed in the women&#39;s 10-meter platform final of the diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The platform duo competed and achieved mutual success&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s single 10-meter platform final of the Hangzhou Asian Games Three days ago, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with a huge advantage in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Tokyo Olympics, the two formed the new women&#39;s synchronized diving combination of the Chinese team. Since &quot;holding hands&quot;, the two have never missed the gold medal in any major or small competition, and their complete sets of movements have basically maintained a score of more than 360. On the court, they are both partners and rivals, so they are often compared together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A common comment is that Quan Hongchan&#39;s specifications (including aerial posture) are slightly higher than Chen Yuxi&#39;s, while the latter&#39;s stability is even better. Entering the Paris Olympic cycle, peak duels between the two often occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the World Diving Championships, Chen Yuxi defeated Quan Hongchan to win the championship; in the Diving World Cup, Chen Yuxi also defeated Quan Hongchan to win the championship, which also made Chen Yuxi only one step away from the Grand Slam. Short of an Olympic singles gold medal, Chen Yuxi has become one of the most stable core members of the Chinese diving team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My advantage is that I am relatively stable, but I cannot say that it is particularly stable, because diving is an event with relatively large changing factors. I can only be regarded as a relatively stable one among many female athletes.&quot; Chen Yu Xi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/6O9C23ovJ5tfv38mLcOZ3igdI73kpznbmFdaEOeO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/6O9C23ovJ5tfv38mLcOZ3igdI73kpznbmFdaEOeO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252995&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, in the women&#39;s 10-meter platform final of the diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Chen Yuxi won the runner-up with 435.65 points&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In fact, before Quan Hongchan was born, Chen Yuxi was also regarded as a genius girl. The experiences of the two are also quite similar - in September 2018, Chen Yuxi was 13 years old. He participated in the adult competition for the first time and won two championships at once, and then entered the national team. Four months later, Chen Yuxi won the women&#39;s single 10-meter platform championship at the World Championships with 439 points. She was considered by the outside world to be a new generation of Chinese diving genius. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CCTV sports reporter Zhang Chaoyang met Chen Yuxi at that time. He recalled in an interview, &quot;Her water splash effect is very similar to the current Quan Hongchan, which is very amazing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/ZXIQ7BNIVjKPjRdScJjCala4FGdNGRxEvh1VSB7J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/ZXIQ7BNIVjKPjRdScJjCala4FGdNGRxEvh1VSB7J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252992&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final of the diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right) and Chen Yuxi (left) won with 375.30 points Champion&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The one-year postponement of the Tokyo Olympics is a challenge for those who have already had the opportunity, and there is an influx of new people , the old man leaves. In 2020, Chen Yuxi has grown 10 centimeters in height, and she needs to readjust many of her movements. In the National Diving Championships, Tokyo Olympics, and World Cup Trials (the first stop was Shijiazhuang), where Hong Chan won the championship, Chen Yuxi, who had experienced a back injury and was in the growth and development period, won the third place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the one hand, I may not have worked hard enough and my movements were not particularly good; on the other hand, that time I felt as if I had seen myself two years ago, just like when I won the national championship in 2018. Once.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/AEhdW1TwtonepccOkoiAFnn5y6Nx9chvwTM5F7FC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;629&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/AEhdW1TwtonepccOkoiAFnn5y6Nx9chvwTM5F7FC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, the champion Chinese player Quan Hongchan (middle), the runner-up Chinese player Chen Yuxi (left), and the third runner-up Malaysian player Pandelela· Linong Anak Pamg at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding partners, Chen Yuxi once said Mentioned in an interview, &quot;The two of us have healthy competition. Only by supervising and improving each other can we improve our own level. If it was just me or her, it is very likely that we would stand still or even regress.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past two years of major and minor competitions, the outside world always likes to compare the results of the two and compare them with each other. When facing the media, Chen Yuxi, who is two years older than Quan Hongchan, always looks like a sister in front of the camera, responding to reporters&#39; questions calmly and patiently. Quan Hongchan beside her is always taciturn and agrees with a smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the game on the evening of October 3, the camera recorded the scene of Chen Yuxi silently squatting down and crying. Next to her, her partner Quan Hongchan was carrying a green turtle-shaped ( Olmila&#39;s backpack, patted her back with his hand, and whispered comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Reference materials: Xinhuanet, &quot;People&quot;, Upstream News, Shangguan News, The Paper.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[闹剧过后，我们如何寻找外星生命？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258060]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Earth is the only celestial body that we currently know has life, but whether the Earth has life in the universe The issue of isolated islands has been debated endlessly. The topic of UFOs and aliens has always been a hot topic of public concern, triggering continuous discussions and becoming a classic theme in science fiction works. At the same time, scientists are also trying to use scientific methods to study this field and look beyond the earth to search for signs of life on exoplanets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Remains of extraterrestrial creatures&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Farce&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are endless revelations about aliens around the world, most of which are due to lack of evidence. Can&#39;t make much of a splash. However, the appearance of the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; at a hearing in the Mexican Congress attracted widespread attention from the media and the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, local time, the Mexican Congress held the first public hearing related to the &quot;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena, UAP&quot; in the capital, Mexico City. At this hearing, Mexican journalist, author and UFO enthusiast Jaime Maussan presented his &quot;discovery&quot; of the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Mozan, the two remains were discovered in a diatom mine in Cusco, Peru, in 2017. After dating by the National Autonomous University of Mexico, the two remains were dated 1,800 years ago. years and 700 years. As can be seen from the pictures at the scene, the remains have an elongated head and three fingers on each hand. The appearance of the two remains is very similar to the alien images described in some science fiction works, causing heated discussions on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mossan stated: &quot;These two remains have nothing to do with humans.&quot; However, the &quot;alien creatures&quot; mentioned by Moosang immediately aroused huge doubts. This is not the first time that Moissan has thrown out similar news. In 2015, Mossan claimed to have discovered the remains of a suspected &quot;alien creature&quot; in Peru and held a ticketed tour. However, the remains were later confirmed to be the mummified remains of a child. In 2017, Mozan claimed to have discovered the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; in the Nazca region of Peru, but was immediately refuted by Peruvian officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;evidence&quot; Moissan gave this time is also unconvincing. In response to Mosan&#39;s statement, the National Accelerator Mass Spectrometry Laboratory of the National Autonomous University of Mexico re-issued a statement that was first released in 2017. The laboratory said in a statement that they were not involved in collecting the samples and had not seen the entire specimen. Therefore, they were only responsible for testing the age of the samples submitted for inspection and would not draw conclusions about the source of the samples. Mosang also claimed that he invited forensic doctors to use X-ray scanning technology to examine the remains and found that there were egg-like structures in the remains. Julieta Fierro, a scientist at the Astronomy Research Center of the National Autonomous University of Mexico, criticized this, saying that more advanced technology than X-ray scanning would be needed to determine whether the two remains were human. Antígona Segura, an astrobiologist at the Nuclear Science Research Center of the National Autonomous University of Mexico, even said: &quot;These conclusions are not supported by evidence at all. The whole thing is shameful.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The Mexican Congress held this hearing to discuss the AirSpace Protection Law (AirSpace Protection Law) and promote relevant legislation. If this law is passed, Mexico will become the first country in the world to recognize &quot;extraterrestrial life forms&quot; &quot;Country that exists. However, after the hearing, the Mexican Congress did not provide conclusive opinions, and the future of this bill is still unclear. Sergio Gutierrez, a member of the Mexican Congress, said: &quot;We are paying attention to this issue and we can continue to discuss it.&quot; However, after being criticized by the scientific community, Moissan&#39;s &quot;discovery&quot; this time There is a high probability that it will end hastily again. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;New &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Report&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; once again arouse people&#39;s attention to extraterrestrial creatures, The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) held a press conference at its headquarters in Washington, DC, on September 14, 2023, local time, and released the latest research report of an independent research team formed by the agency to study unknown anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA defines &quot;unidentified anomalies&quot; as &quot;observations in the sky that cannot be scientifically identified as aircraft or known natural phenomena.&quot; On June 9, 2022, NASA announced the establishment of this research team. The team is composed of 16 experts from different fields such as astronomy, physics, meteorology, etc. These disciplines have varying degrees of connection with the study of unknown anomalies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA believes that researchers have now obtained a certain number of high-quality observations of unknown abnormal events, and have the basic conditions to draw solid scientific conclusions about the nature of these events. Therefore, NASA established this independent research group to examine unidentified anomalies from a scientific perspective and develop a roadmap for how to use data and scientific tools to advance our understanding of unidentified anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public can download the 36-page report from NASA&#39;s official website. The report consists of several parts: the first part briefly introduces the research team and this report, the middle part answers questions such as how the team conducted the research in the form of 8 questions and answers, and the last part is the conclusions, suggestions and Acknowledgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team concluded in this report that there is currently no evidence to support the existence of aliens, and most UFO incidents can be explained by science. But at the same time, they haven&#39;t completely ruled out the possibility of aliens. While the conclusions are not unexpected, the report is important in suggesting what possible data NASA could collect in the future to explore the nature and origins of unidentified anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a press release, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson said: &quot;At NASA, it&#39;s in our DNA to explore and ask why things are the way they are. I would like to express my gratitude to the independent research team for inspiring us on how to better study and analyze unidentified anomalies in the future.&quot; He also emphasized that NASA&#39;s goal is to shift people&#39;s discussion of unidentified anomalies from fantasy to science level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a press conference, NASA said that it has appointed a new director of unidentified anomaly research, who will lead the research team to strengthen artificial intelligence in the process of collecting and analyzing data and the use of machine learning. The report also highlights the need to enhance the application of new technologies in future research. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The answer may be on extrasolar planets&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Planet&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Efforts to find alien life on Earth are based on the fact that alien life has visited the Earth. Such a premise limits the search scope to intelligent creatures capable of reaching the earth. But just as life forms on Earth vary widely, if there is life elsewhere in the universe, it may not be intelligent life, but rudimentary forms like microorganisms on Earth. So when astronomers set their sights on the search for exoplanets, they will be on the lookout for any possible signs of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, at the James Webb Space Telescope’s first year of operation meeting held in Baltimore, Maryland, the United States, an international research team led by the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom announced the results of a famous satellite. This is the latest research result of the exoplanet K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. They found methane and carbon dioxide in the planet&#39;s atmosphere. This is the first time astronomers have found carbon-based molecules in the atmosphere of an exoplanet located in the habitable zone. At the same time, they may also have discovered what is believed to be a chemical on Earth. Chemical substances related to life activities. The research results will also be published in the Astrophysical Journal Letters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This exoplanet is 120 light-years away from the Earth, has a mass about 8.6 times that of the Earth, and a radius 2.6 times that of the Earth. It orbits the cold dwarf star K2-18 and is located in the habitable zone of this system. . Astronomers first probed the planet&#39;s atmosphere using the Hubble Space Telescope, but its composition was controversial at the time. After research, astronomers classified this planet into a category of exoplanets called &quot;Hycean exoplanet&quot;. Such planets have hydrogen-rich atmospheres and ocean-covered planetary surfaces. There are no planets of this size between Earth and Neptune in our solar system. Since then, they have used the James Webb Space Telescope to study the planet in more detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the high-resolution instruments of the James Webb Space Telescope, they confirmed in newly published research that the planet&#39;s atmosphere contains methane and carbon dioxide. At the same time, they also found a weak signal in the spectrum of K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. Analysis showed that this signal may be generated by a molecule called dimethyl sulphide (DMS). On Earth, we currently know that dimethyl sulfide can only be produced by life activities. Most of the dimethyl sulfide in the Earth&#39;s atmosphere is released by marine phytoplankton, which indicates that it may also exist on K2-18&amp;nbsp;b similar life activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our findings highlight the diverse considerations that need to be taken into account in the search for life elsewhere,” said Nikku Madhusudhan, an astronomer at the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom and lead author of the paper. The importance of habitable environments. The search for life on exoplanets has traditionally focused on smaller, rocky planets, but larger hydrogen-marine planets are clearly more amenable to atmospheric observations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, , astronomers still need further observations to confirm the existence of dimethyl sulfide. Madhusudhan said that subsequent observations by the James Webb Telescope will confirm whether dimethyl sulfide is indeed present in the atmosphere of K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. This research team believes that K2-18&amp;nbsp;b and other hydrogen sea planets may be excellent places for us to discover life outside the solar system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The James Webb Space Telescope has been in use for more than a year, demonstrating its powerful observation capabilities and constantly surprising astronomers. As more and more powerful space telescopes and ground-based telescopes are put into use, constructed or put on the development schedule, astronomers will gain increasingly powerful capabilities to observe exoplanets. Maybe discovering extraterrestrial life on Earth is just a fantasy, but if extraterrestrial life really exists, we will be able to detect signs of their activities on an exoplanet in the near future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/LdhG4qqa7a7vUhM2yf5FXKKIbvDGmUxPyUFpWymE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/LdhG4qqa7a7vUhM2yf5FXKKIbvDGmUxPyUFpWymE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Remains on display during a hearing in the Mexican Congress. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Reuters/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/03/2mapv6MsFjVZXXjxxbF70wRaXgQj9T8abzGIy1tm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1094&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/ 2mapv6MsFjVZXXjxxbF70wRaXgQj9T8abzGIy1tm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Member of NASA&#39;s Unidentified Anomaly Research Team. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（NASA/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/03/thCtXyW4lh5rn7bzhiFcHXpwr6JJ30BM9cjSnprR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/thCtXyW4lh5rn7bzhiFcHXpwr6JJ30 BM9cjSnprR .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic imagination of the exoplanet K2-18 b orbiting the cold dwarf star K2-18 picture. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(NASA/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南阳迷笛音乐节营地大量失窃上热搜：全力破案方能挽回声誉丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258070]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 15:28:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Halfway through the long holiday, the Midi Music Festival held in Nanyang, Henan suddenly appeared on the social media hot search list, not because How well done, but because - &quot;stealing things&quot;. For this city that was once famous for Zhuge Wolong, if the case cannot be solved as soon as possible, not only may the next Midi Music Festival be ruined, but it will also affect the reputation of the entire city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, the keywords &quot;Midi steals things&quot; quickly became hot topics on social media. According to information released by netizens at the scene, the music festival had ended the day before, and many music fans who participated in the music festival had not yet evacuated. However, a large number of nearby villagers went into the campground to search for things. According to Solitaire’s stolen property statistics, some people’s clothing and shoes were stolen, some wine and tea were stolen, some camping equipment such as tents, sleeping bags, and moisture-proof mats were lost, and high-value electronic and digital products such as computers, mobile phones, cameras, and recording equipment were stolen. Some &quot;thiefs&quot; only took away the tent, leaving other materials neatly in place. Even the fist-thick cables on the stage were stolen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to self-reported information by the thieves, the total value of the stolen materials may reach hundreds of thousands of yuan. A video circulating on the Internet shows a middle-aged woman who was caught taking something out of her bag while defending herself: &quot;We just went to get it when no one was there,&quot; as if the owner of the tent had temporarily left ( Maybe you go out to eat or even just use the toilet), the things in the tent become ownerless and can be taken as you please. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first original music festival in China, the Midi Music Festival with a history of more than 20 years has become one of the most famous carnivals in the Chinese music industry, especially rock music. For the venue where the music festival is held, tens of thousands of enthusiastic music fans from all over the country will not only bring direct income to the local area, but also become an excellent opportunity to promote the local area. Therefore, many cities, especially third- and fourth-tier cities, are competing to hold or invite large-scale music festivals to be held locally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Midi Music Festival was held in Nanyang and also received great attention from the local area. According to the official social media account &quot;Nanyang Release&quot; of the Nanyang Municipal Government Information Office, on September 29, the opening day of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival, the Secretary of the Nanyang Municipal Party Committee and the Mayor, wearing red volunteer uniforms, personally greeted the guests at the exit of Nanyang Railway Station. Music fans all over the country. Half a month ago, Nanyang City held a preparatory meeting for the Midi Music Festival. The Secretary of the Municipal Party Committee personally made arrangements and required the establishment of a high-standard headquarters at the municipal level to carefully carry out various guarantee work for the music festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening of the music festival, the Nanyang Municipal Government Information Office also released a city image promotional video and a local &quot;food, drink, and fun picture&quot; through its official account to promote local tourism resources. Such high-standard preparation and reception highlight the importance attached to the music festival. It was with this kind of attention that the music festival itself seemed to go without any problems. However, what was unexpected was that large-scale thefts occurred after the festival. It can be said that the previous efforts were ruined. This makes the previous official statement of “protecting the personal and property safety of tourists” a joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to theft, netizens who attended the music festival accused some people of harassing tourists in the name of toasting during dinner in the hotel, and even beating tourists while drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This information spreads rapidly through social networks. If the local area fails to take prompt measures to identify problems such as theft and harassment, it will greatly damage the image of the local area. In addition to the stolen music fans who said that if there is no result in handling this incident, they will never visit Nanyang again. Some netizens also said that they felt very unsafe after watching the video of the villagers taking things away, and they will definitely do so when traveling in the future. Avoid this place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the descriptions of the thieves and live music fans, most of the thieves were local villagers, who even used tricycles to pull the items. This scene can&#39;t help but remind people of the situations that have happened in many places before where villagers stole the crops of foreign agricultural entrepreneurs. It was reported in the summer of 2019 that a sweet potato farmer in Henan contracted 200 acres of land to grow watermelons. When the watermelons matured, nearby villagers gathered in groups to steal the melons. A melon-picking incident also occurred in Jiaxing, Zhejiang, where almost all the watermelons from more than 20 greenhouses were stolen. Some melon thieves were even caught by melon farmers and fell to the ground and were &quot;injured&quot; during the pulling process. Instead, the melon farmers were asked to pay compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these theft incidents, some places often use various excuses to excuse local farmers. For example, it is not &quot;theft&quot;, but they believe the rumor that &quot;the owner doesn&#39;t want it anymore&quot;, or there are people in the local area who are not the owners. The tradition of “picking up the leaks” after harvesting, etc. In the Midi Music Festival theft incident, some participants alleged that after catching the thief and calling the police, the police let the villagers go because &quot;there was no evidence to prove the theft.&quot; If the property of participants cannot be protected for a large-scale event that the government attaches so much importance to, who will dare to come here in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that the quality of villagers in some places is not high, they are greedy for petty gains, and their legal awareness is weak. They have the idea that the law does not punish the public, and they feel that taking some things from &quot;outsiders&quot; will not do anything. If local officials do not take severe measures to punish these thieving villagers and cannot effectively protect the interests of foreign tourists or investors, and their reputation is ruined, no one will dare to travel or invest here again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement from the Midi Music Festival Organizing Committee, the local police have set up a task force to investigate the theft cases. Some fans also reported that some of the stolen items had been recovered. This time Nanyang must make every effort to solve the case, recover the stolen goods, reduce the losses of music fans, and at the same time severely punish the thieves without mercy. Only in this way can it be possible to restore the reputation, restore the music festival, restore the music fans, and restore the tourists from all over the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[颜歌：英语世界里的少数族裔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/ERThthpwjc4pFBkH71171Fy2GAIFQY7zJqMvpifj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ERThthpwjc4pFBkH71171Fy2GAIFQY7z JqMvpifj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Feng Xiaoping/Picture)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in the summer of 2017, Yan Ge was vaccinating her one-month-old son at a clinic in Dublin when she suddenly received an email from Irish writer Lucy Caldwell. She was invited to contribute to Faber&#39;s short story collection Being Various: New Irish Short Stories ( &quot;Short Story Collection&quot;&lt;/span>;) Write a novel. Lucy is the editor of this collection. She had read two of Yan Gefa&#39;s stories in the &quot;Irish Times&quot; and found them interesting, so she came here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ge still remembers her shock at that time: first of all, she was an outsider, no one in the Irish literary world knew her, she had only published two novels in newspapers; secondly, she was the only one in Ireland. How did you become an Irish writer after living for a few years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that email that made Yan Ge feel unreal, Lucy greatly broadened the concept of Irish writers - this concept should include writers who were born in Ireland but grew up elsewhere, and writers who were chosen from elsewhere. Writers who call Ireland home include those who somehow find themselves living in Ireland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What happened next unfolded smoothly. Yan Ge wrote a story that took place in Dublin, &quot;How I Fell in Love with the Well-Documented Life of Alex Whelan&quot;, which was well received and included in this new collection of Irish short stories. The first article (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Published in 2019&lt;/span>;). Later, Angus, the editor of &quot;Different: A Collection of New Irish Short Stories&quot; and director of Faber Publishing, learned that Yan Ge was writing a collection of short stories and approached his agent, Matt, hoping to She gave Faber exclusive preview rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fNclzsO4zmmZmaYmqR2Fj9t55L8glzuUoiCpIvtK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1279&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fNclzsO4zmmZmaYmqR2Fj9t55L8glzuUoiCpIvtK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yan Ge visited Wangcong Temple in his hometown of Pi County when he was a child&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faber is a purely literary publishing organization founded in 1921. It has published the works of 13 Nobel Prize writers and 6 Booker Prize writers. There will be no sky-high royalties, and packaging and promotion will not cost as much as cutting-edge companies. If it is not given to Faber, the agent will submit the work to various publishing houses. If multiple publishing houses compete for the manuscript, it will be auctioned. As a result, the manuscript may be sold at a relatively high price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Matt believes that Faber is suitable for Yan Ge’s work. It is of stable quality, responsible, and can be cooperated for a long time. Moreover, the editors of this book are Kazuo Ishiguro and Sebastian. Barry&#39;s managing editor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally Faber was given exclusive preview rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The exclusive preview period generally does not exceed 10 days. Faber responded quickly. He sent the message on Friday and gave the quotation on Wednesday. After the two parties negotiated, it was determined on Thursday that he would buy the rights to two books, including the completed &quot;Elsewhere&quot; and another book scheduled to be delivered in 2024. The novel &quot;Hotel Destination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This means that the next five years are almost bought out.&quot; Yan Ge is worried that the second book is due to be delivered in April 2024 according to the contract, and because of the Chinese novel &quot;Pingle County Chronicles&quot; All work is behind schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The veteran American literary publisher Scribner will also acquire the copyright for Yan Ge’s collection of short stories and the 2024 novel. Scribner published works by Hemingway and Fitzgerald. It was later acquired by Simon &amp; Schuster and became the company&#39;s flagship publishing house. It also published books by pure literary writers such as Annie Proulx. , and also publishes works by Stephen King, the master of horror novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/JN1pQDJEs7PrVeKtiyHqlhyTdiV0MdHfQob3MpvM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/JN1pQDJEs7PrVeKtiyHqlhyTdiV0MdHfQob3MpvM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The signing process with Scribner went smoothly beyond Yan Ge&#39;s expectations. The editor-in-chief and two young editors chatted with Yan Ge over video for an afternoon about the work, and in the evening they settled on North American rights with their agent. Next, the Italian copyright was also negotiated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ge felt a bit like selling futures at the time: &quot;The unfinished novel was sold directly like this. This was the first time in my writing career of more than 20 years. Yes. It may not be a big deal for an English writer, but it is unimaginable for a writer whose mother tongue is Chinese and writes in English.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2023, &quot;Elsewhere&quot; will be published in the UK and the United States. , winning praise from media outlets including The Irish Times, The Guardian, The New York Times and The New Yorker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2023, Yan Ge took her son and husband back to Chengdu after three years of COVID-19. To be precise, back to Pidu District (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Originally known as Pixian County&lt;/span>;) - her hometown - the birthplace of her story of Pingle Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Xis0q8rlqbXScWzR65rY41RJobjmCII9eySPGN9Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1611&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Xis0q8rlqbXScWzR65rY41RJobjmCII9eySPGN9Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; We are here to oppose English”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will interview you in the summer of 2018 At that time, you were embarking on a creative writing project in the UK, published two novels in the &quot;Irish Times&quot;, and had just completed one of Faber&#39;s &quot;New Irish Novels&quot;. It was a year later that you got an agent. matter. What impressed me most is that you metaphorically joined the &quot;Special Olympics&quot; in the English literary world. Five years later, you have become an English writer signed with a first-class international literary publishing house. Do you still feel like a Paralympian? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t feel that way anymore. English writing is a new career for me now, and I face many problems, but they are not so-called language problems, or language is the most superficial problem, and it may not even be considered a problem compared with other problems. English writing is a kind of artistic self-exploration for me. If I were an artist, my medium would be words. Now I am using a new way, new tools, new materials and media to make works. This new medium will bring a new change to my works. This is the most important thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember the last interview, you were right I said there is nothing terrible about writing in English. The tone is exactly the same as now. Is there any substantial difference between the two? For example, five years ago you were more free to enjoy the freedom of expression that the new language brought to you. Now , after strict writing training in the English literary tradition, have you found some kind of certainty in your writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/eHU1AudW5hab48AceoNgsAEGGT6WpLwPg9ssMeN6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1606&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/eHU1AudW5hab48AceoNgsAEGGT6WpLwPg9ssMeN6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Definitely. During the process of studying and living in the UK, I read more and more things in depth, which must be related. I think these are also based on my culture. After all, I am a Chinese writer, so my literary system and narrative system are Chinese. Although I now understand more or less how the other system works, I feel that Chinese is still my language. The root of this is that, ultimately, the way of thinking about Chinese and Chinese literature is an anti-dualistic way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the English-speaking world, the writing of minority writers like us is a kind of post-colonial cultural expression that must subvert the so-called orthodox English. This is why English as a This is a fate that postcolonial language must face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Irish writers are probably the first group of writers in the world to write in this post-colonial way, and they are also anti-English. After the British occupied Ireland, Irish became an illegal language. If you spoke Irish, you would be fined and arrested. My husband is Irish. As an intellectual and journalist, he always tells me that you can write in English however you want. We are here to oppose this language anyway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So when I returned to Ireland, I felt like I was returning to my second natal home. Dublin was the last stop for the promotion of my new English book. As a result, all the tickets for the sharing session were sold out, the venue was full, and there were people sitting on the windowsill. , I was very moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/avrzkseviR85yr9K8a9wqJRvjyUOm3eLrZSKA2Ll.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1673&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/avrzkseviR85yr9K8a9wqJRvjyUOm3eLrZSKA2Ll.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In that environment, no one will care about your language. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, no one will think about this problem. It may have something to do with Irish culture. Everyone thinks this is a natural thing. The two stories I submitted to The Irish Times were published directly by the editor, which made me feel like I had landed in front of English readers. Originally, I was waiting for the editor to give me a lot of revision comments. Gradually, I learned that newspapers here have this tradition and are not very good at changing the author&#39;s manuscripts. Only magazines and books have an editorial process. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/s6ywYWgeztUMcCVqMgdxXBeSyPXZlFhN0QU0bxL5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1674&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/s6ywYWgeztUMcCVqMgdxXBeSyPXZlFhN0QU0bxL5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In the English writing circle, everyone reads and comments on each other&#39;s manuscripts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;When you first write in English, do you show it to your husband first? I remember when I interviewed Ha Jin in 2001, he said that when he first wrote a novel, he would check whether the words were authentic to his son who was born in the United States. At that time, he had just won the National Book Award in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Some of them will be read to him. My husband is my first reader. When I write Chinese, I will also translate it orally to him. share. But if it involves a subject with a Chinese cultural background, it will not be shown to him, but to people who do not understand Chinese culture at all. For example, there is an article &quot;Hai&quot; (Hai) in &quot;Elsewhere&quot;, which is about Confucius and his disciples. It also alludes to the British political system. People without a Chinese cultural background will see a completely different connotation. I asked a historical novelist to read the manuscript, which was more than 20,000 words. She read it carefully and wrote a lot of feedback. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the English writing circle, one thing that I like very much is that everyone reads each other&#39;s manuscripts, devotes a lot of time and energy to each other&#39;s works, and also gives sharp opinions. . My agent was also one of my early readers. This atmosphere is particularly healthy. These people I trust allow me to be bolder and try more things and experiment with more languages ​​without looking forward or backward. It’s like I’m doing acrobatics in this language. Even if I fall down, there are still people. then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chinese writers don’t do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Chinese literature talks about genius. I prefer the workshop tradition among British and American literary creative groups. Discussions and discussions give me the feeling of being in a community. A girlfriend of mine sent me a manuscript that she had revised 36 times and asked me to make further comments. Chinese writers would avoid doing this because it would cast doubt on their own genius. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My soon-to-be-published Chinese novel &quot;Pingle County Chronicles&quot; is the product of many years of work behind closed doors. When I first finished it, I was very scared and didn&#39;t know how to write it. I sent it to &quot;Harvest&quot; When editing, I especially hope she can give me feedback. For example, for many ancient poems in the book, I asked the editor to find professionals to help review them. If no one comments, I&#39;m like running around naked, which is terrible. I am probably used to the way Western creative writing groups operate, and I am afraid that others will not give me advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zsh2qmh3keyX0vJMj2Y08Uu0P6vmIJHDLtiRydRp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1671&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zsh2qmh3keyX0vJMj2Y08Uu0P6vmIJHDLtiRydRp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; The editor wanted me to delete the redundant convoluted parts.&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When writing in English, have you ever imagined what your readers are like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I write in Chinese, I can imagine my readers. I am not necessarily writing for them, but there is probably an implicit reference to the readers. concept. But when writing in English, I feel a sense of panic all the time - I can&#39;t imagine what the reader looks like. He is definitely not white, but I don&#39;t know who he is - he has no face and no identity. I wasn&#39;t a first or second generation immigrant either, just someone stuck there temporarily, and imaginary readers became one of my biggest problems. Then there is the feeling of doing an academic experiment. According to my own interests, if I get to this point today, I will write this, and if I get to that point tomorrow, I will write that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These are also the novels in &quot;Elsewhere&quot; What’s the reason for the different themes and very different writing techniques? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. When I write in Chinese, I am very rooted - very grounded, so that I can absorb nutrients and feel at ease, but at the same time, it is also tied and fixed. English writing is rootless, very unstable, yet full of vitality and possibility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now is your first English short story Now that the collection has been published, do you know who your readers are? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I met various ethnic minority writers at reading events and book signings in the UK. They felt that my works It inspired them - they told me that someone like me wrote such a book in such a way, which moved them very much. There are people like this everywhere I go. They are very young, and many of them are ethnic minority authors who are studying creative writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very happy, I found that I am writing for these people. We minority writers interact with each other and open up a new English writing space. I just give this The space adds some more possibilities. For example, the most superficial expression is that you can add Chinese to English novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is easy to fall into the trap of dualism when discussing &quot;readers&quot;. Generally speaking, the English readers that come to mind must be the mainstream society dominated by white people. I think this idea is quite original and very 80s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Basically from your agent to your book editor Being white and male represents a certain center of power. Does your work being published by well-known established publishing houses in the UK and the United States mean that you are moving closer to a certain center? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As an ethnic minority writer, the English I write must be essentially against English (Against English). It’s not that I want to join the so-called English literature, but literature that is completed using English as the language (Literatures in English). My agent and editors are very supportive of my starting point. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current context, if you think that people like me must knock on the door and enter a certain center, then it is essentially worship and submission to the Anglo-center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you are not writing for white readers or do not want to enter the mainstream, In addition to challenging traditional English reading habits from a textual perspective—for example, by including some ancient Chinese poems or even Chinese characters—do you express your stance from other perspectives? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will not exclude a certain group, nor will I particularly try to please a certain group. For example, there are local white people in my collection of novels, but there are also Chinese things, including Chinese characters, as well as the non-linear time structure of traditional Chinese literature, and even anti-simplification. But I also hope that every type of reader can enter my text and have his own understanding when he leaves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the partial uninterpretability of the text is also part of my plan. Making certain paragraphs and details into something completely unfamiliar at first glance is also my expression. a part of. In fact, it’s a bit similar to how I write in Sichuan dialect. I don’t want to reject Mandarin readers when I write in Sichuan dialect. I just want to retain the characteristics of Sichuan dialect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WfloG6z6i6dlSkOIHtTQzdDOmxz72QNSy24Djnlf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1220&quot; height= &quot;994&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WfloG6z6i6dlSkOIHtTQzdDOmxz72QNSy24Djnlf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Elsewhere&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the collection &quot;Elsewhere&quot;, it is a bit like a mixture, with some traditional Western literary meanings novel, but also has Chinese logic and Chinese literary values. For example, in &quot;Travel in the Summer&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;travel in summer&quot;&lt;/span>;), I want to express many things. Deliberately a little idle, this kind of technique is not allowed in English novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remember when I first published this story in a Canadian magazine, the editor thought the story was very good, but wanted me to delete the redundant convoluted parts. I felt a little embarrassed at that time. As a writer, I was very willing to accept other people&#39;s opinions, but in the end I wrote her a long email saying that this was an ancient Chinese story, so I hope This classical China is both in content and form. I said that the protagonist of this story is Shen Kuo, and his book wants to cover everything in the universe. This inclusiveness is also the focus of this story. I also talked about some background about implicitness and leisurely writing, and finally she was convinced by me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When it comes to Chinese writers who write in English, people will mention Ha Jin or Li Yiyun, their backgrounds are completely different from yours. They only started writing when they arrived in the United States. However, you were already a budding novelist before going abroad. Your works have been translated into more than a dozen languages. As a &quot;second generation&quot; of Chinese immigrant writers, ”, how do you view your identity? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/NWvZdPVElVapeMpBJCve26MW33AJ2eJMOjzFhIDQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1694&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/NWvZdPVElVapeMpBJCve26MW33AJ2eJMOjzFhIDQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left to right are translator Natasha Bruce, Canadian novelist Madeleine Thien, Yan Ge&#39;s &quot;Our Family&quot; translator Nicky Harman, Yan Ge after the Times Literary Festival Group photo &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It should be said that I am very Fortunately, because I have indeed written more and longer in Chinese literature, I always feel that Chinese is my home field, and I just come to the English world to play, so I am relatively confident. Why should I try to please white people? I feel like my work is more de-duality. If I were asked to write like a white person, I wouldn’t want to. It doesn’t make any sense to me and is a particularly ridiculous thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another fortunate thing is that Ha Jin and Li Yiyun have helped our generation of writers complete the exploration of themes and wrote many &quot;Chinese stories&quot;. Our generation can no longer When writing in English, the subject matter can be broader and the form can be freer. I read Li Yiyun&#39;s first short story collection more than ten years ago when I first went abroad. At that time, I couldn&#39;t see how good it was. That book was actually not written for Chinese readers like me. Now her works have long gone out of the box at that time, becoming more and more open and better. To a certain extent, it is precisely because the kind of &quot;Chinese stories&quot; that the white mainstream society needed have been written before. Now she and many of us can get out of this stereotype and write stories related to China or It has nothing to do with it. If you write about the real or virtual world, the Middle Ages or the sci-fi future, you can be more creative in content and form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Interview Assistant: Zhu Zhu.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子10米台，全红婵失误后反超以微弱优势夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258066]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 13:00:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72935&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69789&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/50c67b3a66.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi will each Holding their cute dolls in their hands..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi held their respective cute dolls in their hands.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/50c67b3a66.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252983&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi held their respective cute dolls in their hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of October 3, 2023, the championship battle for the women&#39;s single 10-meter platform diving event at the Hangzhou Asian Games became Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi The rivalry between this pair of teammates. Quan Hongchan finally won the gold medal with 438.20 points, and Chen Yuxi won the silver medal with a gap of 2.55 points. The Chinese diving &quot;dream team&quot; won the championship and runner-up in this event without any suspense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72929&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69783&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/a6c83674bf.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the Chinese team Quan Hongchan was in the competition. She came back against the wind on the last jump and won the championship..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023 October On March 3, the Chinese team Quan Hongchan competed. She made a comeback against the wind on the last jump and won the championship.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/a6c83674bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252984&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, the Chinese team was all Hongchan in the game. She came back against the wind on the last jump and won the championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72933&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69787&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/fa82db0998.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, after the game, Quan Hongchan waved to the audience..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, after the game, Quan Hongchan Chan waved to the audience.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fa82db0998.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252985&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023 Afterwards, Quan Hongchan waved to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the competition, Quan Hongchan performed perfectly in the second jump, and all 7 judges scored a perfect 10 points! In the third jump, Chen Yuxi was not to be outdone and also scored three 10 points. But in the fourth jump, Quan Hongchan made a mistake in her 207 move and was overtaken by Chen Yuxi. On the last jump, Quan Hongchan performed perfectly and achieved another reversal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72930&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69784&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/dd421d9df2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team Chen Yuxi was in the game. .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;October 2023 On the 3rd, Chen Yuxi of the Chinese team was in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /04/dd421d9df2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252986&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On October 3, Chen Yuxi of the Chinese team competed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72931&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69785&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0bfc42fa6a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;October 3, 2023, Chinese team Chen Yuxi was in the game. In the third jump, Chen Yuxi also scored 3 10 points..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chen Yuxi of the Chinese team was in the game. In the third jump , Chen Yuxi also scored 3 10 points.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/04/0bfc42fa6a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252987&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team Chen Yuxi was in the game. In the third jump, Chen Yuxi also scored three 10 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the game, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan also hugged each other tightly. Previously, in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Quan Hongchan partnered with Chen Yuxi and won the championship with a &quot;disruptive lead&quot;, scoring 85.26 points higher than the second place. Ever since Quan Hongchan won the gold medal in the singles 10-meter platform at the Tokyo Olympics, she and Chen Yuxi began to dominate the 10-meter platform. In the strong dialogue between teammates, the competition and promotion between the two athletes is a positive phenomenon for the Chinese diving team. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72932&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69786&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/04/811a20585d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the Chinese team was all red during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the Chinese team was all red Chan in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/811a20585d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252988&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023, Chinese team Quan Hongchan in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games diving event will be held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium from September 30 to October 4, 2023. A total of 10 gold medals will be produced. gold medal. In the eight events that have already determined gold medals, the Chinese team won all gold medals. October 4th is the last competition day. The Chinese diving &quot;dream team&quot; is still aiming for the championship and aims to win the gold medal in all minor events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72934&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69788&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/87c324647a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi showed the medals in their hands..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi showing the medals in their hands.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04 /87c324647a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252989&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 3rd, Quan Hongchan and Chen Yuxi showed off their medals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[硬气王哲林爆扣韩国队，中国男篮领先14分胜韩国队进入半决赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258064]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:38:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72924&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69778&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game. .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252974&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At noon on October 3, 2023, in the quarter-finals of the Hangzhou Asian Games men&#39;s basketball team, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team defeated the South Korean men&#39;s basketball team 84-70 and advanced to the Asian Games. The top four. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team was tested in the group stage, it ushered in the Korean team, one of the most popular teams in the Asian Games. Compared with other strong Asian teams, the South Korean team is basically playing with all its main players in this Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72925&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69779&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game. &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 252975&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72927&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69781&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/1ecd290854.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhao Rui made a layup during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhao Rui A layup in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1ecd290854.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252976&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023, China Team player Zhao Rui made a layup during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72922&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69776&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Hu Jinqiu made a layup during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Hu Jinqiu A layup in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252977&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023, China Team player Hu Jinqiu made a layup during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72921&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69775&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252978&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国男篮掌握节奏，攻防俱佳，展现出了十足的拼劲，上半场领先20分。下半场，中国男篮失误相对增多，但在防守端依旧强硬，牢牢守住优势，最终以84比70战胜韩国队，打进半决赛。从本场比赛可以看出中国男篮球员的斗志，朱俊龙、胡金秋多次主动倒地拼抢地板球；赵睿开局阶段强势突破连连得分；杜润旺出色地完成了外线投射的任务，在防守端也竭尽全力……中国男篮为了赢得这场比赛确实下了功夫。全场比赛，杜润旺16分、胡金秋14分7篮板、赵睿8分但是有6次失误、朱俊龙16分、张镇麟9分、胡明轩10分、赵继伟5分8助攻、王哲林6分。 &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72923&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69777&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252979&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此前的采访中，中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，作为卫冕冠军，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72926&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69780&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1:4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1/4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252980&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1/4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;接下来，中国男篮将在10月4日20时的半决赛中，对阵曾在世界杯赛场击败过我们的菲律宾男篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72928&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69782&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252981&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[莫斯吾冰川：人迹罕至，傲然挺立丨眼睛在旅游⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:25:13 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>