<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[爱上长者饭堂的年轻人，图什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258867]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Visit:&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Clean and hygienic prices are not expensive&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Elderly The canteen is popular among some young people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The braised pork with pickled cabbage, stir-fried pork with cauliflower, green vegetables, corn and carrot soup... The reporter showed weekly items in the canteen of the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street in Tianhe District. It can be seen from the menu that the canteen serves lunch and dinner from Monday to Sunday. Each meal is a fixed set meal of three dishes, one soup and one rice. It has a complete range of meat and vegetables and rich combinations. It also provides &quot;special meals&quot; for the elderly with special needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Tianhe District meal subsidy standards, seniors of different ages and household registration status can receive subsidies ranging from 3 yuan to 6 yuan on the basis of the original price of 13 yuan. The package price for the public is It&#39;s 14 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with ordinary restaurants, the elderly canteen mainly caters to the tastes of the elderly. It uses boiling, stewing, steaming and other methods to make the ingredients soft and easy to digest, and focuses on less salt, less oil and lower fat. The reporter bought a meal at the scene and found that the overall taste was light and not greasy, and the vegetables were cut into small pieces for easy chewing and digestion. The staff in the canteen told reporters, &quot;Our ingredients are shipped back from the market every day. They are fresh and hygienic, and the quality is guaranteed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/19/f6e41a4d9497fa32c08613c6f6a9335a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/f6e41a4d9497fa32c08613c6f6a9335a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254625&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/19/47af6d44c18fb4bc438a66ae5d8eabd4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/19/47af6d44c18fb4bc438a66ae5d8eabd4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254623&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the canteen for the elderly at the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street, Tianhe District, reporters were at the scene I bought a portion of rice and found that the overall taste was light and not greasy, and the vegetables were cut into small pieces for easy chewing and digestion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At lunchtime, in the elderly canteen on Jinhua Street, Liwan District, people came to line up to eat, including many young people. The reporter noticed that there was a long queue at a restaurant 100 meters away from the elderly dining hall, and the waiting time was long, but here you can have a delicious meal in less than five minutes. &quot;It&#39;s easier than bringing food by yourself, and it&#39;s cheaper and more hygienic than ordering takeout. My aunt&#39;s hands don&#39;t shake when she cooks.&quot; The elderly canteen is the best choice for young office worker Xiao Lu (pseudonym) to have lunch at noon. She said that the elderly canteen The canteen is a good solution to the dietary needs of office workers in their fast-paced life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/09760323e8b0efda552ee4afa82e5388.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3006&quot; height=&quot;2255&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/09760323e8b0efda552ee4afa82e5388.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254621&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/51c0bd6bd6b64eb57eeb24d9b5553c0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/51c0bd6bd6b64eb57eeb24d9b5553c0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254622&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The menu posted at the senior citizens’ canteen on Jinhua Street, Liwan District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outside the door of the elderly canteen in Shigang Community, Haizhu District, a poster reads: &quot;Based on the latest situation of elderly care services, the Nanshitou Street Elderly Canteen is actively developing special services for this street and launching &#39; &quot;For the People&#39;s Canteen&#39; Model&quot;. Here, the canteen not only serves the elderly, but also serves as a social catering supplement to community residents of all ages in Nanshitou Street. Young people can also come to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the dining hall, there is a vertical row in the corridor, which shows that the opening hours of dining area A are 11:00-12:30 and 17:00-18:00. The &quot;Canteen Weekly Menu&quot; is also pasted on the wall, showing the recipes from Monday to Friday in detail. The reporter visited on Tuesday and found that the lunch included steamed chicken with mushrooms and cloud fungus, stir-fried pork with celery and bean curd skin, seasonal vegetables and hand-baked smooth meat. The dishes had a reasonable mix of meat and vegetables, and the overall taste was relatively light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young lady who was taking her children to dine told reporters that she saw the relevant publicity of the &quot;Weimin Canteen&quot; on the Internet platform, and some elderly people nearby also recommended this canteen. She decided to bring her children over for dinner. &quot;The main thing is that the price is relatively cheap and the environment is clean and hygienic. Because it is positioned as a canteen for the elderly, the ingredients are relatively healthy and fresh, so you can feel free to bring your children here to eat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, not all senior citizen canteens are currently open to residents of all ages. When the reporter called the elderly canteen of Huaxin Community on Linhe Street, the person in charge said that young people cannot dine here. Only seniors over 60 years old can dine here with a senior citizen card. The service targets are limited to the elderly with Linhe Street household registration. Applicants need to book related services one day in advance. The central kitchen will prepare the food the next day and deliver it to their doorsteps in the form of fast food. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Trend:&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Some elderly canteens are becoming &quot;community canteens&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Young people and old people do not interfere with each other&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; More and more young people like to go to the elderly canteen. Some netizens are worried that the elderly canteen is designed and built for the elderly, and whether the influx of young people will crowd out the dining space and welfare of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can young people eat in the elderly canteen? Does the emergence of young people affect the operation of the elderly canteen? Staff at the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street said that at present, some elderly canteens are gradually evolving into &quot;community canteens&quot; open to residents of all ages. Secondly, the daily meal supply in the elderly canteen is sufficient, and young people cannot enjoy the elderly subsidy. &quot;Except for the elderly who meet the standards and can enjoy the subsidy, the rest buy it at the original price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Old people usually come to eat after 11 o&#39;clock, while young people don&#39;t come back from work until after 12 o&#39;clock, and the elderly have already finished eating.&quot; The staff said that the meal times of young working people and the elderly are different, which naturally creates a staggered peak and does not conflict with each other. . Therefore, there is no problem of squeezing resources when young people come to dine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked whether the low pricing would put pressure on canteen operations, the staff said that the purpose of opening the elderly canteen is not to make a profit. At the same time, the Yee Hong Center is a comprehensive Elderly care service centers can also maintain normal operations of the institution through other services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the Shigang Community Elderly Canteen also said that young people and the elderly have different meal times. The elderly come earlier, while young people usually come to the canteen around 12 o&#39;clock after get off work. It said that during peak dining periods, the elderly canteen will have separate dining areas for young and elderly people. In order to make it easier for the elderly to get their meals, dining area A for the elderly is closer to the dining outlet, while dining area B for young people is located slightly further away. At the same time, for groups such as the elderly with registered residence in Guangzhou who are eligible for government subsidies, the government will subsidize varying amounts of meals based on the type of service recipients, such as for the elderly with registered residence in Guangzhou who are 60 years old and above, meal delivery elderly, 18-59 Disabled persons with first- or second-level household registration in Guangzhou will receive a subsidy of 3 yuan per meal, while those living in extreme poverty and living in scattered areas will receive a subsidy of 6 yuan per meal. Young people and the elderly who are not registered in Guangzhou do not have a subsidy amount and need to pay for their meals in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that when it comes to matching dishes, the canteen first considers the tastes of local elderly people in Guangzhou, paying attention to the nutrition of the dishes and the softness of the rice. At the same time, the dining area of ​​the canteen has 6-10 dishes to choose from, and they will also put one or two dishes suitable for young people&#39;s tastes, such as some spicy dishes. In addition, some small boxes of chili, soy sauce and other condiments will be placed on the dining table, so consumers with heavy tastes can freely use them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/99a4f7494057b24c81f00ed5e845637c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3468&quot; height=&quot;4624&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/99a4f7494057b24c81f00ed5e845637c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254624&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The elderly canteen in Shigang Community, Haizhu District, launched the &quot;canteen for the people&quot; model, which not only serves the elderly, but also serves as a social The catering supplement covers community residents of all ages in Nanshitou Street, and young people can also come to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Guangzhou also has some dining spots for the elderly co-constructed with universities. For example, the cafeterias of South China University of Technology, Jinan University, South China Normal University, South China Agricultural University and other universities have set up dining halls for the elderly. . In order to ensure the quality of catering services for the elderly, the opening hours of the elderly canteen are staggered with students&#39; dining times, and a dedicated window is set up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7e28111a0d2e4bd1ca6fdb424fe2e078.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7e28111a0d2e4bd1ca6fdb424fe2e078.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254626&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to ensure the quality of catering services for the elderly at Jinan University, the opening hours of the elderly canteen are staggered with students’ dining times, and a dedicated window. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Voice:&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Some people in charge hope to solve the problem of swiping social security cards on the spot as soon as possible&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At a fast food on Shipai East Road in Tianhe ( A restaurant that combines a simple meal with an elderly canteen. There is a price sign at the door. The person in charge told reporters: &quot;Ordinary customers calculate meal expenses based on this price standard, and additional discounts will be given to the elderly. , and the elderly can swipe their social security cards to pay for meals. The elderly and ordinary customers pay in two areas, which can reduce the time of queuing and save time for dining.&quot; The person in charge said that the dishes in the store have taken the public into consideration. It is formulated after the taste, so the tastes of both young and old can be basically satisfied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch time, the customers in the store were old and young, including many nearby students and working citizens. A college student interviewed said: &quot;It&#39;s close to the school, and you don&#39;t have to wait in line for too long. You can get food faster, which is very convenient.&quot; Some students who came to eat also said: &quot;The food here is very delicious. Yes, the price is okay.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/24eb98bc55783a93900c51772bb2eade.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/24eb98bc55783a93900c51772bb2eade.jpeg&quot; data-key =&quot;254627&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A two-in-one fast food (simple meal) and elderly canteen restaurant on Shipai East Road, Tianhe , the customers in the store are old and young, including many nearby students and citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An elderly canteen on Huajing North Road in Tianhe District also operates a two-in-one business model of fast food (simple meals) and an elderly canteen. The difference is that the elderly in this store Different from the dishes for ordinary customers, the store has a weekly menu specifically for the elderly, which changes every Monday. Meals for senior citizens cost 12 yuan, while meals for ordinary customers cost 18-20 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that if the elderly are not satisfied with the dishes of the day, or do not want to eat a certain dish, within their ability, they can discuss with the elders to change the desired dishes. For example, if the elderly don&#39;t want to eat, the store will also provide noodles, dumplings and other dishes for the elderly to choose from; or if the elderly say they don&#39;t want to eat fish, they will replace it with chicken. In this way, the elderly Can have more food choices. The person in charge said that because their home is more humane, it has attracted many elderly people to come here. Even the elderly from the nearby elderly center also come here to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge told reporters that he is 77 years old and has been running a canteen for the elderly for many years, but what has always made him regretful is that the restaurant’s catering system stipulates that the dining time for the elderly is from 11 a.m. to 11 a.m. At 1 o&#39;clock at noon, &quot;many elderly people who came back from the hospital for follow-up visits missed 1 o&#39;clock and had no meal supplements.&quot; The person in charge also told reporters that because only social security cards can be swiped in the store, elderly people with inconveniences cannot come. If you swipe your card in the store, you may not be able to use the discount. The person in charge hopes to solve the problem of only swiping cards (social security cards) on the spot as soon as possible, so that they can provide door-to-door card swiping services and deliver meals to more elderly people with limited mobility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二轮中央巡视启动，“回头看”两家单位丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259035]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/16CZ3PuVIXghK8WhmZW3FjXSzj7JLlMsIzWDZpjs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/16CZ3PuVIXghK8WhmZW3FjXSzj7 JLlMsIzWDZpjs. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254765&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China will carry out inspections of the Party Committee of China Railway Group &quot;Looking Back&quot; look&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China has begun. As of October 19, 2023, there are 14 inspection teams entered 24 inspected units and announced work information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, the second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee will carry out regular inspections of party committees (party groups) of 31 units; inspections will be carried out on the party groups of the National Railway Administration and the party groups of China Railway Group. look back&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 31 companies regularly inspected include 5 government departments, namely the Ministry of Science and Technology, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, the State Administration of Science, Technology and Industry for National Defense, and the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration. Another 26 central enterprises were included in the inspection list, focusing on FAW, Dongfeng, Baowu Steel, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the division of labor, during this round of inspections, the Fifth Central Inspection Team was responsible for &quot;looking back&quot; at the two units. The team leader was Geng Changyou, who is currently the director of the Cadre Bureau of the Central Propaganda Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public reports, the Fifth Inspection Team of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China held a mobilization meeting recently to conduct a &quot;look back&quot; inspection of the National Railway Administration Party Group. Geng Changyou gave a mobilization speech. He said that the inspection team will keep a close eye on the powers and responsibilities, keep a close eye on the &quot;top leaders&quot; and the leadership team, keep a close eye on the outstanding issues that the masses have strongly reported, keep a close eye on the rectification and application of the results of the inspection, and strive to find and correct The Central Inspection Team will work in the National Railway Administration for about 2 months to detect political deviations and outstanding problems in the performance of duties by the inspected party organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the 24 inspection team leaders who have been stationed in the inspected units are cadres from the discipline inspection and supervision system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leader of the Central First Inspection Team stationed in China Minmetals Corporation, China Aluminum Corporation of China, and China Mineral Resources Corporation is Cui Peng, who is currently the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Committee in the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Wang Lishan, leader of the Central Third Inspection Team stationed in the Ministry of Science and Technology, was a member of the Standing Committee of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection. He is currently the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission at the National People&#39;s Congress. Li Yingchun, leader of the 7th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the 11th Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Chen Zhangyong, leader of the 10th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the 8th Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Gao Fei, leader of the 14th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the First Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. La Yifan, leader of the 15th Central Inspection Team, is the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission in the Ministry of Culture and Tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 14 central inspection team leaders who have been stationed in the inspected units, Kong Shenggen, Wang Rongjun, Zhang Fugen, Gao Fei, Zhu Shumin, La Yifan, Li Yingchun, Chen Zhangyong, and Yu Changhui are all in the 20th Served as team leader in the first round of inspection activities of the Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China was launched. This inspection is the first time since the 18th CPC National Congress that three organizational methods, namely regular inspections, mobile inspections and &quot;look back&quot; inspections, are simultaneously arranged in one inspection round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first round of inspections carried out regular inspections of the party committees of 30 medium-sized enterprises, carried out &quot;look back&quot; inspections of the party committees of 5 medium-sized financial enterprises, and carried out mobile inspections of the party groups of the State Sports General Administration. This was also the first time in nearly 6 months. In 2016, the central government once again conducted mobile inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that after half a year of work, the first round of inspection feedback work was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, many central management officials of the inspected units were dismissed, including Li Xiaopeng, former chairman of China Everbright Group Co., Ltd., Zhou Qingyu, vice president of China Development Bank, China Everbright Tang Shuangning, former chairman of the group, Wang Yongsheng, former vice president of China Development Bank, Du Zhaocai, former deputy director of the State Sports General Administration, Xu Wenrong, former deputy general manager of PetroChina, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;A report published in the &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision Magazine&quot; published on October 15, 2023 stated that the second round of inspections was the second round of inspections of centrally managed enterprises after the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. In the centralized political examination, &quot;the two rounds of inspections basically covered all centrally managed enterprises, reflecting the distinctive characteristics of political inspections highlighting key points, and sending a strong signal to strictly manage state-owned central enterprises.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/R2hzaOqQspythqvDnqccZ817OPPpxAVl3BUDuyyc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;613&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/R2hzaOqQspythqvDnqccZ817OPPpxAVl3BUDuyyc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The president of Qiushi Magazine has recently adjusted &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Chen Yangyong is appointed as the president of Qiushi Magazine]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Chen Yangyong Born in December 1963, he holds a Ph.D. in history from Fudan University and is a researcher. He has served as deputy director of the Central Literature Research Office and deputy director of the Central Party History and Literature Research Institute. In 2018, he was appointed editor-in-chief of Qiushi Magazine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yangyong has long been engaged in researching the thoughts and lives of major leaders of the party and the country and editing works. He has participated in &quot;Selected Works of Jiang Zemin&quot;, Jiang Zemin&#39;s &quot;On the Development of China&#39;s Information Technology Industry&quot;, &quot;Mao Zedong, Deng Xiaoping and Jiang Zemin on Scientific Development&quot;, He is the editor of &quot;Li Peng on Rejuvenating the Nation through Science and Education&quot; and other works, and participated in the compilation of &quot;Jiang Zemin&#39;s Thoughts Chronicles (1989-2008)&quot; and &quot;Zhou Enlai&#39;s Chronicle (1949-1976)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Han Wenxiu is appointed director of the Central Agricultural Office]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Zhejiang Daily&quot; 》News, the national on-site promotion meeting for learning and applying the &quot;Ten Million Project&quot; experience was held on October 13 in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. Han Wenxiu, deputy director of the Central Finance Office in charge of daily work and director of the Central Agricultural Office, presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above reports show that Han Wenxiu has been appointed director of the Central Agricultural Office. Han Wenxiu, born in September 1963, is a native of Zanhuang County, Hebei Province. In his early years, he worked as an editor in the editorial department of the Journal of Peking University. In 1989, he joined the Economic Research Center of the former State Planning Commission (now the Macroeconomic Research Institute of the National Development and Reform Commission). In 2005, Han Wenxiu was transferred to the macro group leader (bureau level) of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group Office. From 2010 to 2011, he served as deputy secretary-general of the Guangdong Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China. In 2011, Han Wenxiu was transferred to deputy director of the Research Office of the State Council. In April 2018, he was transferred to deputy director of the Central Finance Office, and later served as deputy director (at the ministerial level) of the Central Finance Office in charge of daily work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The fourth deputy secretary-general of the State Council took office during the year]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People According to news from the Ministry of Social Affairs website on October 17, the State Council appointed Sun Guangyu as deputy secretary-general of the State Council; Chen Min was appointed deputy minister of the Ministry of Water Resources; Xiao Yanshun was appointed deputy director of the Research Office of the State Council; Wang Jingtao was appointed deputy director of the National Internet Information Office; Fan Yun was appointed Deputy Editor-in-Chief of China Central Radio and Television. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu, male, Han nationality, born in December 1966, university degree, Master of Engineering, member of the Communist Party of China. He once served as director of the Department of Safety Supervision and Management of Hazardous Chemicals of the Ministry of Emergency Management and other positions. In June 2022, he was appointed as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2023, the State Council has appointed three deputy secretaries-general. On July 4, Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong took office. Wang Zhijun served as deputy secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee, and Wang Yonghong served as party secretary and director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. On August 30, Xu Shouben took office. He previously served as vice president and party committee member of the China Development Bank. &lt;p>; >;According to Fujian Daily, the Organization Department of the Fujian Provincial Party Committee issued a pre-appointment announcement on October 17, in which Dang Shuai, secretary of the Pingnan County Party Committee in Ningde, is proposed to serve as deputy party and government deputy in the districted city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dang Shuai, male, from Weifang, Shandong, was born in February 1984. He is a doctor of power engineering and engineering thermophysics who was selected and introduced from Tsinghua University in Ningde, Fujian Province in 2012. In July 2012, he was appointed as the deputy county magistrate of science and technology of Zhelong County, Ningde. In October 2014, he was appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Pingnan County Party Committee and the Minister of the Propaganda Department. In 2015, In November, he was appointed as Secretary of the Ningde Municipal Committee and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Communist Youth League. In June 2016, he was appointed as Deputy Secretary of the Gutian County Committee, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the County Government, and Acting County Magistrate. In December of the same year, he was appointed Deputy Secretary of the Gutian County Committee, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the County Government, and County Magistrate. In July 2020, Dang Shuai took office as Secretary of the Pingnan County Party Committee and has been working ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Two new vice-governors of Sichuan Province]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 2023 On the morning of March 13, the Standing Committee of the Sichuan Provincial People&#39;s Congress decided to appoint Phubtendup and Zuo Yongxiang as deputy governors of the Sichuan Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pubu Dundup, male, Tibetan, born in November 1972, from Gyantse, Tibet. He has been working in Tibet since 1996. In October 2023, he was transferred from the Standing Committee of the Tibet Autonomous Region Party Committee and Secretary of the Lhasa Municipal Party Committee to the Standing Committee of the Sichuan Provincial Party Committee and Vice Governor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zuo Yongxiang, male, born in August 1968, is a longevity native of Chongqing. After graduating from Fudan University in 1991 with a major in mathematical statistics, he worked in Changshou County (later changed to Changshou District) in Chongqing for a long time. In 2018, he was transferred to the deputy secretary and district chief of Tongliang District, Chongqing. Since then, he has worked in Yuzhong District and Chongqing District. Work with Chongqing High-tech Zone and Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission. Before this job adjustment, Zuo Yongxiang served as Party Secretary and Director of the Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission, and Director (concurrently) of the Chongqing Municipal Grain Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anti-corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Han Yong, former chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference Under investigation]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 19, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reported that Han Yong, the former Party Secretary and Chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Central Committee. Disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the National Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Yong, born in October 1956, is from Jiutai, Jilin Province. He worked in Jilin Province in his early years and served successively as deputy director of the Criminal Prosecution Division of the Jilin Provincial Procuratorate, deputy director and director of the Economic Procuratorial Division. , Director of the Prison Office, Deputy Mayor of Yushu City (temporary position), Chief Prosecutor of the Songyuan City Procuratorate, Deputy Prosecutor General of the Provincial Procuratorate and Director of the Anti-Corruption Bureau, Member and Deputy Secretary of the Standing Committee of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, Director of the Provincial Supervision Department, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Han Yong went to work in Xinjiang and successively served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, Minister of the Organization Department, Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region, and Director of the Organization Department. In 2015, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps Party committee secretary, political commissar, chairman of China New Construction Group Corporation, and clearly at the ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2016, Han Yong was transferred to the position of Chairman and Party Secretary of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, and will retire in January 2022. In March 2022, Han Yong was appointed deputy director of the Population Resources and Environment Committee of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/6vxCJtnVwPAQ1n3VfTX6PCgCSC4SHBuHW63rJl3s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/6vxCJtnVwPAQ1n3VfTX6PCgCSC4SHBuHW63rJl3s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Yong, former chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. &quot; Cadres born in the 1990s began to embezzle public funds three months after being admitted to public offices]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, the website of the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released a report on the construction of villages and towns in Duma Town, Tianzhu County, Qiandongnan Prefecture The warning about the case of Long Li, a former worker at the service center, revealed that just three months after being admitted to public office, this &quot;post-90s&quot; cadre could no longer withstand temptation and began to embezzle public funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long Li, male, born in May 1991, is from Sansui, Guizhou. He started working in November 2019 and serves as a staff member of the Village and Town Construction Service Center in Duma Town, Tianzhu County. In January 2020, when Long Li was handling the issuance of reclamation and greening funds for the masses, he discovered that after township staff provided explanations, the funds could be transferred directly to the account number provided by the staff. From January 2020 to September 2021, in just one year and nine months, Long Li took advantage of his position to falsely report other people&#39;s bank accounts and fraudulently receive more than 200,000 yuan in state funds for personal daily consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2021, Long Li was placed under investigation. In September 2021, Long Li was fired from public office. In December 2021, Long Li was sentenced to three years in prison for corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Female department official was notified of &quot;beauty corruption&quot;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing City On October 18, the website of the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision reported serious violations of discipline and law by Chen Guifen (deputy bureau level), former member of the Party Group and Vice Chairman of the Beijing Yanqing District Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Guifen was born in Yanqing in July 1970 and was investigated in March 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report stated that Chen Guifen was disloyal and dishonest to the party and resisted organizational review; she violated the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepted gifts and arrangements for beauty activities in violation of regulations. &lt;p>; >;On October 18, the &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot; published an article &quot;Original Intentions Are Dusted by Greed and Destroy Your Body&quot;, which analyzed the serious disciplinary and law violation case of Guo Qing, a former party member and deputy mayor of the Luzhou Municipal Government in Sichuan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Qing, male, was born in October 1963 and started working in July 1983. In November 2021, the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision opened a case for review and investigation into Guo Qing&#39;s suspected serious violations of discipline and law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above report, October 23, 2021, is Guo Qing’s 58th birthday. On this day, he was walking alone on the Luzhou Yangtze River Bridge and felt that the situation was serious. He once had the idea of ​​​​jumping into the river to &quot;finish it once and for all.&quot; However, a call from his family urging him to go home for dinner brought him back to reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2022, Guo Qing was expelled from the party and public office. In December 2022, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Ziyang City, Sichuan Province sentenced Guo Qing to nine years in prison for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ministry and Commission Information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Commerce: Consumers can check Credit information of housekeeping staff】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the CCTV News Client report on October 17, 2023, recently, the &quot;Housekeeping Credit Check&quot; applet established by the Ministry of Commerce was newly launched. Domestic companies will be supported to establish credit records for domestic workers and carry out professional background information verification and verification. At the same time, free credit information inquiry services for domestic companies and domestic workers will be provided to consumers. It is understood that the &quot;Housekeeping Credit Check&quot; applet is an important part of the national housekeeping service credit information platform. Up to now, the platform has collected 19,000 domestic service companies and more than 15 million pieces of credit information about domestic workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Development and Reform Commission: Interview with 4 provinces and cities due to lagging progress due to declining energy intensity]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; According to news from the National Development and Reform Commission website on October 19, the Environmental Protection Department of the National Development and Reform Commission recently interviewed responsible officials of the energy conservation authorities of Zhejiang Province, Anhui Province, Guangdong Province, and Chongqing Municipality regarding the lagging progress in reducing energy intensity during the “14th Five-Year Plan” . In the first two years of the “14th Five-Year Plan”, after deducting the energy consumption of raw materials and renewable energy consumption, the decline in energy intensity in Zhejiang, Anhui, Guangdong, Chongqing and other regions still lags behind the target progress requirements of the “14th Five-Year Plan”. Renewable energy consumption The level needs to be improved, and the energy-saving situation is very serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Health Commission: Fill in the shortcomings and weaknesses of local hospitals in oncology, pediatrics, etc.]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 19, the National Health Commission held a press conference. Xue Haining, deputy director of the Department of Structural Reform of the National Health Commission, said that my country is vigorously promoting the construction of national medical centers and national and provincial regional medical centers to fill the gap in local medical centers through expert support, technology transfer, homogeneous management and other measures. Through these measures, the shortcomings and weaknesses in key diseases and key specialties such as oncology and pediatrics are gradually being alleviated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Medical Insurance Administration: The efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected through centralized procurement are equivalent to those of original drugs]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;CCTV News Client reported that on October 17, the National Medical Insurance Administration held a press conference to introduce the real-world research results on the clinical efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected from the second and third batches of nationally organized drug centralized procurement. In June 2021, entrusted by the National Medical Insurance Administration, Xuanwu Hospital of Capital Medical University led 29 medical institutions in 16 provinces across the country to conduct clinical efficacy and safety studies on 23 representative varieties collected by the second and third batches of national organizations. A real-world study conducted over the past two years, a total of 38 brands of selected generic drugs were evaluated. The research results show that the clinical efficacy and safety of the selected generic drugs are equivalent to those of the original drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Zhengzhou, Henan: Career by 2025 More than 60% of college graduates stay in the local area]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhengzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government website, on October 18, the General Office of the Zhengzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government issued &quot;Deepening the Integration of Industry and Education to Promote Vocational Education High-Quality Development Implementation Plan. The &quot;Plan&quot; proposes that by 2025, 100 industry-education integrated enterprises at the municipal level and above, 10 industry-education integrated training bases at the municipal level and above, 10 industry-education integrated education groups (alliances), and 15 school-enterprise cooperation Demonstrative industrial colleges, 30 industry-education integration practice centers, 50 industry-education integration key majors, 50 government-industry-university-research collaborative education projects, and more than 60% of vocational college graduates stay in the local area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei: the first regional coordinated local standard release in the field of people&#39;s livelihood]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; According to the Beijing Daily client report, in order to promote the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei, Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei recently issued the &quot;Standards for the Psychological Assessment of Minors in Assistance, Protection and Child Welfare Institutions&quot;, which will be implemented on January 1, 2024. The reporter learned that this is the first regional coordinated local standard in the field of basic livelihood security issued by Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. The standards will be implemented through the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei rescue and protection and child welfare agencies. Mental health, social adaptation and other aspects of the minors under the custody of the civil affairs department will be assessed, their psychological problems will be identified, and targeted psychological counseling will be carried out. Enrich and expand the content and methods of rescue and protection, explore and establish a new social protection system for minors with Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei characteristics, and further promote the healthy growth and all-round development of minors. &lt;p>; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hunan Daily, recently, the General Office of the Hunan Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the Hunan Provincial People&#39;s Government issued the &quot;Notice on Implementing Three Systems and Mechanisms including the &quot;Negative List&quot; Management of Prominent Issues in Official Receptions&quot;. Implement a &quot;negative list&quot; management system for prominent issues in official reception throughout the province. Situations that are included in the &quot;negative list&quot; include: not paying accommodation, meals, transportation and other expenses as required; drinking alcohol during official receptions (including personally carrying alcohol); accepting receptions in violation of regulations during official events in the same city; engaging in various private clubs, &quot;One-table meal&quot; venues, high-consumption catering venues, internal reception venues of private enterprises not operated by external parties, and other places accept official receptions in violation of regulations; it is required that vacations, family visits, tourism and other activities be included in the scope of official receptions, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Law Issues Judicial Protection of National Parks Typical cases: many types of lawsuits involved]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, 2023, the website of the Supreme People&#39;s Court reported that the Supreme People&#39;s Court released 10 typical cases of judicial protection of national parks. The typical cases released this time involve many types of litigation and a wide range of protection, including different types of litigation such as environmental resources criminal, civil and public interest litigation, covering the main scope of environmental resources trials; the national parks involved include Sanjiangyuan, Giant Panda, etc. The five first batch of national parks established, including Siberian Tiger and Leopard, Hainan Tropical Rainforest, and Wuyi Mountain, as well as Qianjiangyuan-Baishanzu National Park, a national park candidate area included in the &quot;National Park Spatial Layout Plan&quot; selection, reflect The People&#39;s Court hears cases involving national park protection with many types of litigation and a wide scope of national park protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The President of the Supreme Court stated that he will not accept cases at the end of the year]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 17, the Supreme People&#39;s Court held a discussion on judicial trial data analysis and judgment for the first three quarters of 2023. Zhang Jun, President of the Supreme Court, said that the quality, efficiency, and effectiveness of trials in courts across the country have steadily improved in the first three quarters. The requirements for case closure rates within trial limits must be strictly implemented, and the annual closing ratio and case closure rate indicators must no longer be used, and resolutely put an end to failure to complete cases at the end of the year. end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【粮食安全保障法拟明确：企事业单位加强食堂管理，纠正浪费】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月19日，全国人大常委会法工委举行记者会，发言人杨合庆介绍，粮食安全保障法草案二审稿将提交本月召开的全国人大常委会会议审议，草案二审稿规定机关、团体、企事业单位等应当加强本单位食堂的管理，纠正浪费行为。 2023年6月，十四届全国人大常委会第三次会议对粮食安全保障法草案进行了初次审议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【司法部：严厉整治运动式执法、野蛮执法、逐利执法】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，国务院办公厅印发《提升行政执法质量三年行动计划（2023－2025年）》，就全面提升行政执法质量和效能提出明确要求。行动计划提出，全面推进严格规范公正文明执法，强力整治行政执法突出问题、建立健全行政执法标准规范、完善行政执法工作机制。根据部署，各地区、各部门要开展专项整治和监督行动，强力整治行政执法突出问题，并明确了开展专项整治和监督行动的时间节点和工作步骤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【国家统计局副局长盛来运：我呼吁，也恳请调查户积极配合】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月18日，在国新办举行的前三季度国民经济运行情况新闻发布会上，国家统计局副局长盛来运说：“（2023年）11月1日开始入户调查，这是标准时点，大概时间要持续两周，到11月15日入户调查结束。这里我呼吁也恳请我们的调查户，积极配合人口变动情况抽样调查，如实准确地填报相关信息。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考央视新闻、澎湃新闻、《福建日报》《湖南日报》《中国纪检监察报》等报道）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI生成书籍泛滥：谁在制造“假书”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258953]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/tcvzL0Peu3haQYDXZNgvFe0uYRJlEzgeptumIYvn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/tcvzL0Peu3haQYDXZNgvFe0uYRJlEzgeptumIYvn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254698&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;亚马逊的自助出版系统允许任何人在亚马逊上自行出版和销售书籍，这给AI生成书籍的泛滥提供了漏洞。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“谁在写我的传记？”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当罗里·塞兰-琼斯在亚马逊上发现一本自己的传记时，他奇怪地发出疑问。他翻阅了部分内容，书中显示他生活在一个学术家庭中，父亲是一位和蔼可亲的学者，母亲是一名教师。这本书几乎可以与他自己写的回忆录相媲美，只不过上面的信息“完全是幻想”，他告诉《卫报》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，罗里的父亲是BBC的一位电视导演，母亲也在BBC工作。某一天，他在一个装着信件的鞋盒中发现了父母的感情故事，并由此揭开家族的历史真相，这些故事被记录在他真正的回忆录中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于那本有关他的传记，罗里从未听说过那位传记作者，不过，他很快发现，这本书是由AI生成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗里的遭遇并非孤例。据多家外媒报道，AI生成的书籍正充斥在亚马逊上，这些书籍涉及范围广泛，从传记、食谱、科普书籍到旅游指南等，无所不有。其中，有些书中的某些错误信息甚至会威胁到生命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纽约真菌学会（NYMS）便公开表示，亚马逊等电商平台上的许多AI生成的蘑菇觅食科普书籍存在诸多错误描述，这可能会误导大众吃到有毒蘑菇，“意味着生与死”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“A&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;已经击垮亚马逊”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;6月，作家凯特琳·林奇在社交平台上发帖，指出在亚马逊青少年当代爱情电子书畅销排行榜的前100名中，只有19本是正常的书籍，其余都是AI生成的“废话”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还附上了一本书的截图，名字叫《等你爱我》，封面是一张黑白的海鸥照片。在此之前，在亚马逊的青少年当代爱情类别前100名畅销书排行榜中，这本书位于第90名。底下的两条一星评论也指出，它是一本由AI生成的书籍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“AI已经击垮了亚马逊。”林奇在推文中这样写道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据8月《纽约时报》报道，旅游指南也成为AI书籍泛滥的主要类别之一。3月，旅行者艾米·科尔斯基为即将到来的法国之旅在亚马逊上购买旅行指南。当她输入几个搜索关键词“旅行”“指南”“法国”后，一本排名靠前的《法国旅游指南》引起了她的注意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据作者页面显示，该书作者迈克·史蒂夫斯是一位“著名的旅行作家”。书籍的界面上有一百多个五星好评，该指南还承诺有行程安排和当地人的推荐。于是，艾米·科尔斯基下了单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;令她失望的是，收到书籍后，她发现里面的描述模糊、文字重复，并且缺乏行程安排，看起来像是从维基百科上复制粘贴的。她将这本书退回了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《纽约时报》发现事情并不简单。他们无法找到该书所谓的“作者”之前发表的任何作品，甚至界面上“作者”的照片也显得奇怪，比如耳朵附近存在的异常元素、歪歪扭扭的衣服等，看起来是由AI生成的照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据AI检测工具Originality.ai的结果，几乎可以肯定迈克·史蒂夫斯的书AI生成。此外，《纽约时报》发现，AI生成的书籍也开始渗透到烹饪、编程、医学、园艺等许多类别中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在许多媒体的报道中，AI生成的书籍不仅给读者带来误导信息，也给真人作者造成了极大的困扰。8月，作家简·弗里德曼在自己的博客上称，有一些“垃圾书”被上传到亚马逊上，作者一栏赫然写着她的名字，但她并没有写过这些书，它们极大可能是AI生成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2009年开始，她一直在写博客，很多内容都是公开的，可以用于AI的模型训练。因此，当她读到这些“假书”的第一页时，就像在阅读自己生成的ChatGPT回复一样。更让她觉得雪上加霜的是，这些“假书”被添加到她的Goodreads个人资料中，这很容易引起误导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在社交平台上抱怨这件事情之后，一些作者回应称，他们也有过类似的经历。“人们一直告诉我他们买了我的新书，上面有我的名字，但我从未写过。”一位作者说。还有的作者仅仅一周就举报了29本类似情况的书籍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可怕的是，这种情况可能发生在任何一个有名声、有地位、有需求的人身上，有人看到了从中获利的途径。”在接受美国有线电视新闻网采访时，简·弗里德曼说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“实际上是在允许&#39;垃圾书&#39;的存在”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在罗里发现有关他的传记是AI生成的内容后，亚马逊给他发了一封电子邮件，上面推荐说，“你可能会喜欢这本书”。这让罗里感到生气，亚马逊的算法竟认为这是一本他想要的书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们实际上是在允许&#39;垃圾书&#39;的存在，还把它推荐给最讨厌它的人。”罗里告诉《卫报》。尽管亚马逊之后删除了这本书，但还是有很多作品通过了旨在剔除低质量图书的过滤系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，许多AI生成的书籍出现在亚马逊平台上，跟它本身的自助出版系统KDP（Kindle Direct Publishing）被滥用有很大关系。2007年，亚马逊创建KDP，允许任何人在亚马逊上自行出版和销售书籍。目前，它可以提供超过45种语言选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在亚马逊KDP平台，作者可以自由选择自助出版电子书或纸质书，完成自助出版书籍的上传流程后，亚马逊大约72小时内就能通过审核并进行销售。在此平台上自助出版书籍是免费的，不过，如果出版纸质书，印刷成本会从每本书销售所得的版税中扣除。一般来说，作者可获得的纸质书版税最高为60%，电子书的版税为35%或70%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，随着人工智能技术的发展，在YouTube、TikTok等平台上，许多利用AI生成书籍的教程也纷纷出现，其主题范围广泛，不少用户可以从中快速掌握AI生成书籍的方法，再加上亚马逊自助出版功能的便利与收益，滥用此功能进行AI书籍出版和销售的行为也很难避免。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接到许多作者的投诉后，9月，亚马逊在其KDP的社区页面上引入了新的规则和指南。新规要求作者在发布作品时，回答系统关于作品是否为人工智能生成的提问。在其内容指南部分，亚马逊也增加了有关AI的内容，包括对“人工智能生成”和“人工智能辅助”的定义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《卫报》报道，出于对人工智能的担忧，亚马逊推出限制自助出版者每日最多发布3本书的新规。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但即使新规已经发布，有些影响却已造成。简·弗里德曼的相关事件发酵后，那些假冒她之名的书籍从亚马逊和她的Goodreads个人资料中被删去。但这一过程并不顺利，亚马逊一开始拒绝停止出售那些书籍。简·弗里德曼认为，最终是由于她在写作和出版界的知名度和声誉才促使亚马逊撤下那些书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在亚马逊上发布的人工智能内容泛滥成灾，有时还以误导或欺诈的方式归属于作者，怎么能理所当然地指望在职作者在余生中每周都花时间来监管这些内容呢？”她发出质问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而即使那些书不再出现在她的亚马逊或Goodreads页面上，它们的影响仍然存在。简·弗里德曼在自己的博客上写道：“不幸的是，即使你把这些疯狂的书从你的官方资料中删除了，它们仍然会和你的名字在一起……而你对此却无能为力。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[毕业生求职，“我全都要”容易实现吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258810]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;受经济环境和毕业人数影响，今年毕业的大学生就业形势严峻。我的朋友、刚刚毕业的研究生小言虽然收到了几份offer（工作机会），却一点也不开心，反而更加焦虑。经过一番询问了解才知道，这些工作似乎都无法达到他心中理想工作的标准。如何选择合适的工作，这是每一个毕业生需要思考的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在经济学领域，有一个著名的“蒙代尔不可能三角”。这一理论是说，国家在货币政策的独立性、汇率的稳定性和资本的自由流动这三者之间无法同时满足，最多只能选择其中两个。同理，在就业市场上，我认为也存在着一个类似的“不可能三角”定律。它涉及一个工作岗位的薪资水平、工作平台和相对稳定性这三个条件，很难同时实现，最多只能满足其中两个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我来简要介绍一下这位朋友的基本情况：小言来自西北某省会的农村家庭，本科毕业于211高校，博士毕业于北京知名985高校，成绩非常优异；求学期间发表多篇SCI论文，参与多个国家级课题，获得了不少高级别大赛的奖项。他拿到的三个offer各自具备明确的特点。第一个工作是国家部委事业编，有户口，工作平台好，社会地位相对较高，但收入水平在北京这样的一线城市，除去开支可能所剩无几，面对高昂的房价，他心有余而力不足；第二份工作属于行业垄断性事业单位，既有编制，收入也有保证，但平台一般，后期跳槽受限制较多；第三份工作是家乡211高校，科研平台水平较高，学科实力雄厚，工作时间也相对自由，美中不足的是，随着高校事业单位改革，这份工作没有编制且聘期考核压力较大，他担心未来面临非升即走的结局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管小言最终的选择尚未确定，但我建议他在寻找工作时，首要任务是学会降低对某一特定因素的预期，而不是陷入“我全都要”的境地。仅就这三份工作而言，如果他青睐体制内稳定的工作环境，那或许应该对薪水降低一些预期，第一份工作可能是不二之选；如果他追求更好的薪水待遇，就需要对工作平台的要求有所妥协，这样第二份工作可能更合适一些；如果向往更好的科研平台，有志于学术发展，小言可以试着对编制这个指标看淡一些，挑战一下第三份高校教职也不错。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，月亮有阴晴圆缺，工作也有美中不足，此事古难全。对于大多数毕业的大学生来说，找到的工作基本符合“不可能三角”定律，因此，必要的时候需要我们找准需求，学会取舍，才能少一分焦虑，坦然面对严峻的就业环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系2023年应届博士毕业生）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[歌枕之巅——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（四）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgSx4Ep.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgSx4Ep.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254353&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;松尾芭蕉行至松岛时曾面海而居。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;继续再往北走，经过秋田，进入青森。铁路沿线上尽是正在丰收期的苹果园，有些地段，缀满红果的枝叶就在手边擦过，中间隔着列车的玻璃窗。那种惊喜实在是相当强烈的。真正摸到苹果，得在车站超市里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青森的苹果产量占日本全国产量的一半，是世界闻名的富士苹果的发祥地，另有二三十种其他品种的苹果。青森培育出的“世界第一”苹果，一个在500克以上，有的可以达到1000克甚至1500克。我们在超市逛的时候看到那些青森苹果也堪称巨型，一个一个地卖，一个500日元左右，折合人民币三十元左右。贵是贵点，但汁水丰沛味道甜美。我们三个人在一个小站转车时买了一个分食，居然都吃饱了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在青森，当然有目的地——去金木看太宰治的故居“斜阳馆”，另外还去了十和田，参观著名的十和田美术馆。至于说芭蕉行迹，得在这一圈周转之后进入到一个高潮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们掉头从北到南，从青森坐车至仙台，转在来线至松岛海岸驿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芭蕉句吟：“松岛夏月夜碧水为衣裳”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芭蕉和曾良的奥州之行，他说，这一趟旅行，纯属心血来潮之举，于是也顾不得吴天白发之恨了。这个心血来潮，在他开篇序言里说了，因为松岛之月呈现在他的心里，诱他上路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴天白发，典出白居易“去年九日到东洛，今年九日来吴乡。两边蓬鬓一时白，三处菊花同色黄”和宋人魏庆之的诗句“笠重吴天雪，鞋香楚地花”，都意指旅途遥远艰辛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254354&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;松岛位于日本东北宫城县宫城郡，是松尾芭蕉行迹“歌枕”中的名胜，因群岛上遍植松树而得名。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;松岛，因遍植松树而得名。古代日本传统色名有松叶色一说，顾名思义，松叶的颜色，这是一种四季常绿的深绿色。在日本传统色中，还有好几种跟松叶相关的颜色，有海松色，是接近黑色的绿；有海松茶色，深绿中掺杂了褐黄，是一种沉着俏丽的绿。再有就是海松蓝、黄海松茶、蓝海松茶等等，在我看来就是松叶色的各种衍生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《奥之细道》中，芭蕉时不时会注明走到了某一处“歌枕”。 “歌枕”一词的意思是自古以来出现在日本和歌中的名胜之地。日本的歌枕之巅，有三景之说，天桥立、松岛和严岛（也叫做宫岛）。这三大景点早在江户早期就很有名了。对于我来说，松岛因为芭蕉在《奥之细道》中的描述，感觉文气更甚。芭蕉的“失语”特别有趣，他嚷嚷道，“松岛呀！啊！啊！松岛呀！松岛呀！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;瑞岩寺的枯山水庭院。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;松岛在日本东北宫城县宫城郡，是海湾内的岛群，由大大小小260个小岛组成，因遍植黑松和红松，故名。此地四颜是碧浪、白砂、灰岩、青松，色彩相当明朗协调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年10月30日那天，我和卫东、艳宁，从青森的八户启程前往松岛。从八户驿坐到仙台，转在来线至松岛海岸驿。很小的车站站台，立于铁道中间，夜晚到达，已具凛冽之意的寒风从站台的四面围逼过来。毕竟已经是秋天了，白日的阳光煦暖，到了晚上就溃败而去。我们赶紧坐上酒店和车站之间的来往班车，转过一个坡，就到了酒店“大观庄”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一座趴着的长方形大体量的楼体，巨大的大堂向楼体两端延伸。这种大规模的度假酒店几乎是一模一样的，在箱根，在北海道，都有。我高度怀疑是一个设计师做的。看到这种规模的酒店，就知道松岛的热门程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夜入松岛，看不到什么。清晨起来拉开窗帘，一百八十度的海景景观就在眼前。确实美貌。清冽端素的那种美貌，适合芭蕉这种精神状态清淡枯寂的人。芭蕉在松岛也是面海而居，住处在二楼（我们住的比他更高，三楼），他说，“开窗面海，所谓旅卧风云中，奇妙之感，不可言宣。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我随身带着《奥之细道》。到了松岛，就把书中关于“松岛”的那一章节仔细地又读了一遍。芭蕉叹道，“夫古老相传，松岛风景，扶桑第一，盖不逊于洞庭、西湖也。自东南纳海入湾，湾内三里，汹涌如浙江潮。大岛小岛无数，耸立者直指天外，俯伏者匍匐波上。或二层重叠，或三层堆砌；左右诸岛，或离或连；有负者，有抱者，如爱儿孙然。苍松郁郁，潮打风吹，枝叶虬曲，自然而然，而若矫揉之所致。其景窅然，有美人凝妆之貌。岂古昔神代大山祇之所为哉？造化天工，孰能奋其彩笔，以尽其妙乎？”（郑清茂译）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芭蕉没有到过中国，但借用中国之景，并不勉强。古代日本文人通过对汉语典籍和绘画作品的阅读，对西湖、洞庭湖、钱江潮之类的中国胜景，也有相当的熟悉和亲近，信手拈来，比赋眼前美景，以解词穷之困，是顺理成章的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年冬天，我和同行友人在富良野参观了后藤纯男美术馆。我依稀记得他好像有一幅画松岛的，还是一幅很长的画。我记得我拍了的（特别说明一下，日本很多的美术馆是不能拍展品的，或者只能拍部分展品。我是严格遵守这一规定的。后藤纯男美术馆的所有展品都允许拍照）。 2019年11月，从奥州之行回家之后打开电脑查看，我找出了这幅画，非常惊讶，这不就是我们在大观庄的房间看出去的景色吗？我觉得后藤纯男造访松岛的时候，就是住的大观庄，而且就是我们那一排面海的三楼房间的其中一间。后藤纯男的这幅画作于1987年，叫做《松岛之晨》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;瑞岩寺的附寺圆通院的红叶。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，清晨站在窗前看着眼前的松岛海景，想起日本文化随笔作家白州正子的一段话，她说，“日本是东方的一座孤岛，好坏都在&#39;孤&#39;字上。这座孤岛就像世界文化的风积角落，无论是什么，只要经过日本人之手，就会变身为一种更难以言说的、精巧的、密度更大的东西”。我认同这种说法。文化形态没有明确的高下判断，但有着节奏、速度、质感完全不同的区别。日本文化是世界文化加以凝缩后的呈现，大风大浪把各种文化输送到这个远东的岛国，也就到此为止，然后加以剔除转化后，凝结为晶体化的一种文化形态。它的静态和密度，跟大陆文化和走廊文化是完全不同的。风与浪止于此，但风与浪都凝结其中，仿佛天地间的一滴琥珀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在窗前看松岛的风景，我突然想起这些。在旅途中，一般情况下，抽象的文字会继续刺激我的思考，而视觉上的优美，则会让我相当涣散。松岛是个例外。看来，确实是不一般的松岛啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《奥之细道》里，芭蕉的随从门人曾良吟了一首俳句，“猗欤松岛，杜鹃应借鹤身，唱遍全湾。”这首俳句刻成了句碑，立在了瑞岩寺的门口，跟“芭蕉碑”并置在一起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;松岛的核心是瑞岩寺。芭蕉和曾良是在夏天造访瑞岩寺的，想来满目清幽。我们仲秋到达，清幽残存，秋意的些微黄红之妙掺夹其间。天空的气息肯定是完全不一样了。四季的天空真是奇妙，同样的清朗高远，但秋空就是更为深远杳渺，犹如眼窝更深的一双眼睛，跟其他三个季节不一样。从仙台车站开始就看到一路张贴的松岛红叶旅游宣传海报，红得铺天盖地。海报选取的就是瑞岩寺红叶，准确地说，是瑞岩寺的附寺圆通院的红叶。圆通院的庭院迂回婉转，是一个专门为秋天准备的庭院，遍植枫树，到了深秋就会殷红一片。我们到的时候是个什么景象呢？拿马拉松比赛作比吧，红枫的发令枪已经响了，前面已经冲出去了一些选手，但庞大的队伍还在起跑处。想象我们前脚刚走，圆通院的红叶就会大规模狂跑起来，直至成满园燃烧之势，要说没有一点怅然是不可能的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瑞岩寺是临济宗的重要寺院，建于公元828年，寺内有明治天皇曾经下榻过的房间，专门标注出来。沿着游览路线在本堂、回廊游走一番后，我的注意力还是放在了庭园。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;秋光一旦沉淀下来，是灰蓝色的。尤其是在上午。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从松岛回来之后，我经常把瑞岩寺枯山水庭院的照片翻出来看。被光线分隔出的奇妙光景，阴影处，白砂变成了清透的灰蓝色，砂纹的皱褶里蕴藏细小的风雷，深浅两色的苔藓有着奇妙的玲珑感。越过阴影，强光中，白壁和山岩，与寺外从山崖上连绵而下的松树，以那簇红叶为界限，在此卸掉了角力的势态，静了下来。但这种静止似乎随时都可以打破，如果光线稍微有点变化的话。于是，看的人不由自主屏住了呼吸。所以，定格成照片是对的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艺术哲学家亚瑟·丹托教授对芭蕉很有研究，认为芭蕉俳句的质地“安静、简洁、如钻石般晶莹清冷”。他曾经也说过，想成为芭蕉那样的人。芭蕉的旅行是对艺术、自然和内心的朝圣，他诙谐、自嘲，骄傲且孤独，但有着浓厚的谦卑之心，对先辈、对自然、对用双脚叩击地面的这个行为的本身，他都有十分虔诚的意念。他的修行已经在修行的过程中圆满完成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丹托教授有一段话说得好，他说，“……芭蕉作为一个个体，存在于这样一个个性彰显和个性泯灭相统一的现实之中，既不算入世，也没那么出世；如他自嘲的那样，他就像是一只蝙蝠，既非鼠也非鸟，而是一种处在两种动物生存状态之间的杂交变形生物。我总为他的游记所打动。这些游记，是他体内焦躁不安之感的象征。他总是从感觉或是从对终结的希望出发，无意于回归，以寻求某种终极的逃离，到头来发现，逃离本身就是成就。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于芭蕉，我曾经说，视他为文学上的情人。或者可以说，我想成为他那样的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国草”与“东方神药”的丝路之旅]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;随着雨季到来，非洲圣多美岛的疟疾发病率开始抬头，广州中医药大学赴圣多美-普林西比青蒿抗疟专家组组长黄新安愈加忙碌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月16日上午，刚刚下过雨不久，他和同事们乘坐皮卡车从圣多美市区启程，踩着泥巴路来到迪奥戈·努内斯（Diogo Nunes）村。在那里，专家组老师们指导中心雇员们，挨家挨户采集样本，筛查潜在病例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在中国抗疟专家指导下，工作人员挨家挨户采集样本，筛查潜在病例。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在斐济楠迪市郊，85岁的老农场主库玛依然精神矍铄。16日这天，他开着小货车，从中国援斐济菌草技术示范中心拉回一车菌草平菇菌糟，这种废菌料可以用作农场里水果和蔬菜的有机肥。两个月前，在中国菌草技术专家的指导下，库玛还在农场河岸滑坡上种植菌草，治理逐渐恶化的水土流失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一带一路”倡议提出以来，一个个“小而美”的惠民生项目落地倡议沿线国家。结合自身的发展经验和技术优势，为当地减贫脱贫、公共卫生和环境治理提供中国方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;斐济楠迪市85岁农场主库玛使用废菌料作为农场里水果和蔬菜的有机肥。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“菌草”与“青蒿”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对于很多斐济人来说，菌草是“神奇的草”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在援斐菌草技术示范中心的菌草种植基地，可以看到这些漂洋过海的“客人”。这些巨草身长数米，茎秆粗壮、叶片宽大、根系发达。哪怕是人群里的大高个子，一进草场就像走进了芦苇荡，瞬间就被绿色淹没。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地人按照英语发音习惯，常常把Juncao读成Junkao。其实，菌草技术是中国拥有完全自主知识产权的原创技术。直到现在，国际上菌草的英文名字都是汉语拼音“Juncao”。2001年，中国首个援外菌草技术示范基地在巴布亚新几内亚建成落地，截至目前，这项技术已经推广至全球一百多个国家和地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月22日，中国-太平洋岛国菌草技术示范中心在斐济揭牌启动。福建农林大学国家菌草工程技术研究中心专家林兴生今年1月来到斐济常驻，自此他的任务更重了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在斐济，菌草可以做畜禽的优质饲料，也可用于栽培食用菌——传统来说，就是种植蘑菇的优质培养料。”他告诉南方周末记者，他们的工作包括生产、科研、示范、培训、推广等。自2014年菌草技术在斐济落地实施以来，目前已培训当地菌草技术人才两千三百多人，发展七百多农户种植菌草菇，一千多农户发展菌草养殖，结束了斐济不能生产菌菇的历史。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“菌草浑身是宝，可一草多用。”林兴生表示，除了“以草代木”，作为食用菌、药用菌的培养基质外，菌草还可作为牛羊等家畜的饲料，有效缓解斐济西部干旱区旱季饲料短缺问题，促进当地畜牧业发展。另外，菌草生长快，根系发达，还可用于防治当地水土流失、盐碱地改良等。在斐济种植一公顷巨菌草，可吸收二氧化碳100吨以上，是应对气候变化的有效途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月底，在林兴生和其他专家的帮助下，楠迪当地人库玛家的农场河岸上种上了菌草。刚过去一个多月，原本光秃秃的陡坡上就长出了一丛丛的绿草。进入分蘖期、拔节期后，菌草会越长越快，林兴生“充满信心”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“之前滑坡上水土流失很严重，一下雨泥沙就冲进河里，种植菌草后可有效固土蓄水。这也是我们在斐济开展菌草护坡护岸防治水土流失生态治理的示范点之一。”林兴生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较于高大的菌草，青蒿显得格外“柔弱”。青蒿古名“菣”，意为“治疗疟疾之草”，始载于《神农本草经》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1700多年前，东晋道士、医学家葛洪在《肘后备急方》中留下青蒿抗疟的记载——“青蒿一握，以水二升渍，绞取之，尽服之。”这短短15字的古方，启迪了一代代中医学者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国中医科学院研究员屠呦呦也是从中得到启发，由高温改低温方式提取，最终成功发现了让百万疟疾患者受益的青蒿素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年6月30日，世界卫生组织宣布中国通过消除疟疾认证。据披露数据，中国疟疾本地原发病例，从新中国成立前的3000万/年，已降低至“连续四年为零”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着共建“一带一路”倡议的推进，中国青蒿抗疟的经验也被引入世界上其他国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;圣多美-普林西比（简称“圣普”）是非洲大陆西边的岛国，人口约22万人。这里一年分为旱季和雨季。其中，每年10月到次年5月的雨季里，潮湿和高温的天气，非常利于蚊虫的孳生。而蚊虫正是疟疾传播的重要媒介。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月17日，正在圣普开展抗疟援助的广州中医药大学青蒿研究中心副研究员黄新安告诉南方周末记者，趁着雨季刚刚开始，他们要加快监测、控制的步伐。当前在圣多美，一个村子出现超过3例疟疾患者就可被列入疫源村。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日，圣多美市大水区（Água Grande）一家医院上报了三个疟疾病例，10月16日他们就抽调人手，对重点疫源村进行了大规模筛查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一般我们会通过医院、疫控中心等渠道的反馈数据来确定疫源村，然后和防疟队员们一起进行病例筛查、药物发放、蚊虫消杀等工作。”黄新安说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，在圣多美市大水区自由村（Liberdade），中国青蒿抗疟项目团队曾采取清除传染源优先的“灭源除疟”方案，进行抗疟试点。在此之前，这个六百多人口的村庄，每年疟疾病例达三四百人次。3轮服药之后，团队持续进行流动人口监测和带虫率调查等措施。其后8个月的漫长雨季里，自由村没有出现本地疟疾感染病例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由村试点的成功，让圣普政府和当地的世卫组织官员增强了战胜疟疾的信心。因为立竿见影的治疗效果，专家组派发的青蒿复方药也被村民们称为“东方神药”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在中国菌草技术专家的帮助下，库玛家的农场河岸上种上了菌草。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“商机”与连接&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;菌草种菇项目为当地农户带来了商机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国援斐济菌草技术示范中心专家组组长林兴生举例称，斐济菌草中心为当地农户开展技术培训并提供长满菌丝的菌袋。农户从中心领取菌袋后，通过林下或阴棚阴畦覆土栽培出菇，只需简单浇水保持、掀薄膜通气等简单管理措施，约7-10天就可以采收第一茬平菇，就能有收入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在斐济，普通农户只要在房前屋后种植10平方米的菌草平菇，一年种4次，就可以收获1200公斤鲜平菇，可收入2万元斐济币，折合人民币差不多是6万多块钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这比当地普通农民的年收入高很多，所以当地人把菌草项目称为&#39;quick money、easy money&#39;（来钱容易又快）。”林兴生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在非洲中东部国家卢旺达，种菇的经济效益同样吸引着普通农民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国援卢旺达菌草技术示范中心专家组组长陈晓斌告诉南方周末记者，卢旺达人多地少、工业欠发达。当地工人收入低，平均每天收入仅有9元人民币。通过简便易操作的菌草技术，普通人只需小片空地和基础照料，就能种出“来钱快”的经济作物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较于本地此前的种菇技术，中国菌草种菇技术成本低、产量高、操作简便，受到很多种菇户的欢迎。与卢旺达毗邻的周边国家，如乌干达、刚果金等，也有蘑菇商人到边境贸易点采购鲜菇。不断扩大的国内外市场需求，也激发了种菇户的积极性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了领菌袋种菇外，也有人钻研菌袋生产技术，实现“技术本地化”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在斐济楠迪，农户Ashniel是种菇能手。他不仅完全掌握了菌草菇管理技术，还学会了自己独立生产菌袋。同时，他还改造了加湿机，用于调节出菇场所的湿度。他种出的平菇菌肉肥厚、质量好，不仅吸引了许多人来参观学习，也受到客户的青睐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卢旺达，很多来培训的当地人是受过高等教育的大学生。他们学成之后自主创业，向当地农户有偿销售菌袋。据初步统计，当地人自主生产菌袋的公司及合作社约有五十多家。据陈晓斌介绍，在卢旺达，中国菌草技术是优质菌菇的象征。种菇户或者菌袋生产商在宣传时都会争相打上“Juncao Technology”的标签。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伴随着菌草种菇技术传入，中国蘑菇也悄然融入了当地饮食文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢旺达菌草技术示范中心陈晓斌介绍，每次给学员培训时，老师们都会安排烹饪课程，演示蘑菇的各种吃法。“比如油炸、爆炒、蘑菇汤等”。学员看了以后，也会结合当地饮食习惯进行创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在斐济，种菇户把蘑菇加工后，添加木薯粉等材料，使其变成蘑菇饮料，在卢旺达，由面皮裹馅制成的传统面食Sambusa(中国人叫它三角包),在土豆、牛肉、洋葱等常规馅料外，最近也加入了热卖的蘑菇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“菌草出海”的第一站——巴布亚新几内亚（简称“巴新”）东高地省，菌草和旱稻产业已成为该地区继咖啡之后的第二、第三大农业产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2000年初，中国福建省与巴新东高地省签署友好省份协议，将菌草和旱稻技术列为福建省对东高地省的援建项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国援巴新菌草技术示范基地专家组组长林应兴告诉南方周末记者，多年来，菌草项目在巴新的推广面积、参与农户、培训人员、专家人数等大幅度提高。当前，菌草种菇、菌草畜牧以及旱稻种植等细分项目已推广到了该国多个省份，超过1万农户受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《巴新信使报》2023年10月4日报道，该项目已成为中国与巴新“一带一路”合作的典范，为深化两国发展合作以及中国福建省、巴新东高地省的友好关系发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在斐济楠迪，农户Ashniel种出的平菇菌肉肥厚、质量好，不仅吸引了许多人来参观学习，也受到客户的青睐。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“对症下药”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据世卫组织2020年数据，在全球6大区域中，非洲地区受疟疾影响最严重，2020年该区域疟疾病例占全球总数的95%，疟疾死亡人数占全球的96%。据估计，该地区疟疾死亡人数的80%为5岁以下儿童。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006年，广州中医药大学青蒿研究中心副研究员邓长生在非洲岛国科摩罗做抗疟援助。他从前期调研数据中看到，当时科摩罗的医疗机构中，门诊病例中约60%都是疟疾。在住院病例中，也有超过一半是疟疾病人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以说，当时疟疾是这个国家最头疼的卫生问题。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在当时的科摩罗，很多居民习惯在雨季用地窖收集雨水，供旱季来临时使用。在野外调研时，邓长生看到很多居民的水窖里，密密麻麻爬着蚊子的幼虫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恶劣的饮水环境无疑是疟疾肆虐的原因之一。即使到了近几年，非洲地区的疟疾状况依然不容乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州中医药大学青蒿研究中心主任宋健平教授告诉南方周末记者，2017年，团队在非洲多哥的东莫诺（Est-Mono）地区约15万人群中抽查，在随机抽查的两千多个人中，样本人群的带虫率高达80%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了带虫率极高外，很多非洲国家的抗疟医疗体系非常薄弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多非洲国家都有一个共同的问题，那就是没有基层医疗，或者急缺急诊医生。”据宋健平介绍，有疟疾的人出现症状后，因各种原因无法就医。有的是居民需要自己花钱做检测、购买高价药品；有的是交通不便，无法到达正规医院。无法及时发现，那么就不可能达到早治早防的效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年来，包括宋健平团队在内的中国青蒿抗疟专家们在非洲国家展开青蒿抗疟行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在科摩罗，其团队实施的青蒿素复方全民服药清除传染源行动，遏制了该国的疟疾流行势头，实现了疟疾零死亡。在巴新，项目仅实施一年后，平均人群带虫率为0.07%，下降幅度超过99%，实现了疟疾零死亡。在圣多美，项目组逐步建立了圣普“卫生部-县-村”三级抗疟体系，按照疟疾发病率高低和暴发疫情多少，有针对性地对高发村进行提前干预，抑制疟疾暴发流行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这么多年来，这些方案经过了多个国家上百万人的验证，有非常丰富的临床数据。数据证明，中国方案是有效的、立竿见影的。对于复方青蒿抗疟的方案，我们是十分自信的。”邓长生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋健平认为，疟疾防治是一项复杂而庞大的工作。从药物本身来说，复方青蒿抗疟方案有自己的优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，团队在抗疟制药上不断优化药物配比，让它既能保持青蒿素治愈率高的优点，同时又能减少不良反应，减少服用轮次，尽可能适用于大规模服药现场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有些药物的不良反应发生率高达百分之二三十，这会让病人产生恐惧心理。参与度低意味着覆盖率低，无法达到防治效果。”宋健平说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在非洲大陆，尼日利亚和刚果金两个国家占了全世界疟疾发病的70%。相较岛屿国家，这里发病率更高、感染程度更重、人口更多、人口流动性更强。方案实施起来，可能需要更大的资金量以及更大范围的协同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接下来，宋健平希望一方面持续开发更有效的抗疟药物，另一方面把抗疟经验推广到更多地区。“将来我们希望在非洲大陆有所作为。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生翟桓、包婧玥对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[个人养老金保险名单增加18款税延养老产品 总名单扩容至69款]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，据中国银行保险信息技术管理有限公司（以下简称“中国银信保”）官网显示，个人养老金保险产品名单扩容至69款产品，涉及22家保险公司。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，此次扩容不仅在7月末48款产品种类基础之上增加了3款，并且还将18款个人税收递延型养老年金保险（以下简称“税延养老产品”） 纳入了个人养老金产品体系。扩容后个人养老金保险产品种类包括专属商业养老保险、两全保险、年金保险和税延养老产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254620&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（图片来源：&amp;nbsp;中国银信保）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述18款纳入个人养老金的税延养老产品分别由中国太平洋人寿保险股份有限公司、太平养老保险股份有限公司、平安养老保险股份有限公司、泰康养老保险股份有限公司、太平人寿保险有限公司和中意人寿保险有限公司提供。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开源证券研报显示，税延型商业养老险并入个人养老金主要为税延型养老保险投保人完成第三支柱税优政策协调统一，并降低领取时个人所得税率，利于个人养老金体系的进一步完善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，8月31日，国家金融监督管理总局发布《关于个人税收递延型商业养老保险试点与个人养老金衔接有关事项的通知》。 《通知》主要内容包括对税延养老保险试点与个人养老金衔接过程中的工作要求、业务调整、产品管理、保单转移等进行明确，并且对中国银信保统筹做好客户信息确认、加强系统建设，以及税延养老保险试点保险公司业务操作、公告通知、信息报送等提出要求，原则上应于2023年底前完成各项工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;业内人士表示，个人税收递延养老保险凸显“减负”效应，退休后税收负担较轻。而此次名单的扩容意味着税延养老保险业务与个人养老金制度衔接工作正在有序推进，符合工作预期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2018年，财政部等部门联合印发《关于开展个人税收递延型商业养老保险试点的通知》，启动了在国内的试点业务运行。试点区域为上海、福建及苏州工业园区，税前可扣除额度最高为个人应税收入的6%或12000元/年孰低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平安证券表示，该试点政策对低收入人群缺乏吸引力，对可享受税收优惠的人群来说，税优力度有限。而个人养老金制度下产品选择更多、税收抵扣手续更简便，两类产品属性相似、共享税优额度，税延型商业养老险并入个人养老金将理顺税优型养老保险关系，简化相关手续，便于投资者理解，同时将进一步丰富个人养老金产品选择，提升投资者投保意愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2022年11月个人养老金制度正式实施以来，个人养老金保险产品持续扩容，据中国银保信官网披露，2023年7月末，个人养老金保险产品数量已由试点之初的7款扩容至48款，当前已扩容至69款产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平安证券表示，人口老龄化背景下居民养老储蓄需求持续扩张，而今年以来长端利率保持低位震荡、多家商业银行下调存款利率、权益市场波动较大，竞品收益率下滑，而保险产品遵循定价利率、产品具备保底收益率，同时可提供身故、全残、失能等风险保障，差异化优势进一步凸显。商业养老保险作为养老第三支柱的重要组成部分，有望在个人养老金制度下获得长足发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社会学家刘汶蓉：年轻人的很多选择无法成为“现实选择”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见：《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/258684&quot; title=&quot;纪录片《巢》：互相折磨的两代人，为什么还要住在一起&quot;>;纪录片《巢》：互相折磨的两代人，为什么还要住在一起&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纪录片《巢》把镜头对准了上海一个三口之家，85后男青年毕业多年，与父母蜗居于30平米的老公房。上海社会科学院研究员刘汶蓉关注到这个纪录片，她对这样的家庭十分熟悉。2016年是纪录片开始拍摄的年份，她当时正在做代际关系研究的课题，发现了“啃老”家庭这个群体：“在2016年的时候已经有很多这样的案例，只是现在青年人就业形势更严峻，还有他们的期待不一样了，所以越来越多。最早是2005年还是2006年，上海这边就开始&#39;啃&#39;了，因为房价开始贵了，老年人感受到支持子女的压力越来越大，对&#39;啃老&#39;这件事情当时有一波讨论。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘汶蓉读博时便开始关注、研究中国社会的代际关系问题。21世纪前十年，从事质性研究的学者以大量篇幅谈论孝道衰落、养老危机、代际失衡等问题。她当年的博士论文也源于想要验证“孝道衰落”的说法，结果却把她引向另一个方向。2008年，她在分析兰州和上海的调查数据时，发现代际关系反而呈现紧密化趋势，并且越年轻的人越认同孝道观念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年至2019年，她与课题组走访上海、兰州、大连等地，搜集137个家庭个案，在美国搜集11个家庭个案，结合抽样调查资料，最终得出结论：社会转型强化了中国家庭“亲子一体”的情感结构，代际互助传统表现出强大的韧性，代际纽带仍然发挥着安顿个体生命和激励日常生活的共同体功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在实地调研过程中，刘汶蓉见过许多受家庭兜底、托举的中国年轻人，而在美国调研时，与当地学者交流，东西方家庭两相对照，令她触动。加之自己拥有了母亲的身份与体验，她的心态有了变化。曾经，她一度反感中国的家庭文化，认为“道德绑架”过重，如今她认为这是种温暖的制度设计，中国城市家庭承担了青年人失业和结婚生子的“兜底”工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2160&quot; height=&quot;1215&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;纪录片《巢》中，85后主人公（左）与年过七旬的父母共同生活。片方供图&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;）&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“虽然我们之前的文化理想是自由平等，破除封建主义的孝道和代际父权等等，但是现实中的社会，离开这些，目前没有建立起其他的可以支持人安身立命的文化心灵基础，所以（家庭文化）反而变成了一种价值示范。我们要尊重文化的传承，又要改造。这不是说改造就能改造的，需要深刻的思想上的转型，它是一个比较长的过程。”刘汶蓉对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，刘汶蓉将研究重心转移至青年婚恋上，正在操作课题“大城市青年人的婚恋趋势、困境与社会过程研究”。在与南方周末记者的访谈中，她谈及转型期家庭代际冲突、全职儿女现象、信息社会中的青年困境等话题。以下为其自述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;子女一旦不再结婚生子，很难与父母真正和解&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们70后，往上的时代更加是，在青年时期，我们有非常强烈的离家的动力。为什么呢？父母的管控是非常痛苦的，而我们感受到的爱是非常少的，因为多子女的时候，父母分配给你的时间和精力，包括经济资源，都非常少。这种状态下，孩子不需要评估，几乎是一个自然形成的动力，就是必须要在很早的时候读书远离他们，必须挣到钱养活自己，这种动力非常强。还有必须要结婚，因为结了婚就可以理直气壮地离开那个家庭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种动力下，可以说我们那时都是生存的问题。我们也想要自我实现，从小想过画画啊，唱歌啊，写作啊等等，但是大部分人都只是把它当作自己埋在心里的一个理想。首先要满足自己的生存，要就业，要结婚，要在社会上有一个同辈的支持网络。我们的支持主要是依赖于朋友、同学，这个网络是非常重要的，很愿意花时间精力结交这样的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是现在的年轻人，父母给的生存上的压力非常小，他们把很多精力和思想都花在自己的理想为什么不能实现这件事情上，就显得非常无力，因为他们的自我实现标准是比较高的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然我觉得这种话说出来年轻人会不开心，我知道他们的经历不一样，他们没有办法理解。我的研究也发现，代际之间，因为没有相似的经历，也没有相似的社会角色，互相理解是很难的，更多的是要依赖于父辈，因为父辈比他们成熟。比如和谐家庭依赖于父辈的妥协，无论是自然做到还是经过反思后塑造的，但一定是做到了深刻的、思想观念上的慰藉、包容。如果没有这一条是很难的，因为子代没有相似的人生道路和体验，是很难和父辈达成精神上的和解的。就算他们也认同孝道，认同爱的重要性，但是很难生发出这样一个东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以这也是家庭对人的精神的一个困境吧，特别是现在转型之后，人生道路不再标准化、不复制，每个人个体化了。我后来出一本书专门讨论中国家庭代际关系的情感转型，我最后的结论就是在讲生育对两代人的价值认同和情感沟通的作用。很多青年是在自己结婚生孩子之后，才和父母达成精神上的和解。如果他没有做父母，很难真正理解父母，很难放下父母对自己的伤害。只有他自己站在同样的角色上，（拥有）自己对自己孩子的情感经历的时候，真正意识到做父母的苦衷，发现自己再怎么样有好的意愿，也有很多的不如意，会有很多不可控情况，自己没法成为一个完美的父母，这个时候，他对父母对自己养育过程中的一些事情才能够放下，而且能理解到养育过程的不容易。这种和解其实是很微妙的。我的调查中，父母会自然感受到（和子女）之间的默契，心灵上就会得到一种宽慰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国父母为什么特别在意孩子结婚生子？传宗接代这个事，当下的中国父母已经基本不是很强调了，都会认为它是封建思想，特别是受过教育的父母。但是为什么还会追求这个东西，总觉得好像缺点什么，就是自己做父母的这条艰辛道路没有被认可。这是一个他们价值上巨大的失落，这种失落感无法在现代价值体系中被言说。网络上父母不会讲这些东西，甚至在日常生活中，他们也不知道自己为什么这样。其实是自己没有得到认可，就是不知道自己一辈子忙活了些啥的状态。但是当子女生了孩子，他们在心灵上得到了一种理解和宽慰，和一种价值的认可，这个是很重要的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国家庭文化的活力在于传承性，传承是一个循环，不是线性的。但是一旦子女不再结婚生子，其实他很难理解婚姻中的挣扎，养育中的挣扎，他们心理上很难与父母真正和解。所以，我觉得当下青年人中兴起的自愿不婚不育文化，是中国家庭目前在社会转型中面临的非常大的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们都经历了经济快速发展期，而且青春期没有那么强的信息传播，我们也没有经过很刻意的反思，就是自然而然地享受了这个时代发展的红利。但是当下的青年人成长于完全不同的社会发展阶段，他们面临非常大的精神挑战。我们需要更多的代际之间的理解，我们不能说现在的青少年都很矫情，都很虚无，说他们躺平、没有志向，或者懒惰。每个时代都有因为心理上或者个性上有一些问题，无法走向社会的人。但这个人群如果特别大，就是一个社会问题。我们需要的是代际之间的理解和沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如说青年人的婚恋问题，我们也着急，主流社会非常着急，国家也非常着急，为什么不愿意结婚？为什么不愿意生孩子？我觉得更重要的还是要理解，重要的是要让年轻人从内心认可结婚生子这条道路，还需要告诉他们亲密关系对人的心理健康和长远发展的意义。因为不婚不育，大多是青年人处于风险感知之下的一种自我保护，如果缺乏支持，他们只能顾当下了。所以，我们在文化上，对家庭生活的精神性、心理性，都需要全方位地思考。或者，需要更多的全社会讨论，让大家对婚姻制度、亲密关系有更多的理解，对个人的道路选择创造更多的可能性和空间。我们政府一直说支持婚育，就是给钱，给时间，我觉得还有就是价值层面需要更多地引领，或者说让年轻人更多地认同。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我们担心的是青年永远无法走出家庭”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在城市中产阶级家庭里，95后子女更加回归父母。我的文章《转型期城市家庭亲权回归与孝道再造》，就是回应“妈宝”越来越多，孩子很多东西都愿意听父母的，和父母关系紧密、情感亲密这一现象。日常生活中，他们是小叛逆，但是大问题上面与父母没有什么冲突，不管是择偶的观念，就业的观念，还是入学的观念，好像都很相近。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中产阶层父母来说，他们已经完全改变了过去“家长式”的亲职模式。我在文章中称之为自反性的亲职实践，就是父母反思自己成长经历中的伤痛，形成了一种以爱和情感为基础的养育方式，对子女成长道路进行全方位的规划和协助，期待孩子幸福又成功。另一方面，就是中产父母的资源也不一样。80后的父母，50后，他们自己的财富积累没有那么多，经济压力还很大。但是到了95后就不太一样，整个社会的经济状况都有了很大发展，特别是中产以上、受过大学教育的父母，他们一般自己职业也比较好，经济积累、知识积累也比较好，社会资本、经济资本各方面都比较好，所以能全方位地投入孩子的养育，而且从小是一种亲密亲职和密集养育。这种亲密亲职用的是情感感化和引导的方式，粗暴的强制管控行为变少了。所以孩子在成长过程中与父母没有那么大的紧张和冲突，以至到了青年期依然表现出对父母的高度依赖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得到了00后、10后，心理健康问题特别严重，这当然与学业有关，另一方面也是与长期的家庭结构，就是代际之间的共生有很大关联。孩子被照顾和被安排得满满当当，这种爱让他无法呼吸。孩子在学校也好，在家里也好，都是这种完全被监控的状态。这样的话，孩子的心理是很难健康的，无力感会很强，所以青少年抑郁症现在也日渐增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们中国的家庭主义，就是亲子一体的状态，在生活支持方面有很强的工具性功能。比如，在我国的经济转型过程中，没有出现大批的青年贫困人口，都是父母在支撑，也没有那种大批的无法结婚、落入贫困，甚至流浪的青年人，这都是因为中国家庭父母在托底，所以这是一个工具意义上的好处。但是现在已经到了21世纪的第二个十年，我们看到的更多是精神上的压力，给青年发展上的压力，我们担心的是青年人永远无法走出家庭，困在里面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本也有相似的情况，当经济条件发展放缓甚至停滞以后，青年人获得稳定的好工作、好婚姻的机会减少，父母就保护子女，他们叫“寄居单身”现象，就寄居在父母那里，不婚，有的人也不工作。我看一些资料介绍，这些单身到老的子女，在父母去世后，很可能陷入单身无缘的状态，也是一个非常大的社会问题。我们是不是也会到这一步呢？当人的生存已经不是问题了，发展面临瓶颈怎么办？父母把子女保护起来是一个出路吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于全职儿女，我并不反对，但是父母要做聪明的父母，子女也要做聪明的子女。阶段性的gap没有问题，因为现在你有条件追求更好的事业，追求更高的学历，追求更好的结婚对象，中间成年的时间就必然变得越来越长，但是一定要意识到不能一直这样。子女身份是无期限的，但是做了全职儿女，有一个契约的概念，我可以解约，我可以换工作。它是个职业，是临时的，不是终身的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母和子女都要为跳槽或者为转变职业身份，做自己的准备，不能够“我这样也挺好的”，就接纳这样一个状态，就一直这样。除非你在从事一种创造性的工作，（比如）在家里写东西，但是你还要有办法养活自己，因为你的价值来源不独立的话，自我效能感一定很低，从心理健康上看也绝对不是一个长久之计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西方人把中国的家庭概括为corporation model——认为中国的家庭是一个合作社，其实corporation也是一个以理性架构为基础的组织，是一个事业。组织和事业需要发展，发展需要不断壮大。但是我觉得这些年轻人并没有继承这个家庭主义观点，他是因为外界的风险太大，缩小了自己建立更大亲密圈的努力。其实对他们的家庭来说，是没有发展、没有未来的，也就是说，在他们这两代人之间，结束了就结束了。这不是我们中国的家庭主义传统，他只是满足于自己最朴素的孝道思想，就是我是一个好人，我孝敬父母，父母爱我，我也爱他们，我努力让父母过得好，就完成了我人生的道德上的价值。所以这种“孝道回归”，确实是现在年轻人的真实思想状态，但也绝不是简单的向传统回归。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;这个潮流让人活得非常抽象&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;现在年轻人的需求是比较高的，包括婚恋的标准，非常复杂。我支持年轻人精神上的追求、爱情的追求，但是这些追求又加上现实考量就很难。我做婚恋研究发现，所有的调查者都没有办法回避，择偶到最后都是一个经济指标，但是只有经济又不能完全说服他们，所以就非常纠结。心理的复杂性非常强，不像我们70后有非常强的离家的驱动，真的是没有考虑那么多。因为当时的多子女家庭资源有限、父母对孩子也普遍缺乏耐心，年轻人必须去外地上学、就业、结婚、建立起自己的生活网络，这背后是一种更接近生存需求的动力，所以对工作、伴侣的理想化、完美化追求就比较弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现在整个社会的信息、参照标准不一样，现在的网络、信息传播太发达，给人的无力感太强了。你总觉得有无限的可能，但现实并非如此。他参照的对象永远是最好的那一批人，没有办法对自己身边的人和事，包括对自己满意，活得非常不快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的话，就让年轻人很难活在自己眼前具体的生活当中，导致他们陷入了非常大的无力感。“我不将就，我努力”既是一种个性宣言，也是一种风险规避。他们其实没有努力，因为没办法有努力的途径。人的能量、力量是有限的，只能在自己附近去努力，就像一句老话说得好，要一步一步来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们那时候很容易做到，现在为什么年轻人很难做到，不是说年轻人不好，是因为整个社会的变化，导致人的心理环境的变化。所以要做一些反向的自我训练，必须要通过刻意的、有意识的、深刻的自我规训才能做到，如果你顺着这个潮流就做不到。因为这个潮流下，好像就是有一种文化环境，让人活得非常抽象、不实在。而我们那个时候，即使是随便找一个工作，我们好像也没有觉得不行、不舒服，因为大家都这样，不是不能接受的，大部分人是这样一个状态。这也是一个社会的进步，生存已经不是问题了，现在年轻人才会想“我不要将就，我要追求我自己最理想的那个状态”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一个是风险社会的背景，就是恐惧心理造成的，这个也很重要。我们要看年轻人的注意力放在了哪里，他放得越高远就会越恐惧，他的无力感就会越强。但是这个时代是注意力经济，吸引人的永远是那些高远的东西。消费主义啊，网络文化啊，都是这样的，大多数是满足人生理上的刺激，激发了人的欲望，这种欲望暂时会让你兴奋或者满足，或者产生一种美好的想象，但是它不长久地支持你一步一步地生活。所以我说年轻人活得很抽象，我不愿意用别的词，比如浮躁这类贬义词。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在“成人”变得非常困难，自我认同、稳定下来非常困难。当然人一辈子都要处在这样一个认识自己的过程中，但是年轻人的成长很难进入下一个阶段，因为他无法分清，无法抉择，一直处在这种纠结的状态。而现在的网络文化也好，消费文化也好，游戏也好，都让年轻人更多地沉溺在这个阶段，一直不成年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们一直在欲望和理想中分不清：其实是在满足他们的一种短暂的欲望，不是走在理想的道路上，因为没有在现实中去落地。我们的文化营造的这些氛围，让他们感觉自己在这条路上，造成了好像自己很有追求、很有理想、在奋斗的幻想，这样就错过了生命周期的最佳状态，慢慢地自然而然地滑落。其实有很多研究已经注意到，包括日本对青年的研究调查也是，并不是年轻人计划不婚不育，一开始就坚定地树立“我是一个不婚不育者”，有，但并不是大多数人。只是他们在寻找伴侣的过程中，在探寻自己理想的道路上，滑落到了最后单身的结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得对年轻人还是要更理解，确实是整个环境的影响，社会文化、心理、经济各个方面，其实是整个现代性对人精神的一个压迫。如果再往上走就是到这个（层面），在青年这里非常明显。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现在年轻人没有机会日久生情&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;你在二十来岁的时候看起来有无限可能，到了四十岁，似乎也还有很多可能。但事实上你在现实中，看看你的周围又好像没有什么机会，这就让人很抓狂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我做婚恋研究，发现年轻人觉得有很多机会，互联网上有很多平台。选择似乎非常多，但其实最后都不是选择，就是都没有办法成为现实选择，这就是青年的困境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种选择和我们那时候不太一样。我就讲一个点，很有趣的是，现在大学生不谈恋爱，高中生好像还谈谈，但是大学为什么不谈呢？而且他们工作以后也不找自己单位的，因为会觉得如果不成很尴尬！这个理由初听很不可思议，但仔细想我觉得也挺对的，这是非常理性的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恋爱这个东西是需要时间、情感培养的，需要长期地互相接触。我调查发现，他们每个周末都很辛苦地要去相亲，一周就相亲一次，要绞尽自己的脑汁去跟人谈，甚至参加各种相亲活动。但活动结束以后，那个人就不会出现在你身边了。就算你当时觉得这个人还行，但他在这一周之内不出现在你身边，最多周末再见，很多人都是坚持个两三次就索然无味了。而且关键是条件不会好到让你不顾一切，也许条件还行，但是再一想，还有很多你不满意的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是一种理性衡量了，你按条件来衡量永远有不满意的地方，不可能一个人什么都好，什么条件都完全达到。日久生情不是看条件，即使条件一般但是有感情了，也就在一起了，很多时候是这样的。但是现在年轻人没有这个机会，他没有生出感情的机会，因为他们根本就没有日常接触，甚至是发生一些事件触动你。这样的话，没有感情你就完全看条件，看条件又总是不满意，所以就很难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个社会看起来好像选择非常多，但事实上因为你没有现实的接触，附近没有什么机会，也没有什么可选的。而且他们害怕进入现实生活中具体的关系，他们很怕关系破裂或不愉快的风险，担心受伤和关系的缠绕，对人际关系的投入有一种非常大的担忧和警惕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不知道这是不是独生子女普遍的问题，就是他们的人际边界感很强，担心、害怕关系复杂，与人自然形成一种远离，到哪里都很想把自己择出来。而在我们那个多子女时代，从小就在各种关系里面摸爬滚打，伤害肯定也很多，但是好像自然而然就形成了不怕，觉得这是一个正常的状态，或是生出了应对的生理反应也好，技能也好。现在被家长保护的年轻人，或者独生子女，他们没有这个能力，也不愿意去掺和人际关系，他们觉得那样很low，喜欢独来独往，需要自己的空间比较大。所以我觉得这都是时代的变化，也是时代进步的一个负向后果吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我有一个学生就说，她只要和她父母在一起就可以了。确实有这样的孩子，这样的想法：我在这个世界上也不需要再和谁建立那么强的紧密的关系。因为建立紧密关系需要很多磨合，有很多不适应，挑战非常大。人和人之间的忍让，各种各样的妥协，总之他们不太愿意，觉得这个太复杂了，偶尔一两次，就玩一下，但是很难深入交往。所以我觉得他们宁愿相亲。甚至有学生说，老师，如果国家给我们发一个配偶就好了。他们愿意追剧，磕CP，那种爱情的甜，这样就用完了，不需要在现实生活中找爱的感受了。因为没有那么完美的一个人，让他有那种情感，想到两个人那么甜那么相爱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看别人谈恋爱，如果要组建家庭，“国家发我一个”。所以他们很接受父母介绍。当然父母也跟他们价值观念比较接近，在择偶上意见也能够协调，所以他们挺接受父母安排的，这个和我们当时预见的也完全不一样。我们原来想的都是，随着现代化的发展，教育程度提高，婚姻一定是自由恋爱模式。但是现在看起来也不全是，恋爱是恋爱，但是婚姻的话父母安排挺好的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，这都不是大型调查，大型调查里面可能还很难反映出来。但是我之前看到过一个全国调查数据，就是和1990年代比，21世纪以后父母在子女婚恋决策中的作用在上升。这个我觉得很自然，主要是经济上的原因。现在年轻人结婚，买房、彩礼、看娃哪一个环节都要依靠父母，再加上年轻人心理上对父母的依赖也有所上升，所以父母的话语权肯定上升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改什么？怎么改？难在哪？超大特大城市城中村改造政策解读]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年以来，城中村改造按下“加速键”。住房和城乡建设部近日表示，超大特大城市正积极稳步推进城中村改造，分三类推进实施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一个关乎多方利益的系统性民生工程和发展工程，当前在超大特大城市推进城中村改造的背景是什么？怎么改？难点在哪儿？ “新华视点”记者就此采访了业内专家学者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;为什么改？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;今年以来，城中村改造备受关注。 4月28日召开的中共中央政治局会议提出“在超大特大城市积极稳步推进城中村改造”的要求；7月，国务院办公厅印发《关于在超大特大城市积极稳步推进城中村改造的指导意见》，并召开电视电话会议进行了专门部署。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，住房和城乡建设部对城中村改造提出了具体政策落实措施，分三类推进实施：一类是符合条件的实施拆除新建，另一类是开展经常性整治提升，第三类是介于两者之间的实施拆整结合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城中村被称为“都市里的村庄”，兼具农村和城市的双重特征，是城市化发展过程中的历史产物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上海市中心城区最大的城中村——普陀区红旗村为例，586亩的土地上，曾聚集着90家印刷厂、207个冷库、9个大型初级集贸市场、1000多个摊位，这里人口复杂、群租遍地、违建密布，流动人口多达6万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照相关标准划分，城区常住人口1000万以上的城市为超大城市，如北京、上海、广州、深圳、成都、重庆、天津、武汉等；城区常住人口500万以上1000万以下的城市为特大城市，如青岛、合肥、杭州、长沙、南京、东莞等。全国总计有20余个城市属于超大特大城市范畴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我国超大特大城市吸纳了大量外来人口，这些群体有相当一部分租住在城中村。尽管城中村租房成本较低，但是普遍缺乏必要的基础设施、公共服务，尤其是在卫生安全、社会治理等方面存在诸多隐患。”浙江工业大学中国住房和房地产研究院院长虞晓芬说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市房地产科学研究院院长严荣表示，推进城中村改造，一方面可对经济稳增长发挥积极作用，成为扩大内需的重要拉动点，产生超过十万亿元的直接投资，并拉动家具家电、餐饮服务、纺织品等多方面的消费；另一方面可优化城市空间布局，进一步提升城市治理水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;怎么改？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“城中村产权结构、人员构成、空间分布、历史遗存等具有高度复杂性，这次改造提出拆除新建、整治提升、拆整结合三类改造模式。”广东省住房政策研究中心副主任李宇嘉说，具备条件的，即资金能平衡、群众改造意愿强烈、土地及物业权属清晰的城中村将实施拆除新建；不具备条件的，不硬上，以守住安全底线为原则，常态化开展整治提升，逐步解决问题的基础上再实施改造。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在改造方式上，当前城中村改造特别强调要将村民合法权益保障与先谋后动相结合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虞晓芬说，新政着重强调在大部分村民同意的情况下方可实施改造。改造前，地方政府要先做好产业先行搬迁、人员妥善安置、历史文化风貌保护和落实资金等前期谋划工作。改造时，应先行安排安置房项目供地和建设，确保安置房在合理工期内建成，品质不低于商品住房水平，配套基础设施和公共服务设施与安置房规划、设计、报批、建设、交付使用“五同步”，切实保障好村民利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村是高度复杂的社会综合体，改造后应该保持多样化的业态。”中国城市规划学会副理事长赵燕菁说，城中村本身是一个产业空间，其业态不是预先规划，而是随市场需求变化而不断变化。城中村改造要注重产业导入和培育孵化，努力发展各种业态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1254&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254585&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;拼版照片：上图为2023年8月3日拍摄的改造后的安徽省合肥市瑶海区安拖东村及新庄城中村改造项目（无人机照片）；下图为2015年3月拍摄的改造前的安拖东村及新庄城中村旧貌。新华社发（解琛摄）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李宇嘉说，过去的城中村改造由市场化主导，挑肥拣瘦，经济价值高的被纳入改造计划，而历史遗留问题多、安全风险隐患大的却被留置。 “这一次，全部城中村都要纳入改造范围，征拆时不能只算经济账，只征收经济价值高、问题少的地块，而是要不分好坏全部征收，彻底解决城中村问题，并防止出现新的城中村。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次城中村改造，要求原则上应当按一定比例建设保障性住房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，赵燕菁表示，目前城中村在城市中承担的一个重要功能，就是给流动人口提供租赁性保障房，城中村事实上成为保障房体系中的有机组成部分。 “如果改造后这部分保障房供给减少了，流动人口的居住环境恶化，租金更高，那就没有实现城中村改造的初衷。因此，必须在改造方案中按一定比例建设保障房作为补偿。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;改造要注意哪些问题？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在采访中，专家普遍认为，推进城中村改造要特别注意三个问题：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是拆迁安置问题。虞晓芬说，超大特大城市遗留的城中村，违章建筑多、人口密集、产权关系复杂，是改造难度大的“硬骨头”，其拆迁、补偿等问题十分复杂，矛盾和不确定性因素较多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者在各地采访了解到，在超大特大城市的城中村里，各种经济活动几乎应有尽有。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现实中，城中村在与城市其他功能长期互动中，形成了功能的互补。简单&#39;切除&#39;城中村，城市其他部分也会随之失能。对此要特别慎重。”赵燕菁说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵燕菁认为，改造伊始，就要对城中村承担的城市功能进行认真调研和分析。如果没有找到对这些功能的替代途径，就不要贸然采取“切除”手术，此时应采用“微创”的保守疗法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是资金平衡与筹措问题。虞晓芬说，遗留的城中村建筑密度大、安置成本高，特别是在目前超大特大城市外围房地产市场仍然较为低迷的环境中，相较过去，城中村改造后出让土地的价值下降，必然会增加社会化资本的筹措难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村改造如何啃&#39;硬骨头&#39;，关键还是改造资金怎么平衡。”李宇嘉说，国务院办公厅印发的指导意见提出，鼓励实施区域统筹和成片开发，改造项目土地四至范围可扩大至周边少量低效用地，允许集体土地和国有土地整合、置换。 “也就是说，各地政府可以将过去单一城中村改造的&#39;小平衡&#39;变为片区综合改造的&#39;大平衡&#39;，以丰补歉、以肥补瘦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵燕菁说，城中村改造必须创新改造模式，寻求多样的融资渠道，鼓励和支持民间资本参与，其中特别重要的是原物业所有者的参与。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是标准和规范约束。一些不具备拆迁条件的城中村，实施局部拆建和综合整治，要求按照文明城市标准整治提升和实施管理，这对于一些住房质量较差、标准较低、整治成本高，且部分住房产权模糊、手续不全的城中村，具有挑战性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“城中村改造需要先谋后动、统筹兼顾、整体谋划、积极稳步推进，以新思路新方式破解城中村改造中账怎么算、钱怎么用、地怎么征、人和产业怎么安置等难题，探索出一条新形势下城中村改造的新路子。”中国房地产估价师与房地产经纪人学会会长柴强说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[城市排名，看看就行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，咨询公司Resonance Consultancy发布了“2024年世界最佳城市排名”。2024年还没有到来，但排行就是这么有前瞻性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个排行榜中，名列前茅的依次是：伦敦、巴黎、纽约、东京、新加坡、迪拜、旧金山、巴塞罗那、阿姆斯特丹、首尔、罗马、布拉格、马德里、柏林、洛杉矶、华盛顿，然后才是排位18的北京。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有网友讽刺，这榜里是不是考虑了毒品交易稀有度、枪击、爆炸、抢劫、盗窃啥的？我现在越来越不信老外评选各种榜了，有的城市还没去，当地朋友就说晚上别出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网友的讽刺有一定道理，何为最佳城市，其实很难界定。2018年，曾有研究机构对中国338个地级以上城市进行了排名，评出了15个新一线城市排名。对这个排行榜，有的城市深以为然，有的城市则表示不服。其实，别说“最佳”这个概念太大，不好界定，就连小一些的“城市宜居性”，都很难说明白。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对普通人而言，一个城市是否宜居，无非是上班下班、赚钱发展，衣食住行，也就是收入、消费、公共服务三大类。工作方面，城市经济越发达，收入越高，当然就越宜居。生活方面，越便利、有更高的舒适性、生活成本低，就越宜居。这两个方面和市场有关，市场之外就是政府提供的公共服务。政府提供的公共服务中，教育、医疗可以由市场弥补，但治安只能由政府提供。治安是一个城市宜居的基础，不然挣再多的钱，命都保不住，还有啥意义？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候，这些指标又是相互矛盾的。最典型的就是大城市收入更高、发展机会更多，但与此同时，大城市的房价、消费也都更贵，生活成本很高。那么，大城市到底宜不宜居？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，大城市有更多机会。大城市有规模效应，规模效应之下，会有很多小地方无法维系的服务和岗位。这也就是很多人所说的，回了老家小城找不到工作。所以，具有更高经济指标的大城市，往往能提供更多的岗位、更高的工资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从消费方面看，因为规模效应，大城市作为生态系统更丰富，很多服务会更便宜。比如，要看一个专家号，生活在大城市也就是一个挂号费的事，各种疑难杂症都找得到对口专家。但生活在小城，还会多出出行住宿请假等成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大城市房子虽然贵，但房子也是一种资产。即便花几百万买了房子，这里面的钱仍然是可以收回变现的。更何况，手机、电视、汽车等工业品的价格几乎是一样。这就意味着，只要一个人的收入能够抵消，或者部分抵消大城市的房租，那么，他在大城市的生活水平会更高，更丰富，子女机会更多，应急时也能拿出更多的钱。这大致就是宜居二字所指。越来越多的人涌向大城市，也能证明大城市更宜居。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，人的需求是复杂而多元的，有些人想住200平米的房子，打打麻将，对歌剧、奢侈品没兴趣。有些人为了子女接受更好的教育，情愿住在60平米的小房子。所以，宜居归根到底，还是看个人。这还是抽象地评价大城市与小城市的宜居性，都只能给出一个判断原则，如果要评价具体城市之间宜居性的比较，那更是一本糊涂账。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有过统计知识、研究经验的人都知道，数据是会撒谎的。且不说数据的真假问题，即便数据都是真实的，在指标设置、抽样方法、数据处理、数据解读上，都有太多方法可以操控最终的结论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，设立一个消费指标，由网购活跃度、海淘活跃度、外卖活跃度、观影频次构成。观影似乎能反映文化消费，但电影有个口红效应，就是说经济不好的时候，人们仍然会娱乐，甚至更多地用娱乐来抚慰自己，但会转向价格相对低廉的。很可能旅游消费下去了，电影消费上来了。所以，观影指标未必客观，起码，这没有人均社会消费品总额这个指标来得权威、直接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的指标选择技巧还有很多。如果要把治安当作最重要的指标，设置若干小指标，那么，中国城市的世界排名一定会前进很多，因为中国人生性温良，又有无处不在的天眼。如果把烟火气看作指标，设置10个小指标，那么，纽约的分数可能会提高很多，毕竟连时代广场都乱糟糟的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，城市宜居的指标，往往是非独立的，一个指标好了，其他指标都会跟着好。比如，一个城市大学多了，医疗条件也会变好。因为大学往往有医学院，有了医学院专家自然就多了。但要排除这种独立性，似乎也不行。因为读更好的大学和找专家看病，本质上是市民的教育需求与医疗需求，这的确是两个方面的需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，通过设置指标，的确可以很大程度上影响一个城市的宜居性评价。其他的城市的经济活跃度、城市发达程度，最佳城市等各种排行榜，也是大都如此，可以参考，但不必当作权威。一般而言，你决定去哪个城市工作与生活，那个城市对你来说就是最宜居的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中职学校数量十年间大减，但“这不是坏事”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258931]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766tPBtXF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1263&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766 tPBtXF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 16, 2023, Hohhot, a vocational and technical school teacher introduced the professional situation to students . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A set of data on secondary vocational education once attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media reported that in the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 3,039. Southern Weekend reporters combined data from the websites of the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools continued to decrease, with a cumulative decrease of 2,911. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the websites of the two ministries and commissions, the number of secondary vocational schools in China will be 9,752 in 2022, less than half of the peak in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the country’s adjustment of vocational education policies is the main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools. In addition, the practical difficulties encountered in the development process of secondary vocational schools are also one of the reasons why various places have taken the initiative to merge and reduce schools. However, in recent years, with the changes in the layout of vocational education, secondary vocational schools have also ushered in new changes such as a substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that, combined with the predictions of scholars, in the next few years, the gradual reduction, dissolution, merger and optimization of secondary vocational schools will continue to be a trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Anhui Province has the largest decrease&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;An easily confused concept is that in China, secondary vocational education is divided into four categories, including general technical secondary schools, vocational High schools, adult secondary schools and technical schools. In accordance with the Vocational Education Law and the current &quot;three determinations&quot; (functional configuration, internal organization and staffing) plan of the State Council, vocational high schools, general technical secondary schools and adult technical secondary schools are under the management of the education department, and technical schools are under the management of the human resources and social security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be pointed out that the academic qualifications obtained after graduation from general technical secondary schools, vocational high schools, adult technical secondary schools and technical schools are all secondary education qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the Ministry of Education website shows that in 2013, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide was 12,300. By 2022, this number dropped to 7,201. In the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 5,100 overall. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A closer look at the year-by-year data on the Ministry of Education’s website will reveal that from 2013 to 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased each year by between 151 and 676. In 2021, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased by 2,602 compared with 2020, and there were obvious abnormalities in the range of data changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, a note on the official website of the Ministry of Education shows that the statistics of secondary vocational colleges in 2021 and 2022 do not include technical schools managed by the human resources and social security departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that including data from 2021 and 2022, the number of technical schools increased by 69 and 59 respectively. Combined with the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools in the country from 2013 to 2022 compared with the previous year, the data shows that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide decreased by 2,911 in ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the official data released by the education departments and statistics departments of 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country from 2012 to 2022. Whether each province (autonomous region and municipality) plans to collect data The standards for entering technical schools are not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, looking at the overall situation, nationwide, except for the Tibet Autonomous Region, which has a slight increase in the number of secondary vocational colleges (an increase of 7) on the original basis, the remaining provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) are all. downward trend. The number of secondary vocational schools in Anhui Province has decreased the most, with a decrease of 216 in ten years, a decrease of approximately 44%. Henan Province followed, with a decrease of 198. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, the number of universities has decreased by more than 100 in 10 provinces. Except for Heilongjiang, Shandong, Guangdong, and Zhejiang, the rest are all in the central and western regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Qinghai, Ningxia and other places have experienced single-digit declines over the past ten years due to factors such as insufficient construction of secondary vocational schools, and the change is not significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2022, in a clothing production company in Tongren, Guizhou, students majoring in clothing design at the Yuping Dong Autonomous County Secondary Vocational School were processing clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Policy adjustment is the main reason&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Secondary vocational school It once played an important role in China&#39;s economic development. Its number experienced explosive growth in the late 1980s, from 2,760 in 1978 to more than 20,000 in 1990, an increase of nearly eight times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by the end of the 20th century, with the combined effects of multiple factors such as industrial restructuring, tightening of the employment environment, and expansion of college enrollment, the development of secondary vocational education gradually declined because it was difficult to adapt to the needs of the market and employers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Official data shows that since 1999, the number of secondary vocational schools has been declining year by year, with only a slight increase between 2004 and 2008. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, in 2007, the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Further Improving the Enrollment Management of Various Types of Colleges and Universities&quot;, which stipulated that the corresponding enrollment plan for colleges and universities to recruit secondary vocational graduates should not exceed the number of fresh graduates of secondary vocational schools that year. 5% of students. This proportion limit actually clarifies the employment orientation of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools is the adjustment of national policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014 and 2019, the State Council issued the &quot;Decision on Accelerating the Development of Modern Vocational Education&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;) and the &quot;Notice on Issuing the National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; respectively. It is proposed to “encourage high-quality schools to integrate school resources and optimize the layout and structure of secondary vocational education through mergers, trusteeships, cooperative education, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Decision&quot; was promulgated, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission announced the corresponding implementation opinions of Beijing, requiring the number of secondary vocational schools in the city to be adjusted from 116 to about 60, a reduction of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan started optimizing the layout of secondary vocational schools in 2015, and integrated a number of &quot;weak, small and scattered&quot; schools in the form of cancellation, merger, and transfer. Jiangxi also introduced a new policy for secondary vocational education in 2015, proposing to merge more than 200 secondary vocational schools within three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in 2015, Guangxi proposed that &quot;by 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools in the region will be adjusted from the current 333 to about 240.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, nine departments including the Ministry of Education jointly issued the &quot;Action Plan for Improving the Quality of Vocational Education (2020-2023)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Plan&quot;). Based on the original policy It is further proposed to &quot;comprehensively verify the basic conditions for running secondary vocational schools, integrate &#39;empty, small, scattered and weak&#39; schools, and optimize the layout of secondary vocational schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the adjustment of national policies, the difficulties encountered by secondary vocational schools in their own development are also one of the reasons for the reduction in the number of schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, before the state promulgated relevant policies, local governments had already taken measures to reduce the number of secondary vocational schools, which directly pointed to practical problems in the development of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the beginning of the 21st century, in order to meet the needs of Beijing’s urban function adjustment and industrial structure upgrading, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission merged a number of small-scale, low-efficiency schools with unclear professional characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a bad thing. Only by merging schools with poor quality and low enrollment can we improve the quality and attractiveness of secondary vocational colleges.” Vice Chairman of China Development Research Foundation Fang Jin, the secretary-general, once said publicly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The transformation of secondary vocational schools pays more attention to quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The decrease in the number of secondary vocational colleges has a certain relationship with the transformation of secondary vocational education, because the government may China pays more attention to quality rather than quantity.&quot; Xu Hui, a doctoral candidate in sociology at the University of Jena in Germany and a researcher at the Sino-German Research Center for Skills and Social Development, told Southern Weekend reporters that this reduction in quantity may help concentrate resources and improve the quality of education. , to meet today’s ever-changing professional needs. According to Xu Hui’s observation, under the transformation, secondary vocational education has greatly improved in terms of curriculum diversity, technology upgrading, and career guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ensuing increase in attractiveness is also the result of policy changes. One of the key points is the substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PhD candidate Jiang Beijia and scientific research assistant Fan Yilin of the National Education Macro Policy Research Institute of East China Normal University published a paper &quot;Policy Changes in Vocational Education for Higher Education: Context, Logic and &quot;Mirror&quot;, sorted out relevant policy documents and found that since the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot; issued in 2010, it was first proposed to separate the enrollment of higher vocational examinations from the general college entrance examination. The &quot;National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; clearly states for the first time that &quot;the establishment of a vocational education college entrance examination system&quot; will be completely liberated from the previously restricted enrollment rate in secondary vocational schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the main channels for secondary vocational school graduates to obtain undergraduate degrees include consistent training, vocational education college entrance examination, junior college to bachelor&#39;s degree, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smooth flow of channels for further education has led to an increase in the admission rate of secondary vocational schools. Data released by education departments in many places show that the enrollment rate of secondary vocational schools in recent years has generally exceeded 80%. Taking Shenzhen, which has developed secondary vocational education, as an example, the &quot;Shenzhen Secondary Vocational Education Quality Report 2023&quot; shows that in 2022, the number of graduates from Shenzhen&#39;s secondary vocational schools will be 12,485, and the number of students entering higher education will be 11,173, with the enrollment rate reaching 89.49%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Hui also pointed out that a high secondary vocational education promotion rate can provide students with more opportunities, but a careful balance is also needed to ensure that the quality and resources of secondary vocational education are not ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, at a press conference held by the Ministry of Education to introduce the work related to promoting the high-quality development of modern vocational education, Chen Ziji, Director of the Department of Vocational Education and Adult Education of the Ministry of Education, further explained that optimizing the quality of secondary vocational education The layout structure is mainly achieved through measures such as cancellation, merger, transformation, trusteeship, land replacement, and group school running. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in the future, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide may continue to decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>