<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[94岁老人状告保姆：虐待自己还骗走200万养老钱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQyy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQ yy. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258602&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanny Abuse Case&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t even figure out who Defendant 2 is,&quot; faced the judge&#39;s inquiry. Shen Yinan sat in the seat marked &quot;Defendant&#39;s Agent&quot; with a confused look on his face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Defendant 2 is your father,&quot; the lawyer reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned slightly absurd scene occurred at a pre-trial meeting in a gift contract dispute case. On November 7, 2023, the Shanghai Huangpu District People&#39;s Court conducted an evidence exchange in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Yinan’s mother Lu Delin is the plaintiff, the family’s nanny Jiang Aizhen is the defendant 1, and Shen Yinan’s father Shen Zongli is the defendant 2. According to the civil complaint, Shen Zongli once &quot;gifted&quot; 2 million yuan to the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and now Lu Delin is demanding the return. At the same time, Lu Delin sued the nanny Jiang Aizhen for being abused and demanded that the other party pay 200,000 yuan in mental damages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason Shen Yinan was &quot;confused&quot; was that this was not a single case. Civil contract disputes and criminal cases were both in progress. Relevant legal documents show that Lu Delin&#39;s abuse case has been filed as a criminal case at the Huangpu Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, and the criminal case is currently being processed. Shen Yinan has lived abroad for many years and has insufficient understanding of the Chinese environment. His annual visits to relatives in Shanghai have been interrupted for three years since the end of 2019 due to the COVID-19 epidemic. It was also during this period that nanny Jiang Aizhen lived alone to take care of Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, and the dispute between the two parties eventually went to court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin, a 94-year-old man in Shanghai, posted his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by his nanny and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. Since then, the account has posted multiple videos, in which Lu Delin appeared on the scene to talk about his experience: &quot;I just breathed my last breath of life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an exception. On the day the evidence was exchanged, a similar piece of news in Shanghai hit the hot search again. A nanny said that the elderly person she was taking care of wanted to transfer the property to her. &quot;I didn&#39;t take the initiative, it was my uncle who wanted to transfer it to me,&quot; the nanny explained at the processing window in the video. When the staff discovered something was wrong, they suspended the transfer process and called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Municipal Health Commission recently disclosed that as of the end of 2022, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai, accounting for 36.8% of the total registered population. In modern cities with severe aging, how to care for the elderly decently and the issue of home care for the elderly is attracting the attention of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not arrive at the court on the afternoon of the 7th. The judge said that the court would announce the service and expected to summon Jiang Aizhen again in two months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Delin&#39;s bedroom, daughter-in-law Shen Ailun has asked the cleaning staff to clean it again&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;The later life of a 94-year-old couple&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When I opened the closed door in front of me, the first thing I saw was a sour smell. The house should look well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Building 2401, Lane 118, Xietu Road, Liyuan New Village, Huangpu District, Shanghai. The other side of the mess is the great value of the house itself. This community has a total of 4 buildings, all of which are high-rise. It is located in the center of Shanghai and is close to many subway and bus lines, making life convenient. Relevant information shows that this community was built in the early 1990s, and the current price on the second-hand housing market exceeds 100,000 yuan per square meter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The house in front of me belongs to an old couple, Lu Delin and his wife Shen Zongli. They are both 94 years old and have retired for many years. Lu Delin suffered from myelitis and his lower body was paralyzed in bed; Shen Zongli is now blind in one eye, with only 0.25 vision left in one eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The couple’s only son, Shen Yinan, has settled in the United States for decades, and most of his relatives live abroad. Both of them have been to the United States to help their sons take care of their grandchildren, but each visa lasted only half a year at most. After several trips back and forth, the two of them got older and gradually had to stay in this house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this house is vacant. On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin released his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by the nanny Jiang Aizhen and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli have been picked up by their son Shen Yinan and daughter-in-law Shen Ailun and placed in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan Shen opened the door and showed the decorations in the room one by one. She carefully photographed, numbered, and kept these traces of her life. During the investigation stage of the case, many pieces of evidence came from this. On the table in the corner of the living room are piles of bags of fungus, day lilies, mushrooms and other supplements and wild products. There are a dazzling array of more than ten kinds. Shen Ailun, who was standing on one side, said that she had hired cleaning staff to clean the house inside and out. The sour odor that could be smelled now was only a few remnants, and those supplements &quot;were leftovers, and even more were thrown away.&quot; There are many, many have expired, and the nanny won’t make them for the elderly.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This family was originally &quot;stable and decent&quot;. Lu Delin and Shen Zongli&#39;s monthly pensions were more than 10,000 yuan, plus fixed financial interest, they had an additional monthly income of about 8,000 yuan. In addition to the house I live in, I also had another property under my name. After the demolition two years ago, I received a large amount of compensation, and my financial life is safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Son Shen Yinan regularly returns to China to visit relatives every year, &quot;a total of 586 days in 7 years, an average of 84 days per year.&quot; From 2013 to 2019, Shen Ailun sorted out the entry and exit records in these passports one by one. But this connection was broken by the sudden COVID-19 epidemic. After leaving China on November 29, 2019, Shen Yinan failed to come back for more than three years, and did not see her parents again until February 23, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen&#39;s son&#39;s return time record sheet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, two elderly people and the nanny Jiang Aizhen have lived in this house. A neighbor in the same unit told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that in the past few years, his family had contact with Lu Delin&#39;s family, and occasionally made some food to send to her, but later stopped going to her house. Feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The kitchen is on the right hand side of the door, with moldy and hairy cutting boards and jars scattered on the countertop; on the left hand side of the door is the bathroom, a small bathroom of several square meters with white tiles, which has been renovated. Including showers, toilets, etc., the renovation cost tens of thousands of yuan. The bill came from the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and the price of the shower was noted as 4,000 yuan, but &quot;actually it was only 400 yuan.&quot; Shen Allen found out this detail from the property management office - the property management was involved in the installation of the shower. Master Xia, who has worked in property management in this community for many years, confirmed the discrepancy in this amount to a reporter from Southern People Weekly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258601&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bathroom renovated by the nanny. The showerhead in the picture is marked as costing 4,000 yuan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we arrived in the bedroom, the rancid smell became even more obvious. Lu Delin was paralyzed from the lower body and had been urinating and defecating on a chair-shaped toilet in his bedroom. The sheets and quilts had been replaced, and the mattress overflowing with white powder was put away in a box on the side. Shen Allen opened it and showed it to reporters. It was the one that Lu Delin had been using for the past few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father-in-law Shen Zongli’s shirt was also kept. There were large yellow and black stains on the collar. These were “all evidence.” In this unfamiliar space, Shen Ailun carefully collected traces of the past and determined to litigate with the nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Conflicts that have long been buried&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Lu Delin family first came into contact with the nanny Jiang Aizhen in 2013, through the introduction of their upstairs neighbor Wang Wei. At that time, Jiang Aizhen Work part-time in the area. By 2017, Jiang Aizhen became a long-term, fixed hourly employee of the Lu Delin family. Wang Wei said it was because &quot;Little Jiang did a good job&quot;, and Shen Ailun said it was because Jiang Aizhen was frustrated in finding a job and complained to Lu Delin and his wife that she got the job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting along for a long time, during the three years when the new coronavirus epidemic was raging, Lu Delin and his wife were cared for at home by Jiang Aizhen, with no one else to look after them. It wasn&#39;t until Lu Delin released a video, claiming that he was abused by the nanny and defrauded of his pension, that the conflict broke out in the public eye. For a long time before this, the conflict between the family and the nanny had already been laid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258603&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedding used by Teacher Lu Delin in the past few years has a strong musty smell&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, Jiang Aizhen worked part-time for two hours at home every day, and the couple paid 6,000 yuan a month. In March 2022, Jiang Aizhen moved into this house and changed from a part-time worker to a live-in nanny, and her salary increased to 12,000 yuan per month. Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that while Jiang Aizhen was receiving this salary, she was also working part-time in four other places at the same time. At this point, she felt that the nanny did not have the spirit of contract. &quot;Having paid all the salary of the live-in nanny, how can she still go to work other jobs outside?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; visited to find out more Currently, in Huangpu District, Shanghai, where Lu Delin is located, the hourly salary for hourly workers is about 45 yuan, which rises to about 50 yuan during the evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the Sangcheng Neighborhood Committee to which the community belongs told Southern People Weekly that whether the price is for an hourly or full-time live-in nanny depends on how the employer and the nanny negotiate. Judging from the neighborhood committee&#39;s registration, as long as she spends the night at her employer&#39;s house, she is considered a live-in nanny. Jiang Aizhen has indeed been registered as a live-in nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei, an introducer who also employs part-time workers for a long time, does not think that 12,000 yuan is a &quot;buyout&quot; price. For two elderly people who cannot take care of themselves, more money will definitely be needed. It is normal for the nanny to work other jobs. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter of &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; consulted three local housekeeping agencies based on the current situation of Lu Delin and his wife. They all said that the price of 12,000 yuan is the price of a full-time live-in nanny, which is a &quot;buyout price&quot; and the aunt should not Go do other work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the housekeeping agencies was established in 2014 and is headquartered in Guangzhou. It has branches in Shanghai and Shenzhen. It provides customers with full-time live-in nannies through an employee system. Each aunt has undergone background checks. Their daily life is monitored by the company using a housekeeper model. This company will conduct regular follow-up visits through its stewards, and it is one of the similar institutions that attaches great importance to supervision. Even so, the quality of Auntie still relies on proactive feedback from customers. When family members are not around all year round, the elderly are forced to rely on a single nanny. &quot;This kind of feedback is relatively difficult and can be said to be blank.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258600&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daily use in the kitchen of Lu Delin and his wife The cutting board&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides money, there is incalculable &quot;love&quot;. During the COVID-19 epidemic, the two elderly people were cared for by Jiang Aizhen alone. They were pushed up and down in line to get nucleic acid tests, which was seen by the neighborhood committee. Whether the care is good or not, and whether there is abuse or not, are &quot;matters behind closed doors.&quot; The neighborhood committee and some neighbors use this as an excuse to express their ignorance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Shen Yinan and his wife returned to China, Jiang Aizhen repeatedly claimed that she had &quot;saved the old man&#39;s life&quot; and produced a &quot;certificate&quot; and a &quot;power of attorney&quot; handwritten and signed by Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A power of attorney signed on September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another &quot;certificate&quot; on the same day, Shen Zongli stated that he gave Jiang Aizhen &quot;one million yuan&quot;; in a &quot;certificate&quot; on March 3, 2023, , the amount given to Jiang Aizhen rose to &quot;two million yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not just a paper promise, on August 22, 2022 and February 7, 2023, Shen Zongli’s personal account transferred 1 million yuan to Jiang Aizhen’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three pieces of paper, corresponding to 2 million yuan and the right to live in the house, were given to the nanny Jiang Aizhen. Whether the old man was conscious and voluntary, and whether the gift was legal and valid, the question was ultimately handed over to the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for evidence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who was present at the time?&quot; The judge asked many times to confirm this key question, pointing to the latest gift contract-2023 On March 3, 2019, Shen Zongli handwritten a &quot;certificate&quot; of 2 million yuan to his nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not appear in court. Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun told the judge what happened: Jiang Aizhen took out a certificate signed by Lu Delin, Shen Zongli, and Shen Yinan, and asked Lu Delin and Shen Yinan to sign in the corresponding places, but they refused. At that time, Shen Ailun was present and stopped him. At that time, thinking that the matter was settled, Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun left home to go out on business. When they returned to Shanghai, they learned that the &quot;proof&quot; had actually been written long ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The certificate that was suppressed was signed on March 9, 2023. In fact, as early as a week ago, on March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen obtained the &quot;certificate&quot; signed by Shen Zongli. Shen Ailun discovered that Shen Zongli&#39;s Alipay had been registered, and found someone to use technical means to recover the data on the old man&#39;s mobile phone. He found a video recorded by Jiang Aizhen, which was proof that Shen Zongli had handwritten a gift of 2 million to the nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The power of attorney dated September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recording provided by Lu Delin&#39;s attorney Zhou Zhaocheng showed that a duty lawyer of the neighborhood committee said that Jiang Aizhen had repeatedly pushed Shen Zongli in a wheelchair to the neighborhood committee&#39;s duty lawyer&#39;s office for consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen received the certificate signed by Shen Zongli’s handwriting. In order to ensure that the donation of &quot;2 million yuan&quot; was legal and valid, a week later, she took out a certificate again and added &quot;Lu Delin and Shen Yinan&quot; in addition to Shen Zongli. This certificate was the only one that Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun had ever seen in person. Proof of “donation”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the previous three certificates of donating 1 million yuan, donating 2 million yuan, and letting the nanny live in the house, Shen Yinan saw the nanny Fang issued them online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258599&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 3, 2023, Shen Zongli handwritten a &quot;proof&quot; of 2 million yuan to the nanny Jiang Aizhen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli is the person in control of the family&#39;s &quot;account&quot;. The certificates were all handwritten by him. Shen Ailun said that the nanny treated Shen Zongli and Lu Delin differently. &quot;She knew which one should be coaxed, and used this brainwashing method to defraud the old man of his money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, the family trusted the nanny. The first time I realized something was wrong was when Shen Ailun mailed food to his parents-in-law. When he was talking on the phone, he discovered that his parents-in-law had not received it and did not know about it. Shen Ailun had previously sent a message to the old man&#39;s mobile phone about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The nanny will delete the chat history,&quot; this answer was found by Allen Shen after installing the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, about three years after being separated due to the new crown epidemic, Shen Allen stepped into the door of 2401 again. Her mother-in-law Lu Delin asked her to look at her feet and said they felt bumpy. Shen Ailun found that her toenails were &quot;cut&quot; and she realized something was wrong. Shen Ailun went to check the accounts and found that 2 million yuan in his parents-in-law&#39;s account had been transferred to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the wheelchair to the wall, Shen Allen secretly installed 7 miniature cameras to &quot;monitor&quot; the nanny. The couple pretended to return to the United States and wanted to see if the nanny was taking good care of the elderly while he was away. . Her husband told her that this was to collect evidence, and she must hold back her temper. No matter what she saw, the primary purpose was to preserve evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the next day, Shen Ailun still quarreled with Jiang Aizhen. She recalled that Jiang Aizhen had a habit of speaking, which was a bit like a teacher lecturing a child. He kept saying &quot;What&#39;s wrong with you, what&#39;s wrong with you&quot;, &quot;It made my head buzz.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Conflicts quickly broke out. One day at noon, her mother-in-law Lu Delin said she wanted to eat crabs and asked Shen Ailun to cook them. Shen Ailun asked her aunt (referring to Jiang Aizhen) to make them. Jiang Aizhen said she didn&#39;t eat crabs and couldn&#39;t cook them. &quot;I wanted to scold her at that time, but I held it back,&quot; Shen Allen continued to recall. &quot;The nanny asked my mother-in-law how to do it. My mother-in-law asked her to ask me. She was very normal when she asked me, and then I said, what did you just do? Didn&#39;t you ask my mother? Just do it as my mother said.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Patience seemed to disappear suddenly. Jiang Aizhen suddenly became unhappy, and the volume suddenly became louder, &quot;Your mother asked me to Ask you, you asked me to ask your mother, I really don’t understand you.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as these words came out, Shen Ailun couldn’t hold back his anger, “I really grew up from the eighteenth generation of my ancestors. She started scolding her, and I said don’t talk to me like that. One day I make you cry, so get out of here.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Jiang Aizhen didn’t know about the installation of cameras in her home, but Shen Ailun had already She saw the nanny&#39;s usual behavior through the video, which she found difficult to accept. &quot;She took all her anger out on my mother-in-law, and her voice broke with curses.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching some of the footage captured by the camera, , the night he slept at his in-laws&#39; house, Shen Ailun was afraid that Jiang Aizhen would do something extreme with a knife from the kitchen, so he took away all the large and small knives in the kitchen, put them in the room, locked the door, and took one of them away. The knife was placed under the pillow in case of emergency. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two statements about &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Jiang Aizhen&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The backside of abuse, money fraud, and extreme behavior , is another way of saying &quot;introducer&quot; Wang Wei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei also heard about the 2 million yuan donation, and she also saw the &quot;abuse&quot; scenes circulated on the Internet. But she always thinks that the nanny is doing a good job:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“One of the videos I saw online is that the action is relatively rough. In fact, this is how to pull an old man out of bed. There used to be an old man in my house, and Xiao Jiang also pulled him up like this. Jiang is also almost 60 years old. He is only a part-time worker and has no professional training in nursing, so he can only do this. We are used to it, and it is the same behavior in our family. The aunt is fierce, and her mouth is a bit rude. This is her temperament and character.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is also bleeding when the toenails are cut. The onychomycosis is bound to bleed when the onychomycosis is cut. The moldy bedding must have nothing to do with Xiao Jiang. This is Teacher Lu. The personal habits of the old couple. Their family’s habit is that everything that comes into their home is no garbage, everything is treasure, nothing is thrown away, and the used toilet paper must be dried and used...&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The people who hired Xiao Jiang in this building were all introduced by Wang Wei. She said that the only ones who had problems were Lu Delin&#39;s family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen is a part-time worker introduced by the security guard earlier, and has been working at Wang Wei&#39;s house since 2012. &quot;Before my daughter-in-law returned to Shanghai this time, Teacher Lu&#39;s family had a good relationship with the nanny. They said that the nanny was their goddaughter. Fortunately, they had a nanny, otherwise they would have died. When the daughter-in-law came back, everything was reversed. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that the 2 million yuan was given to Jiang Aizhen in two installments, both for a reason: the first time was due to the epidemic lockdown. I did nucleic acid tests almost every day, and the nanny was the one who pushed her up and down every day. Another time, Mr. Shen’s house was demolished. He said that he, as an old man, could not negotiate, and it was all his fault. I entrusted this nanny to do it, and it seemed that I got some money in the end. Mr. Shen said, &quot;If his aunt hadn&#39;t helped him, he wouldn&#39;t have gotten so much.&quot; In the end, he had to ask Xiao Jiang to support him until his death. We were in the midst of an epidemic lockdown at the time, and we didn’t know when our son would come back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But these two things are different situations in Shen Ailun&#39;s eyes. In terms of physical care, Shen Ailun said that in May 2020, an old man was hospitalized with pneumonia and Jiang Aizhen took care of him, but paid the nanny an extra salary of 300 yuan a day. This was a contract, not &quot;favour or help&quot;; in terms of house demolition, The nanny did not do a good job, and the demolition money was much less than what she deserved...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, who are cared for by Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun, both asked Jiang Aizhen to pay back the money in the video. Before being picked up, when the old man and the nanny were living together, &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; obtained an audio recording, which was a conversation between the nanny Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli about money on March 22, 2023:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nanny: &quot;All the money is transferred away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;I want to keep the money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanny: &quot;The money you keep is not the same as leaving it with me. &quot;?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;Both.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanny: &quot;I want it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;You are bullying me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The helplessness of the &quot;nanny butler&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Is it voluntary to give money to the nanny? Shen Zongli’s answers were inconsistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first he said it was a voluntary gift, but he changed his story later when he saw the flow, audio and video of the nanny withdrawing the money. Relevant audio and video recordings show that the nanny personally admitted that she had withdrawn an extra 70,000 yuan from the elderly person’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that Shen Zongli claimed to have been told by the nanny many times that his own money was the same in the nanny&#39;s account and could be withdrawn at any time if needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years since the COVID-19 epidemic, Shen Ailun has only returned to China once. At that time, he was going to visit his parents-in-law, but he received a note from her mother-in-law at the quarantine hotel, which said &quot;Don&#39;t go back.&quot; Considering the fear of infection at the time, Shen Allen did not return to 2401. Afterwards, Lu Delin told Shen Ailun that the note was written by the nanny and was &quot;forced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, &quot;nanny butler&quot; has become the theme of 2401, and even the &quot;outsiders&quot; who deal with it have noticed it. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Master Xia from the property management company told Southern People Weekly that the two old people could not take care of themselves and had to be accompanied by a nanny when they went downstairs. The nanny was always by their side, so even if the old people wanted to say something, they could not say it. Usually the two old people are at home with no relatives to take care of them. Only Lu Delin&#39;s students come occasionally, but &quot;after all, they are not family members, so they can&#39;t say much. Their family is a decent person who wants to save face and is hard to talk to.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a chain of pedicure shops nearby that nannies Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli go to regularly. The clerk called Shen Zongli &quot;White Rabbit&quot; because he loved to eat White Rabbit toffee and would sometimes eat several pieces at a time. Allen Shen opened the mobile shopping APP and found multiple purchases of White Rabbit toffees, all of which were mailed to 2401. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The store clerk calls their family&#39;s situation &quot;nanny butler&quot;: the nanny comes with a white rabbit, the white rabbit gets a pedicure, and the nanny also gets a pedicure. They do the same project, and the nanny pays the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Such nannies are rare,” the clerk recalled the nanny Jiang Aizhen’s behavior. On the one hand, she felt that she was fierce and powerful, and on the other hand, the nanny always brought the old man with her. Other families are often accompanied by their children and family members. On the day of the reporter&#39;s interview, this pedicure shop received a 103-year-old man, who was accompanied by his niece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a wonton shop a few hundred meters away from the community. Jiang Aizhen sometimes takes Lu Delin and his wife to eat there. After returning to China this time, the owner of the wonton shop once privately told Shen Ailun, &quot;Quickly fire your nanny.&quot; The reporter asked the boss to find out and confirmed this, &quot;I have never seen other nannies speak so fiercely.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There are many elderly people like Lu Delin and his wife in this community. A staff member of the Sangcheng Neighborhood Committee told Southern People Weekly that it is common for family members to visit from time to time, but it is rare for a nanny to be taken care of by herself. Previously, the neighborhood committee tried to mediate after hearing the news, but the nanny did not come. &quot;The nanny never showed up. Our neighborhood committee cannot represent any level of government or relevant departments, and cannot force the nanny to be present. We can&#39;t do it. We don&#39;t have that Power. Also, when the nanny is absent or not present, we also recommend that they take judicial channels and report the case to the court or the police.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member who has worked in the neighborhood committee for many years told &quot; According to Southern People Weekly, I have met the nanny Jiang Aizhen on a regular basis, and during the face-to-face contact, I did not feel anything related to &quot;abuse&quot;. But many things are done behind closed doors, and no one will do anything excessive in public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This will not be an exception. Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to data released by the 2022 Shanghai Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million elderly people aged 60 and above registered in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for 36.8% of the total registered population, of which 300,600 were elderly people living alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether she was abused or deceived, she was a &quot;nanny and housekeeper&quot; for three years. It wasn&#39;t until the conflict broke out and it became a hot search topic that many neighbors saw the news on their mobile phones. Some neighbors had previously seen the news about the daughter-in-law accusing the nanny Jiang Aizhen in the owner group, but many more neighbors knew nothing about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters Shen Yinan, Shen Ailun, and Wang Wei in the article are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“清朗·网络戾气整治”专项行动启动，打击网络厕所、开盒挂人等行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of all provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, and the Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps: &lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In accordance with the overall arrangement of the 2023 &quot;Qinglang&quot; series of special operations, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China has decided to launch a one-month &quot;Qinglang·Internet Violence Rectification&quot; nationwide from now on. Special action. The relevant matters are now notified as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. Clear work goals&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Focus on cyber violence We will focus on key sections where anger easily breeds, strictly crack down on prominent issues such as malicious attacks and insults, provoking group confrontations, and venting extreme emotions, and resolutely punish a number of illegal accounts, groups, and website platforms to effectively curb the spread of online violence. By carrying out special rectification, we will further consolidate the main responsibilities of the website platform, thoroughly identify problems and loopholes, improve the system and mechanism to prevent and control online violence, effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of the majority of netizens, and maintain a good online ecology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Focus on rectifying 7 types of outstanding problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The special actions focus on key platform types such as social networking, short videos, and live broadcasts, and resolutely crack down on the following seven aspects of problems:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1. &quot;Internet toilets&quot; and &quot;open boxes to hang people&quot; &quot;Behavior. Create special BOT accounts, post bars, topics, groups, etc., and receive and publish ridicule, malicious comments, curses and insults directed at specific groups or individuals through anonymous contributions, remote shouting, etc. In the name of exposure and criticism, they maliciously &quot;open the box&quot; and &quot;hang people&quot;, publicizing other people&#39;s names, ID numbers, mobile phone numbers, home addresses, workplaces, personal photos, social accounts and other personal privacy information, inciting netizens to attack and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Use hot social events to maliciously slander and spread rumors. Spread rumors and slander relevant parties involved in emergencies, or edit and process pictures and videos that are seriously inconsistent with the facts, to induce netizens to attack and question the parties involved. Use the image of the parties involved in hot events to create and publish emoticons, and use AI software to synthesize fake pictures or videos such as vulgar pornography, bloody horror, etc., to carry out rumors, attacks, and slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Stigmatize specific groups and incite regional confrontation. Associate individual vicious social events and negative figures with gender, occupation, region and other characteristics, stigmatize and negatively label specific groups, publish gender-antagonistic, class-antagonistic, and regionally discriminatory remarks, carry out generalized attacks, and intensify social conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Vulgar and bad live streaming behaviors such as fierce PK. Online anchors use behaviors such as showing off their courage, fighting, drinking, and swearing to increase their followers and traffic. During other people&#39;s live broadcasts, they use functions such as barrages and mics to conduct personal attacks, and even encourage extreme behaviors such as suicide and self-harm. Make up scripts of violent conflicts such as fights and fights to attract netizens to watch and disrupt public order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. Organized and malicious abuse and reporting of others. In the name of &quot;helping with work&quot; and &quot;relieving worries and anger&quot;, they provide paid scolding services and leave abusive messages and private message attacks on specific accounts. Organize fan groups to use the platform’s “reporting” and “anti-gangster” functions to maliciously report others in batches. Publish comments that provoke war and malicious hype in the fields of entertainment, sports, e-sports, etc., inducing fans to quarrel with each other and control reviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Make up Internet slang and maliciously create rumors. Through pinyin, homophony, pronouns, etc., maliciously fabricate vulgar memes and bad buzzwords to pollute the Internet atmosphere. Use obscene language and foul language to deliberately provoke conflicts and create conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7. Inciting extreme emotions online. Make up sensational post titles and publish &quot;venting posts&quot; that are made out of nothing and have no bottom line. Maliciously exaggerating the conflicts between teachers and students, exaggerating parents&#39; &quot;oppression&quot; and &quot;squeezing&quot; of their children, provoking conflicting relationships, and forming a negative direction for minors. Deliberately exaggerate negativity, anxiety and resentment, and spread hateful and antagonistic remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Severely punish illegal accounts, groups and platforms in accordance with the law&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Special During the operation, we must persist in striking hard, close a group of account groups that seriously violate regulations and have a bad influence, resolutely ban a group of functional sections that gather violence and have outstanding problems, and strictly investigate and punish a group of people who fail to perform their responsibilities and have serious problems. The website platform that resists the temptation to commit crimes forms a powerful deterrent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Strictly investigate and punish illegal accounts, groups, and post bars. In-depth investigation of high-risk accounts and groups, resolutely ban accounts and groups with themes such as &quot;online toilets&quot;, &quot;opening boxes to hang people&quot;, &quot;inciting fights&quot;, etc., and seriously investigate and deal with anchor accounts that organize ruthless PKs and live broadcast fights , severely punish &quot;self-media&quot; accounts that publish &quot;clickbait&quot; content that deliberately incites online violence, close a group of circles, super chats, and post bars named with insulting words and where online violence gathers, and remove them from the shelves and provide paid compensation. Scolding merchants and shops waiting for services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Strictly investigate and deal with illegal function settings. Strengthen the management of key functions such as live broadcast barrage, continuous wheat, and PK, and resolutely clean up and deal with violent content online. Centrally cancel a batch of functional applications that organize malicious reports in batches. It is prohibited to push &quot;online toilet&quot; accounts to users through functions such as &quot;Related Recommendations&quot;, &quot;TA Follows&quot;, and &quot;Potentially Interested People&quot;. Strengthen the review and management of emoticon packages, P-picture puzzles, video editing, AI synthesis and other functions, and clean up and remove emoticon packages, pictures and videos containing prank attacks, provoking confrontation and other content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Strictly investigate and punish illegal platform links. Urge &lt;span>; website platforms to strengthen the management of lists, topics, recommendations, comments, private messages, etc. It is strictly forbidden to push content that incites and promotes online violence in lists, recommendations, etc., by setting up &quot;private message folding&quot; and &quot;message boxes&quot; etc. to reduce harassment from strangers via private messages. For websites, apps, and mini-programs with outstanding problems, punitive measures such as rectification within a time limit, fines, suspension of relevant functions, and shutdown will be taken in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;4. Detailed work requirements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/ span>;1. Do a good job in deployment and promotion.结合本地实际，制定细化实施方案，配齐配强工作力量，狠抓任务部署落实，视情组织对网站平台治理效果进行评估，督促做好整改落实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.压实平台责任。指导属地网站平台全面排查问题漏洞，聚焦重点环节、版块和功能，深入开展自查自纠，完善内容管理机制，确保专项行动取得实效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.强化宣传曝光。公布&lt;span>;专项行动启动、阶段性进展，重点平台每周公布典型案例。加强教育引导，鼓励网民积极参与举报投诉，共同抵制网络戾气。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;中央网信办秘书局&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年11月10日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马云继续减持，阿里巴巴刺向低价]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 15:30:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;阿里巴巴西溪园区。图片来源：阿里官网&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;阿里巴巴西溪园区。图片来源：阿里官网&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月16日，是阿里巴巴2024财年新季度业绩公布的日子，这一天，同步释出了这家巨头企业的诸多重要消息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马云继续减持阿里巴巴创始人股份；此前“1+6+N”分拆计划，部分按下暂停键，阿里云不再完全分拆；盒马上市同时暂停。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴面临着怎样的变局？此后的战略指挥棒将挥向何处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;马云减持套现8.7亿美元&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月16日，阿里巴巴（BABA.NYSE）向美国证券交易委员会（SEC）提交了两份144表格，表示马云家族信托旗下公司JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited拟于11月21日分别出售500万股阿里巴巴创始人股份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照美东时间11月15日阿里巴巴87.07美元/股的收盘价计算，马云家族可通过此次减持套现8.707亿美元。阿里巴巴当日市值约为2217.5亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;144表格，亦被称作“拟议出售证券通知书”。 SEC规定，若美国上市公司的董事、高管或大股东等在任意三个月内转让超过5000股或市值超过5万美元的上市公司股票，则必须填写144表格并向SEC申报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据阿里巴巴的美股招股书，在IPO之前，马云通过四种方式共持有阿里巴巴8.8%股份。其&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本人直接持有0.08%，通过注册在开曼群岛的APN Ltd公司和新加坡非营利机构SymAsia基金会各持有1.49%，及通过注册在英属维尔京群岛的JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited公司分别持有2.78%和2.95%的股份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马云在美股IPO中出售的股份同样来自JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited两家公司，其在IPO后对阿里巴巴的持股降至7.8%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴2014年在纽交所上市以来，马云进行过多次减持。财报显示，马云的大规模减持始于2017年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，马云持股从7.8%降到7%，2018年降到6.4%，2019年降至6.2%，2020年降至4.8%，低于5%的披露红线。此后，阿里巴巴不在财报中披露马云的持股情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴曾回应，马云和蔡崇信会捐出他们所拥有的、总体规模为阿里巴巴集团总股本2%的阿里期权，用以支持环境保护、医疗健康、教育发展和公益生态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年教师节，马云卸任阿里巴巴董事局主席。一年后，马云完成了其董事任期，不再是阿里巴巴董事会成员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年财报显示，马云仍是阿里巴巴合伙人委员会成员之一，其他五名为蔡崇信、张勇、彭蕾、邵晓锋及吴泳铭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴实行合伙人制度，由合伙人提名董事会的大多数董事人选，而非根据股份的多少分配董事席位。阿里巴巴现有28位合伙人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重注1688、闲鱼、钉钉、夸克&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;同在11月16日，阿里巴巴2024财年Q2业绩公布。阿里巴巴财年与自然年不同步，为每年的4月1日至次年3月31日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本季度，阿里巴巴营收2247.9亿元人民币，同比增长9%。净利润为266.96亿元，2022年同期则为净亏损224.67亿元，非公认会计准则净利润为401.88亿元，同比增长19%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“阿里巴巴集团本季度业绩稳健，多个业务展现出全新动能和活力，主动自我变革成效显著。”阿里巴巴集团首席执行官吴泳铭在业绩公告中表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本地生活集团收入同比增长16%至155.64亿元，由饿了么和高德业务的强劲增长带动，订单同比增长近20%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;菜鸟的收入同比增长25%至228.23亿元，主要由跨境物流履约解决方案带动。菜鸟在本季度面向8个国家和地区推出了全球5日达物流服务，包括头程揽收、干线运输、通关、分拣和最后一公里配送。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里大文娱在上季度终于扭亏为盈之后，赢面进一步扩大。大文娱集团本季度收入为57.79亿元，同比增长11%，主要归功于大麦网和阿里影业的线下娱乐业务，及优酷的订阅增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月19日，阿里影业宣布收购大麦网。受惠于2023年暑假线下娱乐市场的复苏和强劲需求，大麦网本季度GMV录得三位数同比增长。 8月，大麦网携手优酷，为TFBOYS十周年演唱会的线下演出及线上直播合作售票。这场独家线上直播打破了优酷的线上付费演出纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而阿里影业联合出品的两部电影《孤注一掷》和《消失的她》位居暑期档票房前两位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月16日晚间，吴泳铭首次作为阿里巴巴集团CEO参加季度财报分析师电话会，他在会上介绍了阿里巴巴第一批战略级创新业务——1688、闲鱼、钉钉、夸克。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭表示，阿里巴巴对战略级创新业务的遴选标准为：具备足够巨大的市场空间；具备独特的市场定位；符合用户需求趋势和集团“AI驱动”战略。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战略级创新业务在组织上将以独立子公司的方式运营，业务上将打破以往在集团内的定位限制，用更独立的策略去面对广阔的市场。阿里巴巴集团将以3-5年为周期进行持续投入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夸克是阿里巴巴旗下的智能搜索App，钉钉是企业级智能移动办公平台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿里擅长的网络交易领域，1688是采购批发网，经常会与拼多多放在一起对比谁更便宜，闲鱼则是二手闲置转让平台，提高这两者在集团内的重要性，显示出阿里巴巴指挥棒向低价市场的倾斜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;阿里云分拆、盒马上市都要暂停&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴Q2财报还公布了各业务板块的分拆进展。令人惊讶的是，阿里云的分拆被按下暂停键。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5月18日，时任阿里巴巴集团董事会主席兼CEO、阿里云智能集团董事长兼CEO张勇宣布，阿里云智能集团将于未来12个月内从阿里集团完全分拆并完成上市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴在本次财报解释，美国近期扩大对先进计算芯片出口的限制，给云智能集团的前景带来不确定性。其完全分拆可能无法按照原先设想提升股东价值，因此决定不再推进其完全分拆，而是会面对不确定的环境，专注建立云智能集团可持续增长的模型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭表示，阿里巴巴集团将在阿里云战略方向上保持长期坚决的投入，同时云智能集团仍会继续保持独立公司运作方式，采取董事会授权的CEO负责制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月，彭博新闻社称盒马正在与中金、摩根士丹利等合作筹备上市事宜，准备来年在香港上市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但本次财报显示，盒马的首次公开募股计划暂缓。阿里并未解释原因。但这或许与盒马并不突出的表现有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本季度，阿里巴巴所有其他分部收入为48.052亿元，相较2022年同期维持平稳。所有其他分部包括高鑫零售、盒马、阿里健康、灵犀互娱、银泰、智能信息(主要包括UC优视和夸克业务)、飞猪、钉钉等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其他分部里，盒马、飞猪、阿里健康和智能信息的收入有所增长，但总体业绩也只是与去年持平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与盒马形成鲜明对比的是，菜鸟集团已申请在香港进行首次公开募股，并已向香港联交所递交了A1文件（上市申请表格）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭在电话会上称，菜鸟未来三年的核心策略，一是加快全球智能物流网络建设，抓住跨境电商快速发展的历史机遇，实现国际业务的快速增长，二是在国内坚持走差异化道路，输出科技能力，保持业务的健康发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：严厉打击倒买倒卖、伪造出生医学证明等违法犯罪行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:40:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国家卫生健康委高度重视出生医学证明管理工作，正在挂牌督办有关地方严肃核查处理贩卖出生医学证明等相关问题，已向湖北襄阳、广东佛山、广西南宁等地派出督导组，督促指导地方深挖彻查、回应社会关切、追究相关责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《出生医学证明》是依据《中华人民共和国母婴保健法》相关规定制发的法定医学证明文件，是公安机关开展新生儿户口登记的重要依据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家卫生健康委对于损害儿童权益、伤害群众利益、扰乱正常医疗秩序，特别是伪造出生医学证明的行为，将严厉打击、绝不姑息,发现一起，查处一起，积极配合公安机关打击倒买倒卖出生医学证明等犯罪行为，对涉案医务人员依法依规严肃处理。欢迎向当地卫生健康行政部门举报相关线索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，国家卫生健康委将指导医疗机构进一步健全完善内部管理机制和流程，并在全国开展出生医学证明规范管理专项检查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究发现鲨鱼可以跟人类一样品尝出苦味]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new study recently published in the US magazine &quot;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&quot; stated that sharks and other cartilaginous fish have the same Genes that detect bitter tastes like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258594&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows a photo of a shark provided by the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo courtesy of the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity/Photo by Andrew Fox)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many animals and plants secrete toxic compounds as a defense, a chemical that enables humans to perceive their taste The bitter taste receptor type 2 (T2R) gene helps humans recognize these compounds and avoid poisoning. Many bony vertebrates also have this bitter taste receptor gene, but researchers have never found it in cartilaginous vertebrates before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this study, researchers from the University of Cologne in Germany and other institutions used the latest gene sequencing technology to sequence the genes of 17 species of cartilaginous fish (including sharks and rays) and found that 12 species of cartilaginous fish All carry a taste receptor gene similar to T2R, which they named T2R1. The researchers then implanted the T2R1 genes from two of the shark species into human kidney cells in the laboratory, and then exposed them to 94 bitter substances that humans can perceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results showed that 7 bitter substances activated the bitter taste receptors of two species of sharks, and the other 4 substances only activated the bitter taste receptors of one shark, which means that these sharks can also taste human food. Perceived bitter substances such as colchicine or bile acids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discovery suggests the ability to perceive bitter tastes may be older than previously thought, possibly before cartilaginous fishes and bony vertebrates diverged from a common ancestor nearly 500 million years ago, the researchers said. has evolved. Teleost vertebrates continue to evolve a variety of bitter taste receptor genes. Although the researchers detected only one T2R1 gene in these cartilaginous fish genomes, this means it may be the original form of the bitter taste receptor gene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[台湾观众可能没有我们这么了解侯孝贤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeK nCcAnsCEY3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to A Little Culture. I am Yu Yaqin, the anchor of this issue. Recently, the famous director Hou Hsiao-hsien has to bid farewell to the film industry due to health reasons. For this reason, today I invited Teacher Wang Yinjie from the China Academy of Art and my colleague Teacher Li Heng to talk about this great fan of Chinese films. A very important film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excerpts of golden verses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He lives in southern Taiwan, which is very different from Taipei in our impression. It has more rural character. This rural character is also the way Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some actors have said that he doesn’t even have a script. He is not a person who particularly likes to coordinate actors. A director who is very standard in the film industry, very sophisticated and precise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He provides a very valuable preservation of personal experience and personal memory for the narration of film history. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1700&quot; height=&quot;1132&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #993300;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Yaqin, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Heng, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yinjie, Associate Professor, School of Film, China Academy of Art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #993300;&quot;>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:58 Director Hou Hsiao-hsien’s life and works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:17 Countryside is Hou Hsiao-hsien’s way of looking at the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 05:22&amp;nbsp;《 &quot;Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; established many of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s aesthetic styles&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:23&amp;nbsp;After 2000, Hou Hsiao-hsien moved towards more international cooperation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:08&amp;nbsp;Jia Zhangke is I came into contact with Hou Hsiao-hsien from &quot;City of Sadness&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 14:33 Hou Hsiao-hsien is not a standardized director in the film industry&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 17:52 Hou Hsiao-hsien has always been photographing individuals with a faint light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 19:57 Taiwanese audiences may not know Hou Hsiao-hsien as well as we do&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:14&amp;nbsp;Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films have many long shots and do not pursue a lot of drama&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;► 26:19 The emotions of the characters in Hou’s films are like hearing thunder in silence&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 32:47 Hou Hsiao-hsien holds a very important position in the hearts of a generation of movie fans&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37: 15 A kind of misalignment: The life needs of young people in Taiwan do not come from directors such as Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 41:11 We need to trust the interpretation of the world by creators of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s generation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 43:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at everyone around him in a level-headed manner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 45:06 The use of dialect is a characteristic of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 47:05 Recommended by Wang Yinjie Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Sad City&quot; and &quot;Flowers of Shanghai&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:49 Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Love in the Wind&quot; and &quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;► 55:53 Three movies recommended by Li Heng: &quot;Once Upon a Time in Childhood&quot;, &quot;Goodbye South Country, South Country&quot; and &quot;Dream Life&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 58:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s masterpiece is so dazzling that it... The light of urban youth-themed works overshadowed&lt;br>;► 01:01:52 Director Hou’s films strive for a certain authenticity of the atmosphere of that era&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:06:30 When there are many things that cannot be said Whenever possible, we use literature as a metaphor and movies to present it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:08:25 Hou Hsiao-hsien provides a way to retain personal experience and memory in telling film history&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:11 :14 Use Southern aesthetics to summarize Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:16:09 Hou Hsiao-hsien influenced young directors from Taiwan, mainland China’s sixth-generation directors, Hirokazu Kore-eda, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Audio Clip/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999;&quot;>;Operation Promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这部罪案片，悬疑为壳，人性为核]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The dramatization of crime films often has two levels . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first level is to explore the truth of the murder. Under the sensory stimulation of extreme violence, the protagonist takes the audience&#39;s perspective to reveal the truth bit by bit. The plot has twists and turns and even reversals, providing plot excitement. The other layer is to explore the theme of human nature. The protagonist often has some kind of commonality with the victim and murderer of the case. The story of the detective story is also the protagonist&#39;s growth of exploring himself and &quot;finding himself&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the case was finally solved, the protagonist found the truth of the case and the answer to the confusion in life. They point to an ending in the interweaving, and the audience sees two stories and gets a double plot impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those character arcs in drama theory are actually not complicated. Excellent stories not only reveal the truth about the character&#39;s personality, but more importantly, tell the arc or change of the character&#39;s inner nature during the course of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing this, it is easy to understand the director&#39;s intention. In crime films, these two layers are often intertwined, but with different emphasis. For example, &quot;The Mistake on the River&quot; currently in theaters focuses on the latter layer. The director was afraid of being misunderstood, so he directly wrote &quot;No Answer&quot; on the poster. It just reminds the audience that the main purpose of this movie is to explore the human nature related to the case. The investigation itself is not important. There is no need to worry about who the murderer is. There is no answer at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the new film &quot;Pursuit&quot; directed by Zeng Yingting and starring Junning Chang and Ethan Ruan is not so literary and extreme. Although this movie has some fresh topics, it does not challenge the audience&#39;s entertainment interests too much and is a very regular crime film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1531&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female worker accident He died tragically and was involved in a series of female murders. Finger-cutting, heart-breaking, imprisonment...bizarre cases, cruel murderers, and sensory-stimulating gimmicks are all cut into the trailer. Seasoned genre film viewers are very familiar with this method of publicity, and of course they know that a gimmick is just a gimmick, and its scale will only be safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that &quot;The Hunt&quot; is a movie dominated by female characters, and you can even consider it a female movie (although it is very genre). In the crime genre, very few women lead the investigation. We might as well try to recall the positioning of female characters in crime films. They are often victims or perpetrators (which appears as a reversal card at this time). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this crime movie, the protagonist is the detective Wu Jie played by Junning Chang. She is the leader and the soul of the drama. If you put aside your female identity, Zhang Junning&#39;s role is not special. This is a decadent Matthew Scudder-like character who looks like a professional, capable, and tough detective on the outside, but is broken on the inside. We have seen countless similar male characters. The decadent man finds himself and his original intention through handling cases, which is very cliché. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Pursuit&quot;, we cannot ignore the gender issue, it is the theme of this movie. The audience is first put into a female perspective. Wu Jie, who has experienced pain in the film, is facing the difficulty of how to survive. She tried to commit suicide in the car. This is the starting point of the character&#39;s story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴洁碰到了无名女尸案，客观上，刑警的本能阻止了自杀的念头。 When she starts to handle the case, the story becomes logical and has two layers: one is that Wu Jie is solving the case of the unknown female corpse and wants to find the murderer; the other is that Wu Jie is also facing her spiritual death and trying to find a way to survive. The answer to go down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Pursuit&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie, detective Wu Jie has a dialogue: &quot;We always say that the corpse will choose someone to handle the case, and she chose me.&quot; Of course the dead would not choose. The fact is that Wu Jie chose this case. She wanted to seek justice for the dead, and her motivation was not only her professional status, but also her responsibility as a woman and her need to heal herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, female identity shows special significance.在故事的表面，是一位女刑警在侦办针对女性的凶案。 Inside, there is a woman who empathizes with women who have been hurt—both physically and emotionally—and ultimately healed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of empathy is not uncommon, but it is difficult to become the main line. There is a scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot; where a group of male detectives are drinking coffee and talking during an indoor scene involving a woman&#39;s autopsy. Jodie Foster, who was inside, felt uncomfortable and helpless when she saw the naked female corpse. Finally, she mustered up the courage to clear the men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the story itself of &quot;Pursuit&quot; did not give me much new ideas and was very routine. However, the empathy between the female detective Wu Jie and the female victims always reminds me of the scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot;. The female perspective runs throughout, and this amplified empathy transcends the limitations of the screen, which is beyond the expectations of ordinary crime films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; As a category. They are all movies with female protagonists, and women are the protagonists in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is easy for the audience to take a certain unconscious stance, not because of the performance of the two actors, but because of the female protagonist&#39;s genre film, which not only brings freshness, but also brings strangeness. Feeling unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;858&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type films and There is no need for extraordinary acting skills, it is very craftsmanship, it should be performed, it cannot be missing or wrong. In my eyes, the &quot;craftsmanship&quot; of performances in genre films is a compliment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Zhang Junning or Zhang Xiaofei, they provide a fresh sense of crime themes. Although the story still has loopholes and problems of one kind or another, more and more complete and different types of female protagonists appear in On the screen, this is a good phenomenon that deserves applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人机连接走到哪一步了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;马斯克旗下的脑机接口公司Neuralink正式开始招募首次临床试验的志愿者。 Ideal volunteer candidates are quadriplegic adults under the age of 40. The trial will see most of the volunteers&#39; skulls removed and implanted with a brain-computer implant, a processing, communication and charging system. The device, which is a chip and wires, has more than a thousand electrodes to receive brain data. By comparison, implants from other rival companies have only about 16 electrodes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thunder that has been ringing has finally turned into raindrops, and the brain-computer interface or human-computer connection will enter the human trial stage. However, implanting a chip in the brain is an invasive procedure that could cause harm to a person if not careful. However, the significance of this research is very important. It can not only decipher the thinking of the human brain, but also make it possible for people to obtain more powerful capabilities with the help of computers and shape the so-called human-machine complex. To this end, we must find a balance between harm and benefits to minimize harm to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a balance is the content of medical ethics intervention. In May 2023, Neuralink said that its first human clinical trial was approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA); on September 19, Neuralink announced that the company had received approval from an independent review committee and would conduct the trial this year. Conducting the first human trial of a brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This shows that Neuralink has done enough homework in terms of ethical review and approval. Before doing this kind of homework, we also followed the procedures of medical clinical trials from animals to humans. Before applying for human clinical trials, Neuralink has conducted relevant tests on pigs and monkeys respectively, and achieved certain results. In particular, the tests on monkeys have proven that it can be applied to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, Neuralink released a video showing a macaque implanted with its device playing video games through telepathy, indicating a major breakthrough in chip implantation in brain control research. The macaque in the video is named Pug, and has a brain-computer interface implanted in his brain. Initially, the research team taught Pug to play games using a game joystick and rewarded him with banana milkshakes through metal straws. At this stage, the brain-computer device records which neurons are activated, models the relationship between Pug&#39;s neural activity and the expected direction of movement, and achieves &quot;brain-computer connection.&quot; Judging from the macaque&#39;s brain thoughts controlling the joystick to play games, the implanted chip shows the preliminary goal of monkey-computer integration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After these results were obtained, Neuralink applied for human trials. Moreover, current human trials also follow the principle that they are only conducted on patients, not healthy subjects. For patients, trials are about balancing benefits and harms. Experiments on patients are to treat their diseases. Even if the process is full of risks, compared with the benefits of giving patients a new life, if the latter is greater or far greater than the former, it is feasible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trial is targeting paralyzed patients and visually impaired people. Through the brain-computer interface, the brain consciousness of paralyzed patients can be obtained, and this consciousness can be received through an external computer, and then the computer can decipher and issue instructions to the corresponding mechanical devices to help patients with cerebral palsy move, at least to take care of themselves. Such as eating, drinking and going to the bathroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the visually impaired, implanted visual chips can help them improve and restore their vision, such as helping patients with retinal dystrophy improve their vision. If successful, it could help more patients. There are currently about 1.3 million blind people and 2.9 million people with low vision in the United States. These two numbers are likely to grow to 2.2 million and 5 million by 2030. If the brain-computer interface can treat visual impairment, this group will also benefit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if an accident occurs in a brain-computer interface experiment or if the damage exceeds the benefits, the principle of putting life and health first will need to be stopped immediately. However, such experiments may also yield unexpected results and new discoveries, helping to reveal more secrets of the human brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, research on brain-computer interfaces in animals has achieved more results. A research team from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute in the United States has developed a new system that combines virtual reality (VR) and brain-computer interface (BMI) to try to detect the thoughts or thoughts in the minds of rats. As in humans, when rodents experience places and events, the hippocampus, an area of ​​the brain responsible for spatial memory, activates specific patterns of neural activity that allow thoughts to wander back in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hippocampus is an important area of ​​the brain responsible for memory and imagination. It possesses a model of the environment called a cognitive map. Therefore, the hippocampus contains a spatial map-like representation of the previously explored environment. to facilitate subsequent recall or simulation. At the same time, the representation of each environment consists of specific place cells, and when the animal passes a specific location in that environment, these neurons fire selectively, recalling past scenes. This situation is similar to people&#39;s memory of the environment and cognition of environmental patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the test, the rats were placed in a specially designed VR system. The brain-computer interface system translated the rat&#39;s brain activity into movement on a virtual reality screen. Rats need to control their hippocampus activity to imagine specific scenes in order to receive rewards, and this thinking process is very similar to humans. When people are asked to go to a certain theater, they may imagine leaving home and going to the theater. Routes and neighborhoods that will be traveled. Afterwards, the rats were asked to move the virtual object from one location to another by imagining it, that is, the rats needed to move the object to the target location in the virtual space by controlling their hippocampus activity. The researchers then changed the location of the target, inducing the rats to produce activity patterns associated with the new location. The process is like the person sitting in the seat imagining picking up the cup next to the water dispenser and filling it with water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that rats can control their hippocampal activity with the precision and flexibility of humans, holding their thoughts in a given position for several seconds, similar to how humans relive past events. event or imagine a new scenario. Moreover, as brain-computer interface systems are increasingly used in prosthetics, the results of this research can be used to design new prosthetic devices to serve people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study on rats once again shows that brain-computer interfaces can know a person&#39;s thoughts and thoughts, just like mind reading. This also means that future brain-computer interfaces can be used for in-depth research on human brain consciousness and thinking, but if they are to be used for healthy people and other purposes, more and stricter ethical and legal supervision is required. Therefore, it is easier to gain consensus by limiting human-machine interfaces to the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海住了18年，这位来自迈阿密的“洋盘”还没打算离开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqYf3c0BPhHY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;607&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqY f3c0BPhHY. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He pointed to a residential building across the street and told the story of his friend who had moved to Singapore; in the next street, the locksmith Master Ji saved him; and further on was He often goes to the small shop where clothes are repaired, and greets him every time he passes by. “If I don’t see them, I might forget them.” He is afraid of losing these living records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combining the life experience of his great-great-grandfather provided him with a new perspective, &quot;Our difficulties are simply incommensurable.&quot; Different from the missionary mission of his ancestors more than a hundred years ago, he has a new perspective on his own mission. The mission becomes clearer, &quot;There is a lot of valuable knowledge here, and I hope it can be seen by more people in the world. I have a visa, can travel, understand the different wisdom of Eastern and Western cultures, and I can do something.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2015, Chris measured Shanghai Xiaolongbao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Where are you in the bubble? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;American Chris has a serious Chinese name - Shen Kaiwei. He said the origin of the name was somewhat boring. When he was working in a hotel in Shanghai more than ten years ago, a colleague in the human resources department named him Shen Jiawei, which he rarely used. When his new book &quot;Yangpan&quot; was published in October 2023, he changed the middle character to &quot;kai&quot;, which happened to have a similar pronunciation to his English name Christopher St. Cavish. Friends who know him well tend to call him Chris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Foreign Deal&quot; records Chris&#39;s life in Shanghai over the past 18 years, including the whole story of his coming to Shanghai by chance, his ups and downs of riding a motorcycle around northwest China, and his unusual Family stories told to others. In Shanghai dialect, &quot;foreign plate&quot; refers to outsiders who don&#39;t know much about local customs. The English title &quot;outsider&quot; may be more straightforward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“To some foreigners, I am too Chinese; to many Chinese, I am too foreigner. I am not building a bubble (for expats in China)” &quot;Comfort Zone&quot;) came to China, but when I drifted out and blended in outside the circle, I would miss it. I came for China, but I can&#39;t live in China full time.&quot; Chris in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height= &quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Foreign Deals-Flat Cover&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Foreign Deals&quot; is Chris&#39;s first book. Earlier, he applied a quantitative framework to the Xiao Long Bao in Shanghai, collecting the weight of the Xiao Long Bao, the weight of the soup, the quality of the fillings, and the thickness of the skin, calculating the structural and technological quality of the Xiao Long Bao, and wrote &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;, &quot;if that counts as a book.&quot; Before writing, he worked as a professional chef in Miami and New York for 10 years. Tired of the static life in his hometown of Miami, he decided to seek opportunities in Asia and then travel around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The initial destination I wanted was Hong Kong. At the beginning of the 21st century, he traveled through Southeast Asia as a backpacker and went to Hong Kong to visit his sister. He loves Hong Kong very much. &quot;It is neither a completely Western culture nor a completely Chinese culture.&quot; In the plan, he would go directly to the kitchen of the Peninsula Hotel and offer to work for free. But The Peninsula doesn’t need a young American who doesn’t speak Cantonese in its kitchen. After repeatedly hitting the wall and going through different referrals, he finally found a job as a chef in Shanghai. That’s how I came to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Chris came to Shanghai for the first time at the age of 24, planning to stay for only one year. What he didn&#39;t expect was that he would still be living here 18 years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working in Shanghai for a year, he quit his job as a chef and traveled around the northwest on a modified motorcycle. The journey is thrilling. The motorcycle was always breaking down and he was always looking for a repair shop along the way. One time the brake pads broke, but no shop had vintage brake parts made in Germany during the war (yes, in the 1930s). He later rode a motorcycle with broken brakes through Tianshui, Gansu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without any danger, he ended his month-long trip. &quot;I was still in Lanzhou in the morning, and arrived in Xining in the afternoon. Everything went too fast. I am used to life on a motorcycle. If I do it again, I might go to Xinjiang. It may not be safe, but...&quot; In short, he later sat down After a 36-hour train ride back to Shanghai, he flew back to Miami the next day. “At that time, I was not sure whether I wanted to come back, so I rented out the house.” Three months later, he returned to Shanghai. Just one more year, he thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many foreigners in China think so too. Wandering and living with the mentality of “just one more year”, only thinking about 12 months at a time. When my passport was filled with visa papers issued once a year, I suddenly realized that I had been living in this country for more than ten years. Chris calls this &quot;tomorrow syndrome&quot; - &quot;Tomorrow never comes. That year will never end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Chris first came to Shanghai in 2005, there were 100,000 foreign residents in Shanghai. Ten years later, that number had doubled, and has decreased in recent years. &quot;Immigration and foreigners will automatically create their own bubble circle - a barbaric one-size-fits-all approach based on the wealth and poverty of your home country. See foreign doctors when you are sick, and spend a lot of money on imported ingredients when cooking.&quot; Although he is very fond of bubbles. The circle ridicules you in every possible way, but in fact you are also a member of the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, Chris was filming the story of a famous hairy crab dumpling restaurant in Shanghai. This hotel will close in the spring of 2023 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sheila Zhao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common greeting in the bubble circle is: Are you coming to China? How long? Can you speak Chinese? People judge who is the boss in this circle based on the answers. “在中国生活了六年的外籍人士会看不起在中国生活了六个月的外籍人士，以此类推，在中国生活了六个月的外籍人士又会看不起在中国生活了六周的外籍人士。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诸如此类的比较也适用于工作，在那条等级分明的鄙视链中，教英语的外籍人士处于最底端，最顶端是商人。 Chris knows several of the latter, &quot;They complain endlessly about the aunties, the Western food, and their Chinese employees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They also complain about the changes. Expats who have been here for a long time often lament how beautiful Shanghai was in the past, but the implication is that it is not as good as it used to be. Chris doesn’t think so. “Shanghai teaches people to accept changes. This can be good or bad. If you find a good restaurant, you should go there today, because it may not be open tomorrow. If you don’t like Shanghai now, it doesn’t matter. Just wait. , it will be completely different in a year.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After staying in the bubble circle for too long, Chris sometimes wants to go out. The Shanghai Xiaolongbao evaluation completed in collaboration with friends is an attempt. After that, he was often in a half-and-half situation—“one foot in the bubble, one foot outside.” “It was like my identity. Sometimes I wake up in the morning and just want to be in the bubble, so I eat sandwiches for breakfast, pizza for dinner, and stay in my room watching YouTube all day. Sometimes I want to go out and chat with my neighbors and friends. I want to really live in Shanghai.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In 2016, Chris learned the ramen making process at a ramen school in Lanzhou. This experience was also recorded in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Writing in a Foreign Country&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After quitting being a chef, Chris switched jobs to work for an English magazine, writing food reports for foreigners in China. It took him several years to switch perspectives from chef to food writer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What you want as a diner is completely different from what you want as a chef.&quot; At the end of October 2023, we made an appointment to meet in a Western restaurant. Chris gave the example of cinnamon rolls on the table, &quot; As a chef, I don&#39;t want them (walnuts and icing) to spill, and the edges to be neatly folded. But that doesn&#39;t affect the taste. As a diner, what I think about is does it taste good? Did I enjoy the meal? It Is the price right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, food is just a medium for him to care about people, helping him to answer more curious questions: &quot;What is their life like? In what ways are we the same and in what ways are we different? ? What is their happiness? What about their sadness?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Writing seems to give me a license to ask people questions that would be excessive or embarrassing in normal interactions.&quot; Some The interview went deeper. For example, when he chatted with Master Tao, a handmade pottery maker in Hongkou, the other party naturally revealed to him the difficulties and struggles in the past. Others are not so lucky. For example, he started visiting the Cen brothers, who were both potters with Master Tao, in 2006. More than ten years later, they still &quot;never said hello&quot; as if they didn&#39;t know him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Chris and his friends released the &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;. They abandoned personal subjective opinions and measured hundreds of Xiao Long Bao in 52 stores from a purely physical perspective. &quot; Writing about food is bound to be subjective, and you have to understand what other people are obsessed with, but everyone insists on their own opinions (including myself), which makes me feel very tired. I want to change it, and let others or other Use things to make judgments.&quot; He confided in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2012, Chris was DJing in a nightclub&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot; unexpectedly gained him a lot of attention. He has been dubbed a &quot;foreigner obsessed with Xiao Long Bao&quot; and appears in many people&#39;s circles of friends and in interviews with the media. A company that specializes in making xiao long bao even invited him to be a consultant for cheese xiao long bao. He refused. The person in charge of the Shanghai Catering Association said in an interview that they would support Chris if he conducts follow-up research. After seeing the news, he walked to the bathroom and cried in the hallway. In his 10th year in Shanghai, he felt accepted by the city for the first time. Although when he later called the Shanghai Catering Association to talk, the other party had completely forgotten about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;, Chris realized that his writing should have more interaction with China. &quot;This is the first step to get out of the bubble circle.&quot; In his circle of friends Gradually more and more Chinese people appeared. Xu Junqian met Chris after the release of &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;. At that time, the latter was recruiting a researcher, and she sent an email to recommend herself. However, the two were slow to warm up, and they did not meet until the following year after exchanging emails. As a test, Chris gave her a name and asked her if she could contact him. Later, the two set off smoothly and went to Yunnan to interview a chef. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of her cooperation with Chris, Xu Junqian went to Altay to interview people who make camel milk, and also went to Shanxi to interview people who make pasta. If it weren&#39;t for work, she probably wouldn&#39;t have taken the initiative to set foot in these places. &quot;Chris speaks Chinese very well, but some dialects are still a bit difficult for him.&quot; When the two collaborate, Xu Junqian is often the interviewer, while Chris listens silently and only adds questions at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through Chris’s perspective, Xu Junqian has seen a lot, and “his skin has become thicker.” In her eyes, Chris is a pure person who “does not pursue eye-catching content or deliberately sensationalize. .&quot; In the spring and summer of 2023, they and the photographer went to Qinghai to interview Han Lu, an old man who makes Lanzhou Ramen. The old man cried when the conversation got emotional. This moment was also recorded by their camera, but Chris later did not use this part of the material. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to her part-time job, Xu Junqian works in a family Work for foreign companies. She likes to compare the two jobs, &quot;They are like the two poles of the spectrum. Foreign-funded companies pursue returns when doing things, and they would like to arrange ABCD solutions for everything. But often, the more cautious they are, the less they dare to be creative.&quot; As for Chris, &quot;He keeps an open mind and always has unexpected gains.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years or so, Chris has worked for several media outlets and experienced marriage, divorce, moving, and depression again. . After resigning from an online media in 2020, he opened a consulting company to provide services for hotels and restaurants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the company&#39;s business is in a mess. &quot;It performed pretty well in 2021, but it was completely dead last year.&quot; The survival problems that writers often face are increasingly bothering him. The trip to Qinghai with Xu Junqian was paid for with his credit card and he paid it back recently. So he would &quot;take some editorial jobs, or do odd jobs for some schools. I had no choice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also thought about moving away from Shanghai to Suzhou or Dali, but neither was feasible. On the one hand, he cannot do without Shanghai&#39;s convenient medical system to prevent depression from recurring. On the other hand, &quot;I have many memories here.&quot; He pointed to a residential building across the street and told the story of his friend who had moved to Singapore; in the next street, the locksmith Master Ji saved him; and further on, He often goes to the small shop where clothes are repaired, and greets him every time he passes by. “If I don’t see them, I might forget them.” He is afraid of losing these living records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other dilemma is more secret, which was told to me by Xu Junqian. In the past two years, when she helped Chris find interviewees, she would always conceal the latter&#39;s nationality and only introduce him as a foreign author who writes about food. During the same trip to Qinghai, they also interviewed another Lanzhou ramen practitioner. The other person’s attitude was neither salty nor bland. He only asked the waiter to serve a few bowls of ramen. “It felt like he wanted us to leave as soon as we finished the noodles.” .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Are people less friendly?&quot; Chris also asked himself. &quot;I don&#39;t think so. Even if they hate the United States, at least they are polite to me. If you go to the United States in the past two years, the situation may be worse, and the hatred against Asians has become more and more intense.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The second time I met Chris, we walked together in a neighborhood he was familiar with. He once lived in an apartment on Huashan Road for four or five years, and he knew almost everything about the changes in the nearby shops&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;Should I stay? Do I want to leave? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2006, when his parents and sister traveled to China, Chris heard the family story for the first time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1867, 24-year-old Hiram Harrison Lowry and his wife left New York after graduating from Christian School and were sent to Fuzhou, China as a missionary. Two years later, they were ordered to Beijing to establish the first Methodist mission in North China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lori has been in China for more than fifty years and has experienced war, disease, intense xenophobia, the collapse of the Qing government, and personal life difficulties. They could have returned to the United States, but they chose to stay. They built schools, churches and hospitals for the poor Chinese at that time, and also served as deans of Huiwen Academy (after a complex evolution, this academy was incorporated into Yenching University and then into the famous Peking University today). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The remains of my ancestors are buried somewhere in Beijing, to the west of the old city wall . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first heard about his great-great-grandfather’s mysterious connection with China, Chris felt it was strange. When the family was walking in the alley near Tiananmen Square looking for the Asili Church (a legacy left by my great-great-grandfather, now the Christian Church Chongwenmen Church), Chris&#39;s mother started counting in broken Chinese. Chris and his sister were stunned, &quot;Can mom speak Chinese?&quot; He vaguely knew that his grandfather, who spoke fluent Mandarin, &quot;had a weird connection with China.&quot; However, his grandfather had a cold relationship with his family and believed in the philosophy of American men in the 1950s. He believes that women should take care of children and never talks too much about themselves with their children. When Chris&#39; mother was 21, her grandfather committed suicide. The clues are interrupted. Later, Chris asked other relatives in the family. They tried to contact Asili Tang, &quot;Maybe it was the language barrier, but they gave up in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter was put on hold for 16 years. Until the spring of 2022, Chris was determined to salvage this piece of history. He saw it as some kind of family duty. The process of collecting information was like a detective challenge. Many diaries were lost or damaged. He spent a lot of energy - &quot;often working 12 hours a day&quot; - to track down Lowry&#39;s life. Finally, in &quot;Foreign Deal&quot;, he used two chapters to reconstruct the life experience of the Lowry couple more than a hundred years ago through detailed historical materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height= &quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Foreign Dishes - Three-dimensional Cover&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After writing &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;, he couldn&#39;t stop I kept asking myself, &quot;Do I stay? Do I leave?&quot; There was no answer. In fact, he asks this question every year, when he goes to renew his visa at the turn of the new and old years of the lunar calendar.新春长假常常被虚掷于焦虑之中，他担心“签证官觉得自己尽责缴纳的税太少，或嫌弃公司的办公室太小”。 The anxiety is getting worse every year, and he wants to keep his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the COVID-19 epidemic, many of Chris’s friends have left China in recent years. Visas are becoming more and more difficult to obtain, and the number of flights back to China is not the same. He feels that now is the lowest number of foreigners in China in recent years. “The ones who remain are people who take China more seriously. They may have already Get married and have children here, or run a company.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This past summer, he did not have a good time. Depression and the bleak financial situation tortured him physically and mentally, so he borrowed money to return to Miami. After returning to his hometown after four years, he is no longer familiar with many things, such as how much tip should be given, and there are also some issues that he does not understand well and the context behind them, such as transgender. He was embarrassed to find that flying to Qinghai to interview an old man who makes Lanzhou Ramen was more attractive and comfortable than driving 10 minutes to a Colombian restaurant near his home to interview locals. &quot;In Qinghai, people assume that you are an outsider.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;He felt that he should stay in China. Sorting out the life experience of his great-great-grandfather provided him with a new perspective, &quot;Our difficulties are simply incommensurable.&quot; Different from the missionary mission of his ancestors more than a hundred years ago, he became increasingly clear about his mission, &quot;Here There is a lot of valuable knowledge, and I hope it can be seen by more people in the world. I have a visa, can travel, understand the different wisdom of Eastern and Western cultures, and I can do something.&quot; He is currently planning a video account, and is also Prepare a book about noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back in 2006. After returning to Miami after a motorcycle trip around the northwest, Chris thought to himself, &quot;One year is not enough for China.&quot; More than ten years later, he said with a smile, &quot;Now I feel that 18 years is not enough.&quot; It’s not enough, I don’t know what is enough.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D真实还原早产儿出生后的六重难关丨国际早产儿日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>