<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“小便事件”冲击青岛啤酒？全链条管控能力或存疏漏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259088]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How much impact will a video of more than ten seconds have on a 100-billion-dollar listed company? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many investors in Tsingtao Beer (600600.SH) have been worried about this throughout the weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A video posted online showed a male employee wearing blue overalls and a safety helmet digging into a suspected raw material warehouse to urinate. The video said it happened at Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. After the market closed on October 20, this video was widely circulated on the Internet and became a hot search topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Market Supervision and Administration Bureau of Pingdu City, where Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is located, confirmed to the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that the malt involved has been sealed and the investigation of the incident is still ongoing. A person from Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 responded to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that the incident in the online video was not in the warehouse of No. 3 Beer, and the person involved was not an employee of No. 3 Beer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement has not been officially confirmed by Tsingtao Beer. A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald noticed that the clothes of the person involved in the online video were similar to the work clothes of Tsingtao Brewery No. 3. Regarding the progress of the investigation of the incident, a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald contacted the Tsingtao Brewery Board Secretary Office several times over the weekend, but was unable to get through as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food safety is a top priority in the beverage industry. Domestic beer giants have rarely encountered such major public opinion in recent years. Many investors have questioned on platforms such as Stock Bar: How can the production safety control capabilities of large wine companies be weak? Could this be some kind of business war &quot;script&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final investigation results will lead to different directions. If it is confirmed that the incident is related to the Tsingtao Brewery factory or employees, it means that there are major problems with the internal control system of this century-old beer giant. If it is confirmed that the incident was committed by a third-party supplier and did not occur within the Tsingtao Brewery factory, Tsingtao Brewery&#39;s responsibility will be relatively reduced, but it will still expose its omissions in the entire chain of supplier control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coinciding with the weakening growth momentum of domestic beer since the third quarter, Tsingtao Beer’s stock price has continued to fall recently. How to characterize this incident and how to deal with it later will test the wisdom of the parties involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau: The malt involved has been sealed&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 said: It is not in the warehouse and is not a Tsingtao Brewery employee&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the video, The urination incident occurred at Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is located in Pingdu City, a subsidiary of Qingdao City, more than 100 kilometers away from Qingdao City. It was formerly known as Beihai Brewery. It was founded in 1986 and had a production capacity of less than 10,000 when it was built. However, after years of capacity transformation, especially in recent years, the scale has continued to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article on Tsingtao Beer’s official WeChat ID earlier this year mentioned: In the past five years, Tsingtao Beer Plant No. 3 has undergone multiple upgrades, with annual production capacity jumping from 750,000 kiloliters in 2018 to 2022. 1.2 million kiloliters, making it a world-class factory. Not only that, Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is also the leader of Tsingtao Beer Intelligent Industrial Park, which gathers 11 industrial chain supporting enterprises and is the largest clustered, intelligent, garden-style industrial park in the global industrial chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do such very elementary production safety incidents occur in a world-class factory? Some investors pointed out that in a factory of this size, the bathroom must be standard and not far from the workplace. Why would employees go to all the trouble to go into the raw material warehouse to urinate, and even be caught on video? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 22, a person from the Third Tsingtao Brewery Factory responded to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that the video of an employee urinating online was not at the raw material warehouse of the Third Factory, and the person involved was not an employee of Tsingtao Brewery. , the specific circumstances of the incident are still under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald contacted the Pingdu Municipal Market Supervision Bureau on October 21. A person from the Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau told the reporter that it was certain that the malt involved had been sealed, but the specifics of the incident The results of the investigation are yet to be officially announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People from the Municipal Supervision Bureau did not respond to whether the incident was committed by employees of Tsingtao Brewery No. 3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;21st Century Business Herald compared the photos on the official account of Tsingtao Brewery Factory No. 3 and noticed that the work clothes of employees at Tsingtao Brewery Factory No. 3 are dark blue, with yellow hats, and there are light-colored strips on the back of the work clothes, which is consistent with The people involved in the video posted online were wearing similar clothes. However, due to insufficient clarity, it is difficult to determine whether the person involved in the video was wearing work clothes from Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/981cc1a404f50dd891c7f657a05c0533.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/981cc1a404f50dd891c7f657a05c0533.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/401a211480df23b912e12a6b4096f4fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/401a211480df23b912e12a6b4096f4fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;(Comparison of the work clothes of Tsingtao Beer Factory No. 3 and the clothing of the person involved in the online video)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer officials issued a situation statement on the evening of October 20: In response to the Tsingtao Beer Factory No. 3 that appeared online on October 19 Our company attaches great importance to the relevant video and immediately reported it to the public security organs, who have intervened in the investigation. At present, this batch of malt has been completely sealed. Our company continues to increase management efforts to ensure product quality, and welcomes consumer supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 produces main brand products&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Consumption intention will be affected in the short term&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What netizens are worried about is: has similar incidents happened before? Budweiser has twice made false alarms due to similar news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2017, a video of female workers manually pouring Budweiser beer was widely circulated. &amp;nbsp;After Budweiser reported the case, an investigation found that the video was fake wine made from recycled Budweiser beer cans from a domestic copycat brewery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, news circulated on the domestic Internet that &quot;an employee of Budweiser beer has peed in it for many years.&quot; It was later discovered that the news was &quot;fake news&quot; from an external spoof website. Budweiser quickly refuted the rumors on its domestic platform, saying that the rumors were &quot;malicious slander of the company&#39;s products&quot; and &quot;this matter is purely fabricated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have strict production procedures. After the malt enters our production line, it will go through various processes such as cleaning, sterilization, disinfection, and fermentation. Consumers should rest assured.” The aforementioned person from the third Tsingtao Brewery Factory said 21st Century Business Herald reporter emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some industry insiders also told reporters that malt is generally cleaned to remove impurities before brewing, and industrial canned beer is also sterilized, which will most likely not affect the drinking safety of the beer. However, there are also draft beer products on the market that are not sterilized and only fermented at low temperatures. The purpose is to retain more flavor. Such products are difficult to preserve and have a short shelf life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is widely circulated on the Internet that Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 mainly produces non-Tsingtao beer brands such as Guoli and Red Snow Dragon. They are not major brands on the market. Most locals in Qingdao do not drink them and they mainly sell them to other places. , some of which brands have been discontinued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald learned that Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 also produces main brand products such as Classic 1903. Classic 1903 is one of the representative products of Tsingtao Beer’s product upgrade in recent years. It has a shelf life of 365 days and theoretically also requires sterilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the overwhelming news will still have an impact on some consumers&#39; willingness to consume. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald noticed that a netizen posted a post saying that he habitually purchased an extra box of Tsingtao beer, but after thinking of the news, he finally chose to delete it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some consumers asked the customer service of Tsingtao Beer flagship store whether the products come from the third factory? Customer service responded that it was not clear which factory the product came from. Since the product is shipped randomly from the warehouse, it cannot be designated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of press time on the afternoon of the 22nd, Tsingtao Brewery and the Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau have not disclosed the results of their investigation into the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it is finally confirmed that he is an employee of Tsingtao Beer or that the incident occurred in a Tsingtao Beer factory, it means that Tsingtao Beer’s internal control system will face torture. If the incident is confirmed to be the behavior of a third party, Tsingtao Beer&#39;s responsibility can be reduced, but there are still omissions in Tsingtao Beer&#39;s full-chain production control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the incident is true, then this incident is a very low-level mistake. As a listed company and the oldest leading beer company in China, Tsingtao Beer reflects the internal management and quality control of Tsingtao Beer The lack of the system will definitely have some impact on the entire image of Tsingtao Beer and its performance in the capital market.&quot; Zhu Danpeng, vice president of the Guangdong Provincial Food Safety Promotion Association, told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The third quarter performance is the focus&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As the relevant video was widely circulated after the market closed on October 20, Tsingtao Beer’s stock price was not affected and closed with a slight increase on the 20th. official. Investors are watching how the market will react after the market opens on Monday, the 23rd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with this unexpected incident, the impact of the recent weakening of beer consumption sentiment on major beer stocks deserves more attention from investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After offline opening this year, the beer industry ushered in a year of recovery. The beer output of designated enterprises across the country increased by 7% year-on-year in the first half of the year, especially in March and April, based on a low base in the same period last year, the year-on-year growth was as high as 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the industry leaders, Tsingtao Beer has enjoyed the dividends of recovery. In the first half of this year, Tsingtao Brewery achieved operating income of 21.59 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 12%; net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was 3.43 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 20.1%. Tsingtao Beer&#39;s stock price hit a record high in April, exceeding 123 yuan per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, starting from June, the consumption enthusiasm in the beer market began to decline. First, in June, the beer production of designated enterprises across the country increased by only 1.6% year-on-year. In the summer of July and August, under the dual influence of heavy rains in the north and typhoons in the south, beer consumption during the peak season was not as expected. Coupled with the impact of the high base in the same period last year, The beer output of designated enterprises across the country has declined, with year-on-year declines of 3.4% and 5.8% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, beer consumption became even weaker. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, the beer output of designated enterprises across the country in September was 2.866 million liters, a year-on-year decrease of 8%. The cumulative output in the first nine months was 29.933 million liters, a year-on-year increase of 2.1%. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer’s stock price has been declining since April. As of last week, the stock price was as low as just over 80 yuan. It has fallen by more than 30% in less than half a year, which is a new low in the past year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer will disclose its third quarter report on the evening of October 27. As of the close of trading on the 20th, Tsingtao Beer’s market value was approximately 110.6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家烟草专卖局原党组书记、局长凌成兴被查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259102]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 10:09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ling Chengxing, former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection Disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“22万美元降至1美元”？美国防部长陷入降薪风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259090]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Austin has been in &quot;trouble&quot; recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It has been more than a thousand days since Austin took office as Defense Secretary on January 20, 2021. The Republican Party is quite dissatisfied with Austin&#39;s &quot;political performance&quot; so far, and recently even publicly proposed to reduce his annual salary from US$220,000 to US$1. The U.S. House of Representatives recently passed amendments to the relevant bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Republican Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene, who proposed the amendment, said fiercely in the House of Representatives: &quot;Austin did not perform his job responsibilities. In fact, he is destroying our military.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is going on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/52d93b7d33.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/52d93b7d33.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Republican Party is quite dissatisfied with Austin&#39;s &quot;political performance&quot; so far. (Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Annual salary&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;cut to US$1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;As the top civilian military leader in the Biden administration, Austin came under fire from Republican lawmakers in the House. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 27, the U.S. House of Representatives voted to approve an amendment proposed by Georgia Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene to replace Defense Secretary Austin’s Annual salary cut to $1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Secretary Austin botched the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan, resulting in the deaths of thirteen U.S. soldiers while abandoning U.S. civilians and military equipment.&quot; Green on social media &quot;During Austin&#39;s tenure,&quot; it reads, &quot;there was no recruiting, but instead a focus on purging the military through purported power.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the House Rules Committee , Greene said in her amendment that she used the Holman rule, which &quot;allows for changes in appropriations legislation to reduce the wages of specific federal employees or to lay off specific federal employees, or to cut specific programs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lawmakers passed her amendment by voice vote, with Democrats not calling for a roll call vote because they expected the pay cut measure to fail. took control of the Senate, and Democrats opposed a defense budget bill crafted by House Republicans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Republican Party is just using some issues and the death of a few soldiers to attack President Biden.&quot; Zhou Yuanxi, an expert on international issues, told Southern Weekend reporters that recruitment is difficult It is a social problem in the United States, and the role played by a secretary of defense cannot be entirely blamed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Austin is the first African-American defense secretary in the United States, with an annual salary of more than $221,000. Austin pensions are estimated to be worth starting at $1.8 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if Austin cuts his salary to $1, the impact on him will be &quot;not too big.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Austin and Biden have known each other for many years and are deeply trusted by the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The outside world generally believes that Austin has &quot;AB side&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Side A, when Austin was still a colonel, he was appointed commander of the 82nd Airborne Division. Because of his outstanding performance, Austin has many &quot;firsts&quot; in his resume. For example, the first African American Secretary of Defense; the first African American Army Deputy Chief of Staff; the first African American Central Command Commander...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Austin’s military resume has a strong Middle Eastern flavor and he served as commander of the U.S. Central Command. Commanding the withdrawal of U.S. troops from Iraq and the fight against the extremist organization &quot;Islamic State&quot; were the highlight moments of Austin&#39;s career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Biden once wrote an article emphasizing that Austin not only has rich experience, skills and strategies as a soldier, but also has diplomatic abilities. Calling Austin a &quot;tested soldier and leader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Biden does not regard the ability of the Secretary of Defense as the primary consideration.&quot; Yang Zhen, deputy director of the Northeast Asia Research Center of Shanghai University of Political Science and Law, believes that this often makes him &quot;Playing minefields&quot; in handling domestic and foreign affairs. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Austin&#39;s &quot;B-side&quot; is considered by the outside world to be the &quot;three sins&quot; required by the Republican Party to reduce his salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Secretary Austin is not doing his job. In fact, he is destroying our military.&quot; Green criticized Austin and said the current draft number is at &quot;crisis levels.&quot; , if assistance continues to be provided to the Ukrainian conflict, &quot;this will undoubtedly lead us to World War III.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Crime&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the difficulty in recruiting soldiers is the U.S. military One of the “old and difficult” problems we face. Draft numbers are down, suicide rates are up, and the cohesion of the military is plummeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the five branches of the Department of Defense, only the Marine Corps and the Space Force have achieved their active duty recruitment goals for fiscal year 2023. The Army, Air Force, and Navy None of them achieved their goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although the U.S. military has adopted many innovative ways to encourage young people to join the military, including the Army reusing the slogan &quot;Do your best&quot; from the 1980s, the Air Force has relaxed Following previous tattoo and drug testing policies, the Navy introduced record financial incentives of up to $140,000. But in the end, these three services still failed to achieve their recruitment goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The United States has encountered various problems and dilemmas in recruiting troops, withdrawing troops from Afghanistan, and responding to Ukraine. Among these problems and dilemmas, a large number of Part of it is a waste of U.S. national power and reduces the U.S.’s international prestige.&quot; Yang Zhen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At a time when recruitment is difficult, the U.S. Army will cut about 3,000 personnel, or about 10% of the number of special operations forces. Included in psychological operations, civil affairs, intelligence personnel, communications units, logistics and other support services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Austin has not yet signed the final documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wisconsin Rep. Derek Van Orden expressed support for Greene&#39;s amendment, noting that suicide rates among active-duty service members and veterans are high in 2021. Thirteen soldiers died during the withdrawal from Afghanistan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many outsiders believe that the withdrawal of troops from Afghanistan has become a &quot;joke&quot; in U.S. military history. The hasty retreat of U.S. forces and the chaos at Kabul airport resulted in the deaths of thirteen U.S. service members in the attack in Kabul. During this withdrawal, Austin was accused by public opinion of failing to properly handle this major military operation, which caused the US military to be in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Austin abandoned thousands of American citizens and allies to terrorists in Afghanistan. He should be directly responsible for this incident.&quot; Former US Navy SEAL Team member Van Orden said publicly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The main contradiction currently facing the United States is the contradiction between the rising cost of maintaining hegemony and the gradually declining comprehensive national strength.&quot; Yang Zhen believes that &quot;from At this point, Austin lacks the political wisdom and strategic vision required for this position.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the U.S. House of Representatives also pointed out that the United States has invested in Ukraine The huge amount of funds has failed to bring substantial strategic benefits to the country. Austin&#39;s failure to provide effective leadership on this issue has cast doubt on U.S. military policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since Russia launched the conflict against Ukraine in February 2022, the Biden administration, with the support of Congress, has provided nearly $75 billion in aid to Ukraine. Includes humanitarian, economic and military support. However, various opinion polls show that there is growing doubt in the United States about the need to continue providing additional assistance to Ukraine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yuanxi believes that after Austin came to power, in the process of assisting Ukraine, an alliance of 54 countries was formed to jointly support Ukraine. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The first bird is shot&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On one side is the Republican Party The other side is the support of the Democrats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Austin has played an important role in helping Ukraine and strengthening defense partnerships around the world.&quot; Minnesota Democratic Rep. Betty McCollum said of Austin defended his performance and said Democrats viewed the Republican pay cut proposal for Austin as a &quot;political stunt.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.militarytimes.com/news/pentagon-congress/2023/09/21/house-gop-plans -to-pass-defense-budget-fail-again-as-shutdown-looms/&quot;>;As part of the debate over the fiscal 2024 defense appropriations bill&lt;/a>;, Republican lawmakers approved multiple similar proposals to cut their Don&#39;t like the pay for DoD jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many interviewed experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that since the bill must pass the Democratic-controlled Senate and be signed by Biden, it is unlikely to be passed. But it marks yet another Republican rebuke of America’s current military leadership and reflects the country’s growing partisan divide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yuanxi believes that cutting the salary of the Secretary of Defense is an emotional expression of the Republican Party’s opposition to Biden’s administration. The main purpose is to &quot;disgust&quot; Biden and pave the way for Trump&#39;s election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This time the House of Representatives has adopted a tactic of clipping its wings. The target is directly at Biden, almost explicitly accusing him of improper employment.&quot; Yang Zhen believes that the House of Representatives believes that Austin is not up to the job, and destroying the U.S. armed forces is not an exaggeration. This is Biden&#39;s biggest problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2023, the results of a poll conducted by the American Gallup Consulting Company, a public opinion polling agency, showed that opinions between the Democratic Party and the Republican Party continue to diverge. It is difficult to reach consensus on most issues, and American politics is increasingly divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yuanxi believes that the fight between the Republican Party and the Democratic Party in the United States is to attack President Biden and the Democratic Party by finding the weaknesses of a person in such a sensitive position as the Secretary of Defense. In fact, this is the result of a struggle between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of September 28, the U.S. House of Representatives voted on four separate appropriation bills. The four appropriation bills involved defense, homeland security, agriculture, and the State Department respectively. and external affairs. Three bills related to defense, homeland security, and the State Department and Foreign Affairs were passed, while the bill related to agriculture was vetoed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is noteworthy is that this budget dispute not only reflects the long-term contradictions between the Democratic Party and the Republican Party, but also creates a &quot;superposition of contradictions&quot; within the Republican Party, creating a complicated situation . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The dispute between the two parties has no bottom line.&quot; Yang Zhen analyzed that in the American political arena, the dispute between the two parties is the main theme, and the current security situation is not a problem for the United States. It is not optimistic. The opposition party&#39;s demand to reduce the salary of the Minister of Defense to US$1 is actually putting the interests of the party above the interests of the country. &quot;This is a very dangerous sign.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;To some Republicans, all Democrats are bad people, and vice versa.&quot; Dr. Todd Grande, a well-known American sociologist, once said Publicly stated, “This is a very simple and quite dangerous way of looking at the world.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 3, the U.S. House of Representatives dismissed the Republican Speaker of the House of Representatives. McCarthy&#39;s motion was voted on, and the result was a narrow vote of 216 in favor and 210 against, passing the motion to remove McCarthy. This also marked McCarthy as the first speaker of the House of Representatives to be voted out of office in the history of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This recall incident has made American public opinion believe that the political struggle between the two parties will become more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Zhen analyzed that this incident left several impressions on voters: first, Biden made a mistake in employing personnel, and his own ability to exercise power is questionable; second, Biden&#39;s ability to exercise power is questionable; It is because the senior officials of the Biden administration are not qualified for their jobs, and this administration must step down; third, all the security problems facing the United States today are due to the Biden administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the degree of political division and intensification of conflicts in the United States, the 2024 election year is destined to be full of uncertainty. Where will the future of American politics go? Still remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Lin Xi also contributed to this article)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[怀化乡村：拨开云雾，宛若仙境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[凯文·凯利：乐观正成为当下的稀缺品]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258993]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/rtQ8pkH6qICN7d7zir27NV4LHexFToo0mwhK5VQt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/rtQ8pkH6qICN7d7zir27NV4LHexFToo0mw hK5VQt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Future Emperor&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 12, 2023, outside the Reading Theater of the East Branch of Shanghai Library, the rain was pouring. In the reception room on the basement floor, KK was discussing the process with two guest hosts, and the camera was pointed at them. An hour ago, KK had just finished an exclusive interview with Southern People Weekly. This was the third media he received that day. The chicken sandwich prepared by the organizer had been lying on the table for more than half an hour, with no intention of being opened. In 12 minutes, the signing event for his new book &quot;Precious Life Advice&quot; will begin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KK wears a decent shirt, trousers and sneakers. He is 71 years old, with a sparse top of his head, leaving only the white hair on his temples and a white beard that stretches from his chin to the side of his face. After nearly 14 hours of flight, he arrived in Shanghai from San Francisco the night before. At this moment, even with a 15-hour time difference and being crammed into a tight schedule, the fatigue in those blue eyes only flashed past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KK is the abbreviation of Kevin Kelly, the founding editor-in-chief of the well-known technology magazine &quot;Wired&quot; and the author of &quot;Out of Control&quot;. Chinese readers often call him this. Kelly&#39;s most influential work in China is &quot;Out of Control&quot; written in the early 1990s. This book was once one of the must-read books for the protagonists of &quot;The Matrix&quot; (1999) before reading the script. It was called &quot;the book of the 1990s&quot; by Chris Anderson, the former editor-in-chief of &quot;Wired&quot; magazine and the author of &quot;The Long Tail Theory&quot;. One of the most valuable books of the era.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading often and always new is one of its value expressions. If you open this book on Douban Reading, you will find that comments from readers from all over the world are densely dotted between the paragraphs. Until the ChatGPT craze in early 2023, there were still articles citing Kelly&#39;s view that &quot;machines are becoming biological, and organisms are being engineered.&quot; &quot;In releasing the power of life into the machines we create, we also lose control of them. They gain wildness, and with that wildness come some surprises and surprises. And then, that is what all creators must face The dilemma: They would no longer fully own their proudest creation,&quot; Kelly wrote in &quot;Out of Control.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book was first published in the United States in 1995. To the public, in an era when computers were still mainly used for office work and production, the concepts such as cloud computing, blockchain, big data, artificial intelligence, virtual reality, and digital currency discussed in &quot;Out of Control&quot; seemed too advanced. . This 528-page &quot;big book&quot; was not popular in the United States at that time, and it would be 15 years before it was truly &quot;born at the right time&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2008, Kelly received a special email in his mailbox. The sender is a Chinese named Zhao Jiamin. At that time, the latter had just taken over as the general manager of the community translation platform &quot;Yiyan&quot; and was eager to explore the platform&#39;s business model. He had high hopes for translation and publishing. Which book should I start with? Zhao Jiamin thought of &quot;Out of Control&quot; recommended by a friend not long ago. It was a book that he fell in love with just by flipping through the catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The year &quot;Out of Control&quot; was published in the United States, Zhao Jiamin was still an undergraduate student in the Automation Department of Tsinghua University. A few years later, he went to the University of Southern California to further his studies and received a doctorate in industrial systems engineering, and then joined Oracle to engage in technology development. For Zhao Jiamin, who has a technical background, he chose this old book not because of his optimism about its potential market value, but because the &quot;complex systems&quot; discussed in the book are a topic that he has been interested in since college. The &quot;complex systems&quot; theory emerged in the 1990s, advocating the use of interdisciplinary methods to study the unified laws behind various complex systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In less than a morning, Zhao Jiamin made the decision to buy the rights to publish this book in China. However, Kelly did not have high expectations for how much new royalties the Chinese market could bring. Instead, it was Zhao Jiamin&#39;s idea of ​​using &quot;crowdsourcing&quot; translation that aroused his interest. Kelly once described the operation of &quot;hive mind&quot; in nature in &quot;Out of Control&quot;. Now this collaborative thinking will promote the implementation of its Chinese version, which makes him &quot;amazed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;Out of Control&quot; was released in China much later than Zhao Jiamin expected. During this period, it went through various twists and turns, such as the integration of the collaborative translation team, the separation of Yiyan.com, Zhao Jiamin&#39;s departure and starting a new business, etc. It was already the second half of 2010 when the review was completed. Under the background of &quot;nothing to delay&quot;, this book was launched at the end of 2010. Coincidentally, it was precisely the various &quot;out of control&quot; in the early stage that made the publication of &quot;Out of Control&quot; the perfect time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, with the popularization of smartphones and 4G networks, China made great strides from the PC Internet era to the mobile Internet era. When &quot;Out of Control&quot; was published in China, WeChat had been launched less than two months ago, Xiaomi and Meituan had only been established for nine months, and Alibaba had just achieved sustained profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That year was a typical dividing point, and China&#39;s economy was about to enter a new upward cycle. If at this time, a highly regarded book tells you that there are traces to follow in the future, then no matter what Whether it is for psychological or financial reasons, of course there will be demand.&quot; Zhao Jiamin recalled to &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot;. In the Chinese translation, the subtitle of the book was changed from &quot;The New Biology of Machines, Social Systems, and the Economic World&quot; to &quot;The Ultimate Fate and Outcome of All Humanity.&quot; Today, Zhao Jiamin still laments that the timing of publication is rare but cannot be sought, &quot;If it had been published a year earlier, it would probably have been unknown. A year late, the moment before dawn has been missed again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Out of Control&quot; &quot;After the publication, Kelly came to China for a week to participate in publicity. Zhao Jiamin described Kelly as one of the few foreign authors he had ever seen who was &quot;especially cooperative&quot;. The publishing team arranged more than a dozen interviews and five or six speeches for Kelly, which he readily accepted and gave his all. Relying on this round of intensive publicity, Kelly gained his first batch of readers in China and was able to establish his reputation among relevant practitioners, scholars who are sensitive to new technologies, and the media. It was precisely with this foreshadowing that &quot;Out of Control&quot; was able to catch another &quot;express train&quot; soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2012, Kelly went to China again. At the Tencent Beijing Clubhouse, talking side by side with Kelly was Tencent CEO Ma Huateng. The latter ranked fourth on the Forbes China Rich List that year. Since 2010, Tencent has been locked in the &quot;3Q war&quot; with Qihoo 360. Just ten days before this conversation took place, both parties announced that they would file lawsuits against the other party for their unethical behavior and abuse of market dominance during the 3Q war. According to Zhao Jiamin&#39;s recollection, Tencent was in urgent need of finding a suitable guest speaker to raise its voice in this public opinion war. Zhao Jiamin recommended Kelly, &quot;He was one of the few choices at the time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the conversation, Ma Huateng said that practitioners, including himself, were &quot;like frogs at the bottom of a well&quot; and &quot;trapped in a certain limited range.&quot; Inside, there is no way to globally observe the changes in the entire industry and the entire environmental ecology.&quot; We hope to get &quot;more forward-looking guidance&quot; from Kelly. The dialogue between the two parties covered topics such as corporate management, monopoly, personal privacy and Internet mobility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this &quot;peak dialogue between the &#39;Future Emperor&#39; and the &#39;Product Emperor&#39;&quot; promoted by the media, Kelly and his &quot;Out of Control&quot; became famous in China. Zhao Jiamin recalled to &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that the sales of &quot;Out of Control&quot; jumped from a few thousand copies at the end of the previous year to tens of thousands. &quot;As a &#39;big book&#39;, this number is far beyond expectations.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Prophet&quot;, &quot;Prophet&quot;, &quot;Godfather&quot;...the titles superimposed in front of Kelly&#39;s Chinese name are becoming more and more abundant. The popularity across the ocean surprised Kelly at the time. &quot;Although the sales of this book in the United States are getting better and better, it is far behind that in China. There is little competition among books of the same type. At that time, China&#39;s Internet had just begun. At first, I was surprised that so many people could find resonance in my book.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Invitations to speak came one after another. In 2014, Kelly was invited to attend the Zhejiang Entrepreneurs Conference. In the previous two conferences, the invited foreign guests were Jim Rogers, a well-known investor who has long been optimistic about China, and John Nesbitt, the author of &quot;Megatrends&quot;. &quot;You have to believe in the impossible. The greatest product in 20 years has not yet been invented!&quot; Kelly sounded encouraging at the end of his hour-and-a-half speech. Then, four words appeared on the huge screen - &quot;You are not late (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s not too late to act now)&lt;/span>;! &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Kelly had published many works such as &quot;What Technology Wants&quot; in China. He is still diligent in promoting. After leaving the large-scale business event with security personnel in Hangzhou, he rushed to Shanghai the next day to attend a book signing in a bookstore and talk to dozens of readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of Kelly&#39;s invited public speeches are about trends, which has always been his biggest selling point in China. In 2016, &quot;Inevitability&quot; was published in China. In the book, he listed &quot;12 inevitable technological forces&quot; that &quot;will shape the next 30 years&quot;. &quot;When our use of technology is close to the trajectory preferred by technology, we will be able to manage complexity, optimize interests and减少科技带来的伤害方面更加得心应手。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和许多知名的未来学者一样，凯利在序言里强调，“这些力量并非命运，而是轨迹。”不过，这并不影响拿到该书全球首发权的“逻辑思维”在宣传文案中称其“预言了未来30年哪些领域会出现重大的财富机会”。公开信息显示，该书纸质版首发第一个月的销量超过10万册。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《失控》在国内名气最大，《技术想要什么》被凯文视作自己思想的集大成，而《必然》则是应用这套方法论所做的输出。”在赵嘉敏看来，凯利作品最大的价值并非预测，而是提供了一套将机器、系统、生物和社会等复杂领域相融合的技术哲学框架，“从这个意义上说，这些书到今天也并不过时，人类对技术和人性的认知依然充满了混乱和矛盾。但相比晦涩的哲学，大多数人的期待会更功利化——先人一步看到未来。这也无可厚非。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/B1k8KBSpzTnQT9Ec4mCteOlBadSv8RZaQUdpKRda.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/B1k8KBSpzTnQT9Ec4mCteOlBadSv8RZaQUdpKRda.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;赵嘉敏&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;新课题&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;受新冠疫情影响，凯利上次到访中国还是四年前。截至2023年9月初，他生活的旧金山直飞上海的航班每周仅有两班。 “以前每天都有好几班，”凯利有些感慨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国交通部2023年8月发布的公告称，自9月1日起，允许中方航司每周执行18对中美直飞往返客运航班，并自10月29日起增加至每周24对（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;注：8月这一数字仅为12&lt;/span>;）。不过，据航空数据分析公司Cirium（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;睿思誉）&lt;/span>;的数据，2023年10月中国航空业的国际航班运力整体水平为疫情前的54.7%；“十一”期间，日韩和中欧航线恢复较快，而中美间航班较2019年仍维持在非常低的水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通常情况，来华航班上会有更多外国人。这次我没有特别留意，但机上似乎大多是中国面孔。”凯利向《南方人物周刊》回忆起一天前的机上见闻。 9月11日抵达上海的那个晚上，他专门去了外滩，过去印象中常有的景观照明主题光影秀没有上演，但熟悉的人气依旧扑面而来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯利来上海的几日，正值第34届上海旅游节前夕。部分主干道两侧悬挂着宣传标语——“走进美好与欢乐”。 2023年上半年，上海文旅消费市场在全国率先呈现加速复苏态势，全市接待国内游客1.39亿人次，实现国内旅游收入1550.19亿元，同比增长均超过100%。与之相对的是上半年入境游客数量仅124万人次，不到2019年的13%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如6月同样时隔四年再度访华的比尔·盖茨所说，“四年之久，世界已发生巨变。”离开外滩熙熙攘攘的人群，凯利发现自己正置身于另一重语境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了应邀参加2023ESG全球领导者大会，凯利此行的另一项重要任务是宣传自己的新书《宝贵的人生建议》。 68岁生日那天，凯利开始动笔为他的子女写下一些人生建议。之后的几年间，他不断写下新的，“从压缩和解压缩中得到乐趣”，并最终挑出了500条集合成册。和需要字斟句酌的大部头迥异，这本两百来页的小册子更符合碎片化时代“短平快”的大众阅读旨趣，似乎人人都能从中获取几分共鸣、启发，抑或缓释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月12日晚，我穿过排队买书的人群到达会场时，距离6点半活动正式开始还有5分钟。可以容纳七百余人的阅剧场已有七成满。我坐在会场中部，左边是一个怀抱粉色星黛露毛绒背包的女生，她正拿着凯利的新书自拍；右边是一个穿着深蓝色polo衫的中年男子，和一个约莫三四年级的小学生；前方是一个挽着白色发髻的老妇人，一个急着往嘴里塞着西红柿的年轻女人，和一个穿着白花红底夏威夷风短袖衬衫的年轻男人；过道里，还有一个抱着几个月大婴儿的年轻爸爸在来回走动。尽管是工作日兼下雨天，但一个小时后，会场几乎坐满。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这场持续一个半小时的对话里，许是照应新书主题，“躺平”成了嘉宾和现场提问者提及最多的共性话题。事实上，对于这个词，凯利并不陌生。在当日稍早的一场媒体采访中，他已经跟记者学会了这个中文词汇的准确发音。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我每晚都躺平。”在回答主持人、中国人民大学新闻学院讲师董晨宇关于“美国的年轻人是否会&#39;躺平&#39;”的问题时，凯利打趣道。他接着提及了自己的经历，“20世纪60年代，我经历过嬉皮士运动，那时年轻人&#39;躺平&#39;是对既有制度的反抗。从某种意义上，&#39;躺平&#39;并非无价值。我经常鼓励人们在年轻时做一些与社会定义的成功毫无关联的事，做一些&#39;浪费时间&#39;、没有即时回报的事情。这些经历将成为你日后人生的缪斯。当然，你终有一天需要站起来，因为只有创造新的才是对旧的反抗。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;话题没能轻易结束。在稍后的提问环节，一个看起来二十岁出头的女性观众再度提问，“年轻人应该如何应对&#39;卷也卷不动，躺也躺不平&#39;的现状？”全场爆笑。在两名主持人长达数分钟的接力翻译后，我并不确定凯利是否能理解这个被翻来覆去表述的问题背后的纠结与曲折。凯利试图表达与矛盾相处的必然性。 “所以我应该接受现状是么？”女生总结道，隐入又一片笑声中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对话结束后，我随人群散去。几个40岁上下的男士聚在一起讨论着对谈和提问环节“未能尽兴”。相比“人生箴言”，他们显然对凯利的“科技预言”更感兴趣。我把这些“技术粉”的反馈说给赵嘉敏听。 “70、80后大多是通过《失控》粉上凯文的，包括我在内的很多人技术思想体系的建立多少受到他的影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年荏苒。 《财经十一人》在《中国独角兽锐减：无奈与生机》中写道，中国现存的头部独角兽公司大多成立于2012年左右，创业门槛较低的移动互联网曾是最好的独角兽赛道，然而随着移动互联网红利期的结束以及大环境等的变化，那些促成独角兽诞生的必要因素正在减弱甚至消失，如今投资依然强劲的是机器人、半导体和ESG（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;环境、社会和公司治理&lt;/span>;）等领域。人们必须适应新的周期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵嘉敏能理解不同群体、不同人生阶段关注点的差异，这何尝不是对焦虑的不同应对。有的人期望在“未来地图”上觅得先机；有的人苦于在“卷”“躺”中内耗，希望在智者箴言中求得定力。就像凯利在《宝贵的人生建议》中所说的，“我的这些建议并不是法则。它们就像帽子。假如一顶不合适，试试另一顶。”人们在不停地“试帽子”，因为日子永远向前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位知名的未来学者曾这样定位自己的角色——“促进有关未来的复杂对话，激发他人思考不可思议的事情，挑战他们对过去、现在和未来的偏见和假设。”从这个意义上看，时隔四年，凯文·凯利这位71岁的美国未来学者会发现，他曾经熟悉的、昂扬的中国读者正赋予他更为棘手的难题。毕竟，“必然”的内在趋势或许有迹可循，而如何疗愈“失控”的当下，没人能给出准确的答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djjsGL5twqf7s0xD4VNzPkUj7j89ZDG6eKEKuy89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djjsGL5twqf7s0xD4VNzPkUj7j89ZDG6eKEKuy89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017年5月15日，凯文·凯利（左）在浙江机器人产业集团奇点机器人体验馆观看机器人操作&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;谈论方向，而非目的地&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你工作中最有趣的部分是什么，最具挑战性的又是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我没有传统意义上的“职业生涯”。我非常幸运，一直都沿着自己兴趣的阶梯攀爬。我是自己的老板，能掌控自己的时间，能实现这点就是世界上最富有的人之一了。最具挑战的是如何充分利用这一优势，创造只有我能创造的东西。就像我在《宝贵的人生建议》中写的，“不要做最好的，做唯一的。”我不想把有限的时间花在他人都能做到的事情上。要弄明白自己的相对优势是很困难的，对年轻人尤其如此。年轻时，找不到确切答案不要紧，你可以朝着这个方向努力。这也是我喜欢谈论方向而非目的地的原因。或许你永远不会到达目的地，但你可以一直朝着它前进。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从20到27岁，你作为独立摄影师，足迹遍布十几个亚洲国家和地区，经济拮据，居无定所。如果有时空信使告诉那时的你，未来你会成为一名未来学家，你会如何反应？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是一个非常好的问题。天哪，（如果真的那样，）我可能不会相信这位信使的话。如果我知道了，很可能会受到诱惑，不再那么频繁地旅行，而现在的我恰恰希望那段年轻时光里能多一些旅行。我越想越觉得不知道未来是件好事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对未来的未知成就了现在的你。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我想是的。你会选择在当下知晓60岁的生活状态么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;实话是我并不那么好奇，也缺乏勇气。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;明白。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;怎么看待那段漫长的异国漂泊对你的塑造？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果没有经历在亚洲的一切，我可能会成为一个完全不同的人。我亲眼目睹对新技术的运用给那里人们的生活带来的巨变，见证了那些无法养活自己的第三世界国家步入全球最富有的国家之列。那段经历培养了我的乐观主义精神，让我能以更自信的方式谈论科技，并非从纯技术层面，而是从技术文化的角度，这也成了我的独特之处。你的独特之处不仅基于你的才能、兴趣和习惯，也源于你的经历。所以，二十多岁是做一些不寻常的、奇怪的、大胆的、有风险的、无法解释的、无利可图的事情的最佳时机。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Rsys9OtcHHcniWm2MPlduoBfiybFRq8zST6H3dD0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Rsys9OtcHHcniWm2MPlduoBfiybFRq8zST6H3dD0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;凯文·凯利在新书签售活动现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（中信出版集团/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;乐观正成为稀缺品&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最初是什么启发你写《失控》？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我很早（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985年前后&lt;/span>;）就接触到互联网。 1987年，我听说洛斯阿拉莫斯会举行首届人工生命研讨会。那场研讨会涉及计算机、人工生命、生物学和控制论等领域的交叉，是一个奇怪的混合体。我在其他地方从未见到过这种会议，我知道自己绝对不能错过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我囊中羞涩。买完机票后，已经负担不起酒店了。研讨会持续了三四天。我白天泡在会场，晚上就去附近的露营地过夜。研讨会共举办了约60场演讲，我全部都参加了，演讲的内容非常新颖有趣。后来，我将每场演讲的关键信息整理好后，发布在互联网上。虽然受众群不大，但反响非常热烈，于是我萌生了要写一本技术融合的书。这是我的第一本书。我从1990年开始写作，完成花了大约三年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在经济快速增长期，人们对未来饱含憧憬，更乐于听取未来学者的见解和预测。然而，刚从疫情中走出，全球经济又面临下行风险，相比未来，许多年轻人会更关注眼前，或者说只有能力顾及眼前。这种变化如何影响你所在的行业？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;关于未来，人们已经有太多压抑的想象，乐观反而成了稀缺品，这也让我更有动力去提供一个乐观的视角，或许我的乐观叙事能提供一条不同的前路。 1980年代，我还年轻，当时的美国经历了严重的经济衰退，很多人失去工作和房产。当衰退出现时，我们需要辨别：挫折是不是暂时的？是政治还是技术因素造成的？是实质性衰退还是技术性衰退？ ……每一代人都会经历起伏，但这些终将过去。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/C0YJuYxf4sn2Mhn2XYLHSbltd8mMaqFqRbWaAtRj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/C0YJuYxf4sn2Mhn2XYLHSbltd8mMaqFqRbWaAtRj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;凯文·凯利在新书签售活动现场给读者签名留念&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（中信出版集团/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;未来学者需要在准确性和可信度之间找到某种平衡&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;人们对未来学者最常见的误解是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;试想回到十年前，如果有人跟你说2023年会是一番什么景象，你很可能不会相信，因为未来常常显得不那么合理。可如果没人相信，就算做出了准确的预测，又有什么意义呢？未来学者需要在准确性和可信度之间找到某种平衡。你努力描绘的未来图景既要准确、对他人有帮助，又要看起来合理。同时满足这些要求并不容易，所以未来学者常陷入无法取胜的困局中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的策略是？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我并非要准确地预测未来，而是从场景出发来想象未来的可能性范围，甄别什么不可能发生也是重要的一环。我看重的是对科技趋势的理解，而非预测准确的终点。当然，我也接受一个事实——误判是大概率事件。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人类既是技术的创造者也是被创造者&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;乐观是这份职业的必需吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;应该说我想成为一个乐观的未来主义者，但乐观并非成功的必要条件。很多科幻电影也属于未来主义范畴，但大多是悲观的、反乌托邦的，它们不仅票房大卖，也收获了广泛的文化影响力。就像看完《终结者》系列，自然会忧心人工智能未来发展的致命后果。太多的人将太多的精力用于提前预演各种可怕的事情，这可能会让积极的预演显得不可实现。这也是为什么我会努力去描绘百年后人类世界的图景，我希望呈现一个我自己愿意身处其中的未来世界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;乐观并不意味着忽视那些技术发展的“副作用”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们很难完全屏蔽技术的弊端，所以我倾向从整体看问题。只要技术每年带来的积极效应比负面效应多出1%或2%，即便这点微小的进步在当下极易被忽视，但随着几十年甚至几个世纪的复利叠加，这种渐进式改进便汇成了人类文明的演进。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类既是技术的创造者也是被创造者，由此带来的紧张将一直存在。我的乐观并非因为问题比我们想象中小，而是因为人类解决问题的能力比我们想象的大。解决技术带来的问题不能靠减少技术，而是更好的技术。如果你现在只有一个不大高明的想法，解决方案绝不是停止思考，而是继续思考，直到更好的主意涌现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不过，人类并不平等地享有技术红利如何使用的决策权，所以那些消极预演也为决策者敲响必要的警钟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;ChatGPT掀起新一轮AI热潮，也引发了广泛讨论。你如何看待围绕AI伦理的争议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;将道德准则通过代码编入AI系统中并不困难，挑战在于对AI应当遵循哪些伦理准则，人们尚未达成共识。大模型是基于大量数据训练的，这些数据的最初生产者是普罗大众。大模型作为人类“平均水平”的结果，不可避免地会表现出偏见和刻板印象。人们希望AI能比普通人更好，但我们并不清楚“比我们更好”的道德和价值标准是什么，我们甚至连“我们”是谁都定义不清。要让AI变得比“我们”更好是个巨大的工程，但我们必须有答案。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;普通人能从未来学家的思维方式中学到什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;凯文·凯利：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;世界是在不断变化和发展的，人的一生中会经历足够多的变化，你必须为变化做好准备。所以其实每个人都应当成为未来学家，因为这项任务无法全由他人代劳。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从非洲法郎到维和驻军：法国如何维持在法语非洲的影响力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259073]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年7月26日，尼日尔发生军事政变，尼政变领袖、前总统卫队长废黜总统巴祖姆，停止对法出口铀矿石，双方谈判失败后，法国总统马克龙宣布将在今年年底前撤出在尼全部驻军。这对前几年法国政府提出的“重返非洲”战略，会有多大影响呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要对其做出预判，就得先了解非洲地缘政治中的“法语非洲”和“非洲法郎”概念。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“法语非洲”和“非洲法郎”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为老牌殖民主义大国，法国在巅峰时期曾拥有近1300万平方公里殖民地，在英国之后位居第二。其殖民地主要在非洲，曾一度占领了非洲总面积37%，如此广大的非洲地区，以法语为官方语言，被称为“法语非洲”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二战后，“反殖民主义”运动在全球兴起，法国曾派出军队武装镇压印度支那、阿尔及利亚的独立运动。战争失败后，法国认识到“殖民主义”大势已去，遂顺应了这一历史潮流，前法国殖民地纷纷独立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从1960年代开始，英、法的殖民体系全面瓦解，在“后殖民主义时代”，老牌殖民帝国与第三世界前殖民地之间的关系，在国际政治层面逐渐进入平等时代。当然，由于经济、科技、文化、社会、生活等其它方面的发展不均等，在国际商贸方面，西方国家拥有市场优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1945年12月，法国政府发行“法属非洲殖民地法郎”，非洲各法属殖民地在法国财政部设立“业务账户”，将外汇全部存入该账户。“法国法郎”与“非洲法郎”之间固定兑换比为1∶1.7。截至1949年，法国通过金融手段，控制了非洲殖民地80%出口额、75%进口额。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1958年9月，法国制定《第五共和国宪法》，把“法兰西联邦”改为“法兰西共同体”。“共同体”各成员国在内政、经济等方面享有自主权，但外交、国防等仍由法国控制。1960年以后，“共同体”内12国先后独立。1961年，“共同体”参议院宣布解体。此后，法国以双边条约、贸易协定、“联系国”等形式，与原共同体成员国保持较为密切的双边关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国的殖民体系瓦解后，法属非洲国家相继独立。新生的非洲国家联合起来，与法国政府进行谈判。这些刚独立的法属非洲国家，于1962年组成了“西非国家货币联盟”，1972年成立了“中非国家银行”，由这两个央行系统来统一发行这些新生国家的法定货币。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西非法郎（FCFA）：贝宁、布基纳法索、科特迪瓦、几内亚比绍、马里、尼日尔、塞内加尔、多哥等8个国家组成“西非经济货币联盟”，发行的货币称为“非洲金融共同体法郎”（俗称“西非法郎”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中非法郎（CFAF）：喀麦隆、中非、刚果（布）、加蓬、赤道几内亚、乍得等6个国家组成“中部非洲经济与货币共同体”，称为“非洲金融合作法郎”（俗称“中非法郎”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“非洲法郎区”覆盖撒哈拉以南15个非洲国家（印度洋上的岛国科摩罗，单独发行科摩罗法郎），约1.55亿人口。“西非法郎”与“中非法郎”汇率相等，但不能相互流通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年，法国发行新法郎（Nouveau Franc），确定其币值为旧法郎的100倍，相当于0.1802克含金量。法国法郎与非洲法郎之间的固定兑换比为1∶50。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1980-1990年代，非洲经济发展长期缓慢、停滞，甚至严重倒退，各国财政赤字猛增、通货膨胀严重、债务问题加剧。全球金融界普遍认为“非洲法郎”估值过高，在“世界银行”和“国际货币基金组织（IMF）”干预下，1994年，“法国法郎”与“非洲法郎”之间的固定兑换比，调整为1∶100。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1999年1月，“欧盟”承认法国与非洲法郎区的货币合作协议，批准“非洲法郎”正式与即将发行的欧元挂钩，固定汇率为（非洲法郎:欧元）655.957∶1。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;政治独立Vs经济或货币“依附”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这些前法属非洲国家既然已实现政治独立，为何非要在经济，尤其是货币方面与法国紧密联系？原因是：这些非洲国家的社会结构和经济发展落后，其国民经济完全依赖法国。现代货币，不再是金本位、银本位或双本位贵金属定义的实体货币，而演变成国家信用符号。缺乏信用的纸币，不会得到国际社会认可，该地区的经济就会崩溃。而货币崩溃后，往往在很短时间内就会发生社会大动荡，甚至恐怖大饥荒、血腥内战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此非洲国家发行的“西非法郎、中非法郎”不得不继续与法郎挂钩，靠法郎的国际货币地位提供信用背书，才保持了这些国家独立后几十年的大致稳定，对那里的百姓而言，更朴实的作用是较稳定的“非洲法郎”能买到粮食，有饭吃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，法国利用法郎与“非洲法郎”之间的关系，从中获利颇丰，对二战后法国的战后重建与经济复兴，起到了重要作用。同时，“法语非洲”的黑人，也能利用自己手中的“非洲法郎”与法国法郎兑换的优势，前往法国学习、经商，产生了大批接受法国思想与文化、说法语的“非洲精英”。这使法国在“法语非洲”占有很大的思想、文化、政治、经济优势。与此同时，法国近6800万人口中，有近800万黑人（含非法移民），占比近12%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在长期合作过程中，法、非双方相互妥协：“西非国家中央银行”“中非国家中央银行”的总部，由巴黎分别迁至非洲的达喀尔、雅温得。联盟成员国将外汇存在法国央行的比例从100%调整到65%。“西非央行”董事会7人，法国董事减为2人；“中非央行”董事会12人，法国董事减到3人，大大降低了法国权重，增加了非洲权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1973年，法国与“西非货币联盟”签署《货币合作协议》，确定货币合作四原则：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、刚性兑换原则，法国确保“西非法郎”的兑换刚性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、固定平价原则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三、自由流动原则，在“西非货币联盟”内部资金流动不受限制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四、外汇储备集中管理原则，西非国家外汇储备存入法国央行的比例，下调到50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“非洲法郎”背后，法郎的国际货币地位、信用背书、法国政府的支持（尤其是法国承诺“西非法郎”兑换刚性），对中非、西非经济的保驾护航，对维持前法属非洲地区的社会稳定存续，起到了重要作用。1970年代，这些非洲国家的日子过得还算凑合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1999年以后，当欧元诞生、法国法郎退出历史舞台后，“非洲法郎”转而与欧元以固定汇率挂钩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;依托法郎与欧元的长期稳定，即使在非洲其他地区战乱四起、政变频繁、社会危机此起彼伏的动荡时代，“非洲法郎”仍保持坚挺币值。这对“法语非洲”国家维持政府存续，在非洲各地持续不断的战乱政变、经济危机、社会动荡中生存下来，起到了至关重要的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与非洲其他地区相比，“非洲法郎区”避免了因货币滥发引起的通货膨胀，维持了货币信用和稳定。2014-2017年间，全球通胀率在2.8%-3.2%之间，撒哈拉以南（“非洲法郎区”以外）通胀率从6.3%飙升到11.3%。而“非洲法郎区”的通胀率则始终保持在0.7%-1.7%之间。凭借良好的货币信誉，“非洲法郎”保持了世界上存续时间最长的固定汇率机制之纪录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994年，中非国家成立“中非经济与货币联盟共同体”，除货币联盟、经济联盟以外，还设立了共同体议会、共同体法院。2000年，西非各国以西非法郎为纽带，组成了经济共同体，逐步消除联盟内部的贸易壁垒、统一关税，实现经济上的共进退。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;法国在非洲的驻军&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“冷战”结束后，意识形态冲突让位于亨廷顿所谓“文明冲突”，“法语非洲”亦不例外。大国争霸背景下的文明冲突，甚至威胁到很多非洲国家政权的存亡。2012年，马里政府军被反政府武装打得节节败退，马里政府万般无奈，只好请前宗主国法国出兵援救，2013年，法军展开“薮猫行动”，将反政府武装赶入马里北部沙漠，帮助马里政府夺回了大部分领土。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前法国在“法语非洲”展开的军事行动，并非两个世纪之前“强权即真理”的殖民主义军事侵略，而是在现代国际法框架内的维稳性联盟军事行动。这类行动的特点是：需要合法政府发出正式邀请。如果所在地政权不同意外国军队继续驻扎，法军就得撤出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法军从尼日尔撤出，就是这类军事行动的范例：法军之前是应尼日尔合法政府邀请，前来“反恐”（维稳）。但尼日尔发生了军事政变，现政权合法性虽不足，但其发出逐客令，法军只好撤出。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;从西非法郎到埃科？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;法国考虑到古代的“殖民主义”一去不复返了，所谓“重返非洲”战略是指法国以现代化社会形态，重新构建与“法语非洲”在平等基础上的新国家间关系。其中首重货币，而法国做出的重大决策，是支持“法语非洲”的货币改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年12月21日，法国总统马克龙与“西非经济与货币联盟”主席达成一致，宣布准备废除“西非法郎”，2020年使用新货币“Eco（埃科）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次货币改革主要有三大变化：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、废除西非法郎，使用新货币Eco。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、西非央行不再将50%外汇上交法国管理，可自由配置外汇组合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三、法国撤回并不再向“西非经济货币联盟”银行机构派驻代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，“西非法郎”改革为Eco后维持两个“不变”：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一：Eco依然与欧元挂钩，维持655.957∶1固定汇率不变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二：法国对西非国家的承诺不变，如未来出现危机，可提供外汇支援。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次“西非法郎”改革，是法国“重返非洲”战略的重要举措之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国目的在于推动“西非法郎区”实行经济一体化，以便吸收法郎区之外的尼日利亚、加纳等国家加入。作为这一新的经济合作区之原创发起者与担保者，法国将在该货币联盟中具有最大话语权，成为非洲廉价劳动力和丰富自然资源的最大受益者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对“西非法郎区”国家来说：掌握货币发行权，顺应了其国内的“金融民族主义”思潮，有利于增加政府声誉、维护政权存续。而西非国家多数面积不大、经济体量较小，区域内没有经济强国为实行统一货币作担保支撑，所以必须依靠法国支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未来，联盟外国家（尼日利亚、加纳）若能够满足一定的经济及其它条件，Eco不排除吸引其加入的可能性，进而建立一个更大范围的货币联盟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很显然：法国的目标，重点在尼日利亚。尼日利亚不但有丰富的石油资源，且人口已超过2亿，保持着全世界最高生育率。有学者预测：到21世纪晚期，尼日利亚人口可能达到7亿左右，在某些学派看来“人口红利”巨大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据协议，新货币Eco发行，需要各国达到一定的经济指标为门槛，譬如：财政赤字不超过GDP的3%、通胀在10%以内、公共负债不超GDP的70%等，对这些国家仍是考验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2022年，“西非法郎区”国家和法国官方均未宣布Eco具体推进时间表。受“新冠”疫情影响，西非国家财政收入锐减、公共开支大幅攀升、财政赤字高企，无法达到之前预设的门槛，新货币的发行将被推迟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国政府在“法语非洲”和“非洲法郎区”下的这盘大棋，当然是考虑到法国利益。但这是“后殖民主义”时代的一种新安排，法国一方面维持了在这些地方的影响力，但另一方面也要出钱出力出信用，一些国家不愿意这样跟法国玩了，法国也得乖乖退出，所以法国总体上是“大哥”或“共主”的角色，有小弟不鸟这个“大哥”或不认这个“共主”，法国也没法像过去那样用强。故而我们要以新思维、新观念、新方法去审视与研究这一现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海漄获雨果奖，系刘慈欣、郝景芳之后中国科幻作家第三人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259098]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;中国作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得最佳短中篇小说奖。这也是雨果奖首次在中国揭晓和颁奖。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/890e411a0bc2df8e6f187aeaac28442c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/890e411a0bc2df8e6f187aeaac28442c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254858&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10月21日，中国作家海漄（中）创作的《时空画师》获最佳短中篇小说奖。新华社记者王曦摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;记者了解到，本届雨果奖提名阶段，超25000部科幻作品（个人）参与了提名，共收到1800多个有效提名，最终评选出包括最佳短篇小说、最佳长篇小说、最佳戏剧表现（短片）、最佳戏剧表现（长片）等在内的17类雨果奖奖项和2类非雨果奖奖项。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;中国作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得最佳短中篇小说奖。最佳短篇小说奖由《兔子测试》获得，最佳长中篇小说奖由《溺水女孩之谜》获得，最佳长篇小说奖由《荨麻和骨头》获得。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/e9ccd12cac7c50f12150cb54bcced58b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/e9ccd12cac7c50f12150cb54bcced58b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254857&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;这是10月21日在成都拍摄的2023雨果奖颁奖典礼现场。新华社记者王曦摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[林旭东谈中国纪录片三十年：不只说发生了什么，还要讲到为什么]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259084]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022480207789&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;林旭东谈中国纪录片三十年：不只说发生了什么，还要讲到为什么.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/06970e325576678022480207789/wTaELxEhscgA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/06970e325576678022480207789/wTaELxEhscgA.mp3&quot;>;林旭东谈中国纪录片三十年：不只说发生了什么，还要讲到为什么.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;点击播放本期播客↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;单集介绍&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大家好，欢迎来到有点文化，我是本期主播一兰，本期播客我们聊一聊关于纪录片的话题。今天我们邀请到的是中国纪录片背后的大神林旭东教授，来跟我们聊一聊中国纪录片的发展史。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林旭东老师是学画画出身的，他曾两度策划了1990年代末在北京举办的世界纪录片大师的座谈会，并直接介入了多部民间纪录片的筹划、制作和批评。可以说，林老师是1990年代以来中国纪录片的活历史、亲历者和见证者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/xfO55HO1lh6JyC3e6XjTdTd1ozUgHvgYjCo0igWH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/xfO55HO1lh6JyC3e6XjTdTd1ozUgHvgYjCo0igWH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254827&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;从1990年算起，中国独立纪&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[他见证了英格兰足球最跌宕的历史丨博比·查尔顿去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/J2BQzh86HBeKMLNZVPGwCCPeFiZDNCEHpLQ5uNlo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/J2BQzh86HBeKMLNZVPGwCCPeFiZDNCEHpLQ5uNlo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;曼联俱乐部官方媒体社交账号&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间10月21日，英超曼联俱乐部在社交媒体发布讣告，英国足球名宿、曼联传奇球星博比·查尔顿爵士逝世，享年86岁。他是最后一位去世的“慕尼黑空难”幸存球员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出生于1937年、1976年正式退役的博比·查尔顿，职业生涯荣誉满身。他代表曼联出战758场，打进249球，数次捧起英格兰顶级联赛冠军奖杯，他也是英格兰队夺取1966年世界杯的核心球员。他攻守兼备，球风强硬但不粗野，被称为“足坛绅士”。他还是足球史上极少数同时拥有世界杯冠军奖杯、欧冠奖杯和金球奖的球员之一，集齐了国家队、俱乐部和个人三大层面的最高荣誉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在曼联俱乐部的145年历史上，曾涌现众多球星，但要说史上第一传奇，绝大多数球迷都会将票投给博比·查尔顿。他也被视为“天选之子”，作为曼联俱乐部“慕尼黑空难”的幸存者，他不但战胜了命运、战胜了自己，还成为曼联走出阴霾的最关键人物。这不仅仅是运气，更是努力的见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;足球世家的天才少年，人生面临空难这道坎&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;博比·查尔顿1937年10月11日出生于英国诺森伯兰郡，他的家族堪称足球世家：父亲和叔叔都是享誉当地的球员，哥哥杰克·查尔顿后来更是成为利兹联队名宿，也是1966年世界杯英格兰队的主力中卫。博比·查尔顿12岁时进入曼联少年队，1954年正式转为职业球员，并随曼联青年队连续夺得三届英格兰青年足总杯冠军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1956年，博比·查尔顿上演曼联一线队首秀。在这场对阵查尔顿队的比赛中，他打入两球，光速般在一线队站稳脚跟，并随队获得1956—1957赛季的联赛冠军。但随后而来的，便是慕尼黑空难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1958年2月6日是曼联俱乐部历史上的至暗时刻。当时，曼联在欧洲冠军杯1/4决赛次回合中，客场对阵南斯拉夫劲旅贝尔格莱德红星队，双方3-3战平，曼联以两回合5-4的总比分晋级。比赛结束后，曼联队员、部分球迷和跟队记者等计划搭乘航班返回英国，但当时的飞机还无法支撑贝尔格莱德至英格兰的直飞航程，中途要在慕尼黑停留加油。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/UMm4zpLGNVn3UBqxNVyDhZrjABZeOx6dlzbTk39u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/UMm4zpLGNVn3UBqxNVyDhZrjABZeOx6dlzbTk39u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1966年7月30日，英国伦敦，英格兰世界杯决赛英格兰队以4比2战胜联邦德国队，博比·查尔顿高举雷米特杯庆祝&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果，休整后的飞机在慕尼黑机场连续两次因引擎出现问题而起飞失败，在第三次起飞时，飞机因积雪导致失控，撞开围栏并撞向一座建筑，随后断为两截，一侧机身与装满燃料的卡车碰撞后发生爆炸。机上44人中有23人不幸遇难，其中包括年仅21岁的天才球星邓肯·爱德华兹、球队队长罗杰·拜恩等多名球员。除此之外，还有两位球员因伤势而彻底告别球场。博比·查尔顿受伤，幸运逃过一劫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空难改变了曼联的发展轨迹。自1945年由马特·巴斯比执教以来，曼联蒸蒸日上，众多年轻小将脱颖而出，其中就包括了后来在空难中不幸离世的天才少年邓肯·爱德华兹。球队迅速成长为英格兰足坛强队，先是五年内四夺联赛亚军，又在1952-1957年间三夺联赛冠军。 1957-1958赛季，曼联被视为欧冠大热，但慕尼黑空难让这一切戛然而止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在那个赛季余下的日子里，一度陷入解体流言的曼联没有错过任何一场比赛，靠一批临时上调的年轻球员坚持踢完整个赛季，赢得了人们的尊重。博比·查尔顿也尽最快速度回到了球场上，他所经历的痛苦和磨砺不比任何人少。除了身体的伤痛之外，还有巨大的心灵痛苦。所幸的是，这位当时的曼联新星最终走出了这道坎，成为曼联复兴的关键人物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/pPmFBwTZyrAvHQY9yqBG1ZT16Humc1ZLjlixOV2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;954&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/pPmFBwTZyrAvHQY9yqBG1ZT16Humc1ZLjlixOV2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1963年5月25日，曼联获得足总杯冠军，博比·查尔顿（右二）和队友庆祝&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;慕尼黑空难后曼联复兴的核心&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;慕尼黑空难发生近一年后，马特·巴斯比复出，着手重建球队，他的建队核心正是博比·查尔顿，未来几年中陆续从青年队提拔上来的乔治·贝斯特和丹尼斯·劳等也成为球队重返巅峰的中坚力量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接下来的那个赛季中，曼联队夺得联赛亚军。但直到1963年，它才夺得空难后的第一个冠军——足总杯冠军，决赛的场上球员中，仅有福尔克斯和博比·查尔顿两人曾经历过空难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，曼联正式迎来复兴，于上世纪60年代中期实现三年内两夺联赛冠军，并在1967-1968赛季的欧洲冠军杯决赛中击败葡萄牙本菲卡队，历史上首次夺得欧冠奖杯，博比·查尔顿在比赛中独中两元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一场轮回式的比赛，博比·查尔顿与他的新队友们一起以冠军奖杯告慰那些逝去的队友们。十年前，曼联距离这座冠军奖杯并不算遥远，但空难击碎了他们的梦想甚至生命。而在这一刻，博比·查尔顿完成了自己的救赎和已逝队友们的遗愿。他与巴斯比都割破中指，将鲜血渗入奖杯，一次次将之举起，每举一次就高呼一位逝去队友的名字，这是欧冠历史上最感人的一幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/Ar0dX4OJgRwncPkSgiMFTEP1Xyw9cgXyhkMiIdqC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/Ar0dX4OJgRwncPkSgiMFTEP1Xyw9cgXyhkMiIdqC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1958年2月11日，慕尼黑空难的幸存者博比·查尔顿（左）和雷猛·伍德在医院接受治疗&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后的博比·查尔顿因为年过三旬，渐渐走上职业生涯的下坡路，曼联也逐渐失去竞争力，但他仍是曼联场上的绝对主力，时有抢眼表现。 1972-1973年赛季结束后，博比·查尔顿选择离开。从1956年到1973年，博比·查尔顿将所有青春与激昂都奉献给了曼联队。他为球队踢了758场比赛，打进249个进球，长期保持着这两项球队历史纪录。直至2008年，他的出场次数被另一位忠诚传奇吉格斯打破，而进球纪录要到2017年才被鲁尼打破。他为曼联带来三座联赛冠军，一座足总杯冠军和一座欧冠冠军奖杯。更重要的是，他忠诚且顽强，带着空难后的曼联从废墟中崛起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开曼联后的博比·查尔顿还曾在低级别的普雷斯顿和爱尔兰的沃特福德联队短暂效力，1976年正式退役。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;966年世界杯的冠军队中坚&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;慕尼黑空难后，博比·查尔顿以自己的最快速度回到了俱乐部的战场上。而在那年的4月19日，他已经入选国家队，这是他首次入选，并上演首秀。不过在1958年世界杯上，博比查尔顿始终枯坐板凳席，未有一分钟出场机会。虽然舆论对主教练始终弃用博比·查尔顿表示不满，但主教练沃尔特·温特伯特姆向报刊坦言，自己后悔选择博比·查尔顿进入世界杯最终名单，因为他相信对方依然受到慕尼黑空难的痛苦折磨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1962年世界杯，博比·查尔顿再度入选英格兰队，并以主力身份出战，但球队在复赛时被最终的冠军巴西队淘汰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/rDrwEdcI8gJuqZkXCE2G70ILXFdzRVqtjybVszFg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;629&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/rDrwEdcI8gJuqZkXCE2G70ILXFdzRVqtjybVszFg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1958年2月19日，博比·查尔顿在家附近进行恢复训练&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在英国举行的1966年世界杯，成为博比·查尔顿国家队生涯的最好舞台。此时正值职业巅峰状态的他，是那支英格兰队的核心。球队在半决赛中力克夺冠大热葡萄牙队，博比·查尔顿在比赛中梅开二度。在之后的决赛中，英格兰队更是上演史上最经典的表现，博比·查尔顿作为中场组织者，帮助球队以4-2击败劲旅西德队，夺得冠军。此时的博比·查尔顿已经是当之无愧的核心踢法，尽管他的光芒被上演帽子戏法的赫斯特所遮盖，但懂球的人都知道他对球队的攻防转换是何等关键，他以杰出表现被评为当届世界杯的最佳球员。此外，他还在那一年的金球奖评选中力压葡萄牙巨星“黑豹”尤西比奥，成为继马修斯之后第二位获得金球奖的英格兰球员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1970年世界杯是博比·查尔顿第四次出战世界杯，尽管球队未能进入四强，但查尔顿仍然入选了此届世界杯的最佳阵容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，在1968年的欧锦赛（即欧洲杯）中，博比·查尔顿率队获得季军，这也是英格兰队的欧锦赛历史最佳战绩。同年5月，他在与瑞典的热身赛中打入国家队生涯的第45个进球，超越格里菲斯成为英格兰国家队历史头号射手。 1970年4月21日，查尔顿代表英格兰队第100次出场。从1958年到1970年，博比·查尔顿在国家队生涯中共出场106次，打进49球，进球数字仅次于后来的鲁尼，还有世界杯冠军的加持，作为英格兰国家队史上最佳球员毫无争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/oCjl7vzyXzMkusmysQy7yhFMeHloRWJ78O2ghLa9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/oCjl7vzyXzMkusmysQy7yhFMeHloRWJ78O2ghLa9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1994年5月8日，曼联获得英超冠军，博比·查尔顿和主教练弗格森在更衣室合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;真正的足球绅士&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;曾经发掘中国球员&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1984年，博比·查尔顿重返曼联，成为球队董事，也是球队最好的名片。 1994年，他被英女王授予爵士称号。 2012年，他获得劳伦斯体育终身成就奖，成为获得这一殊荣的第五位足球运动员——截至目前一共有6名足球从业人士获得该奖，另5位是贝利、克鲁伊夫、贝肯鲍尔、齐达内和温格。 2016年，曼联主场老特拉福德球场的南看台被命名为查尔顿爵士看台。在《世界足球》杂志评选的20世纪最伟大球员中，他名列第12位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博比·查尔顿一直致力于足球运动在全球的交流。 1988年，中国国少队前往英国访问，与众多俱乐部的青少年队交手，博比·查尔顿一眼便相中了中国国少队的宿茂臻与吴崇文二人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴崇文有着极快的速度和鬼魅般的跑位，宿茂臻则有模板型的中锋身体和对抗能力，因此博比·查尔顿力邀二人前往曼联试训。可惜的是，二人都在试训期间遭遇伤病，加上中国足球当时的体制原因，使得他们未能留在曼联。归国后，吴崇文很快便泯然众人矣，宿茂臻则成长为中国足球的中坚力量，也是老球迷心目中的男足“第一金头”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宿茂臻接受媒体采访时透露他退役后曾给博比·查尔顿写信、通电话表示想到英国学习，查尔顿爵士和曼联俱乐部非常欢迎，帮他交费安排报名修读英格兰C级教练的课程，给他提供了很多的帮助。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;835&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月21日，英超第9轮比赛，谢菲尔德联1比2不敌曼联。曼联球员在赛前悼念博比·查尔顿&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从个人品行来说，无论是球员时代还是退役之后，博比·查尔顿都堪称完美，甚至被人戏称“完美到了无趣的地步”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为球员，博比·查尔顿看起来并不像典型的英格兰球员，他体形有些单薄，但实际上却有着大能量，从来无惧于对抗。强硬的对抗能力使得他的细腻技术能更好地发挥，他不但勤奋、有灵气，而且无私，是中场球员的完美模板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;835&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/13ZZrWwWS5cAI7qK01CDhInQV4bKUEYqNJQ2lyP4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月21日，英超第9轮比赛，谢菲尔德联1比2不敌曼联。曼联球员在赛前悼念博比·查尔顿&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最可贵的是，在这完美的背后，深藏着无法释怀的巨大伤痛。博比·查尔顿曾在采访中坦言：“我这一生其实永远地定格在了慕尼黑空难那一天，我从来没有走出来过。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“从未走出来过”的他，选择的不是在沉痛中沉沦，而是坚持。他的外表永远友善从容，善待每一个人，是真正的绅士，然后自己抚慰破碎的内心，不与人言。在此期间，与他一起幸免于空难的人一个接一个离去，他也愈发沉默。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到现在，他也离开人世，再也无法出现在老特拉福德球场的看台上。红魔曼联，失去了它最伟大的观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国奶茶圈最早的幕后大佬，还得是平南老表]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257208]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一个常住人口仅有111万的小县城，竟然有26.5万人都在做奶茶，如果你是本地人，至少你会有一位做奶茶生意的亲戚朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个地方就是广西贵港市的平南县，这里平均每5个人中就有1个卖奶茶，在平南师范街，甚至可以做到十米就有一家奶茶店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自1999年平南人在广州开出第一家奶茶店起，奶茶业的“广西帮”便不断崛起。“广西帮”先在广州、佛山学习经验、打开市场，再在平南不断壮大自身实力，最后走向全国各地。2006年，平南人在全国各地开设的新式奶茶店已多达5万多家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;平南奶茶也成为了无数网友的青春载体，有已移居海外的网友，至今还记得高中每天喝一杯“地下铁”薄荷奶茶的味道，也有网友对“大口九”的珍珠奶茶念念不忘，因为它埋藏着与外婆的回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;然而，在现在的平南街头，“地下铁”“大口九”已经让位于喜茶、蜜雪冰城等连锁品牌，连最新崛起的平南本土品牌也走向了漫漫模仿路。平南奶茶协会的品牌名单上，有的品牌logo是爆炸头的喜茶，还有的牌子干脆直接将喜茶logo左右翻转。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在奶茶内卷的大潮中，平南奶茶似乎迷失了。2021年平南奶茶品牌占比22%的市场份额，是顶峰时期的四分之一。外卖平台上平南县热销的奶茶品牌多为全国知名连锁品牌，而平南县推出的奶茶品牌“热力雪”“沁口香柠”等月销量仅有一千多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为了重返巅峰，平南县打出了“奶茶第一县”的招牌，买账的人却并不多，平南县缺少设立奶茶标准的话语权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管平南本土奶茶品牌辉煌不再，“广西帮”的势力仍然雄厚。主打“手作健康饮品，古法现场熬煮”的阿嬷手作被“中产”排队疯抢，还在北京开起了分店，从广西走出的“正宗台湾口味”茶道夫目前也突破了1000家门店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今天，“知道”就跟你聊聊广西老表的奶茶生意经。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/85b007579b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/85b007579b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/2a753ca2a5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/2a753ca2a5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e9357efbca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e9357efbca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251302&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/604971ed08.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/604971ed08.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251303&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/b347cc21c0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/b347cc21c0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251304&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/4afcbd0e5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/4afcbd0e5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当00后涌入老年大学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259069]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022203307773&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;当00后涌入老年大学.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/a4d363e55576678022203307773/KK9Gee1SEBYA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/a4d363e55576678022203307773/KK9Gee1SEBYA.mp3&quot;>;当00后涌入老年大学.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;点击播放本期播客↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/dflDHrQKN93mbx4zvCNoAyYC7vI3m8tbxVSOhmVa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/dflDHrQKN93mbx4zvCNoAyYC7vI3m8tbxVSOhmVa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254824&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;小雨和她的学生们。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听见南腔北调的真故事，遇见南来北往的社会人，南方周末的听众朋友们，你们好，欢迎收听南周播客《社会人》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管退休对于90后、00后来说还很遥远，但已经有不少年轻人去老年大学提前体验了一把：几百元的学费能学半年，舞蹈、钢琴、书法、国画课程应有尽有，而和学校的最大不&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>