<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《横琴方案》发布两周年，数读成绩单丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72646&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69538&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Second Anniversary of the Hengqin Plan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;8301&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250814&quot; style=&quot; &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在“被强奸”漩涡中挣扎八天后，一位44岁农妇选择自杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house hidden under the trees, Yi Yonghong&#39;s self-report of being &quot;raped&quot; The place where the incident occurred. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height =&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house hidden under the trees is where the &quot;rape&quot; incident described by Yoshinaga Hong took place. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 23, 2023, Yi Yonghong decided to commit suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She placed the suicide note on the plastic stool at the head of the bed, and her purse and mobile phone, which she never left, were neatly placed beside the bed. The purse contained more than 3,000 yuan in cash. She locked the door and ignored the clothes in the washing machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m leaving. I don&#39;t know what I can do to make you less hurt... I don&#39;t ask you to forgive me. I just hope that you can live a happy life and forget that I am a bad wife and mother. .&quot; She said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To commit suicide, she chose a mile away. She had to pass through a large guava field. The unripe fruits wrapped in white plastic bags were hung all over the orchard. They were the fruits of her summer. The guava tree is not high, so you have to bend down when walking through it, and you have to cross a drainage ditch in three to five steps. The last section of the road is a slope about two meters high. Climb up and you will reach the embankment. A wide pond with a wide water surface slowly unfolds in front of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The embankment is covered with mimosa, lush and green. The pair of pink slippers were neatly placed on the steps by Yi Yonghong, with the toes facing the pond. A few hours later, her husband Cheng Shanzhi discovered her. She was wearing a red top and floating in a prone position in the middle of the pond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight days before committing suicide, at the age of 44, she reported that she was raped by fruit vendor Huang Mouguan. The police decided not to file the case because the existing evidence could not prove that a crime had occurred. After committing suicide, the police decided to open a case for investigation on September 7 because &quot;new evidence was discovered.&quot; In order to prove that she was raped, she was preserved in an ice coffin and underwent a craniotomy and a thoracotomy for an autopsy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Misfortune in the banana fields&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Typhoon Taili is approaching. Before the violent storm arrived, Yi Yonghong had to cut down more than 20 acres of plantains at home. Nine years ago, this couple from Yongzhou, Hunan, planted fruits on a contracted land in Wenchang, Hainan. Now the contracted land covers nearly 50 acres, half of which is planted with bananas and the other half with guava. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong’s WeChat chat records show that on the evening of July 14, she and Huang Mouguan finalized the time to harvest bananas the next day. Huang Mouguan opened a fruit wholesale stall near the busiest park in Wenchang, and would go to fruit farmers&#39; homes to buy fruit. In the Wenchang area, most of the fruit growers are outsiders who have crossed the Qiongzhou Strait to make a living, and most of the fruit vendors are Hainan locals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong rarely goes out in public to sell bananas, and spends most of his time working in the banana fields. In early 2023, Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband Cheng Shanzhi started doing business with Huang Mouguan after being introduced by a fellow villager. By the time the incident occurred, he had sold bananas to him five times in total, with a transaction volume of 1,480 yuan. In the first two times, Cheng Shanzhi cut down plantains and traded them with Huang Mouguan. Because her husband&#39;s left ankle was seriously cut due to an accident, Yi Yonghong took over the job of cutting plantains for the next three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was these three experiences of selling bananas alone that pushed Yi Yonghong&#39;s life to a point of no return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The banana land contracted by Yi Yonghong and his wife is not close to the village where she rents, and it takes half an hour by electric bicycle. In 2014, they built a shelter house using hollow bricks next to the plantain field. There was no other house within a radius of 200 meters. When we moved out in 2022, there was only a guard dog and a few free-range chickens left there. The unused old house began to fall into dust and became desolate. There was no longer a fire in the kitchen, and no one could sleep on the bed. Except for resting when working, Yi Yonghong rarely came here. The airtight trees almost swallowed up the small house. house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house at the crime scene. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house at the crime scene. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time Yi Yonghong took over for her husband who injured his foot and cut bananas alone with Huang Mouguan was on July 2. To cut bananas, vendors usually go to the fields to select the bananas, and the farmers carry them to the field, where they are finally weighed and loaded onto trucks. Yi Yonghong seems to particularly like pink. She has a short-sleeved shirt of this color, which she wears specially when working. Her right shoulder is covered with dark green glue marks from banana. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong later told her husband that that time, Huang Mouguan took the opportunity to help her carry the banana on his shoulders and touched her breasts. He also said to her: &quot;Don&#39;t do such hard work, I will give you money.&quot; Yi Yonghong refused him: &quot;Don&#39;t say this, we are doing hard work to earn hard money, I am not that Plant people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No more evidence can be obtained for what happened in the banana field. Other merchants next to Huang Mouguan&#39;s fruit shop said they had not seen him for more than a month after the incident. On the afternoon of September 2, Huang&#39;s wife was selling fruit at a stall next to the shop. She was emotional and refused to be interviewed: &quot;You don&#39;t know how much impact they have on our lives. I am under great pressure.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week later, the bananas had to be picked again. Yi Yonghong and Huang Mouguan met again in the deserted banana field with wild vegetation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of meeting seems inevitable: Yoshinaga chooses to endure it, and there are only three &quot;basho bosses&quot; working with them at the same time. One is a very old man who walks a little shaky, and the other boss does not The last one who came to purchase was Huang Mouguan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his wife&#39;s account to Cheng Shanzhi, Huang Mouguan once again committed inappropriate behavior. After the attempt, Huang Mouguan gave Yi Yonghong an extra 100 yuan in addition to 470 yuan in banana money, &quot;My wife just Throw it back to him without asking for it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time was two days before the typhoon arrived. Cheng Shanzhi said that on July 15, Yi Yonghong arrived at the banana field at the agreed time and selected, cut off the backs, weighed and loaded the bananas. After paying the money, a heavy rainstorm suddenly fell from the sky in the afternoon. Yi Yonghong told Huang Mouguan, who had a canopy installed on the car, that he did not have a raincoat and would wait until the rain stopped before leaving, so he asked him to go first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Yi Yonghong entered the house and sat on the bed that she had not slept on for nearly a year to take shelter from the rain. In the subsequent report, Yi Yonghong said that she was raped at that time. Afterwards, Huang Mouguan left 150 yuan and ran away. Two days later, she told her husband that she felt a little uncomfortable after drinking the honey chrysanthemum tea handed to her by Huang Guan that day. She didn&#39;t know whether it was because of the heat stroke or the chrysanthemum tea, but she felt dizzy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Husband and daughter’s questioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If her husband hadn’t found out, Yi Yonghong originally planned to let these things rot in her stomach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision to &quot;hide it&quot; is not difficult to make. In the subsequent on-site recording of the two parties’ contact, Yoshinaga stated that she was worried that if she told her husband what had happened, he would definitely retaliate against him and eventually harm his two children. “I just want to protect this family.” Cheng Shanzhi added that his wife had other considerations, such as the fact that the other party was rich and powerful and she was a wandering migrant; another example was that she was &quot;raped&quot; at the age of 44, which was &quot;disgraceful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong has been covering up the traces of being &quot;raped&quot;. Huang Mouguan forced her to go to bed for the first time. When Yi Yonghong broke away and ran away, her inner thighs were red. When her husband asked, she lied that it was scratched on her back. After the incident, Yi Yonghong fell three times while riding her bike home. After returning home, Cheng Shanzhi saw that she was unhappy, but she didn&#39;t suffer any injuries, so he didn&#39;t take it to heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the night of the incident, Yi Yonghong asked her husband to sleep in her daughter&#39;s spare room, which made Cheng Shanzhi feel something was wrong. After 23 years of marriage, they rarely sleep in separate beds. Later, Yi Yonghong explained to her husband that the reason for dividing the room was that she didn&#39;t know whether Huang Guan was sick and was afraid of infecting him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how much his wife wanted to hide it, Cheng Shanzhi, who was full of doubts, discovered the clues the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As usual, Cheng Shanzhi rides to the banana patch every morning to feed the guard dog. When he opened the door, he found that the pillows on the bed had been touched, and only a small roll of paper towels was left in a large roll that had not been used for a long time. Cheng Shanzhi &quot;immediately suspected that this might happen.&quot; He didn&#39;t buy any groceries, so he hurried to his home in Sanpaipo Village and asked his wife what happened yesterday, but the answer he got was &quot;nothing happened.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that the roll of paper towels was strangely lacking. He thought that he and his wife would use paper towels to wipe after sex, so he continued to press. Until late at night, after questioning still yielded no results, he called his daughter who was working in Haikou during the summer vacation, hoping that her daughter could ask him something. At first, her 22-year-old daughter Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t believe what her father said, but she felt that he was very angry on the phone. She still called her mother and asked, &quot;Have you been bullied by others?&quot; and &quot;Have you done anything like that with others?&quot; Yi Yonghong was silent and crying on the phone for a long time. After asking the two questions several times in turn, Yi Yonghong finally relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yi Yonghong&#39;s daughter returns to her banana field. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/4e271c4134.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e271c4134. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yi Yonghong’s daughter returned to her family’s banana field. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After listening to his wife’s story, Cheng Shanzhi was very angry. He was angry about why his wife didn’t tell him. If he had told him the first or second time, there would have been no such thing. What happened next. He also couldn&#39;t understand why this kind of thing could happen to him. &quot;If you tell me, your body will not be obtained by others. This is the place that hurts my heart the most. I feel that my wife will be mine for life and cannot be shared with others.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;His wife kept it secret for many times, which made Cheng Shanzhi wonder whether she had been &quot;raped&quot; or cheated on her. That night, Cheng Shanzhi, who had never touched his wife before, slapped Yi Yonghong on the forearm. &quot;Am I still sorry to you in this life? I depend on you for everything, and you are in charge of the money. How do you want me to treat you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I know that no one would believe that something like this happened. If you don’t understand, I can’t even defend myself,” Yi Yonghong said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reconciliation and alarm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On July 17, Typhoon Taili was getting closer and stronger, and a storm was imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That morning, Cheng Shanzhi called Huang Mouguan and asked him to come to his home. He wanted to confront the other party face to face and also wanted to take revenge on the other party. At almost noon, Huang Mouguan came to the door carrying a box of Wong Lo Kat. Cheng Shanzhi opened a switchblade more than ten centimeters long and hid it in his pants pocket. When Yi Yonghong found out, he hugged him and told him not to do stupid things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that the three of them are present at the same time, and it is also the last time. Southern Weekend reporters heard from the live recording at the time that it was not so much a confrontation between two parties, but rather that the three people had their own concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi did not forgive his wife, and said to her angrily: &quot;As long as you get along with him, it&#39;s your own business.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong sometimes shouted hoarsely, He scolded Huang Mouguan: &quot;I can&#39;t protect myself now. I thought you were a very serious person. I&#39;m asking you, why do you want to mess with me? Why don&#39;t you mess with others.&quot; Sometimes he is powerless and self-pitying: &quot;Anyway It’s all my fault, and it doesn’t matter if I die. I have nothing now, and I don’t know where to go.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, Huang Mouguan was supposed to be the target of the crime, but he was like “ &quot;Peacemaker&quot;, while urging the two to live a good life, he agreed to the settlement plan and said to Cheng Shanzhi: &quot;I will give you 10,000 yuan, and we will be settled, and nothing will happen. We are all good brothers.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang Mouguan wrote a note on the spot: &quot;I had sexual relations with Yi Yonghong, and now I will compensate Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband for mental loss of 10,000 yuan.&quot; He signed Huang Mouguan&#39;s name. He took out 6,000 yuan in cash and transferred 4,000 yuan via WeChat. But Cheng Shanzhi did not accept the money. He followed his daughter&#39;s advice, called the police and handed the note to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan listened to the reconciliation via phone. She did not agree with this settlement plan. In addition to the risk of the other party suing for extortion, she also wanted Huang to apologize to his mother and even wanted him to go to jail. &lt;p>; .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 17, Huang The Wang Laoji that Guan brought with him during the reconciliation is still in Yi Yonghong&#39;s home. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in retrospect, Cheng Haiyan always felt that asking her father to call the police was a bit excessive. &quot;(The family) did not communicate well, so they called the police right away.&quot; In fact, the night before Huang Mouguan came to reconcile, Cheng Haiyan filed a complaint to the police, but Yi Yonghong kept crying and said that there was no evidence and the other party would not admit it. Cheng Haiyan believes that even if she fails to win in the end, she still wants Huang Mouguan to apologize to restore her mother&#39;s reputation. &quot;The other party has always wanted to use money to settle the matter. I think no matter how poor we are, we can&#39;t let you bully us like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan tried to call Huang Mouguan to &quot;collect evidence&quot;, but every time he said When it comes to key issues, the other party will say, &quot;Don&#39;t talk about this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to tell whether the public reporting to the police was more difficult for Yi Yonghong to accept than being &quot;raped&quot;. On the evening of July 17, Typhoon Taili landed in Wenchang, bringing heavy rain and strong winds to Bajiao. At this time, Yi Yonghong, Cheng Shanzhi, and Huang Mouguan were being questioned at the police station. Cheng Shanzhi heard that Yi Yonghong had been crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the surprise of the couple, on the afternoon of July 18, the day after the alarm was called, Huang&#39;s wife, son, daughter, sister, and brother-in-law came to their home with the intention of reconciling. The &quot;lawyer&quot; daughter in Huang&#39;s mouth told Yi Yonghong that words of discord would be unpleasant to hear in the future, and would also have a bad impact on her daughter who is currently in school. Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what else she said to her mother, which made Yi Yonghong feel that her daughter didn&#39;t understand the law. She called her daughter and asked, &quot;Do you understand the law or not?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi refused to reconcile. Later, the other party&#39;s attitude began to change. Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang&#39;s wife threatened them and humiliated Yi Yonghong, &quot;wanting to give her husband to her.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The crying collapse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the incident to the two failed reconciliations, to calling the police and being questioned, Yi Yonghong is being pushed to the edge of the cliff little by little. Cheng Haiyan said frankly that her family did not take much care of her emotions at that time, and also ignored the understanding and companionship she needed more. But to Cheng Haiyan at that time, her mother&#39;s behavior was &quot;everything was normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoshiyong Hong’s collapse may have started with a hysterical cry. At around 5 a.m. on July 19, Cheng Haiyan was woken up by her mother&#39;s cry. My mother had cried before, always while lying on the bed covered with quilts and crying silently. This was the first time Cheng Haiyan had seen her crying heartbrokenly like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi stood at the door, he didn&#39;t know what to do. Cheng Haiyan stood beside her mother&#39;s bed, equally at a loss. She was scared and didn&#39;t know how to express concern or comfort her. Even, she couldn&#39;t understand her mother&#39;s pain at this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to be an emotionally rough daughter, because in this family, they are taught that daughters can only rely on themselves, and sons rely on their parents. &quot;My grandmother&#39;s generation would regard their daughters as It&#39;s relatively light and I won&#39;t give too much emotion to my daughter.&quot; Yi Yonghong was taught that it was useless for girls to study, so she dropped out of school before finishing the second grade of junior high school. At that time, Yi Yonghong had good grades, ranked among the top three in her class, and was selected by a dance school, but her grandfather was unwilling to spend money to support her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A group photo of Yi Yonghong&#39;s family. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 825d62be57.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1175&quot; height=&quot;1383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/825d62be57.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A photo of Yi Yonghong’s family. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Haiyan&#39;s generation, she is still treated in this way. When she was a child, Yi Yonghong often told her that her sister must give way to her younger brother, and her younger brother&#39;s clothes must be washed by her sister. The couple&#39;s preference for their son reached its peak in 2015 after his son was diagnosed with acute leukemia. In order not to burden her parents, Cheng Haiyan earned living expenses by herself. She worked as a waiter, dishwasher, and cashier at the front desk. &quot;It was so hard that I felt numb.&quot; In recent years, Cheng Haiyan rarely spends the Chinese New Year with her parents and works outside to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong&#39;s crying did not subside. She repeatedly said &quot;Is this sentence correct?&quot; Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what &quot;this sentence&quot; was. She called her uncle, who was the most suitable person she could think of to comfort her mother. Grandma is old and can&#39;t stand the excitement; her sick brother is doing an internship in another place and is the key target of the family&#39;s concealment; and her aunt and uncle have a bad relationship with their mother and often quarrel. There are few people who can support Yoshiyong Hong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yi Yonghong has a strong self-esteem and is unwilling to let her family know about her. &quot;We rarely ask relatives for help or call them to complain. My mother feels that people will make fun of you and not want to help you,&quot; Cheng Haiyan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My uncle who was far away in Dongguan answered Cheng Haiyan&#39;s call. &quot;He called my mother&#39;s name twice, &#39;Honghong, Honghong&#39;, and she immediately calmed down.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan didn’t know why the backbone of the family suddenly collapsed. She survived even when her brother was sick and undergoing chemotherapy. Cheng Shanzhi also couldn&#39;t understand why his wife couldn&#39;t get over this hurdle: &quot;I didn&#39;t mention divorce, and I didn&#39;t drive you away. As a husband, I still love you, so why can&#39;t I just think about it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi is very satisfied with himself. His wife is beautiful, has fair skin, never puts on makeup, and speaks softly. When she took her home for the first time, people in the village praised him, &quot;Your ancestral grave is so nice.&quot; &quot;What else can I say about this kind of wife? There is nothing to dislike at all.&quot; Cheng Shanzhi often teaches his daughter that she should learn from her mother and be nice to her husband in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong is a traditional and conservative rural woman. Even when they fell in love, they only found out Cheng Shanzhi’s zodiac sign and birthday before they got together. After marriage, in addition to doing farm work, Yi Yonghong naturally took over the housework of washing and cooking. She massaged her husband&#39;s feet every day and trimmed his nails every other time. Jiu went to help him serve the rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the memory of her family, Yi Yonghong rarely interacted with the opposite sex or joked. She always hid when buying sanitary napkins and must put them in black plastic bags. Washed underwear is always hung among other clothes to dry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong doesn’t have many friends. Her pastimes are drinking tea, playing mahjong and scrolling through Douyin. Occasionally, she would take TikTok videos by herself, putting on a fancy template with the filter turned to the maximum, and staring at the camera with a serious expression. Sometimes she laments the hard life, and sometimes she sings the song &quot;Married girl, throw away the water, don&#39;t talk too much when you return to your parents&#39; home&quot; and &quot;Why is it so difficult in this life?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2000, I followed my husband to Hainan to work hard. They planted lemongrass and raised snakes, and finally saved money to build a house in their hometown. However, their son was diagnosed with acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Due to long-term labor, the joints of Yi Yonghong&#39;s hands were deformed and unable to be straightened. She often told her daughter that after following your father, there was no house in her hometown, no house in Hainan, and no home anywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her mother died, Cheng Haiyan always dreamed of her, but she could never see her face. Cheng Haiyan guessed that maybe her mother &quot;didn&#39;t want to see us, and we let her down.&quot; Cheng Haiyan did not dare to read the suicide note left by Yi Yonghong a second time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Questioned resistance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another important reason why Yi Yonghong is under tremendous pressure is that she always believes that the evidence is not enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the incident, in order to hide the incident, Yi Yonghong took a shower and washed the clothes she wore that day. She also threw the used tissues under the tree outside the house and had them removed. Heavy rain washed it away. &quot;I hate myself for not knowing how to use the law to protect myself... There is no evidence of guilt, and I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t win against him,&quot; she stated in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that made Yi Yonghong feel even more desperate was that during the incident, she was not sure whether her behavior was considered resistance. In her suicide note, she said: &quot;If resistance involves scratching as you said, tearing clothes to pieces, there is no such thing. Because I am afraid that he will beat me and harm my family. In my confession, I only said to push him and not to do it. , is this considered resistance?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi seemed to be comforting his dead wife. He said that Huang Guan was a head taller than him, his arms were as thick as his own, and he was tall and tall. &quot;If he holds you with both hands, do you have the strength to resist? No matter whether my wife resists or not, it is you, the man, who takes the initiative to violate my wife, not my wife who violates you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan doesn&#39;t know what resistance is. In her opinion, pushing the other person away is also resistance. She rarely pays attention to news about women&#39;s rights protection. After her mother committed suicide, a friend recommended Cheng Haiyan to watch the TV series &quot;Imperfect Victim&quot;: &quot;The heroine did not know how to resist under mental oppression. I felt that I My mother is mentally rebellious. If she had not resisted, she would not have cried.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Hangyuan, the 66-year-old village team leader, has his own views on resistance. He believes that to leave a mark on the other person&#39;s body, even if a knife is placed on the woman&#39;s neck, she must resist. After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, another version of the story circulated in the teahouse where Yi Yonghong used to frequent in this small village with only 13 households: The two had an affair and committed suicide after being discovered by her husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another factor that complicates the case is the 150 yuan Huang Mouguan left behind when he left. In a confrontation between the two parties after Yi Yonghong committed suicide, Huang&#39;s wife believed that by giving 150 yuan, the nature of the matter changed and became a &quot;business.&quot; After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, the two dirty, black banknotes were crumpled and stacked in Yi Yonghong&#39;s pocket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that his wife was insulted by their money, &quot;He (Huang Mouguan) lost the money and ran away. My wife will definitely pick it up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 21, the sixth day after the incident, Cheng Shanzhi and Yi Yonghong were called again to take statements. This was also the second time they took statements after the incident. It was after recording this confession that Yoshinaga wrote the suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan remembered that after her mother came home after taking the confession, she called her mother and asked: &quot;Are you willing to file a lawsuit? If you are willing to file a lawsuit, I can only try my best to help you. If If she doesn&#39;t want to sue, she won&#39;t sue.&quot; Cheng Haiyan realized later, &quot;(Before) we wanted her to sue, not that she wanted to sue herself. Taking the initiative and being pushed are not the same thing.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong chose to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Yi Yonghong’s experience was reported by the media, on August 26, the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau stated that it had deployed elite police forces to set up a joint investigation team to conduct a comprehensive review. According to Cheng Haiyan’s statistics, after Yi Yonghong’s suicide, the police re-collected the following evidence: 20 bottles of honey chrysanthemum tea (2 bottles unopened, 18 empty boxes), Yi Yonghong’s mobile phone, 150 yuan banknotes, Yi Yonghong’s gynecology department Check the medical records, the underwear worn by Yi Yonghong the next day after the incident, sheets, quilt covers, mats, pillows, bras, trousers, coats, tissues washed away by the rain, as well as the blood, liver and spleen obtained by Yi Yonghong&#39;s autopsy . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to whether Huang Mouguan has been detained and what new evidence is available for filing the case, a staff member of the Political Affairs Office of the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;The case is under investigation and it is not convenient to disclose it.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death, the suicide note was placed on the red stool. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death , the suicide note was placed on the red stool. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Shanzhi’s view, even on the day Yi Yonghong secretly wrote the suicide note, he did not notice anything unusual about his wife. On July 22, after working for a day, the couple decided to have dinner in a restaurant. Cheng Shanzhi bought four cans of Red Bull for his wife. Yi Yonghong loved to drink Red Bull and drank one can almost every day before the incident. Cheng Shanzhi lay on the recliner waiting for her. After taking a shower, Yi Yonghong hugged her husband and kissed him. For dinner, they ordered a piece of white-chopped chicken and a plate of sweet potato leaves. Yi Yonghong still had no appetite. She didn&#39;t even drink her favorite Red Bull and only ate some sweet potato leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 23 was the day when Cheng Haiyan returned to Wenchang from Haikou to record her confession. Early in the morning, Cheng Shanzhi called her: &quot;Hong, let&#39;s go with our daughter to record a statement. The two of us have a companion.&quot; After calling her three times in a row, Yi Yonghong refused. &quot;She said, go ahead, I&#39;ll wait for you to come back at home. I&#39;m very tired and want to take a rest at home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a normal day, Cheng Shanzhi would go pick her up and the couple would always be inseparable when traveling. But that day, &quot;I forgot to give her a hand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汕尾如何“握手”高铁经济时代：拥抱文旅融合发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway will be officially opened in late September. At that time, it will only travel from Xintang Station to Shanwei Station. It takes about 50 minutes. This is the first railway named after the city of Shanwei. It is an important channel to promote the deep integration of the old revolutionary areas of Hailufeng into the Bay. After its opening, it will greatly shorten the distance between Shanwei and eastern Guangdong and the core cities of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6ef41814ed4b3d857360965c9b9b0834.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6ef41814ed4b3d857360965c9b9b0834.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250734 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Aerial photo of Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanwei City seized the important opportunity of the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway and held a press conference on the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway in 2023 to boost the high-quality economic development of Shanwei and a cultural tourism real estate investment promotion on the afternoon of September 12 The meeting will announce a series of activities planned and organized by Shanwei City during the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway and relevant measures to regulate the order of the cultural tourism market, and promote Shanwei City’s high-quality cultural tourism resources, real estate resources and investment environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Visible achievements, creating a new highland for Shanwei’s cultural tourism&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Shantou City is the ‘National It is the &quot;emerging niche city with the fastest growth rate of travel intention&quot;, one of the top ten &quot;new local travel destinations&quot; in the country for National Day in 2022, and will be shortlisted for the Top 10 cities in the annual life travel intensity index in 2022...&quot; Shanwei City Culture, Radio, Television, Tourism and Sports&lt;span >;Bureau Director Xie Wei&lt;span>;Xuan&lt;/span>; said at the press conference that in recent years, Shanwei City has focused on high-quality development, strengthened the supply capacity of cultural tourism products, and unswervingly cultivated the cultural tourism industry It has become a strategic pillar industry for high-quality economic and social development, and the cultural tourism market has achieved considerable results and achieved fruitful results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/e4515ced78a221f8ab57f7f91ea61c06.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/e4515ced78a221f8ab57f7f91ea61c06.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250736&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Jinxiang Silver Beach Tourist Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of this year, the &lt;span>;tourism market was generally active and strong, and &lt;/span>; continued its rapid growth momentum. The total number of overnight tourists in Shanwei City was 9.7866 million, a year-on-year increase of 279.33%; tourists The total number of tourists was 15.1135 million, a year-on-year increase of 294.61%; the total tourism revenue was 7.581 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 130.78%. During the summer vacation from July to August this year, Shanwei seized the opportunity of the country&#39;s &quot;Twenty Measures&quot; to promote consumption, integrated performing arts, sports, culture, food and tourism, and extended more new tourism formats and models that attract young people. Further unleash the consumption potential of the cultural tourism market. From July to August 2023, the city&#39;s total number of overnight tourists was 3.65 million, a year-on-year increase of 204.17%&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;The total number of tourists was 6.2 million, a year-on-year increase of 228.42%&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;The total tourism revenue was 3.4 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 183.33%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/399894f6fc8ddf650b504a8407ceef2a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/399894f6fc8ddf650b504a8407ceef2a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250738&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Red Bay Tourist Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Come to Shanwei by high-speed rail+&quot; series of activities, nine special sessions are waiting for you&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot; This year&#39;s &#39;Super Golden Week&#39; is the first super golden week after the epidemic, and combined with the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway, it will bring unprecedented opportunities for the high-quality development of Shanwei tourism.&quot; Xie Siying, deputy director of the Shanwei Municipal Culture, Radio, Television, Tourism and Sports Bureau, said, The Guangzhou Tourism and Sports Bureau will lead the Municipal &lt;span>;Transportation Bureau&lt;/span>;, Municipal Investment Promotion Bureau, Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, Municipal Education Bureau, Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, Municipal Civil Affairs Bureau, Municipal Health Bureau, and Municipal Development and Reform Bureau Relevant units such as the Municipal Hong Kong and Macao Affairs Bureau and the Municipal Hong Kong and Macao Affairs Bureau have planned to launch a series of promotional activities for the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway from September to December, hoping to widely attract tourists and set off a cultural wave during the &quot;Super Golden Week&quot; with eight consecutive days of National Day and Mid-Autumn Festival. Travel boom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/12ced8b257cbdd4080127a76b8e9a708.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/12ced8b257cbdd4080127a76b8e9a708.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250737&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway Shanwei Station. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revolving around key tasks such as &quot;hundreds of millions of projects&quot;, strengthening the city by ocean, and strengthening the city by culture, Shanwei City has launched a series of activities &quot;Come to Shanwei+ by high-speed rail&quot;, starting from this week to the end of the year , mainly concentrated from September to October, in principle, held once a week. These include Shanwei’s high-quality hot tourist routes, locational transportation advantages, high-speed rail economic investment, high-speed rail economy and Shanwei real estate development, medical and health care, new energy and green energy promotion, Hong Kong and Macao compatriots’ visit to Shanwei, Shanwei Harvest Food Festival, and Shanwei Tourism Market There are nine special activities in the standardized promotion action, which promote and introduce Shanwei&#39;s cultural tourism resources and development opportunities from different dimensions, and promote the development of related economic industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Shanwei City also launched the &quot;Take the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway to Shanwei&quot; activity. On the day the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway was opened to traffic, 200 tourists were recruited to form a tour group and experience Shanwei&#39;s high-quality tourist routes for free. A sightseeing bus line will be opened directly from the high-speed rail station in the urban area. Tourists can reserve free rides through the WeChat applet and enjoy the scenery of Shanwei. &lt;h4>; Give full play to the resource advantages of &#39;red + blue&#39; and polish the business card of &#39;growing Shanwei in winter&#39;.&quot; After the press conference, Xie Weixuan promoted Shanwei&#39;s cultural tourism resources at the Shanwei Cultural Tourism Real Estate Investment Promotion Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;red&quot; is reflected in the fact that Shanwei is a place where red culture gathers. Shanwei is the birthplace of the first Soviet power in the country and one of the 13 revolutionary base areas in the country. The Red Palace and Red Square are the national patriotism education base and the national red tourism classic scenic spot. Zhou Enlai&#39;s Crossing of the Sea &lt;span>;Commemoration&lt;/span>; red tourist area, the former site of the Second Red Division &lt;span>;Division&lt;/span>;, the former site of the Fourth Red &lt;span>;Division&lt;/span>; Department, the former site of the Forty-ninth Regiment Headquarters, etc. The revolutionary relics tell the story of Hailufeng’s vigorous revolutionary history, and eight provincial-level red demonstration villages shine with the splendor of a happy countryside in the new era in Shanwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/87000187c3b7abbb586f751ccfd3da07.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;354&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/87000187c3b7abbb586f751ccfd3da07.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250739&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Red Palace and Red Square are the national patriotism education base and the national red tourism classic scenic spot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Blue&quot; is reflected in the resource advantages of &lt;span>;Shantou Binhai&lt;/span>; city.汕尾属南亚热带季风气候区，海洋性气候明显，拥有长达455公里的海岸线，其中优质沙滩岸线长达150公里，拥有丰富的海洋资源，“百岛十滩九湾”更是精华所在。汕尾冬无严寒、夏无酷暑，是避暑、避寒、避霾的滨海旅游度假胜地，获“冬养汕尾·全国生态旅游示范实验区”称号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/251a00f8049ce079ca9a7fd9f7c81734.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;237&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/251a00f8049ce079ca9a7fd9f7c81734.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;汕尾海岸线航拍图。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文旅发展离不开文体活动的策划。汕尾市举办“冬养汕尾”文旅品牌推广活动暨首届中国散文诗节，获得全国第一个地级市“中国散文诗之乡”荣誉牌匾，并发布了中国散文诗第一部蓝皮书。这是&lt;span>;继&lt;/span>;获得“中国民间文化艺术之乡”称号后，&lt;span>;汕尾增添的又一个&lt;/span>;“国字号”文化品牌。不仅如此，汕尾还荣获“广东省戏剧之乡”“广东省渔歌之乡”“广东省小提琴之乡”三张金名片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/d4dce25401ddb621bb2b4be9b8c58bc2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/d4dce25401ddb621bb2b4be9b8c58bc2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;汕尾拥有三大稀有剧种和一项世界级非遗陆丰皮影。图为皮影戏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，汕尾市携手短视频平台举办2023年华南地区“广东家乡迎新年”暨“山海湖城冬养汕尾”文化惠民贺新春文艺晚会，线上累计观看人数达1.7亿人次。不仅如此，汕尾市还举办“山海湖城冬养汕尾”2023年新春嘉年华，以传统的非遗文化与现代人文相结合，充分展示&lt;span>;汕尾滨海&lt;/span>;旅游城市形象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;盘活房地产旅游资源，提供高品质服务&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;市自然资源局、市住建局相关负责人分别&lt;span>;作&lt;/span>;酒店用地优惠政策、房地产资源的推介。为助力广汕高铁通车系列活动宣传，汕尾市积极谋划举办以“广汕高铁新时代，同城生活更精彩”为主题的2023年汕尾金秋购房节活动，活动期间将协调落实相关部门和企业在购房节推出特别优惠和支持措施，从提高公积金贷款额度、个人按揭贷款优惠利率、发放购房补贴、企业活动优惠四个方面吸引招商投资建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/223819745eecaaf78e082f2a9ec321f4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/223819745eecaaf78e082f2a9ec321f4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250742&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;保利金町湾旅游度假区。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在房地产资源方面，汕尾市拥有汕尾星河湾、保利集团、碧桂园星钻、星河领誉、万德隆阳光城等众多房地产项目，其中汕尾星河湾更是让人眼前一亮。汕尾星河湾位于全国最大的潟湖——品清湖畔，背山面海，坐拥品清湖一线绝美景观，享受优质生态资源。此外，星河湾地段优越，毗邻高铁站，交通便利，同时配备国际五星级标准酒店、千人宴会厅、国际标准体育馆、港湾式休闲商业街、东方意蕴园林等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/bd060dad242d35f40fdf2f3718d50246.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/bd060dad242d35f40fdf2f3718d50246.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;汕尾海洋资源丰富，拥有全国最大的潟湖——品清湖。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在酒店建设方面，汕尾市着重强化提升酒店服务接待能力，抓紧推动星级饭店建设改造，积极推动高档次酒店项目投产建设，着力提升全市接待水平和档次，为游客提供更优质的酒店服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，汕尾市还致力于创新旅游民宿发展新模式。全市新增登记民宿40家，诞生了上英米墅芦苇野舍、金厢海纳金&lt;span>;滩民&lt;/span>;宿小镇、丽君阁·木屋主题文宿等一大批富有乡村特色的民宿。在旅游景区、酒店、民宿和旅游交通集散地等旅游经营单位开展新型公共文化空间建设，已建成12个“粤书吧”、3个“粤文坊”、11个其他类型新型公共文化空间，村综合性文化服务中心及旅游服务中心“两中心融合”试点工作14个以及旅游厕所195座。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3facebb5057d5419bb41005b35a89f37.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3facebb5057d5419bb41005b35a89f37.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;金厢海纳金滩民宿小镇。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广汕高铁开通，意味着&lt;span>;汕尾迎来&lt;/span>;一个全新发展的时代，这一交通基础设施将为当地带来巨大的发展机遇。汕尾市为此做好充分准备，积极宣传当地文旅资源，吸引投资建设，推动文旅相关产业蓬勃发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【精品旅游线路推荐】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;◎海丰：旅游线路以海丰的红色为基底，通过线路将森林康养、休闲农业和滨海生态旅游连接起来，让游客了解海丰的红色基因，领略本地乡村秀美田园风光和体验滨海“漫”节奏生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/a036a19024be67560fb229b8e594280a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/a036a19024be67560fb229b8e594280a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250744&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;海丰县莲花山度假村。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;◎陆丰：规划打造四条精品旅游线路，分别是&lt;span>;：&lt;/span>;“红色堡垒·黄金海岸”“红色海岸·古城风韵”“山水画廊·康养福地”“乡土古韵·农运摇篮”。其中，“红色堡垒·黄金海岸”和“乡土古韵·农运摇篮”入选广东省乡村旅游精品线路。同时为了带给游客更好的旅游体验，陆丰市整合优势资源，重新规划优化“1+1”精品旅游线路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/47a606f4deb2deec1f7703800553d1f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/47a606f4deb2deec1f7703800553d1f0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;陆丰玄武山旅游区。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;◎陆河：根据“春夏秋冬”四季、“南北”乡村示范带、不同主题，共制定了旅游线路13条，其中“醉美山水，人间仙境”“陆河红色客俗梅韵游”“养生之乡，情满荔园”三条线路被评为广东省乡村旅游精品线路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1f02a4a182c47ab5734d45632983b943.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;544&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1f02a4a182c47ab5734d45632983b943.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;陆河县白水寨瀑布。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[茂名鳄鱼雨中出逃，已围捕追回58条]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256743]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 14:36:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[信用卡质效榜：两大梯队均分化严重  华夏仅优于城商行 ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256663]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在跑马圈地式的狂飙突进近30年后，伴随着《进一步促进信用卡业务规范健康发展的通知》（业界称为《信用卡新规》）于2022年落地，中国信用卡市场进入精耕细作时代。各商业银行对卡量的倚重被质效取而代之。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国人民银行发布的《2022年第四季度支付体系运行总体情况》显示，截至2022年末，信用卡和借贷合一卡在用发卡数量共计7.98亿张，同比下降0.28%。这是中国信用卡发卡量有记录以来首度负增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但作为各商业银行核心优质业务板块，在数字金融时代，信用卡业务面临着全新的竞争态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，哪家发卡行的规模和增速依旧亮眼？哪家发卡行的风险管理体系和风控效果更胜一筹？哪家发卡行更有办法留存客户？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员采取定量与定性相结合的研究分析方法，构建了包含三大维度16项指标的综合评价指标体系，并对指标因其重要性进行差异化赋权。这令不同规模和不同类型的商业银行在信用卡业务综合实力上实现了“横向可对比、纵向可排名”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此指标体系下，南方周末新金融中心研究员基于19家主要商业银行的2022年年报数据和第三方评测数据，对其在信用卡业务方面的表现进行了客观评价，并根据评价得分结果发布“信用卡质效榜”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;指标体系&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;三大维度&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;十六&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;项子指标&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自1995年中国首张标准信用卡诞生至今，信用卡这个“舶来品”经过近30年磨砺，已成为各金融机构个人信贷业务的基础工具之一。2022年末，十八家主要商业银行信用卡贷款余额7.89万亿（宁波银行信用卡贷款余额数据未披露，故未纳入统计），占个人贷款余额14.4%，成为仅次于住房按揭贷款的第二大个人信贷市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信用卡业务对商业银行有何重要价值？首先，信用卡业务是银行零售业务的重要支撑；其次，信用卡帮助银行提高客户的忠诚度和黏性；再次，信用卡业务为银行提供消费者相关数据，银行可以更好地为客户和消费者完成画像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于各商业银行信用卡业务的发展趋势特点和信用卡客户满意度调研，南方周末新金融研究中心构建了“信用卡质效榜”评价指标体系&lt;em>;，&lt;/em>;它包含业务规模及增长情况、风险管理、客户服务和产品创新三大维度，并细化成为十五项定量指标、一项定性指标。现将评价指标体系分项说明如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/rB3LjY143PkCBOLBGAvB6nIqPDnWobGzOmO0ep0Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;498&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/rB3LjY143PkCBOLBGAvB6nIqPDnWobGzOmO0ep0Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（1）业务规模以及增长情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信用卡是银行与客户建立长期关系的重要工具，也是银行零售业务的发力重点。信用卡业务规模和增长情况体现了银行的客户获取能力和市场地位，而信用卡的发卡量和发卡量变化反映银行的拓展效果，贷款余额和占比则体现银行信用卡的实际贡献，活跃户数和交易额则反映银行信用卡的营销精准度和黏性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（2）风险管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考察银行信用卡的风险管理能力非常必要。信用卡是银行基于对持卡人的信任而发放的“无抵押循环贷款”，信用卡业务的风险管理能力影响银行的经营效益和竞争力。信用卡是银行重要的收入来源，其营收来自利息、手续费和年费等。若不能有效控制信用卡的坏账率、欺诈率和盗刷率等指标，银行的成本将增加，而利润减少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受疫情影响，2022年商业银行贷款不良率（其中包括信用卡贷款不良率）有所增加。与此同时，大部分上市银行年报披露的改善贷款不良率的措施较为笼统，且各银行间的措施缺乏可比性。为凸显银行在控制贷款不良率上所做的努力和效果，本评价体系采用2022年信用卡贷款不良率指标的同时，通过设置信用卡贷款不良率的变化率指标，直接反映各银行采取措施所取得的成效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（3）客户服务和产品创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信用卡市场竞争日益激烈，银行不断推出新的产品、服务、功能和活动等，以满足客户的多样化需求和提高客户黏性。本评价体系从银行端和消费者两端进行评估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们把银行发行信用卡种类和信用卡业务投诉量分别作为正反两个方向的指标。而消费者端则采用第三方机构的评价，因为第三方机构通过大量、客观的调查问卷等形式得到消费者对信用卡产品的评价，与银行年报中披露的相比会较为客观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们选取中国顾客满意度指数（China Customer Satisfaction Index，简称C-CSI）和中国顾客推荐度指数(China Net Promoter Score，简称C-NPS)作为消费者对信用卡产品评价的指标。C-CSI和C-NPS调查对象为15岁到60岁之间的常住居民，并根据性别、年龄、收入及区域随机抽样，采用入户面访的调查方式完成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们把发卡行当年度具有特色的信用卡服务作为加分项，按公开披露且能够搜集到的特色信用卡服务，每有一项则获得10分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（4）信息披露的奖惩机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们在调研中发现，大部分银行均披露了上述各指标数据，但少数银行未披露一项或多项指标。为减少信息不对称影响，同时惩罚在信息披露中不够充分的银行，凡没有披露相关数据的指标项，本评价系统在计分上对该项指标得分均为最低。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;招行拔头筹&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;华夏仅优于城商行&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们将19家商业银行信用卡业务按得分高低进行排名，评选出“信用卡质效榜”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“信用卡质效榜”显示，信用卡业务起步较早、客户基础庞大的全国性商业银行排名靠前。但并非发卡量规模越大综合得分越高。作为股份制银行，招商银行虽然规模上不及国有大行，但信用卡业务总得分却拔得头筹。这得益于其率先发力零售业务的战略眼光和多年如一日的创新力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nrq2m73w7NwpA0YngHO0HozRPlvgzwOnrwyzdfu2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nrq2m73w7NwpA0YngHO0HozRPlvgzwOnrwyzdfu2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建设银行和工商银行紧追招行分列第二、第三名。其中，建设银行信用卡总得分仅比招行少20分，差距甚微。三家银行构成信用卡业务的领先方阵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六家国有大行中，中国银行和农业银行总得分远在五名之外，不仅被招行远远抛在后面，也被股份行中信、平安和广发行等超越。邮储银行更落在十三名。而在股份制银行中，华夏银行垫底，与招行的分值相差248分之高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/XPGZaas4gffibT9dkNVoXQWhd7gVkP1r0UbYHUiZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/XPGZaas4gffibT9dkNVoXQWhd7gVkP1r0UbYHUiZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工商银行信用卡失分主要在于其仅公布了总投诉情况而没有公布信用卡业务的投诉情况。因此，当我们不考虑信用卡业务投诉这一指标时，招行依旧领跑榜单，工商银行反超建行升至第二位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样，如果不计投诉量这个指标，广发行和交通银行跃居第四和第五名。这说明这两家银行的投诉量相对较大。当然，这不排除灰产的恶意投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;国有行股份行分化严重&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;城商行在追赶&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;无论国有行还是股份行，两大梯队的信用卡得分在各自的阵营中均严重分化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六大国有银行中，在两个榜单中，仅分别有两家和三家跻身前五名，分别为建行工行和建行工行和交行。农行和中行在两个榜单中，排名均靠后。尤其在不计投诉量的榜单中，中行得分排名已到十四位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在股份制银行中，招行一直遥遥领先。中信、平安和广发整体业绩显眼。其中，中信银行信用卡总得分在股份制银行中仅次于招行，主要是该行在消费者服务方面和信用卡业务投诉方面获得比同行更多的得分，其中信用卡投诉一项得分之高压倒其他上榜银行，信用卡种类得分也超过80，显示其覆盖的消费者群体较广。尽管广发行在所有股份制银行中体量较小，但广发信用卡总得分在所有银行中均靠前。这体现了广发行信用卡业务在该行中举足轻重的地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四家城商行信用卡得分位于榜尾，这显示它们在信用卡综合实力方面与大中型银行仍有明显差距。受进入信用卡市场时间较短、业务规模较小和客户基础较弱等因素影响，城商行整体在信用卡发卡量和信用卡贷款余额等指标上落后较多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在城商行中，江苏银行和宁波银行信用卡变化量指标均获得100分，尤其是宁波银行在信用卡业务的投诉占比一项的得分高达90分。这反映头部城商行在信用卡业务上正在努力追赶，并且在一些指标上已取得长足进步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（助理研究员梁承昊邹欢杨超群亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[父亲殴打猥亵女儿者，检察机关不予起诉：义愤彰显人性，震慑奸宄之徒丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256739]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 14:09:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，《检察日报》发布的一个案件，让诸多网友大呼“阳间新闻”“很提气”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年5月9日，李某得知15岁的女儿在某职业技术学院上学期间被该学院副院长谢某某猥亵，来到学校对谢某某进行殴打。谢某某的损伤程度被鉴定为轻伤二级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;检察机关认为，李某打伤谢某某的行为虽涉嫌故意伤害罪，但系向学校主张其女儿合法权益的过程中，出于激愤实施的伤害行为。因李某系初犯、偶犯，其行为事出有因、情节较轻，且具有自首等从轻、从宽处罚情节，故而作出不起诉决定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于谢某某，经检察机关提起公诉，法院以强制猥亵罪判处其有期徒刑二年二个月，禁止其自刑罚执行完毕之日或假释之日起从事与未成年人密切接触的负有教育、培训、看护等特殊职责的职业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网友的反应中，没见到对父亲李某把谢某某打成轻伤二级有微词的，更遑论视为“故意伤害罪”了，倒是各种“打得好”“打死也不为过”的称许声，这样的声音显得“暴虐”吗？并没有。这是内蕴于每一个正常人心中的“朴素正义感”或“法感情”的外显。义愤让我们充满人性，正直一定意味着爱憎分明。孔子说：唯仁者，能爱人，能恶人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网友对当地检察院也不乏溢美之词，如“正义之光”“要送锦旗”。要是机械套用法条，这位父亲将人打成轻伤二级，是可以被起诉并判刑的。现实中不乏这样的案例：夫妻有一方出轨，另一方捉奸在床，激愤之下狂殴情人，然后情人去鉴定伤情，只要够上轻伤，另一方要么赔钱求和解，要么因故意伤害罪去坐牢，让打人者去坐牢虽然合乎法律，却有悖人伦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，在某种程度上，上述案件反映了自然法与成文法/制定法之间的冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓自然法/自然权利，无非是说法律是发现的，不是发明或制定的，也就是常说的“天理”。从进化博弈论的观点来看，自然法是“进化稳定策略”（ESS）的体现，一报还一报，或孔子所说的“以德报德、以直报怨”就是ESS，唯有如此，才能促进社会成员之间的合作、抑制背信与侵犯行为，令社会与文明得以存续。 “对等”最终导出的规则是彼此尊重对方的生命、自由与财产权利，如国人所说的“杀人偿命、欠债还钱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成文法是人所制定的，会参考自然法或习惯法，但与自然法或习惯法并不总是一致，有时甚至会背道而驰，在婚姻家庭与财产继承领域，诸多案例反映了成文法与自然法或习惯法的冲突。独生女杨女士想继承父母遗产，结果发现有22个父母双边的亲属也有继承权（基于成文法），好在这些亲戚不认为自己对杨女士父母的遗产有继承权（基于自然法与习惯法），这就是天理人心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到父亲李某打谢某某的案件，谢某某显然很懂用法律的武器来保护自己，被打后立马鉴定伤情为“轻伤二级”，显示自己也遭受了伤害，以此作为筹码，或想抵消猥亵案中自己所面临的不利局面，因为轻微伤可行政拘留，轻伤可入刑，摆出来“我坐牢，你也要坐牢，大家一起”的姿态。从当地检察机关对这两案都有处理看，显然，对父亲李某打人案，警方也完成了调查并移交了检方，可以推断谢某某被打之后有向警方报案。报案+伤情鉴定，反制李某的指向很是明显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见，当地检察机关对李某不起诉的决定，消解了自然法与制定法在这一事件上的冲突，上应天理，下顺人心，对父亲李某为女儿挺身而出的行为与德性是很好的成全，对那些试图把脏手伸向未成年人的奸宄之徒也是很好的震慑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;个人如何应对自然法与制定法的冲突？父亲李某就是一个很好的表率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同的制定法法条及基于此的不同判决意味着对人不同的行为激励，会改变人的行为，例如山西大同订婚后被控强奸案引发了强烈的关切与争论，大家讨论的一个动机是“如何规避法律风险”，但一般而言，当自己父母子女的权利受到侵犯时，血浓于水的感情与气性会占上风，至少会很生气，常常会站出来，而不会一味瞻前顾后、畏畏缩缩，显得特别“理性冷静”。如果在这个时候一个人都没有表现出血性与勇气，那他很可能根本就没有这个东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一个为自己子女站出来的父亲母亲，都是值得尊敬的。他们在自己子女受到伤害、最为脆弱无助的时候，挺身而出，与侵犯者对峙，将侵犯者的恶行暴露于光天化日之下，这对自己子女是最好的帮助，也是最好的价值观教育。他们让子女知道：当自己受到伤害时，父母就是自己最坚强的后盾与依靠；自己也要像父母一样勇敢，敢于对侵犯与侵犯者说不，敢于主张与捍卫自己的权利。这样的父母多了，不仅那些蠢蠢欲动者心中会反复掂量，也会传达给下一代与全社会一种既坚强又厚重的价值观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：9月20日起将猴痘纳入乙类传染病进行管理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256733]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;National Health Commission Announcement&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to the relevant provisions of the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention and Control of Infectious Diseases&quot;, monkeypox will be included in the management of Class B infectious diseases from September 20, 2023. Prevention and control measures for infectious diseases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is an announcement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;National Health Commission&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt; span>;September 15, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Interpretation of the policy on incorporating monkeypox into the management of Class B infectious diseases&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Monkeypox is a zoonotic disease caused by monkeypox virus infection. In the past, it mainly occurred in Central and West Africa. Since May 2022, monkeypox epidemics have occurred in more than 100 countries and regions around the world. Epidemics in many countries have shown that monkeypox has been transmitted from person to person and has spread widely to countries and regions outside Africa, with a case fatality rate of approximately 0.1%. In September 2022, my country reported its first imported case of monkeypox, and local monkeypox epidemics began to appear in June 2023. Currently, more than 20 provinces across the country have reported monkeypox cases, triggering new local secondary outbreaks and hidden transmission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The National Health Commission and the State Administration for Disease Control and Prevention conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, treat monkeypox as a new emerging infectious disease, and give full play to their multiple capabilities. The important role of departmental coordination in prevention and control, continuous improvement of prevention and control policies and measures, strengthening information release, publicity and education, intervention of key groups and standardized treatment have achieved positive results in monkeypox epidemic prevention and control. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Considering that the monkeypox epidemic will continue to exist in my country for a certain period of time, in order to further carry out scientific and standardized prevention and control of the monkeypox epidemic and effectively protect the life safety and health of the people, The National Health Commission decided to include monkeypox as a Class B infectious disease for management under the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention and Control of Infectious Diseases&quot; from September 20, 2023, and adopt prevention and control measures for Class B infectious diseases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/dcdb718c013bccbff37e45063b6e2e3d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/dcdb718c013bccbff37e45063b6e2e3d.png&quot; data-key =&quot;250883&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/a7e16978f496a2d7dd21f9834e7c5ba3.png&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/a7e16978f496a2d7dd21f9834e7c5ba3.png&quot; data -key=&quot;250884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Website screenshot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年暑期旅游超18亿人次，部分地区游客流入占比超2019年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国庆长假火车票正式开抢，你有多久没坐过绿皮火车了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256725]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 15, train tickets will officially go on sale on the first day of the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday. This year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday runs from September 29 to October 6. According to the 15-day pre-sale period for railway tickets, return train tickets for the last day of the holiday will go on sale on September 22. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While tickets to many popular destinations are hard to come by, there are also many trains and lines that are quietly withdrawing from the public eye. With the development of high-speed rail networks, the popularity of private cars and the expansion of air routes, regular-speed lines have ceased operations in recent years. For example, at Shantou Station in eastern Guangdong Province, all regular-speed trains have been suspended. The surrounding Jieyang South Station and Chaozhou Station have already closed their passenger transportation services, which have nothing to do with passenger travel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In neighboring Japan, this phenomenon is even more obvious. With the aging of the population and the outflow of people to big cities, a large number of local railway lines in Japan have been abandoned and stations removed. Not only is the travel of local residents in towns and villages affected, but many beautiful scenery along the railway are also difficult to see again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How long has it been since you took a green train? Are you interested in trying it out during your vacation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“一带一路”十年，国税总局局长谈如何共同优化税收营商环境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256714]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/ZVGm5aPxEWJIMD9smLx05hWAVWPHbsYSc1b7XvmE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ZVGm5aPxEWJIMD9smLx05hWAVWPHbsY Sc1b7XvmE. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation of China, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a keynote speech. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the State Administration of Taxation that on the afternoon of September 11, 2023, Beijing time , Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation of China, attended the opening ceremony of the 4th “Belt and Road” Tax Collection and Administration Cooperation Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The forum was held in Tbilisi, the capital of Georgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Members attending the forum include heads of tax departments from 32 countries and regions, representatives of 10 international organizations such as the United Nations and the International Monetary Fund, and representatives of some multinational enterprises, totaling more than 300 people. During the three-day forum, participating parties conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as optimizing the overall planning of the tax business environment, tax rule of law and transparency of tax collection and administration, reducing tax burdens, simplifying tax compliance, and building a dispute resolution mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun introduced in his keynote speech that in recent years, China&#39;s tax authorities have continued to optimize the tax business environment, and have carried out the &quot;Spring Breeze Action for Tax Convenience&quot; for ten consecutive years, and have launched a total of 620 tax service measures. Gradually realize that 96% of tax matters and 99% of tax declarations can be processed &quot;online&quot; or &quot;handheld&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of implementing a series of preferential tax and fee policies, Wang Jun said that from 2018 to 2022 alone, the cumulative number of new tax cuts and fee reductions and tax rebates and fee deferrals exceeded 11 trillion yuan, becoming one of the policies to help enterprises bail out. It is the policy measure with the most “gold content” and the most obvious benefits for business entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun also mentioned that China’s tax authorities continue to improve the new tax supervision system based on “credit + risk” to maximize supervision efficiency, minimize supervision costs, and minimize interference to business entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, China’s tax authorities are deeply involved in the formulation and adjustment of international tax rules, providing multiple cross-border tax processing channels for cross-border investment and trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to optimize the tax business environment and jointly build the &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot;, Wang Jun proposed three initiatives: First, embrace the digital trend, accelerate the in-depth integration of digital technology and tax business, and further promote internal and external tax-related data Gather China Unicom and organically connect online and offline to improve precise collection and management capabilities; second, give full play to and expand the role of taxation functions, which can not only provide all-round, full-cycle, and full-chain tax support for technological innovation, but also create new business formats, The tax business environment for the development and expansion of the new model; third, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; tax collection and administration cooperation mechanism will play a &quot;bridge and link&quot; role to help the world economy recover for the better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;The “Belt and Road” tax collection and administration cooperation mechanism was initiated by China and was established in April 2019. It currently has 36 members and 30 observers and has become an important influence under the “Belt and Road” initiative. A powerful multilateral tax cooperation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun said that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has gone through ten years. The holding of previous &quot;Belt and Road&quot; tax collection and administration cooperation forums has effectively promoted the tax authorities of various countries to deepen exchanges and mutual learning and continuously improve transparency. , efficient, stable and predictable tax cooperation mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[丰子恺：无宠不惊过一生丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 10:45:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>