<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[闹剧过后，我们如何寻找外星生命？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258060]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Earth is the only celestial body that we currently know has life, but whether the Earth has life in the universe The issue of isolated islands has been debated endlessly. The topic of UFOs and aliens has always been a hot topic of public concern, triggering continuous discussions and becoming a classic theme in science fiction works. At the same time, scientists are also trying to use scientific methods to study this field and look beyond the earth to search for signs of life on exoplanets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Remains of extraterrestrial creatures&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Farce&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are endless revelations about aliens around the world, most of which are due to lack of evidence. Can&#39;t make much of a splash. However, the appearance of the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; at a hearing in the Mexican Congress attracted widespread attention from the media and the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, local time, the Mexican Congress held the first public hearing related to the &quot;Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena, UAP&quot; in the capital, Mexico City. At this hearing, Mexican journalist, author and UFO enthusiast Jaime Maussan presented his &quot;discovery&quot; of the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Mozan, the two remains were discovered in a diatom mine in Cusco, Peru, in 2017. After dating by the National Autonomous University of Mexico, the two remains were dated 1,800 years ago. years and 700 years. As can be seen from the pictures at the scene, the remains have an elongated head and three fingers on each hand. The appearance of the two remains is very similar to the alien images described in some science fiction works, causing heated discussions on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mossan stated: &quot;These two remains have nothing to do with humans.&quot; However, the &quot;alien creatures&quot; mentioned by Moosang immediately aroused huge doubts. This is not the first time that Moissan has thrown out similar news. In 2015, Mossan claimed to have discovered the remains of a suspected &quot;alien creature&quot; in Peru and held a ticketed tour. However, the remains were later confirmed to be the mummified remains of a child. In 2017, Mozan claimed to have discovered the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; in the Nazca region of Peru, but was immediately refuted by Peruvian officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;evidence&quot; Moissan gave this time is also unconvincing. In response to Mosan&#39;s statement, the National Accelerator Mass Spectrometry Laboratory of the National Autonomous University of Mexico re-issued a statement that was first released in 2017. The laboratory said in a statement that they were not involved in collecting the samples and had not seen the entire specimen. Therefore, they were only responsible for testing the age of the samples submitted for inspection and would not draw conclusions about the source of the samples. Mosang also claimed that he invited forensic doctors to use X-ray scanning technology to examine the remains and found that there were egg-like structures in the remains. Julieta Fierro, a scientist at the Astronomy Research Center of the National Autonomous University of Mexico, criticized this, saying that more advanced technology than X-ray scanning would be needed to determine whether the two remains were human. Antígona Segura, an astrobiologist at the Nuclear Science Research Center of the National Autonomous University of Mexico, even said: &quot;These conclusions are not supported by evidence at all. The whole thing is shameful.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The Mexican Congress held this hearing to discuss the AirSpace Protection Law (AirSpace Protection Law) and promote relevant legislation. If this law is passed, Mexico will become the first country in the world to recognize &quot;extraterrestrial life forms&quot; &quot;Country that exists. However, after the hearing, the Mexican Congress did not provide conclusive opinions, and the future of this bill is still unclear. Sergio Gutierrez, a member of the Mexican Congress, said: &quot;We are paying attention to this issue and we can continue to discuss it.&quot; However, after being criticized by the scientific community, Moissan&#39;s &quot;discovery&quot; this time There is a high probability that it will end hastily again. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;New &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Report&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; once again arouse people&#39;s attention to extraterrestrial creatures, The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) held a press conference at its headquarters in Washington, DC, on September 14, 2023, local time, and released the latest research report of an independent research team formed by the agency to study unknown anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA defines &quot;unidentified anomalies&quot; as &quot;observations in the sky that cannot be scientifically identified as aircraft or known natural phenomena.&quot; On June 9, 2022, NASA announced the establishment of this research team. The team is composed of 16 experts from different fields such as astronomy, physics, meteorology, etc. These disciplines have varying degrees of connection with the study of unknown anomalies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA believes that researchers have now obtained a certain number of high-quality observations of unknown abnormal events, and have the basic conditions to draw solid scientific conclusions about the nature of these events. Therefore, NASA established this independent research group to examine unidentified anomalies from a scientific perspective and develop a roadmap for how to use data and scientific tools to advance our understanding of unidentified anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public can download the 36-page report from NASA&#39;s official website. The report consists of several parts: the first part briefly introduces the research team and this report, the middle part answers questions such as how the team conducted the research in the form of 8 questions and answers, and the last part is the conclusions, suggestions and Acknowledgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team concluded in this report that there is currently no evidence to support the existence of aliens, and most UFO incidents can be explained by science. But at the same time, they haven&#39;t completely ruled out the possibility of aliens. While the conclusions are not unexpected, the report is important in suggesting what possible data NASA could collect in the future to explore the nature and origins of unidentified anomalies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a press release, NASA Administrator Bill Nelson said: &quot;At NASA, it&#39;s in our DNA to explore and ask why things are the way they are. I would like to express my gratitude to the independent research team for inspiring us on how to better study and analyze unidentified anomalies in the future.&quot; He also emphasized that NASA&#39;s goal is to shift people&#39;s discussion of unidentified anomalies from fantasy to science level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a press conference, NASA said that it has appointed a new director of unidentified anomaly research, who will lead the research team to strengthen artificial intelligence in the process of collecting and analyzing data and the use of machine learning. The report also highlights the need to enhance the application of new technologies in future research. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The answer may be on extrasolar planets&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Planet&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Efforts to find alien life on Earth are based on the fact that alien life has visited the Earth. Such a premise limits the search scope to intelligent creatures capable of reaching the earth. But just as life forms on Earth vary widely, if there is life elsewhere in the universe, it may not be intelligent life, but rudimentary forms like microorganisms on Earth. So when astronomers set their sights on the search for exoplanets, they will be on the lookout for any possible signs of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, at the James Webb Space Telescope’s first year of operation meeting held in Baltimore, Maryland, the United States, an international research team led by the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom announced the results of a famous satellite. This is the latest research result of the exoplanet K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. They found methane and carbon dioxide in the planet&#39;s atmosphere. This is the first time astronomers have found carbon-based molecules in the atmosphere of an exoplanet located in the habitable zone. At the same time, they may also have discovered what is believed to be a chemical on Earth. Chemical substances related to life activities. The research results will also be published in the Astrophysical Journal Letters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This exoplanet is 120 light-years away from the Earth, has a mass about 8.6 times that of the Earth, and a radius 2.6 times that of the Earth. It orbits the cold dwarf star K2-18 and is located in the habitable zone of this system. . Astronomers first probed the planet&#39;s atmosphere using the Hubble Space Telescope, but its composition was controversial at the time. After research, astronomers classified this planet into a category of exoplanets called &quot;Hycean exoplanet&quot;. Such planets have hydrogen-rich atmospheres and ocean-covered planetary surfaces. There are no planets of this size between Earth and Neptune in our solar system. Since then, they have used the James Webb Space Telescope to study the planet in more detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the high-resolution instruments of the James Webb Space Telescope, they confirmed in newly published research that the planet&#39;s atmosphere contains methane and carbon dioxide. At the same time, they also found a weak signal in the spectrum of K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. Analysis showed that this signal may be generated by a molecule called dimethyl sulphide (DMS). On Earth, we currently know that dimethyl sulfide can only be produced by life activities. Most of the dimethyl sulfide in the Earth&#39;s atmosphere is released by marine phytoplankton, which indicates that it may also exist on K2-18&amp;nbsp;b similar life activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our findings highlight the diverse considerations that need to be taken into account in the search for life elsewhere,” said Nikku Madhusudhan, an astronomer at the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom and lead author of the paper. The importance of habitable environments. The search for life on exoplanets has traditionally focused on smaller, rocky planets, but larger hydrogen-marine planets are clearly more amenable to atmospheric observations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, , astronomers still need further observations to confirm the existence of dimethyl sulfide. Madhusudhan said that subsequent observations by the James Webb Telescope will confirm whether dimethyl sulfide is indeed present in the atmosphere of K2-18&amp;nbsp;b. This research team believes that K2-18&amp;nbsp;b and other hydrogen sea planets may be excellent places for us to discover life outside the solar system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The James Webb Space Telescope has been in use for more than a year, demonstrating its powerful observation capabilities and constantly surprising astronomers. As more and more powerful space telescopes and ground-based telescopes are put into use, constructed or put on the development schedule, astronomers will gain increasingly powerful capabilities to observe exoplanets. Maybe discovering extraterrestrial life on Earth is just a fantasy, but if extraterrestrial life really exists, we will be able to detect signs of their activities on an exoplanet in the near future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/LdhG4qqa7a7vUhM2yf5FXKKIbvDGmUxPyUFpWymE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/LdhG4qqa7a7vUhM2yf5FXKKIbvDGmUxPyUFpWymE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Remains on display during a hearing in the Mexican Congress. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Reuters/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/03/2mapv6MsFjVZXXjxxbF70wRaXgQj9T8abzGIy1tm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2560&quot; height=&quot;1094&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/ 2mapv6MsFjVZXXjxxbF70wRaXgQj9T8abzGIy1tm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Member of NASA&#39;s Unidentified Anomaly Research Team. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（NASA/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/03/thCtXyW4lh5rn7bzhiFcHXpwr6JJ30BM9cjSnprR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/thCtXyW4lh5rn7bzhiFcHXpwr6JJ30 BM9cjSnprR .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic imagination of the exoplanet K2-18 b orbiting the cold dwarf star K2-18 picture. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(NASA/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南阳迷笛音乐节营地大量失窃上热搜：全力破案方能挽回声誉丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258070]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 15:28:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Halfway through the long holiday, the Midi Music Festival held in Nanyang, Henan suddenly appeared on the social media hot search list, not because How well done, but because - &quot;stealing things&quot;. For this city that was once famous for Zhuge Wolong, if the case cannot be solved as soon as possible, not only may the next Midi Music Festival be ruined, but it will also affect the reputation of the entire city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, the keywords &quot;Midi steals things&quot; quickly became hot topics on social media. According to information released by netizens at the scene, the music festival had ended the day before, and many music fans who participated in the music festival had not yet evacuated. However, a large number of nearby villagers went into the campground to search for things. According to Solitaire’s stolen property statistics, some people’s clothing and shoes were stolen, some wine and tea were stolen, some camping equipment such as tents, sleeping bags, and moisture-proof mats were lost, and high-value electronic and digital products such as computers, mobile phones, cameras, and recording equipment were stolen. Some &quot;thiefs&quot; only took away the tent, leaving other materials neatly in place. Even the fist-thick cables on the stage were stolen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to self-reported information by the thieves, the total value of the stolen materials may reach hundreds of thousands of yuan. A video circulating on the Internet shows a middle-aged woman who was caught taking something out of her bag while defending herself: &quot;We just went to get it when no one was there,&quot; as if the owner of the tent had temporarily left ( Maybe you go out to eat or even just use the toilet), the things in the tent become ownerless and can be taken as you please. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first original music festival in China, the Midi Music Festival with a history of more than 20 years has become one of the most famous carnivals in the Chinese music industry, especially rock music. For the venue where the music festival is held, tens of thousands of enthusiastic music fans from all over the country will not only bring direct income to the local area, but also become an excellent opportunity to promote the local area. Therefore, many cities, especially third- and fourth-tier cities, are competing to hold or invite large-scale music festivals to be held locally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Midi Music Festival was held in Nanyang and also received great attention from the local area. According to the official social media account &quot;Nanyang Release&quot; of the Nanyang Municipal Government Information Office, on September 29, the opening day of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival, the Secretary of the Nanyang Municipal Party Committee and the Mayor, wearing red volunteer uniforms, personally greeted the guests at the exit of Nanyang Railway Station. Music fans all over the country. Half a month ago, Nanyang City held a preparatory meeting for the Midi Music Festival. The Secretary of the Municipal Party Committee personally made arrangements and required the establishment of a high-standard headquarters at the municipal level to carefully carry out various guarantee work for the music festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening of the music festival, the Nanyang Municipal Government Information Office also released a city image promotional video and a local &quot;food, drink, and fun picture&quot; through its official account to promote local tourism resources. Such high-standard preparation and reception highlight the importance attached to the music festival. It was with this kind of attention that the music festival itself seemed to go without any problems. However, what was unexpected was that large-scale thefts occurred after the festival. It can be said that the previous efforts were ruined. This makes the previous official statement of “protecting the personal and property safety of tourists” a joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to theft, netizens who attended the music festival accused some people of harassing tourists in the name of toasting during dinner in the hotel, and even beating tourists while drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This information spreads rapidly through social networks. If the local area fails to take prompt measures to identify problems such as theft and harassment, it will greatly damage the image of the local area. In addition to the stolen music fans who said that if there is no result in handling this incident, they will never visit Nanyang again. Some netizens also said that they felt very unsafe after watching the video of the villagers taking things away, and they will definitely do so when traveling in the future. Avoid this place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the descriptions of the thieves and live music fans, most of the thieves were local villagers, who even used tricycles to pull the items. This scene can&#39;t help but remind people of the situations that have happened in many places before where villagers stole the crops of foreign agricultural entrepreneurs. It was reported in the summer of 2019 that a sweet potato farmer in Henan contracted 200 acres of land to grow watermelons. When the watermelons matured, nearby villagers gathered in groups to steal the melons. A melon-picking incident also occurred in Jiaxing, Zhejiang, where almost all the watermelons from more than 20 greenhouses were stolen. Some melon thieves were even caught by melon farmers and fell to the ground and were &quot;injured&quot; during the pulling process. Instead, the melon farmers were asked to pay compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these theft incidents, some places often use various excuses to excuse local farmers. For example, it is not &quot;theft&quot;, but they believe the rumor that &quot;the owner doesn&#39;t want it anymore&quot;, or there are people in the local area who are not the owners. The tradition of “picking up the leaks” after harvesting, etc. In the Midi Music Festival theft incident, some participants alleged that after catching the thief and calling the police, the police let the villagers go because &quot;there was no evidence to prove the theft.&quot; If the property of participants cannot be protected for a large-scale event that the government attaches so much importance to, who will dare to come here in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that the quality of villagers in some places is not high, they are greedy for petty gains, and their legal awareness is weak. They have the idea that the law does not punish the public, and they feel that taking some things from &quot;outsiders&quot; will not do anything. If local officials do not take severe measures to punish these thieving villagers and cannot effectively protect the interests of foreign tourists or investors, and their reputation is ruined, no one will dare to travel or invest here again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement from the Midi Music Festival Organizing Committee, the local police have set up a task force to investigate the theft cases. Some fans also reported that some of the stolen items had been recovered. This time Nanyang must make every effort to solve the case, recover the stolen goods, reduce the losses of music fans, and at the same time severely punish the thieves without mercy. Only in this way can it be possible to restore the reputation, restore the music festival, restore the music fans, and restore the tourists from all over the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[颜歌：英语世界里的少数族裔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/ERThthpwjc4pFBkH71171Fy2GAIFQY7zJqMvpifj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ERThthpwjc4pFBkH71171Fy2GAIFQY7z JqMvpifj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Feng Xiaoping/Picture)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in the summer of 2017, Yan Ge was vaccinating her one-month-old son at a clinic in Dublin when she suddenly received an email from Irish writer Lucy Caldwell. She was invited to contribute to Faber&#39;s short story collection Being Various: New Irish Short Stories ( &quot;Short Story Collection&quot;&lt;/span>;) Write a novel. Lucy is the editor of this collection. She had read two of Yan Gefa&#39;s stories in the &quot;Irish Times&quot; and found them interesting, so she came here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ge still remembers her shock at that time: first of all, she was an outsider, no one in the Irish literary world knew her, she had only published two novels in newspapers; secondly, she was the only one in Ireland. How did you become an Irish writer after living for a few years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that email that made Yan Ge feel unreal, Lucy greatly broadened the concept of Irish writers - this concept should include writers who were born in Ireland but grew up elsewhere, and writers who were chosen from elsewhere. Writers who call Ireland home include those who somehow find themselves living in Ireland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What happened next unfolded smoothly. Yan Ge wrote a story that took place in Dublin, &quot;How I Fell in Love with the Well-Documented Life of Alex Whelan&quot;, which was well received and included in this new collection of Irish short stories. The first article (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Published in 2019&lt;/span>;). Later, Angus, the editor of &quot;Different: A Collection of New Irish Short Stories&quot; and director of Faber Publishing, learned that Yan Ge was writing a collection of short stories and approached his agent, Matt, hoping to She gave Faber exclusive preview rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fNclzsO4zmmZmaYmqR2Fj9t55L8glzuUoiCpIvtK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1279&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fNclzsO4zmmZmaYmqR2Fj9t55L8glzuUoiCpIvtK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yan Ge visited Wangcong Temple in his hometown of Pi County when he was a child&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faber is a purely literary publishing organization founded in 1921. It has published the works of 13 Nobel Prize writers and 6 Booker Prize writers. There will be no sky-high royalties, and packaging and promotion will not cost as much as cutting-edge companies. If it is not given to Faber, the agent will submit the work to various publishing houses. If multiple publishing houses compete for the manuscript, it will be auctioned. As a result, the manuscript may be sold at a relatively high price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Matt believes that Faber is suitable for Yan Ge’s work. It is of stable quality, responsible, and can be cooperated for a long time. Moreover, the editors of this book are Kazuo Ishiguro and Sebastian. Barry&#39;s managing editor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally Faber was given exclusive preview rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The exclusive preview period generally does not exceed 10 days. Faber responded quickly. He sent the message on Friday and gave the quotation on Wednesday. After the two parties negotiated, it was determined on Thursday that he would buy the rights to two books, including the completed &quot;Elsewhere&quot; and another book scheduled to be delivered in 2024. The novel &quot;Hotel Destination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This means that the next five years are almost bought out.&quot; Yan Ge is worried that the second book is due to be delivered in April 2024 according to the contract, and because of the Chinese novel &quot;Pingle County Chronicles&quot; All work is behind schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The veteran American literary publisher Scribner will also acquire the copyright for Yan Ge’s collection of short stories and the 2024 novel. Scribner published works by Hemingway and Fitzgerald. It was later acquired by Simon &amp; Schuster and became the company&#39;s flagship publishing house. It also published books by pure literary writers such as Annie Proulx. , and also publishes works by Stephen King, the master of horror novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/JN1pQDJEs7PrVeKtiyHqlhyTdiV0MdHfQob3MpvM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/JN1pQDJEs7PrVeKtiyHqlhyTdiV0MdHfQob3MpvM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The signing process with Scribner went smoothly beyond Yan Ge&#39;s expectations. The editor-in-chief and two young editors chatted with Yan Ge over video for an afternoon about the work, and in the evening they settled on North American rights with their agent. Next, the Italian copyright was also negotiated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ge felt a bit like selling futures at the time: &quot;The unfinished novel was sold directly like this. This was the first time in my writing career of more than 20 years. Yes. It may not be a big deal for an English writer, but it is unimaginable for a writer whose mother tongue is Chinese and writes in English.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2023, &quot;Elsewhere&quot; will be published in the UK and the United States. , winning praise from media outlets including The Irish Times, The Guardian, The New York Times and The New Yorker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2023, Yan Ge took her son and husband back to Chengdu after three years of COVID-19. To be precise, back to Pidu District (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Originally known as Pixian County&lt;/span>;) - her hometown - the birthplace of her story of Pingle Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Xis0q8rlqbXScWzR65rY41RJobjmCII9eySPGN9Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1611&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Xis0q8rlqbXScWzR65rY41RJobjmCII9eySPGN9Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; We are here to oppose English”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will interview you in the summer of 2018 At that time, you were embarking on a creative writing project in the UK, published two novels in the &quot;Irish Times&quot;, and had just completed one of Faber&#39;s &quot;New Irish Novels&quot;. It was a year later that you got an agent. matter. What impressed me most is that you metaphorically joined the &quot;Special Olympics&quot; in the English literary world. Five years later, you have become an English writer signed with a first-class international literary publishing house. Do you still feel like a Paralympian? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t feel that way anymore. English writing is a new career for me now, and I face many problems, but they are not so-called language problems, or language is the most superficial problem, and it may not even be considered a problem compared with other problems. English writing is a kind of artistic self-exploration for me. If I were an artist, my medium would be words. Now I am using a new way, new tools, new materials and media to make works. This new medium will bring a new change to my works. This is the most important thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember the last interview, you were right I said there is nothing terrible about writing in English. The tone is exactly the same as now. Is there any substantial difference between the two? For example, five years ago you were more free to enjoy the freedom of expression that the new language brought to you. Now , after strict writing training in the English literary tradition, have you found some kind of certainty in your writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/eHU1AudW5hab48AceoNgsAEGGT6WpLwPg9ssMeN6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1606&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/eHU1AudW5hab48AceoNgsAEGGT6WpLwPg9ssMeN6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Definitely. During the process of studying and living in the UK, I read more and more things in depth, which must be related. I think these are also based on my culture. After all, I am a Chinese writer, so my literary system and narrative system are Chinese. Although I now understand more or less how the other system works, I feel that Chinese is still my language. The root of this is that, ultimately, the way of thinking about Chinese and Chinese literature is an anti-dualistic way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the English-speaking world, the writing of minority writers like us is a kind of post-colonial cultural expression that must subvert the so-called orthodox English. This is why English as a This is a fate that postcolonial language must face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Irish writers are probably the first group of writers in the world to write in this post-colonial way, and they are also anti-English. After the British occupied Ireland, Irish became an illegal language. If you spoke Irish, you would be fined and arrested. My husband is Irish. As an intellectual and journalist, he always tells me that you can write in English however you want. We are here to oppose this language anyway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So when I returned to Ireland, I felt like I was returning to my second natal home. Dublin was the last stop for the promotion of my new English book. As a result, all the tickets for the sharing session were sold out, the venue was full, and there were people sitting on the windowsill. , I was very moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/avrzkseviR85yr9K8a9wqJRvjyUOm3eLrZSKA2Ll.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1673&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/avrzkseviR85yr9K8a9wqJRvjyUOm3eLrZSKA2Ll.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In that environment, no one will care about your language. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, no one will think about this problem. It may have something to do with Irish culture. Everyone thinks this is a natural thing. The two stories I submitted to The Irish Times were published directly by the editor, which made me feel like I had landed in front of English readers. Originally, I was waiting for the editor to give me a lot of revision comments. Gradually, I learned that newspapers here have this tradition and are not very good at changing the author&#39;s manuscripts. Only magazines and books have an editorial process. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/s6ywYWgeztUMcCVqMgdxXBeSyPXZlFhN0QU0bxL5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1674&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/s6ywYWgeztUMcCVqMgdxXBeSyPXZlFhN0QU0bxL5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In the English writing circle, everyone reads and comments on each other&#39;s manuscripts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;When you first write in English, do you show it to your husband first? I remember when I interviewed Ha Jin in 2001, he said that when he first wrote a novel, he would check whether the words were authentic to his son who was born in the United States. At that time, he had just won the National Book Award in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Some of them will be read to him. My husband is my first reader. When I write Chinese, I will also translate it orally to him. share. But if it involves a subject with a Chinese cultural background, it will not be shown to him, but to people who do not understand Chinese culture at all. For example, there is an article &quot;Hai&quot; (Hai) in &quot;Elsewhere&quot;, which is about Confucius and his disciples. It also alludes to the British political system. People without a Chinese cultural background will see a completely different connotation. I asked a historical novelist to read the manuscript, which was more than 20,000 words. She read it carefully and wrote a lot of feedback. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the English writing circle, one thing that I like very much is that everyone reads each other&#39;s manuscripts, devotes a lot of time and energy to each other&#39;s works, and also gives sharp opinions. . My agent was also one of my early readers. This atmosphere is particularly healthy. These people I trust allow me to be bolder and try more things and experiment with more languages ​​without looking forward or backward. It’s like I’m doing acrobatics in this language. Even if I fall down, there are still people. then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chinese writers don’t do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Chinese literature talks about genius. I prefer the workshop tradition among British and American literary creative groups. Discussions and discussions give me the feeling of being in a community. A girlfriend of mine sent me a manuscript that she had revised 36 times and asked me to make further comments. Chinese writers would avoid doing this because it would cast doubt on their own genius. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My soon-to-be-published Chinese novel &quot;Pingle County Chronicles&quot; is the product of many years of work behind closed doors. When I first finished it, I was very scared and didn&#39;t know how to write it. I sent it to &quot;Harvest&quot; When editing, I especially hope she can give me feedback. For example, for many ancient poems in the book, I asked the editor to find professionals to help review them. If no one comments, I&#39;m like running around naked, which is terrible. I am probably used to the way Western creative writing groups operate, and I am afraid that others will not give me advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zsh2qmh3keyX0vJMj2Y08Uu0P6vmIJHDLtiRydRp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1671&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zsh2qmh3keyX0vJMj2Y08Uu0P6vmIJHDLtiRydRp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; The editor wanted me to delete the redundant convoluted parts.&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When writing in English, have you ever imagined what your readers are like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yan Ge: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I write in Chinese, I can imagine my readers. I am not necessarily writing for them, but there is probably an implicit reference to the readers. concept. But when writing in English, I feel a sense of panic all the time - I can&#39;t imagine what the reader looks like. He is definitely not white, but I don&#39;t know who he is - he has no face and no identity. I wasn&#39;t a first or second generation immigrant either, just someone stuck there temporarily, and imaginary readers became one of my biggest problems. Then there is the feeling of doing an academic experiment. According to my own interests, if I get to this point today, I will write this, and if I get to that point tomorrow, I will write that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这也是《在别处》里那些小说题材各异、写作手法也非常不同的原因？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;颜歌：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是的。我用中文写作的时候非常rooted——就很扎根儿，这样可以吸取营养，很踏实，但同时也是牵绊，被固定住了。英文写作就是rootless，非常不安定，又充满活力和可能性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在你的第一本英文短篇小说集出版了，你对你的读者是哪些人心里有底了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;颜歌：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我在英国的读书活动和签售会上遇到各种少数族裔写作者，他们觉得我的作品激发着他们——他们跟我说我这样的身份用这样的方式写了这样的书，让他们非常感动。每到一处都有这样的人，他们很年轻，很多是在读创意写作的少数族裔作者。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我很开心，我发现我就是为这些人而写的，我们这些少数族裔作者相互作用，一起撑开了一个新的英文写作空间，我只是给这个空间多加了一些可能性，比如说最表面化的表达就是，你可以在英文小说里加中文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于“读者”的讨论，很容易陷入一种二元论的陷阱。一般想到的英文读者，一定是白人为主的主流社会，我觉得这个想法还挺原始，挺80 年代的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从你的经纪人到你的图书编辑基本都是白人、男性，代表了某种权利中心，你的作品被英国和美国著名的老牌出版社出版，是否代表着你在向某个中心靠近？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;颜歌：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;作为一个少数族裔写作者，我写的英文本质上一定是在反英文（Against English）。不是想去加入所谓的英语文学（English literature），而是用英语作为语言来完成的文学（Literatures in English）。我的这个出发点，我的经纪人和编辑们都非常支持。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就当下的语境来说，如果认为像我这样的人一定需要去敲门，进入某个中心，那么本质上是对盎格鲁中心的崇拜和屈服。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果你不是为白人读者而写或者不想进入主流，那你除了从文本的角度——比如放一些中国古诗乃至汉字——来挑战传统英文的阅读习惯，有没有从其他的角度来表态？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;颜歌：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不会排斥某一个群体，也不会特别去讨好某一个群体。比如我的小说集里有本地的白人形象，但也有中文的东西，有汉字，也有中国传统文学的非线性时间结构，甚至反精简。但我也希望每个类型的读者都能够进入我的文本里面，能够在他离开的时候有他自己的理解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且文本的部分不可解读性，也是在我的计划之中的，把某些段落和细节做成一个乍看之下彻底陌生的事物，也是我的表达的一部分。其实跟我写四川话的状态有点像，我写四川话不是拒绝普通话的读者，只是想保留四川话的那种特性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WfloG6z6i6dlSkOIHtTQzdDOmxz72QNSy24Djnlf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1220&quot; height=&quot;994&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WfloG6z6i6dlSkOIHtTQzdDOmxz72QNSy24Djnlf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《在别处》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《在别处》这个集子里，它有点像是一种混杂物，会有一些西方文学传统意义上的小说，但也有汉语的逻辑和中国文学的价值观。比如说，在“Travel in the Summer”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《在夏天旅行时》&lt;/span>;）里，我想表达很多事情，里面故意有些闲笔，这种手法在英文小说里按理说是不行的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我记得最开始在加拿大一个杂志发这个故事的时候，编辑觉得故事很好，但想让我把那些多余的绕来绕去的部分删了。我那时候觉得有点为难，本来作为一个写作者，我是很愿意接受人家的意见的，但那次最后还是给她写了封很长的邮件，说这是一个中国古代的故事，那么我希望这个古典的中国既是内容上的，也是形式上的。我说这个故事的主角是沈括，他的书就是想要囊括宇宙万物，这个包含性（inclusiveness） 也是这个故事的重点。我还说了关于含蓄和闲笔的一些背景，最后她被我说服了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;说到用英语写作的华裔作家，人们会提起哈金或者李翊云，他们和你的背景完全不同，他们是到了美国才开始写作，而你出国之前已经是崭露头角的小说家，作品被翻译成十几种文字，作为中国移民作家中的“第二代”，你怎么看待自己的身份？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/NWvZdPVElVapeMpBJCve26MW33AJ2eJMOjzFhIDQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1694&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/NWvZdPVElVapeMpBJCve26MW33AJ2eJMOjzFhIDQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;从左至右分别为翻译Natasha Bruce、加拿大小说家Madeleine Thien、颜歌《我们家》翻译Nicky Harman、颜歌在泰晤士报文学节后合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;颜歌：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;应该说我是很幸运的，因为我的确是在中文文学里写得更多更久，总觉得中文是我的主场，我只是来英文世界玩票的，所以我还是比较有底气的，凭什么去讨好白人？我感觉我的作品的去二元性更强，如果让我写得像个白人一样，我不愿意，这对我来说没有任何意义，是一件特别荒谬的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一件幸运的事情是，哈金、李翊云他们已经帮我们这代作家完成了题材上的探索，写了很多的“中国故事”，我们这一代再用英文写作，题材可以更广泛，形式可以更自由。李翊云的第一部短篇小说集，我十多年前第一次出国的时候读到，当时看不出来有什么好，那本书实际上就不是为我这样的中国读者写的。现在她的作品早就走出了当时的框框，越来越开阔，越来越好。从某种程度来讲，正是因为当年白人主流社会需要的那种“中国故事”已经被写过了，现在的她和我们很多人才能从这个刻板印象里走出来，写和中国有关的或无关的，写现实的或者虚拟的世界，写中世纪或者科幻未来，内容上和形式上都可以更加天马行空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（采访助理：朱朱。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子10米台，全红婵失误后反超以微弱优势夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258066]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 13:00:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72935&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69789&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/50c67b3a66.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐将各自的可爱玩偶捧在手上。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐将各自的可爱玩偶捧在手上。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/50c67b3a66.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252983&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐将各自的可爱玩偶捧在手上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月3日傍晚，杭州亚运会跳水项目女子单人10米台的冠军争夺战，成为了全红婵和陈芋汐这对队友之间的竞争。全红婵最终以438.20分摘得金牌，陈芋汐以2.55分的差距摘得银牌。中国跳水“梦之队”毫无悬念地包揽该项目的冠亚军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72929&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69783&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/a6c83674bf.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。她在最后一跳逆风翻盘，赢得冠军。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。她在最后一跳逆风翻盘，赢得冠军。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/a6c83674bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252984&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。她在最后一跳逆风翻盘，赢得冠军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72933&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69787&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fa82db0998.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，赛后，全红婵向观众招手致意。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，赛后，全红婵向观众招手致意。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fa82db0998.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252985&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，赛后，全红婵向观众招手致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在比赛过程中，全红婵在第二跳发挥完美，7名裁判都打出了10分的满分！第三跳，陈芋汐也不甘示弱，同样拿下3个10分。但在第四跳中，全红婵在207的动作上出现失误，被陈芋汐反超。最后一跳，全红婵发挥完美再度实现逆转。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72930&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69784&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/dd421d9df2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/dd421d9df2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252986&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72931&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69785&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0bfc42fa6a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。在第三跳，陈芋汐同样拿下了3个10分。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。在第三跳，陈芋汐同样拿下了3个10分。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0bfc42fa6a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252987&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队陈芋汐在比赛中。在第三跳，陈芋汐同样拿下了3个10分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赛后，陈芋汐和全红婵也是紧紧地抱在了一起。此前在杭州亚运会女子双人10米台的比赛中，全红婵就和陈芋汐搭档，以“断层式领先”的优势夺冠，分数比第二名高了85.26分。自从全红婵在东京奥运会单人10米台夺金之后，她就和陈芋汐一起开启了对10米跳台的统治。在队友之间的强强对话中，两位运动员之间的相互竞争和促进，对于中国跳水队是一个积极的现象。&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72932&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69786&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/811a20585d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/811a20585d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252988&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队全红婵在比赛中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据悉，杭州亚运会跳水项目于2023年9月30日至10月4日在杭州奥体中心游泳馆举行，总共将产生10枚金牌。在已经决出金牌的8个项目上，中国队全部摘金。10月4日是最后一个比赛日，中国跳水“梦之队”依旧剑指冠军，目标包揽所有小项的金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72934&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69788&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/87c324647a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐展示着手里的奖牌。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐展示着手里的奖牌。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/87c324647a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252989&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，全红婵和陈芋汐展示着手里的奖牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[硬气王哲林爆扣韩国队，中国男篮领先14分胜韩国队进入半决赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258064]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:38:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72924&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69778&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员王哲林在比赛中扣篮。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员王哲林在比赛中扣篮。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252974&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队球员王哲林在比赛中扣篮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月3日中午，杭州亚运会男子篮球1/4决赛，中国男篮以84比70战胜韩国男篮，晋级亚运会四强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国男篮在小组赛经受考验后，迎来了本届亚运会的争冠热门球队之一韩国队。与其他亚洲强队相比，韩国队本届亚运会基本是全主力出战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72925&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69779&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，胡明轩在比赛中带球突破。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，胡明轩在比赛中带球突破。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252975&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，胡明轩在比赛中带球突破。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72927&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69781&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1ecd290854.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员赵睿在比赛中上篮。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员赵睿在比赛中上篮。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1ecd290854.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252976&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队球员赵睿在比赛中上篮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72922&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69776&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员胡金秋在比赛中上篮。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员胡金秋在比赛中上篮。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252977&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队球员胡金秋在比赛中上篮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72921&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69775&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252978&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，中国队球员张镇麟在扣篮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国男篮掌握节奏，攻防俱佳，展现出了十足的拼劲，上半场领先20分。下半场，中国男篮失误相对增多，但在防守端依旧强硬，牢牢守住优势，最终以84比70战胜韩国队，打进半决赛。从本场比赛可以看出中国男篮球员的斗志，朱俊龙、胡金秋多次主动倒地拼抢地板球；赵睿开局阶段强势突破连连得分；杜润旺出色地完成了外线投射的任务，在防守端也竭尽全力……中国男篮为了赢得这场比赛确实下了功夫。全场比赛，杜润旺16分、胡金秋14分7篮板、赵睿8分但是有6次失误、朱俊龙16分、张镇麟9分、胡明轩10分、赵继伟5分8助攻、王哲林6分。&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72923&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69777&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252979&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;此前中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此前的采访中，中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇曾多次明确，作为卫冕冠军，中国男篮在杭州亚运会的目标就是夺冠。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72926&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69780&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1:4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1/4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252980&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，杭州亚运会男子篮球1/4决赛，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明在场边观战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;接下来，中国男篮将在10月4日20时的半决赛中，对阵曾在世界杯赛场击败过我们的菲律宾男篮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72928&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69782&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252981&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，为中国队欢呼喝彩的现场观众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[莫斯吾冰川：人迹罕至，傲然挺立丨眼睛在旅游⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王笛：茶馆里的历史学家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV10jWfkJLuh9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV10jWfkJLuh9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在成都人民公园鹤鸣茶社&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（华小峰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;公共空间&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;历史学家王笛的《茶馆：成都公共生活的衰落与复兴1950—2000》在成都有杏书店举办了新书分享会。书店创办者张丰在书店门口舞台前摆上了传统的茶座：一张桌子，三张竹椅，三杯盖碗茶，一个温水瓶。张丰作为主持人，坐在右边。左边坐的是艺术家王亥，他是王笛当年在成都三中的同学。王笛坐在中间，不需要说话的时候，他不时地给身边的两位倒水。这让张丰感到不好意思。王笛则说：我是茶博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;活动结束后的晚上，我和王笛在有杏书店的路灯下，聊到10点多钟。王笛意识到时间已经很晚，问在一旁等待的张丰：“书店开到几点？”张丰说：“可以一直开着，只要我们乐意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几个月之前，新冠疫情尚未结束，在成都郊区的敦壩酒吧，张丰和在剑桥大学攻读人类学博士的灵子主持了王笛的一次分享会，没有主题，想讲什么就讲什么。王笛从晚上7点半讲到午夜12点，灵子暂停了聊天，让现场围坐的一百多位听众休息一下。王笛以为讲完了。但灵子告诉他，这只是中场休息时间。王笛第二天早上要飞澳门，我以为他会说，今天太晚了，就到这儿吧。没想到他说，今天我舍命陪君子了。活动一直持续到凌晨1点多。这是成都公共空间里令人惊叹的蓬勃气息，参与其中的人会忘记时间。这是“十日谈”，但远不止“十日”。在有杏书店和敦壩，我都见到了风哥，他似乎永远不停地在发布成都公共空间里的各种活动。我赞叹他的精力，他说这没什么，很简单的，不需要花什么时间。我也再次见到了张颖律师，她来参加王笛的分享会，她自己主持的“明亮的对话”仍在运行，她希望人们身处其中，能学到思考的意识，而不只是说话的技巧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛如今回成都，受邀的活动众多，几乎都是从早说到晚。他对各种问题都保持足够的耐心，尽管很多相似的问题他已经回答过许多遍。他出现在各种媒体上。他乐于向大众讲述他的历史研究和写作。他的名字与他研究的主要领域中的“街头文化”、“袍哥”和“茶馆”相连。他关心人与空间的关系，沟通着具体的词与物。他思考历史对于当下的意义，愿意将自己的思考传播到更广阔的范围。他成了广受欢迎的历史学家之一。在分享会上，张丰说到日渐兴起的“公共史学”，称王笛为“茶馆里的历史学家”。他们谈话的背景，四周是通透的，我能看到背景板后边，老阿姨们安逸地坐在竹椅上聊天，戴头盔的快递小哥提着外卖走来，骑电单车的人穿行而过。这是成都市民生活的自然叠加，构成了层次丰富的视觉景观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《茶馆：成都公共生活的衰落与复兴1950—2000》可简称为《茶馆（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;下&lt;/span>;）》。在《茶馆（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;上&lt;/span>;）》，也就是《茶馆：成都的公共生活和微观世界1900—1950》中，王笛比较过四川和其他地方的茶馆，比如广东的茶楼。“广东一般称茶楼，表面看起来像四川的茶馆，但显然是为中产阶级服务的，与四川的&#39;平民化&#39;茶馆不同。”在形容广东茶楼时，王笛用了“堂皇”一词。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在澳门，为了直观地与四川茶馆进行比较，王笛带我们去位于上葡京的一家粤式茶楼喝早茶。这家茶楼更像是精致的餐厅，桌面上菜品的摆设远多于茶具。服务员用手推车给我们端来叉烧酥和萝卜糕。餐桌上已经有烧鹅、虾饺、汤包、烧卖、牛腩和鱼羹。这顿丰盛的早茶，花费一千多块澳门元。周围的设计也颇费心思，墙壁的装饰设计成蒸笼一样的纹理，让人有热气蒸腾之感。王笛曾身处这样的热气蒸腾之中。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;转折年代&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当天正好是内地的高考时间，而澳门的学校开始放假。澳门的高中生不需要高考，他们都是通过申请上大学。王笛觉得现在内地的小孩太内卷了。“我们喜欢帝王史观，其实是崇尚做人上人。我们瞧不起普通人，所以希望自己的孩子不要做普通人。让每个普通人有尊严地生活，这才是我们应该提倡的。这是我强调平民史观的原因。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mW0sgmuN7YkrFjGnaL409XWSgtaZHI3NHYzg1FwI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mW0sgmuN7YkrFjGnaL409XWSgtaZHI3NHYzg1FwI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月17日，王笛在成都有杏书店分享新书&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者卫毅/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛想起自己的过去。1977年恢复高考的时候，王笛正好在上海出差。他回成都工作两年了，之前在苏东坡的老家眉山下乡插队。他哥哥彼时已经去了云南生产建设兵团，他本可以不下乡，但是不下乡的话，没有任何前途可言，不能安排工作。“我还是想着下乡，下乡的话，可能还有推荐上大学的机会。”王笛自愿下乡，表现很好，但还是没有获得推荐上大学的机会。1975年，通过招工，他回到成都，进了成都铁路局机械分局砖瓦厂。“烧砖烧瓦，绝对的重体力劳动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我在砖窑班。砖窑是椭圆形的，火是不灭的，沿着火边，有很多的窑火循环，进去以后就像隧道一样，你从这个窑把砖运出来，就这个天气，三伏天，进去，火是热的，进去只穿短裤，戴口罩，都是汗水啊，只有两个眼睛露出来，窑灰很重啊。几个人把砖摞上去，节奏一样快，就像做运动一样。当时的粮票是定量的，普通居民每人每月26斤，我们因为是重体力劳动，粮票是46斤。看到这个对比，就知道这个劳动有多重了。一般工厂是8小时工作制，我们是4小时工作制，因为不能太累。这是大家都不愿意去的地方。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在砖厂工作一年多，因为会画画，王笛被调到工会。他画了很多画，刷了许多标语。他想成为画家，但没有机会。没能成为画家，但这项业余技能还是让他有机会从重体力劳动中解脱出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时代的变化，让他获得了上大学的机会。中美建交的时候，他更是真切地觉得时代变了。刚上大学不久的王笛，在1978年12月16日的日记上，写下了这样几句话：“真是一个杰出的创举，伟大的一步，中美正式建交了。多少年来的积怨，将很快消除。上午我们正在一教楼上政经课，听到了这一重要新闻，大家兴奋得涨红了脸，当听到邓副主席明年一月将访问美国时，全部鼓起掌来，这充分说明了人心所向。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Xspu7YCSZb2PIyHt7ntjioMvMMeTtwV4asBjCpVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Xspu7YCSZb2PIyHt7ntjioMvMMeTtwV4asBjCpVg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在四川大学历史系的毕业合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那一天的情形虽然过去了很多年，但仍然印在王笛的脑海。历史系77和78级两百多人在一教楼最大的教室上政治经济学课。因为是大课，教室有收音和扩音设备。课间休息时，不知是哪位同学把收音机打开，借着扩音器，大家听到了中央人民广播电台正在播放中美建交的新闻。喧闹的教室安静下来，接着，大家鼓起掌来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澳门大学的教学楼很安静。图书馆里正举办澳门大学教职人员艺术展。王笛的三幅画参加了展览，而他忙于工作，还没有去看过。他带着我们在图书馆里转了好几圈才找到展厅。他的画放在展厅最显眼的位置，三幅人物肖像分别是费正清、詹姆斯·斯科特和卡洛·金茨堡，这是他欣赏的三位学者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;费正清在给芭芭拉·塔奇曼写史迪威的一本书作序时说：“长期以来，美国试图使中国跟自己更相似的努力——这是个堂吉诃德式的努力，但是屡败屡试，现在这种努力又再度兴起了……&#39;最后，中国走了自己的道路，就仿佛美国人从来没有去过那里似的。&#39;”王笛觉得费正清毕生的努力都在加强中美两国人民之间的理解和友谊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛在德克萨斯A&amp;amp;M大学给本科生上课时，曾收集了美国媒体关于“五四”运动的报道，以便让学生能够根据这些原始资料写论文。这些资料让他吃惊，基本上没有被历史学家们使用过。“美国媒体主要是围绕中国发生的重大事件的报道，也有一些中国社会和文化的介绍和分析，以及关于中国的经济和教育。而我使用的个人记录以及媒体对个人的采访，则是从他们自己的眼睛看到的中国，有细节、有故事、有感受，在相当大程度上弥补了大事件后面个人命运和体验的缺失。”个人和细节一直是王笛所强调的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澳门是辛亥革命的重要策源地之一。孙中山当年在这里行医，镜湖医院前有孙中山塑像。王笛推荐我去看马礼逊的墓。“在白鸽巢附近，很有历史感。”王笛的历史学家朋友杨念群、孙江来澳门的时候，他带他们去过。马礼逊编辑出版了第一部英汉字典——《华英字典》，第一个将《圣经》翻译成中文，并在澳门开办了第一家中西医结合的诊所。他是中西方交流的开创性人物，而澳门在历史上一直是中西方交流的桥头堡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在澳门大学的住处，一条航道从阳台下的海面通过。海水的一边是澳门，一边是珠海。看到海岸，王笛会想起在美国钓鱼的日子。他有两大爱好：钓鱼和种菜。他在阳台上种了很多东西——田七、黄瓜、木耳菜……钓鱼的爱好则放了下来。“一个教授在大学旁的海岸边钓鱼总是不太好。”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（笑）&lt;/span>;在自己的阳台上，他从未看到有人在滩涂上钓鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛在中国内地和美国的大学都教过书，如今来到澳门，他觉得又增加了一个思考历史的角度。身处中西交界的地方，对他的研究有帮助。疫情三年，许多学术会议都停了。在澳门和我们吃了这顿饭之后，王笛要去香港，参加中外历史学者的一次会议。会议对大家没有论文要求，只是谈谈最近的一些想法。王笛打算坐巴士去香港，走港珠澳大桥。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;读书&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在澳门，王笛很少去茶楼。他喜欢路边摊。他介绍我们去白鸽巢附近一家铺子吃咖喱牛肉汤。“铺子就在街边，食客就在街上吃，很好吃，我每次路过都要吃。”这种临街铺子家里出来的小孩，用王笛的同学王亥的话来说，就是“街娃儿”。王亥说自己就是“街娃儿”，跟在大院里长大的王笛不一样，“街娃儿”需要更强的混的能力，才能混出来。王亥觉得艺术家可以混出来，但历史学家混不出来。这是两者的区别。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，王笛和流沙河做过一次对谈，这让他感到紧张。小时候，他和流沙河都住在四川文联的院子里，会和哥哥到流沙河那里听故事。住在这个院子里的还有沙汀、艾芜等人。王笛的历史写作有文学性和审美性的自我要求，大概与他从小身处的人文环境的熏陶有关。但那并不是平静的日子。他想读书的时候，要偷偷爬进文联图书馆的书库，那是看书如做贼的年代。王笛小学只读了三年，初中和高中也没有完整地读过，高中因为政审，差点失去升学的机会。但他爱好读书的习惯还是帮助了他，当高考突然恢复的时候，他没有那么措手不及。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1977年恢复高考的时候，王笛21岁，在铁路局工会工作。火车票免费，可以到处走。工会待遇很好，会分到一些稀缺商品。父母觉得铁路局的工作是铁饭碗，即便读了大学，毕业分配的工作也不见得比现在好，建议他再等两年，等工作满五年之后就可以带薪读书，毕业后还可以回原单位。听了父母的话，王笛没有参加1977年的高考。高考那天，他正好去上海出差。那时候他的身份虽然是工人，但“以工代干”，就是以工人的身份做干部的事情，看上去挺安逸。在上海，他正好看到考生进入高考考场。这样的场景对他是一个刺激。他觉得很失落，“有一种被时代遗弃了的感觉。”那一刻他决定，明年一定得考，“不能再等了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他偷偷准备，不敢告诉父母。“怕他们一劝，我又放弃了怎么办。”那时候他住单位，每周回家一次，回去也不提，考完后才告诉父母。父母还是很高兴。成绩相当不错，历史考得特别好。原本想读中文系，其实还是想画画，觉得读中文系和艺术沾点边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在成都鹤鸣茶社第一次见到王笛的时候，头一天晚上，他刚参加了大学同学毕业40周年的聚会。同学们还记得，王笛是当年四川大学历史系78级第一个被录取的学生。历史满分100分，他考了96分。他去报到的时候，是1号。“其实我那时候对什么是历史研究根本不懂，只是喜欢看一些历史书而已。”大学同学的成分很复杂。刚入学的时候，班上最小的同学16岁，最大的32岁。“现在分不出年龄来了，差不多都退休了。同学们有专门旅游的群、专门喝酒的群、专门打麻将的群。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大学同学中像王笛这样还在工作的人，很少。王笛是澳门大学讲座教授，可以到70岁退休。同学们为了40周年聚会，打算集体到安仁镇玩两天。王笛有事情，得回澳门。成都的同学决定提前一天在成都聚一下，为了能见一下王笛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛行事低调，每次回成都都是静悄悄地来，静悄悄地走。这次回成都，有多场公开活动，躲不了了，大家聚了一下。“我不愿意变成主角，别人为你做活动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他去看了父母。父母九十多岁，住在养老院里。过去在成都的大量书籍，由于多年闲置未用，他都捐给了川大，让研究生们分了。现在，他有点怀念那些书。他就是用那些书写出了自己的第一本书——《跨出封闭的世界》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在海外这么多年，他用新收集的研究资料写出了《街头文化》、《袍哥》、《茶馆》等著作。成都双流区目前正在筹办一个王笛文献中心，他收集的那些资料以后会放到这里，可以让其他有需要的研究者使用。王笛刚去看过这个地方。文献中心两层楼，很漂亮。王亥在帮他做这件事。王亥出现在王笛的许多活动上，他有着跟王笛截然相反的性格，用“社牛”都不足以形容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在澳门，王笛书架上的书不算特别多。他现在几乎不收藏书了，书太沉，他经常需要用，不方便。他主要看电子书，很多时候是听书。他眼睛不好。他给我看他正在读的电子书，有斯科特、哈耶克、王鼎钧，还有新晋诺贝尔文学奖得主安妮·埃尔诺。他当年想用一个虚拟的世纪老人的口吻讲《茶馆》的故事，类似埃尔诺在《悠悠岁月》里的“无人称自传”。埃尔诺在自己回忆的同时，也触发他人的回忆，回忆的共鸣呈现出时代的演变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛一直在记忆里寻找这些共鸣时刻。这些时刻很多是向下沉的。比如，他在砖瓦厂做砖的时候，和二三十个工人挤在大工棚里，没有自己的私人空间。工人们睡了，他在灯下看书，但没有一个人说他灯亮到那么晚，影响他们睡觉。工人们还用废木料给他做了一个桌子，让他读书画画。“很可能就是那段时间的经历，对我后来的民众史观和下层视角，有着潜移默化的影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在有杏书店，王笛说起他那一代人，既做过农民又做过工人的城市知识分子，在中国历史上可能是绝无仅有的一代。在22岁的时候——不算太早也不算很晚的年龄——他通过突然而至的高考，扭转了命运。31岁的时候，他成为当时中国大学历史系最年轻的副教授。一切看上去一帆风顺的时候，他又做出决定，去美国读研究生，重新开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;在美国&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;四川大学历史系副教授王笛准备赴国外继续学业时，获得了美国两所大学历史系的录取通知。一所是约翰·霍普金斯大学，一所是哥伦比亚大学。他选择了前者，跟随美国著名历史学家罗威廉攻读博士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗威廉推荐王笛去读卡洛·金茨堡的《奶酪与蛆虫》。这是王笛第一次读微观史著作。金茨堡运用宗教裁判所档案，书写了16世纪意大利北部一个乡村小磨坊主梅诺基奥的心灵史。在梅诺基奥眼中，宇宙是一块被蛆虫咬噬的千疮百孔的奶酪。原著是意大利语，王笛阅读的英文本恰好是约翰·霍普金斯大学出版社出版的。这部微观史经典之作他读了无数遍，后来又在他开设的新文化史讨论课上，与学生们一次次精读书中细节。他认为这样的精读和讨论比给学生开一列长长的书单有用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛写的是微观史。他的三个主要的大题目，都跟罗威廉有过充分讨论。罗威廉带学生，不是说自己专长什么，就让学生写什么。“学生自己要有这个冲动，老师是帮助深化。不是说老师有个大的构想，然后布置给学生。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他跟罗威廉商量博士论文写作的时候，还没有“街头文化”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（street culture）&lt;/span>;一词。“我先说了这个概念，他说好。我觉得学生要独立思考，要不断深化，老师是让问题具体化，而不是让老师代替思考。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛一直在践行着微观史观。他觉得这对于我们习惯了历史写作要有重大意义和宏大叙事的读者来说，需要更多的适应和了解。并不是更多更细的历史书写，就是微观史。“如果我们写一本有关曾国藩或胡适的书，哪怕细节再多，再细致，也不是我们所称的微观历史。微观历史的前提之一，就是要写普通人的历史。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金茨堡主张重视“被迫害和被征服的人”，因为这些人往往“被许多历史学家视为边缘人物而不予理睬，甚至通常全然无视”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛用微观史的方法写博士论文《街头文化》的时候，他的导师罗威廉正在写《救世——陈宏谋与十八世纪中国的精英意识》。罗威廉认为，这位出生于广西临桂横山村的清朝官员身上，能看到当时精英的心态，这是“经世”的典范，是盛清时代的缩影。显然与王笛感兴趣的研究并不一样，但这并不妨碍他们一起去美国国会图书馆查阅资料。“这里可能是全世界图书资料最多的地方。”罗威廉去找陈宏谋，王笛去找茶馆。罗威廉会问王笛，陈宏谋的这几句诗怎么翻译合适。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6ctY5BDmIsGaal8JWH6ziptVp4brWrixf8H8sMXY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6ctY5BDmIsGaal8JWH6ziptVp4brWrixf8H8sMXY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在成都与读者分享&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（华小峰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗威廉在《救世》的导论里表达了自己的思考：“现在看来，叙事型著作和对历史文本的密集阅读是完全必要的，对微观史的强调使得对历史人物个人生活的详细研究获得了极高的地位。意大利历史学家卡洛·金茨堡的《奶酪与蛆虫》就是微观史研究的经典之作。这让我怀疑，在这个年代，一位学者花费许多时间去研究一位男性精英和一位重要的政治人物，是不是最有效的治学之道。意大利一位意气风发的历史学家乔瓦尼·莱维在《年鉴》上发表的许多文章，雄辩地证明：那些大人物研究，如适当处理同有关小人物的研究一样，有助于我们了解过去的历史。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有许多人也会认为，王笛的微观史研究，跟另一位历史学家杨念群对于帝王的研究，会产生冲突和矛盾。王笛并不这样看。“其实我们所说的并不矛盾，历史很多时候确实是帝王和精英决定，他讲的是实情，但我表达的是历史观，统治人的人要研究，被统治的人也应该研究。杨念群研究帝王，并不是说他赞同帝王的做法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛从罗威廉那里学到很多东西，包括导师并不主导一切。王笛现在澳门大学给学生上新文化史的课。读金茨堡的《奶酪与蛆虫》和娜塔莉·泽蒙·戴维斯的《马丁·盖尔归来》等英文原著。两个星期读一本，一个星期3小时，一本书讨论6小时。他和学生抠每一个细节。他鼓励学生独立思考，有理有据地向老师提出不同意见，有时意见对，有时不一定对。老师和学生的意见都并非不容质疑。“这是对话的方式，不是为了证明谁对谁错。有时候同样的资料，大家使用的方式是不一样的，对历史的解读是有多种视角的，但一切都建立在仔细阅读的基础上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前说到，王笛当年也收到哥伦比亚大学历史系的录取通知。录取他的是历史学家曾小萍&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Madeleine Zelin）&lt;/span>;，她的代表作是《自贡商人：近代中国早期的企业家》。王笛的博士论文《街头文化》在斯坦福大学出版社出版的时候，匿名外审人之一就是曾小萍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/DGR4RJsBSdLmhTvu9Dw6YAKtsXlcI4mdZ4e3SaqI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/DGR4RJsBSdLmhTvu9Dw6YAKtsXlcI4mdZ4e3SaqI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在阳台种菜&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者方迎忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾小萍给《街头文化》写了六七页评语，相当于一个小论文。她给王笛提出了很多修改意见，其中一条是：这本书的观点不是很清楚。这让王笛感到苦恼。“我去问罗威廉，怎么把主要观点突出表达。罗威廉告诉我一个方法。他说，每一章你用一句话来概括，然后你把各章的这些话组成一个段落，那个段落的主题句，就是你的主要观点。这个太厉害了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，《街头文化》获得美国城市史研究学会最佳著作奖。王笛对曾小萍和罗威廉都很感激，严格的评审提出的问题，用有效的方法解决问题，都让他受益匪浅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗威廉已经七十多岁，年长王笛不到十岁。有时，王笛还会向罗威廉请教。2019年，由罗威廉和他在霍普金斯大学的同事梅尔清&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Tobie Meyer-Fong）&lt;/span>;共同推荐，王笛被选为该校的杰出校友&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Soecity of Scholars）&lt;/span>;，这是很大的荣誉。王笛原本2020年春天要到美国参加颁奖典礼，并参加校长主持的晚宴，已经邀请罗威廉参加，但因为疫情限制，最终没能成行，这是他疫情期间最大的遗憾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在美国史学界，华裔教授获得认可并不容易。王笛说起何炳棣和黄仁宇，认为他们两人是美国华裔历史学者的两个极端例子。“何炳棣的研究方式是美国史学界的正统，讲究实证，能得到专业上的承认，他一帆风顺，1970年代就担任美国亚洲学会会长，这是很不容易的。黄仁宇是另一个极端。他的书是大历史的写法，比如《万历十五年》，缺乏个案的研究基础，在美国史学界很难被接受，所以他的书在美国的出版屡遭挫折，最后他甚至失去了教职。黄仁宇的书纵横上下千年，读起来很舒服。今天，黄仁宇在读者里的名声远远大于何炳棣，《黄河青山》读起来比《读史阅世六十年》要震撼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛当年在德克萨斯A&amp;amp;M大学任教时，是历史系唯一一位华裔教授。上了年纪之后，最让王笛头疼的是交通不方便。大学里有机场，他要回中国，需要先从大学城坐小飞机到休斯顿、奥斯汀或达拉斯，然后飞到洛杉矶或旧金山，再飞到北京或上海。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在美国教了17年的书，从助理教授做到正教授，觉得要换一个环境了。当澳门大学向他抛出橄榄枝的时候，他接受了，2015年来到澳门大学。经过一年适应之后，他留了下来，曾担任澳门大学历史系主任，并担任讲席教授至今。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;波澜翻滚&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在澳门，王笛很多时候在食堂吃饭，或者在家用面条和速冻水饺解决问题。偶尔做川菜，也是采取最简单的办法，用火锅底料煮各种配菜。澳门大学横琴校区通过海底隧道与澳门相连，这里就像一个小社会，王笛因此能够远离尘嚣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的书桌斜对着阳台，落地窗外的船就这么从现实和历史的交通要道通过。他像生活在历史和现实之间。他是同时有历史感和现实感的学者。他希望能借助对历史的思考，对当下有所意义。“历史充满偶然性，没有规律，但历史可以帮助我们思考。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛办公室外的墙上有许多图片和照片，有他从事专业研究的介绍，有日常生活的照片。其中一张2000年大学同学聚会的照片，同学们在打麻将。王笛不会打麻将，在研究茶馆之前，他也很少去茶馆。他看上去不像典型的成都人。他的同学王亥这样的“街娃儿”可能才是。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛当年也许比王亥更想成为一个画家。他的书里经常有他的插画，比如我们正在聊天的鹤鸣茶社。他根据照片画了一张。他给《历史的微声》画了很多人物头像。“这合乎我的理念，他们是我崇敬的人，我从他们那里汲取的思想和思考，展示这些需要借助艺术的手法，需要一些插图。我不喜欢简单放照片。《那间街角的茶铺》我也是画了插图的。画插图的想法，是我和这两本书的责任编辑李磊商量后的共识。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些年，王笛在国内出版的书很多，多到各出版社需要排队，避免在宣发上撞车。他对人民文学出版社正在推出的“王笛作品系列”很满意，“责任编辑李磊光是每本书的书名就想了好多作为备选。在文学性表达以及大众阅读和推广方面，也给了我很多提示和建议，并且安排了上海书展我和许纪霖的对谈，还有我和张明扬在上海思南的活动。”王笛说，在美国二十多年，他出版的东西并不多。“我1991年去的美国，到了2015年，24年我只出了两本英文书和一本中文书，很少吧，但好多东西就是积累，积累之后会有爆发。”王笛今年67岁。有一种说法，60岁到70岁是一个历史学家的黄金时期。王笛正处在这样的时期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来鹤鸣茶社的路上，他一直在听书。“我眼睛不好，眼睛留着写作。”他是珍惜时间的人，早上起来，漱口刷牙，做饭吃饭，他都在听书。他说他的生活是三书：写书、读书、教书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在澳门，按照王笛的指点，我在白鸽巢前地一所教堂后边的角落里，找到了马礼逊的墓。墓前的地盘上，有几位工人在拉线测量，估计是教堂和墓地需要修缮。几个小孩在教堂前踢球，球进到院子里，他们才会跑过来。白鸽巢前地是一个公共空间，这里最多的是下象棋的老人。传统像石头一样坚固。王笛说，在香港和旧金山都会看到类似的景象，那种从传统中延续下来的公共空间的构成部分，有的不以时间为转移。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年9月的成都双流彭镇观音阁茶馆前，我同样看到了下象棋的人，他们在那里坐了一早上。王笛《茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（下）&lt;/span>;》中转述了张戎在《鸿：三代中国女人的故事》中的回忆。成都的许多茶馆在“文革”之初被强行关闭。“一个男孩甚至一掀棋盘，棋子全撒落在地板上，大叫着：&#39;不要象棋！你不知道这是资产阶级的爱好吗？&#39;随后把棋子棋盘都扔到河里，一些学生在茶馆墙上刷标语。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“破四旧”运动中，茶馆受到了冲击，在那里，喝茶“被视为旧社会的陋习，茶铺被看作藏垢纳污、阶级异己分子与落后群众聚集之所，强行取缔、关闭了茶馆”。此时，老虎灶在成都居民生活中仍然占有重要地位。20世纪60年代的成都居民家中，燃料缺乏，老虎灶提供的开水比自己烧开水方便便宜。在茶馆喝茶少了，但买开水回家泡茶的人并没有减少。茶铺起到水铺的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在茶馆研究的问题上，王笛关心的是，是否地区或地方的研究可以提供理解中国社会和文化的普遍性知识。“微观研究的意义在于，能够为把对历史的认识上升到一个更广义的层次提供个案分析，其不仅能丰富我们对地方的知识，而且有助于我们对中国的理解。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家与社会关系问题，是西方研究中国历史的一个着眼点。在1980年代末和1990年代初，罗威廉使用公共领域&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（public sphere）&lt;/span>;这一概念来研究近代中国时，遭到不少学者反对，他们认为哈贝马斯的概念不适用于中国。“20世纪下半叶的中国有相当长一段时间，便处于有&#39;国家&#39;无&#39;社会&#39;的时代，国家掌握了政治、经济、社会、文化的一切资源，这是此前任何政权未能实现的。传统的&#39;公&#39;的领域也几乎不复存在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;姜文导演的《让子弹飞》已然是当代中国电影的经典之作，其中的桥段脍炙人口，在各种社交场合被频频引用。电影改编自马识途《夜谭十记》中的《盗官记》。在《盗官记》里，有这么一段对成都茶馆的细致描述：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们去过成都吗？那里有一个少城公园，少城公园里有一个鹤鸣茶社。在那里有一块颇大的空坝子，都盖着凉棚，面临绿水涟漪，是个好的风景去处。凉棚下摆满茶桌和竹椅，密密麻麻坐满喝茶的茶客，热闹得很。到处听到互相打招呼、寒暄问好的声音，到处是茶倌放下铜盘叫着“开水”的声音。这是一个普通的茶座，那些做小生意的、当教员的等等小市民们，就在这里来谋事，说合，讲交情，做买卖，吵架，扯皮，参加“六腊之战”，“吃讲茶”……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是曾经的鹤鸣茶社，许多情状还在，许多则已成往事。比如说“六腊之战”，指的是每年六月和腊月是学校教员受聘期满的月份，教员们为了争取继续聘用，四处奔走，为生活而战。“吃讲茶”则是双方发生争执时，会请袍哥主持公道，双方在茶馆谈判，或和或打，就看这茶吃得怎样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/SM7mhTluQgqDzzOqCC5msjUxrmhRjmqhEIuapyiR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;623&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/SM7mhTluQgqDzzOqCC5msjUxrmhRjmqhEIuapyiR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252386&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在成都鹤鸣茶社拍摄茶客&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（华小峰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马识途的小说写的是民国时的事情。1949年之后，马识途的回忆是这样的：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;既然茶馆不再是能支持革命的地方，我们必须坚决地消除它们。因此，茶馆倒闭了。尽管人们不喜欢这种不便，但他们除了无条件服从外，无能为力。实际上，一些有识之士认为我们可以取茶馆之益而去其之弊，当然，这样的话，茶馆的弊处将会完全被消除，茶馆将成为一个文化活动中心以及宣传教育的场所。但当局没有听见这些声音，因此，茶馆在四川大地上几乎消失殆尽。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛觉得鹤鸣茶社的历史几乎可以单独提出来独立成书，鹤鸣茶社的历史就是一部波澜起伏的电影，而不同人的眼中，有不同的茶和历史——&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看到同样的历史资料，人和人理解不一样。我们今天在鹤鸣茶社，可能不同的人有不同的感受。有的人可能看到脏乱差，有的人看到的是人和人在聊天社交，有的人看到茶倌在忙着掺茶，有的是看到谋生的人，有的看到掏耳朵的人，有的是看到我们在这聊天，摆着书，还有人在旁边照相。每个人看到的都不一样。本来这就是一个大千世界。卡尔·波普尔说，我们写不出整体的历史，包括鹤鸣茶社，我们都写不出整体的历史。我们看到的只是通过个体的眼睛，或者个体的研究者来理解的历史，任何历史都只是部分的历史。每个人写的都是碎片，不可能是全面的历史。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有的人说成都很好啊，有的人说成都就是大家无所事事。同样的事情，有的是积极的，有的是消极的。大家的经历不一样。有的工作很满意，有的始终找不到好工作，能说感受是一样的吗？历史就这样复杂，没有标准，也没有规律。相信历史有规律是很可怕的事情。过去的三年，病毒让全球都改变了。这有什么必然性啊。三年前，没有人预见得到疫情对世界的改变。所谓规律，是可以预见到的未来，历史真的不是这样的，很多时候只是人的一念之差。我们的现代社会，整个人类文明，不是人为设计的，一个社会自然进化可能更合理。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛从鹤鸣茶社旁边人头攒动的餐饮店里买了几碗水饺，这是我们的午餐。他说起吃的历史。“我读幼儿园的时候，吃不饱饭，我还记得，小孩子跟着老师去其他班看看有没有剩下的饭，没有啊。这样的饿肚子的事情，就是人为设计的结果。”王笛生于1956年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表达了他对整个中国历史的看法。“我们要让社会充分发展。举个简单的例子，如果大家都在泰坦尼克号这样的大船上，如果在正确的航道上，大家没感觉有什么，一旦出现问题，大家就都完蛋。如果我们分乘50条船往前走，看起来缺乏效率，但哪一种选择更安全，这是非常简单的道理。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（上）&lt;/span>;》的尾声，王笛用了《寻梦》作为标题。他用非常感性的笔触描述了1949年的最后一天：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在过去的50年里，他们所光顾的茶馆，他们视为理所当然的坐茶馆的生活习惯，竟一直是国家权力与地方社会、文化的同一性和独特性较量的“战场”。他们每天到茶馆吃茶，竟然就是他们拿起“弱者的武器”所进行的“弱者的反抗”。这也即是说，弱小而手无寸铁的茶馆经理人、堂倌和茶客们，在这50年的反复鏖战中，任凭茶碗中波澜翻滚，茶桌上风云变幻，他们犹如冲锋陷阵的勇士，为茶馆和日常文化的最终胜利，立下了汗马功劳。如果他们知道自己在捍卫地方文化中所扮演的关键角色，就不会嘲笑这位通过时间机器突然降临、要为他们撰写历史的小同乡了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小同乡”指的是王笛自己。2023年9月，王笛第九次来到成都双流彭镇观音阁茶馆，时间机器仿佛再次启程。他毫无意外地再次看到了在那里打牌的甘大爷和胡大爷。老板李强用老虎灶上取下来的水壶给他们的茶杯里倒入鲜开水，波澜翻滚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在王笛叙述的那些试图改变世界的大人物眼中，他们想着的是世界的波澜翻滚，而不是这碗茶。王笛在《历史的微声》最后一章中，提到了他脑海里浮现过的一个画面：“帝王或者英雄站在高高的山巅上，俯瞰整个大地，为自己马上要创造历史，而心潮澎湃，豪情万丈。极目望去，在他的眼中，是乌泱泱的人海，芸芸众生，小如蝼蚁。对他来说，面对这样的人海，多一个不多，少一个也不少，个体在这里已经失去了意义；个体的命运，在这里是无关大局的；芸芸众生之间，是没有区别的，甚至看不清他们的面孔。他们没有自己的故事，也没有自己的历史，当然也就没有自己的未来。如果这些芸芸众生为了帝王或者英雄所谓的&#39;宏大事业&#39;而死去，就无声无息地化为了尘土。在宏大的历史叙事中，个体是整体完全可以忽视的东西，这就是整体史的本质。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在观音阁茶馆，王笛走到甘大爷和胡大爷旁边，再次拍下了许多照片。而正在打牌的两位大爷对此习以为常，连眼皮都没抬一下。每天上午都出现在茶馆里，用一杯一块钱的茶度过一个上午，这样波澜不惊的生活也许才是最正常最让人安心的生活。王笛告诉我，“人民能够日复一日、年复一年预期到他们能够过着安静和平的生活，难道这不就是最宏大的叙事吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;真实是什么？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;王笛在办公室收到了四川大学学报寄给他的期刊。期刊的开篇便是他写的论文《“啯匪”和“会匪”：哥老会起源的新思考》。秘密会社一直是他所关心的主题。当年的《袍哥》是这一研究过程中的插曲。和袍哥有关的大量材料需要更丰富的形式来表现。对沈宝媛论文的研究，更像是对《奶酪与蛆虫》的一次具体的借鉴。“原本并不打算写微观史，只是正好有这么一个资料。”意大利偏远地区的故事勾起他对四川乡下一起案件的联系。这正说明文明当中的许多形式具有共性，我们跟世界并不是那么不一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近他会写到“三支半香”，会写到哥老会现实和精神的起源。他会运用霍布斯鲍姆《传统的发明》所提到的理念。袍哥联系着更繁复而未明的历史。如何认识这些故事，如何认识文本，如何认识档案，是重要的事情。“不要认为记载在档案上的东西就是历史。档案的真实性并不比别人写的小说更真实。”王笛说起二十四史。“二十四史就是官修的历史。这是皇帝希望我们相信的历史。许多历史经过伪造、修改，甚至销毁。如果没有二十四史，今天留给我们的历史，也许不是更少，而是更多。这些官修的历史有多少真实性？我敢说百分之一的真实性都没有。官修的历史只能代表官方，跟每个人的经历有出入。我反复强调，一个学者要有批判精神，包括对史料和历史写作的批判，没有批判的话，你的写作没有任何意义。当然，每个人都没法写出完全真实的历史，我们只是力图写出接近真实的历史。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TTdxD1WmktHHLBUgJQWhAr8LLxHBF2fPhclLVsnm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TTdxD1WmktHHLBUgJQWhAr8LLxHBF2fPhclLVsnm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在澳门大学校园里&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者方迎忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和王笛站在下班高峰期的成都合江亭附近的路边等车。往西边走一段路，就到新南门。以前，成都还有城墙城门城楼的时候，南门叫“江桥”，南城楼是“浣溪”。顺着锦江往西边的方向看，看到的是和其他城市差不多的天际线，看不出这是成都。往东不远的地方是九眼桥遗迹。成都许多地方只剩下一个地名。那些貌似还在的地方，跟往年已经不一样。锦里、宽窄巷子好像是古色古香的街道，但保留下来的东西并不多。王笛原本住在大慈寺对面，庙里曾经有一个文博大茶园，“非常壮观”。他觉得这里曾是最有成都茶馆文化特色的地方，但已经有了翻天覆地的变化，成了太古里。文博大茶园长大的孩子和太古里长大的孩子看到的成都，哪个更真实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都是和茶馆相连的，茶馆让成都成为成都。“到口子上啖三花”曾经是成都人的口头禅，就像北京人说“您吃了吗”一样。不一定真的去喝茶或吃饭。一种可以成为日常口语的指代物，说明这件事情在日常生活中的重要。在口子上，在街角，那种传统茶铺不好找了。所以，游客们会去双流彭镇的茶馆打卡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛在观音阁茶馆门口跟老板李强聊起过去。他觉得观音阁茶馆现在的“两张皮”挺好。“一张皮”是网红打卡之地。他们在这里喝一碗茶10块钱，买了茶可以喝茶休息拍照。“另一张皮”是当地茶客的日常生活，以甘大爷和胡大爷每天雷打不动出现在茶馆为标志，他们用的是大茶杯，茶叶不一样，1块钱。两者相辅相成，构成了一个传统和现实融合的空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是成都历史为数不多的“活化石”之一。未硬化的室内泥地，土木结构的空间，竹椅、温水瓶、茶碗、老虎灶，各种嘈杂声随之而来。这是现实的声音，也是历史的回声。这是王笛所说的“历史的微声”。这里，普通的个体不是一个个抽象数字，而是一个个具体的人。他们喝着茶，打着牌，聊着天，将生活日复一日地进行下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访魏纪中：亚运会溢出的正面社会效应越来越大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258062]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;87岁是一个早该退休的年龄了，但魏纪中计划工作得再久一些。“新中国最健康的人”马约翰的一句话一直激励着他：“一个人要为体育事业干50年。”现在，他完全可以自豪地说：“我已经远远超过了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/dgb5qbv2Pj6F9dC6VsYbUwdejdtsaFRLQLWAI50a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/dgb5qbv2Pj6F9dC6VsYbUwdejdtsaFRLQLWAI50a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月22日，亚奥理事会终身名誉副主席魏纪中在亚奥理事会与杭州亚组委媒体吹风会上回答记者提问。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1958年，摆在魏纪中面前的有两条路：一条通往人民文学出版社，这符合外界对一名南京大学法国文学专业毕业生的期待；另一条路通往国家体育运动委员会（现国家体育总局），这源自一个年轻排球运动员的内心期盼。魏纪中决定遵从内心。他的英语和法语流利，这使他很快参与到新中国体育的外联事务中，是国内与国际奥委会主席萨马兰奇接触最多的人之一。在他六十五年雄心壮志的体育工作中，他几乎参与了新中国所有体育大事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1986年起，魏纪中开始担任中国奥委会秘书长，然后成为中国奥委会副主席。魏纪中相信，体育能够向世界展示更“开放”的中国。深谙国际体育事务规则的魏纪中曾在国际排球联合会、亚洲奥林匹克理事会等担任多个重要职务。人们认为，魏纪中是2008年北京申奥成功的关键人物之一，他为申奥提出了不少建设性意见，是中国奥委会与国际奥委会之间的“桥梁”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杭州亚运会期间，魏纪中仍然保持着充沛的精神，他的工作排满行程，要一直待到亚运会闭幕。作为亚奥理事会终身名誉副主席，魏纪中参与亚组委的官方新闻发布会，接受媒体采访，回应亚运会举办的相关问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月29日，魏纪中在杭州接受了南方周末记者专访。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“越来越多国家和地区希望举办亚运会”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;杭州亚运会是中国举办的第三次亚运会。三届亚运会的举办背景有什么不同？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1990年我们办北京亚运会，当时主要是改革开放后的对外需要。那届亚运会本来应该由日本广岛举办，后来我们通过亚奥理事会与日本广岛组委会协商，让他们把1990年亚运会先让给我们，然后他们再办1994年亚运会，日本广岛组委会同意了，这样我们就取得了1990年在北京举办亚运会的资格。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年广州亚运会，政治背景发生了一些变化。小平同志南方谈话以后，改革开放进入一个新的阶段，在这样的背景下，广州开始申办亚运会。而杭州举办亚运会，是在整个改革开放取得明显成就的基础上，我们要进一步开放，用开放来促进改革。在这样的大背景下，我们又申办了杭州亚运会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三次举办亚运会，整个国家的大环境和世界的大环境都有所区别。所以我说，每一届亚运会的举办，都有它的意义，而且除了体育的意义以外，还有不同的社会和政治意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/FSA2O42Krc4eDfhf3DkveyWV4GpZ9TkYDjONwvS9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/FSA2O42Krc4eDfhf3DkveyWV4GpZ9TkYDjONwvS9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，夜幕下的杭州奥体中心体育场。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚运会目前一共举办了十九届，这是你第十一次参加亚运会。在你看来，亚运会越来越难办了吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的看法正好相反。从现在情况来讲，希望举办亚运会的国家和地区越来越多：下一届在日本名古屋，日本以后还有卡塔尔和沙特阿拉伯等国家和地区接着举办。因此，亚运会越来越难办，和实际情况不符。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，从我们办亚运会的意义来说，除了促进体育运动发展，亚运会溢出的正面社会效应越来越大了。2006年，卡塔尔以举办亚运会为契机，使卡塔尔从比较单一的石油输出经济，变成现在比较全面的开放型经济。卡塔尔当时只有一个国际饭店，没有什么高楼，你今天到（卡塔尔首都）多哈去看看，面貌全部改变了。从多哈（亚运会）以后，很多国家和地区已经认识到通过办亚运会所溢出的社会效益和经济效益，可以促使整个国家的发展，这一点大家的认识越来越一致。而且亚奥理事会也帮助各个国家和地区在办亚运会的同时，使它能够产生比较持续的社会效应和经济效益。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;为了让更多国家拿奖牌&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1990年北京亚运有27大项308小项（金牌），杭州亚运会设40大项481小项（金牌），亚运项目数量多、类型多、金牌多，亚运会为何会考虑设置如此多的项目，这是否会降低体育的竞技性？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们为什么增加了这么多项目？目的就是促进亚洲体育运动发展，主要是发展中国家体育运动的发展。根据多年摸索，我们发现，（这）主要靠政府的支持和全社会对于体育的认同，这两点通过亚运会能够实现。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们设立更多项目就是为了使得更多国家和地区的运动员能够在亚运会当中取得好的成绩，也就是说，能够拿到奖牌。一个体育现在相对还不太发展的国家，通过运动员在亚运会上的表现，能够拿到金牌或者奖牌，对人民是一个鼓舞，政府也会满意。政府满意了之后，就会对于其他体育运动有更多的支持。因此，我们亚奥委采取了开放的政策，这些开放的政策，就是要让一些体育欠发达国家的运动员有机会来参与亚运大家庭的活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥运会主要是一些精英运动员的比赛，当然也照顾到群众性，但主要是精英运动员的比拼。因此，国际奥委会和组委会负担一切费用。而亚运会是付费参加的，也就是说每个运动员和官员每人每天要交50美元。当然，这50美元是不够（覆盖成本）的，组委会补贴给他们一些。比如，杭州亚运会运动员的餐食标准是500元，这一项就超过了缴纳的费用。政府愿意付费来让运动员参加比赛，这就说明政府对于体育运动的支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，参加亚运会的运动员越来越多，已经超过奥运会参赛人数，这就说明亚洲体育运动是在发展的。我们设立更多的项目，特别是一些地方性的传统项目，就是要让更多国家和地区的奥委会能够在运动会上取得成绩。现在来讲，我们参赛的国家和地区的奥委会获得奖牌的比例已经超过80%。这样做确实能够推动发展中国家和地区的体育运动和发展，社会对于体育运动的认同度越来越高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;电竞是杭州亚运会颇受关注的项目之一。关于电竞入亚，亚奥理事会、国家体育总局和杭州亚组委进行过多次研究讨论。最终的决定是怎么作出的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;电子竞技是从电子游戏发展产生的，和传统体育类似。传统体育的一些项目，包括像足球、篮球、排球，也是从一些民众娱乐项目过渡到正式比赛项目。电子游戏和电子竞技有一个很大的而且涉及面很广的群体，职业选手来自这个群体，他们传统体育的天赋可能不那么高，却在电子竞技方面可能有更大的发展。既然有这么一个群体存在，我们就不能忽视。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于电子竞技，我们有一个认识的过程。电子竞技是体育，这个有争议，因为电子竞技与辞典里对体育的定义不符，但是从运动的观点来讲，电子竞技的竞技性一面与运动的定义有一定相符的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛泽东主席说“发展体育运动，增强人民体质”，把体育和运动区分开来，这两者有共同点，也有不同之处。我同意这样一个观点，电子竞技是一个运动项目，同时也是一个文化创意项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们和国际奥委会在这个问题上不断沟通，电子竞技也不断改善，国际奥委会逐渐承认了电子竞技在不少方面和传统体育有共同之处。因此，国际奥委会首先提出来奥林匹克运动的虚拟化，现在又成立了电子竞技委员会。这就是说，我们传统体育的认识和电子竞技的认识是相向而行，开始融合，目的就是要使更多年轻人或者爱好者能够进入奥林匹克大家庭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于电子竞技如何进入这个综合性的运动会，现在大家正在探讨。杭州亚运会把它作为一个与传统体育并列的项目。其他综合性运动会，比如英联邦运动会、南美运动会或者非洲运动会等，采取的是另外一种方式，就是把电竞作为一个业态和传统体育业态并列起来，一个大的运动会的范围之内，有两种业态的情形。如何更好地融合也在探讨之中。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“举国体制还是适用”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一直有一种声音，尽管我们举办了亚运会和奥运会，在大部分体育赛事中具有金牌竞争力，但是似乎大众体育或者说群众对体育的热情仍然不够，你是怎么看这个问题的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;关注金牌是很重要的，但是过度关注金牌就会引发我们过去所谓的“锦标主义”。如果陷入锦标主义，有的时候就会产生一些负面影响，比如不择手段地去取得锦标。结果是重要的，但是结果不能代表一切。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们不能忽视群众体育。通过办亚运会、办奥运会，群众对于体育运动的认识，不断地提升。比方说，我们在办2022年北京冬季奥运会之前，就提出几亿人参与冬季运动的倡议，而且在冬季奥运会举办以前基本上实现了。这说明人民对于体育运动的认识不断提高，因此参与热情也是高的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，我们如何把他们很好地组织起来？竞技体育和群众体育是两个方面，但这两个方面是互通的。我们贯彻这样一个方面，竞技体育那些专业运动员，是从群众体系中产生的；专业体育的提高，必然又会给群众体育指导。所以我觉得，普及和提高，变成互动的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你有一个观点，举国体制仍然是我们在竞技体育中的优势所在。现在一些大球类项目的发展遇到一些困境，你认为现有环境下，职业化的路径在何处？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;举国体制对于竞技体育和群众体育都适用。实际上，这种举国体制、集中训练精英的方法，在其他国家也是有的。这是一种专业性体育，奥林匹克运动也是从业余性逐渐过渡到专业性，以及最后接受一定程度的职业性。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基本的路径就是群众性、专业性和职业性。从专业性到职业性，这里有商业化的问题，关于商业化的问题，我始终记得萨马兰奇主席生前告诉我的一句话：体育绝对不能被商业所控制，但是体育可以利用商业。因此，现在我们有些项目的发展是走市场化道路，但是还要有政府很好的支撑。举国体制还是适用，问题是，怎样来体现举国体制？方式方法可能要改革或者改进。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我决定不了，而且我也不参与决定”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你为中国体坛做了许多建设性工作，外界现在有一些争议，比如插手中国女排教练和中国乒乓球教练的任命等，你怎么回应这些争议性问题？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我从事体育工作六十多年了，但是从我来讲，始终是一个执行者，我不是什么体育运动的领导者。过去网上有一些误会，认为我可以决定一切。不，我决定不了，而且我也不参与决定。整个运动员、教练员的选拔问题都是由专业人员和政府体育领导机构决定的，我只不过根据给到我的任务，或者接受上级的指示去执行，所以我想利用这个机会也澄清一下，我决定不了排球的教练人选，也不会插手乒乓球运动。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我没有那么大能力，也没有这么多权力，说我决定这一切、我干预这些决策，我觉得这个是（因为）大家不太了解（情况）。当然我有一些看法可能是错误的，我接受大家的批评，但我绝对不能够决定什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从1958年大学毕业至今，几十年如一日奋斗在体育一线，仍未退休。你对体育的激情来自何处？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;体育主要是我的兴趣和爱好，虽然我87岁了，但是在杭州亚运会，我还是要从早晨7点工作到晚上10点。虽然我退休了，还是应当在需要的时候发挥一些余热。不是说我一定还要做什么，但是一旦国家或者某些国际体育组织有这样的需要，那么在我的能力范围内，我还是尽量去做，因为体育事业是关系到民众健康、民族精神和群众关注度的一个公益事业。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这两年，国内的体育项目、人员管理日趋收紧，你观察到，国内整个体育环境有哪些比较大的变化？怎么对待这些变化？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在处在一个新老交替阶段。在这种新老交替的时间里，需要有一定的磨合期。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得现在从（体育）管理层来讲，可能是处在一个磨合期，在磨合期里面发生一些这样或那样的问题是自然的。正是因为在磨合期，所以群众对于这些问题的看法会有不同，这也是很自然的。群众的这些意见，可能有的是比较准确的，有的因为信息差的原因不那么准确。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;运动员的交替，教练员的交替，这是一个过程，这个过程需要磨合，需要逐渐完善，因此我们一方面要尽量缩短这个过程；另外我们也要承认有这样一个过程，从管理层到群众，我们共同出力或者献策，使得这个过程的磨合更加顺利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么要学英语？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258046]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;最近公开的一次访谈，任正非提到了自己关于英语学习的看法，他说：“在农村学英文困难，这我理解，但是熬一熬，不就熬出来了吗？可能口语表达不那么好，但是有文字的识别能力也行啊。”这话对市面上甚嚣尘上的一些看法挺有针对性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须说明，一门学科对个人日常生活有没有用，不能作为是否进入学校让学生学习的标准。要说日常生活的用处，物理、化学、历史、地理又有多大用处？小学上到三年级能算账、能写字就够了。比较而言，随着大众教育水平的提高与国际交流的扩大，英语与日常生活的结合越来越密切：查阅了解某些知识与技术、看产品说明书、去国外旅游，都会用到英语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;维基百科的信息显示，截至2020年3月25日，W3Techs预测前一百万互联网网站使用的语言文字百分比中，英语占比59.3%。中文为1.3%。更熟悉地使用英文，对于一个人增长见识，是非常有用的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从国家层面来说，很大程度上，中国人学习外语是为了学习国外先进的技术。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何教学，都是一个呈金字塔型的层层筛选体系。中国有庞大的体校制度，从小学阶段就开始为体育发掘、输送人才，这就是中国体育健儿在各种赛事上获得奖杯的基础。同样，只有每个人都从一年级开始学加减法，到了初中学牛顿三定律、高中学动量守恒、机械能守恒定律，最后才有十万分之一、百万分之一的奥数冠军、诺贝尔物理奖得主。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英语也同样如此，只有从小学就开始学，大学要考英语，才能筛选出最尖端的人，他们熟练地掌握英语，能够从事各种研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人说，哪有必要都学，尖端人才学好英语就好了。但是，在小学初中高中的时候，没人能预料到后来。如果学校体系给出英语不重要的信号，高考再屈从于这个趋势，降低英语比重，必然影响高中生对英语学习的态度与热情。如果高中生普遍英语基础不好，必然影响本科生英语的整体水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有些学校，本科生的有些科目是英语教学，这有利于提高学生的专业英语水平，进而有利于紧跟国际先进水平。比如，一个中国学者在国外期刊上发表一篇学术论文，最常见的语言就是英语。发表的过程，有外国同行专家审稿，给出意见，发表就是一种认可。这有利于中国这个领域的学者，向着正确的技术方向发展。实际上，这就是一个技术扩散的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如果学生高三毕业后，英语普遍都差，英语授课就无法进行，后续的在国外发表英语论文的可能性就会变小。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，技术扩散，并不只发生在发表论文、参与国际研讨会这种“高层次”，生产中的各个领域、各个层面都存在技术的扩散与交流，很多时候，比我们想象中的场景更接地气、更普通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这段时间，生成式AI火了，美国在这方面领先，中国也在加快追赶。要想使用国外的生成式AI，从网络设置、注册、写提示语、学习技巧都需要语言能力。比如，在AI生成图像与视频上，一个英语熟练的图形、家装、海报设计师，就比一个缺乏语言能力的要快，后者甚至不会去接触这个新东西，因为语言难度太大。这就可以给前者领先半年、一年，甚至几年的时间，这会赢得客户，最终优势被固化下来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再比如，一个做工艺品的小老板，如果能经常上国外的技术交流网站，就能发现很多奇思妙想。有时候技术扩散，就是“看一眼”的事。但是，如果没有英文基础，他根本不会去这些网站，既没有能力找到这些网站，也没有意识去做这件事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人主张少学英语或降低英语分值的一个很重要的原因，就是觉得英语对农村孩子不公平。但论文《LDFA方法及其在项目功能差异分析中的应用研究》，根据国家教育考试中心的数据，采用完全随机抽样的方法，抽取了2500人的英语考试成绩，发现城市和农村在高考英语成绩上，没有显著差别，甚至农村还高上0.45分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这在意料之外，却在情理之中。实际上，很多研究都发现，英语特别是应试英语，没有需要。语言学习无非是多读、多听、多背，熟能生巧。在智能手机普及的时代，英语环境的成本非常低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，无论从个体生活的意义，还是国家技术进步，抑或城乡教育公平，都不应当轻视英语学习，这样我们的孩子才能接触与发现更大的世界，从小到大不仅能开阔视野，长大后还能在专业领域提高知识与技能。这一点，至少在未来相当一段时间内仍是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[专访编剧芦苇：好的电影都有社会意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257491]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1460&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp . jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, &quot;Alive&quot;, &quot;Tuya&#39;s Marriage&quot;, etc. written by Lu Wei The film won awards at international film festivals such as Cannes and Berlin. The picture shows a still from &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Wei is 72 years old. He never uses social media. His daily contact is only through the phone. Over the years, he has become accustomed to I write with pen and paper and write one movie script a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October 2022, he said goodbye to his relatives and friends in Xi&#39;an and took a flight to the United States via Guangzhou. In addition to visiting his son whom he had not seen for a long time, during this trip, he also had to collect information for the next script. &quot;One advantage of writing scripts in the United States is that it is quiet and no one disturbs me. Unlike here, for example, if there is an event, you can&#39;t go even if you don&#39;t go. They are all acquaintances and friends. If you don&#39;t go, people will feel presumptuous, and it is easy to give people a A misunderstanding occurred.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1415&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei poses with Zhang Yimou, Lu Le, and Zhao Jiping (from left to right). As screenwriters, directors, cameramen, and musicians, the four of them are top-notch actors in the industry. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among China&#39;s professional screenwriters, there are few who have the same connection with three generations of film history as Lu Wei The directors have all worked together and witnessed the ups and downs of Chinese cinema over the past four decades. In 1988, his first work as a screenwriter, &quot;The Price of Madness,&quot; became the box office champion of the year. Since then, a series of works such as &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, &quot;Alive&quot; and &quot;Tuya&#39;s Marriage&quot; have won awards at international film festivals such as Cannes and Berlin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before his departure, his study was a little messy. The walls and table were covered with large and small paintings and photographs. There was a note nailed to the wooden board against the wall, written in Lu Wei&#39;s handwriting: &quot;Make up your mind to write &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot;! This is a key battle to fulfill your long-cherished wish. Go all out and never give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The multinational big-budget movie &quot;Wolf Totem&quot; released in 2015 After that, Lu Wei spent more of his creative energy on low-cost films, which gradually made him move away from the center of capital. In his view, movies have no big or small size, only good or bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is no retirement in the job of a screenwriter. Now I only write what I like and don&#39;t consider anything else.&quot; He told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Although the remuneration for small-cost films is low, it is not about money. Problem, the advantage is that there is no burden, and there is great freedom of choice. The level of attention is not a matter for me to consider, I only care about my script.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1402&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1995, Lu Wei and Jiang Wen (right ) during the filming of &quot;Song of Qin&quot; in Xi&#39;an. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Wei&#39;s latest screenwriter&#39;s Tibetan story &quot;Lausang Family Affair&quot; has not yet been released. I have finished writing a new martial arts-themed script &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot;, and then I want to put the story of &quot;Barefoot Doctor&quot; Sun Lizhe on the screen to reflect the past of the &quot;educated youth&quot; generation. &quot;Sun Lizhe went to the countryside in northern Shaanxi from Beijing and saved many people by learning medical skills. Since it is difficult to see a doctor now, I wrote about Sun Lizhe as a way to look up to him. I hope that all Chinese doctors can become people like Sun Lizhe. The Chinese people will be blessed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to his creations, Lu Wei’s public statements are also eye-catching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, on the occasion of the 100th anniversary of the birth of Chinese cinema, Lu Wei and his friend Wang Tianbing held a dialogue titled &quot;When will Chinese cinema grow up?&quot; and sharply criticized films including Zhang Yimou, Chinese directors including Jia Zhangke and Lou Ye think they don&#39;t know how to write stories and their themes are confusing. He was an outspoken critic of &quot;The Promise&quot; and parted ways with his old friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Lu Chuan&#39;s &quot;Nanjing!&quot; Nanjing! &quot;The King&#39;s Feast&quot; was severely criticized by Lu Wei. However, in 2013, when he attended the press conference of Lu Wei&#39;s new book &quot;Secrets of Film Screenwriters&quot;, he said: &quot;I was very confident at one time. I wrote the script according to the logic of commercial feature films and shot it.&quot; At that time, I was thinking about subversion. Fortunately, I met Lu Wei at the crossroads of my life. After having an in-depth chat with him, I felt that I was wrong at the time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; won gold After receiving the Palme d&#39;Or, director Chen Kaige (left) took a photo with Lu Wei. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/11/17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1281&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11 /17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1992, Lu Wei and Gong Li (right) in &quot;Farewell&quot; Ji&quot; studio. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luwei is greatly influenced by Hollywood movies and values ​​the watchability and social significance of movies. , has been working as a screenwriter for more than 30 years. He talks about the &quot;genre&quot; of movies more than the &quot;art&quot; of movies, and believes that there are no secrets to screenwriting. In the recently published book &quot;Film Screenwriters Have No Secrets&quot;, Lu Wei disclosed for the first time the detailed inside story of writing the script of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;. What surprised some fans is that this film is currently the only film to win the &quot;Palme d&#39;Or&quot; award at the Cannes Film Festival. Lu Wei&#39;s requirements for the scripts of Chinese-language films are that they must be &quot;typified&quot; and the stories must be good-looking, reasonable, and true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said: &quot;The title of the first book talks about the &#39;secrets&#39; of film screenwriters. I don&#39;t like it. I think there are no secrets for film screenwriters, they are just rules. The new book published this time I I just want to tell everyone this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, Southern Weekend reporters interviewed Lu Wei in Xi&#39;an. At that time, the most important &quot;National Day&quot; prime period of the year did not achieve the expected results. In terms of box office results, the Chinese mainland film market has rarely experienced a severe &quot;film shortage&quot; with only five new films being released in the entire month, and only three new films scheduled for release in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked about his views on new Chinese movies, he said: &quot;There are not many Chinese movie scripts that are qualified. Some movies are obviously script-problems. They require a lot of investment and effort, but the foundation is not good.&quot; Okay. The script is the foundation of the movie. If this foundation is not solid, the movie will definitely not be exciting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I finished college in a movie theater&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You used to study art. You first entered Xi&#39;an Film Studio as an art artist. How did you later transform into a film screenwriter? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the beginning, I did not prepare to be a screenwriter in my life plan and ideals. Later I came into contact with movies and also worked in film art. One day I suddenly realized that script writing is also a kind of plastic art, which is connected with fine art. I used to paint with colors, but now I paint with words. The principle is the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was completely by chance that I entered Xiying Film Factory. When I was recruiting workers, I was told that there was such a company that was recruiting people, but the job type was probably a cook. Although I was not willing to be a cook, I thought this unit was good and related to art. I didn’t know anything about movies at that time, but I just thought I could get in touch with art, so I joined. I thought to myself that even if I was a cook, I would still have a chance in this unit. As a result, I didn’t even work as a cook for a day. People knew that I could draw. After seeing my paintings, they said, “No problem, you can become an artist.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To do film art, it is inevitable to have to deal with it. to a movie script, because the content of the script determines the content of your work. If you do a lot of art, you will be able to see the problems in the script, how the script should be written, and how to write it is interesting. At that time, there was a so-called youth film crew. All the creative staff, including art and photography, would meet together to discuss the scripts. I often gave comments to some scripts. Later, I made many comments, and sometimes the director used them to provoke me. Fa said, &quot;Then you write and say that this is not good and that is not good, then you can do it yourself.&quot; So I really did it myself. They also felt that the script that was written was better than the original one. This also gave me confidence that the original script could be written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first work for which you were signed as a screenwriter was &quot;The Price of Madness&quot; directed by Zhou Xiaowen &quot;Well, this film was a sensation at the time and was the box office champion in 1988. But this is not the first time you have participated in screenwriting work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first one was &quot;They Are Young&quot;, but it failed. Wu Tianming was the director at the time, and he knew that I could write scripts. , pay more attention to me. Later I wrote &quot;The Last Madness&quot;, and that movie was somewhat well-received. It sold for a lot of money. Then I wrote &quot;The Price of Madness&quot;. At this time, I signed my name as the screenwriter. Wu Tianming was very supportive of me. I said, &quot;If you want to be a screenwriter, I will transfer you to the literature department. If you want to be a director, I will transfer you to the directing team. You can tell me what you want to do and I will support you.&quot; After hearing this, I felt that the director of the factory was treating me so favorably. I was very grateful to him, and I said I&#39;d better write a script. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you choose the screenwriter and director? Screenwriter, what&#39;s the difference between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I know a lot about screenwriters, but I don’t know about directors. I think the screenwriter is the designer and the director is the construction engineer. It often happens that the engineer can&#39;t understand the designer&#39;s creativity, so he will change your drawings to what he wants, so the final product may be different from what the designer imagined. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been a director and made a film called &quot;The Long Road to Xixia&quot;. I won the Golden Rooster Award for Best Director&#39;s Debut that year and also won several international awards. But I don’t think I’m a good director, and my directing business is not good. My nature is not suitable for being a director, and I really don&#39;t like to direct people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, with the progress of the film industry, the importance of screenwriters has Sexuality has gradually come to the fore. In addition to screenwriting majors offered in colleges and universities, screenwriting classes have also begun to appear in society. When you were young, there were few dedicated places to learn screenwriting. How did you improve yourself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just watching movies. Movies are different from other things. For science and engineering knowledge, it is best to receive systematic training. Movies are a very intuitive art. You can learn it by watching movies. Through analysis and research, you can become an expert. There is no need to learn. Not to mention attending a film college, I didn’t even have a complete education. I went to the countryside to work as a farmer in a mountain village in Baoji in the second grade of junior high school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am lucky because my father works in the People&#39;s Building in Xi&#39;an, which is a reception unit. He is the captain of the automobile team and is responsible for receiving some foreign experts and senior cadres. , so I had the opportunity to watch some foreign movies very early on, such as &quot;Quiet Don&quot;, &quot;Nights of Kabylia&quot;, and &quot;The Bicycle Thieves&quot;... In fact, the cinemas in the 1950s and 1960s were relatively abundant. Yes, it was not until the mid-1960s, when the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; was about to begin, that films began to be &quot;one size fits all&quot;. It was not until the late period of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; that some North Korean films began to come in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was making movies, it was still very difficult to watch movies. It gradually improved after 1980, when some foreign movies gradually came in, and it became easier to learn movies at that time. In addition to the convenience of working in the West Film Studio where you can watch some movies, Beijing has begun to hold events such as American Film Week and Spanish Film Week. At that time, a ticket cost about 25 cents, but it didn’t matter that you couldn’t buy it. I could only buy black market tickets, and some movie tickets could be sold for ten yuan. The salary at that time was very low, only thirty-six yuan, but I still wanted to see what I really wanted to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many movies that impressed me deeply, such as &quot;General Patton&quot;, &quot;The Dark Horse&quot;, &quot;Guess Who&#39;s Coming to Dinner&quot;, &quot;Into the Wild&quot;, etc. At that time, I had to take a train from Xi&#39;an to Beijing, and there was no I had extra money to stay in a hotel, so I settled in a friend&#39;s house, and then bought black market tickets every day. &quot;Dark Horse&quot; directed by Ballard is about the friendship between a child and a black horse. I liked it very much and watched it five times in one go. At that time, watching movies was mainly about learning the look of the movie, writing down my thoughts, and building an understanding of the composition of the movie. I completed my college studies in the cinema. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reading is equally important in your career. In this special era, you You participated in a book club. What was the atmosphere like at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1973, we started to organize a reading group, which can be regarded as a reading club. There are more than ten like-minded friends. The conditions for joining That means you have to have a certain level of education and be interested in theory. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have no organizational form and no name. We just conduct a learning exchange in the name of a gathering of friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We read theoretical books, such as &quot;Dialectical Materialism and Historical Materialism&quot; by Ai Siqi. We used it as an outline, discussed it chapter by chapter, and then summarized everyone&#39;s opinions on it. Use your insights. This book was an orthodox book at the time, and there was no danger in studying from it. After the &quot;September 13 Incident&quot;, the central government advocated the study of theory and designated several Marxist-Leninist classics, which we have all systematically read, such as the introduction to &quot;Das Kapital&quot;, &quot;Anti-Dühring&quot; and &quot;Ludwig &quot;Feuerbach and the End of German Classical Philosophy&quot; and &quot;The Communist Manifesto&quot;. In fact, at that time we had already begun to have our own thinking about the social situation and felt that some changes were about to happen. We just didn&#39;t know where this change would lead, so we thought Relying on reading to figure out some problems is our motivation for learning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At that time, you were trying to clarify some confusions about your future. How is it judged? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just know that I have hobbies and think that I must work hard to achieve my pursuit, but I don’t have any idea how to achieve it. I was studying and studying art at the same time. In order to find books, I also went to the libraries of various universities to steal books. I was discovered later and was detained at the police station for three days. Fortunately, we were lucky. The director was very kind to me. I always felt that the kid who stole the books was because I love reading and asked me to write a promise and go home. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We were in an era of information poverty, an era of extreme blockade, with no information at all. Today is an era of information explosion. Both are abnormal, one is hungry and the other is too full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei spent more than a year writing the movie script of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, most of which was spent doing various research. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;You cannot write &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; as a pure art film&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Going back to the book &quot;Movie Screenwriters Have No Secrets&quot;, you seem to have special respect for Hollywood movies because of the 1980s. Do you mainly watch American movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It exists in all countries, but it is undeniable that Hollywood has the greatest influence around the world, and American movies are a good learning object. Because their film composition is the clearest. This may also be a characteristic of Americans, who are relatively simple and direct. After studying, it comes to actual combat. Writing scripts means writing one after another, constantly moving towards new goals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have repeatedly emphasized that &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; should be written Genre film, does this have anything to do with its huge investment? When you talked about this movie in your book, you also emphasized that the script is for directors and investors, and the simpler the better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Screenwriters have to create based on cost, and this must be the case, because I am a professional, and the investment in &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; is It was a huge sum of money at the time, and I felt that it couldn&#39;t be turned into a purely artistic film. I remember when I first started writing the script, Wu Tianming told me how much a certain play would cost and not to overwrite it. Later, Peter Chan asked me to adapt Ha Jin&#39;s &quot;Waiting&quot;. My first question was how much to invest. This is a habit of mine. Later, he said there was no limit, so I started writing. Although the story is a small story, my The background is a big scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; is also adapted from a novel. In this book, you and Wang Tianbing analyzed the differences between the novel and the script, and you still think that the original novel is second-rate. Why do you think so? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think this is a classic novel, just a common romance novel. Chen Kaige once came to me In a letter, he talked about his wish for us to read the text of the novel again. The original author later published a new version of the novel based on the movie. Even so, the movie and the novel are still different in many places. The ending is very different, and many characters are newly added by us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Cheng Dieyi and Duan Xiaolou in the novel We finally met in Hong Kong, but your ending was that Cheng Dieyi committed suicide. Why did you change it that way? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This may be related to the experiences of many Peking Opera artists. I hope that every detail and scene in the movie &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; Provenance. For example, the character Yuan Siye, when he was shot at the end in the movie, he walked towards the execution ground with dramatic steps. That was the real story of the execution of a &quot;drama tyrant&quot; named Gao in Wuhan. The scene in which Cheng Dieyi was criticized comes from the past when people from the literary and art circles paraded through the Imperial Academy in Beijing during the Cultural Revolution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How long did you prepare for this script? Are you satisfied with the finished film? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It didn’t take long to write. It was mainly research, which took more than a year. For research, I had to travel everywhere, including the reference room of the Northern Kunqu Opera Theatre, the Opera Research Institute of the Chinese Academy of Arts, the library of Peking University, and the Beijing Library (now the National Library). I rented a room in a hotel next to the library. I went to the library every night and took a notebook to copy information. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movie was shot very well in the end. The regret is that some details can still be refined and some academic research can be done. There are also some performances that can be better, such as the old eunuch’s final performance. , I also felt that it was too pretentious and my understanding of this character was wrong. Of course, this cannot shake the final quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1450&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Wei (first from left), Ge You (middle) and veteran artists on the set of &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Alive&quot; is adapted from Yu Hua&#39;s masterpiece. Which one do you think is more difficult than &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Alive&quot; is very difficult, because this novel is well written, so it is not easy to change, so be careful when making changes. fear. When I wrote &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;, my spirit was free, and I felt in my heart that it should be based on mine, and the novel was wrong; but when adapting &quot;Alive&quot;, I wanted to try not to touch the novel as much as possible, but of course I still had to touch it. , after all, they are two carriers. For example, in the novel &quot;Alive&quot;, Fugui&#39;s son died by drawing blood. In reality, this is too rare. There is a problem with the audience&#39;s acceptance. The writing is a bit cruel and beyond our life experience, so I changed it to a car accident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Judging from the ending, &quot;Alive&quot; finally gave People hope that it is not as cruel as the original work, and seems to be more tender than &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This movie is about family life. The style is a little different, but the quality of the two is the same. I should have written &quot;Alive&quot; shortly after I finished writing &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;. The origin is that I previously collaborated with Zhang Yimou on a film about Shaanxi shadow puppetry, and he also went to pick up the location. Later, he saw &quot;Alive&quot; and told me to do this first. I also liked this novel, so I agreed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I made a documentary about old Shaanxi artists performing shadow puppetry. Zhang Yimou liked it very much and found it particularly charming. He watched the film at my house and was very excited. He stayed at my house that night. , we chatted all night and said that we must put shadow puppetry on the screen, and then we put this element into &quot;Alive&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let him become a living person&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Do you think that period was considered a better time for Chinese films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course, the policy is relatively loose, and the filmmakers also have a very fighting spirit. Everyone was willing to unite and make a good movie. At that time, personal demands seemed to be gone, and they just wanted to make a good movie. The desire for fame and fortune is relatively weak, and the movie has not begun to be marketed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the filming of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; was completed, Chen Kaige asked me to go to Beijing, so I went. He said that he had set up a company. I&#39;m a little skeptical about this, because when you set up a company, your motives are not necessarily so pure, and you have pressure, unlike in the system. I said something that maybe he didn’t understand. I said, “I don’t think so if you run a company. I think you’ll be hurt.” In fact, I meant that doing art wouldn’t be so pure in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, I am willing to continue to cooperate with him after that. He was going to shoot &quot;Feng Yue&quot; and asked me to be the screenwriter. When I saw that it was about the &quot;Demolition of the White Party&quot; in Shanghai, I decided to do it. I went to Shanghai to do research and wanted to find out what was going on. After I went to the Shanghai Research Institute of Literature and History to read the information, I found that there was no &quot;explosion of the White Party&quot; in history, so I was unwilling to write this script. Only if I believe it can I write a script. If I don&#39;t believe it, I can&#39;t write it. After I talked to Chen Kaige, he asked me if I could fictionalize it, and I said I couldn&#39;t do that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, I persuaded him at the time that &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; had been successful. Could we make a movie with a small investment but that we really wanted to make? But he still made &quot;Feng Yue&quot;, although It was basically the original cast of Farewell My Concubine, but it was a box office failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have also criticized the fifth generation directors for not being able to write scripts, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I mean they are not very good at telling stories. They are relatively unfamiliar with drama. What they study in school are all works of art and they admire It is also a work of art, and no effort has been made to the plot. The film school seems not to pay much attention to the plot, emphasizing the artist&#39;s style and the artist&#39;s personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many directors have made masterpieces, but later The works are becoming more and more disappointing. What do you think of this problem?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is normal. For example, athletes may create creative works when they are in good condition. World records, when the state is not good, that is, at an average level, they also have to face failure and the result of being eliminated. Filmmakers are the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You and many directors will have disagreements. , such as &quot;Red Cliff&quot; and &quot;White Deer Plain&quot;, what is the reason behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am not unhappy with John Woo. He and the producer approached me to write a red cliff story. Later, he didn&#39;t use the script I wrote. He used his lover&#39;s script, and I published my version as a book. The main reason is that my understanding of &quot;Red Cliff&quot; is different from his. I think Red Cliff is a battlefield and a struggle, while he thinks the theme is peace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had a very unpleasant quarrel with the director while filming &quot;White Deer Plain&quot;. He did not understand the theme of &quot;White Deer Plain&quot; and thought it was the relationship between man and land. But I think this book is about the father. The struggle with Zi is a conflict between two generations. What&#39;s more, his focus is not on movies, so some people say that this version of &quot;White Deer Plain&quot; is &quot;The Biography of Tian Xiao&#39;e&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are there any scripts that you have written but have not yet been filmed? Do you feel regretful? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; I just finished writing a script about the history of the Hetao area. It is a story about a swordsman from the Qing Dynasty, called &quot;The Legend of the Seven Stars of the Swordsman&quot; . I have always had a special liking for martial arts films, and I also like Hetao folk songs. I just wanted to make a martial arts film with singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have always paid attention to new films, and you have often done so before. Review some new movies. What do you think of the recently released domestic films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was good to shoot &quot;The Myth of Love&quot; in Shanghai, but it also had its problems. For example, the three female characters are all too beautiful, and they don’t look like people from the market. They look like movie characters at first glance. There is also a problem with the image of the male protagonist. He is a good old man, too conceptual, and a bit simple. From my understanding of good old people, they are not that simple. These take away from the dramatic power of the film, but the story is good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you create movie characters, how do you let them A more believable character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You have to understand him and put the character into a real life scene. Don’t conceptualize, don’t simplify, don’t flatten, let him be a living person, a person with emotions, a soul, and emotional appeal. We often have misunderstandings when photographing heroes. Heroes all have emotions and desires. Truth, goodness and beauty, only truth can be good and beautiful. Some movies always make people unconvincing, but they are just not true. Such movies cannot be made by sycophants. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, theme-themed movies have once again become an important movie phenomenon, can you write the main melody movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have written two. There is also a main theme in the greatest movie of all time, namely Eisenstein&#39;s &quot;Battleship Potemkin&quot;. This is the Soviet main theme and was later regarded as the masterpiece of montage theory. I have never been convinced. In fact, my parents are both old Eighth Route Army soldiers. I think the main theme can be filmed. Unfortunately, the two films I wrote myself were not filmed. I still want to film them if I have the opportunity in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among the recent movies, you seem to be very optimistic about &quot; &quot;I&#39;m not the god of medicine&quot;, what&#39;s the reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Luwei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It has far-reaching social significance. Difficulty in getting medical treatment is the common aspiration of the whole society. This movie happened to reveal this problem, so I think it has social significance. From an artistic point of view, this movie can continue to be refined, but this movie has extraordinary significance. Good movies, such as &quot;The Crow and the Sparrow&quot; and &quot;Small Town Spring&quot; have profound social significance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天成奇峡：云蒸霞蔚的“世外密境”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>