<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[京津冀洪灾后的这两月：弥合的伤口，艰难的重生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258800]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 17, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, villagers received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. .(Visual China/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 17, 2023, villagers in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When floods besieged Zhuozhou, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Wholesale Market was the hardest hit area. More than a month has passed, and the smell of rotten protein and slightly sweet fermentation that once permeated the market has dissipated. The wind blows, raising the dust that the remaining silt has dried up, leaving only a smell of earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the floods first receded, only mud was left in Xiu Mingyu’s shop, an auto parts dealer. There were yellow water stains on the walls and several large cabinets. Nishui Yinzi&#39;s loss of auto parts is roughly estimated at 300,000 yuan - on a good day, her annual income is only around 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The most terrible thing is that in April 2023, Xiu Mingyu had just paid the arrears of store rent, which she had to borrow 100,000 yuan from a friend. Qi. The lease expires in April next year. If the store cannot reopen, the rent will be in vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In late July and early August 2023, extreme heavy rains swept across the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region, causing floods in many places in Beijing and Hebei. Among them, the people who are most affected by floods are the people living around Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On weekdays, the prosperity of Beijing seems to be within reach. But when disaster strikes, the test they face becomes even more severe. In October 2023, when there were no traces of floods in the core urban areas of Beijing, they were still working hard to rebuild their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Agricultural Products Wholesale Market in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“How much business can compensate for losses?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Both rented cooked food at Dashiqiao Wholesale Market Lin Fenyi, who works at the stall, did not work up the courage until August 8 to go to her cooked food processing factory in Congyuan Village, Zhuozhou City to see the aftermath of the disaster: four cold storages had holes ripped open by water, maggots were crawling on the rotten meat, and the air was filled with It was filled with a stench that reached straight to the Tianling Cap. She wiped away tears on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After wiping away the tears, the factory was still saved. Lin Fenyi spent 40,000 yuan to hire a forklift to shovel mud, but it turned out that she could not drive into the factory. She took a big shovel and used human power to push the mud out of the factory door little by little, and then the forklift shoveled it to the roadside. The rotting meat was dug and buried in pits. When the pits were filled, the carrion was piled on the road, and the village sent people to push it off the field. Xiu Mingyu was also very busy trying to reopen the store. For a month, she went to the shop at 8 a.m. every morning to wash and wash her hands, and worked until 7 p.m. at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 1st, the store reopened, with white walls and shelves full of new products, giving it the appearance of a new life. But the troubles kept coming one after another. The new container I bought for several thousand yuan soon swelled due to the moisture in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiu Mingyu is in urgent need of funds. She received a call from someone claiming to be a bank employee, asking if she needed a loan. The store&#39;s goods were short of 80,000 to 100,000 yuan, but she couldn&#39;t trust the private number calling from Liaoning. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Business is also deserted. Xiu Mingyu guessed that her store was on a low ground, and after the flood, no one would dare to go to the store to buy anything when it rained. However, even if the customer flow remains the same, &quot;How much business can compensate for these losses?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the flood just passed, she was not sure about post-disaster livelihood. A month later, she was already a little calm. She felt comfortable earning a small amount of money in the store. As long as she wanted to open up, she could make do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After spending 300,000 yuan, Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory also resumed production in mid-September. She desperately tried to make up for the losses of the past month or so. During the factory shutdown, some old customers turned to other manufacturers to place orders. For this reason, she thought of a &quot;ruthless move&quot;: &quot;People sell pig head meat in the market now, and half a catty sells for 12 yuan, so I have to sell it for 11...I won&#39;t make a penny, dragging my former customers. Don&#39;t drag customers.&quot; , you have no transaction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The transaction is open, but the &quot;pulse&quot; is still very weak. Before the disaster, Lin Fenyi pledged 1 million yuan on the goods and spent another 1 million yuan on expanding the factory. She said there was almost &quot;no money&quot; on the books. After work resumed, she had to lay off only three or four workers; condensing machines , sausage filling machines and other machines were all scrapped, and there was no money to replace them. After three days of resumption of production, the shipment volume was only one ton, which was one-sixth of the original maximum production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Debts accumulated quickly. In addition to the hundreds of thousands of yuan she borrowed to expand the factory, she also owes money to various suppliers. One of the pig trotters suppliers, who owed more than 10,000 yuan, came to collect payment several times and was &quot;really getting worried.&quot; Lin Fenyi showed the other party screenshots of her WeChat balance. One time it was a few hundred yuan, and another time it was just over a thousand yuan. &quot;It&#39;s not enough for my children to go to school and buy things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Xitan Village, Zhuozhou City, Du Huanying, who runs a nursing home in partnership with Yan Cheng, is also in a similar predicament. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The nursing home covers an area of ​​5 acres and has more than 60 rooms. Du Huanying remembered that before the flood came, the government moved 58 elderly people in the nursing home to another nursing home in the city in advance because the nursing home was located on a low ground. By August 7, 6 elderly people had been picked up by their family members, and 2 elderly people had passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After borrowing 500,000 yuan to invest, Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home partially resumed operations. On the afternoon of September 15, the nursing home was filled with iron frame beds that had been moved out, and Du Huanying was wiping the rust spots on the bed. She said that the elderly people who had been temporarily moved out had been moved back into their homes, but the economic losses exceeded one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Du Huanying’s nursing home in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the Hebei Provincial Local Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, as of August 23, Zhuozhou City’s financial institutions had visited a total of 1,584 matching companies. households, with loans of 108.905 million yuan issued; the city&#39;s rural housing insurance has prepaid 26,960 households, a total of 80.88 million yuan; planting insurance has prepaid 105,300 acres, a total of 52.6222 million yuan; breeding insurance has prepaid 11,644 heads, a total of 17.1295 million yuan; Vehicle insurance has paid out compensation for 10,157 vehicles, up to 658 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to CCTV, after the disaster, 14 counties (cities, districts) in Baoding provided counterpart support to 11 towns in Zhuozhou. By the beginning of October, a total of 28 construction teams with 1,040 people from outside Zhuozhou had helped the affected people repair their houses. In addition, the total number of flooded houses in Zhuozhou City is 54,323. Excluding those who are not willing to rebuild, the total number of restoration and reconstruction tasks is 52,843, and 46,706 have been completed. All 124 dilapidated and collapsed buildings that need to be completed in 2023 have started construction, and people&#39;s production and living order is being restored at an accelerated pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Life around Beijing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beijing has a complex meaning for Xiu Mingyu. Today, many of her customers are car owners commuting between Beijing and Zhuozhou. But she once had to leave Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than 20 years ago, Xiu Mingyu left his hometown in Henan and went to Beijing. He started as a supermarket salesperson with a monthly salary of 400 yuan, and his husband learned to do auto repair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The couple&#39;s life has always been tight. After deducting living expenses from their salary, there is not much money left. In 2009, a child was born, and life became even less affluent. A family of three lived in an urban village in Haidian District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After working in a supermarket for seven or eight years, in 2014, Xiu Mingyu decided to open an auto parts store with her husband. A year later, the couple moved to Shijingshan District on the outskirts of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The store was still being renovated, and the two received a clearance notice again. Now recalling the experience of being forced to move twice, Xiu Mingyu is glad that when she left Shijingshan, at least the local government compensated her for the cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Fenyi also worked as a North Piao. When she was sixteen or seventeen, she left her hometown in Heilongjiang and went to Beijing to sell clothes, where she met her husband, who was a construction worker at the time. In 2004, the two got married and returned to their husband&#39;s hometown in Zhuozhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I first returned to Zhuozhou, life was not easy. Lin Fenyi remembers that when she was in confinement after giving birth to her daughter, her husband’s old house still had cracks in it. Her father did not dare to come see her. After his brother came, he asked: &quot;Sister, how can you find such a poor person? How can you live in such a house?&quot; He introduced his sister to a way out, making cooked food, &quot;It&#39;s better to do some small business.&quot; It’s better than working for someone else.” The couple slowly started a cooked food business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng didn’t have to leave his hometown. He prides himself on being &quot;very smart&quot;. In a township in Zhuanghe City, Liaoning Province, he learned to be a doctor and carpenter at the age of 17, drove a large truck, ran an oil mill, a wood processing factory, and worked as an agricultural machinery station. Webmaster. After struggling for more than ten years, his hometown was about to be flooded due to the construction of a reservoir. He became a &quot;reservoir immigrant&quot; and went to Zhuozhou to live with his relatives in 2000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he arrived in Zhuozhou, Yan Cheng also struggled a lot. He once ran an auto repair shop and earned 300,000 yuan a year. However, he had to close down due to an accident in 2008. In 2015, he joined Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nursing homes are not a profitable business. Du Huanying said that their fees are not high to begin with, but special groups who encounter family difficulties only charge cost. The hospital only earns 150,000 yuan a year, but the investment is huge. Initially, the two spent 2.8 million yuan building a courtyard for more than 40 elderly people. Later, a local official suggested that they expand, so they spent more than 2 million yuan to expand a second courtyard in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The second courtyard had just been completed when it encountered an epidemic. The nursing home is under closed management and cannot admit new elderly people. Yan Cheng&#39;s son-in-law said that during the epidemic, they did not ask the elderly family members to pay for various medicines. &quot;It has not been easy to make money for three years during the epidemic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Lin Fenyi&#39;s eyes, her business has not been making money for a long time. In the beginning, she and her husband knew nothing, so they could only throw in three to five thousand yuan to accumulate experience. If a batch of goods was broken, they would throw it away and replace it with another batch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This line is dirty and tiring. When stewing pig heads, work starts at 5 a.m. and the pig heads are shaved first. This work makes people covered in oil. Afterwards, the brains are cut open, and the pig head divided into two sections is boiled in a pot. After cooking, the bones and meat are separated, washed, bagged, and put in the cold storage to freeze. The work can only be finished at eight or nine in the evening. There is no heating in the winter. The place - about ten years ago, my husband&#39;s old house was demolished, and the family had to live in the factory bungalow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Linfen Yijia’s factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After so many years, their lives are finally on the right track: Xiu Mingyu opened a shop, bought a house, and settled down in Zhuozhou. The fate of being constantly exiled seems to have come to an end; Yan Cheng and Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home survived the epidemic, and even elderly people from Beijing came to stay there; Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory gradually made money, hired workers, and her husband took care of it. When it comes to purchasing goods, she is in charge of sales, and the cooked food is sold to Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until the flood hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng is 64 years old and cannot retire yet. &quot;I have to help her (Du Huanying). If I don&#39;t, she will fall down immediately.&quot; The cost of building a nursing home is still nearly 4 million yuan, and new debts have been incurred after the flood. This old man, who had been swallowed by water twice in his life, decided to work for a few more years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The missing son, the deceased wife&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son Ma Lihua disappeared in the mudslide more than two months ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Initially, Ma Xianlin, a villager in Tangjiazhuang Village, Laishui County, pinned his hope of finding his son on an excavator. By mid-September, he had no choice but to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;21-year-old Ma Lihua is a student majoring in imaging medicine and will just graduate in the summer of 2023. He was supposed to have a life slowly unfolding in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tangjiazhuang Village is one of the villages severely affected by this round of heavy rains and floods. On July 31, Ma Xianlin narrowly escaped from the mudslide that poured into the yard, but Ma Lihua was nowhere to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son should have walked out of this mountain. When she was a child, Ma Lihua occasionally said she didn&#39;t want to study anymore, and Ma Xianlin would always show up and give her own account: He dropped out of elementary school in the third grade and was uneducated, so he had to work in a coal mine. Earning money was difficult and dangerous. So, my son returned to school obediently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, Ma Lihua just completed more than nine months of hospital internship and graduated from a college in Tangshan. During the summer, he was learning to drive while planning for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ma Xianlin said that a relative in Zhuolu County once wanted to introduce his son to a job in a small hospital, but he refused and insisted on going to Beijing. My sister, who has been a fitness instructor in Beijing for 10 years, also wants to take her younger brother with her. If she can&#39;t go to a big hospital, she goes to a small clinic. She remembered that her brother once asked her if she wanted to go outside to practice. She replied decisively, &quot;Just stay by my side.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, the day when siblings get together may never come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first time that 65-year-old Ma Xianlin has lost a close relative. When he was 12 years old, his father was hit in the head by a falling stone while working in the production team. He died before he could be carried to the hospital. The mother was so anxious about her husband&#39;s death that she lost her sight. A few years later, several of Ma Xianlin&#39;s sisters got married and left home, leaving him and his mother alone in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It wasn&#39;t until he was in his thirties that Ma Xianlin married a wife and had someone to take care of his mother, so he was able to go out to work. In Hebei, he worked in private coal mines and also paved roads and built walls. Four years ago, Ma Xianlin got old and couldn&#39;t move big rocks, so he bought 30 sheep and started herding them in his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The flock continues to multiply. In 2022, Ma Xianlin sold 48 lambs for 20,000 to 30,000 yuan. By this year, he already had 160 sheep. Based on the calculation of 700 yuan for a lamb and 1,400 yuan for an adult sheep, this will be a good income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly, in a mudslide, nearly half of the sheep disappeared. For more than a month after the disaster, he went up the mountain every day to look for sheep, but he harvested very little. He had a bone spur in his leg and had to take medicine every day to treat the leg pain. He had to walk up and down the mountains to herd and find sheep, which was unbearable for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am getting older and my younger (children) are gone.&quot; In the end, he made up his mind to sell all the sheep after autumn. On September 12, when asked about his future livelihood, Ma Xianlin remained silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 15, Southern Weekend reporters contacted Ma Xianlin again, hoping to learn about the progress of his search for his son. He didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirty kilometers away in Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, 67-year-old villager Pang Shenggong also lost his loved ones in flash floods and mudslides on July 31. His wife was swept away by the current, and the family searched for seven or eight miles but could not find her. Later, someone found her body 70 to 80 kilometers away from her home and brought her back to the village for burial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 12, 2023, Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he met the Southern Weekend reporter on September 15, Pang Shenggong was no longer willing to mention this sad incident. He had just come out of the mountains, wearing a bamboo hat and his clothes were no longer messy - a month ago, he was covered in mud when cleaning up the washed-out house, and his trousers were only tied with a cloth belt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In his impression, his wife has a cheerful personality and likes to dance in the village yangko team. But three years ago, my wife had a fall. After the operation, her body was not as good as before, and she could not walk on the aisle. &quot;I can&#39;t leave you for a while,&quot; Pang Shenggong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is not easy to make a living while being chained to your home. Since the 1980s, Pang Shenggong has been working outside the home and often goes to Beijing. He worked in the coal mines of Fangshan District to dig coal and build railways. He continued to work until he was in his fifties. In order to take care of his children and go to school, he gradually stopped going out and worked small jobs in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After his wife&#39;s surgery, Pang Shenggong never worked as a minor worker again. Fortunately, the younger son is moving goods in a warehouse in Gu&#39;an County, Langfang City, so he can supplement Pang Shenggong&#39;s monthly salary of three to four thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Pang Shenggong has moved into the temporarily unused house of the third brother in the east of the village, and is ready to live a hard life. &quot;How much money do you have to spend?&quot; His voice gradually faded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Hebei Daily, on September 22, the first batch of post-disaster reconstruction projects in Laishui County have started intensively, with a total investment of 185 million yuan, including river cleaning The siltation project, four bridge reconstruction projects and the first batch of post-disaster power distribution network reconstruction projects will be completed before the 2024 flood season. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Villages in the suburbs of Beijing heal the wounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the suburbs of Beijing, mountains separate the villages from the prosperity . A flood passed through and the force of nature tore the village apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, according to villager Liu Huazao, there were originally one or two thousand people living in the village. An entire street in the south was seriously damaged by the flood. About one to two hundred people were temporarily relocated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 27, Liu Huazao&#39;s father went to Tongren Hospital for eye laser treatment. Some time ago, he always felt like mosquitoes were flying in front of his eyes. After checking, he found out that the vitreous body had fallen off. Liu Huazao felt that this was caused by his father being upset and having severe high blood pressure after the flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At around 10 a.m. on July 31, when the water rose the most, the Liu family and their neighbors climbed onto the roof to escape Shen Da. 1.7 meters of water. That night, the water came up again, leaving a second water line about 1 meter high in the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But favor is slowly closing some wounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the water receded, Liu Huazao felt &quot;it&#39;s good to be alive.&quot; The villagers who had survived the disaster met and said to each other, &quot;Just live, don&#39;t talk about anything else.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The relatives are closer. One after another, relatives outside the country reached out to help Liu Huazao&#39;s family, &quot;giving them some money.&quot; The disaster-stricken family even lacked clothes and cooking utensils. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The neighbors suddenly have a &quot;life-changing&quot; friendship. In the past, Liu Huazao didn&#39;t move around very frequently with the villagers, just &quot;meet and say hello.&quot; But he felt that the moments of life and death in the water inspired goodwill in people&#39;s hearts. On the day the family hid on the roof, a neighbor in the front yard helped hold Liu Huazao&#39;s daughter. After the disaster, the villagers helped each other. When the silt in their own homes was almost cleared, they would be cleared by others. Elderly people in the village who had children in other places would ask them what shortcomings there were in their homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembered that before the water supply in the village was restored, a group of young people organized water trucks to deliver water for washing to the villagers. For four or five days, they stopped the car at the entrance of the alley and called the villagers to get water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu, who opened a supermarket in the village, witnessed the complexity of human beings in the flood. Five to six thousand yuan in cash was taken away from the supermarket by water, but she only got back more than one thousand yuan. She heard that someone found money, but she didn&#39;t know if it was lost by her family and couldn&#39;t ask for it. She also heard that many people picked up the wine that was washed away from her home, but very little was returned. Only one bottle of 10 bottles of liquor worth more than 1,000 yuan was returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhu Xiu did not feel resentful about this. &quot;If you lose it, it&#39;s not like someone stole it from you. Whoever picked it up belongs to the one who picked it up... We just accept that we are unlucky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiuye I thought maybe insurance would pay some compensation. Last year, she took out an insurance policy in a daze. After the disaster, someone from the insurance company came and told her that the insurance was not for property, but for people. Zhu Xiu, who couldn&#39;t even find the contract, had no choice but to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also discovered the kindness between people. A winery promised to replace her damaged wine for free, and relatives and friends provided money, food, and pots and pans after the disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the supporters, many, like Zhu Xiu, are migrant workers in Beijing. &quot;There is a feeling of closeness... Being so far away from my hometown makes me feel that we can understand each other.&quot; She remembered that about 20 years ago, she and her husband first settled in Cijijiao, and later more foreigners came. Work in the village. Some migrant workers had no money left after buying tickets to Beijing, no place to sleep, and no food to eat. It was she who made noodles and steamed buns and spread bedding in the rented room to provide food and accommodation for them. When those who couldn&#39;t find a job had to leave, she would give them travel expenses. Now, it seems that goodwill from the past has been repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 27, 2023, Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Beijing Daily, on the morning of August 27, Fangshan District held a post-disaster reconstruction swearing-in meeting at Sandu Bridge. The overall goal of reconstruction is &quot;basic recovery in one year, comprehensive improvement in three years, and long-term high-quality development.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Xiuli, chief of the Planning and Urban Design Section of the Fangshan District Planning and Nature Commission, said in an interview with CCTV that according to Beijing&#39;s unified standards, for collapsed buildings It is recommended that dilapidated houses be demolished and rebuilt. Each house will be compensated at a rate of 95,000 yuan. For repairable houses, a repair compensation of 30,000 yuan will be given, and low-income households will receive double compensation. For houses that are uninhabitable, each person will be paid a total of 3,960 yuan for three months. rental subsidy. In addition, each person is provided with a living allowance of 660 yuan. Staff from the Fangshan District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee said that repair compensation of 30,000 yuan has been gradually distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have to stand up no matter what”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the villagers’ accounts, the flood was not the first change that Ci’s housework had experienced. , this once prosperous village has been in decline for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembers that the household chores thirty years ago were more generous than they are now. At that time, there was a dragon dance lantern show, a two-story shopping mall and a movie theater. What supports these are the workers in the surrounding coal mines and cement plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu&#39;s husband is one of them. More than 20 years ago, Zhu Xiu was still farming in her hometown in Anhui, and her life was difficult. When she saw a fellow villager working in Cijiujiu&#39;s cement factory, she came with her husband. Her husband followed the car in the factory, and she sold vegetables in the village. . She remembered that there were many migrant workers at that time, and dozens of people could live in a small courtyard in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the local area, factories and coal mines are a double-edged sword. Liu Huazao still remembers their pollution. When he was a child, there would be gray dust like white flour in the village. On the other hand, although working as a factory and miner does not make much money, it is a job that can make a living at home. Liu Huazao&#39;s father had worked in a cement factory in his early years, driving a tractor to transport stones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 2000, cement plants and coal mines were closed down one after another. The pollution is gone, and the livelihood at home is even more cut off. If they want to make a living, villagers can only run to the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu found that the Anhui fellows who worked at Ciji as housekeepers left one after another, but she did not leave. After her husband lost his job at the cement factory, she borrowed money from relatives and friends to open a supermarket in the village. More than ten years ago, a market was built in the village, and people from surrounding towns came to do business. The supermarket was once very prosperous. &quot;Our business used to be the best in this village.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Around 2015, the village ushered in a turning point - demolition. Some villagers chose to move away and wait to move into the resettlement community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan didn’t leave. The bus driver, who was a farmer, wanted to buy a house for himself, his son and his married daughter, but he failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family did not leave either. Apart from being dissatisfied with the compensation package, the family has gotten used to life in the village. The small courtyard can enjoy the cool air, and the elderly can grow cucumbers, tomatoes, and eggplants, and save some money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only private houses are being demolished, but around 2019, the market in front of Zhuxiujia Supermarket was also demolished and moved elsewhere. Her business gradually shrank, and the supermarket&#39;s annual revenue dropped to two to three million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, in the summer of 2023, there was a record-breaking flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 31, villager Li Guangnan ran out with waist-deep water. On August 20, he returned to work at the bus company. More than a month later, his old life seemed to be back, but he knew that order was far from being restored. When he was working as a driver, he earned a monthly salary of nearly 10,000 yuan at most. In 2022, because of his hearing loss, he took a second job and took a cleaning job, so his monthly salary was reduced to 4,000 yuan. In two years, he will retire, and his income will be cut in half. Life may be even more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan has always been worried about his son. He has worked in both the bus and subway companies, but he didn&#39;t last long and was still old. Before the disaster, my son was driving Didi. After the flood washed away the car, he didn&#39;t even drive Didi again. At the end of September, when asked whether he wanted to return to his old career, his son only replied: &quot;Maybe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family, who did not want to live in a high-rise building, also faced reality. Compromised. The house had to be rebuilt. Before he raised 600,000 yuan to break ground, Liu Huazao rented a house in a nearby community for a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is most worried about his 5-year-old daughter. Just after the flood, his daughter said to him: &quot;Dad, I was so scared that day.&quot; Liu Huazao told her not to be afraid, he would come to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly two months later, Liu Huazao discovered that although her daughter knew that floods would wash away tablets and toys, she still didn’t understand that floods would endanger her life, and she was mentally unstable. Something went terribly wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is also working hard to escape the shadow of the flood. Liu Huazao knows that he is the backbone of the family, and only by adjusting himself can his family feel relieved. So, he tried hard to find some little surprises for himself: plastic objects can still be used after being rinsed, and some electronic devices can still turn on their screens with a swipe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu’s half-life hard work was gone with the water. In mid-September, when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the second time, she said that she felt quite depressed and couldn&#39;t think about it for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the third time at the end of September, she finally recovered. The store still had to stay open, and she didn&#39;t want to cheat the suppliers who agreed to her credit. &quot;You have to stand up and work hard no matter what. You can&#39;t just lie down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She thought that if the business was not going well, she would open a store somewhere else. As for her hometown where she still had three acres of land, Zhu Xiu knew that she would never be able to go back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Ma Xianlin and Ma Lihua, pseudonyms are used in the article)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20家上市银行中报出炉：信贷投放最多的行业不良率高还是低？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258820]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Changes in bank credit asset quality reflect the pulse of the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin, director of the Macro-Prudential Administration Bureau of the People&#39;s Bank of China, attended the press conference on financial statistics for the third quarter of 2023 on October 13 and said that as of the end of June, the average non-performing ratio of systemically important banks was 1.27%, maintaining achieve higher asset quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin said that the total assets of systemically important banks account for 61% of the total assets of my country&#39;s banking industry and 55% of the total assets of the financial industry. Systemically important banks have relatively high structural and business complexity, and relatively strong correlations with other financial institutions. Therefore, data from systemically important banks better reflects the latest changes in the banking industry and even the macroeconomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, 19 of the 20 systemically important banks have been listed on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges, making them the most fully disclosed group in the banking industry. Since 2023, which industries have the best and worst credit assets of systemically important banks? Which banks have the most effective measures to resolve non-performing assets? Which banks have the most adequate disclosure of information about their non-performing assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;823&quot; height= &quot;1102&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New For this purpose, researchers from the Financial Research Center conducted a special review and data analysis of the interim reports of the 20 listed banks with the largest assets (including 19 systemically important banks and China Zheshang Bank). The study found that as of the end of June, the total loan balance of 20 listed banks was nearly 150 trillion yuan, accounting for 63.5% of the total loan scale of all financial institutions; the total scale of non-performing loans was approximately 1.92 trillion yuan, accounting for approximately 48% of the total scale of non-performing assets of financial institutions. %, the average non-performing loan ratio is about 1.28%, which is lower than the average non-performing loan ratio of the banking industry of 1.62%, indicating that the credit quality of large and medium-sized commercial banks is better than that of small and medium-sized banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the real estate industry , manufacturing and business services industries rank among the top three in terms of non-performing loan size, and the accommodation and catering industry, real estate industry and mining industry have the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The balance of non-performing credit card loans exceeded that of personal housing loans for the first time in three years, and the non-performing loan rate was 4.2 times higher than that of personal housing loans. Looking at the regional distribution of non-performing loans, the western region has the largest scale of non-performing loans, and the northeastern region has the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Large loan size and low NPL ratio&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Transportation, warehousing and postal industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Which Which industry receives the greatest support from bank credit? Are their NPL ratios positively or negatively related to bank support? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center combed through the interim reports of 20 listed banks and found that each bank disclosed the distribution of corporate loans in 20 major industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing and postal services are the three industries with the most credit granted by the 20 listed banks. The total loan balance of the three industries at the end of June exceeded 10 trillion. Yuan. With regulators vigorously promoting the high-quality development of the manufacturing industry, the manufacturing industry has become a credit area that major commercial banks attach great importance to. Among the 20 listed banks, 19 banks rank in the top two in terms of manufacturing investment scale. However, the leasing and business services industry ranks first among the 20 banks’ credit lending industries the most, with 10 companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Has the massive increase in industry credit been accompanied by a sharp increase in non-performing loans since then? An analysis by researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that increased credit in some industries is indeed positively related to the growth of non-performing loans. This is especially obvious in the real estate industry. As the credit scale ranks fourth in the industry and the average non-performing rate in the industry ranks second, it has become the industry with the most concentrated credit risks of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1161&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But 20 The industry distribution of credit granted by listed banks does not completely coincide with the industry distribution of non-performing loans. As of the end of June 2023, the average non-performing ratios of the manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing, and postal industries that provide the most credit are only 1.8%, 1.45%, and 0.64% respectively. The real estate, manufacturing, leasing and business services industries have the highest scale of non-performing loans, with balances of non-performing loans reaching 295.1 billion, 266 billion and 208.8 billion respectively. The total scale is close to 770 billion, accounting for 57% of the non-performing balance of corporate loans. The total non-performing loans 40%. Among them, the transportation, warehousing and postal industry has credit extensions of up to 13.8 trillion yuan, but its non-performing ratio is only 0.64%. It is a typical industry with large loan scale and low non-performing ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1232&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also found , the increase in the scale of credit in a certain industry is not necessarily accompanied by the year-on-year increase in the scale of non-performing loans. For example, compared with the end of 2022, as of the end of June 2023, the manufacturing loan balance has increased by as high as 18.83%, and the loan growth rate is at the forefront of all industries, but its non-performing loan balance has remained the same or even slightly decreased compared with the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Banks are most willing to lend in the &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yangtze River Delta&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The intensity of credit support for different industries is differentiated At the same time, in which areas do banks have the greatest differentiation in their countercyclical investments? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that most of the 20 listed banks disclosed the regional distribution of credit and the regional distribution of non-performing loans, but each bank’s regional division method Not the same as above. Among them, the regional distribution rules of six banks, namely Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank of China, China Merchants Bank and China Minsheng Bank, are completely consistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1303&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center analyzed the mid-term reports of the above-mentioned six banks and found that the six banks in the Yangtze River Delta region have the largest credit scale, the highest proportion, the fastest growth rate, and the lowest average non-performing loan ratio. Based on the conclusions of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center&#39;s special survey on Suzhou&#39;s financial ecology in April 2023 (see Southern Weekend APP&#39;s &quot;Suzhou Financial Ecology In-depth Research Special Topic&quot; for details), researchers from Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that as China&#39;s economic engine region , the financial ecology of the Yangtze River Delta region (mainly Shanghai, Jiangsu, and Zhejiang) maintains a leading level in the country. Banks generally want and are willing to lend to the real economy, and the ultra-low non-performing ratio further strengthens the banks&#39; position in the Yangtze River Delta market. Dare to lend, truly lend, and increase confidence in credit extension. Therefore, the Yangtze River Delta region is undoubtedly the area where commercial banks dare to lend the most, and it is also a must-have for the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;975&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rated system Among the five city commercial banks that are important banks, four are from the Yangtze River Delta region. The asset scale, operating efficiency and asset quality of these city commercial banks are among the best in the industry. This proves that the Yangtze River Delta region has the best financial ecological environment in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the credit growth rate of the 20 listed banks in the northeastern region (Heilongjiang, Jilin, and Liaoning) is the slowest, the credit proportion continues to shrink, and the non-performing loan ratio is high among all regions in the country. Data shows that large state-owned banks are more determined than joint-stock banks and city commercial banks in implementing the strategic intentions of decision-makers to revitalize the Northeast. The financial support of large state-owned banks to the Northeast is also the mainstay for the stable operation of the financial industry in the Northeast. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Non-performing personal mortgage loans surged&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The momentum eased&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although corporate loans are the mainstay of commercial bank credit, personal loan business is becoming increasingly important , especially personal housing loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scale of personal mortgage loans remains the largest among all personal loans of commercial banks, and the non-performing rate has been at the lowest level among all types of loan business for a long time. Therefore, it has become the most valued high-quality asset of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes have occurred in the asset quality of personal mortgage loans? In order to facilitate comparisons with the same caliber, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center selected 10 banks’ personal mortgage businesses for statistical analysis. These 10 banks include six state-owned commercial banks, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank, and Bank of Communications, and four national joint-stock commercial banks, China Merchants Bank, Industrial Bank, Shanghai Pudong Development Bank, and Minsheng Bank. As of the end of 2022, the total scale of personal mortgage loans of 10 banks accounts for 80% of the total scale of personal mortgage loans in the banking industry. Therefore, the personal mortgage business of the 10 banks has strong industry representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research shows that starting from 2022, the growth rate of non-performing loan balances of personal housing loans has increased significantly. At the end of June 2022, the total non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 104.871 billion yuan, a sharp increase of 16.8 billion yuan from the end of 2021, with a month-on-month growth rate of 19.1%; in the second half of 2022, the non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks increased again. An increase of 30.4 billion yuan. By the end of 2022, the total balance of non-performing loans has increased to 135.255 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 53.6%; in the first half of 2023, the balance of non-performing loans has reached 138.629 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 32.2%, but the month-on-month growth rate is as high as fell back to 2.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second central bank The quarterly monetary policy implementation report shows that at the end of June, the balance of personal housing loans of major financial institutions across the country (including foreign capital) was 38.6 trillion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.7%, and the first year-on-year negative growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the surge in non-performing loan balances and the stagnant growth rate of loan scale that turned negative, the non-performing rate of personal housing loans has increased significantly since 2022. At the end of June 2023, the average non-performing rate of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 0.48%, an increase of 0.15 percentage points from the end of 2021, an increase of 45%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center believe that despite the rapid growth in the scale and non-performing ratio of personal housing loans, compared with other types of credit, personal housing loans are still high-quality assets of commercial banks and will continue to be an important part of each bank&#39;s personal loan business. focus. At the same time, the central bank and other ministries and commissions have successively introduced new housing loan policies and continued to loosen restrictions on the real estate industry. The asset quality of personal housing loan business is expected to stabilize in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Credit card business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Facing test&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to personal mortgage business, credit card business is also the strategic focus of commercial banks. How does it perform? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center comparatively analyzed the interim reports of 13 commercial banks that disclosed the quality of credit card loans and found that the credit card business has seen multiple trend changes since 2022. First, two important indicators recorded negative growth for the first time on record. Among them, at the end of 2022, the cumulative number of credit cards issued was approximately 798 million, showing negative growth for the first time on record; the outstanding credit balance of credit cards was 8.69 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 0.9%, which was significantly higher than the average annual growth rate of 8% between 2019 and 2021. decline. As of the end of June 2023, the outstanding credit balance of credit cards of 13 listed banks (the scale of credit card business accounts for about 85% of the total scale of the banking industry) was 7.44 trillion yuan, a decrease of about 23 billion yuan from the end of 2022, which was also the first time on record. decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;948&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is credit card The quality of business assets is facing tests. As of the end of June 2023, the total non-performing balance of credit card accounts receivable of 13 commercial banks reached 148.2 billion yuan, slightly exceeding personal housing loans with a limit of 4 billion yuan. Following the 2020 interim report, it has once again become the personal loan business with the largest non-performing loan. . Correspondingly, the average non-performing loan ratio of credit card receivables of 13 banks is 2.29%, which is also a new high in the past three years after the 2020 mid-term report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2023, the asset quality pressure of commercial banks’ credit card business will increase significantly. Among them, the credit card non-performing loan balance and non-performing loan ratio reached two peaks in June 2020 and June 2023 respectively, with the peak in June 2020 being slightly higher than that in June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center further studied the two peaks and found that the peak of credit card non-performing in June 2020 was mainly due to the sudden impact of the epidemic on household and personal balance sheets, superimposed on the factors of untimely repayment caused by restricted movement of people during the epidemic; During the period when the epidemic is calming down, the balance of non-performing loans and non-performing loans of commercial banks&#39; credit cards have tended to fall, but the low point of the decline is still significantly higher than before the epidemic. Since 2023, commercial banks have responded to regulatory requirements and no longer blindly compete for land, but have turned to intensive cultivation and prudent credit extension. The growth of credit card issuance volume, credit scale, unfinished credit scale and other indicators has significantly slowed down or even experienced negative growth. This has also led to a high non-performing rate in credit card business. However, as banks continue to implement prudent strategies, credit card non-performing rates are expected to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Which banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; “&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;optimize”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; bad disclosures? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The two indicators of non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio are the most important and most sensitive indicators to measure the quality of credit assets. Which commercial banks have the courage to conduct complete and comprehensive information disclosure on the quality of their credit assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comparative study of this item by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center is mainly based on whether 20 listed banks disclose information on corporate loans by industry and region, and whether the industry and region of non-performing loans are separately Disclosure: When disclosing the components of personal loans, including personal housing loans, consumer loans, operating loans, and credit card loan balances, proportions, and growth rates, whether the corresponding non-performing loan balances and non-performing ratios are disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study found that in terms of the quality of information disclosure on non-performing loans, the level of disclosure of 20 listed banks varied. Large state-owned banks basically disclosed the above information at the same time. Only Bank of China stated &quot;non-performing&quot; as &quot;impairment&quot; in its annual report, which may easily cause certain misunderstandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the national joint-stock banks, China Merchants Bank has the most complete disclosure of non-performing loans, while other joint-stock banks have more or less &quot;optimized&quot; non-performing loan-related data according to their own needs when disclosing. Typical &quot;optimization&quot; methods include setting personalized &quot;caliber&quot;. For example, when disclosing the industry distribution of non-performing loans, some banks do not directly disclose the non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio data of each industry. However, through other relevant data disclosed by the bank, the distribution of non-performing loans in different industries of the bank can be estimated; For another example, when disclosing the non-performing status of personal housing loans, some banks merged this business with other personal loan businesses with certified mortgages; in addition, when disclosing the regional distribution of non-performing loans, 6 of the 9 joint-stock banks were based on the Yangtze River Delta A total of 6 regions are divided and disclosed, including the Pearl River Delta, the Bohai Rim, the central region, the western region and the northeastern region. However, Ping An Bank and Zheshang Bank divide the country into 4 regions; Industrial Bank divides the country into 4 regions based on geographical regions. The city, province or other important city where the headquarters is located is listed and disclosed separately; individual banks will also fine-tune the provinces under a certain region, making it difficult to make horizontal and vertical comparisons of the regional distribution of the bank&#39;s credit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some banks disclose weaker asset quality for retail loans than for corporate loans. Among the 20 listed banks, 13 banks directly disclosed or indirectly disclosed the distribution of personal loans in their interim reports. However, extending to 2020 and previous annual reports and interim reports, only about 10 banks disclosed the asset quality of personal loans. As a leading city commercial bank, Bank of Beijing has disclosed neither the industry distribution nor the regional distribution of non-performing loans in its previous annual reports and interim reports. It has disclosed the least asset quality among the 20 listed banks. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frequency of mentions of &quot;bad&quot; in financial reports can also be used as an indication of the bank&#39;s credit disclosure adequacy in terms of loan quality. Statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found that China Merchants Bank was mentioned as &quot;non-performing&quot; the most in the 2023 interim report, a total of 94 times, while the Bank of Jiangsu was mentioned the least often, only 19 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True and accurate , completeness, timeliness and fairness are the principle requirements for the information disclosure of listed companies. Standardization, easy to understand and easy to obtain are the basic requirements for the form of information disclosure of listed companies. According to this, a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that listed systemically important banks are the benchmark for China&#39;s banking industry and should also be the benchmark for information disclosure in the banking industry. Annual reports and annual reports should be based on various requirements for information disclosure by listed companies. The disclosure of important information such as interim reports is strictly controlled. In particular, indicators related to bank asset quality and their changes have attracted more attention from investors and the public. Listed banks should disclose true, accurate, complete, timely and fair information, and ensure that the disclosed information is standardized. , easy to understand and obtain, and continuously improve the compliance and transparency of corporate governance of listed banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[挑选、比较和竞争：2024届毕业生的第一场双选会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1103&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D 2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Guangzhou, after the double selection meeting on Jinan University . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lights were all bright in the thousands-square-meter gymnasium, and 28 tables were arranged in a circle. The tabletop is covered with blue velvet, and beside each table stands a promotional poster as tall as one person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on September 20, 2023, at the Wushan Campus of South China University of Technology in Guangzhou, in half an hour, the special double election meeting for Shenzhen state-owned enterprises will begin. This is the third &quot;double selection meeting&quot; prepared by this 985 university for the 2024 graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The topic of employment for graduates in 2023 is still hot, and the school recruitment season for 2024 has begun again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Owen Xin, a senior student in our school’s School of Business Administration, has been waiting on the sidelines for a long time. She had done a lot of planning in advance. She was wearing a white T-shirt with a small colorful pattern and the hem was tucked into light-colored suit pants. It was half casual and half formal. On a certain social platform, a state-owned enterprise employee once posted, Different from the stereotype of full-body formal wear, &quot;business casual&quot; is the image of employees favored by state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Specially for state-owned enterprises”, Owen Xin stepped into the venue of the autumn recruitment fair for the first time. She had long made up her mind to take the civil service examination, and the administrative position in a state-owned enterprise, which was the least stable, was regarded as a &quot;guaranteed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every fall semester begins, thousands of freshmen enter colleges and universities, and thousands of fresh graduates are about to be sent to the next stop on the train of life. But it is not easy to get off the bus. According to data released by the Ministry of Education, the number of college graduates in 2024 is expected to reach 11.87 million, reaching a new high, an increase of 290,000 from 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Double selection usually means the beginning of the new school recruitment season. This is a traditional recruitment form that directly invites companies to join the school to achieve offline face-to-face communication and two-way selection between companies and job-seeking students. Every step and every person leading to the workplace is surrounded by selection, comparison and competition. As policies, markets, and employment concepts change, the status of academic qualifications, majors, industries, and positions has also changed several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last 10 days of September 2023, Southern Weekend reporters visited a total of four double selection meetings of varying sizes in three schools in Guangzhou. At the same time, the autumn double elections across the country started almost simultaneously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1106&quot; height= &quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Guangzhou, the theme of the South China University of Technology was the double selection meeting for the 2024 campus recruitment of Shenzhen state-owned enterprises. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Enterprises that are in trouble&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;They are not You know, our company is very good.” Wang Ming, the head of human resources at a state-owned real estate company in Shenzhen, complained at the Chinese Workers’ Dual Election Meeting on September 20. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the group was founded in 1989 and went public three years later. It is mainly engaged in real estate development and operations and is directly managed by the Shenzhen Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This state-owned enterprise is well prepared. Most companies present only sent two personnel, while they sent three. But obviously, the extra manpower was not put to much use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were very few inquiries. When he was bored, Wang Ming took two photos. One picture is of another company, with four or five students queuing up in front of the booth, waiting for consultation; the other picture is of their own booth, with two HRs staring blankly in front of no one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ming’s group is not the only company that has faced the cold shoulder in this double election. Even if they are state-owned enterprises and some established real estate companies, they have been left out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2010, the golden age of the real estate industry, they were also a popular unit in the double election. &quot;The real estate industry has been in decline since two or three years ago.&quot; HR from one of the companies said frankly, &quot;Many students majoring in civil engineering and architecture have chosen to change industries, and students who intend to find employment in the real estate industry are also more cautious.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;Fortunately, good policies have been introduced.&quot; Wang Ming said, taking out his mobile phone and showing the &quot;internal information&quot; he had obtained. The screenshot with black text on a white background mentioned that some districts in Guangzhou will completely cancel property purchase restrictions. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the &quot;inside information&quot; was publicly confirmed. On the afternoon of the same day, Guangzhou issued the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot; - Guangzhou became the first city among the first-tier cities in the country to partially relax purchase restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time in the past, the three industries of Internet, real estate, and education were known as the “Three Giants of School Recruitment” due to their large number of school recruitment positions and strong talent absorption capabilities. Zhaopin Recruitment Job Demand Data It shows that in 2021, the three giants jointly provided 56% of positions for fresh graduates. In the same year, the situation changed. Due to various reasons, the three giants frequently laid off employees, and the motivation for school recruitment was also insufficient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If real estate practitioners can still see some opportunities from policy changes, the education and training industry still does not know what the future holds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HR Deng Wenqing of a well-known education and training institution considers herself to be very &quot;hardworking&quot;. Since September, as the company&#39;s human resources representative in Guangzhou, she has participated in three double-election meetings. &quot;I was basically the last one to leave.&quot; Another double selection meeting on September 26 was originally scheduled to end at 5 p.m. Deng Wenqing sat until 5:30. Whenever a student stopped in front of the booth, she enthusiastically handed over the brochure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But her diligence cannot eliminate the impact of the education and training reform two years ago. An economics master&#39;s student stopped when passing by the booth and asked bluntly: &quot;Is this unrestricted? Does the state not care?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Wenqing repeated the explanation: &quot;The double reduction is for compulsory education and make-up classes. We only focus on high school subjects in this area, and focus on comprehensive quality training in junior high schools and below, without restrictions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another double selection meeting at the same time, it was also necessary to explain to the students that another tutor The HR of training institutions also adopts basically the same statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going back to July 2021, the &quot;double reduction&quot; curtain has begun. In one year, subject-based off-campus training institutions across the country have been reduced by more than 90%, and 25 related listed companies have announced that 100% of them will no longer engage in subject-based training in the compulsory education stage. In the past two years, in order to reduce media exposure, Deng Wenqing&#39;s organization has been very low-key in its online recruitment promotions. During the campus recruitment season, HR in various places has turned to offline recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few people talk about the past glory of the education and training industry. In 2020, in the first quarter China job market sentiment report jointly launched by the China Employment Research Institute of Renmin University of China and Zhaopin Recruitment, the education and training industry once ranked first, surpassing the Internet and e-commerce. That year, a leading company launched a spring campus recruitment of 3,000 people, and several online education institutions that became famous that year had a total recruitment of nearly 10,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the double selection meeting on September 20, Deng Wenqing received a total of 12 resumes, and the master of economics who raised the question finally took away a brochure and promised to go back and read it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1246&quot; height= &quot;932&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in Guangzhou, at the double selection meeting on the campus of Jinan University, many graduates gathered in front of the booth of a new materials company. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two-way selection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking Guangzhou as an example, usually Throughout the entire employment season, more than 200 double selection meetings will be held from September to June of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Enterprise recruitment is nothing more than online and offline channels. Online, some recruitment information is posted on the employment website or employment official account. Offline is information sessions and this kind of (double selection) Job fair.&quot; Xu Yang, the project manager of a school recruitment human resources company in Guangzhou introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a human resources service platform focusing on campus recruitment. According to the official website, the platform has reached cooperation with more than 50 universities, hosts more than 200 offline dual selection meetings every year, and has provided services to a total of 206,000 companies. Three of the four double-election meetings visited by Southern Weekend reporters were hosted by this platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, a regular double selection meeting is jointly organized by a university and a human resources company. The school provides the venue and student source data, and the human resources company is responsible for connecting with the company, arranging the venue, etc. Xu Yang said that in the offline format, the double selection meeting is more effective than the information session. Dozens to hundreds of companies are present at the same time. &quot;It will be more efficient in solving employment needs, and the school also recognizes the double selection meeting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for recruitment efficiency, the most intuitive thing for companies is the on-site consultation situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng is running for the double election in his second year. He is the person in charge of the Guangzhou branch of a civil service examination training institution. The institution has only been established for three years. The training business covers civil servants, selected students, public institutions, etc., full-time There are less than 20 lecturers, and it can only be considered a small and micro enterprise in terms of scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the afternoon of September 28, in front of the teaching building of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies, next to Wu Feng’s booth, there were almost no interruptions in the number of students who came to consult. This day is approaching the Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day holiday, so there are not many students participating in the double selection meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng has several copies of &quot;Real Questions for the Written Examination for Selected Students in Guangdong&quot; on his desk. The slogan &quot;Scan the QR code to get it&quot; attracted many students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The public examination is more popular now.” Wu Feng knew that his company had taken advantage of the popularity of the public examination and the postgraduate entrance examination. For many fresh graduates who have not thought clearly about their way out, the iron rice bowl is undoubtedly the &quot;certain way out.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even if the &quot;public examination&quot; is popular, not every time you participate in the double selection meeting, it will be so smooth. Wu Feng mentioned that in the fall of 2022, he went to Sun Yat-sen University to participate in the double selection meeting, but the results were not satisfactory. &quot;Our company is smaller, and those students may prefer big companies more.&quot; This year, the Sun Yat-sen University stop was canceled on his recruiting schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a longer time dimension, school enrollment retention rate also determines corporate recruitment decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li, HR of a news website in Foshan, has participated in the double selection meeting for four years. It is planned that this year she will go to Guangzhou University, Guangdong University of Foreign Studies and other universities to recruit, but the journalism and communication major ranks high A well-known university in the province is not among them. The reason lies in the recruitment retention rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li remembers that in the spring recruitment of 2021, her employer recruited four boys in the same dormitory from this university. After a month, &quot;all left.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Among the four people, some have returned to their hometowns, some have taken the civil service exam, and some have taken the professional education exam.” Huang Li added, “Re-recruitment also requires training, which is time-consuming and costly. I don’t want to recruit students from this university anymore.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies choose schools and are also chosen by schools. &quot;If it is an unknown company with only 10 or 20 people, it will definitely not be accepted. This is irresponsible to the company itself. If they come here, they will not be able to recruit people.&quot; Jinan University double selection on the afternoon of September 26 At the meeting, another person in charge of the aforementioned school recruitment platform revealed that the school will have certain requirements for participating companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Take JNU as an example. What it requires must be well-known companies. For example, how many of China’s top 500 companies, how many of the world’s top 500 companies, what is the salary range, and the academic qualifications suitable for the position (is it Bachelor&#39;s degree and above), these requirements will be met.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some double selection sessions will limit the themes and gather certain types of companies into one session. For example, the double selection meeting held at South China University of Technology on September 20 was aimed at Shenzhen state-owned enterprises, and the double selection meeting held at Guangdong University of Technology on September 26 was aimed at the micro-semiconductor industry. On September 27, another dual-selection meeting held by South China University of Technology gathered more than 200 companies, focusing on recruiting high-level talents in education, scientific research, and medical and health fields that are urgently needed and in short supply in key fields in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1236&quot; height= &quot;924&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, in Guangzhou, the Guangxi-themed double-election meeting on the campus of South China University of Technology carried the slogan &quot;I want to go to Guangxi&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Supply and demand issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to participate in the event on September 27 For the double selection meeting of South China University of Technology, Li Jiamin, a master&#39;s student majoring in materials science at Sun Yat-sen University, specially set out from Shenzhen and took the school bus for nearly two hours to arrive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her enthusiasm dropped by half after entering school. Different from the double-election meeting a week ago, this time the venue was outdoors, crowded, noisy and hot, and corporate leaflets scattered everywhere were trampled under people&#39;s feet. Soon, she was sitting next to the wall to rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiamin graduated from a college in Shanxi three years ago. She concentrated on preparing for the postgraduate entrance examination and &quot;went a lot of effort&quot; to get into the CUHK. When enrolling as a graduate student, her supervisor told her and her classmates not to go to graduate school just to improve their academic qualifications and find a job. But Li Jiamin was not convinced, &quot;The facts are there. The starting salary of graduate students is higher than that of undergraduate students. Everyone thinks so.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in this double election meeting, she specifically inquired about industry salaries. Others told her that in Shenzhen, a monthly salary of less than 20,000 yuan for a master&#39;s degree in materials science is considered low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, every science and engineering student who had no clue when filling out their application form would tacitly memorize the same formula, &quot;Biochemical and environmental materials, four major sinkholes.&quot; In the stereotype, they are synonymous with little money, tiring work, and fierce competition. However, under the guidance of policies such as carbon peaking and carbon neutrality, traditional industries are transforming into new materials, new energy, semiconductors, and smart manufacturing. It is not uncommon for fresh graduates to earn an annual salary of 300,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But today&#39;s double selection meeting still disappointed her a little. &quot;(The monthly salary offered by the company) is around 15,000 to 17,000, which is much lower than I expected.&quot; She brought six resumes, and she had a few left before leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the four years since he has been engaged in campus recruitment, Xu Yang has observed that the asymmetry between supply and demand for jobs at the double selection meeting has become increasingly prominent. On the one hand, students&#39; enthusiasm for employment continues to increase and the number of participants is rising; on the other hand, the number of participating companies and the number of jobs released is decreasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The needs of enterprises are affected by the general environment. In 2021, more than 100 companies will participate in the double selection meeting we will organize at Guangzhou Foreign Language School, but today there are less than 60.&quot; September 28 On the same day, Xu Yang said this at the double election meeting of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xu Yang’s view, the asymmetric supply and demand relationship has both good and bad effects on the employment situation. &quot;The good thing is that for companies, there are fewer people to recruit, but there are more students coming. Companies can have more opportunities to select the right people. But it has indeed become harder for students to find jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 28, a female student from Guangdong Pharmaceutical University finished her interview with Wu Feng and stopped in front of the booth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked why she was interested in the public examination institution, the girl pulled the Southern Weekend reporter aside and whispered, &quot;You can work part-time and take the public examination at the same time.&quot; Then her expression changed again. She was suspicious, &quot;I told you, how can I find a job?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her worries may be unnecessary. Wu Feng doesn&#39;t mind that the lecturer is preparing for the civil service exam at the same time. On the contrary, he encourages it. In his opinion, &quot;you will get started faster if you have experience in preparing for the exam.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng even said that when it comes to the interview stage, he will directly advise job seekers to prepare for the public examination. After the examination, they will determine their initial intentions and final re-examination. But when he said this, he frowned and did not relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Wang Ming, Deng Wenqing, Xu Yang, Wu Feng, Huang Li, and Li Jiamin are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[登上热搜的“支原体肺炎”究竟是个啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258836]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:36:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine Outside the emergency clinic, parents wait with their children. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254373&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, parents waited with their children outside the emergency clinic on the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sure enough, it&#39;s mycoplasma again!&quot; On October 16, 2023, Dr. Ding Guodong from Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, formerly We planned to watch 30 special numbers in the morning, and temporarily added 10 more numbers, which lasted until 1 p.m. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The doctors in our department are basically full every day, and the inpatient beds are also very tight. Some children may have to wait for several days before they can be admitted.&quot; Ding Guodong is the deputy chief physician of the Pediatric Respiratory Department. He and his colleagues have been working at an overloaded pace since mid-September. “At this stage, almost 90% of the hospitalized children in the Pediatric Respiratory Department are infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae. , and the proportion of drug-resistant mycoplasmas is very high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae has a diameter of 50-300 nanometers, nearly one thousandth the diameter of a human hair. It is a microorganism between bacteria and viruses.由这种微生物引起的肺炎，是中国5岁及以上儿童最主要的社区获得性肺炎（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指在医院外罹患的感染性肺实质炎症&lt;/span>;），多发于秋冬季。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自九月开学季以来，不止上海，北京、河北、江苏等多地医院都出现肺炎支原体患儿较多的情况，而且呈低龄化特点。据央视新闻10月13日报道，近期全国呼吸道感染性疾病发病率整体上升，肺炎支原体进入多发季，患儿需及时就医、对症用药。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“您前面有246位”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月15日下午四点前，秦楠楠终于给儿子挂上了号，此时北京儿童医院一位副主任医师的号已经排到第556号。候诊过程中，她发现有人已经拿到800多号。好不容易到了采血环节，秦楠楠拿到了第1310号，号码条上还贴心标明“您前面有246位”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京儿童医院呼吸科主任徐保平10月13日接受媒体采访中介绍，9月以来，该院发热咳嗽门诊的日接诊量在3000-4700人次，其中20%的病人支原体抗体检测为阳性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，院方特意在一面墙上贴着提示，“近期就诊患儿数量大幅上升，医院已经调配全院医护人员连续加班支援门诊，竭尽全力保证患儿就医需求，请您理解并耐心等候。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“北京儿童医院专门开了一个发热咳嗽的门诊，做得有点像方舱，另一边普通门诊也是一样人头攒动，当天光是抽血化验，我们就等了近两个半小时。”秦楠楠说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;同样长队的还有上海交通大学医学院附属新华医院。 10月16日傍晚，接近下班时分，该院位于一楼的急诊和二楼的儿内科门诊，挤满了来看病的家长和孩子，找不到空座位的人只能暂时坐在走廊地上休息。这一天上海的气温只有20摄氏度左右，但不少人的汗水早已浸湿了额前的头发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新华医院的儿科全国闻名，外地来看病的人多，还有一些基层医院治不了就转诊来的病患。丁国栋对南方周末记者感叹，最近全院医护人员白天只要有空，都去门急诊支援，夜间都有很多医生留下来加班，看门急诊或者收患儿住院，“病人实在太多了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月12日晚，首都医科大学附属北京儿童医院输液中心，坐满了挂水的孩子和陪护的家长，咳嗽声此起彼伏。南方周末实习生习丽杰/摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月12日晚，首都医科大学附属北京儿童医院输液中心，坐满了挂水的孩子和陪护的家长，咳嗽声此起彼伏。南方周末实习生习丽杰/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“耐药好些年前就有了”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和一般的细菌性肺炎不同，由于肺炎支原体没有细胞壁，普通家庭所熟悉的青霉素和头孢，对肺炎支原体完全无效，原因是这类抗生素都是以细胞壁作为靶点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一般来说，大环内酯类抗菌药物，如阿奇霉素、红霉素，目前是肺炎支原体感染的首选治疗药物。但让许多儿科医生颇感棘手的是，耐药肺炎支原体感染的现象较为普遍，也就是说，用大环内酯类抗菌药物疗效不佳，甚至无效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国家卫健委在2023年2月发布的《儿童肺炎支原体肺炎诊疗指南（2023年版）》也指出，国内对大环内酯类抗菌药物耐药的感染较普遍，可能是导致重症肺炎支原体肺炎等发生的主要原因之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“耐药支原体的感染并不是今年才有的，好些年前就有了。”丁国栋主任告诉南方周末记者，他所在的儿童呼吸科病房主要是收治一些病情较重的患儿，这些患儿大多数做了耐药基因检测，结果显示，几乎90%都是耐药支原体感染。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年发布在《中国病原生物学杂志》的一篇论文指出，近年来耐药株检出率越来越高，一项宁波地区2019-2021年住院儿童肺炎支原体感染研究显示，耐药率超70%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这样一来，临床医生需要根据患者病情和年龄，适当选用二线药物，比如四环素类抗菌药物（多西环素和米诺环素等）或者喹诺酮类的药物抗感染治疗，同时加用糖皮质激素抑制机体过强免疫炎症反应，减缓肺内、肺外的并发症进展和严重程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此外，在当下气温变化较大的季节交替时期，合并感染对免疫力较差的孩子也是巨大的挑战。就在两三天前，丁国栋在病房查看的一个患儿，同时感染了耐药肺炎支原体、流感病毒、腺病毒，呼吸衰竭，情况十分危急，“同时合并感染多种病原体，一般会比单一感染要严重”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;因此，丁国栋提醒，除了保持卫生习惯，做好日常防护之外，现在正逢流感疫苗接种之际，家长可以带小朋友及时接种疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;流行何时休？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和新冠病毒感染类似的是，感染肺炎支原体并痊愈后，体内抗体水平随着时间推移而逐渐下降，存在再度感染的可能性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;秦楠楠的儿子7岁了，这不是他2023年第一次感染肺炎支原体，在这波流行季前已经得过一次，所以家里人没有太过于慌乱，心里对孩子的症状表现比较有数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月12日，北京疾控中心在其官方微信号发文称，肺炎支原体感染可全年发生，北京地区每年8月到12月是肺炎支原体感染的高发期，一般在每年11月左右达到高峰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“肺炎支原体是北京地区急性呼吸道感染的重要病原体。肺炎支原体分为I型和II型共两种亚型，目前北京市主要流行亚型为I型。”该文表示。同时，根据北京疾控中心10月13日发布的疫情周报，手足口病是10月2日-8日那周报告发病数最高的传染病。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;肺炎支原体主要通过飞沫传播，在咳嗽、打喷嚏、流鼻涕时的分泌物中均可携带病原体。但它并非法定传染病，所以地方疾控中心不一定监测。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“疾控中心反馈说，肺炎支原体往年都会有传播，但暂时是没有纳入到监测范围，因为需要监测的都是按照政策需要监测的相关传染病。”10月17日，广州卫生热线工作人员答复南方周末记者称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上海市儿童医院团队2023年1月发表的一项回顾性分析显示，不同地域的气温、湿度等都可能影响肺炎支原体的流行，中国南、北方肺炎支原体感染的高峰不同，北方地区冬季高发，南方地区夏秋季高发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护患者隐私，秦楠楠为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州导盲犬的新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258750]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际盲人节，广州导盲犬学校迎来新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月15日，广东广州，导盲犬训练员在新校舍里看护犬只。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月15日，广东广州，导盲犬训练员在新校舍里看护犬只。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月15日是第40个国际盲人节，这一天，广州导盲犬学校石岗路新校舍开幕，未来或将为更多视障伙伴提供优质的导盲犬服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新校舍面积近400平方米，共有十只导盲犬进驻。设有导盲犬繁殖区、初生导盲幼犬的母婴室、犬舍、美容室、隔离室等导盲犬生活及训练配套，另设导盲犬知识科普的活动空间，更完善的硬件设施进一步有助于学校将国际标准的导盲犬服务进行本土化发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来到新校舍的导盲犬。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来到新校舍的导盲犬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广州导盲犬学校于2020年成立，学校有8只上岗的导盲犬，两只因健康问题提前退休。一只合资格的导盲犬大约需要经过18个月的培训，包括了寄养家庭的寄养训练、由训练员负责的引导训练以及使用者跟导盲犬一起的共同训练三个阶段，成本大约需要25万元，目前都是由爱心企业或爱心人士支持的，而视障人士申请导盲犬则完全免费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月15日，广东广州，一只在寄养家庭的导盲犬。导盲幼犬八星期⼤时要在合适的寄养家庭寄养⼀年左右，学习如何与⼈相处。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254297&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月15日，广东广州，一只在寄养家庭的导盲犬。导盲幼犬八星期大时要在合适的寄养家庭寄养一年左右，学习如何与人相处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，全国导盲犬训练基地仅有5家，分别位于大连、上海、广州、西安和郑州。据中国盲人协会的统计数据显示，中国盲人数量约有1700多万。然而，中国盲人协会原副主席滕伟民2021年在接受媒体采访时曾表示，中国的导盲犬事业刚刚起步，目前全国导盲犬数量仅有200只左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来自导盲犬家族的导盲幼犬Pepper和Bailey正式成为学校第二和第三只母种犬。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254298&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来自导盲犬家族的导盲幼犬Pepper和Bailey正式成为学校第二和第三只母种犬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国际导盲犬导师、广州导盲犬学校校长李苑甄在广州导盲犬学校新校舍开幕活动上表示，来自导盲犬家族的导盲幼犬Pepper和Bailey已经通过了性格评估和各项专科身体检查并获得优秀评价，正式成为学校第二和第三只母种犬，将推动导盲犬血统本土化培育进程，担当起壮大广州导盲犬团队的重任。而从澳大利亚导盲犬学校引入的导盲幼犬Merci当天也满一周岁了，现场所有关心和支持导盲犬服务发展的伙伴，一起为导盲犬Merci送上生日的祝福，并感谢寄养家庭的默默付出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来自澳大利亚导盲犬学校的导盲幼犬Merci满一周岁了。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月15日，广东广州，来自澳大利亚导盲犬学校的导盲幼犬Merci满一周岁了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李苑甄表示，导盲犬可以为人类带来很多服务和贡献。希望公众可以更多理解视障朋友的需要，支持导盲犬训练的需要，接纳在训的导盲犬搭乘公交或者去到商场等更多不同的公众区域进行训练。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;从寄养家庭回到导盲犬学校，导盲犬要经过大约半年的专业训练，毕业后与成功配对的申领者进⾏⼀个⽉的共同训练，通过所有评估才可以为盲⼈服务。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;从寄养家庭回到导盲犬学校，导盲犬要经过大约半年的专业训练，毕业后与成功配对的申领者进行一个月的共同训练，通过所有评估才可以为盲人服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生成式人工智能的价值观，关乎人类未来丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据全国信息安全标准化技术委员会网站，该机构制定的《生成式人工智能服务安全基本要求》面向社会公开征求意见。该文件要求：不使用语料黑名单来源的数据进行训练；单一来源语料内容中含违法不良信息超过5%的，应进入黑名单。并在附录中给出了语料及生成内容共5类31种的主要安全风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于生成式人工智能，国内监管几乎与技术发展同步，反映了对这一技术的高度重视。由国家网信办联合多部门出台的《生成式人工智能服务管理暂行办法》已于7月10日发布，自8月15日起施行，其第17条规定：提供具有舆论属性或者社会动员能力的生成式人工智能服务的，应当按照国家有关规定开展安全评估，并按照《互联网信息服务算法推荐管理规定》履行算法备案和变更、注销备案手续。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，已有多家大模型通过备案，可正式上线面向公众提供服务，包括文心一言（百度）、云雀（抖音）、紫东太初（中科院）等。该办法第4条与第7条，分别对提供和使用生成式人工智能服务及对模型进行数据训练提出了若干要求，涉及价值观与数据来源等多个方面。显然，正在征求意见中的《生成式人工智能服务安全基本要求》呼应并细化了这些规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生成式人工智能有何特别与殊胜之处？想必大家听得耳朵都起茧了。目前，某些生成式人工智能如GPT-4或已跨入通用人工智能（Artificial General Intelligence, AGI）的门槛。而AGI翻成“通用人工智能”其实有一定误导性，因为General Intelligence指的是“一般智力”，让孩子测智商，做排除了特定语言与文化影响的瑞文矩阵（Raven&#39;s Matrices）试题，测出来的就是这个“一般智力”。 AGI意味着，通过人工方法，大模型实现了可与人类心智媲美的“一般智力”。微软科学家们的论文显示：GPT-4 的智能非常接近人类水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个革命性的突破。此类企近或达到AGI的大模型，哪怕长期稳定在一个相当于人类中等智力水平上，它的学习能力也是任何人类都望尘莫及的：可以学习人类创造与积累的所有显性知识，任何以文字、图片、音频与视频呈现的知识它都可以掌握。这意味着大量人类中的知识工作可以被此类生成式人工智能所替代，如翻译与外语口语老师。这会在多大程度上重塑我们的生产与生活方式，是大家都在关切与深思的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，生成式人工智能持什么价值观，是绕不过去的一个问题。我们每个人都有价值观。我们为什么有这样的价值观，既取决于基因与其他先天禀赋，也取决于后天的教养与习染。同理，如果不加任何干预，生成式人工智能的“价值观”就取决于给它喂的语料，更多地给它喂浸渍某种价值观的语料，它就会更多地呈现该种价值观。如果在先给它人为设置了某种特定价值观，那么它就会秉持这种价值观，就会排斥与负面解读与它价值观不一致的语料。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从GPT的早期版本来看，这种特征已经出现。一个经典的例子是：要求它给拜登写一首赞美诗，它欣然同意，且写得很肉麻；要求它给特朗普写一首赞美诗，它断然拒绝，表示要“政治中立”。这背后是开发它的人持有这些价值观，既可以给它在先设置特定价值观，也可以给它喂浸渍特定价值观的语料，从而实现对生成式人工智能的价值观塑造。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，在众目睽睽之下，开发者会尽可能隐藏生成式人工智能的价值观，而采取一种言语上“不得罪任何人、不冒犯任何人”的策略，听起来挑不出什么毛病，这种策略本身也是某种特定价值观的反映。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再畅想一下，现在的生成式人工智能相当于只有大脑、没有可自由移动的有形身体，就像一个灵魂飘荡在赛博空间。如果将来把这一灵魂“注入”仿生机器人甚至行动能力上远超人类身体的智能机器人，那对人类社会的冲击与潜在危害就更大了。人类真的能有效驾驭它们，令它们只造福而不危害人类吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻作家阿西莫夫设定过机器人三定律：机器人不得伤害人类，或坐视人类受到伤害；除非违背第一定律，否则机器人必须服从人类命令；除非违背第一或第二定律，否则机器人必须保护自己。这恐怕只是一厢情愿。未来具备AGI的智能机器人，完全可能被输入或“自行进化”出反人类的价值观，令文明与人类的存续岌岌可危；或者某些持扭曲价值观的个人或组织将具备AGI的智能机器人武器化，消灭别的民族或种族或其所讨厌的群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故而，我们现阶段讨论：生成式人工智能现在能干什么、将来能干什么？应该持什么价值观？对我们生产与生活方式会有多大及哪方面的冲击？人类能否有效驾驭它？会对文明与人类存续本身构成多大挑战？这些问题都是有意义的，也与地球上现在及未来的每一个人利害攸关。这不是杞人忧天，而是未雨绸缪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“加沙没有安全的地方”，巴以厮杀循环何时休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCLMiDOB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCLMiDOB.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是10月15日在加沙边境以色列一侧拍摄的以色列轰炸加沙地带后升起的浓烟。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社伊兰·阿萨亚格摄/基尼图片社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在突发紧急情况，很抱歉要再次推迟原定的采访计划。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月14日晚上，联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处（以下简称“近东救济工程处”）工作人员给南方周末记者发来消息，推迟与通讯主任茱莉亚·图马的采访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在前一天，该机构宣布，“由于以色列增加对加沙地带的袭击”，已将其运营中心和工作人员迁至加沙地带南部，继续支持加沙地带的巴勒斯坦难民。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而据联合国人道主义事务协调办公室（OCHA）10月17日发表声明称，在加沙遇难的人道主义工作人员已增至31人。声明表示，加沙已经连续第六天“全面停电”。加沙医院正处于崩溃的边缘，用于运行备用发电机的燃料储备几乎完全耗尽，这将危及数千名患者的生命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前两天的15日早上，以色列国防军发言人乔纳森·康里库斯在社交媒体上发布一段视频，再次向加沙北部居民发出了警告，令该地区的巴勒斯坦人逃往南部。之前以色列军方也向加沙发出类似的撤离令。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场暴力厮杀，在循环中持续扩大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在以色列连日的反扑行动下，如今的加沙街区已变得面目全非，四处可见残垣断壁，建筑已成废墟一片。惶恐之中，很多加沙居民踏上了逃难之旅。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们每天都在目睹死亡。”当地人赛义德·修艾布在社交媒体写道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，以色列已经对加沙地带实行全面封锁，包括断供水、电和煤气，关闭各通行口岸，并轰炸通往埃及的拉法口岸，导致其基础设施无法正常工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着当地人道主义危机迅速加深，联合国多个机构纷纷发出严厉警告。“近东救济工程处”负责人菲利普·拉扎里表示，加沙正在“迅速变成地狱”，濒临崩溃。他敦促所有各方，“结束这场悲剧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月16日，国家国际发展合作署新闻发言人徐伟表示，中方正向联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处及巴民族权力机构分别提供紧急人道主义援助，用于解决加沙地带食品、医疗、居住等急需。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着巴以新一轮冲突持续，双方死伤人数也在不断上升。截至当地时间10月15日，冲突已造成双方超4100人死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海国际问题研究院外交政策研究所研究员李伟建向南方周末记者表示，以色列的“报复行动”将会持续一段时间。“哈马斯的行动对以色列来说是羞辱，因此以色列需要得到心理平衡。”他认为，以色列会借这次力量，定时清除哈马斯。“事实上他已经在做这件事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“城市巷战”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“近东救济工程处”实习生吴晨雨10月12日收到邮件，上面显示“机构（加沙办公室）有11名工作人员遇难。”尽管已经知道了这个消息，但她仍然感觉到非常难过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晨雨是该机构约旦办公室实习生。她告诉南方周末记者，该机构总部管理5个实地办公室，分别是黎巴嫩、加沙、西岸、叙利亚和约旦。她所在的约旦救济处，暂时还没有受到战火波及，“但是其它实地办公室如加沙，工作人员被通知要撤离。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日晚些时候，哈马斯向以色列特拉维夫及周边地带、中部城市巴特亚姆、南部城市阿什凯隆等地发起火箭弹袭击。外界分析，巴以双方谁都无法具体预测地面战会出现什么情形。哈马斯在以往巴以冲突中已经证明自身能够生存，并拥有“适合巷战的强力武器”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯下属武装派别卡桑旅在14日向以色列军方发布信息称，该组织已经为以军“任何地面军事行动”做好“充分的应对准备”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加沙地带面积约360平方公里，人口密集、房屋林立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，哈马斯声称已修建长达500公里的隧道。不少专家学者分析认为，隧道网络会放大巷战难度，一旦以军和哈马斯在那里展开“城市巷战”，双方都会遭受比本轮巴以冲突头几天更高的伤亡，并对以军队构成致命威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“加沙地带一共有两层，一层是平民的，另一层是哈马斯的。”以色列国防军发言人10月12日表示，这些隧道只是哈马斯的“掩体”，这样他们就可以继续策划跨境行动，并向以色列发射火箭弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少媒体报道披露，这条“迷宫般的巨大地下隧道网络”修建在加沙地下30米深处，入口隐藏在房屋、学校及其他公共建筑的底层，用于哈马斯运送人员、物资，储存弹药等，同时躲避以色列的炮弹和侦察。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去几天，以色列不断对加沙发动空袭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但冲突爆发一周后，哈马斯仍能向以色列发射火箭弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外界认为，这是因为被隐藏在地道里的火箭弹可以随时移动。哈马斯军事领导人之一萨利赫·阿鲁里在本轮巴以冲突爆发前曾说过的话，“哈马斯的防守方案比进攻方案更强有力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不认为以色列士兵有能力袭击这些隧道。”特拉维夫大学中东和非洲研究中心的巴勒斯坦历史学家沙乌勒表示，但以方“会找到把哈马斯熏出来的方法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浙江外国语学院环地中海研究院院长马晓霖认为，以色列不能也不会彻底消灭哈马斯。他说，哈马斯由小到大，不乏以色列纵其壮大以对抗巴解组织主流派的“功劳”。保留加沙地带作为所谓的“哈马斯坦”，可以继续分裂、弱化、内耗巴勒斯坦阵营，而让以色列战略受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;报复与顾忌&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“怎么也想不到，这趟旅途竟是如此。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已经从以色列顺利回到中国的饶萍曼，回想起逃离以色列的场景，彷佛就在昨天。在特拉维夫机场等待15小时后，10月8日上午，饶女士登上了从特拉维夫到埃塞俄比亚的飞机，随后经埃塞俄比亚-曼谷-香港路线回到中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，作为对哈马斯的报复，以军已对加沙地带发动多轮空袭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军10月16日下午公开表示，哈马斯情报局局长在以军的一次暗杀行动中被打死。目前，哈马斯方面对此暂无回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军还在一份声明中称，以军完成了数十万名预备役军人的动员，后勤部门正努力确保地面部队的武器装备供应。并表示战斗所需的装备已经转移到集结区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为“反扑”行动，以色列的行动可称”全方位”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日，以色列国防军宣布将对加沙地带实施更为广泛的地面军事行动计划，扩大对加沙地带的攻势，包括发起“空中、海上和陆地的联合协调攻击”。以色列总理内塔尼亚胡此前威胁称，以军将通过地面攻势“摧毁哈马斯”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军表示，以军士兵正在进行“重大地面行动”的准备工作，以军将对加沙地带实施“广泛的地面进攻计划”来扩大攻势，包括实施“空中、海上和陆地联合协调攻击”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李伟建认为，此时以色列的心态，并非决心要打“胜负”战，而是以色列认为这次受到的损失太大，所以一定要哈马斯付出代价，加倍的要报复。“这种心态之下，以色列一定会在报复方面做得更多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月12日夜间至13日凌晨，以军对加沙地带哈马斯和其他组织的约750个目标进行了空袭。其中包括隧道、军事大院、用作高级成员军事指挥中心的住宅、武器仓库、通讯室以及12栋藏有哈马斯资产的建筑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而就在那前一天的11日，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡在当夜发表了电视讲话，他发誓要“粉碎和摧毁”哈马斯武装分子，并称该组织的每个成员都是“死人”。以军还袭击了哈马斯在加沙地带的两个军事基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其中一处大院中，哈马斯北部师指挥官的总部被摧毁，哈马斯海军部队一座的军事基础设施也遭到袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军表示,自10月7日本轮巴以冲突发生以来,以军已在约旦河西岸逮捕了超过330名巴勒斯坦人，其中包括百余名与哈马斯有关的人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，不少专家学者告诉南方周末记者，以色列的“反扑”行动不会无限扩大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马晓霖判断，被以色列人称为“马蜂窝”和“该死地带”的加沙地带，一旦纳入版图，以色列将再次背负沉重的国际法、道义、舆论、经济、人口结构和安全负担，也将断送已取得重大进展的与阿拉伯国家和解进程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以色列也有很多顾忌的地方。”李伟建分析，如果以色列过度造成人道主义危机，或者是杀害了很多平民，最终也会激发阿拉伯世界的愤怒。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“互相伤害”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;以色列“撤离令”发布后，加沙北部的居民开始纷纷逃往南部，寻找庇护的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社交媒体流传的视频中，乌泱泱的居民将随身携带的物品，塞进皮卡车、汽车。还有一些居民，不得不挤在牲畜拉着的平板车上，艰难地移动着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有一些居民拒绝离开，守在已经倒塌残破的房屋中。面对镜头，他们表示，尽管家园可能充满危险，但离开是“背弃土地和历史”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新一轮冲突爆发后，赛义德·修艾布一家不得不从靠近以色列边境的布雷伊难民营，来到代尔巴拉赫难民营。他在社交媒体上持续记录着。他表示，“加沙没有安全的地方。以色列告诉人们往南方去，但他们仍在南方轰炸。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在以色列的“封锁”之下，世界卫生组织发言人贾萨瑞维奇表示加沙的医院正在耗尽医疗用品和床位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国人道主义事务协调厅10月13日发布消息，称新一轮巴以冲突爆发以来，加沙地带流离失所者人数已超过42万人。联合国机构呼吁筹款向加沙地带和约旦河西岸的巴勒斯坦人提供援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，以色列政府发布了“被哈马斯怪物杀害和焚烧婴儿的可怕照片”。这三张照片发布在内塔尼亚胡办公室的社交媒体账户上。但哈马斯否认了这些指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前已经逃到土耳其的杨然，在巴以冲突新一轮的冲突发生时，就带着行李搬进了以色列所在学校的庇护所。他告诉南方周末记者，那里水电和网络齐全，也比其他庇护所更安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“战场主要集中在南部，我所在的中部除了第一天几千发火箭弹，之后的火箭弹就减少了，甚至第二天公交火车都恢复了。”杨然透露，以色列人因为每年可能都会有一到两次火箭弹袭击，所以“比较习以为常”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以色列经济损失的大小将取决于这些预备役人员离开工作岗位的时间。”以色列希伯来大学经济学教授埃亚尔·温特表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自冲突爆发以来，以色列国防军征召了诸多预备役军人执行任务。这些预备役军人来自各行各业，他们脱离日常经济生产活动，投入战斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;多线作战”的泥潭&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前，以色列已全面“封锁”哈马斯控制的加沙地带，切断水电供应。此举让联合国担忧加沙地带人道主义危机加剧。联合国秘书长古特雷斯敦促各方，允许联合国向加沙地带提供人道主义援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为“两边忙”的美国，巴以冲突升级后“大动作”频频。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国白宫10月16日发布消息称，美国总统拜登将于10月18日访问以色列后，前往约旦首都安曼，与约旦国王阿卜杜拉二世、埃及总统塞西和巴勒斯坦总统、巴勒斯坦民族解放运动（法塔赫）主席阿巴斯会面，商讨冲突相关事宜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日，美国国防部长奥斯汀下令让“艾森豪威尔”号航母打击群前往东地中海。并表示，这是作为“努力遏制战争扩大的一部分”。拜登则公开表示，白宫正迅速“向以提供弹药和导弹拦截系统”等额外安全援助，他敦促美国国会，采取紧急行动批准资金，满足包括以色列在内美国“关键伙伴”的安全需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国派航母舰队为以色列站台，并威慑伊朗和真主党，但不会主动介入加沙战事而在中东四面树敌，更不想再陷中东泥潭。”浙江外国语学院环地中海研究院院长马晓霖说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在此次冲突中，被外界猜测是哈马斯“支持者”的伊朗，则与哈马斯高层进行首次会面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间14日晚，伊朗外交部长阿卜杜拉希扬在卡塔尔首都多哈会见哈马斯领导人哈尼亚。他呼吁，以色列不要发动对加沙地带的地面进攻。并警告说，如果黎巴嫩真主党加入冲突，本轮冲突可能会进一步扩大到中东其他地区，这将使以色列遭受巨大损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场暴力厮杀，究竟何时停止循环？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯政治局成员马尔祖克10月10日表示，哈马斯“已经实现目标”，对讨论停火“类似事情”和“所有政治对话”持开放态度。卡塔尔半岛电视台网站报道称，哈马斯已经俘虏了足够数量的以色列军人，但哈马斯只有在战争结束后，才愿意商讨解决换俘的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，以色列与黎巴嫩边境地区也爆发冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎巴嫩国家通讯社报道，当地时间10月15日，以色列对黎巴嫩南部边境小镇达希拉（Al-Dhahira）发起炮击，造成公共道路交通完全中断。外界普遍认为，如果黎以边境局势进一步升级，以色列可能在北部面临“第二条战线”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马晓霖则表示，这场冲突主战场已转移到加沙地带，无论伤亡多大，战事不会溢出巴以黎叙四国。“加上沙特和伊朗元首为讨论巴以冲突而首次通话，这表明双方曾主导的地区身份政治博弈不会反复，巴勒斯坦问题或被继续边缘化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来，以色列还是会考虑到未来的发展。”李伟建分析，以色列要和中东国家和阿拉伯国家打交道，也希望能够维护好已经好不容易打开的局面，改善同其他国家关系的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外交部发言人毛宁呼吁，当务之急应是推动局势降温、停火止暴、保护平民，避免人道主义灾难。大国在处理国际地区热点问题时，应当坚持客观公正，保持冷静克制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，饶萍曼、杨然均为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年前三季度中国GDP同比增长5.2%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Data released by the National Bureau of Statistics on the 18th showed that preliminary calculations showed that China’s gross domestic product (GDP) in the first three quarters ) 91.3027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.2% at constant prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at quarters, GDP grew by 4.5% year-on-year in the first quarter, 6.3% in the second quarter, and 4.9% in the third quarter. From a quarter-on-quarter perspective, GDP grew by 1.3% in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sheng Laiyun, deputy director of the National Bureau of Statistics, said at a press conference of the State Council Information Office that day that in the first three quarters, faced with the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, various regions and departments Resolutely implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, focus on expanding domestic demand, boost confidence, and prevent risks, and the national economy continues to recover and improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall agricultural production situation is good, the recovery of industrial production is accelerating, and the service industry continues to recover rapidly. In the first three quarters, the added value of agriculture (planting industry) increased by 3.6% year-on-year; the added value of the national industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 4% year-on-year, 0.2 percentage points faster than the first half of the year; the added value of the service industry increased by 6% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market sales tend to be active, the scale of fixed asset investment continues to expand, and the import and export of goods are generally stable. In the first three quarters, the total retail sales of consumer goods reached 34,210.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.8%. National fixed asset investment (excluding rural households) increased by 3.1% year-on-year; excluding the impact of price factors, it increased by 6% year-on-year. The total import and export of goods was 30.8021 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumer prices rose moderately, the employment situation was generally stable, and residents&#39; income grew steadily. In the first three quarters, the national consumer price index (CPI) rose by 0.4% year-on-year, and the national average urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.3%. The per capita disposable income of residents across the country was 29,398 yuan, a nominal increase of 6.3% year-on-year; after deducting price factors, the real growth was 5.9%, 0.1 percentage point faster than the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Overall, the national economy has continued to recover in the first three quarters, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced, laying a solid foundation for achieving the full-year development goals. However, it must also be noted that the external environment has become more The situation is complex and severe, domestic demand is still insufficient, and the foundation for economic recovery still needs to be consolidated.&quot; Sheng Laiyun said that in the next stage, we must do a good job in implementing the policies that have been introduced to achieve effective results, and continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous improvement of endogenous power, and the continuous improvement of social It is expected to continue to improve, risks and hidden dangers will continue to be resolved, and efforts will be made to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“江浙沪独生女”人设走红，这届年轻人在羡慕什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjB k6gukrSbaP. png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021999449192&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data -filename=&quot;The character of &quot;The Only Child in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, what are the young people of this generation envious of.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot; width= &quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot;>;The character of &quot;The Only Girl in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, and young people in this generation are envious What to admire.mp3 &lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;In the imagination of netizens, the only daughter of a wealthy middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys family resources and pampering, and her parents are open-minded enough. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture generated by &quot;AI Huitu&quot;/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, and meeting social people who come from south to north, Hello Southern Weekend listeners, welcome to Southern Weekly’s podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; became popular on the Internet, becoming the most enviable female character template after &quot;Single Aunt&quot; and &quot;Runaway Wanyu&quot;. In the imagination of netizens, an only daughter born in a well-off middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys the resources and love of her family. Her parents are open-minded enough, so she has the confidence to pursue career development and the capital to go home and settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, is this really the only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai? What will be the other side of returning under the wings of your parents and enjoying the protection of your family? What expectations do the two labels &quot;rich&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; carry for contemporary young people? Behind the changes in the female template, how are our attitudes towards life and work changing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this podcast, we invite two guests who are both &quot;only children from Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; to discuss the above issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;This issue’s guests&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Sun Lin (left), lecturer at the Chinese Studies Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong and PhD in Anthropology, and Ge Shurun ​​(right), a doctoral candidate at the School of Journalism, Renmin University of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>; Listening tips: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►03:34 &amp;nbsp;“Someone will tell me the truth” is the very attractive part of this label&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►06:22 &amp;nbsp;In the process of growing up, the only daughter born in the 1980s in Shanghai believed in trying things out&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►08:48 &amp;nbsp;The &quot;Pyramid of Filial Piety&quot; emphasizes cost-effectiveness&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►11:51 &amp;nbsp;Interview with the elderly in Shanghai, almost no one expects their children to support them in old age&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►15:09 &amp;nbsp;Returning to the family character and independent character co-exist&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 20:25 &amp;nbsp;Changes in the external environment have made young people more in need of family to resist risks&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►25:46 &amp;nbsp;The labels of &quot;Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; hide some social prejudices&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;►29:06 &amp;nbsp;In addition to money, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; also emphasizes the emotional support of the family&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►31:02 &amp;nbsp;Different female templates are pursued by different people. Or is it a conflict between ideals and reality&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►35:22 &amp;nbsp;The label also ignores the obligations and responsibilities that an only child will face&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►39:29 &amp;nbsp;Enlightened parents will also Giving hints on &quot;should you come back and take the civil service exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editors: Wang Yixuan, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operators: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>