<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[凤凰传奇粉丝逆龄化？00后为何迷上父母辈偶像]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大同校园欺凌事件惊骇舆论场：未成年人施暴为何没有下限？ 家长如何应对和预防？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257823]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The bullying incident of minors at Dacheng Bilingual School in Datong, Shanxi shocked the country. While everyone was shocked, they were also asking: Are some children born evil? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, only if we go deep into the world of minors can we correctly and deeply understand the origin of such events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, why do seemingly weak and powerless children bully their peers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, bullying has little to do with physical strength. Bullying is essentially a mentality and method. The purpose is to construct and establish a domination-obedience power relationship between the perpetrator and the victim. The mental pleasure that bullying brings to the perpetrator is a pleasure of dominance. There is no evidence that physically weak people have a weaker desire to conquer and dominate than physically strong people. On the contrary, in some situations, physically weak people have more incentives to pursue a sense of conquest and dominate others in order to make themselves appear stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weak physical strength is only relative, there is always someone weaker than him or her. Moreover, bullying by physically weak people often has a characteristic of grouping together. In the face of organized bullying, it makes no sense even if the person being bullied is physically stronger. For these people, the pleasure of subduing a physically strong person and crawling at their feet is unparalleled. Therefore, when a group of physically weak people get together and bully others in an organized manner, they often leave videos to record their so-called achievements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should also be noted that violence by minors has nothing to do with gender. When the Datong incident caused unprecedented concern, Cai Yaqi, a real-name certified criminal law teacher, received a submission: a female classmate was bullied by other female classmates in the dormitory, and also had forced sex, and the perpetrator also took a video . Therefore, in cases of bullying of minors or even sexual bullying, do not rely on physical strength and gender. This will bias the understanding of the nature and causes of bullying, and lead to wrong prevention and response methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, bullying is a tool used to pursue a relationship of conquest and dominance. A newborn calf may not be inferior to a tiger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adults may often have a limit to bullying due to the need for &quot;face&quot;, moral sense or &quot;fighting without breaking up&quot;; minors, due to their immature minds, do not have so many scruples. Once bullying is committed, There is often no lower limit, enough to frighten adults and make people feel like some children are born devils. The other side of &quot;newborn calves are not afraid of tigers&quot; is not so beautiful. The transition of minors from bullying to sexual bullying and sexual violence is a reflection of this internal logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any civilized society is to some extent based on sexual taboos and sexual shame. Even if modern society has broken some and relaxed some, it is difficult to change this fact. Taking the things that are most private and shameful to you, forcing you and humiliating you in public can break you mentally. The abuser has completed your mental discipline and achieved spiritual control over you. You become mentally a slave to your abuser. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two points constitute the occurrence of minor bullying and even sexual bullying. On this basis, we can have some coping and prevention methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, specifically regarding the Datong campus incident, everyone noticed that the incident occurred in the school dormitory. It is very problematic for such a young child to live in school away from his parents. Of course, as the number of school closures decreases, the distribution of children will become increasingly sparse, resulting in an average distance for each child to go to school. At some stage, they may have to live on campus to save time commuting every day. However, if the child only goes to primary school, it is better to go to school nearby to ensure that the child goes home every day. Parents can also understand the child&#39;s situation and mental state at school, and any problems can be detected early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, you must understand that the world of children is not innocent. Humans are social animals. In fixed interactions with two or more people in a stable environment with many people, there will inevitably be implicit or explicit hierarchical relationships, dominance and being dominated, or influencing and being influenced. relation. This cannot be eliminated. As long as it is based on the personality charm of the leader and the voluntary obedience of the followers, it is basically harmless. However, parents should pay attention to whether such relationships involve coercion and violence, and whether there is a qualitative change into a dominance-obedience relationship or a violence-victimization relationship. If such signs are discovered, they must intervene in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether your child is a perpetrator or a victim, you should intervene and stop it. This is the approach of a decent and responsible parent. Never think that your child is the abuser and take advantage, then refuse to intervene, and then shirk responsibility and be irresponsible when other parents discover the problem. Children&#39;s behavior is likely to be shaped by the words and deeds of such parents and their subtle influence, which magnifies a family&#39;s educational failure into harm to other people and society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, the sex education our children need most urgently is anti-coercion, anti-rape, anti-sexual assault, and anti-obscenity education. This should be given to children before they enter kindergarten and primary school. Repeated reminders and education should help children establish the awareness that: my body is private and sacred and cannot be touched by just anyone; if someone tries to touch their body, they should stop and report it to their teachers and parents; I My personality and dignity cannot be insulted. I have the courage to defend my body, rights, personality and dignity, and dare to say no to all bullying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[朝鲜决定驱逐非法入境朝鲜的美国士兵]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257784]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/77abcf1d4d861baae180de4765d5b010.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; height=&quot;417&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/27/77abcf1d4d861baae180de4765d5b010.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252490&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;US soldiers who illegally entered North Korea Travis King data map&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CCTV News reported on September 27 that the Korean Central News Agency reported on the 27th that in response to the station incident that occurred in the Panmunjom Joint Security Area on July 18 The investigation into the illegal intrusion of Private Travis Kim of the South Korean U.S. Army into North Korea has been concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/f8fb158a6b64d55f388ee18ea338fcb7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/f8fb158a6b64d55f388ee18ea338fcb7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Panmunjom Joint Security Area&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reports stated that after investigation by relevant North Korean authorities, Telavi King confessed that he was disgusted with the inhuman abuse and racial discrimination within the US military, and was extremely disappointed with the unequal American society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reportedly, the relevant departments of North Korea decided to expel Travis Kim, an American soldier who illegally entered North Korea, in accordance with North Korean laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[求职大学生为拿offer将学历改为高中：民营雇主为何拒绝“大材小用”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257746]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a job search news has attracted attention. According to &quot;Shangguan News&quot;, a newly graduated post-2000 college student said that he started looking for a job in early July, but he has never found a suitable job. Most of the jobs I wanted to take required work experience, and the hundreds of resumes I submitted came to nothing. He said that the requirements for the position are not high and the intensity is not high, and a monthly salary of 3,000 is acceptable. For this reason, he even thought about working in a factory as a general worker, but he could not find even this kind of job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The college student involved admitted that this result made him feel &quot;a little embarrassed&quot;: after studying for so many years, he could not even find a job. In anger, he changed the highest education level on his resume to high school. Unexpectedly, when he opened the recruitment software the next day, there were dozens of greeting messages from HR. This news resonated with many netizens. Some netizens expressed their own opinions in their replies, saying that finding a job with a high school degree would make it easier to get a front-desk and promotion-type personnel/administrative job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the situation of the person involved, he applied for these positions with a &quot;downward compatibility&quot; mentality. He is still looking for a job after graduating in early July, which means that he missed the autumn recruitment and spring recruitment in the past year, and had to turn to social recruitment, hoping to find a way out. However, it has been difficult for me to get out of the &quot;undergraduate position&quot; that I wanted. &quot;Hundreds of resumes have gone to waste&quot;, so I can only be &quot;downward compatible&quot;, &quot;even if I am a general worker in a factory, I can do it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, these more &quot;downward&quot; employers are unwilling to recruit candidates with undergraduate degrees. The college student in question was &quot;downward compatible&quot; with these positions with the mentality of &quot;acceptable&quot;, but the employer did not favor this undergraduate with a higher academic qualification. An HR person even expressed his own opinion in the Weibo comment area of ​​this news, saying that the unit he works for must first screen out the highly educated undergraduates who come to apply for jobs, and give priority to applicants whose highest education is high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The college student in question applied for positions with “low requirements and low intensity” with a bachelor’s degree, but was repeatedly rejected. However, when he changed his highest degree to high school, he gained a lot of attention from HR. The question reflected in this news about &quot;voluntarily changing applicants with lower academic qualifications&quot; is why employers reject applicants with higher academic qualifications and better conditions on the grounds of &quot;overqualification&quot;. In fact, the employer&#39;s decision-making exactly reflects the laws of the market economy and does not violate the general principles of the job market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The job market itself is part of the market economy and follows the market mechanism. Employers pay wages to employees in exchange for their work contributions. The two follow the principle of voluntary reciprocal exchange. Both employers and employees must consider the cost-benefit ratio. For employers, the principle of recruiting employees is to &quot;find the most suitable person&quot; rather than &quot;finding the best person&quot;; for employees, the principle of finding a job is also to &quot;find the most suitable job&quot; rather than &quot;finding the best person&quot;. good job&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in this news, the employer obviously does not think that the college student in question is the &quot;most suitable person&quot;, because the applicants from the high school with the highest education are qualified for the job, and the employer pays to hire them Comply with market transaction principles. Private enterprises pay more attention to &quot;cost-effectiveness&quot; and &quot;fitness&quot; when recruiting people. There is no way to &quot;win by relying on more&quot; based on academic qualifications alone. If recruiting applicants with undergraduate degrees, the employer will have to worry about other risks, such as higher salary requirements, whether the applicant will &quot;leave after a short period of time,&quot; and whether he or she will obey the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employer’s concerns are not unnecessary, because they are also in line with the thoughts of undergraduate candidates. It can be seen from the news that the college students involved chose to apply for these &quot;low-demand, low-intensity&quot; jobs with a &quot;downward compatibility&quot; mentality: This job is not the best, nor is it the most suitable. Yes, it’s just the jobs that can be found at the moment. It is a rational choice for employers to reject &quot;overqualification and underutilization&quot; based on their own interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, &quot;backwards compatibility&quot; of candidates is not impossible. In addition to &quot;taking the initiative to apply for jobs with lower academic qualifications&quot;, it is also common to see in society that &quot;PhDs in nuclear physics from Peking University are admitted to the urban management establishment&quot;, &quot;Graduates from prestigious schools go to the street office&quot;, &quot;Masters and PhDs from prestigious universities gather for primary school teacher positions&quot;, etc. &quot;Real cases often trigger heated discussions in the public opinion field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the &quot;sinking positions&quot; in the front desk and promotion in the news, the positions such as &quot;urban management establishment&quot; and &quot;street office&quot; can hardly be called senior positions, but these positions have successfully attracted highly educated talents. One thing the positions have in common is that they are all in the public sector. The public sector does not need to consider the problem of &quot;a small temple cannot accommodate a big Buddha&quot; like the private sector. This is also confirmed by the news about public examinations that appear frequently in the public opinion field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, similar news also reminds that universities, parents and college students themselves should rethink the nature of higher education, avoid excessive investment that leads to negative output, and effectively improve their own position in the job market. Be competitive and find the job that suits you best. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[8月全国彩票销售增长53.6%，前八月增长51.6%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257760]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/3043A223FCE084B67B9B9B585B9FCD1AA.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 862 &quot;height =&quot; 487 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/2 3/09/27/3043A223FCE084B67B9B585B9FCD1AA. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252359&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1. National lottery sales&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August, a total of 52.957 billion yuan of lottery tickets were sold nationwide[1], an increase of 18.481 billion yuan year-on-year. An increase of 53.6%. Among them, the sales of welfare lottery institutions were 18.643 billion yuan, an increase of 5.972 billion yuan or 47.1% year-on-year; the sales of sports lottery institutions were 34.314 billion yuan, an increase of 12.509 billion yuan or 57.4% year-on-year. Mainly affected by factors such as the increase in major events and the launch of new instant lottery tickets, lottery sales grew faster than the same period last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cumulatively, from January to August, a total of 375.761 billion yuan of lottery tickets were sold nationwide, an increase of 127.852 billion yuan or 51.6% year-on-year. Among them, the sales of welfare lottery institutions were 126.325 billion yuan, an increase of 26.413 billion yuan or 26.4% year-on-year; the sales of sports lottery institutions were 249.436 billion yuan, an increase of 101.439 billion yuan or 68.5% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7c33315724d96bd672f351d2244cd4ef.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;588&quot; height= &quot;332&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7c33315724d96bd672f351d2244cd4ef.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252358&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;二, Lottery sales by type&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August, Lotto digital lottery sales were 15.303 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 14.8%; guess-type lottery sales were 22.153 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 61.2%; instant lottery sales were 120.39 billion, a year-on-year increase of 150.7%; Keno lottery sales were 3.462 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 32.8%. In August, the sales volume of Lotto digital, guessing, instant, and Keno lottery tickets accounted for 28.9%, 41.8%, 22.7%, and 6.6% of the total lottery sales respectively. The sales of video lottery tickets were 180,000 yuan, an increase of 16% year-on-year. Ten thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cumulatively from January to August, the sales of Lotto digital lottery tickets were 114.887 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 11.896 billion yuan, an increase of 11.6%; the sales of guess-type lottery tickets were 163.006 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 80.389 billion yuan, an increase of 97.3% ; Instant lottery sales were 74.296 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 31.228 billion yuan, an increase of 72.5%; Keno lottery sales were 23.571 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 4.338 billion yuan, an increase of 22.6%. From January to August, the sales volume of Lotto digital, guessing, instant and Keno lottery tickets accounted for 30.57%, 43.38%, 19.77% and 6.28% of the total lottery sales respectively. Video lottery sales amounted to 1 million yuan, an increase of 470,000 yuan year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/31a2526cb14942a59e118161f0dd3046.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;570&quot; height= &quot;323&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/31a2526cb14942a59e118161f0dd3046.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3. Points Regional lottery sales&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August, compared with the same period last year, lottery sales in all provinces across the country increased. Among them, Guangdong, Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shandong increased significantly, with a year-on-year increase of 1.991 billion yuan respectively. , 1.742 billion yuan, 1.600 billion yuan and 1.280 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cumulatively from January to August, compared with the same period last year, lottery sales in all provinces across the country increased. Among them, Jiangsu, Guangdong, Zhejiang and Shandong increased significantly, with a year-on-year increase of 12.052 billion yuan respectively. , 11.690 billion yuan, 10.689 billion yuan and 9.278 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lottery agencies at all levels must closely track and analyze new situations and new issues, effectively strengthen lottery issuance and sales, and ensure the smooth operation of the market. Financial departments at all levels should further strengthen lottery supervision, actively create a good external environment, maintain market order, and promote the sustainable and healthy development of the lottery industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remarks: [1] Lotto digital lottery sales are calculated according to the end of the sales period; guess-type lottery traditional football games and regional networked single-field guessing games are counted according to the end of the sales period. Guess-type lotteries nationwide The online single-game guessing game counts sales according to the lottery draw time of the betting content; the instant lottery counts the sales according to the sales time; the video lottery counts the sales according to the sales time; the Keno type lottery counts the sales according to the end of the sales period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又一个3:0！杭州亚运会乒乓男团中国队完胜韩国队，获该项目八连冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Chuqin defeated the South Korean team 3-1 Player Lin Zhongxun got a good start for the Chinese team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7b3fb8f73d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7b3fb8f73d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Chuqin defeated South Korean team player Lin Jongxun 3-1, giving the Chinese team a good start. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the men&#39;s team final of table tennis at the Hangzhou Asian Games on September 26, 2023, the Chinese team featuring Wang Chuqin, Fan Zhendong, and Ma Long defeated the South Korean team Won the championship and won the eighth consecutive championship in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first set of the final, Wang Chuqin played against Lin Zhongxun. After winning the first game 11-9, Wang Chuqin lost one game 8-11. The game was very close, and there were many ties in the game. In the third game, Wang Chuqin took the initiative and easily won 11-5. In the fourth game, Wang Chuqin won the game 12-10 after saving a game point, scoring the first point for the Chinese team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Chuqin was in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/3a70d1ccfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/3a70d1ccfb.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252494&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Chuqin was in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Fan Zhendong competed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/bc41affede.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/bc41affede.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, China Team player Fan Zhendong during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Zhendong competed with Ahn Jae-hyun in the second set. After easily winning the first set 11-6, Fan Zhendong fluctuated in the second set and saved three consecutive game points in a passive situation. , and then scored two more points in one go, winning the second game 12-10. The game became one-sided. Fan Zhendong easily won the third game 11-3, and the Chinese team led 2-0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Fan Zhendong was in the game. He defeated South Korean team player Ahn Jae-hyun 3-0.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c4c8ea7763.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/c4c8ea7763.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252496&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023 On the same day, Chinese team player Fan Zhendong was in the game. He defeated South Korea&#39;s An Jae Hyun 3-0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the third set, Malone played steadily. Except for the close score in the second set, he easily defeated Park Kang-hyun 3-0. The Chinese table tennis team achieved eight consecutive Asian Games men&#39;s team titles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Ma Long was in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/3fb88b6c6b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/3fb88b6c6b.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Ma Long competed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that Malone, who has been playing for the national team since 2002, only signed up for the team competition in this Asian Games. Therefore, this men&#39;s team final is also Ma Long&#39;s last game at the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Ma Long defeated South Korean team player Park Kang-hyun 3-0 to seal the victory.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ea3efc5fca.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/27/ea3efc5fca.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Chinese team player Malone defeated South Korea&#39;s Park Kang-hyun 3-0 to seal the victory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, the Chinese table tennis men&#39;s team athletes took a group photo after the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/020a1dcd72.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/020a1dcd72.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023 , Chinese table tennis men&#39;s team athletes took a group photo after the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿童友好公园，一米高度看世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257792]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Guangzhou in September, the highest temperature is still close to 39°C, and the pool in the park has become the most lively place. At the Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, children walked through marine life and played under dolphins and octopuses. However, the colorful colors at the bottom of the pool do not represent the colorful underwater world, but the oil spill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few months ago, the pool was still monotonous marble white. After taking an environmental protection class, a dozen children painted the bottom of the pool colorfully with paint, implying that after an oil spill, under the reflection of light, What the ocean looks like. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FoWhvc8K5DwpYMePAmES4M92IuwIUMBKZfTh5TqE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FoWhvc8K5DwpYMePAmES4M92IuwIUMBKZfTh5TqE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, the colorful paddling pool is painted for children to symbolize the luster of the ocean after an oil spill. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more and more parks tailored for children and allowing children to participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou has the largest child-friendly park system in the country, including 1 municipal-level + 12 district-level children&#39;s parks. In 2023, &quot;Promoting the continuation of the municipal children&#39;s park project&quot; was included in the work report of the Guangzhou Municipal Government for the first time. Since 2001, Shenzhen has released two rounds of ten-year plans for children&#39;s development, incorporating child-friendly city construction into the top-level design for the first time. Currently, Luohu and Pingshan Children&#39;s Parks have been opened, and Longgang Children&#39;s Park will also be completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being friendly to children means being friendly to the future of the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Promoting the Construction of Child-Friendly Cities&quot; by 23 departments including the National Development and Reform Commission, child-friendliness refers to providing appropriate conditions, environment and services for the growth and development of children, and effectively protecting children&#39;s right to survival and development. rights, rights to protection and rights to participate. Guangdong and Shenzhen were selected into the first batch of national child-friendly cities. In March 2023, 23 departments including the Guangdong Provincial Development and Reform Commission issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for the Construction of Child-Friendly Cities in Guangdong Province&quot; to promote the construction of child-friendly parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we invite an environmental engineer to give a class, we will leave after reading the slides in the classroom. In the park, we let the children think about what humans have gained from the ocean and what they have given.&quot; Children in Guangzhou Yu Mingjie, deputy director of the park, told Southern Weekend reporters that the children understood that humans have also caused damage in the process of obtaining materials from the ocean. Even after the paddling pool was painted colorful, some children thought, &quot;Should we destroy or create?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a8jsOp74iGWTKdgd0Gc5eE5xTaQYkmWNp90suhEi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a8jsOp74iGWTKdgd0Gc5eE5xTaQYkmWNp90suhEi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the water in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;See the world from a height of one meter&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What do children love to do in the park? Play with water and sand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Weikai, a senior engineer at the Guangzhou Urban Planning, Survey and Design Institute, and others once calculated the regional heat of Guangzhou Children’s Park. From 9 a.m. to 5 p.m., the pool and sandy areas are the most densely populated with children. The place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Water and sand are ever-changing and full of infinite creativity. In the eyes of children, they are &quot;magical toys&quot; given by nature. Studies have shown that playing with water and sand can not only stimulate touch, vision and physical perception, but also cultivate children&#39;s curiosity and imagination and promote brain development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c3gHbcJUo1ASiicWsf8kRmMG9Tb1xEImoiIjIC0f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c3gHbcJUo1ASiicWsf8kRmMG9Tb1xEImoiIjIC0f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the sand in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When designing children&#39;s parks, they pay attention to the needs of children to play with water and sand. Shenzhen local standard &quot;Children&#39;s Park (Park) Design Specifications&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Shenzhen Design Specifications&quot;) requires that even small parks with a minimum area of ​​2 hectares should have sandy areas. When the park area reaches more than 10 hectares, a paddling pool can be installed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2gl3VcyI6uFvyqjyunpGcxZR7jQaPiQxU13H9Tfv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2gl3VcyI6uFvyqjyunpGcxZR7jQaPiQxU13H9Tfv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the water in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the sandpit and pool being exclusive for children, the plant brands in the children&#39;s park are also different. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The introduction of lychee trees in parks usually includes the Latin name, family, genus, species, character, etc., but in Shenzhen Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, the title of the explanation board is: &quot;How many lychees should you eat in a day?&quot; &quot;Pieces?&quot; It reminded many children in Guangdong of their experience of being scolded by adults for eating less lychees because of &quot;heat&quot; (a Guangdong term used to mean &quot;getting angry&quot;). Adults are also easily attracted, &quot;a bit like the headlines of public accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nan Fangfang, head of the direction ecology team, introduced that these interpretive signs are designed according to the &quot;3-30-3&quot; rule: 3 seconds for children to become interested; 30 seconds to have a simple understanding of things; scan 2D code to gain more in-depth and detailed knowledge in 3 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Explanatory signs in other scenic spots are only maintained once every 3-5 years. Pingshan Children&#39;s Park wears out much faster and needs to be updated every year. He is very happy, &quot;There are many people using the explanation, which is better than being deserted.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to sum up the design idea of ​​the children&#39;s park in one sentence, it would be &quot;seeing the world from a height of one meter&quot;. When adults walk into the children&#39;s park, they feel as if they have entered the &quot;Land of Dwarves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adults have to bend down to see the maps and guidance signs clearly; soft rubber mats are laid in each play area, and rounded corners are designed in places that are prone to bumping. The &quot;Shenzhen Design Code&quot; also requires that: trash cans can be shaped like lively cartoons, and the height of the input port should not exceed 80 centimeters; the operating height of children&#39;s drinking fountains should not exceed 70 centimeters; both men&#39;s and women&#39;s toilets in public toilets should be equipped with children&#39;s toilets and men&#39;s toilets The proportion of inner low-level urinals in the total urinals should not be less than 50%, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/x1CfgQNQR5H1mBnOx4SuBDTq0J9nklGOU1EHjjWy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;1692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/x1CfgQNQR5H1mBnOx4SuBDTq0J9nklGOU1EHjjWy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Adults have to bend down to see the signs in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, the open lawn surrounded by the big banyan tree is the Guangzhou Park The largest inner area. Children can set up tents, run, jump and enjoy the sunshine without any scruples, but cannot play football - refer to the &quot;Guangzhou Park Lawn Opening Management Guidelines (Draft for Comments)&quot;. Failure to play football on the open lawn of the park may seriously damage the lawn vegetation. activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lEjU7wrVqVwxVjMNANvCf94M41eek3fOG3vdSdrm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lEjU7wrVqVwxVjMNANvCf94M41eek3fOG3vdSdrm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The large lawn in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The park has also been thinking of solutions and plans to open a dedicated sports area to build There are football fields, basketball courts, tennis courts and a model car park for children to have more fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The needs of parents should also be considered. Children are enjoying themselves in the park, and parents cannot just sit there and watch their phones overheat and shut down under the scorching sun. Moreover, many parents are elderly. Yu Mingjie has also noticed this. He is making barrier-free renovations in the park and adding some new rest areas so that &quot;parents can drink tea and coffee indoors while seeing their children.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mBlzN0nt4MP4f0zR3uwXt0LoHqfjmcz5VHSF4jSH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mBlzN0nt4MP4f0zR3uwXt0LoHqfjmcz5VHSF4jSH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252539&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A parent is giving water to his child in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Experience danger safely&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Children are lively and active. Compared with ordinary parks, children&#39;s parks have greater pressure on safety. A UNICEF survey of 35,000 children in 65 countries found that a quarter of children would feel unsafe in parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yafei works as an operations manager in Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, and has to &quot;fight&quot; with children climbing trees multiple times every day - there is a crooked tree next to the swing, which is the children&#39;s favorite. Preventing children from climbing trees has even become a key task for the park management staff. &quot;We will try to coax them a little at the beginning, and then we will be more stern. If it doesn&#39;t work, we will contact the parents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each project in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park is equipped with staff. The number is slightly larger than that of other parks, with 60-70 people on duty every day. The park is also equipped with more than 40 emergency devices. Children can talk to the park alarm center by pressing a button. &quot;It is normal for children to get lost and look for their mother, 20 to 30 times a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To ensure safety, age or height restrictions on facilities are the most common methods. In Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, stainless steel slides and swings are suitable for those aged 4 and above, while more complex balance beams and climbing nets require those aged 6 and above 12 years old respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the regulations, it cannot stop children under age. In a net-climbing project, if you are not tall enough, it will be difficult to climb up to the last climbing point. There are often children who are half-climbed and their hands and feet are weak and dare not continue, so they have to be carried down by their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ziFDpqTKiUXj6dva8kdTe4msE9ocnzFWrypOyi3w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ziFDpqTKiUXj6dva8kdTe4msE9ocnzFWrypOyi3w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The net-climbing slide in Pingshan Children&#39;s Park is difficult for children with insufficient physical strength and height to climb up. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children&#39;s parks will also receive contradictory complaints from parents. On the one hand, they want their children to play More facilities mean more experiences; on the other hand, there are worries about safety. This contradiction is also a question that Liu Yuelai, associate professor at the School of Architecture and Urban Planning of Tongji University, has been thinking about - should we just encircle the railings and make them the safest? He feels that how children overcome dangers and difficulties also needs to be taken into consideration. Child-friendliness is more important than caring for and taking responsibility for children, creating conditions for children to experience, practice and grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, adults often prevent children from stepping into puddles. If all puddles are eliminated, children will be bored. If some difficulties are designed, children can realize that they can overcome them, which is &quot;more important than adults eliminating all dangers.&quot; While ensuring safety, the water depth, slope, etc. comply with national regulations, which can enrich the park&#39;s landforms and provide more fun for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the research, Nan Yishan also found that when it comes to snakes, children and parents are not curious, but afraid: there are no snakes in the park, right?因此，他们设计的解说词开头就是童声说：“蛇和人相互的误解特别深，人见到蛇，紧张、惧怕，蛇见到人，惊恐、张皇”，进而将科普重点放在如何与蛇相处、被蛇咬怎么办。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;让&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;儿童参与公园建造&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鲜有人知道，南越王博物院是广州市儿童公园的旧址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州市儿童公园始建于1958年，1995年扩建时发掘出南越王文物，迁到不远处的人民南路与一德路交界处，后广州白云机场迁建，2014年，又搬到了老白云机场地块。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这段“公园简史”给了艺术家陈洲灵感。他曾在广州美术学院任教，之后专注于儿童自然教育。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州市儿童公园有“艺术进公园”策划项目，目的不是办成网红展，而是呈现小朋友们制作艺术品的初心、理念、过程和成果。陈洲就带着孩子们参观了南越王宫，畅想两千多年前王宫的样子，让孩子们自己动手，打造心中的王国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孩子们发现南越王宫的通道像地下迷宫，就模仿迷宫用环保材料设计通道，有的只有孩子才可以钻进去。南越王是谁，长什么样？他们觉得是鸭子、是鸟，就在自己做的宫殿上画上了这些图案，有的纹络甚至有了古代房屋瓦当的风格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多个快递箱串联，孩子们搭建了一个连接儿童公园历史和现在的时空迷宫——“生长的宫殿”。宫殿展出后，陈洲经常收到微信好友申请，后来他发现，有个小朋友把他的微信二维码贴到了宫殿上，“是孩子的恶作剧，也有家长加上我，告诉我孩子是真的很喜欢这个作品”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EzScAI2eA58ShksvdvX8CIxhUaCXBnHPTHgSs73O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EzScAI2eA58ShksvdvX8CIxhUaCXBnHPTHgSs73O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;参观了南越王宫后，孩子们自己设计了“生长的宫殿”。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿童艺术展引来不少专业艺术家参观，有的还希望明年参与其中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国《儿童权利公约》将儿童权利分为三类，其中之一就是参与权，但根据前述联合国儿童基金会的调查，只有26%的儿童表示当地政府听到了他们的意见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿童公园也有着相似的困境。儿童公园的刻板印象就是卡通和多彩，哪怕卫生间都是五颜六色。刘悦来有着不同意见，有时候到处都是彩色，对孩子反而是一种刺激。色彩是重要的，但重要的是自然界的颜色，“比如观察蝴蝶、向日葵颜色怎么变化，沉浸其中，孩子会对自然更友好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在儿童公园的建设中，儿童是有发言权的，甚至可以成为主角。刘悦来发现，四年级以上的小朋友自我主张和表达的意愿已经非常强烈，且拥有比较强的空间造型能力。在参与儿童公园建造的过程中，儿童从消费者变成了生产者。 “这种有秩序和内生动力的自组织也是公民教育重要的实验”。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为儿童公园的用户，孩子们怎么玩游戏设施，决定了设施的功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坪山儿童公园的空中网床原本为了小朋友和家长坐着休闲，但小朋友更喜欢把它当作蹦床。起初，公园管理人员劝导大家不要蹦跳，但奈何想蹦跳的人多。咨询设备厂商后，在控制小朋友的年龄和数量、保证安全的前提下，允许在上面适度蹦跳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a4U7H4gQyVegtGpOVo45wGZUctJ1cmroXTCSVHJk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a4U7H4gQyVegtGpOVo45wGZUctJ1cmroXTCSVHJk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;广州市儿童公园大榕树下，艺术家带领小朋友仿照“克莱因瓶”编织起了“克莱因之茧”，供大家在其中穿梭捉迷藏，小朋友们不仅是“克莱因之茧”的创作者，也是使用者，这些作品永久性地留在了公园里，成为小朋友们游乐的设施。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;公园成为&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;生活的一部分&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;城市这么大，何处好“遛娃”？这个问题困扰着家长。儿童公园重要性提升的背后，正是儿童活动空间的减少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大城市的房子在变小，甚至客厅也在变小，“大家也没太多待客需求，小朋友在家里活动的地方就更小了，只能跑到外面去玩。”王亚飞观察到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在来到深圳坪山儿童公园做运营之前，王亚飞一直在住宅、商业机构做运营管理，到儿童公园之后他的心态“年轻不少”。 “小孩子说话活泼可爱，让人心情放松，相处久了感觉自己都有点幼稚”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坪山儿童公园周边有不少住宅小区，一些小朋友成了公园的常客，几乎每天放学都会来公园里玩，久而久之，王亚飞跟他们也成了朋友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FH0H73nDVXyLBmzgeslarsG4DpJiHqSKuCy1VCn2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FH0H73nDVXyLBmzgeslarsG4DpJiHqSKuCy1VCn2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;坪山儿童公园儿童书屋。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者宋炳晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小朋友在公园玩难免磕碰，儿童公园常备创可贴。起初一盒100片的创可贴够用一个月，后来越来越不够用，最快的时候半个月就能用光。王亚飞偶然发现，原来不少小朋友一次拿走了三四片，甚至当在家受伤时，首先想到的是：公园有创可贴用，专门去公园取。儿童公园已经成为他们生活的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“扩大面向儿童的公共服务供给”正是国家发改委等23部门印发的《关于推进儿童友好城市建设的指导意见》的要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，刘悦来发现，儿童公园“长相”越来越趋同。 “有点像开发商盖的房子，户型都差不多，使用的设备无非是不锈钢、铝合金或者其他一些耐用塑料，没有地方性表达。”比如，地处西北的公园设施就可以有当地特色，训练儿童平衡的树桩不用采购产品册中千篇一律的工业品，而是用当地的榆树，既能节约成本，又体现了地方文化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《深圳设计规范》也提到，植物应体现深圳特色，不少于70%的植物数量产地距公园的运输距离小于500千米，选用维护少、耐候性强、病虫害少的乡土树种，适量选择适应深圳气候的外来特色景观树种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为儿童量身定制，避免了不同用户群体的资源“争夺”。儿童公园里，除了家长，几乎没有别的成年人。广州大学建筑与城市规划学院硕士生导师邓小飞认为，广州在各区建设专门的儿童公园，功能明确且专业，目标服务群体清晰，更能满足儿童群体的需求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但“小”和“远”是王亚飞听到最多的家长反馈，坪山儿童公园一期占地5.7万平方米，相当于8个足球场，但只比综合公园要求面积的一半大一点。面积小自然会让家长觉得，孩子不够尽兴——从福田开了一个小时车过来还不够玩的，为什么不多开20分钟到面积更大的惠州大亚湾儿童公园呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州即便有规模最大的儿童公园集群，也依旧不够密集。邓小飞对广州的儿童公园体系做过研究，若只出行半小时，只有少数人能够获取到儿童公园资源，要扩大到出行一小时，儿童公园资源才能够覆盖广州市绝大部分儿童群体，这与广州市三级儿童友好生活圈还有点差距。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《广州市建设儿童友好城市规划导则》提出构建30分钟公交可达全域的儿童友好生活圈；依托街道及居住区，构建15分钟步行可达街道级的儿童友好生活圈；依托居住小区，构建5分钟步行可达社区级的儿童友好生活圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邓小飞建议，广州可在人口密集的老城区和北部边缘城区等地区，增加儿童公园的数量和面积。对于空间紧缺的老城区，可以考虑利用闲置或低效的土地资源，如废弃工厂等，改建或扩建原有儿童公园，还可以在现有的公园、广场、街道等公共空间中设置儿童游乐设施，打造儿童活动场地等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年8月发布的第一批广州市儿童友好系列试点名单中，除儿童专类公园外，流花湖公园、越秀公园等也入选。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深圳也有类似的思路。 《深圳市建设儿童友好型城市行动计划（2021-2025年）》提出，建设更多社区公园以及小尺度游园，在城市公园、社区公园中拓展充足的儿童游戏场地。到2025年，建成100个以上儿童友好公园。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高标准对接国际经贸规则，“应聚焦数字经济领域的制度型开放”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6t2GGa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6 t2GGa. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Yangshan Deep Water Port is also an important part of the free trade zone. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The top priority this year is to align with international high-standard economic and trade rules and promote high-level and comprehensive Institutional opening. It is necessary to test the system for the country and steadily promote the pressure test of institutional opening such as rules, regulations, management, and standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 30, 2023, Gong Zheng, Deputy Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee and Mayor Said this at the meeting of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone Promotion Leading Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June, the State Council issued &quot;Several Measures on Piloting Conditional Free Trade Pilot Zones and Free Trade Ports to Align with International High Standards and Promote Institutional Opening&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Several Measures&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the Shanghai Municipal Government issued an implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;, stating that &quot;in one year, we will focus on promoting trade in goods, trade in services, digital trade, temporary entry of business personnel, and optimizing Various pilot measures in the business environment and other aspects have been implemented.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone align with international high-standard economic and trade rules? What progress has been made? What are the current obstacles? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to this topic, Southern Weekend reporters exclusively interviewed Peng Delei, dean of the School of Law at East China University of Science and Technology and researcher at the Lingang-East China University of Science and Technology Free Trade Zone Innovation Research Institute. He has been paying attention to related topics since 2019, and Published many articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is still room for institutional innovation in the digital economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The State Council will issue &quot;Several Measures&quot; in June 2023. What is its importance? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In September and November 2021, China formally applied to join the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) and The Digital Economic Partnership Agreement (DEPA) demonstrates China’s determination to further deepen domestic reforms and expand high-level opening up to the outside world. The introduction of &quot;Several Measures&quot; marks the beginning of my country&#39;s formal alignment with international high-standard rules such as CPTPP and DEPA in terms of substantive content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thirty-three articles of &quot;Several Measures&quot; are mainly based on the CPTPP rules. Some provisions are also reflected in the content of DEPA, such as DEPA Article 2.6 for six-hour customs clearance of express cargo, etc. Trade facilitation measures. This shows that the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has relatively mature conditions to apply these rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that in practice, Shanghai has been at the forefront of the country in terms of facilitation of trade in goods. Recently, Shanghai has also highlighted this in the implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once mentioned that compared with international high standards such as CPTPP and DEPA According to the rules, there is still room for further expansion in the scope of the digital economy content in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;. How should we understand it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are two rules related to digital trade in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;, one is about online consumer protection, and the second is about Software source code disclosure issues. However, CPTPP Chapter 14 E-Commerce (Digital Trade) covers 18 items, and each item also contains different amounts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;non-discriminatory treatment of digital products&quot;, that is, any Party grants digital products created, produced, published, contracted, represented or first commercialized in the territory of another Party. Treatment of products, or treatment of digital products whose authors, performers, producers, developers or owners are persons of another Party, shall not be less favorable than the treatment it accords to other similar digital products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, there is a rule in the CPTPP regarding the &quot;location of computer facilities&quot;: No Party shall require a covered person to use or set up computing facilities in the territory of that Party as part of carrying out activities in its territory. Conditions of business. Each party will also consider the issue of data security, so the CPTPP adds an exception to this rule, that is, nothing in this article shall prevent a party from achieving legitimate public policy objectives, which leaves a certain amount of time for each party to policy space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the premise of protecting national security, more systematic considerations are needed on how to further align with international high-standard rules on non-discriminatory treatment of digital products and the location of computer facilities in the future. These provisions are also key provisions in DEPA, and they have an important impact on digital economic activities such as digital trade. Of course, this also provides space for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to be implemented first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is in line with international high standards in the field of digital economy , what are the advantages? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with other domestic free trade pilot zones, at present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone mainly undertakes the function of institutional innovation. We should take the lead in aligning with international high-standard rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there are many high-standard international rules. Taking CPTPP as an example, it covers 30 chapters including investment, e-commerce, and environment. If the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone wants to benchmark every chapter at this stage, I think it will be difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the conditions of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, it is more advantageous to actively benchmark DEPA and focus on institutional opening up in the field of digital economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the industrial foundation for the development of digital trade in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is unmatched by other pilot free trade zones. Shanghai is an international economic center, financial center, trade center, shipping center and technological innovation center. Trade The foundation is mature, and the newly established Lingang New Area in 2019 is also actively exploring the construction of an international data port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Article 84 of the newly revised &quot;Legislative Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee shall, in accordance with the authorized decision of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, formulate the Pudong New Area &quot;Regulations, implemented in Pudong New Area&quot;, which also provides a legal basis and guarantee for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to carry out pilot trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone should promote China’s accession in the field of digital economy High-standard economic and trade agreements provide practical support. What are the main obstacles faced at this stage? How to break through? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone actively benchmarks against DEPA, which has overall significance for China to join DEPA. The extent to which the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has adapted to DEPA and the problems it has encountered can provide an experience reference for China in subsequent negotiations to join DEPA. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is still in the exploratory stage in the process of connecting with CPTPP and DEPA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in terms of cross-border data flow, national security must be taken into consideration, and risk assessment and prevention and control must be done when aligning with international high-standard rules. What risks are faced by the free flow of data, how big the risks are, and what impacts they will bring, definitely require more detailed and systematic consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can break through from two entry points and gradually expand the scope of docking. First, we can consider learning from the negative list approach and research and develop an important data catalog. If this type of data is in the directory, the management specifications need to be stricter; otherwise, they can be relatively loose. Secondly, some qualified companies can also be allowed to pilot cross-border data flows. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“We attach great importance to the construction of a digital trust environment”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the establishment of the Lingang New Area, some explorations have been completed in promoting institutional opening up in digital trade. What are the highlights? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, the &quot;About Supporting Lingang New Films&quot; issued by the Lingang New Area Management Committee and the Shanghai Municipal Commerce Commission on August 30 Implementation Plan for the District to Deepen High-level Institutional Opening and Promote Innovative Development of Trade in Services (hereinafter referred to as the “Implementation Plan”). This is a comprehensive plan for the development of service trade in the Lingang New Area and has breakthrough significance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; proposes specific measures for the safe and orderly flow of data and the innovative development of digital trade. For example, a data supervision sandbox pilot was launched to promote the implementation of a number of cross-border data cooperation projects such as electronic invoices and digital identities. The data supervision sandbox is equivalent to piloting some supervision measures on a certain subject in a region, and then judging whether it is suitable for promotion based on feasibility and effect. The implementation of electronic invoices and digital identities can improve trade efficiency and reduce business operating costs. These measures are actually the content of DEPA and are also the specific actions for Lingang New Area to align with international high-standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Lingang New Area is also relatively advanced in the construction of digital infrastructure, such as the layout and construction of international communication submarine cable facilities, as well as the new National (Shanghai) Internet Exchange Center and international Internet dedicated channels. Construction etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the field of digital trade, Lingang New Area can take the lead in the future What international high-standard economic and trade rules should we try? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In terms of benchmarking DEPA, there are two aspects that can be tried first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen cooperation among digital enterprises. DEPA’s chapter on “Cooperation with SMEs” mentions that “Parties shall engage in digital SME dialogue. The dialogue may include the private sector, non-governmental organizations, academic experts and other stakeholders from each Party”. It is recommended to establish cooperative organizations or conduct regular forums to promote exchanges between small and medium-sized enterprises and Chinese and foreign-funded enterprises, and the demands of foreign-invested enterprises in China can also be reflected through this mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the cross-border data flow issues that digital investors are concerned about, on the premise of ensuring national security, it can also solve the worries of foreign investors investing in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to strengthen mutual recognition of digital enterprises. Article 4.2 of DEPA states that “Parties shall endeavor to mutually recognize the data protection trust marks of other Parties as an effective mechanism to facilitate cross-border information transfers while protecting personal information.” After mutual recognition of information and security is completed, if both parties need to conduct data flow or transactions, many procedural requirements can be reduced and costs can be saved, which is equivalent to establishing a white list for each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Chinese-funded companies have previously been awarded the Data Protection Trust Mark (DPTM) by the Singapore Infocomm Media Development Authority. It is used to certify businesses that have deployed data protection measures to demonstrate that their operations comply with Singapore’s Personal Data Protection Act. Similarly, Article 12 of my country’s Personal Information Protection Law also contains relevant statements, which is to promote international exchanges and cooperation in personal information protection and promote mutual recognition of personal information protection rules and standards with other countries, regions, and international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The cross-border flow of data is considered a basic prerequisite for digital trade. What is the current practice in this regard in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The cross-border flow of data in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is generally governed by the Data Security Law, National Security Law and Personal Information Protection Law. operating within the framework. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I communicate with the practical community, I feel that they attach great importance to the construction of a digital trust environment. The digital trust environment includes network security, personal privacy protection, etc. For example, in the process of digital trade, it is necessary to ensure that large-scale data leaks or cyber attacks cannot occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai has made a lot of efforts in developing digital trade. For example, the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; mentioned that the Lingang New Area will build the country&#39;s first digital trust pilot zone. In addition, in July this year, the Standing Committee of the 16th Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress publicly released the full text of &quot;Shanghai Provisions on Promoting Data Circulation and Transactions in Pudong New Area (Draft)&quot; to solicit opinions from the society. The overall context and value concept of this consultation draft is to strengthen the use of data. In the past, many policies emphasized the protection of data. If data can be fully utilized, it will help promote the development of the data economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Business environment assessment indicators benchmark against international standards&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has been piloted and has achieved many results. In your opinion, what is the most important outcome? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the most important thing is to implement the “pre-establishment national treatment plus negative list management system” for foreign investment. This concept was proposed with a certain background, mainly based on some demands and paradigms put forward by the United States on investment access during the bilateral investment negotiations between China and the United States at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at first, we didn’t know whether these two systems could be implemented, so we first tried them in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. In 2013, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone piloted the first negative list for foreign investment access. Years of trying have since provided many helpful experiences. Therefore, by the promulgation of the Foreign Investment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China in 2019, the &quot;pre-establishment national treatment plus negative list management system&quot; was officially written into law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two systems have been implemented from pilot to legal form and implemented nationwide, achieving the effect that the experience of the Pilot Free Trade Zone can be replicated and promoted, reflecting the pioneering spirit of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. mission to try. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Free Trade Pilot Zone Key Work List (2023)&quot; issued by the Ministry of Commerce -2025), specifically requires the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to strive to create a world-class business environment. What can be done in this regard? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone attaches great importance to the construction of business environment. For example, the Lingang New Area is actively benchmarking against the World Bank&#39;s newly released business environment project concept document in May this year, namely the B-READY project. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as I know, Lingang New Area invites accounting firms to conduct business environment assessments every year. Not long ago, my colleagues and I went to Lingang New Area to participate in a seminar on the business environment. We talked about the three chapters of B-READY: dispute resolution, bankruptcy and labor. For example, online arbitration can be used Facilitate and improve the business environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the new version of the World Bank’s business environment assessment indicators includes content related to digital trade, that is, the digital trade restrictions index. In the future, China may also include restrictions on digital trade as part of its business environment assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 is the tenth anniversary of the establishment of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. Next The free trade pilot zone promotion strategy will be vigorously implemented. How do you think it should be improved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At this stage, my country’s overall goal requirements for the improvement strategy of the free trade pilot zone can be summarized into three aspects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it is necessary to improve the alignment with international high-standard economic and trade rules. Currently, it is mainly based on DEPA and CPTPP; second, it is necessary to improve the level of market access, focusing on increasing investment and service trade. Large stress test; third, reform system integration and collaborative innovation should be improved, focusing on strengthening cross-department, cross-field, and cross-industry overall coordination, and enhancing the systematicness, integrity, and coordination of pioneering trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海自贸试验区十周年：对接世界，做制度创新的“试验田”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5 GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. 2095, Jinjing Road, Jinqiao Development Zone, Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, is the office of Volvo Construction Equipment Investment (China) Co., Ltd. This area is home to many automobile manufacturing and parts companies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of this century, Jinqiao, as the first national export processing zone, attracted Volvo to open an assembly plant here. By 2012, Volvo Construction Equipment signed a memorandum of understanding with the Shanghai Municipal Government to establish its regional headquarters in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the office, Zhan Xu, director of Volvo Construction Equipment, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that for the company at that time, it was like a young man starting to make life plans. He had many ideas, but met a bottleneck. &quot;The place where I live is an electronics factory, can I only be a factory boy and factory girl for the rest of my life?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Xu described that the establishment of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone solved the hesitation of &quot;this young man&quot;, &quot;It tells all companies what Pudong, Shanghai and even China will develop into.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2015, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was expanded to include the Lujiazui Financial Area, Jinqiao Development Area, and Zhangjiang High-tech Area, in addition to the four special customs supervision areas including the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone. In August 2019, the country&#39;s only new free trade pilot zone was unveiled in the Lingang area of ​​Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 29, 2023 is the tenth anniversary of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. Over the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has been a pioneer in testing systems and exploring new paths for the country, and has also become an important driving force for Shanghai&#39;s economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;White Paper on the 10th Anniversary of the Construction of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone&quot;, as of the end of 2022, Pudong New Area has established a total of 18,691 new foreign-invested projects, with a cumulative registered foreign capital of US$217.274 billion, and a cumulative paid-in foreign capital of US$74.994 One hundred million U.S. dollars. Pudong New Area will achieve a regional GDP of 1.6 trillion yuan in 2022, creating 1/74 of the GDP with an area of ​​1/8000 of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering a new stage, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is facing new expectations. The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed to &quot;implement the strategy of improving the free trade pilot zone.&quot; At the same time, China is applying to join the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement (DEPA). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency on September 26, 2023, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, recently issued important instructions on further promoting the construction of the free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that on the new journey, based on a comprehensive summary of ten years of construction experience, we must deeply implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy, bravely be a pioneer in forging ahead and overcoming difficulties, and work in a wider field and Carry out deeper exploration and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Responsive to all requests, no disturbance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“If there is no free trade pilot zone Without support, a lot of business may be done overseas. With the establishment of the pilot free trade zone, we have one more way to go. Since the pilot free trade zone wants to engage in innovation, companies will feel that they might as well come to the government to talk.&quot; Zhan Xu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2018, Volvo Construction Equipment became the first company in the Pilot Free Trade Zone to realize cross-border settlement of offshore trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend learned from the Jinqiao Management Committee that at that time the customer ordered two sets of engineering equipment produced in South Korea from Volvo Construction Equipment. The transaction and transportation occurred overseas, and the fund settlement (receipt from overseas customers, The two processes of payment to Korean factories) are carried out in the free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his early years, Zhan Xu ran through industrial and commercial windows and dealt with the government for a long time. &quot;In the past, we participated in policy briefings, but now we attend more research meetings. Many ideas for institutional innovation in the free trade pilot zone came from the enterprise side.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that in the past, enterprises went to The government mostly consults on policies. Now when companies encounter problems, the government helps bring relevant people over and everyone sits down to discuss solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talking about the changes brought about by the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, Zhan Xu spoke highly of the reform of the commercial system. &quot;All the approval procedures have been simplified. One trip is required for each matter, and sometimes there is no need to make a trip at all. This not only saves manpower and costs for the company, but also plays a great role in stimulating corporate vitality and improving corporate confidence.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to a press conference held by the Shanghai Municipal Government on September 15, 2023, in the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has deepened the reform of the commercial system around the entire life cycle of enterprises and innovatively carried out &quot;separation of licenses and licenses&quot; and &quot;post-licensing&quot; Pilot projects such as &quot;license reduction&quot; and &quot;one industry, one license&quot; have issued more than 5,000 comprehensive industry licenses in 31 industries. The average approval time has been reduced by nearly 90%, application materials have been reduced by nearly 70%, and form-filling elements have been reduced by more than 60%. %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has also taken the lead in implementing the registered capital subscription system, the business entity registration confirmation system, the market quasi-operation commitment immediate entry system, innovating business entity exit mechanisms such as simple cancellation, and continuously reducing institutional transaction cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We respond to requests and don’t disturb anything.” Wu Haixia, CEO of Xingbei Group, expressed similar feelings to Zhan Xu when recalling the company’s process of building Shanghai Free Trade No. 1 Life Technology Industrial Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia told Southern Weekend reporters that when the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was officially launched, the company had just arrived at the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone to acquire the land. As the first biomedical entrepreneurial park in the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone, we will encounter many new situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free Trade No. 1 currently plans to build three phases of the park. About 150 companies have settled in the first and second phases of the park. Wu Haixia said that biopharmaceutical companies have different building height requirements from other companies. With the help of the management committee, the maximum floor height of the first-phase park was only 24 meters, and by the third-phase park, it can reach 50 meters. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, at that time, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone implemented a comprehensive land use reform pilot in the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone. This reform is also very attractive to the biomedical industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Several Opinions on Comprehensive Land Use Planning and Land Management in the Bonded Area of ​​the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone&quot; that came into effect on November 20, 2016 (valid until November 19, 2021), encourages The land uses are compatible, and the land use types are mixed with two or more uses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Several Opinions&quot; stated that factors such as spatial layout, industrial integration, building compatibility and traffic environment should be comprehensively considered, and functional guidance requirements for comprehensive land use in the bonded area of ​​the free trade pilot zone should be put forward, and the planning of mixed comprehensive land use should be clarified Type of use, proportion, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The land used by biopharmaceutical companies is generally based on the ratio of 1/3 office, 1/3 R&amp;D, and 1/3 production. But strictly speaking, office and R&amp;D cannot be located on industrial land. .With comprehensive land use reform, it can better meet the needs of the biomedical industry.&quot; Wu Haixia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;System innovation can reduce costs for enterprises&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhan Xu has been in foreign-funded enterprises for 27 years. In his view, whether a multinational company chooses to stay in one place for development depends on whether it can do more business and whether the market is good; second, whether there are risks in operation and whether the rules are clear; third, whether there is any institutional innovation. , which is an important factor in promoting high-quality development of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the above-mentioned press conference that of the 302 free trade pilot zone system innovations replicated and promoted at the national level, nearly half were originated from Shanghai or were simultaneously piloted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Hongming Supply Chain Co., Ltd. is an enterprise established nearly 30 years ago. Since 2006, it has gradually transformed from a traditional logistics enterprise into a digital supply chain enterprise, currently mainly engaged in integrated circuits, medical equipment and other industries. Provide supply chain services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you walk into Hongming&#39;s office at No. 899 Dangui Road, Pudong New Area, you can see two rows of unmanned workstations. Intelligent robots are completing actions such as identifying and entering waybills and automatically filing customs declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the adjacent office, Bai Li, senior manager of Hongming Customs Management Department, told Southern Weekend reporters that the company&#39;s transformation has benefited from many innovative measures in the customs supervision system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baili gave an example. A domestic factory purchased a piece of equipment from abroad. When a screen of the piece of equipment failed, the past practice was for the factory to place an order overseas and go through customs clearance, tax payment, and international transportation. Waiting for the process, it may take a week for the new screen to arrive at the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In a mature manufacturing process, the assembly line machines are lined up one after another. If this one breaks, all the others behind it will be broken.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Started in 2006 , Hongming has opened bonded warehouses in areas such as Waigaoqiao, which is equivalent to putting this screen at the &quot;doorstep&quot;, saving the time and cost incurred by the original &quot;ordering from overseas&quot; model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But as the size of transactions increases, companies need a more cost-effective approach. &quot;In order to serve factories in ten places across the country, a company needs to put 10 screens, which incurs the cost of 10 screens. So, can it only put 5 screens?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone Launched The special customs supervision model for the circulation of bonded goods between regions has solved the most troublesome problem of the national circulation of bonded goods in the industrial supply chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now bonded goods between free trade pilot zones can flow quickly and freely, and the data and information flow sent by enterprises are sent to the regulatory authorities, replacing the traditional paper documents between the regulatory authorities of the two places. Circulation.&quot; Bai Li said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hongming has established 24 industrial supply chain logistics centers in 14 cities across the country. This model now covers all its logistics centers, effectively reducing inventory costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned press conference introduced that the institutional innovation achievements of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone and the Lingang New Area are mainly reflected in four aspects: focusing on the supply of innovative institutions required for industrial development and enhancing new driving forces for high-quality development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the biopharmaceutical industry, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone took the lead in piloting the medical device marketing authorization holder system (MAH) in December 2017. Eligible medical device registration applications in the Pilot Free Trade Zone People can apply for a medical device registration certificate individually and then entrust production to an enterprise with qualifications and production capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free Trade No. 1 is the first biopharmaceutical business park in China that meets MAH requirements. Wu Haixia said that Free Trade One has built the country&#39;s first CDMO platform with industrial park attributes and built 6 production lines. The CDMO platform can provide enterprises with services in research and development, small trials, pilot trials, animal experiments, human trials, registration and approval and other processes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia said that generally speaking, the investment in a production line is more than 10 million yuan. In the past, companies had to wait about 2 years from application to finally getting the certificate, during which the production lines were idle. The economic investment of the enterprise has not been maximized and time has been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that under the MAH system, companies can share production lines, &quot;which can reduce costs, improve utilization, and release huge dividends.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 5, 2018, Shanghai The Food and Drug Administration issued an announcement &quot;Expanding the pilot reform of the city&#39;s medical device registrant system to the entire city.&quot; Starting from June 1, 2021, the revised &quot;Regulations on the Supervision and Administration of Medical Devices&quot; will be officially implemented, and the medical device registrant system will be fully implemented across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia also suggested that the whitelist system for biomedical research and development supplies and special imported items should be further promoted and improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that as &quot;raw materials&quot; for biomedical research and development, special items such as microorganisms, human tissues, biological products, blood and their products have been planned to be imported in recent years with the development of the industry. However, special items may carry risks of various infectious diseases, and Shanghai Port is extremely cautious about related imports and exports. The rapid development of the biomedical industry has put forward higher demands for rapid customs clearance of special items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant systems will be gradually implemented in Shanghai starting from 2020, but there are still few open parts. It is hoped that the free trade zone can accelerate the implementation of this system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Make full use of the legislative power of Pudong New Area&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with other free trade pilot zones, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was established the earliest, and Pudong The new district has the unique advantage of “legislative power”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 10, 2021, the 29th meeting of the Standing Committee of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress voted and adopted the &quot;Decision on Authorizing the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee to formulate regulations for the Pudong New Area&quot;. Authorize the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee to formulate Pudong New Area regulations based on the practical needs of Pudong&#39;s reform and innovation, in compliance with the provisions of the Constitution and basic legal and administrative rules, and implement them in Pudong New Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This unique advantage played an important role when Hongming participated in an institutional innovation in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Hongming and the Pudong Integrated Circuit Industry Association reported that the company&#39;s application for exemption from compulsory product certification (i.e. &quot;CCC exemption&quot;) took a long time, resulting in the failure of equipment parts to be delivered to semiconductors in time. Problems with the production plant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem Hongming encountered at that time was that the normal CCC exemption required about 2 working days to be issued, but the supply chain after-sales maintenance service needed to be provided 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. The support of the original policy was not enough It can no longer meet industrial needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bai Li raised a pen and made several gestures on the table. &quot;For example, a fuse is very small, but once it blows, the entire machine stops.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, traditional CCC exemptions are for upstream and downstream enterprises in the industry, and the supply chain companies themselves do not have development applications. permissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baili believes that supply chain companies as chain owners are not only familiar with goods and products, but also have the clearest understanding of the flow of the entire supply chain. If the main unit of the innovation chain can apply, the supervision will be upgraded from point supervision to chain supervision, and the entire flow of goods will be clearly visible where it comes from and where it goes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the promotion of Pudong Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, Hongming took the lead in piloting the convenient channel for CCC exemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main contents of the pilot include allowing rapid certification through &quot;self-declaration, automatic certification, and integrity supervision&quot;; through process reengineering, the 5-working-day manual approval will be transformed into a &quot;zero-wait&quot; automatic system Release. At the same time, the restriction that logistics trading enterprises cannot be the subject of CCC exemption applications has been broken, expanding the scope of CCC exemption subjects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2022, Hongming and regulatory authorities will continue to improve processes and systems. &quot;By 2023, companies and associations feel that they can combine the legislative power of Pudong New Area to fix the pilot policies and promote them.&quot; Bai Li said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1, 2023, the country&#39;s first CCC exemption management measure &quot;Several Provisions on Exemption from Compulsory Product Certification in Pudong New Area, Shanghai&quot; was officially implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Pudong Market Supervision Bureau described that one of the main innovations in the management measures is that according to relevant regulations, logistics trading companies cannot be the applicant for CCC exemption. With the approval and authorization from the General Administration of Pudong, supply chain enterprises that clearly provide services to key industries can be applicants for CCC exemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the fourth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 16th Shanghai Municipal People’s Congress held on July 24, 2023, the Municipal Development and Reform Commission mentioned that it would take the opportunity to make full use of the Pudong New Area’s legislative power to base itself on its own Based on the practical needs of reform and innovation in the Pilot Trade Zone and Lingang New Area, we will study and formulate a number of policies and measures in terms of strengthening the innovation engine, high-level institutional opening, reform system integration, and urban governance modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Innovative intellectual property protection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Promoting institutional innovation in the field of intellectual property is also the first step for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to align with international high-standard economic and trade rules such as CPTPP and DEPA. important aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 10th anniversary press conference of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone held by the Shanghai Municipal Government on September 15, Shen Weihua, deputy director of the Municipal Commerce Commission, said that the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is under the guidance of the Ministry of Commerce and other national ministries and commissions. and support, focus on the provisions of post-border management systems such as trade in goods, trade in services, digital trade, intellectual property rights, and government procurement in CPTPP and DEPA, and study reform measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Chao, Executive Deputy Director of Pudong New Area, introduced at the press conference that in the 10 years since the construction of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, a high-level intellectual property protection system has been improved, including the implementation of rapid patent pre-examination, patent implementation investigation, etc. &quot; &quot;Quick Protection&quot; system, shortening the invention patent authorization cycle from 3 years to 3 months, exploring the implementation of a punitive compensation system for intellectual property infringement, and taking the lead in building an international intellectual property protection highland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2021, the Shanghai Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Rights Protection Mutual Aid Fund was launched. This is the country’s first market-oriented intellectual property rights protection mutual aid fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the Lingang Market Supervision Bureau took the lead in establishing the non-profit social organization &quot;Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Exchange Promotion Center&quot; and used the center as a platform to operate funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Zhenhua, director of the Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Exchange and Promotion Center, told Southern Weekend reporters that the fund was launched in the Lingang New Area mainly because the new area has institutional innovation soil, coupled with the agglomeration of cutting-edge technologies and key industries. There is a need for intellectual property protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他指出，随着新片区企业参与国际经济贸易程度的深入，面临的国际知识产权竞争愈发激烈，许多企业由于在人才、资金、信息等方面基础薄弱，在国际竞争中往往处于劣势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在此背景下，基金的落地完善了临港新片区多元化知识产权维权体系，有助于在临港新片区形成长效的市场化运作维权互助机制，为产业创新发展保驾护航。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前基金成员单位达到近180家，覆盖临港新片区重点产业领域，资金规模近130万。 2022年启动了基金扩充计划，根据理事会年费管理办法进行管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，所谓市场化，就是在政府引导下，坚持企业“自发组织、自主管理、自治运营”，基金的募集、管理、使用等都通过市场化机制解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为全国首创，基金没有成熟的经验可供借鉴。冯振华说，遇到问题、调查研究、解决问题，这个循环一直伴随着基金成立和运行的整个过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“临港新片区企业的真实需求就成为了基金成立的最重要标准。”该中心介绍，筹备小组在密集调研了近50家企业后，确定了基金成立和运行的基本思路，即“公益性与市场化相结合，知识产权与重点产业相链接，体系建设与纠纷应对相平衡”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立以来，基金帮助临港新片区企业成功应对知识产权纠纷并提供维权资金支持案例2起，提前介入知识产权纠纷提供咨询超过15次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临港新片区一家从事创新型医疗器械研发和生产的公司在上市过程中，遭遇了全球医疗器械行业巨头的专利狙击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，除了企业自身积极应对之外，基金发挥了重要的维权援助功能，协调多方专家智库资源予以纠纷应对指导，提供维权资金支持，同时也为公司提供知识产权咨询，帮助其进一步完善知识产权布局，降低经营风险，最终在专利无效案中胜诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冯振华看来，未来自贸试验区在知识产权方面还可以关注以下问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是让企业了解国际经贸规则，提前做好准备以便应对潜在的知识产权风险；二是主动融入国际高标准经贸规则体系，甚至通过先试先行探索经验来影响经贸规则；三是平衡中国技术创新和产业发展与国际规则中知识产权相关规定适用的关系；四是关注新技术、新业态为知识产权相关规则适用带来的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大胆试、大胆闯、自主改&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月18日，南方周末记者在沃尔沃建筑设备的仓库里看到一台大型的绿色的再制造发动机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在场的工作人员介绍，这台发动机是全国首单“重点行业再制造产品进口试点”货物，是公司向瑞典订购的，于9月1日抵达仓库，后续将交付客户用于售后。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了让货物快速到达工厂，浦东海关提供了门到门查检服务。现场查检主要是确保单货相符，以及进口机器设备的相关参数、性能等是否与申报内容相符，确保商品既通得快、走得顺，又管得住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，中国在政策层面对进口再制造产品按照旧机电产品进行管理。 “如一缔约方采取或维持措施禁止或限制旧货的进口，则该缔约方不得将这些措施适用于再制造货物。”詹旭现场念了一段CPTPP关于再制造产品的内容。他表示，从国际规则来看，再制造产品是允许进口的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6月1日，国务院印发《关于在有条件的自由贸易试验区和自由贸易港试点对接国际高标准推进制度型开放的若干措施》，第一条就是“支持试点地区开展重点行业再制造产品进口试点”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在詹旭看来，这次针对再制造产品的制度创新产生了多赢的结果。企业拓宽了业务空间，自贸区增加了贸易种类，同时与国际高标准规则接轨。此外，对打通国内国际双循环，达成低碳减排目标等也有重要意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了保障首单试点进口货物顺利通关，上海海关提前介入，全程参与，研究制定了专项监管方案和应急预案。由企业所属地浦东海关负责联系企业，做好企业的事前指导、再制造产品的通关监管等工作，通过专窗受理申报、“门到门”查检等服务措施，确保重点行业再制造产品进口高效、安全通关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么叫做制度创新？因为这个改变不是领导批个条子，而是要讲出个所以然，要大家坐下来研究。”詹旭说，改变这条规则涉及哪些部门、各自要做出怎样的变化、规则改变后的监管和推广要怎么处理等问题都要研究清楚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年来，詹旭对自贸区的理解也在发生变化。他最初觉得，自贸试验区是在上海出台税收优惠等方面的政策。过了一段时间，他开始理解，设立自贸试验区不是在一个地方搞特殊化，而是针对一些特殊的问题进行试点，然后全面铺开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其实原来没想到那么宏大的层面。过去觉得，自贸试验区是不是在解决招商引资的问题？后来我慢慢体会到，自贸试验区是要对接国际标准，把解决方案放在国际视野去综合考虑。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“浦东发布”介绍，上海自贸试验区提早谋划落实上述《若干措施》试点任务，目前已取得了积极进展，初步形成了一批制度创新成果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了率先开展再制造产品进口试点，成果还包括持续优化金融创新业务审批服务，瑞士再保险集团子公司瑞再企商保险申请增资支持个人保险业务拓展，10日内即获批准等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月30日，上海市委副书记、市长龚正在中国（上海）自由贸易试验区推进工作领导小组会议上说，“十年来，上海自贸试验区大胆试、大胆闯、自主改，充分发挥了开路先锋、示范引领、突破攻坚的作用，彰显了全市经济增长极和发动机作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来，要更好发挥高水平改革开放&#39;试验田&#39;作用，在制度创新上取得更大突破。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会：赛场内外，同样精彩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257774]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of 17:00 on September 27, 2023, the Chinese delegation It is far ahead in the medal list of the Hangzhou Asian Games, with a total of 124 medals, including 69 gold medals, 39 silver medals, and 16 bronze medals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Li Bingjie, who won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final, showed her medal.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final championship Li Bingjie displays her medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will be held from September 23 to October 8, 2023, with a total of 15 competition days. The competition events of this Asian Games include 40 major events, 61 sub-events, and 481 minor events. It is the Asian Games with the largest number of events. It is worth noting that non-Olympic events, as the distinguishing mark of the Asian Games from the Olympic Games, mostly originate from traditional folk sports activities and have a deep public base and strong regional characteristics. This Asian Games has added new non-Olympic sports such as skateboarding, break dancing, and e-sports, which not only increases the enjoyment of the games, but also demonstrates the diversity and inclusiveness of Asian sports culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the e-sports events of the Hangzhou Asian Games kicked off at the Hangzhou E-sports Center in China.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports events The tournament kicked off at the Hangzhou E-Sports Center in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind every game and every medal is the sweat and hard work of the players. The Hangzhou Asian Games brought unlimited passion to the Asian region and demonstrated the elegance of Asian sports on a global scale. However, the Asian Games is not just about the medals, it is also exciting both inside and outside the stadium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 22, 2023, the Hong Kong, China delegation attended the welcome and flag-raising ceremony and officially stationed in the Asian Games Village in Hangzhou.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, the Hong Kong delegation from China attended Welcome and flag-raising ceremony, officially stationed in Hangzhou Asian Games Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 22, 2023, Fok Qigang, head of the Hong Kong Asian Games delegation, accepted media interviews at the welcome and flag-raising ceremony.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On September 22, 2023, Fok Qigang, head of the Hong Kong Asian Games delegation, was interviewed by the media at the welcome and flag-raising ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the host Chinese delegation entered the venue to the music of &quot;Singing the Motherland&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 23, 2023, the host Chinese delegation Enter the stage to the music of &quot;Singing the Motherland&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Hangzhou Asian Games is the second international sports event held by China after the Chengdu Universiade. It is also an important window to showcase China&#39;s image in the new era. Like the Chengdu Universiade, domestic and foreign sports audiences can enter the venues and watch the fierce competitive events at close range. Swimming, basketball, table tennis, etc. are the most popular sports in the first week of the competition. Southern Weekend reporters saw at the venue that many enthusiastic spectators would arrive at the ticket gate two or three hours in advance to wait for admission. On the Internet, discussions about athletes&#39; competitive skills, figures, and even appearance and temperament remain high among Asian Games-related categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 20, 2023, an Asian Games-themed light show will be staged every night on the Qiantang River.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every night there is an Asian Games themed light show on the Qiantang River. The picture was taken on September 20, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, a fan of swimmer Wang Shun displayed a poster of her cheering for Wang Shun at the swimming pool.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023 , a fan of swimmer Wang Shun displayed a poster of her cheering for Wang Shun at the swimming pool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the Asian Games swimming events were held fiercely in the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, the Asian Games swimming event was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center The central swimming pool is in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the host city of the 19th Asian Games, Hangzhou has also done its best to let athletes and spectators from afar feel the enthusiasm of the organizers. The Asian Games-themed light show on the banks of the Qiantang River lights up on time every night, attracting many tourists to watch. The overall environment, accommodation conditions and food arrangements of the Asian Games Village were praised by the athletes and Asian Games technical officials. The canteen of the media center was also praised by foreign media workers during the live broadcast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Uzbek veteran Chusovitina saluted the audience with her right hand touching her heart after completing the vault.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Uzbekistan veteran Chusovitina saluted the audience with her right hand touching her heart after completing the vault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Imaddin, a media person from Saudi Arabia, said that the only regret of this Asian Games is that &quot;seeing that October 8 is the closing ceremony, the day of the Asian Games It ended too soon.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, players from the Chinese table tennis men&#39;s team and the Korean team were interviewed by the media after the game.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 26, 2019, players from the Chinese men&#39;s table tennis team and the Korean team were interviewed by the media after the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“三星堆”在香港]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 22:34:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>