<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[江苏宿迁遭遇强龙卷风，灾情造成5人死亡4人重伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:32:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At about 17:20 on September 19, Daxing Town, Suyu District, Suqian City, Jiangsu Province Economic Development Strong tornadoes occurred one after another in Cai Township in the southern part of the district. The level was determined to be EF2, causing casualties and property losses in some areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tornado disaster mainly occurred in towns and villages with densely populated areas and complex building structures. The occurrence period coincided with off-duty hours. Due to the sudden attack of the tornado, the disaster caused a total of 5 deaths and 4 deaths. seriously injured. According to preliminary statistics, 5,512 people were affected by the strong tornado, 1,646 houses were generally damaged, 137 houses collapsed, 41.8 hectares of crops were damaged, 405 people were temporarily relocated, and some walls of more than 2,000 square meters of pig houses collapsed and the roof collapsed. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the disaster occurred, the local area immediately coordinated and directed relevant forces to carry out on-site search and rescue, casualty transfer and treatment, mass resettlement, nuclear disaster relief and other work. The emergency, public security, fire protection, health, housing construction, power supply and other departments rushed to the scene immediately to carry out emergency rescue and aftermath treatment; the affected towns and villages quickly organized local people to carry out self-rescue and mutual rescue. After overnight rescue operations, the injured have been sent to hospitals for treatment, the affected people have been properly accommodated, all power supplies in the affected areas have been restored, and road traffic has been restored to smooth flow. The Suqian Municipal Emergency Management Bureau stated that social order in the disaster area has returned to normal, relevant insurance companies have rushed to the site to carry out investigation and claim settlement, and other aftermath work has been fully launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影的滋味丨凝视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256928]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr5dZZKv9GGN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;833&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr 5dZZKv9GGN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Moonlight Warrior&quot; is adapted from Hong Ying&#39;s novel of the same name, telling a story that began in 1970 A story that spans more than thirty years in Chongqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evening time is usually spent reading or watching movies. Yesterday I watched the movie &quot;&quot; adapted from Agatha&#39;s novel &quot;Death on the Nile&quot; finds director Kenneth Branagh starring as detective Poirot, who also plays Professor Niels Bohr in Nolan&#39;s latest film &quot;Oppenheimer.&quot; Oppenheimer thought that his tutor was too much and did not allow him to attend a long-awaited lecture. He injected potassium cyanide into the apple. The next day he remembered that he ran away and found the apple in the hands of Professor Bohr. When Bohr was about to eat, Oppenheimer stopped him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to understand human despair? Oppenheimer was desperate at that moment. The taste of a good movie will make people imagine. My family said that before he met me, he was on vacation in South France. He thought that life was unpredictable, his heart was empty and he had no cares. He walked toward the river, and was discovered by his friends and caught on the river bank. Not long after, he met me at a birthday party in England. He said that your hair was half long and half short at that time, which was very avant-garde. I say people are like this. If you are extremely miserable inside and don’t live a decent life, you will use external forms to dilute the pain, such as intentionally or unintentionally tending to be abnormal, or even clothes and shoes. Good guy, I wore high heels for many years. With such irregular hair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, you don’t have a tattoo. He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I had a tattoo, would you still fall in love with me? I asked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said, even if you had, I would never have been disgusted with you at that time. When people meet at the right time, everything will be forgiven and tolerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This made me think deeply. So many things have happened in the past three years, and everyone&#39;s destiny has changed. I used to be a fetishist. Everywhere I went, I would collect souvenirs, ranging from a small piece of porcelain to a large sculpture. I loved looking for old postcards and stamps at antique flea markets. One year I attended the Frankfurt Book Fair, and I happily walked around the largest open-air market in the area with my friends. When I saw an old carpet with a silver spoon, I took it without a counter-offer. Now I won&#39;t accept it. There are so many things outside my body and it&#39;s so tiring. Except for books, I don’t throw them away. From last year to this year, I have been cleaning out necessary and unnecessary items, extra pots, bowls, chopsticks, extra clothes, shoes and furniture. The house gradually became a little empty, and I felt relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being alive is better than anything else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie and this story &quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot; was the first time I heard it from my family and neighbors when I was five years old. A family was walking on the wide and long stone steps of Middle School Street. The mother above was wearing a kimono. We have to return to Japan. Below is the father and his three daughters rushing behind. On both sides of the stone steps are people watching. Decades passed, and that scene kept flashing in my mind. From this, I wrote a short story of less than 3,000 words, and then rewritten it into a script of 50,000 words, and then changed the script into a novel of more than 200,000 words. Every character came alive in my heart. After the novel was published, I broke down the previous script and rewrote it. Each scene was based on the actual situation and actors were found according to the image of the characters in the script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The early stage of a movie involves script preparation, preparation of funds and team, and then shooting. The later stage involves editing, sound, music, and color grading and special effects. The early stage is difficult, and the late stage is even more difficult. Many people will lose patience during this process. I strive to absorb fresh professional knowledge, research and think, so that my hearing, smell, and intuition are always in a sharp state. It’s like walking from one distant country to another. You must first determine the location, plan the route, prepare the equipment needed along the way, and then put aside all worries. No one can dissuade you. They all say that the road ahead is a trap, a pit, and a road of no return. , but I don’t believe it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strong wind and heavy rain? This happens too often and there is no need to be afraid. Robbers appear on the road, beggars appear on the road, and smiling tigers appear on the road. Tang Monk, when you go to the West to obtain Buddhist scriptures, you meet monsters who want to eat your flesh in order to live forever. As for me, everything I encounter is God’s way of testing my sincerity towards movies. The film is so bitter and hard that it is completely inedible and must be swallowed whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;949&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The heroine Qin Jiahui of &quot;Moonlight Warrior&quot; is a nurse who first met Dou Xiaoming, a 12-year-old boy at work. Stills from the movie Moonlight (2023). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first cut is timed to show it to others, including friends and professionals. After the cut was finalized, it was viewed by the film promotion company. Some people liked it, saying that it brought with it the charming smog curtain of Chongqing in the 1970s. Mom&#39;s Noodle Shop on Zhongxin Street, it has the real smoke and smoke of the mountain city, and the spicy, sweet and sour taste is worth savoring. Taste; some people don&#39;t like it, saying it&#39;s not like the usual Chinese movies. You are too brave to cross the border from a writer to the film industry to make such a nostalgic and unflattering movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Occasionally I will express my opinion, and sometimes I will remain silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young male protagonist Dou Xiaoming in &quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot; is played by Zuo Hang. Many of his fans urged &quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot; to be released as soon as possible on Weibo, and even said unpleasant things. I expressed my opinion on Weibo, saying that the cycle of making movies is not what they imagined. The filming of this movie was at the end of 2021, and the post-production period was a year, because during the epidemic, many of the post-production companies, including the main creators, were in isolation. It has only been less than three months since our film received the Dragon Award. We have been doing follow-up work and looking for the most suitable promotion company. It’s not that we don’t want to go to theaters and meet the audience as soon as possible. The tweet attracted polarizing comments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In depression, I recalled my favorite Chinese and foreign movies, and thought of the scene in &quot;Tunnel War&quot; in which the Japanese invaded the village and were beaten and fled; I thought of the figure running in the wilderness in &quot;Jane Eyre&quot;; I think of the piano music in &quot;Casablanca&quot;; I think of the charming desert in &quot;Lawrence of Arabia&quot;; I think of the long shot of the boy finally walking to the seaside in &quot;The 400 Blows&quot;, the endless sea and the cloudless sky; I think of the endless sea and cloudless sky; In &quot;La Dolce Vita&quot; the heroine walks down the stairs with rays of sunshine. I try to be calm, accept the things I can&#39;t change, and try to change the things I can. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was immersed in my own work and didn’t have time to pay attention to you, but you immediately kicked me out of your world and ran counter to me. We were such good friends and relatives. Because of making this movie, I I have lost you, and I have also lost my eldest sister who was born to the same mother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, I have encountered many things that make me inexplicably sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From time to time I meet people asking me why I didn’t contact him/her before making a movie? Claiming that if I find him/her, my movie will have stars, funding, and will have greater commercial value. I said, if I come to you then, you will not pay attention to me. If you pay attention to me, it is not too late to extend a hand to me now. This kind of people say that the first-rate movies in the world are those with a cost of more than 500 million; the second-rate movies are those with less than 500 million, with big productions and big actors; and the third-rate movies are small productions with no stars. Hong Ying, you are making this third-rate movie. You are a writer, and it is your duty to be a writer. You want to promote your movie, which is just nonsense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interrupted the other person: What I do is my business, and are you talking about a movie? You&#39;re talking about money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Money can produce movies. There is no first-rate, second-rate or third-rate money. Money is money, but money never equals movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Film is art, the seventh art, Giotto. Kanudu said that film is a comprehensive art that includes static art and moving art, time art and space art, plastic art and rhythm art. Movies use lenses to tell stories, tell a story about a person who is gradually forgotten, tell long-standing legends, tell historical truths, and use visual and sound effects to tell the story of justice and ideal spirit that existed in long ago. Movies are about realizing impossible dreams. Movies use It’s just about making dreams. Without dreams, how can we make movies? How to watch movies? Ingmar Bergman said, My movies are not to make your soul feel comfortable, but to make you fight with your soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height= &quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hong Ying on the set of the movie &quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What does the movie mean to me? I often ask myself, and I am also asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times it feels like the movie has entered my body, sucking my blood and aura. Do I walk into the river with stones in my arms? But the movie wouldn&#39;t let go of me, so I had no choice but to look back. I saw that when I was a child, I and my father were sitting on the bank of the Yangtze River, watching the boats sailing on the river. They were all in fixed focus, and they came to me frame by frame. They were the world. This world was not as gray and dark as the one I lived on the south bank of the river. Hopeless, so poor, this world has bright colors and hope, endless passion and love on the other side of the river. This is a movie that will always belong to those who are indomitable, believe in the good side of the world, and never lose the ability to love others and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was dreaming that night, and I was standing on the Chongqing riverside again, together with the executive director, waiting for the ship to ship the filming equipment. Mist comes. I walked forward, the river flowed carefully, I could hear my own footsteps, and I saw an abandoned cable car in front of me. It was exactly the same as the one I had walked along the river thousands of times when I was a child. There was even a bridge hole. I walked over and immediately Walking back from the cave, I saw the fog dissipating, and the mountains, houses and some factory sheds on the other side were looming. The river was green and rippling with waves. Looking to the left, I saw the scenery of the Jialing River to the left of Chaotianmen in the center of Chongqing. I was extremely excited, and there was a wide beach on the right. I pointed there and said to the people around me, why should we go to the opposite side to shoot that fight scene? No, it is right here. This is the scene I was most familiar with when I was a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Somehow, I feel that this is a gift from Chongqing, where I was born and raised, to my firm heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I woke up and clearly remembered that it was a morning in the winter of 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years, it seems like a long time, it seems like a blink of an eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While writing this article, I read a Weibo post by Xiaofeng, the host of &quot;Xiaofeng Live Room&quot; on Weibo: &quot;&quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot; is really the most mysterious movie of the year, directed by the internationally renowned Hong Ying, winner of the Rome Prize for Literature, adapted it from her own novel and directed it for the first time. She loved this story so much. Pamuk liked &quot;The Museum of Innocence&quot;, but he just built a museum with limited time and space. It is unimaginable. He picked Füsun and Kemal by himself and let them sway in the old streets of Istanbul, but Hongying did it. She not only hypnotized us on paper, but followed Dou Xiaoming and Qin Jiahui into the winding mountain city Xiejie, also put their stories on the screen, allowing the dense atmosphere of the mountain city and the majestic beauty of the river to flow through our eyes. Congratulations to &quot;Moonlight Samurai&quot; for being nominated for the Best Screenplay Award at the Hollywood Next Generation Independent Film Award. This Another piece of much-anticipated good news.&#39; The film awards&#39; highest honor goes to outstanding storytellers and visionary filmmakers from around the world.&#39; Outstanding storytellers, yes, that five The girl who ran and shouted in the drizzle by the Yangtze River when she was young, the daughter who only found out about the river where she was born at the age of eighteen and has determined her life since then, she has always been the woman who lives by telling stories like Scheherazade!&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her words touched the softest part of my heart. Even if one person sees my walking track or notices my movies, I should be grateful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Dou Xiaoming and Qin Jiahui, I was swaying on the steepest stone staircase in the mountain city. I saw the city lights pouring on the river little by little, and the tugboat came from the darkened confluence of the two rivers. , sounding the air horn, and someone holding a loudspeaker shouted, &quot;Stop at Pier 2,&quot; and then used local swear words in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s such a familiar scene. It’s not someone else’s tugboat, it’s my father’s. From the old photos he showed me, I know its appearance and shape. Of course, it has long since become a pile of waste. Iron, but I imagined it appearing on the river more than a hundred times. I resurrected it in the movie and made it exist forever. My father, I believe that you will see this movie in Tianzhiling. This movie pays tribute to Chongqing and Chongqing people. It also pays tribute to foreigners and foreigners like you. Father, I believe that you will see this movie. Finally, you will nod to me and show me a rare smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汽车4S店被要求“限时搬迁”：优化民营经济发展环境应落到实处丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province were &quot;required to relocate within a limited time&quot;, which attracted industry attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Automobile Dealers Association recently posted on its official social media that a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City have received notices from government departments requiring them to relocate to designated automobile parks within a time limit. The article said that according to incomplete statistics, almost all car 4S stores within the Third Ring Road of Shijiazhuang City are involved, and there are more than 100 dealers of various brands. The large-scale relocation and reconstruction are expected to cause direct economic losses of more than 1 billion to the dealers. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, &quot;Automotive Business Review&quot; magazine reported that according to statistics from the Shijiazhuang Commerce Bureau, the relocation involved 177 sizable 4S stores, affecting almost all 4S stores in Shijiazhuang. The notice, stamped with the bright red seals of the local Natural Resources and Planning Bureau, the Public Security Bureau, the Urban Management Bureau, the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, the Fire Rescue and the Subdistrict Office, requires that all 4S stores be relocated and vacated before September 30, and the stores must be closed. , those who do not move into the automobile industrial park must close their stores before September 10th; temporary and illegal 4S stores must be demolished by themselves before September 10th, otherwise they will be demolished by force; &quot;Refuse to cooperate, maliciously obstruct and hinder the execution of official duties&quot; &quot; will be &quot;seriously dealt with in accordance with the law, and those suspected of committing crimes will be held criminally responsible in accordance with the law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, demolition work has begun, and many car brand showrooms have been razed to the ground in the Hebei International Automobile Trade Park, the largest local automobile park. According to reports, the relocation of automobile 4S stores was carried out in the name of &quot;comprehensive improvement of temporary (illegal construction) low-end market&quot;: the government requires existing 4S stores to be closed and demolished, and relocated to four new parks planned by the government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon in various places to require companies to relocate to new parks planned by the government under various pretexts. A few years ago, a county in eastern Shandong Province required all stone companies in a town famous for stone production to relocate to a newly built &quot;stone industrial park&quot; in the name of &quot;industrial agglomeration.&quot; A few years later, on the grounds of &quot;air pollution control&quot;, all barbecue restaurants in the county were required to move to the newly built &quot;BBQ Street&quot;. If you don&#39;t want to relocate, then close without negotiation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is true for the car 4S store in Shijiazhuang that &quot;requires time-limited relocation&quot;. Once a document is issued by the city government, the district and sub-district offices will enforce it. If they are unwilling to relocate, they will close the store and demolish it. However, the expenses and costs associated with relocation, as well as the possible impact on industrial development, need to be calculated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What impact may relocation have on companies and industries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, of course, the renovated business premises must be abandoned and moved to a new location. Not to mention the rent, renovating is a huge expense. According to an estimate from an article by the China Automobile Dealers Association, each new store after the centralized relocation is expected to require an additional construction investment of 10 million to 20 million yuan. In recent years, car sales have dropped from their peak, especially due to the impact of the epidemic. Many dealers were already struggling to survive until the epidemic was relaxed, and they are planning to take advantage of the opportunity to develop their business. Some stores even just opened a few months ago, and were required to dismantle and relocate the store before selling a few cars. The tens of millions of yuan invested just now were in vain. It was difficult for the store owners to invest more funds in the construction of new stores, so they had to Forced into bankruptcy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some shop owners questioned the procedural issues. According to a report by Shijiazhuang Daily in June, the policy formulated at the special meeting of the Municipal Party Committee at that time was to &quot;build first and then destroy&quot;. First, ensure that the new automobile industrial park is completed and put into use by the end of September, and then complete &quot;overdue temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; in October. &quot;4S store relocation and renovation. However, in actual implementation, &quot;establish first and then destroy&quot; has become &quot;first break and then establish&quot;. According to reports, the four new parks currently planned are still under construction. Even if work is rushed 24/7, it will be difficult to complete before the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Part of the reason why Shijiazhuang City proposed the relocation and rectification of 4S stores is that some current 4S stores have problems such as &quot;extended temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; and are a &quot;low-end market&quot; that need &quot;rectification and improvement.&quot; In fact, the current automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City are relatively concentrated in four parks. Some of these parks are automobile industrial parks previously planned by the government, and some are actively gathered and formed spontaneously during the market development process. The location selection of these stores was a decision made by dealers after investigating factors such as the business district environment and customer needs, and was also in line with the municipal planning at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Requiring time-limited relocation&quot; affects not only 4S stores, but also the millions of existing car owners in Shijiazhuang, as well as new car owners who are preparing to buy cars. Officials require almost all 4S stores to close before the end of September. It is not yet known when the new park will be completed. Even if the new park is built, and even if the 4S store has the money to relocate, the decoration of the new store will usually take at least two to three months. There will be a window of several months in between. During this period, let alone citizens being unable to buy new cars, it is even difficult to ensure vehicle maintenance and repairs for old car owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the central government issued the &quot;31 Articles on the Private Economy&quot;, which requires optimizing the development environment of the private economy, protecting the property rights of private enterprises and the rights and interests of entrepreneurs in accordance with the law, and promoting the development and growth of the private economy. The Hebei Province Private Economy Leading Group also announced the &quot;Hebei Province Private Economy Development Work Points in 2023&quot; in April 2023, proposing to continue to optimize the business environment. As for optimizing the business environment, the most fundamental thing is probably not to provide enterprises with various industrial guidance and policy preferences, but to reduce interference in the market, respect the property rights of enterprises and the autonomy of entrepreneurs, and allow entrepreneurs to make market decisions independently. Only with more services and less guidance, more support and less trouble can the private economy develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[证监会再出“新招”规范上市公司分红强化制度约束和激励]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256974]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:30:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the common wish of investors to obtain higher dividends within a reasonable range. On September 18, a reporter from 21st Century Business Herald learned that the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to launch a series of measures to improve the normalized dividend mechanism for listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has introduced and implemented a &quot;linking&quot; policy between dividends and shareholding reductions. Listed companies have not distributed cash dividends in the past three years, or the cumulative cash dividend amount is less than 30% of the average annual net profit in the past three years. , controlling shareholders and actual controllers are not allowed to reduce their holdings of the company’s shares through the secondary market. According to the person in charge of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, it is planned to further strengthen institutional constraints on companies that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends to urge dividends, promote the optimization of dividend methods and rhythm, so that companies that pay dividends can get more incentives, and at the same time, strengthen the supervision of companies that exceed their ability to pay dividends. constraints, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the amount of dividends paid and the proportion of A-share companies ranked among the top in the world. Data show that in the past five years, the amount of dividends paid by A-share listed companies has increased year by year, with a cumulative dividend of 8.2 trillion yuan, and the amount of dividends has exceeded the amount of financing that year. In 2022, a total of 3,291 Shanghai and Shenzhen listed companies in my country&#39;s domestic market paid cash dividends, accounting for 67.1% of the total number of listed companies at the end of 2022. The total cash dividends for the year reached 2.06 trillion yuan, of which the amount of dividends attributed to A-share shareholders was 1.62 Trillion yuan. From an international comparison, the number of dividend-paying listed companies in the domestic market ranks first among the world&#39;s major securities markets, the total amount of cash dividends ranks second in the world, and the proportion of dividend-paying companies ranks second in the world. In addition, 163 listed companies announced cash dividend plans for their 2023 semi-annual reports, with dividends expected to be 203.01 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Mature companies with continuous improvement in dividends, and companies listed on the main board have a higher proportion of dividends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the sustainability and growth of dividends of listed companies in my country have continued to improve. Data shows that as of 2022, the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for five consecutive years has increased from 20% ten years ago to 48%, and the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for 10 consecutive years has increased from 8% to 31%; 412 listed companies have paid dividends continuously. The proportion of companies that have grown in three years has increased from 3% ten years ago to 12%, and the proportion of companies that have grown in five consecutive years has increased from 1% to 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dividend yield and dividend payout ratio also show a fluctuating upward trend. The dividend yield distribution range has gradually increased from 0.5%-1.5% before 2010 to the current 1.5%-2%. In 2022, the average dividend payout rate in my country&#39;s domestic market is 32.5%, and the average dividend rate is 1.97%, which is in the middle and upper reaches of major global markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which sectors and industries pay higher dividends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders believe that dividend features are generally in line with the company’s development stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of sectors, the dividend payout rate of main board companies is the highest, reaching about 33%, which is 8 percentage points higher than the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of industries, industries with stable performance and low investment demand tend to have higher dividend ratios. Judging from the average dividend payout ratio, energy, major consumption, and public utilities rank among the top three, with dividend ratios as high as 50%, 48%, and 45% respectively. Listed companies in these industries have low new investment needs and relatively stable cash flow. Hence the average dividend payout level is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, the real estate, industry, and information technology industries have greater investment demand, and the average dividend payout ratio is also lower, at 28%, 26%, and 25% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the dividend level of A-share companies in the start-up and growth stages is lower than that of companies in the mature stage. Due to their relatively weak financing capabilities and strong willingness to save and defend, private enterprises have slightly lower dividend levels than state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Whether a high proportion of dividends is reasonable or not needs to be viewed comprehensively and accurately&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dividends of listed companies need to comprehensively consider multiple factors such as profitability, cash flow, debt, growth stage, development goals, etc. Different types of The attitudes and demands of shareholders towards cash dividends are not completely consistent, and it is necessary to balance the interests of the company and shareholders, major shareholders and small shareholders.&quot; The interviewed experts believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this expert, whether a company can pay dividends and how much it pays are mainly affected by three factors: first, the undistributed profits accumulated by the company from its operations in the current year and in the past; second, the cash it currently has; It is whether the retained earnings can meet the company&#39;s future development needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dividend ratio needs to be determined comprehensively based on the company&#39;s profitability, development stage, and future development needs. According to industry insiders, whether a company pays dividends and how much it pays are not necessarily linked to the profit of the year. Although the dividend ratio of some companies in individual years is relatively high, it is still reasonable. This must be comprehensively analyzed and viewed accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, some companies have stable profits and cash flow and have little investment demand, so they maintain a high dividend payout ratio. On the other hand, some companies will keep the amount of dividends unchanged despite declining profits or losses, and stabilize investor expectations through continued dividend payments, which will lead to higher dividend payout ratios in certain years. At the same time, in order to reduce redundant funds, some companies will implement special dividends based on accumulated undistributed profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts interviewed believe that, of course, it is not ruled out that major shareholders may distribute dividends arbitrarily and hollow out the company regardless of the company&#39;s future development needs. This should be strengthened, but this should be a very small number. To judge whether dividends are reasonable, we need to start from three dimensions: first, we need to see whether the profits are real and whether there is fraud; secondly, we need to see where the cash comes from and whether it is borrowed money to distribute dividends; finally, we must make a comprehensive judgment based on the motivation of major shareholders to pay dividends. A high proportion of dividends cannot be equated with dividends beyond capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, we need to view high-proportion dividends comprehensively and accurately. On the one hand, we must identify dividends based on false profits at the expense of the interests of listed companies; on the other hand, we welcome dividends based on the company’s true profit level and development needs. A high proportion of dividends that can effectively return investors.&quot; said an industry insider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four aspects will be followed to further standardize dividends of listed companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to review the &quot;Supervisory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 3 - Cash Dividends of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Dividend Guidelines&quot;) ) &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association&quot;) and other rules have been revised. On the basis of the &quot;linking policy&quot; for dividends and shareholding reductions that have been introduced in the early stage, we will continue to improve and optimize the cash dividend supervision system and strengthen information disclosure supervision. , conveniently optimize the mid-term dividend payment process, better play the role of investment side, and continue to enhance investors’ sense of gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the head of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, this policy adjustment will proceed from four aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen institutional constraints and urge companies to pay dividends that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends. The first is to strengthen information disclosure supervision. For companies listed on the main board that do not pay a certain proportion of dividends, they are required to disclose and explain the reasons. The second is to strengthen disclosure requirements for companies with large financial investments, and urge companies to improve the efficiency of asset use and better focus on the main business and return investors. The third is to strengthen inquiries and supervisory interviews. Strengthen regulatory inquiries to help investors make better judgments on dividend information, and urge more dividends through interviews and other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, promote further optimization of dividend methods and rhythm. Specific measures in this regard can be summarized in two points: First, simplify the mid-term dividend payment procedures to facilitate the company to further increase the frequency of dividends and allow investors to better plan capital arrangements. Second, guide the company to formulate a dividend policy for stable growth. Promote companies to amend their articles of association to improve the operability of dividend policies; guide companies to explore dividend distribution policies with stable growth and reward investors with more stable dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, let companies with good dividends receive more rewards and &quot;taste the sweetness.&quot; On the one hand, it gives more &quot;honor&quot; to companies that pay good dividends. The exchange will study how to further favor high dividend-paying companies in the evaluation of information disclosure; the Listed Companies Association will study and optimize the preparation method of listed companies&#39; dividend lists and increase publicity efforts to guide companies to establish a correct value orientation. On the other hand, promote the development of more influential dividend index products; encourage fund companies to issue dividend fund products, and guide market funds to increase their preference for cash dividends from listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, strengthen restrictions on companies that pay dividends beyond their capabilities. Although paying dividends beyond capacity is not a prominent problem in A-shares, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will still pay close attention to it and take multiple measures to strengthen prevention. The first is to work hard to ensure that the company&#39;s performance is true and the basis for dividends is solid, and to effectively prevent listed companies from falsifying their finances and financing dividends. Second, for listed companies that have high asset-liability ratios and insufficient operating cash flow, but continue to pay dividends at a high proportion, detailed disclosure of the rationality of the dividend plan and its impact on the company&#39;s production and operations is required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“杀猪盘”受害者决定复仇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D57PCasl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D5 7PCasl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The story of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is inspired by a large number of real cases of &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, decided to take revenge after being defrauded of 550,000 yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met for the first time, Zhou Dongyu asked Ma Yingxin in a joking tone, what do you think about me? Like a person who has been cheated? It was September 2021, not long after Ma Yingxin returned to China. In the first week after arriving in Beijing, she had a meal with Zhou Dongyu and talked about Zhou Ran, the heroine of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, a victim of emotional fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingxin felt that the real intention in the witty words was that she thought the audience would not be convinced if she played a deceived person. Ma Yingxin’s answer: When you think you will not be cheated, you are basically increasing your chances of being cheated. After hearing this, Zhou Dongyu did not refute or admit, &quot;But she did go back and think about it for two days and said, let me play this role.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I believe that after the movie is released, the first reaction of the audience will be, will Dong Yu be deceived?&quot; Ma Yingxin told the Southern Weekend reporter, but this was precisely one of the reasons why she chose Zhou Dongyu. &quot;I don&#39;t want to choose someone who everyone will think will be deceived when they see her. Then she acted in this story. I don&#39;t think she conveyed anything. It&#39;s precisely Dong Yu who is like this. Maybe in the audience&#39;s perception, they don&#39;t believe her. If you will be deceived, then it will be more interesting for us to read this story.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was early autumn in Beijing in September. In an office building near the China World Trade Center, Ma Yingxin wore a black knitted sweater and pushed Wearing a wheelchair, he entered the conference room neatly. After a car accident when she was young, she has been using a wheelchair. Stopping in front of the long white table, she did not say any greetings and only said softly, &quot;Let&#39;s get started.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creation of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is based on a large number of real cases. The background of the story is the emotional scam in telecommunications network fraud, commonly known as &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. After 2019, Ma Yingxin began to receive relevant news frequently. What puzzled her was that mainstream comments were belittling and blaming the victimized women. They were &quot;love-brained,&quot; &quot;stupid,&quot; and even the word &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; itself was a stigma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people, without thinking deeply about this problem, think how could I be deceived. But in fact, so many people have been deceived.&quot; When writing the script, in addition to online information, Ma Yingxin also Ask a friend to find the real victim and chat. She discovered that there were many more victims than she thought, and many of them were very smart and outstanding people. Emotional deception is different from ordinary financial fraud. The victim will feel humiliated and dare not tell others. Some people do not even call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emotional fraud usually refers to online fraud that induces victims to make &quot;investments&quot; based on opposite-sex online dating. The long-term process of establishing an emotional relationship is called &quot;pig farming.&quot; In recent years, as more information has been disclosed, people have discovered that the means of emotional fraud are highly specialized and even involve psychological knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman working in the financial industry in a big city in China also had doubts when communicating with scammers. The other party claimed to be a colleague. She asked some questions about the industry intentionally or unintentionally, and the other party could answer them appropriately. After being deceived, the woman did not tell her family, and only a few friends vaguely knew about it. She worries that if her colleagues find out, what she says in the company will have no weight in the future. When talking to Ma Yingxin, she always used a relatively relaxed tone, &quot;I thought everyone had passed the financial test, so there should be no problem.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, Ma Yingxin finished writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;. The heroine Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, is a female drifter from Beijing who was defrauded of 550,000 yuan. She followed clues to a small coastal town and met the con man Lin Zhiguang, played by Zhang Yu, and his friend Xu Zhao, played by Zhang Youhao. Emotional deception is based on imitation, performance, manipulation, and insight into and gaming of the subtleties of the human heart. Zhou Ran decided to retaliate in his own way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影的拍摄地点在福建漳州的东山岛，麻赢心希望寻找一个雾气弥漫的小岛——写剧本时，她最早想到的便是三人在雾中相遇的画面。她想到，这个画面就像受骗女性的状态——“她在雾里面，什么也看不见，但有一个男的声音一直传来，有九个月她一直在一场大雾里”。直到声音的来源从雾里走出，出现了具体的男人形象，雾开始散了，“从这一刻开始，周冉看清了一些事情，她要采取行动，终于不是在一个被雾笼罩、什么也抓不到的境地。我看清你了，反而你不知道我是什么情况我是什么心态，她掌握了主动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1986年，麻赢心出生于东北。她从小喜欢看电影，有网络付费电影后，某一个月爸爸交了两三千元网费，“看一部电影就从网费扣钱，可想而知看了多少”。成年后，麻赢心到西班牙读书，学法律，生活了十多年。她喜欢阿莫多瓦，近十年一直在创作剧本，拍过短片《逝言》和《椅中人》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《鹦鹉杀》是麻赢心的第一部长片，作为在海外生活的新晋导演，搭建起这个项目缘于偶然。几年前，她在西班牙的文学讲座上遇到了作家双雪涛，她介绍自己在西班牙从事电影工作，也写剧本，双雪涛说，如果你想听听别人的意见，欢迎发给我。 2020年底，写完《鹦鹉杀》的剧本后，她在微信上发给了双雪涛，“我说两年前你来西班牙我们交换了微信，我是谁谁谁，你当时说可以把剧本给你看看，我现在手上有一个发生在国内的故事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两天后，他们通了一个很长的电话。当时双雪涛正在场边准备踢球，打到比赛结束了也没上场。 “那通电话里没有聊太多剧本的问题，他其实在了解我能不能做一个导演。”后来，双雪涛成为《鹦鹉杀》的监制，合作过《平原上的火焰》的顿河担任制片人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个半小时的采访里，麻赢心偶尔需要将双手撑在轮椅扶手上，抬起身体放松。在导演这个身份之前，她可能会面临一些标签，“可能是女性，其次是我个人的身体状况”，她都可以接受，但归根到底，她想自我介绍为：一个诚实的创作者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《鹦鹉杀》的片名部分源自鹦鹉学舌。骗子鹦鹉学舌地使用话术，帮助教学，完成行骗，本质是一种模仿行为。她想表达，“女性对情感的珍视不是女性的一个劣势，或者是一个应该被剔除的东西。”这就是女性的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;导演麻赢心1986年出生于东北，长年在海外生活。 《鹦鹉杀》是她的第一部长片。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;这些女性就是普通人&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;很聪明，甚至很出色&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾说不会因为某个社会议题拍摄一部电影，更多是某个议题契合了你想讨论的问题，用这个议题去发展出一个故事。你觉得“杀猪盘”很像一个寓言，对你来说，它包含了什么内容？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我在看“杀猪盘”新闻的时候，下面的评论一直在讨论受害者是愚蠢的，一定是一些很愚蠢、恋爱脑的女性才会被骗。看到这些话，从我对人的理解上，我是抱有怀疑的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得人这一生不可能不跟人发生感情的链接，不仅局限于情感恋爱关系，和你的朋友，和周遭的人也永远有情感和信任的联系。如果是这样，来了一群人，是一群人，他处心积虑来骗你，你有什么办法？这和你是不是一个聪明的人无关，除非你不跟人产生关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我想办法去了解受害者到底是一些什么样的人，看网上资料，托朋友联系，我得到的结论是，这些人就是普通女性，和我、我身边的人没有什么不同，对生活和爱情有正常的期望。她们是很聪明，甚至很出色的女性。所以我不会塑造一个典型的或者有任何奇观性的受害者形象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，关于人为什么会受骗这件事，我和监制双雪涛有一个沟通，他说骗子是一个古老的行业，从古至今以感情行骗是一直在发生的事情，只不过今天换了一个形式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被骗的过程包含了很多人本质的问题，比如人有对真挚感情的永恒渴望，还有人跟人之间以感情去操纵、欺骗、博弈，这是非常紧张的关系，在戏剧上很紧张。所以这个故事有两个层面，一个是“杀猪盘”本身是对受害者女性不公平或者有失偏颇的印象，还有就是这个议题又包含了其他更加本质的议题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你从受害者被骗后的情感状态和内心斗争切入，这个视角是一开始就形成的吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我花了半年到一年时间在想剧本，我觉得创作不是对现实的完整再现，我不想拍一个有这么多新闻资料在我手里，再以电影的形式组合出来的东西。电影需要有一个结构，这个结构能把你最想讨论的东西放进去。后来有两个比较明确的想法后，我开始写剧本，一个是我要让受害者和骗子在现实中见面，第二是我要重演一个骗和被骗的过程，断断续续写了大概半年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雪涛对很多骗子电影非常感兴趣，他觉得这部电影是对骗子电影的一种颠覆，因为它们通常是在骗子身上做文章，描述骗子好厉害，有多么高明。他说你从一个受害者的角度做文章，保持了骗子电影的类型，同时是一种颠覆。另外，他也说骗子从古至今存在，有大骗子、小骗子，还有行业骗子，所以这也是一个关于信任的电影。从这两个角度讲，这个议题都很值得做。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，他说我提供了一个女性的角度，因为男性要做这部电影可能会变成另一个样子。顿河之前和女导演合作过，觉得这是一个女性表达，很珍贵，应该有这样的表达。他顿河作为一个男性，并不能对里面每一个表达都理解得非常精准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;故事中的两位男主人公在诈骗园从事“杀猪盘”，真实身份扑朔迷离。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“不要觉得这部电影要给女性上一课”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么会选择周冬雨演周冉？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们推进这个项目之后最先考虑的就是谁来演周冉，因为这是要靠一个女演员扛起来的戏。当时顿河就推荐了冬雨，因为他们合作过《平原上的火焰》。坦白说我当时是犹豫的，冬雨当然非常好，但是在我心里是一个少女，我觉得这个角色和她的银幕形象是恰恰相反的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时《平原上的火焰》有亲友放映场，我去看了，那部电影前半部分冬雨还是一个少女，但后半部分她展示出了另一个状态。另一个更重要的原因，我发现冬雨可以处理非常复杂的情绪，这是一种很罕见的能力，因为周冉就是要不断处理复杂情绪，不是一个简单的我要复仇这样的角色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么理解周冉这个角色的复杂性？这个故事里有很多暗流涌动、真真假假的博弈，你觉得她犹豫过吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得她复仇的决心是从她见到这个骗子的那一刻起，甚至在她见到骗子之前就有了，但她是见到这个骗子之后决定了她复仇的方式。因为这个骗子走到她的面前说，我是真心的，我有多么多的苦衷，你是多么特别的一个人，到这一刻还在运用话术。她之前也许想让他坐牢，想要抓到他，但是那一场戏之后激起了一个更深的东西，她觉得只让他坐牢是不够的，所以她采取了后面一系列的方式。包括她在车里听到其他受害女性的声音，也给她很大的力量，她一定要做这件事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是你说她过程中有没有摇摆和挣扎，我觉得是有的。因为她是一个普通人，不是一个训练有素的骗子，她去做这件事已经超出了普通人能承受的范围。如果她没有挣扎，就是一个复仇，我来演了一场戏，没有任何情感的波动，最后把你送了进去，对我来说不是那么有力。反而是她有过那么一丝挣扎，最后完成了这件事，我觉得是一个非常有力量的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;通过女性受害者的视角，你最终想要指向的表达是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得可以通过这个受害者的遭遇去理解女性的普遍遭遇，以及普遍的理智与情感的挣扎。尤其这些年有所谓“恋爱脑”这样的词汇出现，我觉得一直在对女性天然对情感的珍视这件事进行某一种矮化，而模糊了这样一个事件当中真正有问题的一方，就是利用情感去谋取利益的人才是有错的，或者才是社会真正需要警醒的地方。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它其实不算是这部电影的核心，但是我自己的想法就是，我希望至少我们拍一部女性为主角的电影，观众走出电影院的时候，不要仅仅觉得这部电影要给女性上一课、女性不要怎么怎么样。我们之前非常少的几场放映里面，女性观众能理解她复仇的方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;麻赢心认为“杀猪盘”是一个寓言，包含了信任、情感等更本质的议题。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;真心到底是什么呢？他也不知道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在B站的账号“周末电影派”里专门讲过一期章宇，这次和章宇合作感觉怎么样？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;林致光这个角色当然也有和他过往银幕形象非常不同的地方，比如在《风平浪静》和《东北虎》里面，他是内敛寡言、很克制甚至很压抑的角色，要么就是另外一种很莽撞、直接、生猛的角色。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林致光是完全不同的，他是一个想非常非常多的人，不断在进行真真假假的表演，很善于用语言去操纵别人，利用语言去博弈或欺骗别人。一样的地方是章宇本身也是一个非常善于思考的人。当时他看完剧本，觉得很有意思，但与此同时有一些意见，写了一页纸发给了顿河。顿河截图发给我，我看到就很不服气，说你怎么有这么多意见，我就写了封信给他，回答这些疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得章宇就是这样一个演员，他有非常多问题要问你，但是得到解答之后他是可以去沟通的，他会很开心。而且林致光在处理人的关系上有某种相对温和的特质，这也是章宇本人有的，他也是一个很温和的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那张纸上写了什么内容？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;比如为什么要杀掉一条章鱼，这是针对我吗，这个意象有什么意图。我说电影不要去解释，越解释东西越少。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他自己对这个角色进行了什么创作吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他创作最多的是林致光的语言，我们为这件事也battle了很多次，他想要林致光有一个非常柔和的、南方又不是那么南方的口音。这个角色骗人，又说自己在东南亚，他应该有一个独特的口音，而不是章宇的口音，不是一个讲普通话的人，这是他觉得对这个人物挺重要的部分。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对这两个男性诈骗者的形象是怎么理解的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;林致光是一个不相信任何东西的人，他在网上扮演阿昌，生活中又扮演林致光，所以他基本是活在扮演当中的人。他非常善于操纵别人，非常擅长操纵情感，是一个空空荡荡，很无助，很彷徨的人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许照是一个被毁掉的人，比较年轻就到了那个地方，他对这一切没有任何认知，为了生存开始做这些事。他还没有真正体验过什么是爱，什么是真心，就已经在运用它去骗人了，这导致他是一个很混沌的状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以在现实中他面对周冉，面对一个真实的女性，他其实也很混沌，分不清自己到底有没有爱她，有没有珍惜她。林致光有一句台词说，我以为你真的喜欢她。他说我是真的喜欢她，你说的嘛，要真心。但是这个真心到底是什么呢？我觉得他也不知道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;麻赢心在拍摄现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;女性复仇的方式是独特&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;、&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;有力的&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;周冉和林致光在车里接吻的镜头，不是一个很直接的亲吻镜头，甚至有点像“借位”。为什么这样设计？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是有意这样的，因为他们不是肉体关系，是精神上的博弈，所以肢体部分我会尽量往下压。那场戏最重要的是语言上的博弈，情感的博弈，周冉用一轮又一轮语言把林致光瓦解掉，获得他的信任。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最后林致光回到了车厢，他是真的被俘获了吗，还是不得不回来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题之前也有人问过我，我不觉得林致光爱上了周冉，在这么短的时间里，尤其是对林致光这样一个人来说，几乎是不可能的。我认为他那一刻是对于这个女性能够原谅他，甚至有可能跟他建立未来的生活，对这件事情产生了妄想。即使他是一个骗子，他也有一刻产生了妄想，所以回到了这个车厢。还有一种可能性是，他需要回到车厢才能拿到那笔钱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那场戏冬雨处理得也非常复杂，我几乎不太愿意用语言解读那场戏，但我核心的认识是最后的对峙，冬雨的表演非常有力量，她甚至做了一个鬼脸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那是她自己加的反应？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，她在那一刻突然有那一个动作，我认为是一个非常强大的反应，而且是只有她会给的一个反应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对于你来说，周冉最终的复仇是一种女性主义表达吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得我在这部电影里非常诚实，我本身是一个女性，所以一定是女性的表达，但是它是不是女性主义的表达，坦白说女性主义我还在学习。但这部电影至少提出了一种女性看待事情的方式，和她行动的方法。提到复仇，你总会觉得它是一种暴力行为，因为由复仇带来的联想，之前是由男性电影或以男性为主导的电影来给人建立印象的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个新的印象，女性复仇的方式是独特的。如果你认同情感或者谎言能给人伤害，那她复仇的方式就是有力的。确实有一些观众会觉得是不是不够爽，期待一些更暴力或更剧烈的复仇方式。但对我而言，反而这种方式才是真正有力的，而不是更暴烈、更外化的东西，我觉得她真的用了一个人是如何被摧毁的方式去报仇或回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你觉得林致光体会到了这种伤害，或者接收到了这个信息吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得林致光至少是诧异的，是他意想不到的。至少从表演上来说，最后那一场戏章宇的角色非常用力地看周冉，他就是想要看到一些答案，但是他看不到。我认为至少这个问题会困扰他。而且除了被绳之以法，对过去做的事情，他可能有机会真正地反思。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[211高校女硕士遭杀猪盘被骗138万：财务决策与婚恋决策分开是防骗关键]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;211 female master&#39;s degree was defrauded of 1.38 million in two weeks&quot; became the first hot search topic . The client, Xueer, joined a bank in Shanghai after graduating from a 211 college in Jiangsu with a master&#39;s degree. In May and June this year, she posted about choosing a spouse on a social platform. A man took the initiative to contact her, saying that he lived in Wujia Plaza, Yangpu District, Shanghai, graduated from Shanghai University of Finance and Economics, worked in a major Internet company, and was on a business trip in Beijing. After communicating online for a period of time, the other party sent Xueer a link and asked her to click to download an app called &quot;luno&quot; and teach her to buy coins on it, and then use the coins to buy up and down to earn some extra money. At first, Xueer made some money. Later, the other party asked Xueer to invest more than 1.3 million yuan for various reasons. In the end, Xueer found out that she had fallen into a scam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The endless emergence of &quot;pig-killing plates&quot;, killing all kinds of people, naked chat traps for men, and marriage and love traps for women show that scammers have a precise grasp of the psychological differences between the sexes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although they have high education, high income, and good looks, many women are also trapped in it. The reason is that some highly educated women often fail to make good financial decisions and marriage decisions during marriage, especially when they mix them up, giving scammers an opportunity to take advantage of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called financial decision-making involves financial expenditure, investment and other behaviors. It is necessary to comprehensively consider the reasonable feasibility of the investment project, investment scale, investment stop-loss standards, and the consequences of investment failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; cash-out routine often uses high interest rates to induce victims. However, what you want is high interest rates, and scammers are targeting your principal.人们应建立一个投资常识，投资产品的预期收益与投资风险是正相关的。 Just like the daily purchase of various financial products, financial products will be marked with different grades. Financial products with low expected annualized yields but marked with low risk mainly invest in high-credit-rated bonds (such as treasury bonds), money market and other low-risk financial products. , and financial products with high expected annualized returns but marked with medium and high risks will have a high proportion of high-volatility financial products such as stocks, commodities, and foreign exchange in the investment product portfolio. When customers purchase products, financial management institutions also conduct personal investment risk assessments and recommend investment varieties that are more in line with their risk preferences based on past investment categories, income status and other information reported by them to avoid blind investments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, when the woman hears the other party introducing investment products that &quot;guarantee no loss and interest rates far exceed the market average&quot;, she should be alert. Guo Shuqing once reminded the majority of financial consumers and investors: high returns mean high risks. If the return rate exceeds 6%, there will be a question mark. If the return rate exceeds 8%, it will be very dangerous. If the return rate exceeds 10%, you will be prepared to lose all your principal. In addition, do not trust unknown information, do not disclose personal information at will, do not open unknown network links, and do not transfer money easily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever you encounter a large amount of capital investment, learn more about investment and financial management expertise in advance, or ask people or institutions with relevant experience to provide advice, and then make investment and investment decisions based on your own risk tolerance, funding level, etc. Decisions on whether, the amount of investment, and how to stop losses promptly when problems arise should become the &quot;financial intelligence&quot; possessed by everyone. Especially as highly educated women, they should have minimum learning ability. Xueer in the above case works in a bank. Although she is engaged in IT work, it is not difficult to find a few colleagues who understand financial management for advice. However, she was deceived by her husband, especially the initial profit from &quot;investment&quot;, and stepped deeper into the trap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, men and women also need to make good decisions about marriage and love. Generally speaking, in the marriage and love market, men and women have different demands. Men tend to pay more attention to women&#39;s appearance, age, etc., while women focus on men&#39;s wealth, family background and other criteria. For Kochi women, there are many men who are excellent in certain aspects in the marriage and love market, but there are very few rich men. The tall, rich and handsome people with both appearance and wealth are a typical scarce group. Their choice space is huge, so they are interested in the &quot;rich and handsome&quot;. The competition for &quot;handsome&quot; is actually very fierce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why scammers create rich and handsome characters is that they know that this group of people is in a seller&#39;s market, and women are often hard to find. Once they meet, some women are eager to capture Prince Charming tightly, have a serious dependence mentality, and are prone to obey the tricks of scammers. Some women are too pursuing the perfection of love and high returns on investment, and ignore the risks and uncertainties in reality. When faced with the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; scam, he was tempted by emotions and interests, and fell into the scammer&#39;s trap, ultimately losing both his life and money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you are a man or a woman, when making a marriage decision, you must make at least three prior assessments: First, objectively evaluate your own conditions. What is your approximate ranking in the marriage market? Don’t just think about winning five million by buying a lottery ticket for two yuan. He who knows others is wise, and he who knows himself is wise. The ancients are honest and do not deceive me. Secondly, if the other person&#39;s words, deeds and person make you feel comfortable, like bathing in the spring breeze, then don&#39;t be too proud. You should blow a cold breeze and judge rationally. Is this the other person&#39;s character or is he always catering to you? It&#39;s understandable to covet emotional value, but the price the other party secretly bids may be too expensive for you to bear. Third, even if you decide that the other person is the right one, don’t tie your marriage and love decisions to your financial decisions. More and more men and women who have reached the stage of marriage are beginning to emphasize the &quot;AA system&quot; of property and living expenses after marriage. How can you give your hard-earned money to the other party to help invest before marriage? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 10:25:34 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳门街坊的横琴生活：粤澳合作区两周年记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdw CKSbR0bN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, accompanied by the crisp prompts when passengers cleared customs, the new passenger inspection building standing at Hengqin Port once again ushered in a busy moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, about 12,000 Hong Kong and Macao residents travel between Hengqin and Macao through the Hengqin Port. Macao resident Huang Huixia is one of them. Almost two years ago, she moved to the Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone in Hengqin and became a &quot;new Hengqin native&quot;; now, she lives in Hengqin and returns to Macau three or four times a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The transportation is more convenient, the house is more spacious, the living environment is more comfortable, the community services are better, and more and more Macao people come to the cooperation zone...” Talking about the two projects in Hengqin Huang Huixia has a treasure trove of her life experiences over the years. In the future, as the Macau light rail extension Hengqin Line project comes into use, the transportation from Hengqin to Macau will become more convenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 5, 2021, the &quot;Overall Plan for the Construction of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;) was issued, giving Hengqin &quot;a new platform to promote the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy&quot; It has four major strategic missions: &quot;a new space to facilitate the life and employment of Macao residents&quot;, &quot;a new demonstration to enrich the practice of &#39;one country, two systems&#39;&quot; and &quot;a new highland to promote the construction of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area&quot;. Twelve days later, the management agency of the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone was officially unveiled, and the construction of the cooperation zone has entered the &quot;fast lane&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the issuance of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot; in 2009, the country has successively introduced a series of innovative policies to draw a bright blueprint for the development of Hengqin.&quot; Dean of the Institute of Regional Opening and Cooperation at Sun Yat-sen University Mao Yanhua told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has multiple advantages such as superior location conditions, solid cooperation foundation, and strong support. The current development momentum is strong, and the future will definitely be more promising.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;&lt;strong>;Macao Neighbors in Hengqin&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“My original house in Macao was very small, only about 60 square meters. After moving to Hengqin, the living area suddenly increased. 150 square meters.&quot; After two years of moving to Hengqin, Huang Huixia has the most vivid feelings about the changes in Hengqin&#39;s living environment, transportation conditions, community services, medical care, and customs clearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early autumn, the water of Tianmu River is shining, with green trees and lush vegetation on both sides. Strolling along the 7.2-kilometer-long ecological corridor along the river, rhythmic urban waterfront landscape belts such as ecological community areas and park-like communities gradually unfold, and across the water are the Macau Tower and the Grand Lisboa Tower. , MGM Hotel and other Macau landmark buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia moved to Hengqin Shangcun from Macau two years ago, where 60% of the residents are Macau residents. Shangcun is only about ten minutes&#39; walk from Tianmu River. In her free time every day, she would go for a walk by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Huixia still clearly remembers the situation when she first moved to Hengqin. At that time, due to insufficient flow of people and few bus lines, it took a long time to go back to Macau. &quot;Now I travel to and from Macau three or four times a week. There are several buses to Hengqin Port after leaving the community.&quot; Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hengqin Port is located on the west bank of the Cross Gate Waterway on Hengqin Island and is connected to the Macau Bridge. It is at the intersection of &quot;one country, two systems&quot; and the junction of &quot;internal and external radiation&quot;. At present, Hengqin Port has achieved &quot;cooperative inspection and one-time release&quot;. Entry-exit personnel only need to &quot;stand in the same hall, line up once, and undergo inspection once&quot; to complete the entry-exit procedures for both the mainland and Macao. The average customs clearance time per person is only 30 About seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customs clearance time has been greatly shortened and the process has been optimized, allowing Macao residents traveling between the two places to live a more comfortable life in the twin cities. Huang Huixia clearly feels that more and more Macao residents are passing through customs and entering the cooperation zone every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics, there are currently more than 7,000 Macao residents settling and working in Hengqin. The average daily passenger flow of Hong Kong and Macao residents entering and exiting through Hengqin Port will increase from more than 5,900 in 2022 to nearly 1.2 in 2023. Thousands of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to major improvements in the living environment, daily life and transportation conditions, the elderly care, medical and community services in the Hengqin Cooperation Zone are also constantly moving closer to Macau standards. In 2019, the Macau Federation of Neighborhood Associations set up a service center in Hengqin and formed a professional service team to provide Macau-standard home care home care services for seniors aged 60 and over in the cooperation zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As of the end of August 2023, we have provided services to more than 960,000 residents in Qinzhou and Macao.” A person in charge of the Macau Neighborhood Association told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to the continued advancement of the cross-border practice policy, there are currently a total of 67 short-term medical practitioners from Hong Kong and Macao practicing in Hengqin. &quot;New Hengqin residents&quot; including Huang Huixia can seek medical treatment from familiar Macao doctors without leaving the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can participate in local insurance in Hengqin and enjoy the same medical insurance treatment as Zhuhai citizens. It is very convenient to buy medicines and see doctors, and the personal expenses are not high.” Huang Huixia said, “Follow-up’ Macao New After the completion of the Neighborhood project, a Macau medical team will be stationed and a large medical service center will be equipped, making life more convenient in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Macau New Neighborhood&quot; mentioned by Huang Huixia is a cooperation area The first comprehensive livelihood project for Macao residents, it will be equipped with various Macao standard public services and social welfare, and will create a high-quality and livable community for more than 10,000 Macao residents. Currently, the project has entered the acceptance stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Life in the cooperation zone will definitely get better and better in the future.” Huang Huixia told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Four New Industries&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking advantage of the rapid development of the Hengqin Cooperation Zone, Wang Ruiming came to Hengqin to seek development. In the past few months, he acquired an Australian-funded company and plans to establish a new company, mainly engaged in the financial and Internet industries, which is expected to be officially opened at the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he is engaged in the financial industry supported by the cooperation zone, his company can enjoy a 15% tax preferential policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ruiming is a &quot;third generation overseas Chinese&quot;. In recent years, attracted by the business policies and environment of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, he has been actively deploying in the Bay Area and has registered financial companies in Hong Kong and Shenzhen, focusing on funds, trusts, insurance and other businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hengqin’s financial industry is highly open and cross-border capital flows freely. It is the most active area for cross-border RMB settlement. Many Fortune 500 companies have settled here. It is very promising to become China’s financial industry in the future. A new highland for opening up to the outside world.&quot; Wang Ruiming told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the added value of the financial industry in the cooperation zone reached 8.8 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 40% of &lt;span>;GDP&lt;/span>;, with a year-on-year growth of 2.9%, showing a trend of accelerating agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The cooperation zone has made solid progress around the &#39;Four New Industries&#39;. Not only has the industry positioning become clearer, but a system and mechanism for consultation, construction, management and sharing has also been initially established.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macao has a small land but a large population. There are more than 680,000 people living in less than 33 square kilometers of land, with an average of more than 20,000 people per square kilometer. It is one of the cities with the highest population density in the world. Problems such as insufficient land resources and a single industrial structure have always plagued Macao&#39;s development. Hengqin, across the water from Macau, covers an area of ​​106 square kilometers and has significant spatial advantages, providing sufficient space to support the diversified development of Macau&#39;s economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 2009, the State Council approved the implementation of the &quot;Hengqin Master Development Plan&quot;, clearly stating that Hengqin should be used as a carrier to jointly create a cross-border cooperation innovation zone, in order to gradually change the economic structure of Macao. Single questions provide new space. With the gradual advancement of high-quality development in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the introduction of the &quot;Hengqin Plan&quot;, the integration of Hengqin and Macao has reached a new level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the beginning of development, Hengqin has been given the mission of serving the diversified economic development of Macao. In more than ten years of development and construction, this mission has not only remained unchanged, but has become more prominent.&quot; Mao Yanhua pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its inauguration and operation, the Hengqin Cooperation Zone has focused on the &quot;four new&quot; strategic positioning and vigorously developed the &quot;four major&quot; technological research and development and high-end manufacturing, Macao brand industries such as traditional Chinese medicine, culture, tourism, exhibition and trade, and modern financial industries. Industry&quot; and launched a series of new policies targeting the integrated circuit industry, financial industry, cultural tourism and exhibition industry, etc. In the past two years, a number of key projects have been accelerated, and the integrated development pattern of Macao and Macao has been initially established. The supporting role in promoting the moderately diversified development of Macao&#39;s economy is gradually emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023 alone, there will be more than 40 integrated circuit companies actually operating in the cooperation zone, initially forming an integrated circuit design industry ecosystem covering intellectual property (IP), third-generation semiconductors and other fields; Guangdong The Australian Cooperative Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and Technology Industrial Park contributed nearly 80 million yuan in corporate tax revenue in the first quarter, a year-on-year increase of 59%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With industrial agglomeration and policy dividends, the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone has become a new platform and new highland for Australian people and enterprises to invest and start businesses. Currently, there are more than 5,600 Australian-funded enterprises in the cooperation zone, an increase of 22.3% compared with before the cooperation zone was established, and the registered capital exceeds 148 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《横琴方案》开启了粤澳深度合作区建设的新篇章。”毛艳华表示，“未来合作区建设要继续围绕服务澳门产业多元发展这一初心，从建设一流产业功能园区出发，大力发展实体经济，利用好创新体制，进一步吸引园区内外要素充分流动集聚，从而打造珠江西岸高质量发展的新增长极。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中黄惠霞、王瑞明系化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rS zHzGpQrZ3O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2019, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram in operation was nicknamed &quot; Dangdang car”. In June 2023, Zhangjiang trams will be suspended. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retro, good-looking, fresh... City trams once had such Internet celebrities label, but in the past few months, news of tram outages have appeared frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, an announcement circulated on the Internet stating that due to difficulties in operating funds, modern trams in Honghe Prefecture, Yunnan will cease operations on August 10, 2023. On August 11, the chairman of Honghe Prefecture Modern Tram Co., Ltd. responded that the announcement was false news. At present, the local tram has not been suspended and is operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Tianjin Development Zone Guide Tram Line 1, which had been in operation for 16 years, announced that it would cease operation and started procurement of demolition projects. In June, Shanghai Zhangjiang Tram No. 1, which had been in operation for 13 years, was suspended and the tracks were quickly dismantled. Two years ago, in 2021, the trams in Zhuhai, Guangdong, were suspended and planned to be dismantled after more than three years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram was out of service, and workers were dismantling the track. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Shijun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, 3 of the 39 rail lines across the country have been suspended. According to the &quot;Urban Rail Transit 2022 Annual Statistics and Analysis Report&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Report&quot;) released by the China Urban Rail Transit Association, as of the end of 2022, a total of 39 tram lines in 23 cities across the country have been put into operation, with an operating mileage of 578.3 kilometers. , equivalent to half the distance from Beijing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary reason for the suspension of operations is low passenger flow. This is not the first time such news has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, after the opening of the Chengdu Tram Chengdu Tram Line 2&#39;s first section, the line was not connected to the urban rail transit network and the passenger flow was low, which led to great pressure from public opinion and suffered &quot;some problems&quot;. &quot;Trams are useless&quot; controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are trams frequently suspended? How to avoid the &quot;chair transport&quot; situation? Compared with subways with large passenger flows, trams are &quot;urban rail transit low-capacity systems,&quot; Li Hongchun, an expert and deputy director of the academic committee of the China Urban Rail Transit Association and vice president of the Modern Tram Branch, told Southern Weekend that doing a good job Line network planning achieves a high degree of integration of multiple transportation modes, and low-capacity systems can develop systematically and healthily. There are also many successful cases in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Low passenger flow is the key to the suspension of trams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Insufficient passenger flow and serious losses are the key reasons for the suspension of trams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jiemian News, before the suspension, the daily passenger volume of Shanghai Zhangjiang trams had dropped sharply to about 1,000 passengers. Wang Qingfeng (pseudonym), a bus enthusiast who works in Zhangjiang, recalled that sometimes “when we get on the bus from the starting station, there are almost no passengers on the bus along the way.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 25, 2022, at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on a working day, there were almost no passengers in the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram car, and there was only one conductor. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The operating pressure of the Honghe Prefecture tram, which denies rumors of suspension, is not optimistic either. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the tram passenger intensity in Honghe Prefecture was 0.01 (10,000 passengers/km·day), ranking at the bottom in the country. The passenger volume that month was only 26,000, with an average of less than 900 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 29, 2018, a tram was undergoing joint debugging and testing in Honghe, Yunnan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low operating frequency is an important reason that affects passenger flow. The longer the departure interval, the lower the attractiveness of passenger flow. Low passenger flow further affects the departure interval, forming a vicious circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval between Zhangjiang tram trains before they stop running is 15 to 20 minutes. For commuters, the waiting time is too long. &quot;Instead of waiting for the tram, it&#39;s better to buy a shared bicycle.&quot; Wang Qingfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only shared bicycles, but also the opening and operation of many subway lines such as the eastern extension of Shanghai Metro Line 2, Line 11, and Line 13, have dispersed the passenger flow of trams. Before the suspension, in February 2023, Zhangjiang trams reduced their operating hours from 17 hours a day to only 4 trips during the morning and evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pudong Modern Rail Transit Co., Ltd. stated in the announcement that in recent years, the public transportation system in Zhangjiang area has been continuously enriched and improved. Multiple urban rail lines have been put into operation, and ground bus lines have been optimized and adjusted many times. The passenger flow of Zhangjiang Tram 1 has been declining year by year, and ground buses will replace the connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Insufficient technical applicability and high maintenance costs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to low passenger flow and long departure intervals, the trams in Tianjin Development Zone and Shanghai Zhangjiang are subject to The vehicles are imported products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both use the Translohr system produced by the French company Raul, which has rubber wheels, single track and a small footprint. However, not many cities around the world use this system. With the gradual decline of Raul after its acquisition, the production of related parts has been greatly reduced, resulting in high vehicle maintenance costs and long maintenance cycles, and some parts are facing the risk of &quot;supply interruption&quot;. Difficulties in purchasing parts have also led to difficulties and high costs in maintaining trams in Shanghai Zhangjiang and Tianjin Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qingfeng recalled that when he was riding a tram in Zhangjiang, he discovered that there was a thick wooden pole in the driver&#39;s cab. The tracks are sometimes blocked by debris, and drivers need to get out of the car and use wooden poles to clear the debris, which greatly affects traffic efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Zhuhai tram, Li Hongchun mentioned in an interview that the TramWave ground power supply system it used lacked engineering practice, and the builders had insufficient understanding of the applicability of the technology, resulting in system problems after the line was opened. The failure rate is high and the operation service is unstable. At the same time, factors such as low passenger flow and high maintenance costs have directly affected the remaining section of Line 1 that was originally planned to be rebuilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being low in frequency, the out-of-service trams were also considered too slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Report&quot; shows that the average travel speed of subways in 2022 will be 36.47 kilometers/hour, the average travel speed of trams nationwide is only 22.3 kilometers/hour, and the travel speed of Zhangjiang trams is only 19 kilometers/hour Hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the maximum design speed of Zhangjiang trams is 70 kilometers per hour. The reason for the slow running speed is that trams do not have dedicated right of way - they share the road space with all vehicles and are still subject to traffic lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Zhangjiang tram does not have a dedicated right of way. It shares the road space with all vehicles and is still subject to traffic lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long trams waiting for traffic lights exacerbate congestion. For example, the Zhangjiang tram passes by Pudong Foreign Languages ​​School Affiliated to Shanghai International Studies University. Parents will park their private cars on the roadside when picking up their children. When the tram comes in, it will occupy the entire road. One citizen said: &quot;You can either use the non-motorized lane next to it to overtake, or you can only follow the Dangdang tram.&quot; Dangdang tram is the nickname given to Zhangjiang trams by Shanghai residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Planning issues, not standard issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking around the world, trams are not a niche issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;China Tram Development Report (2020)&quot; released by the Modern Tramway Branch of the China Urban Rail Transit Association shows that subways and trams are the mainstream systems of urban rail transit in the world, of which subways account for 47 %, trams account for 42%, and light rail accounts for 11%. In Europe, trams are the mainstream public transportation mode in many cities. For example, in Berlin, Germany, trams account for as high as 55.6% of the rail transit mileage. In China, this proportion is only 5.71%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some voices pointed out that the tram was &quot;unacclimated&quot; after it came to China. But Li Hongchun reminded that many tram projects are operating well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In very large and megacities, trams can be used as extension lines and encrypted lines of large and medium-sized transportation systems such as subways. For example, Beijing&#39;s Xijiao Line, as an extension of Metro Line 10, starts from Bagou Station and connects tourist attractions such as Xiangshan Park, National Botanical Garden, Yuquan Country Park and the Summer Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Western Suburb Line is positioned to be “mainly for commuting, supplemented by tourism,” Li Hongchun added. The Xijiao Line is the first tramway in the country to be operated with multiple connections - two train sets are connected together to increase passenger flow. During the &quot;Xiangshan Red Leaf Festival&quot; in 2019, the maximum daily passenger flow reached 94,700, making it the first single tram in the country. The daily passenger flow is the highest recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the May Day holiday in 2022, in order to reduce the full load of the carriages, the Beijing Xijiao Line will adopt a multi-connection operation mode. A single train will change from 5 carriages to 10 carriages, with 8 groups per day. Heavy-duty trains are put into operation with a minimum departure interval of 5 minutes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China News Service reporter Jia Tianyong Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Huai&#39;an, Jiangsu, trams even serve as the city&#39;s backbone public transportation, ensuring Passenger flow demand. Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is the first tram line in China that enters the core area of ​​the city, and its passenger flow has always been at the forefront of tram lines in the country. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the passenger flow in Huai&#39;an was 580,000, reaching nearly 20,000 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 16, 2020, in Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province, modern trams that were suspended due to the epidemic resumed operation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In tourist areas, trams can also play the role of special tourist buses, such as the Nanping Wuyi New District Line in Fujian , connecting Nanping City High-speed Railway Station to Wuyishan Station, seamlessly connecting with Wuyishan Scenic Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the experience of successfully operating trams, unlike large-capacity systems such as subways, trams, as low-capacity systems, are redeveloped on existing road resources, which is difficult and needs to be adapted to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that the suspension of some trams does not reflect problems with the tram system itself, but problems in planning and design. For example, the area near the first phase of the Zhuhai tram project is mostly high-end communities. Residents mainly travel by car. Moreover, the north side of the line is dominated by mountains. The development intensity along the line is low, there is little residential land, a lack of commercial facilities, and the line radiates from one side. , resulting in low passenger flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to plan rationally? Li Hongchun believes that trams are positioned as an environmentally friendly transportation system that fills the gap between large-capacity subways and conventional buses. First, we must ensure a clear level of public transportation planning and strengthen integration with comprehensive transportation. For the connection of hubs, the division of labor between trams and conventional bus systems must be properly handled, and the line network layout must consider the integration of large-capacity systems and medium- and low-capacity systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 26, 2020, the first tram in Wuyishan City, Nanping City, Fujian Province slowly drove out of the Xiandian depot and entered the trial operation stage. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Sanya tram is located closest to the entrance and exit of Sanya Railway Station, and the Jiaxing tram The station is directly connected to the newly developed campuses on both sides by pedestrian tunnels, making these designs more convenient for residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Site selection needs to be supported by a certain population density. Li Hongchun mentioned that it is necessary to accurately predict the passenger flow in the line corridor to avoid the situation where the actual passenger flow does not reach the estimated amount. In terms of construction timing, &quot;we must first consider what needs to be built most, not where it is easier to build.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first section of Chengdu Rong Line 2 was opened, the low passenger flow was questioned because it had not yet been connected to the urban rail network. After the opening of the second section, it was connected to the subway, and the passenger flow reached nearly four. Ten thousand people, an increase of dozens of times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of operations, regarding the issue of tram rights of way, Li Hongchun believes that priority signals should be provided for trams to ensure the safety, speed and efficiency of tram operations. For example, Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is equipped with three major systems: tram signal priority control system, intersection red light electronic police and road section checkpoint system, and intersection video surveillance system, and arranges traffic coordinators to realize tram priority at intersections. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that under the dual influence of my country&#39;s rapid urbanization and the substantial increase in private car ownership leading to congestion, the development of public transportation is an inevitable trend in history. The construction cost of the subway is at least ten times higher than that of the tram. Compared with the bus, the tram has the advantages of large transportation capacity, high comfort and punctuality. Under the trend of carbon neutrality, tram It is an important option for public transportation construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 9:30 am on October 26, 1909, Congkuanchengzi (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changchun&lt;/span>;) Ito Hirobumi, who arrived in Harbin by special train, stepped off the train. A short man wearing a peaked cap and western clothes calmly touched his chest, ribs, and abdomen. He fired three shots and then fired four shots at the accompanying Japanese officials, shouting &quot;Ula Golia!&quot; in Russian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened suddenly, and everyone was still dreaming. Ito Hirobumi was put on a special train and died 30 minutes later. The man with a resolute face, An Zhonggen, was captured in an almost tragic manner; the seven gunshots fired over the Harbin Railway Station, which was built in 1899 and named in 1903, rapidly and profoundly changed the 20th century. The situation in Northeast Asia at the beginning - Although the train station was demolished and rebuilt in 1959, there are still vivid traces of this incident in the station, including the Ahn Jung-geun Memorial Hall and the platform where the incident occurred: the &quot;Δ&quot; and &quot;□&quot; on the ground , respectively, where Ahn Jung-geun and Ito Hirobumi are standing, about 5 meters apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old scene of Harbin Railway Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Ruo Ge As Li said, &quot;When poems and legends are silent, only buildings speak.&quot; - Around the train station, everything is completely different from what it was more than a hundred years ago. Only the Church of Saint-Iver still quietly &quot;leans&quot; on it. Stand aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Street: &quot;The Cross-Communication of Multiculturalism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Old Harbin&quot; without city walls is actually neither ancient nor modern - it is The &quot;modern city&quot; grew up amid the roar of trains. China&#39;s defeat in the Sino-Japanese War and many factors such as Tsarist Russia&#39;s use of alliance with Japan as bait to seize more interests in Northeast China gave birth to the construction of the Middle East Railway. In 1896, Russia obtained the right to build the Middle East Railway. In June of that year, Russia&#39;s Middle East Railway The General Administration of Construction moved from Vladivostok (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vladivostok&lt;/span>;) to Harbin. At the same time, the railway was divided into The six ends of the east-west and south-west lines are being constructed in opposite directions at the same time. As the center of the 2,500-kilometer &quot;T&quot;-shaped railway that runs from Manzhouli in the west, Suifenhe in the east, and Lushun, Dalian in the south, it has quickly become an international city with &quot;sky-high buildings, merchants, soaring land prices, and every inch of land is precious.&quot; - &quot;The desolate wilderness turned into a prosperous port in an instant.&quot; Capitalism has become the &quot;power&quot; for Harbin&#39;s rapid growth and rise, but at the same time, foreign capital has inhibited and hindered the development of national capitalism, making it an &quot;alien&quot; between traditional Chinese cities and modern capitalist cities; a railway has even more influence on Harbin. The local architectural culture has had a huge impact, with a wave of compulsory and replacement architectural design trends - integration, addition, mutation... In the silent dusk more than a hundred years ago, in this city with wonderful characteristics, it began Continuously “cultivating”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Harbin Railway Station and St. Iver&#39;s Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Red Army Street, which shoots out straight from Harbin Railway Station, was originally named Horvat Street. It is the starting point and germination of Harbin&#39;s city construction. It spreads outwards with it as the axis, showing the annual rings of the city&#39;s growth. The original site of the Longmen VIP Building was built in 1907. At the other end, there were the Russian Consulate General in Harbin and the Officers Club of the Russian Trans-Amur Military District, as well as the &quot;famous&quot; Yamato Hotel in the Northeast; the Sino-Russian Daosheng Bank, built in 1920, is now It is the Heilongjiang Provincial Research Museum of Literature and History, still maintaining the original French Renaissance style; the Cheschakov Tea House’s mixed classicism, baroque and Renaissance style exterior bay windows, overhanging awnings, and open-air balconies are set among the Among the green trees, looking at the signboard of &quot;HSBC Camera Company&quot;, it is difficult to imagine that it was designed by Zhdanov, a Russian Jewish architect who has lived in Harbin for 37 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Red Army Street and the east-west Dazhi Street once intersected at the ancient Gothic wooden structure St. Nicholas Church. Nowadays, there is no trace of the Church of San Nicola. The International Hotel built in 1937 looks like a huge accordion. Opposite it is the former Italian Consulate, the Gibelosso building built in 1919, which is full of exquisite reliefs. The octagonal exterior walls are stacked upward layer by layer to form a lovely eclectic building dominated by Baroque style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another group of &quot;solemn vs. cute&quot; buildings is on Dazhi Street. The famous &quot;big stone house&quot; Harbin Railway Bureau Office Building was completed in February 1904 as the Middle East Railway Administration. Magnificent, majestic and dignified, it is like a &quot;huge castle&quot;; the Harbin Railway Museum, just across the street, has a simple interior decoration, while the exterior maintains the yellow and white colors from its days as the Middle East Railway Club, full of joy. breath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lama Terrace&quot; where St. Nicholas Church is located is the highest point in Harbin. It can be protected from floods when the Songhua River rises. Therefore, starting in 1899, Russia began to regulate the location of this place. The Qinjiagang area (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Nangang District&lt;/span>;) is undergoing large-scale urban construction. Within five years, the China Eastern Railway Administration Building and the Moscow Shopping Mall Building were built. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Heilongjiang Provincial Museum&lt;/span>;) and other European-style buildings were completed, and the east-west axis of Qinjiagang - Horvat Street, Dazhi Street and Main streets such as the New Business Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today&#39;s Guogol Street&lt;/span>;) were built. In the 1930s, the Qinjiagang area had &quot;grand buildings, neat streets&quot;, &quot;fresh air and fragrant flowers&quot;. Most foreign consulates were concentrated here, becoming Harbin&#39;s administrative center and a gathering place for foreigners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiulin Company located in Nangang District today&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;East and West The various subsystems of Fang civilization collide, rub, infiltrate, and blend with each other here. The unprecedented integration of the architectural culture of various ethnic groups in the world presents a &quot;cross-communication of multiculturalism.&quot; The Middle East Railway brought a large number of overseas Chinese - according to statistics, in 1923, the total population of Harbin reached 400,000, with nearly 200,000 overseas Chinese and more than 180,000 Chinese. Twenty or thirty years after the Russo-Japanese War, Harbin has become an international city. It brought Russian culture, Jewish culture, Japanese culture, Tatar culture... and nearly 70 churches including St. Nicholas Church, St. Sophia Church, and the Church of the Annunciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhdanov is to Harbin what Hudec is to Shanghai. Among the three churches &quot;clustered&quot; on Dongdazhi Street, the Church of Our Lady of Saints and Saints designed by Zhdanov (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Church of Our Lady of Protection&lt;/span >;) is the most eye-catching. This Byzantine-style church is said to have preserved the 2,600-kilogram bell that was cast in Moscow in 1899, but it is not available to see now. What can be seen is the notice board erected next to the church: &quot;Please pay attention to your behavior, God is working.&quot; Watching you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Church: Bells Echoing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the Virgin Mary Church, which is located on the busy main road of the city, the Tatar Church, also designed by Zhdanov The Tai Mosque is hidden among the residential buildings on Tongjiang Street. The red and white walls are full of Byzantine style of quiet and dignified temperament. It is like a &quot;mysterious little castle&quot;. Especially at dusk, it has a sense of simplicity. From 1899, when the first Russian Jew, S. I. Berzeri, came to Harbin to the 1940s, countless Jews came to this &quot;second home&quot; and built buildings here, including a hexagonal church with a dome holding up the Shield of David. Many Jewish buildings including the Star Synagogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tatar Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least a hundred years ago, the majestic The bells once echoed over Harbin. In the sound of the bells, expatriates from all over the world, adventurers and exiles of all kinds stopped to listen and found a moment of solace in their hometown in this foreign land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symbol of Harbin - St. Sophia Church, the melodious bells played on important religious festivals can be said to be the deep memory of the city for the older generation of Harbin people. It is said that in the church on a snowy day in winter, the Byzantine-style appearance can allow more snow to stay on the surface of the building. The wind blows the snowflakes, which are like the ultimate romance in a crystal ball; on a snowy night, the church will turn into gold bricks. The castle with bright tiles and the towering cross are like stars in the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hagia Sophia on a snowy night, the scenery is as dreamy as a crystal ball. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to observe the details of the church quietly, the best time is at dusk. The full dark green dome full of momentum is lifted very high by the main body of the clear red brick building. The golden cross shines brightly, showing a dynamic beauty of rising successively. Viewed from the side, the tops of the four tents are staggered, and the slanting light shines on it. The architectural details cast mysterious shadows, honest and simple. Step into the church and enjoy the daily rotating concerts, as well as the mottled walls and Roman-style arched windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting sun reflects on the top of the church, which reminds people of its sister with the same name on the other side of the Eurasian continent, and also allows people to relive the rich history of the city&#39;s past. In fact, this church had &quot;humble origins&quot; and was only the military chapel of the 4th Infantry Division of Tsarist Russia in Eastern Siberia. In March 1907, it was renovated with funds from the Russian businessman Cheschakov, whose home was on Red Army Street. In 1912 A layer of bricks was laid on the original foundation. In 1923, the Russian architect Kasikov re-selected a site in the southeast corner of the old church and built it. It was completed in November 1932, giving it what it looks like today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Concert in Saint Sophia Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saint Sophia The architectural style and decorative style of the church draw on the Russian brick carving art of the 17th century. The St. Alexeev Church at the corner of Gogol Street and Shikes Street organically combines a huge building volume with facade brick decoration. Giving it a strong Russian accent and unique mood. Although this century-old building, which was originally an Orthodox church and was converted into a Catholic church in 1980, also has a majestic and scattered beauty. Even under the clear blue sky in the northeast, it can be regarded as the appearance of the city&#39;s architecture, but it is not as lively as Sofia Square. There are very few people around after sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lights&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: Chinese Baroque&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Qiulin Kvass rustles after opening the bottle cap. This famous drink looks like Beer, slightly red in color but with only 1% alcohol content, is very suitable for &quot;bottle blowing&quot; when traveling and hiking - such as walking from Alexeev Church, along Gogol Street to the L-shaped building built in 1908 A grand building with a light green tone - Qiulin Yangxing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many old buildings on Gogol Street, but while maintaining their former glory, they have inevitably declined and become dilapidated - just like Daowai District. To the north from the train station, east of the railway across the river, is the Daowai District, formerly known as &quot;Fujiadian&quot;, where immigrants from Shandong and Hebei settled in Guandong. Although it is one of the earliest urban centers in Harbin, due to the lack of complete and precise planning, in the 1930s the streets here were &quot;narrow and uneven&quot; and &quot;everywhere you go is so disgusting that you have to cover your nose and avoid it.&quot; &amp;nbsp;——The folk proverb at that time said: &quot;Nangang is heaven, inside the road is the world, and outside the road is hell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unique &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; architecture also grew here. Along the street, the Western Baroque facade is used, while incorporating the auspicious decorative patterns of traditional Chinese architecture. Iron railings or &quot;Guanyin bottle&quot;-style concrete railings are set up on the edge of the protruding platform. Stepping inside, it is purely a northern courtyard. The architectural shape combines earth and western elements, giving it its own charm. The Chinese Baroque neighborhood, which is mainly located on South Second and Third Streets and has been renovated into a tourist attraction, is lackluster. Many of the green brick streets and wide courtyards have been transformed into catering shops. They are more organized but lack the liveliness and prosperity of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; on Dong Jingyu Street in the neighborhood is the most authentic. Originally built in 1890, this long street was originally called Zhengyang Street. It is also the birthplace of Harbin&#39;s national commerce: Zhengyang Tower, Laodingfeng, Shiyitang, Daluoxin Department Store, Hengdeli, Tongji Shopping Mall... every inch of land Jin&#39;s Old Street used to be lined with businesses. At the intersection of Jingyu Street and Nantou Street, the four-story brick and wood structure Purification Hospital was built in 1920. It was formerly known as Tongyi Qinghuo Store. It is one of the masterpieces of &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot;: the swaying reliefs of vine flowers from Ioni The exterior walls of the sub-column and Corinthian columns are winding all the way down, and the gorgeous and luxurious style is unforgettable, fully reflecting the hope of fame of the national industrial and commercial people at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Purification Hospital located outside Laodao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All famous, Prosperity and bustle have their end. Today&#39;s Laodaowai has lost its popularity due to large-scale construction, and its decline is fully visible: dilapidated buildings can be seen along the street, and the roofs are covered with decaying grass, as if the old buildings are sighing; the cats and dogs wandering on the street look full of vicissitudes of life. Feeling; beside the ruins, you can occasionally see small electric cars with the sign of &quot;darning&quot;, which is a common livelihood for middle-aged and elderly women in the Northeast - sewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In old Harbin, if the window of &quot;Zhong&quot; is &quot;Zhengyang Street&quot;, the epitome of &quot;West&quot; is Central Street - in Xiao Hong&#39;s pen, the city street is like a &quot;complex and unclear color&quot; &quot;Map&quot;, Harbin today has similar characteristics - it is also a commercial street, Jingyu Street outside the road has become a large construction site, and Central Street inside the road, at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning, there are tourists wandering around carrying kvass bottles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Laodaowai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Night, spring night, Central Street is a night full of music. Music from homeless people, music from Japanese dance halls, music from foreign restaurants... After 7 o&#39;clock, in the middle of Central Street, at a crossroads, the loud loudspeaker screamed, this The singing almost resounded throughout the street.&quot; Xiao Hong once wrote about Central Street in &quot;Spring Hangs on the Treetops&quot;, with a lot of irony and banter; however, the &quot;gradually countless&quot; things she recorded were &quot;like long ropes pulled in the sun&quot; The bright lights, like a string of yellow copper bells, seem to be still hanging on the 1,450-meter-long Central Street, which starts from the Songhua River Flood Control Victory Memorial Tower in the north and ends at Jingwei Street in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On some side streets, it is quieter. The light of the street lamps imprints the shadows of the leaves on the road. The aging Russians are talking about the good days that no longer exist. ... In You may think it is ugly during the day, but on a beautiful night, you put beautiful clothes on everything, and everything seems to be beautiful.&quot; The shorter streets in Jin&#39;s works form a fish-like formation with the Central Street. The bone-shaped street layout supported the &quot;enchanting&quot; appearance of this street after the completion of the China-Eastern Railway in 1903, where foreign merchants gathered and shops were dotted; especially in 1924, the Russian engineer Komut Rashok was responsible for the design and supervision of the construction. After the rectangular bread-shaped granite pavement was replaced, the bread stone road replaced the muddy dirt road. The appearance of the street was greatly changed, and it became rich and luxurious. In the 1930s, Central Street had become an architectural art gallery and an international architectural expo. Both sides of the street Most of them are Baroque, Gothic, Renaissance and other styles of buildings, creating a beautiful skyline; there are many foreign stores, dance halls and cinemas, restaurants and bars... At that time, Central Street became a place of pilgrimage for commodity fetishism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Street (today’s Central Street) is beginning to take shape&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the streets paved with square stones, the sound of Victorian carriages has long since passed into the twilight of history. Only the pieces of breadstone that have been worn away by the passing years are still shining brightly on today&#39;s pedestrian streets. Visitors tell stories about the smoky past of the long street - on summer evenings, the brilliant sunset shines slantingly on more than 70 European-style and imitation European-style buildings, and they seem to have their own unique character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Music: Soul of the North&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is also the Madiel popsicle that is essential when visiting Central Street - Matsuura 1918 West, which was renovated in the Matsuura Yoko Building. Diagonally across from the restaurant is Madiel&#39;s cold drink hall. Nowadays, &quot;Madiel&quot; can be eaten all over the country at different prices, but it is said that they are all &quot;a bit uninteresting&quot;. You still have to buy 5 yuan a piece here, which is made in the front store and in the back factory, without wrapping paper, which is the most authentic: In winter, the daily sales here start at 10,000 sticks, and sales usually explode on New Year&#39;s Day, with 30,000 to 40,000 sticks sold a day. During the peak tourist season in Harbin, &quot;Naked Madiel in the North Wind&quot; is one of the features of Central Street. Everyone wants to &quot;cool themselves down to the bottom.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After nibbling on the popsicles, you can turn around and taste the hot red cabbage soup, mandarin fish in milk and delicious canned shrimps at the Madier Western Restaurant - since the Russians started cooking pots in Tianjia in 1898 With the opening of railway canteens, Russian-style Western food began to take root in China. In the Central Street area alone, there are Tadaos and Huamei (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;former Mars There are more than 30 Western restaurants such as Western Food Tea Shop&lt;/span>;) and Madiel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The food and delicacies are endlessly memorable, especially when accompanied by music - whether in Matsuura, Huamei, or Madiel’s own Western restaurant on the first floor, Madiel can often be heard in the summer The music show on the balcony on the second floor of the hotel includes violin music, saxophone performance or bel canto solo. Artists who appeared to be from Central and Eastern Europe took turns performing hard, attracting tourists to stop and adding a lot of excitement to Central Street. It was also reminiscent of their &quot;predecessors&quot;, the foreign musicians who gathered here in the first half of the 20th century. : In 1936, singers Alexander Wilkinsky and Fedor Chaliapin came to Kazakhstan to hold a concert; in 1938, 10-year-old Helmut Stern came to China with his parents, and at the age of 14 He held a concert in Harbin and later joined the Harbin Symphony Orchestra, which was founded in 1908 and was once known as the &quot;First Symphony Orchestra in the Far East.&quot; After going to Israel in 1948, he became the chief violinist of the Berlin Philharmonic... Starting in the 1920s, Foreigners in Harbin have founded nearly 30 music schools. The strong music atmosphere that has lasted for a century has become an important cornerstone for Harbin to be awarded the title of &quot;City of Music&quot; by the United Nations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old view of Madier Hotel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Madiel Hotel Er&#39;s balcony music show is just a small note in the &quot;Music City&quot;. &quot;In the Madier Hotel, that hotel with a big stage and a luxurious hall, a play was organized between the movie screenings and a dance program was started... I happily put aside the boring rehearsals of the troupe and went to them specifically There.&quot; Dancer and poet Larisa Angell lived in China for 34 years and often performed at the Madier Hotel founded by Russian Jew Joseph Kasper in 1906. Her beautiful figure and summer Photos of Ryabin and Wilkinski, as well as tableware, lamps, electrical appliances, accessories, and promotional posters of Madier Cinema, together form the &quot;historical and cultural corridor&quot; in the hotel; during her years of activeness in Harbin , this very ancient building on Central Street is regarded as &quot;having the most luxurious ballroom and restaurant, the most modern and comfortable guest rooms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the scenery of the Madier Hotel was unparalleled, until the &quot;Casper Kidnapping Case&quot; that shocked Harbin in 1933 came to an abrupt end. On the evening of August 24 of that year, after dining at the Madier Western Restaurant, Simon, the son of Joseph Kasper Sr., was kidnapped by the Inspector General of the Kazakhstan Police Department, Martinov, and 15 gangsters; on December 3, Simon’s body was found It was discovered in Xiaoling near Harbin, causing an outcry. The following year, the sad old Joseph took his wife and children and left for France. Soon he died of illness in Paris. Madier also declined from glory to glory. Only the leather bag left by Casper in the &quot;Historical and Cultural Corridor&quot; of the hotel can be traced. Talk about being a witness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 25, 1948, representatives of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and democrats such as Shen Junru and Zhang Bojun in Kazakhstan reached an &quot;Agreement on Various Issues Concerning the Convening of a New Political Consultative Conference&quot; in the No. 1 conference room of the Madier Hotel. . At that time, the 73-year-old &quot;Heng Lao&quot; Shen Junru lived in a hotel and often went for walks along the Songhua River. He saw the rare scene of the river freezing and then thawing again, so he wrote a poem: &quot;After the river freezes, I see rushing water and snow. Even the tide is not full. The atmosphere of the earth also changes with people and events. From now on, geese from the north no longer have to go south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Dormition Church in the Cultural Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south bank of the Songhua River at the end of Central Street is Stalin Park, a narrow and long &quot;riverside&quot;. From here you can You can enjoy the scenery of the river that is sometimes rapid and sometimes gentle, touch the soul of the northern city, and feel the carnival atmosphere of the &quot;Harbin Summer&quot; concert that has been held for more than 60 years in the summer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rivers and songs flow into the distance, deposited over hundreds of years. Harbin is like a sponge, absorbing all sounds, while those mottled old buildings become witnesses of the city&#39;s historical changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province publicly announced the verdict of the original party group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress In the case of member and deputy director Gong Jianhua accepting bribes, the defendant Gong Jianhua was sentenced to 15 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 5.5 million; the bribery income of Gong Jianhua and his The interest shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2004 to 2020, the defendant Gong Jianhua used his position as deputy secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, executive deputy mayor, leader of the Nanchang Municipal Planning Land Operation Leading Group, deputy secretary of the Yichun Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, and municipal Chairman, Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, Secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers or status, provide relevant individuals with land listing, project contracting, and project development. Provided assistance with matters such as job promotion and job promotion, and illegally received property equivalent to more than RMB 83.61 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the defendant Gong Jianhua’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes, and the amount of bribes he accepted was particularly huge.鉴于龚建华主动投案后如实供述罪行，主动交代办案机关尚未掌握的部分受贿事实，具有自首情节，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，受贿所得及其孳息已全部查封、扣押、冻结到案，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其依法可从轻处罚。 The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3 nh27B3yxPJUsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, during an academic conference, Li Wei (pseudonym), a professor at the School of Physical Education of Shihezi University, casually agreed to a friend’s request for a paper name. It was a paper related to swimming. In 2021, a third-party agency discovered that the paper was suspected of being synthesized by reverse translation software and reported it to the Ministry of Education for confirmation, and the Ministry of Education fed back the situation to Shihezi University. The school launched an investigation and sent a letter to the other school, and found that Li Wei, the corresponding author, had not previously known about the existence of this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei was punished and could not participate in various project applications and evaluations for three years. During the ongoing self-examination of academic misconduct in college theses and the cleanup of false claims, Li Wei was reported again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in late May 2023, many universities have successively announced the launch of self-examination and cleanup of academic misconduct in papers, requiring self-examination and cleanup of academic papers since January 2018. Previously, on April 27, 2023, the General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a self-examination notice, requiring universities and scientific research institutes to self-examine and clean up common academic misconduct including plagiarism, plagiarism, forged peer reviews, ghostwriting and investment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main purpose of self-examination is to reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers and strive to curb the increase. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a self-examination operation that was not intended to be made public. Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the notice only became known to the outside world because two universities posted the notice as an attachment online. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The self-examination document is “not public &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the notices issued by each school, the main objects of this self-examination are These are all academic papers published by teachers and students of the school as the first signed unit. The focus areas of self-examination are basically the same, and they are all relatively common academic misconduct. It mainly includes six categories: plagiarism, plagiarism, and duplication of publications; forging corresponding authors, forging or manipulating peer reviews; forging, fabricating, and tampering with experimental data and pictures, using one picture for multiple purposes, and selective use; buying, selling, and ghostwriting papers; and purchasing experiments. Research data; nominal phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the notice of the Ministry of Science and Technology, universities and scientific research institutes in all provinces should carry out self-examination and clean-up work. However, according to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, only nearly 30 universities, including Shihezi University, Qinghai University, and Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, have issued this notice on their official websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice was originally a non-public document, but it became known to the outside world after two universities posted it online as an attachment to the notice. In fact, the notice documents issued by the Jiangsu and Anhui Provincial Science and Technology Departments did state &quot;This matter will not be made public&quot; at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a top-down campaign to investigate academic misconduct. Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact nearly 30 universities that publicly released the notice. Among them, Shihezi University, Qinghai University, Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University were interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, different universities have slightly different self-examination methods. However, they all adopt the method of teachers filling in forms and reporting by themselves. The content of the form mainly contains the personal information of the self-examination teacher, such as position, school, research direction, etc., as well as paper information, including paper title, DOI/PMID, publication time, publication journal, author category, academic violations, etc. The college’s statistical researchers are required to screen academic papers published within the verification period, identify academic papers with the above six conditions, put forward rectification suggestions, and form a self-examination work summary report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specific inspection methods can be roughly divided into focused spot inspections and comprehensive inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University and Yanshan University adopted a comprehensive inventory approach. A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University told Southern Weekend reporters that they had comprehensively checked 8,671 papers signed by teachers at the school within the time limit. The school organized an investigation team. The teachers first filled in the self-examination form, and then the college compiled and submitted it. Finally, the school&#39;s scientific research office reported it to the XPCC Education Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Social Sciences Office of Yanshan University said that after the announcement, the secondary college organized teachers to conduct self-examinations and submit self-examination forms and commitment letters. The college issues a self-examination report based on the self-examination situation, which is finally summarized and reported by the Social Science Office. Southern Weekend reporters contacted some colleges of the school to inquire about the implementation status. Among them, a staff member from the office of the School of Construction Engineering and Mechanics confirmed the statement of the aforementioned person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinghai University and Southwest University of Science and Technology adopt focused spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that the school&#39;s Science and Technology Office takes the lead and adopts a two-level system. First, the college&#39;s professor committee organizes self-examination, and then the school inspection office conducts random inspections. Specific to different disciplines, the degree of rigor varies. For example, due to the subject characteristics of medicine, academic misconduct is prone to occur. The school conducted a census of more than 150 papers published by teachers from the clinical medical school between January 2022 and May 2023, while other disciplines were Spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然通知中要求是2018年1月至2023年5月，但前述负责老师表示，青海大学每年都有两次检查，分别在期中和年终，因此此次将2022年至今的论文作为重点再查一遍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why he adopted the method of focused spot checks was that Qinghai University’s strong disciplines are mainly agriculture and forestry. “Due to the plateau specificity, many papers do not have experiments and data, and cannot be copied from other places. Therefore, The probability of academic misconduct will be relatively small.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spot checks are conducted on a proportional basis. He gave an example, based on the total number of papers published by the college within the period, for example, 50 papers were published, and 10 papers were randomly checked, including the original data of the scientific research and whether the person named on the paper was a member of the research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology said that they mainly screen key papers, and others mainly rely on feedback and reports from school teachers and other staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Almost no problems were found&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of large-scale self-examination has little impact on This is the first time for many universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant officials from Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University stated that similar large-scale system self-examination work had not been carried out before. The person in charge of Southwest University of Science and Technology emphasized that issues such as academic misconduct and pseudonymity were previously mainly investigated and handled through reports from others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in most notices, the self-examination time left for teachers is about one month. At present, the self-examination work has basically been completed at the school level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some self-examination window periods are shorter. The Science and Technology Office of Shijiazhuang Railway University issued a notice on July 26, 2023, requiring each college to complete the self-examination and cleanup work before July 30. If problems are found, a summary form should be filled out in a timely manner and submitted to the Science and Technology Office, and remedial measures such as corrections and retractions should be taken, and &quot;no feedback after the deadline will be deemed as a paper without academic misconduct.&quot; They gave each college only four days for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the four schools interviewed, the result of the self-examination was “almost no problems.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕山大学的老师表示，自查工作在7月底就已完成，“没发现任何问题”，并强调，相关结果已经上报省教育厅。 Teachers from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology also said that the school has completed a preliminary screening and found no relevant violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether a self-examination report needs to be issued, a staff member from the office of the School of Architectural Engineering and Mechanics of Yanshan University said, “The school only requires us to fill in a self-examination form and issue a report if there are any problems, but our school should no problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, the teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that since inspections were organized twice a year before, no serious academic misconduct was found this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only exception is Shihezi University. They self-identified three illegal articles. The violations were improper naming, purchasing data, and repeated publication. They belonged to the School of Physical Education, School of Medicine, and School of Animal Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the improper listing and purchase data are illegal articles that have been investigated before this inspection. Although notices from the science and technology departments of many provinces stated that papers that have been investigated and dealt with may not be included in the scope of this self-examination. However, the teacher in charge of the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University believes that it &quot;still serves as a warning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to punish after investigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology stated that if problems are found during self-examination and cleanup, scientific researchers must promptly report to the unit and take remedial measures such as corrections and retractions. Those who comply with the lenient treatment circumstances specified in Article 34 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; may be given lenient treatment in accordance with the regulations; those who conceal or make false reports shall be punished in accordance with Article 3 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; Article 15 and other relevant regulations will be dealt with seriously and publicly announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University explained that the school has criticized and educated the teachers involved and required them not to apply for projects within three years. They are not allowed to be prioritized and receive talent titles, nor can they apply for science and technology projects. award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University will take lenient treatment for those who took the initiative to report in this self-examination.动物科技学院张小千、李劼在2019年发表《培养温度对嗜热链球菌抑制法检测结果的影响》一文。涉事老师当时分别向《黑龙江畜牧兽医》和《中国奶牛》两家期刊投递论文，其中《黑龙江畜牧兽医》为核心期刊。 2019年5月，《中国奶牛》率先将论文发表，4个月后，《黑龙江畜牧兽医》刊出此文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现重复发表后，论文作者曾反复与《中国奶牛》期刊负责人交涉，要求对方撤稿，但被拒。直到2023年7月，论文作者借由科技部的相关通知进行协商，对方最终同意撤稿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石河子大学科研处的老师表示，由于论文作者主动报告，且此前数次联系杂志社撤稿，因此处理方式上就从轻，仅批评教育。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;为何自查？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为何会有此次自上而下的大规模自查？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述科技部通知中对此的解释为，压实各单位主体责任，削减学术不端论文存量，着力遏制增量，引导科研人员强化科研诚信意识等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，自查的核心在于消除存量、遏制增量。前述接近科技部的人士解释，比如某位科研人员十年前买了一篇文章，要么已经发表用以申报职称获利，要么一直没用。如果没用的话，现在各种严打，只能憋着，一旦发表，没准哪天就会爆雷。不管怎样，他们都会忐忑不安。而自查清理是很好的机会，“就是给这些犯过错误的科研人员一个机会，不论当时是无知也好、侥幸也罢”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，也是给科研人员一个自查梳理的机会。 “梳理一下总归是好事，增强诚信意识，摸清家底，不至于出现被挂名却不自知的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于遏制增量，“如果知道大家都在盯着这个事，他们以后也不会再干了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述接近科技部的人士提及，由于是自查，有从轻减轻情形，“如果没有从中获利，甚至可以不予追究，不过批评肯定是要的”。他认为，自查更多起到教育和震慑的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，这并非首次开展清查。南方周末记者了解到，2022年也曾在部委层面开展过这项工作，目的是让相关部门和地方层面了解到部委对科研诚信工作的重视，但当时“并未公开”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于可能存在瞒报情况，前述接近科技部的人士表示，如果自查时没问题，而将来查出问题，且处于2018年至今的时间段内，那一定会加重处理，“这相当于对抗诚信检查”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拉长时间线看，自查背后，是近年逐渐多发的论文撤稿情况和趋严的科研诚信管理措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年4月20日，学术出版巨头施普林格发布声明称，107篇已发表于《肿瘤生物学》的论文因涉嫌同行评审造假而被撤稿。而这些涉事论文全部来自中国，发表时间为2012-2016年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科协当时发表意见，希望施普林格出版集团能够尽快完善内控机制，加强对期刊的管理，把问题论文处理在发表前，而不是发表之后一撤了之，同时高度警惕以经济利益为目的、与“第三方”机构有勾结的“掠夺性期刊”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月15日，美国恒祥咨询（Healsan Consulting LLC）发布《2022年SCI论文撤稿简报》。简报显示，截至2022年12月31日，全球范围内总共有41642篇SCI撤稿，其中中国19421篇。具体到2022年1月1日至2022年12月31日期间，全球有5488篇SCI撤稿，其中中国的撤稿数量为2879篇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对科研诚信的重视程度也日益提高。 2018年5月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅印发《关于进一步加强科研诚信建设的若干意见》。意见强调，要严厉打击严重违背科研诚信要求的行为，建立终身追究制度，一经发现，随时调查处理。这是首次以中央发文的形式，将科研诚信工作的重要性提到极高程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，2020年，科技进步法修订，进一步明确了科研失信的相关惩戒措施。 2022年，科技部等22个部门对《科研诚信案件调查处理规则（试行）》进行修订，使得科研失信行为的调查处理工作有了更为具体的处理规则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，从2018年开始，科技部每年陆续公布科研失信行为调查处理结果，2017至2019年各有一批处理结果，2020年有两批，2021年和2022年则公布了四批。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此轮自查之后将有后续。前述接近科技部的人士表示，尤其是一点问题都没查出来的，恰恰在重点关注范围内。 “这次盖着单位的红章来，一篇有问题的文章都没有，但如果之后频繁撤稿，或者被调查出现问题，那单位的主体责任肯定落实不到位，到时一定严肃查处。”他表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>