<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》专访，导演邱礼涛，“我要拍巨变的年代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259584]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1部手机配8个壳：当年轻人不换手机爱换手机壳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259376]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9sNwIITCv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9s NwIITCv2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a certain brand’s 1,999 yuan mobile phone case has caused heated discussion. Previously, a mobile phone with 8 mobile phone cases has also become a hot search topic, and discussions about mobile phone cases have become increasingly popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, it costs thousands of yuan to replace a mobile phone, but it may only cost a few yuan to replace a mobile phone case. The dazzling array of mobile phone cases has gradually become a Mobile phone replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moreover, young people seem to be less and less fond of changing their mobile phones. An iResearch consulting report shows that 79.5% of Generation Z change their mobile phones within 1 to 3 years. At the same time, a research report from Ping An Securities stated that the time it takes for Chinese users to change their phones has lengthened from 28 months to 43 months, reaching a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A mobile phone made of iron and a mobile phone case as smooth as water. Since 2017, the market size of mobile phone cases has continued to expand, doubling in five years. Different from the &quot;one machine and one shell&quot; of the elders, contemporary young people are keen to play &quot;dress up show&quot; on their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although a popular poll on Weibo shows that half of netizens will choose mobile phone cases with a price of less than 9.9 yuan, major mobile phone brands have embarked on a trend of skyrocketing mobile phone case prices. road. The lowest price of mobile phone cases sold on Apple&#39;s official website is 398 yuan, while Huawei&#39;s latest Mate 60 RS Extraordinary Master Edition mobile phone case, Star Diamond Smart Window Protective Cover, is priced at 1,999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;CASETiFY, known as the &quot;Hermès&quot; of mobile phone cases, is the best-selling Hello Kitty and Sanrio co-branded model on Taobao, priced at 439 yuan. More than 1,000 people placed orders. With the blessing of the star&#39;s same style effect, Zhao Lusi&#39;s same style, TNT&#39;s same style, etc. attract star-chasing girls to donate generously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mobile phone cases have also become a fashionable item in the DIY industry. Cream glue, acrylic, and diamond stickers are all materials that can never limit the imagination of mobile phone case modifications. In many DIY shops in Guangzhou, the cost of DIYing a mobile phone case is about 30 to 100 yuan, making it a new choice for many sisters&#39; gatherings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of many people, small mobile phone cases actually provide a space for self-expression. Young people can use mobile phone cases to find people who like the same anime, A close friend of the same celebrity, or some mobile phone cases themselves convey their own values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk to you about why young people are keen on &quot;wholesale&quot; mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255641&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/26/687c278ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /687c278ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /3314847adf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3314847adf.png&quot; data -key=&quot;255643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么钱买不来“父慈子孝”？富裕家庭面临价值观代际断裂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259531]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Youdao means that &quot;one can only know the etiquette by being practical&quot;. In the era of material abundance, the atmosphere within the family is relaxed, and &quot;the father is kind to the son.&quot; filial piety&quot;. Especially wealthy families or middle-class families with better economic conditions do not have the stress and oppression of material scarcity, and parents are able to provide their children with more choices and express their deep love. The better the economic conditions, the sweeter the relationship between relatives. This seems to be a law that needs no proof. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from many social news reports, this conclusion is quite unreliable. It seems that the family ties of wealthy or well-to-do middle-class families have not become generally better because of money. Discord between relatives is still quite common; the tense relationship between parents and children does not seem to be any better than in ordinary families. It can be seen that some problems cannot be solved by money alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the contemporary young &quot;old people&quot; or so-called &quot;professional children&quot; have good family backgrounds, and their parents are middle-class or above - otherwise they cannot support their family&#39;s long-term public and postgraduate entrance examinations. This kind of family atmosphere can be imagined. Most parents support and complain at the same time. Their children are bored and unable to leave. There were many cases where the quarrel was so loud that the family relationship was broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents who give large betrothal gifts and buy houses and cars for their children are essentially providing for them. The children are all adults and can take away a large amount of their parents&#39; property at once, which is rare in other countries. It would be fine if we could get a harmonious relationship, but the reality is often that the money is not enough, the support cannot be exchanged for gratitude, and family relationships become tense or even broken, which is a common farce or even tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the above are just the worries of ordinary middle-class families, are wealthy families (rich or wealthy middle-class families) better off? Not sure. In recent years, life has been difficult for some wealthy people, and many overseas students have experienced reduced or even cut-off funding. In a short period of time, there have been many complaints on Xiaohongshu: the standard of living has dropped, what you want to buy cannot be afforded, and the standards of accommodation and tourist hotels have been downgraded. Others complained about their parents and worried that their life studying abroad would be ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who can support their children to study abroad and enjoy a high standard of living are considered wealthy in China. The family has financial difficulties and has to cut back on children&#39;s expenses. This is probably the last resort for most parents to reduce expenses. These adult children did not feel anxious or worried about their parents, but instead focused on the small gains in front of them. This is so heartless and is enough to upset many parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the above cannot be inferred that poor families have better family relationships, but it is to point out that many families have substantial wealth accumulation, and parents pay more for their children, but they fail to get a better family. relation. When a new generation of young people witness this situation, their confidence in having children will be easily affected. Many people even think that raising children is completely wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did things come to this? Seeing this, traditionalists say: Filial piety has been lost. From the perspective of traditional ethics, many children&#39;s behavior can indeed be called unfilial, but this set of values ​​has no market in the contemporary era. Young people simply do not listen, and parents have no confidence to speak out. Blaming young people will not solve the problem at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essence of conflict between family members is still a conflict of values. In traditional society, several generations share a set of values ​​and have roughly the same lifestyle, but in modern society, this is different. Most parents represent traditional values, while their children are more up-to-date, so estrangement is inevitable. Especially in the past 100 years or so, China has been rapidly experiencing the disintegration of tradition. The generation gap between two and three generations is unprecedentedly deep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Value differences do not necessarily evolve into actual conflicts. The conflict between adult children and parents is also a game of voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as the children surpass their parents’ achievements and prove with facts that the later wave surpasses the previous wave, even if the parents are dissatisfied, it is just irrelevant nagging. After the parents retired safely, their differences finally disappeared and they became a harmonious relationship of &quot;father is kind and son is filial&quot;. After a poor family becomes prosperous, the relationship between father and son is still harmonious for the most part. The reason is that power is transferred smoothly within the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But not all children can surpass their parents’ achievements. Especially parents who succeeded in their early years and led their families into the ranks of affluence, their insight and ability are extraordinary, and their accumulated resource circle is beyond the reach of their fledgling children. On the one hand, parents work hard to provide resources for their children and help them grow; on the other hand, their achievements are difficult for future generations to overcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To give a simple example, both husband and wife are top academics, but there are actually very few children who can get into the school where their parents graduated. This is just one part of the exam. In the fierce social competition, it has become the norm that children cannot surpass excellent parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents are confident that the values ​​they believe in are still valid. This is the experience they rely on for success. They provide financial support to their children and provide guidance and criticism. The children are accustomed to a comfortable life and do not feel inappropriate about their parents&#39; support (once their parents refuse to support them, the children will inevitably resent it), but at the same time they have new ideas and can easily become disgusted with their parents&#39; instructions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we get older and our children grow older, the elders’ voice has been declining for a long time, and conflicts within the family are inevitable. In families with many children or in the classical era of primogeniture, conflicts will not be too intense - parents will use property inheritance rights to restrain their children, and the latter will consciously move closer to their parents. Contemporary trends are entirely detrimental to parents and beneficial to children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how powerful parents are, due to legal restrictions, their binding force on their children is destined to become weaker. The new generation of children are mostly only children, so they naturally inherit the family business. Even if the ability is low and the words and deeds are outrageous, there will be almost no substantive punishment. This emboldened them. It is not difficult to understand that rich people cannot control their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trend cannot be reversed. If wealthy families or wealthy middle-class families want to alleviate intergenerational conflicts, they can only fundamentally coordinate the values ​​of the two generations. The responsibility falls on parents: they need to pay special attention to their children&#39;s values. Especially as parents of entrepreneurs, they cannot only provide their children with favorable living conditions, but allow their values ​​to go into the opposite direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The job of an entrepreneur is to judge consumer needs, discover market gap opportunities, provide products and services smartly, and obtain benefits that exceed those of ordinary working-class people. Entrepreneurs do not do specific labor, but create wealth by organizing production and discovering opportunities. Sometimes it is hard to make a small amount of money, sometimes it is easy to make a big fortune. Entrepreneurs are both envied and often hated and misunderstood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Understanding the work of entrepreneurs requires long-term study and in-depth understanding. Classical entrepreneurs require long-term training to train successors, teach them through words and deeds, and examine their abilities and conduct. This is the process of value transfer. When contemporary entrepreneurs educate their children, most of them entrust their education to schools and provide them with all financial support instead of imparting values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Send their children to study abroad and receive elite or business school education, thinking that this will broaden their horizons and surpass their parents&#39; abilities. The result is obvious: the sons and daughters of entrepreneurs have been separated from the business world for a long time. They often only know how to consume and not produce, and finally show their mediocrity in real market competition. It is not uncommon for children to fall into depravity due to lack of parental restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary European and American education is the stronghold of far-left ideology, and campuses are filled with various &quot;progressive&quot; ideologies. Anti-capital, anti-corporate, anti-patriarchal, and anti-family ideas are prevalent. Rich Chinese send their children to study in the hope that they will inherit the family business. However, they are likely to usher in &quot;unworthy children.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Economist Mises analyzed this phenomenon in his book &quot;The Anti-Capitalist Mentality&quot;. In Mises&#39;s era, businessmen and entrepreneurs usually had many children and usually only one heir. They inherited the values ​​of their fathers and worked hard to manage their industries. The second son, evil son, illegitimate son or close relative child (such as nephew) who is &quot;abandoned&quot; by the family will lose the right to inheritance early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These people live a comfortable life and have a good education, but they are full of prejudices and misunderstandings about their fathers&#39; business operations. They are so arrogant that they think that through thinking and transformation, they can surpass their parents and those in charge of the industry. Mises called this phenomenon &quot;nephew&#39;s resentment.&quot; This can largely explain why in the era of great turmoil, some people who could live a comfortable life actually embarked on the path of &quot;rebellion&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although what contemporary entrepreneurs face is not so extreme, the phenomenon of value rupture is very similar. Worshiping elite education, ignoring the inheritance of family education, and intergenerational fractures in family values. To make matters worse, most contemporary entrepreneurs have few children, and the family business is in danger of having no successors. The elders are anxious but unable to do anything, while the children take it in stride. This difference in attitude exacerbates tensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[洞穴潜水圈里的门派江湖：关于金钱、性命和纪录的游戏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, the Jiudun skylight salvage site. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 16, 2023, Jiudun skylight salvage site. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiudun Skylight, which is well-known in the cave diving world, has another name - the source. People living in Daxing Town, Duan County, Guangxi call this underwater cave. It is connected to the underground river and is the birthplace of Chengjiang River, which runs from north to south and is 42 kilometers long. The surface of the water is unremarkable, a pool of clear water lies beside the national highway. Under the clear water, caves unique to karst landforms extend toward the center of the earth. As for the depth, it is still unexplored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deep and mysterious cave is shrouded in charming colors. Cave diving enthusiasts wearing black quick-drying suits and carrying air bottles gather here all year round. Wei Caifeng, a 58-year-old villager, opened a restaurant near the source, and divers are regular customers. She couldn&#39;t understand why these people were still keen to dive here if this cave was so dangerous. She counted on her fingers the divers who died here: one in 2022, two in 2021, one eight years ago, and including Han Ting in 2023, there are already five. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the most dangerous extreme sports, a small mistake can kill divers, but the dark cave still attracts them. It is a scenic spot but also an abyss; it is a playground and a fair of fame and fortune; it is a place where life flourishes and where death is quiet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Each breath costs 7 yuan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Han Ting went into the water for the last time, he ate egg fried rice from Wei Caifeng’s shop. At six or seven o&#39;clock in the evening on October 7, Wei Caifeng fried a pot of egg fried rice for eight people and brought it to the skylight for nine meals. She told Han Ting and his party to put the pot at the door of the store if they had time after eating. &quot;Han Ting comes to my house for dinner every time. He is very gentle and smiles every time he comes back. It is such a pity (this happened).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, to break the cave diving World record: 46-year-old Han Ting (nicknamed Lao Mao in the circle) died during diving training and his body fell on a slope about 113 meters deep in the North Cave of Jiudun Tianchuang. After losing contact for 18 days, the media followed up and reported that the life of this Zhejiang native, known as &quot;Asia&#39;s No. 1 Diver&quot;, began to become more widely known. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting’s unexpected death has made most people in the diving community feel sorry for him. But in this dangerous extreme sport, this result does not seem surprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Duan, there are many dangerous caves like Jiudun Skylight. As a member of the Guangxi underground cave exploration project, 43-year-old Wei Jie often looks for such underwater caves everywhere. He claims to have visited about 150 caves, 80% of which are untouched. Domestic cave diving started relatively late, only starting around 2010. &quot;It is still in its infancy. The United States started in the 1970s, and we are 40 years behind others,&quot; Wei Jie said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie said that there are many natural caves available for diving in Guangxi, such as Liuzhou, Guilin and other cities. The average cave depth is about 80 meters, while the average depth of the famous Duan is about 300 meters. Many cave diving enthusiasts told Southern Weekend reporters that domestically, Du&#39;an&#39;s cave resources are ranked first. Compared with international comparisons, &quot;Du&#39;an&#39;s cave diving is relatively difficult.&quot; The underwater visibility is average. The cave is too deep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of technical diving, cave diving and deep diving have higher risks. Xu Tianhua, who started technical diving in 2018, told Southern Weekend reporters that his foreign diving instructor was invited to Du&#39;an more than ten years ago to conduct a cave evaluation to see whether it was suitable for development into a tourist resource. The assessment concluded that it is not suitable for large-scale promotion, &quot;the depth is too deep and the risk is very high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the high risk, the high investment of time and money also makes this sport more difficult to promote. Many interviewees said that they have spent up to one million yuan on diving in the past few years. In addition to purchasing training courses, equipment, and various expenses incurred by diving around the world, there are also some consumables, such as Helium. The cylinders used by divers to dive contain a mixture of compressed gases, mostly containing oxygen, nitrogen and helium. The market price of helium is about 7 cents/liter. When a diver dives to 100 meters, each breath he takes costs about 7 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie said frankly that in the cave diving circle, cave diving enthusiasts who do not make a living as instructors are mostly high-net-worth individuals. They often come from first-tier cities. There are some self-employed coal and mining bosses. Most of them are over 35 years old, and of course there are some young rich second generations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high threshold has made cave diving a veritable niche extreme sport. According to many people in the cave diving circle, there are only about 100 active divers in China with full cave diving licenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not every cave dive is a desperate effort&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Jiang Yuchen from Beijing did not expect that he would embark on the path of cave diving. Six years ago, he and his mother started diving together as diving partners. At that time, he suffered from depression, and diving was used as a long-term and effective treatment for him. He described that after diving into the cave, it was like returning to his mother&#39;s womb and feeling very peaceful. But things are not calm above the water. Jiang Yuchen can often see his disapproving and angry remarks in the news about cave divers’ accidents: “They say we are full of food and are seeking death, and we are irresponsible.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie pessimistically believes that Dongqian is meaningless except for the value of &quot;self-realization&quot;. In his opinion, underwater archeology, salvage, and construction are valuable, but their normal diving does not involve these. “It’s all for fun. Your actions are not of any help to this society, but only satisfy yourself. Many of us It’s time to dive for the sake of diving.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after entering the cave, Wei Jie seemed to have left the &quot;theory of meaning&quot; behind. He described it to a Southern Weekend reporter as the pleasure of being in an uninhabited land: &quot;Maybe you are the first to arrive. Human beings here, every ray of your light is the first ray of light that the world shines on this cave, or even the only ray of light.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from Wei Jie&#39;s &quot;meaningless&quot; view, the same Li Wen, an enthusiast, believes that cave diving is not only exciting, but also very rigorous. &quot;Rigorous means that this is not a competitive sport, not about who is stronger or who is more powerful, but a management sport. It is about yourself.&quot; A movement to get yourself into a better state.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 18, 2023, in a cave in Du&#39;an County, Li Wen and his party were preparing to dive. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023 , in a cave in Duan County, Li Wen and his party were preparing to dive. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For cave diving, every enthusiast has his or her own reasons and pursuits. Some people do it to see fish, some people do it for healing, and some people do it to break through themselves. &quot;Different starting points will lead to different final results.&quot; said a cave diving enthusiast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all interviewees agreed that although most cave diving is dangerous, the risks are controllable and even safe. Xu Tianhua said that every time he goes into the water, he takes into account the risks he faces and has various methods to deal with the risks. &quot;It&#39;s not what you imagine. Every dive seems to be like trying your best.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Once something goes wrong, we will withdraw according to the emergency plan and will not stay there. The hole is there There, whether you dive today or tomorrow, it is all there, it doesn&#39;t matter if it happens overnight.&quot; Wei Jie agreed with Han Ting&#39;s previous point of view, &quot;Cave diving is an art of giving up. You can give up any dive at any time, but never Don&#39;t give up on yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Risks are not static. For Han Ting, the Asian cave diving record holder, challenging the world record means challenging the limits of mankind, and with the arrival of the limit comes incalculable unknown risks. &quot;Risks and challenges coexist. It&#39;s like a scale, self-fulfillment or self-destruction, whichever side leans more,&quot; Wei Jie said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Challenging the limits is not acceptable to all cave diving enthusiasts. &quot;Competitiveness and desire are called bad motives for us and should be avoided. If your purpose of diving is for performance, then you may not be suitable for our philosophy.&quot; Li Wen is 39 years old and has 10 years of cave diving. experience, but he refused to reveal his deepest dive record - &quot;I don&#39;t think this is something worth publicizing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four sects, two differences&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this concept The difference is due to different cave diving systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, there are four active cave diving systems in China, namely PASI, TDI, IANTD and WUD. Except for WUD, which is a domestically created system, the other three are all originated from abroad. Li Wen said that different systems have different concepts of cave diving, and the training process is also slightly different, but &quot;almost 95% are the same.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the number of people in the water as an example. Systems such as WUD emphasize the importance of the team and stipulate that there must be two or more divers traveling together. But in the PASI system and TDI system where Han Ting works, divers have more opportunities to dive alone. &quot;As long as there are two people involved in the potential accident like the old cat&#39;s accident, it may not necessarily happen.&quot; analyzed Wei Jie, who is a member of the WUD system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Tianhua feels that &quot;it is difficult to find divers of the same level to form a team to dive at depths like Laomao.&quot; Xiao Liang, who has taken Han Ting diving courses and belongs to the TDI system, believes that when diving in a &quot;small space and large depth&quot;, the matching of divers&#39; abilities is also very important. &quot;If the abilities do not match, the two together will not be able to survive.&quot; Take care of another person. Sometimes it’s safer to be alone.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small circle of about a hundred people, apart from whether to allow solo diving, another major disagreement lies in whether to pursue depth. Many interviewees admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that there is indeed a trend of comparison in the industry. &quot;There was also an era abroad that pursued depth, but it seems to be gone now,&quot; Li Wen said. Wei Jie said bluntly: &quot;No one is convinced by the other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to different systems, this small circle has formed different &quot;sects&quot;. &quot;Let me make an analogy, just like the movie &#39;Young and Dangerous&#39;, each gang has a celebrity, and there are many younger brothers under the celebrity, that is, followers.&quot; Xiao Liang said. However, not everyone is keen to follow the &quot;sect&quot;, and some enthusiasts also play by themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, Li Wen and a group of five people were diving in an underwater cave in Duan County. The four people accompanying them were from three different systems. &quot;This sport itself is very niche, and there are not many people who can play together. People from different organizations are all the same enthusiasts. It is fate in itself, and it is also rare.&quot; Li Wen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Jiang Yuchen has 2 years of experience in cave diving. His deepest dive record is 101 meters. At the age of 20, he became the youngest X-CCR (a closed circuit respiration) in TDI (China). device) diver. Jiang Yuchen admitted that he does pursue depth, but he doesn&#39;t care about depth as much as others. &quot;Because I am still very young, I will have at least 30 more years to do high-difficulty diving.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Yuchen feels that 50 years old is a hurdle. He explained that after the age of 50, various body functions will age, and metabolism will decline. The slower speed means that the body&#39;s efficiency in emitting inert gases such as nitrogen will also decrease, making it difficult to do long-term and difficult dives, &quot;such as breaking records.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day Han Ting had the accident, he was three days away from his 47th birthday. In 2020, 44-year-old Han Ting dived to 234 meters in Jiudun Skylight, setting an Asian cave diving depth record. This Asian record was broken by WUD member Chen Qian in Jiudun Skylight on March 30, 2023, setting the deepest record of 258 meters. But in just the past 28 days, this depth has been refreshed again. On April 27, 2023, Han Ting set an Asian record of 277 meters at Jiudun Skylight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As team support for Chen Qian’s Asian record, Wei Jie denied that they were pursuing depth. “This number is very meaningful to him (Chen Qian) because May 8 is It was his wife’s birthday. He dived to this depth to commemorate his deceased wife.” Regarding Han Ting breaking the record in less than a month, Wei Jie said: “We are not convinced, so why should we be? The purpose of commemoration has been achieved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie analyzed that the reason why Han Ting chased the record so quickly may be because of commercial promotion. Before Chen Qian broke the record, Han Ting once appeared at a product launch conference as the holder of the Asian cave diving depth record. &quot;If he was not the number one in Asia when that product was launched, it might be troublesome, because he was the number one in Asia at that time. Here with us&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter obtained an investment plan marked &quot;Blue Flag Diving&quot;. Blue Flag Diving is a diving club founded by Han Ting and others in 2014. The plan shows that as the head coach of Blue Flag Diving, Han Ting will challenge the world record at Jiudun Skylight in October 2023. At that time, the Guinness World Records Certification Officer will be invited to the site in person and the challenge process will be broadcast live on multiple platforms. &quot;We will Make it a widely spread traffic portal for extreme sports.&quot; The plan promises that after reaching cooperation with the brand, &quot;Coach Han will record a promotional video for each partner.&quot; As of press time, Blue Flag Diving Club staff had not responded to Southern Weekend reporters on the authenticity of the plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Han Ting. Picture from the official website of China Exploration Association&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Ting. The picture comes from the official website of the China Exploration Association&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beacon placement and wiring&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the domestic cave diving circle, the desire for records does not only occur at the tip of the pyramid, nor does it only occur at the depth. Jiang Yuchen told Southern Weekend reporters that in some mature caves abroad, there are almost no personal belongings, but in Jiudun Skylight, there are many signs with the names of divers. These signs wrapped around the leash usually appear at depths below 100 meters because they are not interesting in shallow water. &quot;For example, if you put one at 100 meters, and someone else puts one at 120 meters, then he must be better than you.&quot; Jiang Yuchen said frankly that this kind of behavior can easily lead to comparison and competition in the circle, &quot;This is true in any system. It is not worth promoting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting also missed the bid in Jiudun Skylight. In a video posted by Han Ting on Weibo, when he reached the target depth of 277 meters, he stopped diving as planned, tied a knot, locked the line, and placed an arrow mark. The orange triangular arrow mark said &quot;DJ&quot;. &quot;It was to commemorate his friend Dong Jie, so it was Dong Jie&#39;s name.&quot; Jiang Yuchen said. On September 26, 2022, Dong Jie and a diving companion died here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the many markings, the lines of the Jiudun skylight are also messy. Many interviewees said that when diving into a cave, you must pull the guide wire, which is one of the safety measures to ensure the return trip. If there is already a main line in a cave, the diver can dive along the already laid main line without pulling the line. &quot;Usually, we will respect the main line that was laid out first. Unless the line is pulled very unreasonably, we will make corrections based on it.&quot; Wei Jie introduced that in 2015, a Frenchman laid the main line in Jiudun Skylight. Later, Many teams in China went in to do wiring, but &quot;the wiring was too messy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person with the power to lay the main line is usually the first diver to enter the cave. However, in pursuit of being first, some divers will tear off the main line, re-route it, and claim to be the first person to explore the cave. Jiang Yuchen said that this approach is excessive. His ultimate goal is to discover unknown caves, explore and map them, post a sign without any personal identification, and then tell everyone from the bottom of his heart that diving is possible here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many interviewees pointed out that the uneven level of cave diving instructors is also one of the reasons for the frequent occurrences in the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie, who has 10 years of experience in teaching cave diving, gave an example. His system requires instructors to dive in the teaching cave at least 100 times and be able to exit the cave safely without lights or guide ropes. Become a coach, but many people become coaches without meeting this standard. &quot;If they are not familiar with it themselves, then the risk is very high if they teach others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the diving field, it is very important to meet a capable and responsible instructor, because students&#39; understanding of diving is easily influenced by the instructor, and usually, this understanding is directly linked to safety. . If you want to evaluate a coach&#39;s ability, Xiao Liang suggests asking him three questions: How many people have you taught? How many years of diving and teaching experience do you have? How much did you spend on diving? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike driving school instructors, diving instructors have the power to judge whether students meet the standards and whether they can issue certificates. &quot;If the coach says you are good, you can be good. If the coach says you are not good, you can&#39;t. But the level of coaches is different, which will cause bias between systems. In fact, it is not a problem with the system at all. It is when people have problems that the system will appear. There is a problem.&quot; Xiao Liang explained that the current cave diving system mostly comes from abroad and is only for management coaches, so the coach has great power. &quot;He is the person who leads you into the diving world, and your knowledge is also based on this coach.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Liang took Han Ting&#39;s class three years ago. He commented that Han Ting was a good coach. &quot;His ability is among the top in the country. He is serious in class and takes care of everyone. He is the type that most people will like and recognize.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In the end, it is robot salvage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Having The diving circle composed of enthusiasts with different purposes, different concepts, and different systems can hardly be said to be a community. Showing a difference when they face the death of their peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of Han Ting&#39;s accident, some insiders said they were not surprised, but more interviewees expressed regret for Han Ting&#39;s death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;It was an underwater robot that finally salvaged Han Ting&#39;s body. The picture shows the staff operating the robot underwater. Photo provided by Deep Blue&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The person who finally salvaged Han Ting&#39;s body was under water robot. The picture shows the staff operating the robot underwater. Photo courtesy of Deep Blue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Han Ting’s family faced was a more practical problem. On the 13th day after Han Ting&#39;s death, that is, October 20, the body had not yet been recovered. Han Ting&#39;s brother and sister-in-law told Southern Weekend reporters that retrieving the body was a very complicated and dangerous matter. &quot;Considering safety issues, in principle, Domestic divers will no longer be accepted for salvage work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on the eighth day after Han Ting&#39;s death, a total of 14 divers went into the water to recover the body, but they all failed. Sister-in-law Han Ting began to understand what Han Ting said - when the day comes when I can&#39;t come back, you don&#39;t come to fish for me. &quot;He may have thought at that time that if something happened to him, he would be in a very deep place, and no one in the country could fish him out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wen has experience in salvaging the remains of divers. He analyzed that, Salvage at a depth of 113 meters, &quot;although it is within the capabilities of human divers, is indeed on the edge.&quot; He had made preparations before, &quot;If there is help over there, I can go there at any time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wen explained that aside from the risks of caves and large depths, a simple salvage mission is already very risky. &quot;We use CCR respirators when we go down. CCRs naturally have buoyancy changes. If I bring him up, it is equivalent to a person driving a car with eight steering wheels. It will be dangerous if any steering wheel is not noticed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the family’s statement that they will no longer accept help from domestic divers, some interviewees in interviews with Southern Weekend reporters felt that it was not just a professional opinion. An interviewee who did not want to be named told a reporter from Southern Weekend: &quot;There was a problem with Lao Mao underwater. The people from their organization did not fish it out, but people from other organizations went to fish it out. For them, this facade will also be a little bit... Question.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting&#39;s body is located at a depth of 113 meters. Wei Jie believes that there are six or seven people in China who have the ability to salvage him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is surprising is that the final plan is not to salvage with divers, nor to salvage with man-machine cooperation, but only with robots in the water. On October 25, 2023, on the 18th day after Han Ting&#39;s death, two underwater robots brought Han Ting&#39;s body ashore. Sun Yan, the Deep Blue robot operator in charge of the salvage mission, told Southern Weekend reporters that the underwater north cave has a narrow terrain and the south cave is wider to meet the salvage needs, so it was decided to use two underwater robots to work together to lift the victims from the north cave. Salvage will be carried out after moving to the south cave to avoid collisions among the victims during the salvage process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, the salvage team successfully operated, and Han Ting’s body was brought out of the water 18 days after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Li Wen, Wei Jie, Xu Tianhua, and Xiao Liang are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多省辟谣“推行工龄退休”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Source: Shandong People Social Media&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, an article titled &quot;Shandong Province will implement a &quot;service-age retirement&quot; system&quot; and related screenshots were spread online in a small number of WeChat groups, WeChat Moments, and self-media. After verification, the article and related screenshots were found to be false information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shandong Province strictly implements the retirement policy uniformly stipulated by the state. There is no &quot;retirement based on seniority&quot; as stated in online articles and related screenshots. Please do not believe or spread rumors. We reserve the right to hold relevant rumor makers accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public policies issued by the Shandong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security will be released to the public through our department’s portal website and the “Shandong Human Resources and Social Security” WeChat public account. Thank you for your continued attention and support to the work of Shandong Human Resources and Social Security! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;Shandong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;October 29, 2023&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Source: Hebei People&#39;s Society&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Recently, an article titled &quot;Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security: Hebei Province will implement the &quot;retirement based on seniority&quot; policy from January 1, 2024&quot; and articles and screenshots of similar content have been posted in a few WeChat groups, WeChat Moments, Distributed online through self-media and other media. After verification, the relevant articles and screenshots were found to be false information. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hebei Province strictly implements the retirement policy uniformly stipulated by the state. There is no such thing as &quot;retirement based on seniority&quot; as stated in online articles and related screenshots. Please do not believe the rumors. Don&#39;t spread rumors. We will reserve the right to hold relevant rumor makers accountable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Public policies issued by the Hebei Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security will be released to the outside world through the Hebei Human Resources and Social Security Network and the &quot;Hebei Human Resources and Social Security&quot; WeChat public account. Thank you for your continued support of the Hebei People Social work’s attention and support! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Source: Sichuan People&#39;s Society&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently , an article titled &quot;Department of Human Resources and Social Security: Sichuan Province will implement &quot;retirement based on working age&quot; and will be fully implemented on January 1, 2024&quot; and related screenshots were spread online in a small number of WeChat groups, WeChat Moments, and self-media. . After verification, the article and related screenshots were found to be false information. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sichuan Province strictly implements the retirement policy uniformly stipulated by the state. There is no such thing as &quot;retirement based on seniority&quot; as stated in online articles and related screenshots. Please do not believe the rumors. Don&#39;t spread rumors. We reserve the right to hold relevant rumor makers accountable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Public policies issued by the Sichuan Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security will be released to the public through our department’s portal website and the “Sichuan People and Social Security” WeChat public account. Thank you for your continued support of Sichuan people. Social work’s attention and support! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Sichuan Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right ;&quot;>;&lt;span>;October 27, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[朱哲琴：见山还是山]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259472]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi8FeyCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;703&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi 8FeyCC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhu Zheqin was a teenager, he dreamed of becoming a traveler. A few years later, she won the second prize in popular singing in the professional group of the Youth Singing Competition. If she embarks on the path of an acting singer, she can choose from many record companies, performance opportunities, and gain both fame and fortune; she can also leave everything behind and pursue what she really wants to do, but she doesn&#39;t know what she wants to do at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1991, the year after participating in the Youth Singing Competition, 23-year-old Zhu Zheqin left Guangzhou for Chengdu, still determined to be a tour guide. Her collaborator at the time and for many years to come, the composer He Xuntian, was a little angry and said it was a pity that she didn&#39;t sing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although she failed to become a traveler, she later went to India, Bhutan, Nepal, Tibet, Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, Guizhou, and Xinjiang to collect music. Her singing has also gone far. Her first album &quot;Yellow Child&quot; (1992) showed artistic qualities in addition to popular singing. &quot;A Sister&#39;s Drum&quot; (1995) was published in 56 countries, becoming the first A Chinese album released globally, with &quot;Yangjinma&quot; (1997), the scope expanded to 65 countries. In the wave of New Age Music that emerged at the end of the 20th century, Zhu Zheqin is a representative figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes she attributes herself to the laws of history - her popularity in the 1990s coincided with people&#39;s pursuit of spirituality after their material life was abundant. Sometimes she just said that people are really strange. What is a living thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took her a long time to figure out what she wanted to do. During this period, he released 6 albums, including a live recording album, held a world tour, served as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program, and initiated goodwill actions and original design platforms based on the protection and inheritance of Chinese traditional music and handicrafts. Then, by chance, I started sound art and have been creating it happily ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, social activities and artistic creation caused her to become relatively quiet in the field of music performance. After not giving a concert for nearly ten years, on September 30, 2023, she performed new music and sound art works, including a small concert, at the Aranya Jinshanling Community in Chengde, Hebei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I haven&#39;t sung for you for a long time.&quot; I saw her on the second day of the performance. We walked into a meditation room at the foot of the mountain. She took off her shoes and coat, and her black body disappeared on the gradually dimming tatami. Most of the lighting in this room comes from a floor-to-ceiling window. Outside the window is the dry landscape, only a sliver of sky is exposed, and dusk is approaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;A long-lost slightly impromptu concert&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from July, at the invitation of Aranya, Zhu Zheqin stayed in Jinshanling for three months to create music and sound art. It is located at the junction of Beijing and Hebei. The ridge is dotted with ruins of the Great Wall of the Ming Dynasty, which are ruined and mixed with rubble. To the southwest is the capital city, where the forests are gradually dyed in autumn. The Jinshanling area is inhabited by aboriginal mountain people, and real estate development has attracted many &quot;new mountain people&quot; to buy homes or travel with their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intentionally or unintentionally, Ma Yin, the founder of Aranya brand, wants to create a paradise here. First of all, transportation here is inconvenient, and secondly, it is extremely close to nature. At a dinner party and a conversation, Ma Yindu said: In the next ten years or more, we will spend more time in pain than happiness in our lives, so warming people&#39;s hearts may be a mainstream thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin’s exhibition will be completed in two landmark buildings in Aranya Jinshanling. One is the upper courtyard designed by architect Liu Yichun. It is built according to the mountain and is composed of a courtyard, a terrace and a hall. It is the spiritual highland of the community. One is the Valley Concert Hall designed by architects Li Hu and Huang Wenjing. It looks like a boulder and an alien object from the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three months of residency, Zhu Zheqin visited the concert hall and upper courtyard at different times, early morning, dusk, midnight, windy, rainy or foggy. &quot;It&#39;s like you get to know a very strange person.&quot; Friend, you have to know his character, know when he is the softest and most moving, and also know when he is the strongest. This is my working method.&quot; Especially the Valley Concert Hall, contrary to conventional concert halls, it does not There is no condition to completely purify the sounds of human voices and musical instruments, because its roof reaches the sky and the four walls are cut out, connecting the inside and outside. Sitting on the concrete seats of the concert hall is like sitting in a hollow boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is completely opposite to the concept of a standard concert hall. It does not block ambient sounds, but hopes that you can hear ambient sounds in an open state, feel the changes in light, and know that everything wakes up in the morning. .&quot; For musicians, these are unique and rare performance venues that burst the imagination, but they also have great limitations. They make people rethink, what kind of performance is a good performance? What kind of listening experience does this performance bring to the audience? Why do these two buildings appear here? Why do people come here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On several occasions, Zhu Zheqin went mountain climbing with Bai Chunxiang, the local Great Wall protector. Once she saw the back of Bai Chunxiang sitting on the Great Wall. She looked at it for a long time and thought, how should we as contemporary people deal with themselves in these cultures? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;She seemed to be embarking on a new journey, with old experiences falling off like frozen leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Zhu Zheqin spent 15 days in the mountains to collect various sounds, downloaded sounds from other planets from NASA’s official website, and used ambient electronic music editing throughout. She decided to compose in a minimalist way in three sections. The melody has only five notes, do re mi so la, and the lyrics only have three sentences - &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, Seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still mountains, and seeing water is still water.&quot; She invited Jinshanling aborigines and &quot;new mountain people&quot; to form a choir, and also successively contacted other musicians, including arranger Meng Ke Zhuolan, guzheng Chang Jing, and wind blower Wang Hua and percussionist Chen Shijie, all of whom participated in her tour ten years ago, are now reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete performance design is as follows: in the afternoon, the audience follows the guide silently throughout the entire process through the four performance locations along the upper courtyard building complex, using their &quot;hearing&quot; to experience nature and the musicians&#39; understanding of natural sounds. The performance of the performance was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;; in the evening, I entered the Valley Concert Hall to listen to the concert, which was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall structure of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; is strictly arranged, and each paragraph is mainly improvised. The day&#39;s weather, audience interaction, and the sounds of flora and fauna in the valley will all become part of the improvisation. Therefore, except for the chorus, which is composed, the other parts are improvised, and each rehearsal and performance will be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final rehearsal and recording was going on in the concert hall the night before the official performance. At 8 o&#39;clock, the mountain breeze passed through the hall, and the recording tube was full of whistling wind. Meng Ke Zhuolan&#39;s curly hair was blown all over her head. She stood at the mixer at the top of the back row and shouted to Zhu Zheqin at the bottom: &quot;Aren&#39;t you scared?&quot; Zhu Zheqin looked at her happily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Later we thought it was actually good to have wind, because if your music is open enough, it can accommodate this.&quot; Meng Kezhuolan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the night, the rehearsal was over. The next morning, Zhu Zheqin got up and turned on the recording to listen again. Suddenly, he kept crying. &quot;I feel extremely happy. I have never shed tears because of a good meal, but I may have read a poem, stood in front of the sea, watched a movie, and listened to Dupree&#39;s Elgar Cello Concerto in E minor, It makes me feel like my life has been turned into gold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;166 cushions were squeezed into the originally 140-seat Valley Music Hall, and people were still coming in. Many people had to stand at the entrance to listen. At 6pm, the show starts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert hall was very dark at first, with only a beam of white light shining in from the roof, scanning the entire venue back and forth. In the center of the sunken stage, Zhu Zheqin’s long hair was tied up in a bunch, with his eyes closed, like an immortal sitting in a cave. middle. The sound of 432 Hz always surrounds this fairy cave. This is a soothing and healing sound frequency that Zhu Zheqin specially used this time. It is superimposed with the sounds of streams, frogs, chimes and alien planets to create a space far wider than a concert hall. Zhu Zheqin&#39;s voice has a long breath and a wide range, from far to near, from humming to singing. She was so happy with the performance that she clapped her hands and danced, swaying her three-meter-long costume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Derek Bailey discusses the concept of free improvisation in Improvisation: Its Essence and Musical Practice, he considers it to be a celebration of the moment. Li Jianhong, a musician who is keen on improvisation and the translator of &quot;Improvisation&quot;, regards improvisation as a channel. He believes that for a conscious musician, improvisation is always a way to explore the true self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Zheqin, all these are true, and can be interpreted in another way. Improvisation is also a coexistence between everyone and nature, and is a humble and great part of it, like flowing water, frogs, wind, and trees. Like crows, they live for a short period of time, but they also create enduring arts such as music, poetry, and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the three-part singing was over, the musicians were supposed to be introduced, but that night she felt that anything she said in the middle of the performance was superfluous. So she performed all the way to the impromptu &quot;Finale&quot; that was originally prepared for everyone to leave at will. Halfway through the &quot;Finale&quot;, people still stayed where they were. Then she introduced the choir and performing members, thanked many people, and then said: &quot; It&#39;s been a long time since I sang for you.&quot; She paused and continued, &quot;We are already at the age when we are about to go down the mountain, but we climbed up a mountain together. This is rare in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the time Near 8 o&#39;clock, Zhu Zheqin was worried that a strong wind was coming, and finally told the audience who were unwilling to leave, everyone should go back. People stood up one after another, but she was reluctant to leave. Amid the rustling footsteps leaving the concert hall, her singing voice suddenly sounded again, with a broad and clear voice: &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still water. Mountains, water is still water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255462&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;World Hear·Ethnic Music Discovery Tour&quot; Guizhou Station, Zhu Zheqin led a team to record Miao girls singing &quot;Soul of Rice Flowers&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A week later, I met Guo Rong in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin has been working together for 11 years. Guo Rong found that every time there was a new art project, Zhu Zheqin would always leave a place for the &quot;old people&quot; who had worked together. Zhu Zheqin is surrounded by collaborators who have worked together for more than ten years, and she has become close partners in life with many of them. Guo Rong said that Zhu Zheqin maintained his enthusiasm for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large part of the reason why Zhu Zheqin was so moved at the end of the concert and later at the dinner was that many friends came, including Xi Chuan, Li Xianting, Xu Bing, Zhang Xiaogang, Wu Ershan... &quot;It&#39;s too luxurious.&quot; She choked up when talking about these names, &quot;Their works have been with me for many years, and the spirit, energy, touch, and encouragement released by their creations have been useful to me for life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After (New Crown) I miss these friends very much during the epidemic. I feel that life is meaningless. They come and go naturally, but they are the scenery of my life. If they need my voice, I think I should sing to them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dinner As usual, let the guest of honor say a few words during the ceremony. Zhu Zheqin took the microphone and said he had nothing to say. Everyone said, &quot;Let&#39;s sing.&quot; She said, &quot;Come on.&quot; &quot;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot;.&quot; It&#39;s too long ago. &quot;Return.&quot; Just right, this is the theme song she wrote and sang for the movie &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Christmas Eve 2019, Zhu Zheqin received a call from Wu Ershan and asked her if she wanted to go to Qingdao for Christmas. When I arrived in Qingdao, I discovered that it was a huge studio with thousands of people busy every day. Wuershan has been preparing for 10 years and spent 3 billion to make a trilogy of mythological epics. He hoped that Zhu Zheqin would write a song for &quot;Fengshen&quot;. They met as early as the 1990s. Zhu Zheqin watched Wu Ershan move from contemporary art to advertising shooting and then to film director. She felt that she did not have the courage to target a wider audience like Wu Ershan, and subconsciously refused: &quot;This is For a commercial blockbuster, I am not a traffic star and cannot bring you traffic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our first choice is Teacher Zhu, and he is also the only choice. We want to write an art song with a melody Full, and at the same time the voice span is very large, because if you want to express very full emotions, it will involve a very large span between notes. No one (except her) can sing.&quot; said Meng Kezhuolan, who is Wu Ershan&#39;s wife , is also the music director of &quot;Fengshen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guests fell silent, there was no accompaniment, and the sound was dry and dull, not suitable for singers to sing. But the three-part song was sung melodiously and stretched by Zhu Zheqin. It tells the story of the young Ji Fa who was sent to Chaoge as a hostage, and then escaped from the control of the tyrannical Shang King Yin Shou and returned to his hometown. The song was still being recorded during the COVID-19 epidemic. She had to return from abroad. According to epidemic prevention regulations, she was quarantined when she was in transit in Hong Kong, and then quarantined again after arriving in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin said that this is Ji Fa&#39;s homesickness, and it also embodies some of her nostalgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11 o&#39;clock during the dinner, the brightly lit restaurant suddenly lost power and became completely dark. The staff found real and fake candles for lighting, and the guests were happy and cheered softly. Then someone said, let’s go see the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The moonlight is bright and clear, the mountains are silent, and the cold night makes people shrink their necks and stamp their feet. A small group of people filed out through the narrow glass door and gathered on the platform to sing again, &quot;The moon passes through the white lotus-like clouds&quot; and &quot;You ask me how deeply I love you/How much I love you.&quot; / My love is true / My love is true / The moon represents my heart”... Sometimes it is a solo, sometimes it is a chorus of three or three, and someone brings a piano, and the echoes are like ripples. spread among the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They will definitely lose power when they are together. The spiritual energy field is too strong.&quot; Zhu Zheqin also remembered during the interview, &quot;It was like that in the 1980s and 1990s. There were no exhibitions at that time. There were no paintings to sell, no records, no concerts, all of this was nothing. Zhang Xiaogang was still painting stage sets for the Sichuan Opera Troupe as a living profession. But what he loved most was painting. He painted hard, and he had no money. No reason. In recent years, it seems that people paint just to go to auction, and how high the price is, and how good it is. In fact, it is not true. In my opinion, those are just projected phenomena. There is a powerful spiritual power behind it. I What I cherish is that kind of thing. I think that kind of thing will change the world and heal myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, the narrow door that everyone passes through from the restaurant to the terrace seems to have become a door to time and space. , outside the door is their spiritual hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;I think people of every era are the masters of this era. The history of this era is created and left by us, so what do we want to create? If we are dissatisfied with reality, Then why don&#39;t we do some ourselves? I&#39;m not one to complain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was singing &quot;A True Story&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Red-Crowned Crane&quot;&lt;/span>;) and became famous after winning the Youth Singing Competition, a fan appeared at the door of the hotel in the middle of the night and said to her, I think you are the Red-Crowned Crane. She was scared away because &quot;it impressed them so strongly that they stayed there forever.&quot; She didn’t know what she wanted at that time, but she knew what she didn’t want—not to become a singer, not to be packaged, not to enter a paradigm. &quot;Someone in my heart said, no, no, no. But, what are you going to do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Double CD &quot;Moonrise&quot; by Zhu Zheqin and ethnic singers&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, the market economy developed rapidly and social trends moved away from single collectivism. Zhu Zheqin recalled That feeling of liberating the mind, &quot;Actually, people are quite confused, and they don&#39;t know where they are in this coordinate.&quot; She did not sign with any record company, nor did she join an art troupe, and disappeared from the public eye. She went to Chengdu from Guangzhou, and a year later, &quot;Yellow Child&quot; composed by He Xuntian and sung by Zhu Zheqin was released. Later, historian Luo Xin wrote about a detail when he was reflecting on and criticizing racial thinking. On a winter night when he was working on his doctoral thesis, he heard &quot;Yellow Children&quot; being played on the radio, &quot;that empty and desolate feeling of loneliness and hopelessness.&quot; &quot;It tells the loss of the East in front of the West.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, &quot;A Sister Drum&quot; was released. This was the second collaboration between Zhu Zheqin and He Xuntian. They took a trip to Tibet, which they regarded as a spiritual holy land, and returned many times. But no matter how impressive the natural scenery, humanities and art in Tibetan areas are, what makes Zhu Zheqin most unforgettable is still the &quot;people&quot;. It is &quot;the scenes of their lives in poverty that made me have to re-evaluate the weight of my life.&quot; She got a new name, Dadawa. Dadawa is reminiscent of Dadaism, which was later basically annexed by Surrealism. Dadawa is the Tibetan word for the moon. Dadawa is neither the East nor the West. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot; and &quot;Yangjinma&quot; two years later form a complete expression of their Tibet, which is mysterious and strong on the one hand, and everyday and light on the other, bringing Zhu Zheqin to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, she also made a physical journey across Asia. From Kashmir to the Himalayas, I sweated and sneezed while clicking the shutter in the spice markets of India, and took a tricycle to look for gypsies. Gypsy Bopa played the music on a very simple folk violin. Zhu Zheqin was fascinated by it. It took him a while to come back to his senses and said that it was like hearing real music for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also during that trip, she saw Hindus waiting for death by the Ganges River, and the cremated corpses rolled down to her feet. &quot;Journey to the Ganges is another starting point in my life, where I realize the meaninglessness of life. Our life is redefined by our values ​​and culture, which celebrates the greatness of life. A person&#39;s birth must be celebrated, and a person&#39;s death must be commemorated. . But if you imagine that a fish is born and dies, it is a natural thing, nothing more. The truth of the universe is that you are like a leaf, yellow today and withered tomorrow.&quot; She thought, if life is like this, what will happen to people? Life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ask the Mountain·Theme Concert&quot;, Zhu Zheqin and musicians performed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Asking is the beginning of Tao&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the first year of the new coronavirus pandemic, Zhu Zheqin entered a &quot;dormant state&quot;. She spent most of her time at home, cooking, taking care of the yard, and thinking about nothing. &quot;I rarely have such a stage where I shut down my phone. Suddenly I felt how fragile the world is and how vulnerable human civilization is to an invisible virus.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second year, she began to I thought, if there are no recordings, no exhibitions, no concerts in the future, what else will I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin was admitted to the Guangzhou &quot;Little Skylark&quot; Chorus at the age of 7 and performed at the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall. At the age of 13, she recorded children&#39;s singing teaching materials. She can sing any type of opera. During school, she worked as a singer in a karaoke hall, and then she became famous. , hold concerts, explore your own expression and style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the trip to India shattered the meaning of life, Zhu Zheqin felt that he had reached a point in time where all expressions seemed pale and feeble, and he had to look inward to find something more essential. &quot;When you find yourself weightless or confused, only by daring to throw yourself out can you have a chance to regain your life.&quot; In 2009, she accepted the appointment as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program and launched the &quot;World Sees-China &quot;Ethnic Culture Protection and Development Goodwill Action&quot;, conducting field research on folk music and handicrafts in ethnic minority areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, she realized that she and the entire generation had a very weak understanding of their own culture. Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;In modern China, a &#39;modernity&#39; suddenly appeared, but this &#39;modernity&#39; may have nothing to do with its own culture and is a collage. From the time we started to imitate to the time we realized that imitation was not It is not ourselves, and then we have to find and construct it. The first stage is to create something from scratch, and then we have to take root, grow up, be local, and reflect the face of the people of this land and water.&quot; She deliberately made young people Many musicians participated in the project to organize and adapt folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, she released her last album to date, &quot;Moonrise&quot;, a double CD. One is a collection of original ethnic minority music, and the other is a musician&#39;s work that has been arranged and sung. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the creative team of &quot;Moonrise&quot; held a world tour with ethnic singers and young musicians. Meng Kezhuolan served as composer and arranger. She was less than 30 years old at the time and mainly wrote chamber music. Before a performance, Zhu Zheqin asked Meng Kezhuolan to come and listen. That was the first time she heard a singer and musician singing Miao Fei Song sitting in front of her. As soon as the other person opened his mouth, she got goosebumps all over her body. &quot;I was suddenly photographed there. His earthy, tanned look no longer existed in front of me. I thought to myself that if he were in a Miao village, all the girls would fall in love with him.&quot; Until a few days ago, wind player Wang Hua still remembered that tour during the rehearsal of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and said that it was the best performance he had participated in in so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;World Seeing&#39; thing seems to help others, but it actually saved me.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said frankly, &quot;After the meaning of life was shattered, it gave me a stage to learn and do something. Specific things. At that time, I had a very big feeling. I thought I was a drop of water, but I was also an ocean. Only when I became a water drop could I be an ocean.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after that, Zhu Zheqin never released an album and had only a handful of public performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As a singer, I use singing to express my thoughts and feelings, but apart from that, I have always been more interested in inner energy.” Along this path, she entered sound art, “I want to Know what else is inside me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it didn&#39;t go well at first. In 2014, Gao Peng, then director of Today Art Museum, approached Zhu Zheqin and asked her to create a sound art work. After two visits, her reply was pending. Guo Rong hoped to persuade Zhu Zheqin to start a new attempt. She said: &quot;Teacher Zhu, I came to your team because I like your music and your voice.&quot; Something seemed to be touched in Zhu Zheqin&#39;s heart. A few days later, she flew abroad. Before leaving, she left a note for Guo Rong, which listed 20 issues, including time points, production schedules, and problems faced... Guo Rong was relieved when she saw it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, I think the process of her asking these questions is also a process of self-answering. If I didn&#39;t answer her at that time, someone else would answer her. If no one else answered her, she would answer these questions herself. Question.&quot; Guo Rong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, the Sound·Jue Zhu Zheqin sound art exhibition opened. Today Art Museum was painted into a dark box, with a pool on the ground. Zhu Zheqin recruited dozens of people to walk back and forth beside the pool, making sounds and playing chimes. She did not sing, but stood in the crowd, and all the sounds turned into ripples, reflected on the wall, turning the invisible into something tangible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The mystery of all things lies in the combination of things. The world is a temporary combination of consciousness, and music is sound. The essence of sound is waves and vibrations. So I think vibration is a very direct way to approach consciousness. . I am very lucky to be on this road.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;It was only when I became aware of my voice that I fully understood myself. I want to create a field and let everyone enter, so that people can realize that everyone is actually affected by something. Driven by an inner energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you are at the scene, as both Meng Ke Zhuolan and Guo Rong have described, it seems that everyone has come to another time and space, temporarily breaking away from external forces and moving inwards. Zhu Zheqin tried to create this feeling in his seven subsequent sound art works, including &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three lyrics in &quot;Ask the Mountain&quot; are also a portrayal of her journey back to her inner self. In the beginning, people looked at things through the universal laws of phenomena. The saying goes: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; When superficial phenomena are denied, solid and perfect things become vulnerable, and perfection is just a fantasy. This is: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, &quot;After the first year of the COVID-19 epidemic, I thought, when I was 6 years old, no one said that I would have concerts, wouldn&#39;t I still sing every day? I just love this thing, it is Bringing me joy in life, helping me grow and perceive the world, isn’t it more real than anything else? When you reach this point, you will see your true nature. Just like birds singing in the sky and fish swimming in the sea, if I have wings, I will Fly.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;In such an era, I think it is more important to maintain an imagination, maintain poetry, and maintain free thoughts about reality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this a mountain or a mountain? . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the concert &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;, everyone will get a small guide card at the entrance of the Valley Concert Hall, which reads: Creation stems from the perception of the mountains, and does not seek to understand the mountains and the world. Any definition of &quot;mountain dwelling&quot; nor explore any answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the performance, I walked up the mountain along the path connecting the Valley Concert Hall and the Upper Court. There was a small dark green sign hanging on a tree on the roadside, with a black arrow pointing to the depths of the mountain. There is a line of small words attached to the arrow: There will be answers in the mountains. Continuing in the direction pointed by the arrow, the same arrow guide appeared one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sign ends in front of an old cave. This is a small house built against a shallow cave, with three real people enshrined inside. There was a kang built against the wall. There were traces of fire underneath, but now the window paper was broken and air leaked from all sides. There was no sound for a while. Am I the only one in this world? &quot;Will there be answers in the mountains&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While listening to me talk about this experience, Zhu Zheqin looked at a certain place on the roof. The meditation room fell into silence, and became darker as the sky darkened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, she said, when you start asking, that is the beginning of the Tao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to Huang Yao for his help)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她研究在美中国本科留学生，发现高远志向下的挣扎和迷茫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259545]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QRIdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1226&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QR IdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 17, 2022 local time, New York University graduates celebrated their graduation ceremony. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The annual application season for international students is here again. According to the &quot;2023 Study Abroad in China White Paper&quot; released by New Oriental, more than 50% of people intend to study abroad with a bachelor&#39;s degree or below. The situation of studying abroad is picking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, two other reports are also worthy of attention. On September 25, 2023, the National Student Credentials Certification Center in the United States released a report &quot;Completing College&quot; that showed that the undergraduate dropout rate for Chinese students in the United States was as high as 25%. In the same month, WholeRen, a Pennsylvania-based education consulting company, released the &quot;2023 White Paper on the Current Situation of Chinese Students in the United States.&quot; According to statistics, 70% of Chinese students who have been dismissed from the United States are undergraduates, and more than half of the students are studying in the top 50 schools in the United States. The top two reasons for being dismissed were academic dishonesty and poor academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The data only presents the tip of the iceberg. In the seemingly distant American education system, many Chinese students are indeed experiencing struggles under the glamorous impression&lt;/span>;. Ma Yingyi, a professor of sociology at Syracuse University in the United States, wrote the book &quot;Ambitious and Anxious: The Success and Struggle of Chinese College Students in American Higher Education&quot; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ambitious and Anxious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;How Chinese College Students Succeed and Struggle in American Higher Education&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;) &lt;/span>;, describes the status of Chinese students in the United States as &quot;ambition and anxiety coexist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that whether they came from wealthy families or ordinary families, these international students began to experience this contradiction before arriving in the United States, and it intensified after entering college. They have big dreams, but in pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles and feel confused about their futures. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this takes place against the background of the rapid development of Chinese society. All these anxieties forced them to think about the ultimate question: Is it really worth studying in the United States? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The samples surveyed by Ma Yingyi included 507 Chinese international students from 50 American undergraduate colleges and universities, all born in the 1990s. The survey period was from 2011 to 2019. The book won the 2021 American Association for Comparative and International Education Higher Education Best Book Award and the American Sociological Association’s Bourdieu Book Honor Award. Recently, Ma Yingyi accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The increase in undergraduate international students is not due to the financial crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you pay attention to the group of Chinese international students in American undergraduate education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My research began in 2011. At that time, major universities in the United States began to have a large number of Chinese undergraduates. Prior to this, most Chinese students studying abroad in the 1980s and 1990s studied in China for graduate school and then went to the United States to study for Ph.D., or they completed their undergraduate studies in China and then went to the United States for graduate school, as was the case for me. Twenty years ago, I first came to the United States after earning my bachelor&#39;s degree in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But around 2007, a large number of students came to the United States to study for undergraduates after completing high school in China, and some even went directly to the United States to study in high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that most of the previous generation of international students either relied on scholarships from the United States to study for master&#39;s or doctoral degrees, or were sponsored by the Chinese government to study in the United States. As for the generation of undergraduates I follow, 90% are completely self-funded. For in-state students, tuition at public universities in the United States is very cheap, but international students have to pay extra, which is higher than out-of-state students, and private universities charge even more. Therefore, whether applying to public or private universities, the cost for Chinese international students is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, this is a brand new phenomenon, reflecting the rise of the middle class and the accumulation of wealth in Chinese society. Then during the research process, I gradually discovered the duality of ambition and anxiety among this generation of international students. Whether it is academic or social life, or planning for the future, this contradiction is reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Study abroad agencies on the market now recommend that parents study in the United States for their children Prepare for a huge cost of one million a year, which is higher than the cost in the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, Singapore and other regions. Why are there so many Chinese families willing to pay? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The cost of undergraduate study in the United States may be the highest compared to other regions, so many people mistakenly believe that Chinese students studying in the United States They are all children of entrepreneurs, but in fact they are only a minority. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sociology, income and wealth are two different concepts. Income is your salary. Judging from income alone, China&#39;s middle class may not be able to afford tuition fees in the United States. But wealth is different. Wealth can include real estate, stocks, etc. In China, it is mainly real estate. Since the 2000s, China&#39;s urbanization has developed rapidly, the housing market has taken off, and many families who are not considered wealthy have also accumulated a certain amount of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the samples I collected, some parents were middle school teachers, and some were even working-class parents. Because they own a house, they choose to liquidate this wealth to support their children&#39;s studies abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do teachers at American universities think of this change? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I once met an administrator at Purdue University. He said that the school had a financial crisis after the 2008 financial crisis. It just so happened that Chinese undergraduates arrived at this time and had the ability to pay high tuition fees. He described it as a &quot;perfect marriage.&quot; At that time, I discovered that this was a very systematic phenomenon, and there were not only needs from both parties behind it, so I started researching it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The increase in international undergraduate students studying in the United States is due to the Financial crisis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many people say that the increase in Chinese students came after the financial crisis in 2008, when American universities were short of money. But my survey data shows that the year with the highest annual growth rate in the number of Chinese students studying in the United States was 2007, before the financial crisis. Therefore, it is not the demand from American universities that has led to the rapid increase in Chinese students studying abroad, but more the demand from the Chinese middle class and above for their children’s education. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, China experienced rapid economic development, the rise of the middle class, and residents&#39; income also increased rapidly. Another factor I mention in the book is the appreciation of the renminbi from 2006 to 2014. By 2014, the renminbi had appreciated by about 37%, making Chinese households more able to pay. On the other hand, it is still very difficult to get into good universities in China, and the United States is still the place with the largest concentration of good universities in the world, so many people come to the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Three stages have &quot;ambition and anxiety coexisting&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did your research develop? How do you observe the &quot;coexistence of ambition and anxiety&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My survey started in 2011. I initially used a sampling method to conduct an online survey, and then selected students who were willing to participate in in-depth interviews. We received 507 questionnaires from 50 institutions, and finally conducted in-depth interviews with 65 Chinese students who studied undergraduate in the United States from 2013 to 2016. I let students choose English or Chinese, and almost everyone speaks Chinese. Over the next three years, I conducted fieldwork in nine high schools in six cities in China and interviewed school counselors, principals, and teachers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I divide their experience into three stages. The first stage is before students come to the United States, they need to prepare for applications, exams, and school selection. The whole process is full of anxiety. This largely comes from their ambition, because they want to enter the top 30 or top 50 schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second stage is to choose a major. I have to choose a job that satisfies my interests and is easy to find a job. This is where conflicts with my parents begin to arise. They are also anxious during the social stage. Chinese students are very unfamiliar with American students’ social and entertainment methods, making it difficult to integrate. The purpose of many students going abroad is to get in touch with diverse cultures and different circles, so this also brings a lot of pressure and a sense of gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final stage is planning for the future. When I did my research, the job market was not what it is now, but there were all kinds of problems. For example, if you want to stay in the United States, you have visa issues. When you return to China, you have difficulty integrating into domestic circles, how to use domestic social capital, and how to choose a career. They are also eager to get satisfactory returns on their academic qualifications and experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This duality of &quot;ambition and anxiety&quot; can be clearly observed in these three stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with international students from other countries, Chinese students have this kind of Will duality be more prominent? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Any international student will face this situation. Specifically, when it comes to Chinese students studying abroad, many of them sell their homes or take out loans to support their children studying abroad. Most of this generation are only children, and many of them need to return to their parents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, from a philosophical perspective, ambition itself can generate anxiety. But Chinese international students are more prominent in this regard. During the writing process, I realized that to understand this generation of international students, it is actually very important to understand the Chinese society behind them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past two decades, Chinese society has actually been a state of coexistence of ambition and anxiety. No country has changed as much as China. People from all walks of life have felt many changes. Many people have achieved prosperity and many people have great aspirations and ambitions. People&#39;s horizons have broadened and their incomes have increased. At the same time, they are always worried about what opportunities they have missed. They are eager to gain an international perspective, but this requires a lot of resources. People have also begun to worry about whether their investment can obtain sufficient returns. All this brings Come to anxiety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is naturally true for Chinese students coming from this environment. Moreover, international students are not a random group of people in any society. They are a group of people with ambitions and certain privileges. Sociologically speaking, migrant populations are more ambitious and goal-oriented than migrant populations. International students want to study to get a degree and see the wider world. They even bear the expectations and eyes of the entire family, and bear the pressure and opportunities brought about by social changes. Opportunities and challenges coexist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, although China&#39;s society has undergone tremendous changes, education has not changed that much. The main reason is that the college entrance examination is still the baton. The primary and secondary education received by Chinese children and American children is very different. Chinese students go to American higher education with the imprint of Chinese education. This change itself also brings great challenges to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, Chinese international students may be the group with the most &quot;dual nature of ambition and anxiety&quot; among the international student groups in the world, or among the floating population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1007&quot; height= &quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Left: &quot;Ambition and Worry: The Successes and Struggles of Chinese College Students in American Higher Education.&quot; Right: Ma Yingyi, professor of sociology at Syracuse University, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Encountering a &quot;sense of gap&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You also mentioned in your book that after some Chinese students come to the United States, they will be troubled because their school is in a &quot;village&quot; Shock? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most famous case is the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, which everyone says is a cornfield. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has a lot to do with the history of the development of higher education in China and the United States. Chinese universities are concentrated in big cities, while in the United States there are actually not many big cities, but there are many university towns, which are schools built in large rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each state has its own flagship school, and the top QS-ranked schools are not necessarily in big cities. Of course, university rankings are one-sided and easily misleading information. Universities in the United States are very diverse. There are very good academic colleges and community colleges in public schools. Different schools have different missions. They are not strictly superior or inferior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why do international students value university rankings so much? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;One reason is that the admissions system in the United States is very different. It does not only look at scores. You don’t know what proportion the scores will account for. , there is no way to quantitatively determine whether it is 10%, 5%, or 90%. Every school is different, every major is different, and every school is different in different years. No one will tell you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American students may choose this school for various reasons such as good results in a certain sport, the school being close to home, or even the beautiful scenery. But Chinese students don’t understand this, and university rankings have become a source of stress and anxiety for them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among your interviewees, this &quot;sense of gap&quot; still exists In what ways does it appear? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The sense of gap in life, including interpersonal communication. They may have thought Americans were warm and open, but later discovered that making friends was not as easy as they thought. For example, some students were ambitious at first and hoped to make many American friends, but they were quickly frustrated. A very important way of social entertainment for American college students is weekend parties. Many people at the party drink and play some drinking games, such as putting a ping pong ball on a beer bottle and everyone blows it together. Whoever the ball hits gets a drink. . Many Chinese children cannot join in, and many find drinking games unbearable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people feel frustrated and return to the circle of Chinese students. The entertainment in this circle may be eating together, singing at KTV, girls going shopping, and boys playing games. Many Chinese students will feel that I should not hang out with Chinese people when I go abroad. Their parents will even urge them to make American friends, saying, &quot;If you don&#39;t make American friends, your English will not be as good as before you went abroad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a Chinese student who speaks English very well, is outgoing, and has many American friends. Everyone thinks he grew up in the United States. However, after he integrated into the circle of American college students, he was disappointed. He did not enjoy the multiculturalism as he had imagined before, so he returned to the circle of Chinese people, assuming leadership positions in the Chinese international student group and hosting the Spring Festival Gala. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think this is a very interesting return. I went out for a while, had my imagination shattered, and then came back. In a philosophical sense, this return is a process of finding oneself. Although he finally returned to the Chinese students, he came out to see, interact with, and experience a different world, which was different from the one he had originally The state of not going out is completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do they adapt to this &quot;sense of gap&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This sense of gap will affect their satisfaction with studying abroad and will affect their entire state, including study, social interaction, daily life, etc. , in fact, it is difficult to adapt. But time itself brings habits, and students who have never been accustomed to it may choose to leave. For example, some students&#39; undergraduate schools are in large rural areas in the United States. After graduation, they will apply to study for graduate students in big cities such as New York and Boston. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, you still need to deepen your understanding of yourself and the new environment. Before studying abroad, you should first understand what you really want, what the school can provide, and try to reduce some misunderstandings. Only in this way can you reduce the problems caused by misunderstandings in the future. Come with dissatisfaction and anxiety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is very beneficial to make some preparations to adapt to the environment. For example, a student whose family conditions are relatively good, his parents found him an American friend on Twitter to accompany him to practice speaking, communicate and communicate with him. Some students will go to American schools in advance to adapt to the environment. I also did some statistical analysis and found that participating in more club activities, participating in school organizations, etc. can improve students&#39; satisfaction with studying abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to daily life, international students do not speak in class and it is difficult to integrate well Classroom and academic activities have actually always been a problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;They may really want to express themselves and participate, but it is difficult for them to participate. This situation of not getting what you want actually brings a lot of psychological burden. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have personal experience with classroom discussions. I often ask my classmates to discuss in class. Discussions are not entirely a challenge to English communication. Language is the most basic threshold. Many students who are very good at English also find it difficult to participate in discussions. My survey shows that 60% of students think that their English is very good, but only 20%-30% of all students think that they often speak in class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What factors are holding them back? I think a very important reason is the difference in basic thinking patterns, and students cannot express themselves bravely and fully. Most Chinese classrooms are always looking for standard answers, and students are always worried about whether what they say is right. In contrast, American university classes are open-ended discussions with no right answers. This is a considerable difference. Chinese students need to change their thinking patterns to participate effectively in discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Leverage strengths and avoid weaknesses, rather than make up for gaps&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This book was published in 2020. In the following three years, we have all experienced more changes. Have you observed any new situations? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;International students all over the world are having a difficult time during the COVID-19 epidemic. It is inconvenient to travel and they are far away from their families. It should be said that Chinese international students are in a worse situation. difficulty. My basic conclusion has not changed, but these three years have clearly made &quot;worrying&quot; worse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand &quot;worried&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The specific challenge is uncertainty, which is reflected in all aspects of studying abroad. When will flights be added? Would it be easier to return home? Why are student visas and work visas so difficult to apply for? U.S. policies and public opinion trends will increase the psychological pressure on Chinese students. This is a pressure that Chinese students did not have 10 years ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, when I wrote this book, there seemed to be a very consistent tendency to choose the United States, but now many students have chosen Europe, Japan, including Hong Kong, China, etc. This is a relatively big change. . Recently released data shows that the number of Indian students in the United States has exceeded that of Chinese students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the trend of younger students studying abroad? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;More and more families are choosing to send their young children to study abroad. This may be due to structural reasons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the elimination system of standardized tests, most people are not winners. Although some students have become winners, in this competitive environment, they are unable to obtain a more balanced physical and mental development, or they are unhappy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So many families choose to study abroad at a young age. Obviously everyone knows that there are risks. Compared with college students, the risks are higher. However, after analyzing the risks and rewards, they feel that the benefits outweigh the disadvantages, so they make the decision. This choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for Chinese international students and parents? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most important thing is to learn more about yourself through various methods. For example, through parents, friends, or by participating in various activities to understand yourself more comprehensively. Studying abroad actually just opens a window. After arriving, you have to make many choices, including which courses to take, which societies to join, what future path to choose, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A great advantage of American higher education is that it provides many choices. For a person to make a choice that suits him or her, a very important prerequisite is self-awareness. So you need to understand yourself, what your strengths are, what your weaknesses are, what you are passionate about, and what abilities you cannot develop. One person cannot be good at everything. The most important thing in modern society is to do things that you are good at and interested in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It doesn’t matter if you don’t know yourself well. I think this is a lifelong lesson. But students should have this awareness now, and start focusing on their own interests and strengths from now on, making use of their strengths and avoiding weaknesses, rather than making up for gaps. I think both students and parents need to make adjustments in their thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以舆论战开打，以色列缘何撤销公共外交部？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259553]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, 2023 local time, the Israeli cabinet decided to revoke the country’s main responsibility for public diplomacy through a telephone vote. , the Ministry of Information for External Propaganda Affairs (generally referred to as the &quot;Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs&quot; in news reports), and said that the ministry&#39;s budget will be transferred to the recovery and reconstruction of communities around the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a gesture by the Israeli government directed at both its domestic public and the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abolish the so-called inaction departments internally, find scapegoats, and try to homogenize domestic public opinion. It has demonstrated its determination to burn its boats to the outside world, and any attempt by the outside world to interfere with Israel&#39;s will will be rejected. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs mean? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The term &quot;public diplomacy&quot; was first proposed by Professor Edmund Glean of Tufts University in the United States in 1965. He believed that public diplomacy is to ensure that one&#39;s own country maintains effective relations with foreign countries. Thought connection”. More generally speaking, public diplomacy is a strategic plan to carry out national marketing and create a positive and good international image. It is a &quot;popular project&quot; to win the hearts and minds of the international people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Israel directly announced the immediate dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs. It is obvious that it has deeply felt the changes in international public opinion. Israel’s external propaganda department cannot escape the blame for this, although Israel is doing a positive job The battlefield has an overwhelming advantage, but the corresponding situation is not shown on the battlefield of public opinion. The reasons behind this are worthy of scrutiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, global public opinion has embarrassed Israel, which not only seriously interferes with Israel&#39;s upcoming retaliatory actions, but also has the potential to further weaken Israel&#39;s internal unity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this atmosphere, Minister of Public Foreign Affairs Atbaryan&#39;s voluntary resignation not only gave herself a step down, but also showed her support for the Netanyahu government. She said, &quot;Put aside Self-deprecation aside, running a ministry in such a horrific time of war is an expensive problem and the Israeli people need every shekel.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the latest opinion poll conducted by the &quot;Jerusalem Post&quot; showed that nearly four-fifths of the people believe that the Netanyahu government needs to deal with this large-scale Hamas infiltration and Responsible for the massacre of Jews, the Israeli government must not only unite internally and externally at this moment, but also consider a potential post-war political reckoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Israel’s internal struggles remain complex and changeable, which has profoundly affected Israel’s security environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israeli media pointed out that the Ministry of Public Affairs not only failed to fulfill its obligations, but even interfered in Israel&#39;s internal affairs for a long period of time. This minister from the Likud Party has used his power to vigorously promote the government&#39;s judicial reform and made a series of inflammatory remarks. For example, in April 2023, Atbaryan directly pointed out that the military, police and media composed of The deep state network is working hard to overthrow the government, which is reminiscent of how the Turkish government described the Gulen movement before the attempted coup in 2016, highlighting that the Israeli state and society are gradually being torn apart. In addition, she has launched scar-revealing attacks on her political critics, underscoring her right-wing conservative ultra-hardline political stance, which runs counter to Israel&#39;s desire to be diplomatic in its international propaganda matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on October 12, before the department was disintegrated, she issued a resignation statement, saying that the power of her department had been weakened, and there was an overlap of powers between the Ministry of Expatriate Affairs and the Ministry of Public Affairs. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs only received its budget six months after the new government was formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first cabinet member to resign after a new round of conflict between Palestine and Israel broke out. This is just a microcosm of Israel’s domestic struggle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Palestinian-Israeli conflict, analyzed only from a technical level and from an absolutely neutral political stance, has greatly shocked Israel. It is comparable in form to the Fourth Middle East War and in terms of psychological trauma. Compared with the &quot;9·11&quot; incident in the United States. This is not unrelated to the division of domestic public opinion caused by Israel&#39;s promotion of judicial reform in the past year. The root cause is the long-standing dispute between left and right, religious and secular disputes in Israel&#39;s internal affairs, as well as the frequent changes of governments in recent years. hidden fundamental crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, fortresses are breached from within. Israel’s recent political chaos has seriously affected its military and intelligence systems, giving Hamas room to take advantage of the situation. In addition, the peace process between Israel and Saudi Arabia About to enter its final chapter, Hamas urgently needs to give the international community a heavy blow and prove to the world that Middle East reconciliation that bypasses the Palestinian-Israeli issue is putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs heralds the imminence of a larger-scale bloody operation. Israel is consolidating all resources and preparing for war. Israel&#39;s domestic thinking in fighting Palestine urgently needs to form a united front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel’s move is also preparing for the worst for the safety of the hostages, that is, it ignores the hostage weight in the hands of Hamas, ignores domestic and foreign voices in favor of reconciliation negotiations, and treats Hamas the possibility of a complete liquidation. But this is undoubtedly a difficult decision. Hundreds of thousands of soldiers on the Israeli border are hesitant. During Biden&#39;s visit, he issued &quot;Advice to Israel&quot; and so on. These all prove that the large-scale ground war against Gaza will not only affect Israel&#39;s The international image is more likely to cause further division within Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The situation on the battlefield of public opinion is tense&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a medium for public diplomacy and a window for understanding the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the importance of public opinion is self-evident. With the many conflicts that have broken out in recent years Similarly, the public opinion field is the second battlefield opened by all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, various advanced technological means, such as 5G, streaming media, artificial intelligence and mobile-based social media networks, have made the battlefield of public opinion mixed, making it difficult to distinguish between true and false, and the situation is changing rapidly, which has brought about The &quot;information tide&quot; has a strong ability to induce and differentiate positions and values ​​and create opposing emotions for the public who lack certain professional knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the public opinion war in this Palestinian-Israeli conflict, it has the following three major characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the mature development of streaming media and online live broadcast technology has given global audiences a stronger audio-visual impact on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. The timeliness and impact of information dissemination have greatly increased, and it has also provided opportunities for the proliferation of false information. It has provided a breeding ground for various conspiracy theories, historical-realistic information confusion and propaganda, and fake accounts and robot trolls have emerged one after another on social media. While expanding attention, it has also set off a confrontation between the two factions around the world. These include positional opposition (supporting Israel or supporting Pakistan), religious opposition (Judaism and Islam), ethnic opposition (Arabs and Jews), and intra-sect opposition (moderate factions exist within both Arabs and Jews). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Hamas launched its attack, it used heavy bulldozers to break through the Gaza separation wall and carry out bloody killings inside the Israeli border posts. The video was broadcast live on the Internet. This video set off a new wave of sectarianism in the Arab world. , nationalistic sentiments, but also directly angered groups sympathetic to Jews. It is precisely because of the popularity of the Internet and mobile devices that war has achieved a certain form of visibility and transparency, and has become a hotbed and soil for breeding public opinion wars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, when the Western media reported on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the wording was the Israel-Hamas War, not the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. This highlights the asymmetric nature of the conflict and is a precautionary endorsement of a potential high-intensity Israeli military strike. Hidden behind this is the challenge to the loopholes in international law and the laws of war. Because the laws of war are applicable to sovereign states, the Israeli Defense Forces&#39; attack on Hamas is most likely to be a &quot;police-like war.&quot; Such a narrative will also separate the public from the perspective of ethnic and religious conflicts. The legitimacy of the war on terrorism is obviously greater than the battle for territory. It can be seen that the inclusion of stance in narrative strategies is an eternal pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the public opinion war in this conflict has typical sinking and spillover effects. This conflict has transcended the conflicts between Palestine and Israel and Kazakhstan and Israel, and has shown a trend of spillover and camp formation. Currently, both sides are working hard to seek legitimacy for the war, and have moved from the level of international authoritative media to the level of mass entertainment media. The two sides are competing for the right to speak across the air in other countries. This is not common in previous war conflicts, but it is inevitable for the vigorous development of modern information technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, after Israel announced the dissolution of its Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs, it has in a sense reaped the consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Hamas publicly released two old Israeli women. A video of them shaking hands with masked Hamas members and saying goodbye went viral on social platforms, and they later faced dozens of reporters. , the released elderly people said that Hamas treated them very friendly and responded to their requests. The accounts of those who have witnessed it are extremely impactful, which has compressed the public opinion space in Israel now and even for a long time in the future, and also caused doubts in the Israeli media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The game between Palestine and Israel has never stopped when narrating the war. The mutual siege is not only a portrayal of the real battlefield, but also a manifestation of online public opinion. This is a microcosm of the structural contradiction between Palestine and Israel in the field of international political communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(The author Yang Fuxin is an assistant researcher at the Institute of Environmental Studies at Zhejiang International Studies University; Ma Xiaolin is a professor at Zhejiang International Studies University and an environmental Director of the Mediterranean Institute)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[难以推开的石门，看完很扎心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 22:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;In recent years, female-themed works have exploded, but most of them Focusing on the plight of urban women, there are still very few films with small town women as protagonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which was recently released on streaming media, is a precious image of the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The directors of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; are rising independent film stars Huang Ji and Otsuka Ryuji, who are a husband-and-wife team. The two co-produced the &quot;Women&#39;s Trilogy&quot; &quot;Eggs and Stones&quot;, &quot;Stupid Bird&quot; and this &quot;Stone Gate&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;391&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in Hunan In the small town, Huang Ji&#39;s perspective mainly focuses on the survival plight of rural women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eggs and Stones&quot; focuses on the left-behind girls who were sexually assaulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stupid Bird&quot; &quot;Through the carrier of &quot;mobile phone&quot;, it shows the growing confusion of left-behind girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height= &quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot; It takes the experiences of female college student Lin Sen as a slice to reflect reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ages of the heroines in the trilogy are consistent, they are 14, 17 and 20 years old respectively, and the same actor Yao Honggui was chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is more mature than the previous two films. The film style is very similar to the early works of domestic sixth-generation directors that we are familiar with. It uses non-professional actors, talks about marginalized groups, and prefers extreme Life-like scenes and an objective and calm perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the kernel , with Huang Ji’s own characteristics and personal experience, his friend and work partner Otsuka Ryuji can also make some observations about the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The narrative of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; relies on the three identities of a 20-year-old girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, she is Lin Sen, a beautiful female college student, studying as a flight attendant at a vocational school. She has a stable relationship with her boyfriend Liu Long, who even paid for her to enroll in an English training class. With the unexpected pregnancy, Lin Sen&#39;s life also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen&#39;s My parents run a small clinic. The father is disabled, the mother is addicted to micro-business, and a medical accident that caused a female patient to miscarry made the family worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sensible Lin In order to help his family pay off debts, Sen started working crazily to earn money. She worked as an opening welcome model and also went to shopping malls to sell milk powder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height= &quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpected pregnancy and Family debt caused Lin Sen&#39;s originally peaceful life to plummet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen has no intention of becoming a mother, her boyfriend cannot be held responsible, and her creditor wants a child. With the help of her parents, she agreed to an incredible plan to give birth to a child to pay off the debt to the poor woman &quot;Yinfang&quot; who unfortunately had a miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pregnancy is a unique life experience for women. The difficulties unmarried young women face when they have an unexpected pregnancy, whether to have an abortion or not, are common themes in feminist films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Romanian film &quot;April, Three Weeks and Two Days&quot; and the French film &quot;As It Happens&quot; are both set in the last century when abortion was not accepted by most countries. Due to the complex social status quo, women Uterine autonomy is often not possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American movie &quot; &quot;Juno&quot; and the Norwegian film &quot;Ninja Babies&quot; focus on the physical changes and mental stress that pregnancy and childbirth bring to women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In domestic movies , Li Yu&#39;s &quot;Beautiful Beauty&quot; also reproduces the various pressures faced by women after unexpected pregnancy, mainly due to the relatively conservative social public opinion environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference in &quot;Stone Gate&quot; lies in the alternative way of handling the heroine Lin Sen&#39;s pregnancy - not having an abortion but abandoning her for adoption. ‍‍‍‍‍‍Children are also used as a commodity to solve her immediate life problems. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, this is Lin Sen’s active choice, but the film also pays attention to the soft coercion she suffered. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like at the beginning of the film, her boyfriend took her to an English speaking training venue. Others were communicating freely, and the topic revolved around the country they wanted to go to. After Lin Sen found that she couldn’t fit in, she went to the Start playing with your phone on the sofa. She has no strong desire to improve her English. She came here because her boyfriend took the initiative to make the choice for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;842&quot; height= &quot;375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍This one , we can clearly feel the girl Lin Sen&#39;s numbness towards life and new life, the lack of vitality and confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high frequency of static shots in the film further exaggerates this sense of silent despair. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen She rarely showed her emotions. Even when her boyfriend asked for an abortion, she didn&#39;t make a fuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the pain in her breasts during pregnancy and the tearing during childbirth, as well as Lin Sen’s unbearable expression and voice, tell us that her pain is indeed real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In pain and In confusion, she gradually lost control of her destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The plot of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is not complicated, but the film is 147 minutes long because the director placed many shots on the social landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many scenes, Lin Sen does not participate in the main narrative, appearing as a background board and becoming a silent observer. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, she would watch her boyfriend shoot a Douyin wedding promotional video, and watch underground industry managers openly interview young girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen’s mother Obsessed with selling three-no products and telling his story at the organization&#39;s annual meeting. ‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outbreak Later, crowds of people gathered at medical equipment institutions to buy medical masks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is &quot; The biggest feature of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is also the film&#39;s problem. On the one hand, the unrestrained display of shots greatly affects the rhythm of the narrative, and too many idle strokes make the movie long and boring. On the other hand, it also leads to the heroine becoming a tool, making the entire story biased towards curiosity and lacking the power to move people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although film and television works showing women in small towns have been relatively scarce in recent years, they were not uncommon in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excellent works can maintain an excellent balance in grasping female narratives and social and cultural landscapes. Let’s not mention the classic representative works of the fourth and fifth generation directors, such as &quot;Qiu Ju&#39;s Lawsuit&quot;, &quot;The Love of Humans and Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Beginning of Spring&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here is an example of an unpopular masterpiece - &quot;The Crying Woman&quot;. The director and screenwriter of this film, Liu Bingjian, used the story of Wang Guixiang, a Guizhou woman who made money through mourning, to show the public that China has a long history of funeral culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wang Guixiang Her strong vitality, her shrewd and kind feminine charm, and the warmth and warmth of people in rural society can all leave a deep impression on people. &quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which failed to do this, also formed a contradiction, with its novel subject matter but bland plot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth mentioning that &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is almost the same as a documentary in terms of realism. It is a story that grows out of the shooting environment and the actors&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors who play Lin Sen’s parents are director Huang Ji’s biological parents. They run this clinic in reality, and their home is also the real residence of the director and his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie Filmed over a ten-month period following the pregnancy cycle, and with a limited budget, it didn&#39;t have a set designed in advance like many films, and the actors were thrown directly into real space. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha is the main filming location. The lens captures its glamorous and prosperous side, as well as its chaotic and dark corners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍‍In addition to the director The camera strives to be close to reality, and also tries its best to show the living conditions of girls in non-developed areas. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original setting of the heroine Lin Sen was an imaginary image of a proactive female college student. But this was completely different from the state of actor Yao Honggui at the time, and it was also different from the current situation of many young college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director and his wife rewrote the character design, and the protagonist’s story is a mixed experience of female college students obtained from interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the unexpected pregnancy experience of a small town girl, the film reflects the structural dilemma of this group. It originates from many constraints such as patriarchy, commodity society, and power class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine was The oppression does not occur openly, but it does not mean that multiple exploitation does not exist. This complex structural dilemma creates a low margin for error in women’s choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, it seems that Lin Sen can make different choices, take the initiative to have an abortion, not pay off the debt for his mother, or give birth to a child and raise him, but no life path will become easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are too many stone doors in her life that are difficult to push open, and she can only avoid falling by climbing hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending of the film It is open-ended, and we have no way of knowing the final fate of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the audience can see is that the male employer hopes to postpone the adoption date due to the epidemic. The heroine Lin Sen, who is waiting for the handover, was triggered by the child&#39;s cry and got chest pain and got out of the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it hurts and there is no escape. Escape, the pain is still there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of hope in her life made her breathless. However, instead of floating helplessly in the ocean of life, it is better to fight hard and push open the stone door to try to welcome new life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“上海警察上门抓德牧”成事件：警犬军犬的谣言为何大行其道？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news about &quot;Shanghai police came to arrest German Shepherd&quot; triggered a &quot;storm in a teacup&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was first reported online that on October 24, the police from Wusong District, Shanghai came to the door and seized a 16-year-old German shepherd. The owner surrenders the dog. In the videos and texts circulating on the Internet, the dog has become a &quot;retired police dog&quot; or even a &quot;retired military dog.&quot; The words &quot;18 special police officers in three vehicles broke down the door and caught a 16-year-old dying old dog&quot;. Hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, the Shanghai Wusong Subdistrict Office issued a notice on this matter. The report stated that a resident of Haibin San Village was raising large and aggressive dogs (wolfdogs with hybrid blood) without a license, and had repeatedly walked dogs without leashes and large dogs without muzzles and other illegal dog-raising behaviors. After receiving reports from surrounding residents, police officers from the police station, staff from the Dog Breeding Office, comprehensive law enforcement officials and the district&#39;s special police detachment jointly came to rectify the situation. The dog owner took the initiative to open the door and cooperated with the work, and took the initiative to hand over the dog to the relevant departments for containment and disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After careful review of this incident, there are many contradictions and inconsistencies between the information transmitted online and the official report. Even after the report was released, many people expressed &quot;disbelief&quot; and need to be analyzed one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;bloodline&quot; of the dog involved. Someone on Weibo said it was a retired police dog, but the &quot;uniform&quot; in the video posted online only had &quot;POLICE&quot; in English and no Chinese &quot;police dog&quot;. This is obviously inconsistent with the &quot;standard dress&quot; of domestic police dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the first batch of retired police dogs in Shanghai were opened for adoption on September 5, 2022. The eight police dogs announced at that time were all from the police dog training base of the Songjiang Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau. Bradford, Malinois, Rottweiler, Springer Spaniel, German Shepherd, Doberman, etc., but only one Springer Spaniel and two Labradors are open to the public for adoption, and the remaining five including the German Shepherd are retired Police dogs can only be adopted by units. At the same time, adoptive citizens also need to receive follow-up visits every three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, there is indeed a German Shepherd among the retired police dogs open for adoption in Shanghai, but it was not given to citizens for adoption. Therefore, the rumors that the dogs involved were just &quot;retired police dogs&quot; and &quot;German shepherds&quot; are self-defeating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;retired military dog&quot; theory, there is a lack of any supporting information, and it directly conflicts with the &quot;POLICE uniform&quot; in the online video. China&#39;s &quot;Interim Regulations on the Work of Military Dogs&quot; defines military dogs as special combatants and an integral part of the military&#39;s combat effectiveness. After military dogs retire, they will generally enter military dog ​​breeding and training bases to &quot;live out their old age&quot;. Military dogs with meritorious service will also enjoy recuperation treatment. Even if adoption is open, adopters have very high requirements, including &quot;must love dogs&quot;, &quot;must have experience raising large dogs&quot;, and &quot;cannot be a living environment in an urban community&quot;. Some units will also require adopters to have Military personnel will vouch for them, and they must have a stable income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Zhengzhou 10 million reward for finding retired military dogs&quot; incident on July 9, 2023, the &quot;retired military dog&quot; gimmick instantly proved that this is a &quot;starting picture, the rest are all It’s fake news, because the description in the “reward notice” is completely contrary to the regulations for the adoption of retired military dogs. In this incident, the terms &quot;retired police dog&quot; and &quot;retired military dog&quot; are inconsistent and can be proven to be pure rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether the dog owner’s dog-raising behavior is legal and compliant, and the truth behind the door-to-door rectification actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 12, paragraph 3, of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; passed in 2011 and revised in 2016, prohibits individuals from raising aggressive dogs. Violators of this provision will have the aggressive dogs taken into custody by the public security department. The &quot;Shanghai Catalog of Prohibited Individual Breeding of Violent Dogs&quot; stipulates 24 types of ferocious dogs, including German Shepherds, French Wolfdogs, and Kunming Wolfdogs. Therefore, whether the owner of the dog involved adopts a German shepherd or a hybrid wolfdog, it is undoubtedly a violent dog breed that is prohibited from personal breeding, and dog registration, annual inspection and dog management fees are out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the official report, the owner of the dog involved also engaged in illegal dog-raising behaviors such as walking the dog without a leash and without wearing a muzzle. This is also consistent with the &quot;20 reports from surrounding residents&quot; in the online information. The statement is consistent. Articles 21 and 30 of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; also clearly stipulate that dog owners shall abide by public order and shall not interfere with the normal lives of others. Residents&#39; committees also have the right to formulate and supervise dog breeding conventions or regulations in their residential areas. Management, dog owners should comply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that the illegal dog-raising behavior of the dog owner involved has been confirmed, surrounding residents naturally have the right to report and request the public security department to take in the dog. This request is reasonable and reasonable, and the joint door-to-door rectification by various local departments is also in line with current laws and regulations. Judging from the live videos and pictures, &quot;18 special police officers&quot; is also false information, and relevant social media bloggers have deliberately exaggerated it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this incident also shows that relevant public issues have lost focus, which may not be a blessing to the public interest. Faced with the public issue of &quot;how to regulate dog ownership,&quot; some people are willing to mobilize by creating fake news and create traffic and attention with &quot;tragic narratives.&quot; Similar behavior is no longer a public discussion, but an out-and-out &quot;information war&quot; and &quot;public opinion war&quot; method, trying to blur the focus and muddy the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, laws and regulations regulating dog breeding have been implemented in various places for many years, in order to better protect people&#39;s rights. Dogs are not civil subjects and are the private property of their owners. &quot;Conflict between humans and dogs&quot; is a false issue that does not exist. The real issue is how to regulate dog breeding: only when the premise of protecting human rights is established can we talk about protecting people&#39;s property rights to dogs. Protecting people from being hurt by dogs and preventing &quot;dog bites&quot; should still be a real issue that public opinion pays attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报深圳欢乐谷过山车碰撞事故救治情况：目前17人留院诊治]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259549]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;821&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>