<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[广西官宣“试管婴儿”纳入医保，你怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259594]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the implementation of the three-child policy, many places have intensively released fertility support policies, among which medical insurance provides for assisted reproductive medical services. support is an important measure. For example, in July 2023, Beijing officially included 16 assisted reproductive technologies such as ovulation induction examinations and embryo transfers into medical insurance. Recently, Guangxi has officially announced: &lt;strong>;From November 1, medical services such as &quot;test tube baby&quot; will be included in medical insurance, and up to 70% can be reimbursed&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice mentioned that some therapeutic assisted reproductive medical services such as &quot;ovum retrieval&quot; will be included in the payment scope of basic medical insurance and work-related injury insurance funds; when insured persons enjoy basic medical insurance benefits, there will be no The minimum payment standard for the fund, the reimbursement ratios of basic medical insurance for employees and basic medical insurance for urban and rural residents are 70% and 50% respectively, which are included in the maximum annual fund payment limit for insured persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the authoritative medical journal &quot;The Lancet&quot;: from 2007 to 2020, the incidence of infertility in China has increased from 12% to 18%. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, there will be 9.56 million births in the country in 2022, with one child accounting for less than 50%, and the natural population growth rate is -0.60‰—&lt;strong>;This is the first time that New China has experienced negative population growth since 1961&lt;/strong>; strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some experts said that the inclusion of &quot;test tube babies&quot; in medical insurance will be a good boost to reduce the burden on patients and increase the national fertility rate. At present, there are first-, second- and third-generation IVF technologies, with an average cost of 30,000 to 100,000 yuan. This price will also vary depending on the age and physical quality of the individual. Some experts are cautious. The &quot;reservoir&quot; of medical insurance is limited. If it is included in the scope, it may increase financial pressure. Young people should be encouraged to marry early and have more children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this? Welcome to share your opinions in the message area and I will send you hot comments! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[志向和焦虑并存，留学还是好选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259576]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;International students have lofty dreams, but in the process of pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles, and also have negative feelings about I feel confused about my future. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. All these anxieties force them to think about the ultimate question: Is studying abroad really worth it?</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[东北亚新安全态势初现，如何推动局势缓和？| 智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the post-epidemic era, leaders of various countries have reunited, but they have not yet achieved significant results on political, economic and climate issues. Results. It is difficult for countries to unite collectively and instead prefer small-scale alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, even in Northeast Asia, a similar new security situation has emerged, and the roles of South Korea and China in dealing with the new situation have also attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New security issues emerge in Northeast Asia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 13, the summit held at Camp David, Maryland, brought together the leaders of South Korea, the United States, and Japan to jointly respond to pressing international security issues situation. During the summit, the leaders announced the opening of a &quot;new era of trilateral partnership&quot; and emphasized the three countries&#39; commitment to security cooperation. They held a joint press conference to outline plans and cooperation strategies involving tripartite cooperation, the Camp David Principles and the Camp David Spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the meeting, in order to ensure the stable development of trilateral cooperation between the United States, South Korea and Japan, a cross-level and cross-field systematic cooperation foundation was established. In addition to standardizing the U.S.-South Korea-Japan summit, officials from each country, including the ministers of foreign affairs, defense, and national security advisers, also agreed to hold annual meetings in their respective fields to closely coordinate cooperation plans among the three countries. In addition, the three leaders decided to establish communication channels to facilitate rapid consultation and rapid response when urgent regional issues that threaten the common interests of the three countries arise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to strengthen strategic cooperation among the three countries in the region, the three countries agreed to establish a ministerial-level dialogue called the &quot;U.S.-South Korea-Japan Indo-Pacific Dialogue&quot; and explore new areas of cooperation within the Indo-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the leaders discussed practical cooperation measures to enhance joint operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the United States, South Korea and Japan reiterated their commitment to maintaining an international order based on norms such as sovereignty, territorial integrity and peaceful resolution of conflicts. Similarly, the three countries also agreed to support strengthening maritime security capabilities in ASEAN and the Pacific Island countries when implementing the Indo-Pacific strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, on September 13, Kim Jong-un and Putin held a summit meeting at the Vostok Cosmodrome in Amur Oblast, Russia. This time they met again after about four years and five months since April 2019. The background of the emergency meeting is that North Korea faces strong sanctions mainly imposed by the United States and Western countries. North Korea is subject to United Nations Security Council (UNSC) sanctions and suffers severe food shortages and technological deficiencies. Russia is also facing economic sanctions from the European Union and other countries, and is working hard to solve the long-standing &quot;weapons shortage&quot; problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current international situation, Russia and North Korea are considered unique partners capable of meeting each other&#39;s needs, and the two countries also intend to cooperate in the activities of the United Nations Security Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If new security issues arise in Northeast Asia, South Korea, China, and related countries will experience a vicious cycle of instability in terms of security and broader economies. Resolving the North Korean nuclear issue will also become more complicated, and regional economic development will surely stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;South Korea and China promote cooperation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this context, South Korea and China are one of the major countries with the potential to control this situation. The relationship between the United States and Russia is still hostile, and the bilateral dialogues between the United States and North Korea and between South Korea and North Korea have been stagnant for a long time. South Korea and China can play a key role in mitigating and responding to new security issues in Northeast Asia through cooperation. Therefore, in order to achieve this goal, South Korea and China can cooperate in various ways and contribute to easing tensions in Northeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the trilateral summit between South Korea, China and Japan is a direct opportunity for cooperation. The trilateral summit has been held eight times since 1999. However, the trilateral summit has not been held since December 2019, with South Korea currently chairing the summit. The tripartite summit, which has been suspended for three years, may clear away the dark clouds hanging over Northeast Asia. South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs aims to host a trilateral summit within this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, South Korea and China may hold a summit summit. The summit was proposed by South Korean Prime Minister Han Deok-soo. A recent survey conducted by the South Korean newspaper Mainichi Yonhap Newspaper in collaboration with the public opinion research company Opinion and Public showed that 82.3% of the respondents believed that the South Korea-China summit was &quot;necessary&quot; to be held, while only 11.3% of the respondents believed that &quot; No need&quot;, 6.3% of the respondents were unsure. Regardless of differences in region, age or political affiliation, a majority of respondents believe a summit between the two countries is necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, while rebuilding trust between South Korea and China, it is necessary to activate various security cooperation mechanisms. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations in 1992, South Korea and China have made significant progress in various fields. The relationship between the two countries developed from a good-neighborly and friendly cooperative relationship in 1992 to a China-ROK cooperative partnership for the 21st century in 1998, and further developed to a comprehensive cooperative partnership in 2003, and was upgraded to a strategic cooperative partnership in 2008. However, after the THAAD missile defense system was deployed in South Korea in 2016, relations between the two countries became tense, resulting in restrictions on exchanges and cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the strategic competition between the United States and China and the international order have affected the security exchanges between South Korea and China. The uniqueness of North Korea-China relations and the South Korea-US alliance will also limit exchanges between South Korea and China. Additionally, the political climate may affect communications between South Korea and China, resulting in a lack of substantive agenda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from the perspective of the common national interests of pursuing stability, peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, it is necessary for South Korea and China to resume exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, it is necessary for the two countries to maintain communication channels to resolve sensitive security and military issues and prevent accidental conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea and China are close neighbors, partners and indivisible. Today, cooperation between South Korea and China can jointly dispel the shadows and jointly open up a path to achieve regional stability, peace and prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(Author: Lee Chang-hyung, Director of the Korea Continental Strategic Research Institute, Korea Institute for Defense Analysis; Translator: Zheng Weihao)&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[枪械教官“大开杀戒”，“全美最安全州”响起无差别扫射枪声]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259575]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Year&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;October&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Day&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;The body of Robert Card, was found in the woods near Lisbon, Maine with an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound to the head. In the past two days, Lewiston, Maine, in the northeastern United States where he lives, has almost become a &quot;ghost town.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is the &quot;suspect&quot; in a mass shooting there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, the local police said on social media that a &quot;mobile gunman&quot; was found in Lewiston and asked people to &quot;shelter in place&quot; and &quot;stay at home and Lock the door.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the shooting on the evening of October 25, 2023, the U.S. police have been searching for Card. He carried out indiscriminate killings in a bowling alley and a bar, killing at least 18 people and injuring dozens more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the Lewiston, Maine, police confirmed that the 40-year-old Card was a certified firearms instructor and a member of the U.S. Army Reserves. But this summer, he behaved erratically while training at the U.S. Military Academy and was admitted to a mental health treatment facility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The mass shooting is considered the worst shooting on record in Maine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Once known as &quot;the safest state in the United States&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As one of the least populous states in the United States, the state has high rates of gun ownership but relatively low levels of gun violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The number of victims in this shooting &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; almost equals the number of homicide victims in the state for all of 2022. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Why did the gunman go on a killing spree here?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Why has gun violence erupted on a large scale in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It has become the focus of attention of the international community&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;29&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Day&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Zhang Weiwei, dean of the China Institute at Fudan University who was attending the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing, spoke at the meeting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; about the issue of gun control in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;He once said in a TV program&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the Chinese people’s view of “political Tao” is the overall and long-term interests of the people, using “Tao” To manage the &quot;skills&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;If there is no concept of &quot;political ethics&quot; and only legal provisions, it will be difficult to promote &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;gun control &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; reforms in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 727&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the gun-wielding man shot in Lewiston, Maine, USA on October 25 (video screenshot). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/AP/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Indiscriminate shooting&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 25th&lt;span>;Night&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;If nothing else happens&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A group of young people gathered in the Lewiston bowling alley&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;will spend their &quot;bowling night&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The bowling alley is located approximately 3.2 kilometers north of the Bates College campus, on the outskirts of the city center. There&#39;s also a small bar not far away that&#39;s a popular spot for local bowling leagues and young partygoers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;But soon, a gunshot interrupted the carnival&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;I heard about 10 gunshots, and I thought the first shot was the sound of a balloon popping.&quot;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;A bowler said in an interview with the media&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;When he turned around, what he saw was not a balloon, but a man holding a weapon. man. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Robert Card appeared at the door armed with a semi-automatic rifle. The bowling alley was packed with parents and teenagers, with panicked young bowlers scrambling to hide behind the pins. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The gunfire did not stop because of the panic of the crowd and the crying at the scene, but became more intense. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Then&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Card began to face the crowd without mercy. Differential shooting. Immediately after&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;he chose to change a place&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;continue to cause tragedy in the bar&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In less than &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; minutes, the police received a large number of calls from the bar. Police phone number&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;People said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kard continued to shoot&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in the bar. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;But the Lewiston police were still a step slower. After Card fired continuously and wildly&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; drove away and fled&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;He was not caught on the spot&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dr. John Alexander, the local chief medical officer, said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This time The attack was &quot;unprecedented&quot; for the small city. About 50 medical providers, nurses, respiratory therapists and surgeons responded to the call to help treat victims, he said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After the incident&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The streets of Lewiston were empty and huge. Signs remind people to lock their doors and stay&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; indoors. The whole city came to a standstill due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;this crazy shooting case&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a city 50 miles (80 kilometers) away from the shooting scene, schools, doctor&#39;s offices and grocery stores&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; All closed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Meanwhile&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Portland, Maine’s largest city, closed its public &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;facilities&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The Canada Border Services Agency issued an &quot;armed and dangerous&quot; alert to officials stationed at the U.S. border. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;People are anxious and silently praying that the police can catch the murderer sooner&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;At the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;next day&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; morning press conference, Maine The commissioner of the state Department of Public Safety&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that more than one hundred police investigators&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;including&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Federal agents &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are also &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; involved, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in full swing &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; throughout the city&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Search for the murderer, leaving no corner that can be easily hidden. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Police in Maine said the suspect had recently&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;appeared&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mentally Health concerns, including &quot;hearing voices and threats to shoot at a military installation in southern Maine.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;His &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;sister-in-law Katie Card&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;accepting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the media&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;In the interview, he stated that his family had reported to the police and the army that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; was experiencing a serious mental health crisis&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Rick Goddard, a neighbor of the Card family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;being interviewed by the media&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Shi&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; said that a few weeks ago&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; looked &quot;completely normal.&quot; Goddard lives&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;near the incident site&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and knows the Card family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and revealed&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is where Card grew up&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;every ledge hidden behind, every&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;The&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;bush,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade is very familiar with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Kade has received training as a firearms instructor, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Member of the U.S. Army Reserve&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Police said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kade &quot;heard voices&quot; and threatened to blow up a &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;military&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;base. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;So&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;he was sent to a mental hospital, but he only stayed there&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;for two weeks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;Leaved&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is reported that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the gunman used a gun with an extended magazine and Semi-automatic assault rifle with scope. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The gunman’s firearm is very powerful.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Deputy Director of the Northeast Asia Research Center of Shanghai University of Political Science and Law&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Yang Zhen analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the gun used by the gunman this time was an AR -15 type rifle, this model is shorter than a baseball bat, lighter than a bowling ball, cheap, simple to shoot, has slight recoil, easy to aim, and has a large number of copies, making it easy to obtain parts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is unclear how or when &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Kard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; obtained the shot Firearms used in the incident. The motive for the shooting is still unclear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Judging from the modus operandi and past experience, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The shooter&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;may have suffered psychological trauma, distorted personality, and has not received effective treatment for a long time&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;so it is possible&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Anti-social and anti-human tendencies caused by external factors stimulation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Before&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Before the gunman was caught&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A shadow falls over &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Until&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;local time&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; year &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;October&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;month&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; on the evening of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The state&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; held an emergency press conference&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Public Safety Commissioner Michael Sawchak said Card&#39;s body was found &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; near the Androscoggin River in the Lisbon Falls area. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It is about 10 kilometers away from the place where the shooting occurred. Card died of an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;When &quot;safest&quot; becomes unsafe&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Gunmen with military backgrounds carry out mass shootings&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is not an exception in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;For example, in 2018, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;there was &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; shot and killed in a Thousand Oaks bar. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Innocent&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;people’s &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;former Marine Corps&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;team members, and in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a church&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Sutherland Springs, Texas&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Air Force veteran who shot and killed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;26&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; people. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;U.S. Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) Agent Ferguson said the weapons used in the shooting were purchased legally and said &quot;more than three&quot; guns were found. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the list of &quot;Top 10 Safest States in the United States&quot; by U.S. News &amp; World Report&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ranks among the best&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;While Democrats control the governorship and both chambers of the state Legislature, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Maine has long resisted guns. Control measures &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;because &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;hunting is an integral part of the culture there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This year&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the Maine House of Representatives &lt;/span>;&lt; A measure to strengthen background checks for private gun sales was approved in June, but the proposal failed in the state Senate. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In addition&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the state House of Representatives also passed &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; a bill &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;banning&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Possess, sell, or manufacture&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;bump stocks and other rapid-fire modified devices&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, but the bill was also blocked by the Maine Senate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is worth noting that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine allows the purchase of certain Assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and no &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;similar&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; written extreme risk protection statute. These measures, also known as &quot;red flag laws,&quot; allow law enforcement or family members to seek an order from a judge to temporarily restrict someone&#39;s access to a gun if they believe they pose a threat to themselves or others. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to a 2020 RAND Corporation study, between 2006 and 2017, 45% of Maine households had at least a gun, compared to the national average of 32%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The state has high rates of gun ownership but relatively low levels of gun violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The number of victims in this shooting nearly matches the state’s homicide total for all of 2022. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Many US media revealed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that this shooting incident marked the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; 36th mass &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; shooting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; incident that has occurred in the United States this year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Based on&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;United States&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gunviolencearchive. org/&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guns&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Violence Archive data&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span>;, as of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;On October 26, at least 35,275 people died from gun violence in the United States this year, with an average of nearly 118 deaths every day. Suicides account for the vast majority of gun violence deaths this year. This year 19,734 people died by firearm suicide&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023 is expected to be the deadliest year on record for mass shootings in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is noteworthy that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Maine Governor Janet. Mills is a Democratic attorney general. On October 25, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Biden had a phone call with him and expressed that the White House would provide support to Maine&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Zhen believes that the United States is currently experiencing internal and external troubles, especially the U.S. presidential election, which has actually begun to have undercurrents of politics. struggle. Biden&#39;s move is, on the one hand, a show to the public, and on the other hand, it is an attempt to pull Janet away and help her survive the subsequent criticism and accountability. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;Confrontational Thinking&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The gun problem in the United States is an old problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Whenever a U.S. president ambitiously wants to reform the gun trade&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;, members of Congress will show very fierce opposition. In the end, the president often compromises with members of Congress, and the issue goes away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei, Director of the Institute of International Affairs at Renmin University of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Talked to Southern Weekend reporters&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;There is no way to completely eradicate&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;gun violence&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in the United States. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Just like treating every presidential election as a &quot;venting tube&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Violent shootings in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Be regarded as&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;more extreme&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;venting&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After hundreds of years of development in the United States, the gun trade has formed a huge vested interest group. These vested interests established a so-called &quot;National Rifle Association.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The association provides nearly 90% of the funding for anti-gun control activities in the United States .&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen said&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the association also uses monetary donations to win over members of Congress to influence legislation. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From this point of view, gun control in the United States is a dead end. The constant occurrence of shootings has plunged this dead end into an endless loop&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; .&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thinks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The frequent shooting cases in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is an &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;old and persistent disease&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. The United States has had a tradition of carrying guns since the founding of the country, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and then&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;later turned into a constitutional amendment,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;now&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Plus the Rifle Association has hijacked this culture of violence&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After this mass shooting&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sought re-election In a White House statement, Biden mentioned legislation he has enacted to reduce gun violence. Biden said, &quot;While we have made progress on gun safety through the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act and the establishment of the first White House Office of Gun Violence Prevention, it is not enough.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; urged that Republican lawmakers &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; should &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; pass the ban as early as &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Assault weapons bill, universal background checks for gun manufacturers and ending&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;liability immunity, &quot;fulfilling our responsibility to protect the American people.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen believes that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The Biden administration is currently beleaguered internally and externally and is in dire straits. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“In this context, gun ban is just a disease of mustard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;He added&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Just put on a posture and deal with it, it is unlikely that there will be a follow-up&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, they&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;We have neither the ability nor the will to completely solve this problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;However, people are still paying attention&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Why have there been so many shootings in the United States in recent years? Not only is there no &quot;cooling down&quot;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; but it is getting worse&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On October 16, 2023, the FBI released a latest investigation report. This report details the crime situation in American society in 2022. According to the report, in 2022, hate crime cases across the United States have reached 11,634. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Visible&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The phenomenon of hate crimes in American society is clearly visible to the naked eye. Visible rates are spreading rapidly. Conflicts between white people and people of color, conflicts between local residents and immigrants, and conflicts between different political factions have erupted intensively in American society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thinks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; At present, there are many contradictory problems in the United States&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;such as the advocating of individualism&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the culture of violence&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Oppositional thinking&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Social tearing&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Race Conflicts, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;Currently, the entire American society is in a state of division. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Now the United States continues to &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;be &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; belligerent&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Whether it is support for Israel&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;or exporting a violent war culture everywhere&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;definitely It affects the people in the country&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot; Wang Yiwei&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;analyzed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;including the so-called To defend personal freedom&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the freedom to permanently hold a gun, etc., guns are often used to resolve dissatisfaction with society, especially those who are well-trained in the military&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Military&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen believes that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in recent years, the United States has taken more aggressive actions toward foreign countries, which has not only intensified social conflicts , and worsened the financial situation. Once the financial situation is poor, it will inevitably lead to a reduction in investment in social governance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He analyzed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that the United States is a country of immigrants, and the increase in foreign aggressive behavior will lead to an increase in social conflicts. ,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to a much higher degree than other countries. Poor social governance has led to the proliferation of guns and insufficient police force, which will naturally lead to frequent shootings. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;It is worth noting that since 2020, the FBI has conducted The number of investigations into cases of terrorism and extremism has more than doubled. The Justice Department has established a new domestic counterterrorism unit to respond to the evolving security landscape. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The divisions in American society are still intensifying&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Yang Zhen judged&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that next year’s US general election will further tear apart American society and intensify class conflicts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:25:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》专访，导演邱礼涛，“我要拍巨变的年代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259584]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1部手机配8个壳：当年轻人不换手机爱换手机壳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259376]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9sNwIITCv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/KBFUSLEv34V8c4MQjy4j8GEE1pNRRQ9s NwIITCv2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a certain brand’s 1,999 yuan mobile phone case has caused heated discussion. Previously, a mobile phone with 8 mobile phone cases has also become a hot search topic, and discussions about mobile phone cases have become increasingly popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, it costs thousands of yuan to replace a mobile phone, but it may only cost a few yuan to replace a mobile phone case. The dazzling array of mobile phone cases has gradually become a Mobile phone replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moreover, young people seem to be less and less fond of changing their mobile phones. An iResearch consulting report shows that 79.5% of Generation Z change their mobile phones within 1 to 3 years. At the same time, a research report from Ping An Securities stated that the time it takes for Chinese users to change their phones has lengthened from 28 months to 43 months, reaching a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A mobile phone made of iron and a mobile phone case as smooth as water. Since 2017, the market size of mobile phone cases has continued to expand, doubling in five years. Different from the &quot;one machine and one shell&quot; of the elders, contemporary young people are keen to play &quot;dress up show&quot; on their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although a popular poll on Weibo shows that half of netizens will choose mobile phone cases with a price of less than 9.9 yuan, major mobile phone brands have embarked on a trend of skyrocketing mobile phone case prices. road. The lowest price of mobile phone cases sold on Apple&#39;s official website is 398 yuan, while Huawei&#39;s latest Mate 60 RS Extraordinary Master Edition mobile phone case, Star Diamond Smart Window Protective Cover, is priced at 1,999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;CASETiFY, known as the &quot;Hermès&quot; of mobile phone cases, is the best-selling Hello Kitty and Sanrio co-branded model on Taobao, priced at 439 yuan. More than 1,000 people placed orders. With the blessing of the star&#39;s same style effect, Zhao Lusi&#39;s same style, TNT&#39;s same style, etc. attract star-chasing girls to donate generously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mobile phone cases have also become a fashionable item in the DIY industry. Cream glue, acrylic, and diamond stickers are all materials that can never limit the imagination of mobile phone case modifications. In many DIY shops in Guangzhou, the cost of DIYing a mobile phone case is about 30 to 100 yuan, making it a new choice for many sisters&#39; gatherings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of many people, a small mobile phone case actually provides a space for self-expression. Young people can find people who like the same anime and TV series through mobile phone cases. A close friend of the same celebrity, or some mobile phone cases themselves convey their own values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk to you about why young people are keen on &quot;wholesale&quot; mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/55373e95c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/2d54bdaac5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/62e734b882.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/9d648c4144.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255641&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/26/687c278ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /687c278ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26 /3314847adf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3314847adf.png&quot; data -key=&quot;255643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么钱买不来“父慈子孝”？富裕家庭面临价值观代际断裂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259531]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Youdao means that &quot;one can only know the etiquette by being practical&quot;. In the era of material abundance, the atmosphere within the family is relaxed, and &quot;the father is kind to the son.&quot; filial piety&quot;. Especially wealthy families or middle-class families with better economic conditions do not have the stress and oppression of material scarcity, and parents are able to provide their children with more choices and express their deep love. The better the economic conditions, the sweeter the relationship between relatives. This seems to be a law that needs no proof. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from many social news reports, this conclusion is quite unreliable. It seems that the family ties of wealthy or well-to-do middle-class families have not become generally better because of money. Discord between relatives is still quite common; the tense relationship between parents and children does not seem to be any better than in ordinary families. It can be seen that some problems cannot be solved by money alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the contemporary young &quot;old people&quot; or so-called &quot;professional children&quot; have good family backgrounds, and their parents are middle-class or above - otherwise they cannot support their family&#39;s long-term public and postgraduate entrance examinations. This kind of family atmosphere can be imagined. Most parents support and complain at the same time. Their children are bored and unable to leave. There were many cases where the quarrel was so loud that the family relationship was broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents who give large betrothal gifts and buy houses and cars for their children are essentially providing for them. The children are all adults and can take away a large amount of their parents&#39; property at once, which is rare in other countries. It would be fine if we could get a harmonious relationship, but the reality is often that the money is not enough, the support cannot be exchanged for gratitude, and family relationships become tense or even broken, which is a common farce or even tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the above are just the worries of ordinary middle-class families, are wealthy families (rich or wealthy middle-class families) better off? Not sure. In recent years, life has been difficult for some wealthy people, and many overseas students have experienced reduced or even cut-off funding. In a short period of time, there have been many complaints on Xiaohongshu: the standard of living has dropped, what you want to buy cannot be afforded, and the standards of accommodation and tourist hotels have been downgraded. Others complained about their parents and worried that their life studying abroad would be ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who can support their children to study abroad and enjoy a high standard of living are considered wealthy in China. The family has financial difficulties and has to cut back on children&#39;s expenses. This is probably the last resort for most parents to reduce expenses. These adult children did not feel anxious or worried about their parents, but instead focused on the small gains in front of them. This is so heartless and is enough to upset many parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the above cannot be inferred that poor families have better family relationships, but it is to point out that many families have substantial wealth accumulation, and parents pay more for their children, but they fail to get a better family. relation. When a new generation of young people witness this situation, their confidence in having children will be easily affected. Many people even think that raising children is completely wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did things come to this? Seeing this, traditionalists say: Filial piety has been lost. From the perspective of traditional ethics, many children&#39;s behavior can indeed be called unfilial, but this set of values ​​has no market in the contemporary era. Young people simply do not listen, and parents have no confidence to speak out. Blaming young people will not solve the problem at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essence of conflict between family members is still a conflict of values. In traditional society, several generations share a set of values ​​and have roughly the same lifestyle, but in modern society, this is different. Most parents represent traditional values, while their children are more up-to-date, so estrangement is inevitable. Especially in the past 100 years or so, China has been rapidly experiencing the disintegration of tradition. The generation gap between two and three generations is unprecedentedly deep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Value differences do not necessarily evolve into actual conflicts. The conflict between adult children and parents is also a game of voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as the children surpass their parents’ achievements and prove with facts that the later wave surpasses the previous wave, even if the parents are dissatisfied, it is just irrelevant nagging. After the parents retired safely, their differences finally disappeared and they became a harmonious relationship of &quot;father is kind and son is filial&quot;. After a poor family becomes prosperous, the relationship between father and son is still harmonious for the most part. The reason is that power is transferred smoothly within the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But not all children can surpass their parents’ achievements. Especially parents who succeeded in their early years and led their families into the ranks of affluence, their insight and ability are extraordinary, and their accumulated resource circle is beyond the reach of their fledgling children. On the one hand, parents work hard to provide resources for their children and help them grow; on the other hand, their achievements are difficult for future generations to overcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To give a simple example, both husband and wife are top academics, but there are actually very few children who can get into the school where their parents graduated. This is just one part of the exam. In the fierce social competition, it has become the norm that children cannot surpass excellent parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents are confident that the values ​​they believe in are still valid. This is the experience they rely on for success. They provide financial support to their children and provide guidance and criticism. The children are accustomed to a comfortable life and do not feel inappropriate about their parents&#39; support (once their parents refuse to support them, the children will inevitably resent it), but at the same time they have new ideas and can easily become disgusted with their parents&#39; instructions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we get older and our children grow older, the elders’ voice has been declining for a long time, and conflicts within the family are inevitable. In families with many children or in the classical era of primogeniture, conflicts will not be too intense - parents will use property inheritance rights to restrain their children, and the latter will consciously move closer to their parents. Contemporary trends are entirely detrimental to parents and beneficial to children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how powerful parents are, due to legal restrictions, their binding force on their children is destined to become weaker. The new generation of children are mostly only children, so they naturally inherit the family business. Even if the ability is low and the words and deeds are outrageous, there will be almost no substantive punishment. This emboldened them. It is not difficult to understand that rich people cannot control their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trend cannot be reversed. If wealthy families or wealthy middle-class families want to alleviate intergenerational conflicts, they can only fundamentally coordinate the values ​​of the two generations. The responsibility falls on parents: they need to pay special attention to their children&#39;s values. Especially as parents of entrepreneurs, they cannot only provide their children with favorable living conditions, but allow their values ​​to go into the opposite direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The job of an entrepreneur is to judge consumer needs, discover market gap opportunities, provide products and services smartly, and obtain benefits that exceed those of ordinary working-class people. Entrepreneurs do not do specific labor, but create wealth by organizing production and discovering opportunities. Sometimes it is hard to make a small amount of money, sometimes it is easy to make a big fortune. Entrepreneurs are both envied and often hated and misunderstood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Understanding the work of entrepreneurs requires long-term study and in-depth understanding. Classical entrepreneurs require long-term training to train successors, teach them through words and deeds, and examine their abilities and conduct. This is the process of value transfer. When contemporary entrepreneurs educate their children, most of them entrust their education to schools and provide them with all financial support instead of imparting values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Send their children to study abroad and receive elite or business school education, thinking that this will broaden their horizons and surpass their parents&#39; abilities. The result is obvious: the sons and daughters of entrepreneurs have been separated from the business world for a long time. They often only know how to consume and not produce, and finally show their mediocrity in real market competition. It is not uncommon for children to fall into depravity due to lack of parental restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary European and American education is the stronghold of far-left ideology, and campuses are filled with various &quot;progressive&quot; ideologies. Anti-capital, anti-corporate, anti-patriarchal, and anti-family ideas are prevalent. Rich Chinese send their children to study in the hope that they will inherit the family business. However, they are likely to usher in &quot;unworthy children.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Economist Mises analyzed this phenomenon in his book &quot;The Anti-Capitalist Mentality&quot;. In Mises&#39;s era, businessmen and entrepreneurs usually had many children and usually only one heir. They inherited the values ​​of their fathers and worked hard to manage their industries. The second son, evil son, illegitimate son or close relative child (such as nephew) who is &quot;abandoned&quot; by the family will lose the right to inheritance early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These people live a comfortable life and have a good education, but they are full of prejudices and misunderstandings about their fathers&#39; business operations. They are so arrogant that they think that through thinking and transformation, they can surpass their parents and those in charge of the industry. Mises called this phenomenon &quot;nephew&#39;s resentment.&quot; This can largely explain why in the era of great turmoil, some people who could live a comfortable life actually embarked on the path of &quot;rebellion&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although what contemporary entrepreneurs face is not so extreme, the phenomenon of value rupture is very similar. Worshiping elite education, ignoring the inheritance of family education, and intergenerational fractures in family values. To make matters worse, most contemporary entrepreneurs have few children, and the family business is in danger of having no successors. The elders are anxious but unable to do anything, while the children take it in stride. This difference in attitude exacerbates tensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[洞穴潜水圈里的门派江湖：关于金钱、性命和纪录的游戏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, the Jiudun skylight salvage site. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/80dc0f47c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 16, 2023, Jiudun skylight salvage site. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiudun Skylight, which is well-known in the cave diving world, has another name - the source. People living in Daxing Town, Duan County, Guangxi call this underwater cave. It is connected to the underground river and is the birthplace of Chengjiang River, which runs from north to south and is 42 kilometers long. The surface of the water is unremarkable, a pool of clear water lies beside the national highway. Under the clear water, caves unique to karst landforms extend toward the center of the earth. As for the depth, it is still unexplored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deep and mysterious cave is shrouded in charming colors. Cave diving enthusiasts wearing black quick-drying suits and carrying air bottles gather here all year round. Wei Caifeng, a 58-year-old villager, opened a restaurant near the source, and divers are regular customers. She couldn&#39;t understand why these people were still keen to dive here if this cave was so dangerous. She counted on her fingers the divers who died here: one in 2022, two in 2021, one eight years ago, and including Han Ting in 2023, there are already five. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the most dangerous extreme sports, a small mistake can kill divers, but the dark cave still attracts them. It is a scenic spot but also an abyss; it is a playground and a fair of fame and fortune; it is a place where life flourishes and where death is quiet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Each breath costs 7 yuan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Han Ting went into the water for the last time, he ate egg fried rice from Wei Caifeng’s shop. At six or seven o&#39;clock in the evening on October 7, Wei Caifeng fried a pot of egg fried rice for eight people and brought it to the skylight for nine meals. She told Han Ting and his party to put the pot at the door of the store if they had time after eating. &quot;Han Ting comes to my house for dinner every time. He is very gentle and smiles every time he comes back. It is such a pity (this happened).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, to break the cave diving World record: 46-year-old Han Ting (nicknamed Lao Mao in the circle) died during diving training and his body fell on a slope about 113 meters deep in the North Cave of Jiudun Tianchuang. After losing contact for 18 days, the media followed up and reported that the life of this Zhejiang native, known as &quot;Asia&#39;s No. 1 Diver&quot;, began to become more widely known. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting’s unexpected death has made most people in the diving community feel sorry for him. But in this dangerous extreme sport, this result does not seem surprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Duan, there are many dangerous caves like Jiudun Skylight. As a member of the Guangxi underground cave exploration project, 43-year-old Wei Jie often looks for such underwater caves everywhere. He claims to have visited about 150 caves, 80% of which are untouched. Domestic cave diving started relatively late, only starting around 2010. &quot;It is still in its infancy. The United States started in the 1970s, and we are 40 years behind others,&quot; Wei Jie said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie said that there are many natural caves available for diving in Guangxi, such as Liuzhou, Guilin and other cities. The average cave depth is about 80 meters, while the average depth of the famous Duan is about 300 meters. Many cave diving enthusiasts told Southern Weekend reporters that domestically, Du&#39;an&#39;s cave resources are ranked first. Compared with international comparisons, &quot;Du&#39;an&#39;s cave diving is relatively difficult.&quot; The underwater visibility is average. The cave is too deep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of technical diving, cave diving and deep diving have higher risks. Xu Tianhua, who started technical diving in 2018, told Southern Weekend reporters that his foreign diving instructor was invited to Du&#39;an more than ten years ago to conduct a cave evaluation to see whether it was suitable for development into a tourist resource. The assessment concluded that it is not suitable for large-scale promotion, &quot;the depth is too deep and the risk is very high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the high risk, the high investment of time and money also makes this sport more difficult to promote. Many interviewees said that they have spent up to one million yuan on diving in the past few years. In addition to purchasing training courses, equipment, and various expenses incurred by diving around the world, there are also some consumables, such as Helium. The cylinders used by divers to dive contain a mixture of compressed gases, mostly containing oxygen, nitrogen and helium. The market price of helium is about 7 cents/liter. When a diver dives to 100 meters, each breath he takes costs about 7 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie said frankly that in the cave diving circle, cave diving enthusiasts who do not make a living as instructors are mostly high-net-worth individuals. They often come from first-tier cities. There are some self-employed coal and mining bosses. Most of them are over 35 years old, and of course there are some young rich second generations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high threshold has made cave diving a veritable niche extreme sport. According to many people in the cave diving circle, there are only about 100 active divers in China with full cave diving licenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not every cave dive is a desperate effort&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Jiang Yuchen from Beijing did not expect that he would embark on the path of cave diving. Six years ago, he and his mother started diving together as diving partners. At that time, he suffered from depression, and diving was used as a long-term and effective treatment for him. He described that after diving into the cave, it was like returning to his mother&#39;s womb and feeling very peaceful. But things are not calm above the water. Jiang Yuchen can often see his disapproving and angry remarks in the news about cave divers’ accidents: “They say we are full of food and are seeking death, and we are irresponsible.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie pessimistically believes that Dongqian is meaningless except for the value of &quot;self-realization&quot;. In his opinion, underwater archeology, salvage, and construction are valuable, but their normal diving does not involve these. “It’s all for fun. Your actions are not of any help to this society, but only satisfy yourself. Many of us It’s time to dive for the sake of diving.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after entering the cave, Wei Jie seemed to have left the &quot;theory of meaning&quot; behind. He described it to a Southern Weekend reporter as the pleasure of being in an uninhabited land: &quot;Maybe you are the first to arrive. Human beings here, every ray of your light is the first ray of light that the world shines on this cave, or even the only ray of light.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from Wei Jie&#39;s &quot;meaningless&quot; view, the same Li Wen, an enthusiast, believes that cave diving is not only exciting, but also very rigorous. &quot;Rigorous means that this is not a competitive sport, not about who is stronger or who is more powerful, but a management sport. It is about yourself.&quot; A movement to get yourself into a better state.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 18, 2023, in a cave in Du&#39;an County, Li Wen and his party were preparing to dive. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/30/11fd3a26bb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023 , in a cave in Duan County, Li Wen and his party were preparing to dive. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For cave diving, every enthusiast has his or her own reasons and pursuits. Some people do it to see fish, some people do it for healing, and some people do it to break through themselves. &quot;Different starting points will lead to different final results.&quot; said a cave diving enthusiast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all interviewees agreed that although most cave diving is dangerous, the risks are controllable and even safe. Xu Tianhua said that every time he goes into the water, he takes into account the risks he faces and has various methods to deal with the risks. &quot;It&#39;s not what you imagine. Every dive seems to be like trying your best.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Once something goes wrong, we will withdraw according to the emergency plan and will not stay there. The hole is there There, whether you dive today or tomorrow, it is all there, it doesn&#39;t matter if it happens overnight.&quot; Wei Jie agreed with Han Ting&#39;s previous point of view, &quot;Cave diving is an art of giving up. You can give up any dive at any time, but never Don&#39;t give up on yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Risks are not static. For Han Ting, the Asian cave diving record holder, challenging the world record means challenging the limits of mankind, and with the arrival of the limit comes incalculable unknown risks. &quot;Risks and challenges coexist. It&#39;s like a scale, self-fulfillment or self-destruction, whichever side leans more,&quot; Wei Jie said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Challenging the limits is not acceptable to all cave diving enthusiasts. &quot;Competitiveness and desire are called bad motives for us and should be avoided. If your purpose of diving is for performance, then you may not be suitable for our philosophy.&quot; Li Wen is 39 years old and has 10 years of cave diving. experience, but he refused to reveal his deepest dive record - &quot;I don&#39;t think this is something worth publicizing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four sects, two differences&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this concept The difference is due to different cave diving systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, there are four active cave diving systems in China, namely PASI, TDI, IANTD and WUD. Except for WUD, which is a domestically created system, the other three are all originated from abroad. Li Wen said that different systems have different concepts of cave diving, and the training process is also slightly different, but &quot;almost 95% are the same.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the number of people in the water as an example. Systems such as WUD emphasize the importance of the team and stipulate that there must be two or more divers traveling together. But in the PASI system and TDI system where Han Ting works, divers have more opportunities to dive alone. &quot;As long as there are two people involved in the potential accident like the old cat&#39;s accident, it may not necessarily happen.&quot; analyzed Wei Jie, who is a member of the WUD system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Tianhua feels that &quot;it is difficult to find divers of the same level to form a team to dive at depths like Laomao.&quot; Xiao Liang, who has taken Han Ting diving courses and belongs to the TDI system, believes that when diving in a &quot;small space and large depth&quot;, the matching of divers&#39; abilities is also very important. &quot;If the abilities do not match, the two together will not be able to survive.&quot; Take care of another person. Sometimes it’s safer to be alone.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small circle of about a hundred people, apart from whether to allow solo diving, another major disagreement lies in whether to pursue depth. Many interviewees admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that there is indeed a trend of comparison in the industry. &quot;There was also an era abroad that pursued depth, but it seems to be gone now,&quot; Li Wen said. Wei Jie said bluntly: &quot;No one is convinced by the other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to different systems, this small circle has formed different &quot;sects&quot;. &quot;Let me make an analogy, just like the movie &#39;Young and Dangerous&#39;, each gang has a celebrity, and there are many younger brothers under the celebrity, that is, followers.&quot; Xiao Liang said. However, not everyone is keen to follow the &quot;sect&quot;, and some enthusiasts also play by themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, Li Wen and a group of five people were diving in an underwater cave in Duan County. The four people accompanying them were from three different systems. &quot;This sport itself is very niche, and there are not many people who can play together. People from different organizations are all the same enthusiasts. It is fate in itself, and it is also rare.&quot; Li Wen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Jiang Yuchen has 2 years of experience in cave diving. His deepest dive record is 101 meters. At the age of 20, he became the youngest X-CCR (a closed circuit respiration) in TDI (China). device) diver. Jiang Yuchen admitted that he does pursue depth, but he doesn&#39;t care about depth as much as others. &quot;Because I am still very young, I will have at least 30 more years to do high-difficulty diving.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Yuchen feels that 50 years old is a hurdle. He explained that after the age of 50, various body functions will age, and metabolism will decline. The slower speed means that the body&#39;s efficiency in emitting inert gases such as nitrogen will also decrease, making it difficult to do long-term and difficult dives, &quot;such as breaking records.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day Han Ting had the accident, he was three days away from his 47th birthday. In 2020, 44-year-old Han Ting dived to 234 meters in Jiudun Skylight, setting an Asian cave diving depth record. This Asian record was broken by WUD member Chen Qian in Jiudun Skylight on March 30, 2023, setting the deepest record of 258 meters. But in just the past 28 days, this depth has been refreshed again. On April 27, 2023, Han Ting set an Asian record of 277 meters at Jiudun Skylight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As team support for Chen Qian’s Asian record, Wei Jie denied that they were pursuing depth. “This number is very meaningful to him (Chen Qian) because May 8 is It was his wife’s birthday. He dived to this depth to commemorate his deceased wife.” Regarding Han Ting breaking the record in less than a month, Wei Jie said: “We are not convinced, so why should we be? The purpose of commemoration has been achieved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie analyzed that the reason why Han Ting chased the record so quickly may be because of commercial promotion. Before Chen Qian broke the record, Han Ting once appeared at a product launch conference as the holder of the Asian cave diving depth record. &quot;If he was not the number one in Asia when that product was launched, it might be troublesome, because he was the number one in Asia at that time. Here with us&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter obtained an investment plan marked &quot;Blue Flag Diving&quot;. Blue Flag Diving is a diving club founded by Han Ting and others in 2014. The plan shows that as the head coach of Blue Flag Diving, Han Ting will challenge the world record at Jiudun Skylight in October 2023. At that time, the Guinness World Records Certification Officer will be invited to the site in person and the challenge process will be broadcast live on multiple platforms. &quot;We will Make it a widely spread traffic portal for extreme sports.&quot; The plan promises that after reaching cooperation with the brand, &quot;Coach Han will record a promotional video for each partner.&quot; As of press time, Blue Flag Diving Club staff had not responded to Southern Weekend reporters on the authenticity of the plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Han Ting. Picture from the official website of China Exploration Association&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d93591b399.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Ting. The picture comes from the official website of the China Exploration Association&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beacon placement and wiring&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the domestic cave diving circle, the desire for records does not only occur at the tip of the pyramid, nor does it only occur at the depth. Jiang Yuchen told Southern Weekend reporters that in some mature caves abroad, there are almost no personal belongings, but in Jiudun Skylight, there are many signs with the names of divers. These signs wrapped around the leash usually appear at depths below 100 meters because they are not interesting in shallow water. &quot;For example, if you put one at 100 meters, and someone else puts one at 120 meters, then he must be better than you.&quot; Jiang Yuchen said frankly that this kind of behavior can easily lead to comparison and competition in the circle, &quot;This is true in any system. It is not worth promoting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting also missed the bid in Jiudun Skylight. In a video posted by Han Ting on Weibo, when he reached the target depth of 277 meters, he stopped diving as planned, tied a knot, locked the line, and placed an arrow mark. The orange triangular arrow mark said &quot;DJ&quot;. &quot;It was to commemorate his friend Dong Jie, so it was Dong Jie&#39;s name.&quot; Jiang Yuchen said. On September 26, 2022, Dong Jie and a diving companion died here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the many markings, the lines of the Jiudun skylight are also messy. Many interviewees said that when diving into a cave, you must pull the guide wire, which is one of the safety measures to ensure the return trip. If there is already a main line in a cave, the diver can dive along the already laid main line without pulling the line. &quot;Usually, we will respect the main line that was laid out first. Unless the line is pulled very unreasonably, we will make corrections based on it.&quot; Wei Jie introduced that in 2015, a Frenchman laid the main line in Jiudun Skylight. Later, Many teams in China went in to do wiring, but &quot;the wiring was too messy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person with the power to lay the main line is usually the first diver to enter the cave. However, in pursuit of being first, some divers will tear off the main line, re-route it, and claim to be the first person to explore the cave. Jiang Yuchen said that this approach is excessive. His ultimate goal is to discover unknown caves, explore and map them, post a sign without any personal identification, and then tell everyone from the bottom of his heart that diving is possible here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many interviewees pointed out that the uneven level of cave diving instructors is also one of the reasons for the frequent occurrences in the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Jie, who has 10 years of experience in teaching cave diving, gave an example. His system requires instructors to dive in the teaching cave at least 100 times and be able to exit the cave safely without lights or guide ropes. Become a coach, but many people become coaches without meeting this standard. &quot;If they are not familiar with it themselves, then the risk is very high if they teach others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the diving field, it is very important to meet a capable and responsible instructor, because students&#39; understanding of diving is easily influenced by the instructor, and usually, this understanding is directly linked to safety. . If you want to evaluate a coach&#39;s ability, Xiao Liang suggests asking him three questions: How many people have you taught? How many years of diving and teaching experience do you have? How much did you spend on diving? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike driving school instructors, diving instructors have the power to judge whether students meet the standards and whether they can issue certificates. &quot;If the coach says you are good, you can be good. If the coach says you are not good, you can&#39;t. But the level of coaches is different, which will cause bias between systems. In fact, it is not a problem with the system at all. It is when people have problems that the system will appear. There is a problem.&quot; Xiao Liang explained that the current cave diving system mostly comes from abroad and is only for management coaches, so the coach has great power. &quot;He is the person who leads you into the diving world, and your knowledge is also based on this coach.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Liang took Han Ting&#39;s class three years ago. He commented that Han Ting was a good coach. &quot;His ability is among the top in the country. He is serious in class and takes care of everyone. He is the type that most people will like and recognize.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In the end, it is robot salvage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Having The diving circle composed of enthusiasts with different purposes, different concepts, and different systems can hardly be said to be a community. Showing a difference when they face the death of their peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of Han Ting&#39;s accident, some insiders said they were not surprised, but more interviewees expressed regret for Han Ting&#39;s death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;It was an underwater robot that finally salvaged Han Ting&#39;s body. The picture shows the staff operating the robot underwater. Photo provided by Deep Blue&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/30/ce383f53c7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The person who finally salvaged Han Ting&#39;s body was under water robot. The picture shows the staff operating the robot underwater. Photo courtesy of Deep Blue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Han Ting’s family faced was a more practical problem. On the 13th day after Han Ting&#39;s death, that is, October 20, the body had not yet been recovered. Han Ting&#39;s brother and sister-in-law told Southern Weekend reporters that retrieving the body was a very complicated and dangerous matter. &quot;Considering safety issues, in principle, Domestic divers will no longer be accepted for salvage work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on the eighth day after Han Ting&#39;s death, a total of 14 divers went into the water to recover the body, but they all failed. Sister-in-law Han Ting began to understand what Han Ting said - when the day comes when I can&#39;t come back, you don&#39;t come to fish for me. &quot;He may have thought at that time that if something happened to him, he would be in a very deep place, and no one in the country could fish him out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wen has experience in salvaging the remains of divers. He analyzed that, Salvage at a depth of 113 meters, &quot;although it is within the capabilities of human divers, is indeed on the edge.&quot; He had made preparations before, &quot;If there is help over there, I can go there at any time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wen explained that aside from the risks of caves and large depths, a simple salvage mission is already very risky. &quot;We use CCR respirators when we go down. CCRs naturally have buoyancy changes. If I bring him up, it is equivalent to a person driving a car with eight steering wheels. It will be dangerous if any steering wheel is not noticed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the family’s statement that they will no longer accept help from domestic divers, some interviewees in interviews with Southern Weekend reporters felt that it was not just a professional opinion. An interviewee who did not want to be named told a reporter from Southern Weekend: &quot;There was a problem with Lao Mao underwater. People from their organization did not fish it out, but people from other organizations went to fish it out. For them, this facade will also be a little bit... Question.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting&#39;s body is located at a depth of 113 meters. Wei Jie believes that there are six or seven people in China who have the ability to salvage him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is surprising is that the final plan is not to salvage with divers, nor to salvage with man-machine cooperation, but only with robots in the water. On October 25, 2023, on the 18th day after Han Ting&#39;s death, two underwater robots brought Han Ting&#39;s body ashore. Sun Yan, the operator of the Deep Blue robot responsible for the salvage mission, told Southern Weekend reporters that the underwater north cave has a narrow terrain and the south cave is wider to meet the salvage needs, so it was decided to use two underwater robots to work together to lift the victims from the north cave. Salvage will be carried out after moving to the south cave to avoid collisions among the victims during the salvage process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, the salvage team successfully operated, and Han Ting’s body was brought out of the water 18 days after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，黎文、魏杰、许天华、萧亮为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多省辟谣“推行工龄退休”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：山东人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，一篇名为《山东省将实行“工龄退休”制度》的文章和相关截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，该文章和相关截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过我厅门户网站和“山东人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对山东人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;山东省人力资源和社会保障厅&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;2023年10月29日&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：河北人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近日，一篇名为《人社部：2024年1月1日起河北省将推行按“工龄退休”的政策》的文章和相似内容文章、截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，相关文章和截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们将保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过河北人社网和“河北人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对河北人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;来源：四川人社&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近日，一篇名为《人社厅：四川省将推行按“工龄退休”，将在2024年1月1日全面实施》的文章和相关截图在少数微信群、微信朋友圈、自媒体等网上传播。经核实，该文章和相关截图内容为虚假信息。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省严格执行国家统一规定的退休政策，不存在网传文章和相关截图中所说将按“工龄退休”的情况，请大家不信谣、不传谣。我们保留追究相关造谣者责任的权利。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省人力资源和社会保障厅出台公共政策都会通过我厅门户网站和“四川人社”微信公众号对外发布，感谢大家一直以来对四川人社工作的关注和支持！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;四川省人力资源和社会保障厅&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年10月27日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[朱哲琴：见山还是山]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259472]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi8FeyCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;703&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi 8FeyCC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhu Zheqin was a teenager, he dreamed of becoming a traveler. A few years later, she won the second prize in popular singing in the professional group of the Youth Singing Competition. If she embarks on the path of an acting singer, she can choose from many record companies, performance opportunities, and gain both fame and fortune; she can also leave everything behind and pursue what she really wants to do, but she doesn&#39;t know what she wants to do at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1991, the year after participating in the Youth Singing Competition, 23-year-old Zhu Zheqin left Guangzhou for Chengdu, still determined to be a tour guide. Her collaborator at the time and for many years to come, the composer He Xuntian, was a little angry and said it was a pity that she didn&#39;t sing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although she failed to become a traveler, she later went to India, Bhutan, Nepal, Tibet, Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, Guizhou, and Xinjiang to collect music. Her singing has also gone far. Her first album &quot;Yellow Child&quot; (1992) showed artistic qualities in addition to popular singing. &quot;A Sister&#39;s Drum&quot; (1995) was published in 56 countries, becoming the first A Chinese album released globally, with &quot;Yangjinma&quot; (1997), the scope expanded to 65 countries. In the wave of New Age Music that emerged at the end of the 20th century, Zhu Zheqin is a representative figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes she attributes herself to the laws of history - her popularity in the 1990s coincided with people&#39;s pursuit of spirituality after their material life was abundant. Sometimes she just said that people are really strange. What is a living thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took her a long time to figure out what she wanted to do. During this period, he released 6 albums, including a live recording album, held a world tour, served as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program, and initiated goodwill actions and original design platforms based on the protection and inheritance of Chinese traditional music and handicrafts. Then, by chance, I started sound art and have been creating it happily ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, social activities and artistic creation caused her to become relatively quiet in the field of music performance. After not giving a concert for nearly ten years, on September 30, 2023, she performed new music and sound art works, including a small concert, at the Aranya Jinshanling Community in Chengde, Hebei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I haven&#39;t sung for you for a long time.&quot; I saw her on the second day of the performance. We walked into a meditation room at the foot of the mountain. She took off her shoes and coat, and her black body disappeared on the gradually dimming tatami. Most of the lighting in this room comes from a floor-to-ceiling window. Outside the window is the dry landscape, only a sliver of sky is exposed, and dusk is approaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;A long-lost slightly impromptu concert&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from July, at the invitation of Aranya, Zhu Zheqin stayed in Jinshanling for three months to create music and sound art. It is located at the junction of Beijing and Hebei. The ridge is dotted with ruins of the Great Wall of the Ming Dynasty, which are ruined and mixed with rubble. To the southwest is the capital city, where the forests are gradually dyed in autumn. The Jinshanling area is inhabited by aboriginal mountain people, and real estate development has attracted many &quot;new mountain people&quot; to buy homes or travel with their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intentionally or unintentionally, Ma Yin, the founder of Aranya brand, wants to create a paradise here. First of all, transportation here is inconvenient, and secondly, it is extremely close to nature. At a dinner party and a conversation, Ma Yindu said: In the next ten years or more, we will spend more time in pain than happiness in our lives, so warming people&#39;s hearts may be a mainstream thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin’s exhibition will be completed in two landmark buildings in Aranya Jinshanling. One is the upper courtyard designed by architect Liu Yichun. It is built according to the mountain and is composed of a courtyard, a terrace and a hall. It is the spiritual highland of the community. One is the Valley Concert Hall designed by architects Li Hu and Huang Wenjing. It looks like a boulder and an alien object from the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three months of residency, Zhu Zheqin visited the concert hall and upper courtyard at different times, early morning, dusk, midnight, windy, rainy or foggy. &quot;It&#39;s like you get to know a very strange person.&quot; Friend, you have to know his character, know when he is the softest and most moving, and also know when he is the strongest. This is my working method.&quot; Especially the Valley Concert Hall, contrary to conventional concert halls, it does not There is no condition to completely purify the sounds of human voices and musical instruments, because its roof reaches the sky and the four walls are cut out, connecting the inside and outside. Sitting on the concrete seats of the concert hall is like sitting in a hollow boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is completely opposite to the concept of a standard concert hall. It does not block ambient sounds, but hopes that you can hear ambient sounds in an open state, feel the changes in light, and know that everything wakes up in the morning. .&quot; For musicians, these are unique and rare performance venues that burst the imagination, but they also have great limitations. They make people rethink, what kind of performance is a good performance? What kind of listening experience does this performance bring to the audience? Why do these two buildings appear here? Why do people come here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On several occasions, Zhu Zheqin went mountain climbing with Bai Chunxiang, the local Great Wall protector. Once she saw the back of Bai Chunxiang sitting on the Great Wall. She looked at it for a long time and thought, how should we as contemporary people deal with themselves in these cultures? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;She seemed to be embarking on a new journey, with old experiences falling off like frozen leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Zhu Zheqin spent 15 days in the mountains to collect various sounds, downloaded sounds from other planets from NASA’s official website, and used ambient electronic music editing throughout. She decided to compose in a minimalist way in three sections. The melody has only five notes, do re mi so la, and the lyrics only have three sentences - &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, Seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still mountains, and seeing water is still water.&quot; She invited Jinshanling aborigines and &quot;new mountain people&quot; to form a choir, and also successively contacted other musicians, including arranger Meng Ke Zhuolan, guzheng Chang Jing, and wind blower Wang Hua and percussionist Chen Shijie, all of whom participated in her tour ten years ago, are now reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete performance design is as follows: in the afternoon, the audience follows the guide silently throughout the entire process through the four performance locations along the upper courtyard building complex, using their &quot;hearing&quot; to experience nature and the musicians&#39; understanding of natural sounds. The performance of the performance was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;; in the evening, I entered the Valley Concert Hall to listen to the concert, which was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall structure of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; is strictly arranged, and each paragraph is mainly improvised. The day&#39;s weather, audience interaction, and the sounds of flora and fauna in the valley will all become part of the improvisation. Therefore, except for the chorus, which is composed, the other parts are improvised, and each rehearsal and performance will be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final rehearsal and recording was going on in the concert hall the night before the official performance. At 8 o&#39;clock, the mountain breeze passed through the hall, and the recording tube was full of whistling wind. Meng Ke Zhuolan&#39;s curly hair was blown all over her head. She stood at the mixer at the top of the back row and shouted to Zhu Zheqin at the bottom: &quot;Aren&#39;t you scared?&quot; Zhu Zheqin looked at her happily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Later we thought it was actually good to have wind, because if your music is open enough, it can accommodate this.&quot; Meng Kezhuolan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the night, the rehearsal was over. The next morning, Zhu Zheqin got up and turned on the recording to listen again. Suddenly, he kept crying. &quot;I feel extremely happy. I have never shed tears because of a good meal, but I may have read a poem, stood in front of the sea, watched a movie, and listened to Dupree&#39;s Elgar Cello Concerto in E minor, It makes me feel like my life has been turned into gold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;166 cushions were squeezed into the originally 140-seat Valley Music Hall, and people were still coming in. Many people had to stand at the entrance to listen. At 6pm, the show starts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert hall was very dark at first, with only a beam of white light shining in from the roof, scanning the entire venue back and forth. In the center of the sunken stage, Zhu Zheqin’s long hair was tied up in a bunch, with his eyes closed, like an immortal sitting in a cave. middle. The sound of 432 Hz always surrounds this fairy cave. This is a soothing and healing sound frequency that Zhu Zheqin specially used this time. It is superimposed with the sounds of streams, frogs, chimes and alien planets to create a space far wider than a concert hall. Zhu Zheqin&#39;s voice has a long breath and a wide range, from far to near, from humming to singing. She was so happy with the performance that she clapped her hands and danced, swaying her three-meter-long costume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Derek Bailey discusses the concept of free improvisation in Improvisation: Its Essence and Musical Practice, he considers it to be a celebration of the moment. Li Jianhong, a musician who is keen on improvisation and the translator of &quot;Improvisation&quot;, regards improvisation as a channel. He believes that for a conscious musician, improvisation is always a way to explore the true self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Zheqin, all these are true, and can be interpreted in another way. Improvisation is also a coexistence between everyone and nature, and is a humble and great part of it, like flowing water, frogs, wind, and trees. Like crows, they live for a short period of time, but they also create enduring arts such as music, poetry, and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the three-part singing was over, the musicians were supposed to be introduced, but that night she felt that anything she said in the middle of the performance was superfluous. So she performed all the way to the impromptu &quot;Finale&quot; that was originally prepared for everyone to leave at will. Halfway through the &quot;Finale&quot;, people still stayed where they were. Then she introduced the choir and performing members, thanked many people, and then said: &quot; It&#39;s been a long time since I sang for you.&quot; She paused and continued, &quot;We are already at the age when we are about to go down the mountain, but we climbed up a mountain together. This is rare in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the time Near 8 o&#39;clock, Zhu Zheqin was worried that a strong wind was coming, and finally told the audience who were unwilling to leave, everyone should go back. People stood up one after another, but she was reluctant to leave. Amid the rustling footsteps leaving the concert hall, her singing voice suddenly sounded again, with a broad and clear voice: &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still water. Mountains, water is still water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255462&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;World Hear·Ethnic Music Discovery Tour&quot; Guizhou Station, Zhu Zheqin led a team to record Miao girls singing &quot;Soul of Rice Flowers&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A week later, I met Guo Rong in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin has been working together for 11 years. Guo Rong found that every time there was a new art project, Zhu Zheqin would always leave a place for the &quot;old people&quot; who had worked together. Zhu Zheqin is surrounded by collaborators who have worked together for more than ten years, and she has become close partners in life with many of them. Guo Rong said that Zhu Zheqin maintained his enthusiasm for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large part of the reason why Zhu Zheqin was so moved at the end of the concert and later at the dinner was that many friends came, including Xi Chuan, Li Xianting, Xu Bing, Zhang Xiaogang, Wu Ershan... &quot;It&#39;s too luxurious.&quot; She choked up when talking about these names, &quot;Their works have been with me for many years, and the spirit, energy, touch, and encouragement released by their creations have been useful to me for life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After (New Crown) I miss these friends very much during the epidemic. I feel that life is meaningless. They come and go naturally, but they are the scenery of my life. If they need my voice, I think I should sing to them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dinner As usual, let the guest of honor say a few words during the ceremony. Zhu Zheqin took the microphone and said he had nothing to say. Everyone said, &quot;Let&#39;s sing.&quot; She said, &quot;Come on.&quot; &quot;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot;.&quot; It&#39;s too long ago. &quot;Return.&quot; Just right, this is the theme song she wrote and sang for the movie &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Christmas Eve 2019, Zhu Zheqin received a call from Wu Ershan and asked her if she wanted to go to Qingdao for Christmas. When I arrived in Qingdao, I discovered that it was a huge studio with thousands of people busy every day. Wuershan has been preparing for 10 years and spent 3 billion to make a trilogy of mythological epics. He hoped that Zhu Zheqin would write a song for &quot;Fengshen&quot;. They met as early as the 1990s. Zhu Zheqin watched Wu Ershan move from contemporary art to advertising shooting and then to film director. She felt that she did not have the courage to target a wider audience like Wu Ershan, and subconsciously refused: &quot;This is For a commercial blockbuster, I am not a traffic star and cannot bring you traffic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our first choice is Teacher Zhu, and he is also the only choice. We want to write an art song with a melody Full, and at the same time the voice span is very large, because if you want to express very full emotions, it will involve a very large span between notes. No one (except her) can sing.&quot; said Meng Kezhuolan, who is Wu Ershan&#39;s wife , is also the music director of &quot;Fengshen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guests fell silent, there was no accompaniment, and the sound was dry and dull, not suitable for singers to sing. But the three-part song was sung melodiously and stretched by Zhu Zheqin. It tells the story of the young Ji Fa who was sent to Chaoge as a hostage, and then escaped from the control of the tyrannical Shang King Yin Shou and returned to his hometown. The song was still being recorded during the COVID-19 epidemic. She had to return from abroad. According to epidemic prevention regulations, she was quarantined when she was in transit in Hong Kong, and then quarantined again after arriving in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin said that this is Ji Fa&#39;s homesickness, and it also embodies some of her nostalgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11 o&#39;clock during the dinner, the brightly lit restaurant suddenly lost power and became completely dark. The staff found real and fake candles for lighting, and the guests were happy and cheered softly. Then someone said, let’s go see the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The moonlight is bright and clear, the mountains are silent, and the cold night makes people shrink their necks and stamp their feet. A small group of people filed out through the narrow glass door and gathered on the platform to sing again, &quot;The moon passes through the white lotus-like clouds&quot; and &quot;You ask me how deeply I love you/How much I love you.&quot; / My love is true / My love is true / The moon represents my heart”... Sometimes it is a solo, sometimes it is a chorus of three or three, and someone brings a piano, and the echoes are like ripples. spread among the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They will definitely lose power when they are together. The spiritual energy field is too strong.&quot; Zhu Zheqin also remembered during the interview, &quot;It was like that in the 1980s and 1990s. There were no exhibitions at that time. There were no paintings to sell, no records, no concerts, all of this was nothing. Zhang Xiaogang was still painting stage sets for the Sichuan Opera Troupe as a living profession. But what he loved most was painting. He painted hard, and he had no money. No reason. In recent years, it seems that people paint just to go to auction, and how high the price is, and how good it is. In fact, it is not true. In my opinion, those are just projected phenomena. There is a powerful spiritual power behind it. I What I cherish is that kind of thing. I think that kind of thing will change the world and heal myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, the narrow door that everyone passes through from the restaurant to the terrace seems to have become a door to time and space. , outside the door is their spiritual hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;I think people of every era are the masters of this era. The history of this era is created and left by us, so what do we want to create? If we are dissatisfied with reality, Then why don&#39;t we do some ourselves? I&#39;m not one to complain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was singing &quot;A True Story&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Red-Crowned Crane&quot;&lt;/span>;) and became famous after winning the Youth Singing Competition, a fan appeared at the door of the hotel in the middle of the night and said to her, I think you are the Red-Crowned Crane. She was scared away because &quot;it impressed them so strongly that they stayed there forever.&quot; She didn’t know what she wanted at that time, but she knew what she didn’t want—not to become a singer, not to be packaged, not to enter a paradigm. &quot;Someone in my heart said, no, no, no. But, what are you going to do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Double CD &quot;Moonrise&quot; by Zhu Zheqin and ethnic singers&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, the market economy developed rapidly and social trends moved away from single collectivism. Zhu Zheqin recalled That feeling of liberating the mind, &quot;Actually, people are quite confused, and they don&#39;t know where they are in this coordinate.&quot; She did not sign with any record company, nor did she join an art troupe, and disappeared from the public eye. She went to Chengdu from Guangzhou, and a year later, &quot;Yellow Child&quot; composed by He Xuntian and sung by Zhu Zheqin was released. Later, historian Luo Xin wrote about a detail when he was reflecting on and criticizing racial thinking. On a winter night when he was working on his doctoral thesis, he heard &quot;Yellow Children&quot; being played on the radio, &quot;that empty and desolate feeling of loneliness and hopelessness.&quot; &quot;It tells the loss of the East in front of the West.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, &quot;A Sister Drum&quot; was released. This was the second collaboration between Zhu Zheqin and He Xuntian. They took a trip to Tibet, which they regarded as a spiritual holy land, and returned many times. But no matter how impressive the natural scenery, humanities and art in Tibetan areas are, what makes Zhu Zheqin most unforgettable is still the &quot;people&quot;. It is &quot;the scenes of their lives in poverty that made me have to re-evaluate the weight of my life.&quot; She got a new name, Dadawa. Dadawa is reminiscent of Dadaism, which was later basically annexed by Surrealism. Dadawa is the Tibetan word for the moon. Dadawa is neither the East nor the West. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot; and &quot;Yangjinma&quot; two years later form a complete expression of their Tibet, which is mysterious and strong on the one hand, and everyday and light on the other, bringing Zhu Zheqin to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, she also made a physical journey across Asia. From Kashmir to the Himalayas, I sweated and sneezed while clicking the shutter in the spice markets of India, and took a tricycle to look for gypsies. Gypsy Bopa played the music on a very simple folk violin. Zhu Zheqin was fascinated by it. It took him a while to come back to his senses and said that it was like hearing real music for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also during that trip, she saw Hindus waiting for death by the Ganges River, and the cremated corpses rolled down to her feet. &quot;Journey to the Ganges is another starting point in my life, where I realize the meaninglessness of life. Our life is redefined by our values ​​and culture, which celebrates the greatness of life. A person&#39;s birth must be celebrated, and a person&#39;s death must be commemorated. . But if you imagine that a fish is born and dies, it is a natural thing, nothing more. The truth of the universe is that you are like a leaf, yellow today and withered tomorrow.&quot; She thought, if life is like this, what will happen to people? Life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ask the Mountain·Theme Concert&quot;, Zhu Zheqin and musicians performed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Asking is the beginning of Tao&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the first year of the new coronavirus pandemic, Zhu Zheqin entered a &quot;dormant state&quot;. She spent most of her time at home, cooking, taking care of the yard, and thinking about nothing. &quot;I rarely have such a stage where I shut down my phone. Suddenly I felt how fragile the world is and how vulnerable human civilization is to an invisible virus.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second year, she began to I thought, if there are no recordings, no exhibitions, no concerts in the future, what else will I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin was admitted to the Guangzhou &quot;Little Skylark&quot; Chorus at the age of 7 and performed at the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall. At the age of 13, she recorded children&#39;s singing teaching materials. She can sing any type of opera. During school, she worked as a singer in a karaoke hall, and then she became famous. , hold concerts, explore your own expression and style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the trip to India shattered the meaning of life, Zhu Zheqin felt that he had reached a point in time where all expressions seemed pale and feeble, and he had to look inward to find something more essential. &quot;When you find yourself weightless or confused, only by daring to throw yourself out can you have a chance to regain your life.&quot; In 2009, she accepted the appointment as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program and launched the &quot;World Sees-China &quot;Ethnic Culture Protection and Development Goodwill Action&quot;, conducting field research on folk music and handicrafts in ethnic minority areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, she realized that she and the entire generation had a very weak understanding of their own culture. Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;In modern China, a &#39;modernity&#39; suddenly appeared, but this &#39;modernity&#39; may have nothing to do with its own culture and is a collage. From the time we started to imitate to the time we realized that imitation was not It is not ourselves, and then we have to find and construct it. The first stage is to create something from scratch, and then we have to take root, grow up, be local, and reflect the face of the people of this land and water.&quot; She deliberately made young people Many musicians participated in the project to organize and adapt folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, she released her last album to date, &quot;Moonrise&quot;, a double CD. One is a collection of original ethnic minority music, and the other is a musician&#39;s work that has been arranged and sung. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the creative team of &quot;Moonrise&quot; held a world tour with ethnic singers and young musicians. Meng Kezhuolan served as composer and arranger. She was less than 30 years old at the time and mainly wrote chamber music. Before a performance, Zhu Zheqin asked Meng Kezhuolan to come and listen. That was the first time she heard a singer and musician singing Miao Fei Song sitting in front of her. As soon as the other person opened his mouth, she got goosebumps all over her body. &quot;I was suddenly photographed there. His earthy, tanned look no longer existed in front of me. I thought to myself that if he were in a Miao village, all the girls would fall in love with him.&quot; Until a few days ago, wind player Wang Hua still remembered that tour during the rehearsal of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and said that it was the best performance he had participated in in so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;World Seeing&#39; thing seems to help others, but it actually saved me.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said frankly, &quot;After the meaning of life was shattered, it gave me a stage to learn and do something. Specific things. At that time, I had a very big feeling. I thought I was a drop of water, but I was also an ocean. Only when I became a water drop could I be an ocean.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after that, Zhu Zheqin never released an album and had only a handful of public performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As a singer, I use singing to express my thoughts and feelings, but apart from that, I have always been more interested in inner energy.” Along this path, she entered sound art, “I want to Know what else is inside me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it didn&#39;t go well at first. In 2014, Gao Peng, then director of Today Art Museum, approached Zhu Zheqin and asked her to create a sound art work. After two visits, her reply was pending. Guo Rong hoped to persuade Zhu Zheqin to start a new attempt. She said: &quot;Teacher Zhu, I came to your team because I like your music and your voice.&quot; Something seemed to be touched in Zhu Zheqin&#39;s heart. A few days later, she flew abroad. Before leaving, she left a note for Guo Rong, which listed 20 issues, including time points, production schedules, and problems faced... Guo Rong was relieved when she saw it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, I think the process of her asking these questions is also a process of self-answering. If I didn&#39;t answer her at that time, someone else would answer her. If no one else answered her, she would answer these questions herself. Question.&quot; Guo Rong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, the Sound·Jue Zhu Zheqin sound art exhibition opened. Today Art Museum was painted into a dark box, with a pool on the ground. Zhu Zheqin recruited dozens of people to walk back and forth beside the pool, making sounds and playing chimes. She did not sing, but stood in the crowd, and all the sounds turned into ripples, reflected on the wall, turning the invisible into something tangible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The mystery of all things lies in the combination of things. The world is a temporary combination of consciousness, and music is sound. The essence of sound is waves and vibrations. So I think vibration is a very direct way to approach consciousness. . I am very lucky to be on this road.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;It was only when I became aware of my voice that I fully understood myself. I want to create a field and let everyone enter, so that people can realize that everyone is actually affected by something. Driven by an inner energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you are at the scene, as both Meng Ke Zhuolan and Guo Rong have described, it seems that everyone has come to another time and space, temporarily breaking away from external forces and moving inwards. Zhu Zheqin tried to create this feeling in his seven subsequent sound art works, including &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three lyrics in &quot;Ask the Mountain&quot; are also a portrayal of her journey back to her inner self. In the beginning, people looked at things through the universal laws of phenomena. The saying goes: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; When superficial phenomena are denied, solid and perfect things become vulnerable, and perfection is just a fantasy. This is: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, &quot;After the first year of the COVID-19 epidemic, I thought, when I was 6 years old, no one said that I would have concerts, wouldn&#39;t I still sing every day? I just love this thing, it is Bringing me joy in life, helping me grow and perceive the world, isn’t it more real than anything else? When you reach this point, you will see your true nature. Just like birds singing in the sky and fish swimming in the sea, if I have wings, I will Fly.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;In such an era, I think it is more important to maintain an imagination, maintain poetry, and maintain free thoughts about reality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this a mountain or a mountain? . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the concert &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;, everyone will get a small guide card at the entrance of the Valley Concert Hall, which reads: Creation stems from the perception of the mountains, and does not seek to understand the mountains and the world. Any definition of &quot;mountain dwelling&quot; nor explore any answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the performance, I walked up the mountain along the path connecting the Valley Concert Hall and the Upper Court. There was a small dark green sign hanging on a tree on the roadside, with a black arrow pointing to the depths of the mountain. There is a line of small words attached to the arrow: There will be answers in the mountains. Continuing in the direction pointed by the arrow, the same arrow guide appeared one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sign ends in front of an old cave. This is a small house built against a shallow cave, with three real people enshrined inside. There was a kang built against the wall. There were traces of fire underneath, but now the window paper was broken and air leaked from all sides. There was no sound for a while. Am I the only one in this world? &quot;Will there be answers in the mountains&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While listening to me talk about this experience, Zhu Zheqin looked at a certain place on the roof. The meditation room fell into silence, and became darker as the sky darkened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, she said, when you start asking, that is the beginning of the Tao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢黄尧的帮助）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她研究在美中国本科留学生，发现高远志向下的挣扎和迷茫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259545]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QRIdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1226&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QR IdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 17, 2022 local time, New York University graduates celebrated their graduation ceremony. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The annual application season for international students is here again. According to the &quot;2023 Study Abroad in China White Paper&quot; released by New Oriental, more than 50% of people intend to study abroad with a bachelor&#39;s degree or below. The situation of studying abroad is picking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, two other reports are also worthy of attention. On September 25, 2023, the National Student Credentials Certification Center in the United States released a report &quot;Completing College&quot; that showed that the undergraduate dropout rate for Chinese students in the United States was as high as 25%. In the same month, WholeRen, a Pennsylvania-based education consulting company, released the &quot;2023 White Paper on the Current Situation of Chinese Students in the United States.&quot; According to statistics, 70% of Chinese students who have been dismissed from the United States are undergraduates, and more than half of the students are studying in the top 50 schools in the United States. The top two reasons for being dismissed were academic dishonesty and poor academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The data only presents the tip of the iceberg. In the seemingly distant American education system, many Chinese students are indeed experiencing struggles under the glamorous impression&lt;/span>;. Ma Yingyi, a professor of sociology at Syracuse University in the United States, wrote the book &quot;Ambitious and Anxious: The Success and Struggle of Chinese College Students in American Higher Education&quot; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ambitious and Anxious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;How Chinese College Students Succeed and Struggle in American Higher Education&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;) &lt;/span>;, describes the status of Chinese students in the United States as &quot;ambition and anxiety coexist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that whether they came from wealthy families or ordinary families, these international students began to experience this contradiction before arriving in the United States, and it intensified after entering college. They have big dreams, but in pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles and feel confused about their futures. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this takes place against the background of the rapid development of Chinese society. All these anxieties forced them to think about the ultimate question: Is it really worth studying in the United States? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The samples surveyed by Ma Yingyi included 507 Chinese international students from 50 American undergraduate colleges and universities, all born in the 1990s. The survey period was from 2011 to 2019. The book won the 2021 American Association for Comparative and International Education Higher Education Best Book Award and the American Sociological Association’s Bourdieu Book Honor Award. Recently, Ma Yingyi accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The increase in undergraduate international students is not due to the financial crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you pay attention to the group of Chinese international students in American undergraduate education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My research began in 2011. At that time, major universities in the United States began to have a large number of Chinese undergraduates. Prior to this, most Chinese students studying abroad in the 1980s and 1990s studied in China for graduate school and then went to the United States to study for Ph.D., or they completed their undergraduate studies in China and then went to the United States for graduate school, as was the case for me. Twenty years ago, I first came to the United States after earning my bachelor&#39;s degree in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But around 2007, a large number of students came to the United States to study for undergraduates after completing high school in China, and some even went directly to the United States to study in high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that most of the previous generation of international students either relied on scholarships from the United States to study for master&#39;s or doctoral degrees, or were sponsored by the Chinese government to study in the United States. As for the generation of undergraduates I follow, 90% are completely self-funded. For in-state students, tuition at public universities in the United States is very cheap, but international students have to pay extra, which is higher than out-of-state students, and private universities charge even more. Therefore, whether applying to public or private universities, the cost for Chinese international students is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, this is a brand new phenomenon, reflecting the rise of the middle class and the accumulation of wealth in Chinese society. Then during the research process, I gradually discovered the duality of ambition and anxiety among this generation of international students. Whether it is academic or social life, or planning for the future, this contradiction is reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在市场上的留学中介会建议家长为孩子去美国留学准备一年一百万的巨额费用，相比英国、加拿大、澳大利亚、新加坡等地区花费更高。为什么还有那么多中国家庭愿意支付？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;美国本科留学的费用成本相比其他地区可能是最高的，所以很多人误认为，赴美留学的中国学生都是企业家的子女，但其实那样的人只是少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社会学里，收入和财富是两个不一样的概念。收入是你的工资，仅从收入来看，中国的中产阶层或许无力承担赴美的学费。但财富不一样，财富可以包括房产、股票等，在中国主要是房产。从2000年代开始，中国城市化发展迅猛，房市腾飞，许多并不算富裕的家庭也积累了一定的财富。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我收集到的样本中，有些父母是中学老师，有些甚至是基层工薪阶层。因为有房子，他们选择变现这个财富来支持孩子出国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;美国大学的老师们怎么看这种变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我曾遇到一位普渡大学的行政官员，他说学校在2008年金融危机以后出现了财政危机，恰好这个时候中国本科生来了，也有了支付高昂学费的能力。他形容这是一个“完美的婚姻”。我当时发现这是一个非常系统的现象，这背后不仅有双方的需求，于是开始着手研究。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;赴美本科留学生的增加是因为美国的金融危机吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多人说中国留学生的增加是在2008年金融危机之后，那时美国大学缺钱。但我的调查数据显示，中国赴美留学生人数年增长率最高的年份是2007年，是在金融危机之前。所以并不是美国大学的需求导致中国留学生迅速增加，更多是因为中国中产及以上阶层对于子女教育的需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时中国经历了经济发展迅速、中产阶级崛起，居民收入也迅速增加。我在书中提到的另一个因素是2006 到2014 年人民币升值，到2014 年，人民币升值了大约37%，中国家庭的支付能力更强了。另一方面是中国的好大学仍然非常难进，而美国目前为止仍然是世界上好大学最聚集的地方，所以很多人来到美国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;三个阶段都有“志向和焦虑并存”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的研究是如何展开的？又是怎样观察到“志向和焦虑并存”的情况？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的调查从2011年开始，最开始是用抽样法在线调查，再挑选出愿意参加深度访谈的学生。我们收到了来自50所院校的507 份调查问卷，最终对65名2013年到2016年在美国读本科的中国留学生做了深度访谈。我让学生选择英语或中文，几乎每个人都说中文。之后三年，我在中国六个城市的九所高中进行了实地调查，还采访了一些学校辅导员、校长和老师。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我把他们的经历分为三个阶段。第一个阶段是学生来美国之前，需要准备申请、考试、择校，整个过程充满焦虑，这很大程度来源于他们的抱负，因为他们就想进排名前30、前50的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个阶段是选专业。要选一个满足自己兴趣又好找工作的，这里开始出现与父母的矛盾。在社交阶段也焦虑，中国学生很不熟悉美国学生的社交方式和娱乐方式，导致难以融入。很多学生出国的目的就是想接触多元文化，接触不同的圈子，所以这也带来很大的压力和落差感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后一个阶段是对未来的规划。我做调研的时候，就业市场还不像现在这样，但也有各种问题。比如想留在美国就有签证的问题，回中国又有难以融入国内圈子、如何使用国内社会资本以及择业的问题。他们也迫切希望自己的学历和经历能够获得满意的回报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这三个阶段中都可以明显观察到这种“志向和焦虑并存”的二元性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相较于其他国家留学生而言，中国学生身上这种二元性会更突出吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;任何一个留学生都会面临这种状态。具体到中国留学生，不少人家里卖房或借贷供养孩子留学，这一代又大多是独生子女，很多人需要回到父母身边。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然从哲学的眼光来看待，志向本身就能产生焦虑。但中国留学生在这一点上更加突出，我在写作的过程中意识到，理解这一代留学生，其实非常重要的是理解他们背后的中国社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去二十年，中国社会其实也是一种志向和焦虑并存的状态。没有哪个国家像中国变化这么大，各个阶层的人都感受到很多变化，很多人实现了富裕，很多人有很大的抱负和野心。人们视野开阔，收入增加，同时也总在担心自己错失了什么机会，他们迫切希望获得国际视野，但这需要很多资源，人们也开始担心，自己的投资是否能获得足够的回报，这一切都带来焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自这个环境的中国留学生自然也如此。而且留学生在任何社会里都不是一个随机的人群，他们都是有志向、有一定特权的一群人。在社会学上，流动人口相对不流动人口是更具野心和目标性的。留学生要读书拿学位，要见识更大的世界，他们甚至背负着整个家族的期待和目光，承载着社会变迁带来的压力和机会，机遇和挑战并存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，中国的社会虽然发生了巨大的变化，但教育变化相对没有那么大，主要还在于高考仍是指挥棒。中国孩子和美国孩子接受的中小学教育差异非常大，中国留学生是带着中国教育的烙印到美国的高等教育去的，这个变化本身也给他们带来很大的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之，中国留学生可能在全世界留学生群体里面，或者说流动人口里，是最具备“志向和焦虑二元性”的群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1007&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左：《雄心勃勃与忧心忡忡：中国大学生在美国高等教育中的成功与挣扎》。右：美国雪城大学社会学教授马颖毅。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;遭遇“落差感”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在书中还提到，一些中国留学生到美国后，会因学校在“村里”而震惊？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最有名的案例是伊利诺伊大学香槟分校，大家说它是一片玉米地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这和中美高等教育发展的历史有很大的关系。中国大学集中在大城市，而美国其实大城市没几个，但有很多大学城镇，就是在大农村建的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个州都有自己的旗舰学校，QS排名靠前的学校不一定在大城市里。当然大学排名是一个片面的、容易误导大家的信息。美国的大学非常多样，公立学校里有非常好的学术类院校，也有社区大学，不同的学校有不同的使命，它们没有严格意义上的优劣之分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么留学生那么看重大学排名？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;一个原因在于，美国的招生制度很不一样，它不是只看分数，你都不知道分数会占有多大比例，没有办法定量地判断是10%，还是5%，还是90%，每个学校都不一样，每个专业也不一样，每个学校不同年份也不一样，没有人会告诉你。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国学生也许因为这个学校的某项运动取得过很好的成绩、学校离家近，甚至风景好等各种五花八门的原因而选择。但中国学生不了解这些，大学排名就成为他们背负的压力和焦虑的其中一个来源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你的访谈对象中，这种“落差感”还出现在哪些方面？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;生活上的落差感，包括人际交往。他们此前可能认为美国人热情开放，后来才发现交朋友没有想象的那么容易。比如，有些学生刚开始雄心勃勃，希望能交到很多美国朋友，但很快受挫。美国大学生非常重要的社交娱乐方式是周末聚会，聚会上很多人都要喝酒，同时玩一些喝酒游戏，比如在一个啤酒瓶上放个乒乓球，大家一起吹，球击中了谁，谁就喝酒。很多中国孩子没办法加入其中，很多人觉得喝酒游戏难以忍受。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人就觉得很挫败，回到中国学生的圈子。这个圈子的娱乐可能是大家一起吃饭，去KTV唱歌，女孩逛街，男孩打游戏。很多中国学生会觉得，我出国不应该还是跟中国人在一起玩，甚至他们的父母会督促他们交美国朋友，说“不交美国朋友的话，你英语都还不如出国以前”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一位中国留学生，英语说得非常好，性格外向，有很多美国朋友，大家都以为他是在美国长大的。但他融入美国大学生圈子后，挺失望，没有像此前想象的那样享受多元文化，所以又回到了中国人的圈子，在中国留学生群体里承担领导职务，主持春晚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个很有趣的回归，出去转了一圈，想象破碎，再回来。在哲学意义上，这种回归是一个寻找自己的过程，尽管他表面上最后又回到中国学生当中，但他出来看过了、交往过了、感受过了不一样的世界，那和他当初没有走出去的状态，是完全不一样的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他们都是如何去适应这种“落差感”的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这种落差感会影响他们对留学的满意度，会影响他们整个状态，包括学习、社交、日常生活等，其实是很难适应的。但时间本身能带来习惯，一直不习惯的学生有可能会选择离开，比如说有些学生本科学校在美国的大农村，那他们毕业以后，就会申请去纽约、波士顿之类的大城市读研究生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之还是要加深对自己和新环境的理解，留学之前，先了解自己到底想要什么，学校能够提供什么，尽量减少一些误解，才能减少之后因为误解带来的不满意和焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做一些准备工作对于适应环境很有好处，比如一位学生，家里条件比较好，父母在Twitter上给他找了一个美国朋友，专门陪他练口语、交流生活，还有一些学生会提前到美国学校附近适应环境。我还做了一些统计分析发现，多参加社团活动、参加学校组织等都可以提升学生的留学满意度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了生活，留学生不在课堂上发言，难以很好地融入课堂和学术活动其实也一直是个问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他们可能非常想表达、想参与，但很难参与。这种求而不得的状况，其实带来很多心理负担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于课堂讨论我有切身体验。我经常上课让同学们讨论，讨论不完全是对英语交流的挑战，语言是最基本的门槛，很多英语很好的同学同样难以参与讨论。我的调研显示，60%的学生都认为自己的英语很好，但所有学生里只有20%-30%的同学认为自己经常上课发言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是什么因素阻碍了他们？我认为，一个非常重要的原因是基本思维模式的差异，学生不能勇敢充分地表达自己。大多数中国课堂一直在寻求标准答案，学生总担心自己说出的话对不对。而美国大学课堂是开放式的讨论，没有正确答案，这是一个相当大的差异。中国学生需要改变思维模式，才能够有效地参与讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;扬长避短，而不是补差补缺&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这本书2020年出版，之后这3年间，我们都经历了更多变化，你有没有观察到一些新的情况？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;全世界的留学生在新冠疫情期间都很困难，旅行不便，远离家人，中国留学生应该说是处境更困难。我的基本结论没有改变，但这三年显然让“忧心忡忡”变严重了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;怎么理解“忧心忡忡”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;具体的挑战是不确定性，这体现在留学生活的方方面面。航班什么时候能增加？回国能不能容易一些？学生签证、工作签证怎么这么难办？美国的政策、舆论趋势等，都会增加中国学生的心理压力。这都是10年前的中国学生所没有的压力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，写这本书时，选择美国好像是非常一致的倾向，但现在有很多学生选择了欧洲、日本包括中国香港等，这是一个比较大的改变。近期发布的数据显示，在美的印度留学生已经超过了中国留学生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你如何看待留学低龄化的趋势？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;越来越多家庭选择送年龄小的孩子去留学，这可能是出于结构性的原因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在标准化考试的淘汰体系里，大多数人都不是优胜者。有一些学生虽然成为了优胜者，但在这种竞争的环境下，他没办法获得比较平衡的身心发展，或者他不开心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以很多家庭选择低龄留学，显然大家都知道是有风险的，相比于大学生而言风险更高，但他们分析了风险和回报之后觉得利大于弊，才会做出这种选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对于中国留学生和家长有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最重要的就是通过各种方式多去了解自己。比如通过父母、朋友，或者通过参与各种活动去更全面地认识自己。留学其实只是打开了一个窗口，来了以后要做出很多选择，包括选什么课、参加什么样的社团、选择怎样的未来道路等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国高等教育一个很大的优势，就是提供了很多选择。一个人要做出适合自己的选择，非常重要的前提就是自我认知。所以要了解自己，了解自己优势是什么，弱点是什么，对哪些东西有热情，哪些能力是培养不出来的。一个人不可能擅长所有的东西，现代社会最重要的是，要做自己擅长和感兴趣的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不够了解自己的话也没有关系，我觉得这是一辈子的功课。但是学生现在要有这种意识，从现在就开始关注自己的兴趣特长，扬长避短，而不是去补差补缺。我觉得学生和家长都需要做出思维上的调整。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>