<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[詹安泰、王季思与张仲浦的一段文字因缘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259332]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5EJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5 EJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I recently obtained from Mr. Zhang Zhongpu’s philosophical heir, Mr. Zhang Yan, his collection of sages’ books and artifacts, including Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi. There are one lost letter each to Mr. Zhang, and each of them is accompanied by a note of poems and a note of music. Following the elegant wishes of Teacher Zhang Yan, Hui Yu compiled and published it, writing a short essay and a brief explanation, for the benefit of others, and at the same time, it can be used to preserve the origins of a passage written by a senior scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987), courtesy name Zhanyun and nickname Oubo, was born in Yugan, Jiangxi. He studied engineering at an early age and studied at Jiangxi Polytechnic College, determined to save the country through science. He then changed his studies to law and graduated from the Law Department of Peking University in 1937 with a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. He then specialized in literature, loved classical literature and was good at writing poetry. Dedicated to education throughout his life, he served as a Chinese language teacher at Nanchang Normal University, Linchuan Simple Normal University, and Yuqian Yuting Middle School. In 1934, he taught at the former National Zhejiang University, Zhejiang Normal University, and Hangzhou University, mainly taking charge of modern Chinese literature courses. He is the author of &quot;Guo Moruo&#39;s Historical Drama &quot;Qu Yuan&quot;&quot; (Shanghai Literature and Art Publishing House, 1959), &quot;Analysis of &quot;The New Story&quot;&quot; (co-authored with Wang Rongchu, Zhejiang Literature and Art Publishing House, 1983), &quot;Yan Milou Poetry Manuscript&quot; ( Northern Literature and Art Publishing House, 2004), &quot;Notes on Xia Wanchun&#39;s &quot;Ode to the Great Sorrow&quot;&quot; (Threadbound Book Company, 2016), &quot;Modern Patriotic Poet Huang Zunxian&quot; (Tianhe Press, 2016), etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot; contains nine letters from Zhan to Long Yusheng, Chen Zhongfan, Yang Shuda, Luo Xianglin and Liu Baiduan. &quot;The Complete Works of Wang Jisi&quot; contains nearly 50 letters by Wang. At the end of his letter to Zhang Hanqing in October 1987, he wrote: &quot;I used to occasionally write some prose, but lately I have been immersed in ancient books and have rarely experienced new life experiences, except for relatives and friends. Outside of letters and letters, they rarely write.&quot; It can be imagined that Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi still have a lot of letters and letters lying around, waiting to be compiled. The two lost letters disclosed in this article can be regarded as a source of inspiration, or they can be regarded as A little bit of celery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;804&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhan Antai&#39;s letter and words to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Letter from Zhan Antai to Zhang Zhongpu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhong Pu Written by: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hui Shufeng It is reported that the great work is pure and healthy, and the workmanship is greatly admired. &quot;If you avoid the soldiers, you will face the water of Aotang. When you leave the country, you will still have new willow shoots.&quot; I recite it repeatedly, but there is still pain left. On the first day of the Yuan Dynasty, I occasionally wrote small words, and recorded them on separate sheets of paper to beg for correction. After many years of neglect, thorns grew on my hands. I took a photo of Huanghuagang and sent it to Brother Qu Chan. I hope I have conveyed it to you. At this moment, I would like to pay tribute&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chun Qi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp &amp;nbsp; nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Diantaitonshou&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; on the second day of the first lunar month&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send Brother Qu Chan a piece of paper begging to be conveyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A brief examination of the writing time of this letter shows that it was February 1, 1957, the second day of the first lunar month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The letter involves Xia Chengtao (Qu Chan). According to the &quot;Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, Mr. Xia and Zhang Zhongpu went to Guangzhou to participate in a scientific research seminar at Sun Yat-sen University on January 5, 1957. On January 14, the two of them, accompanied by Zhan Antai and Wang Jinguang, visited Huanghuagang. The diary stated that they were &quot;majestic&quot; and &quot;taken a photo&quot;. This is the so-called &quot;Photography in Huanghuagang&quot; in the lost letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the previously published lost letters and the relevant contents of &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, it can be seen that after Zhang Zhongpu returned to Hangzhou from Guangzhou, he wrote to Zhan Antai and attached his own work. Check his &quot;Yan Mi Lou Poetry Manuscript&quot;, the sentence &quot;avoiding the soldiers and leaving the water in the Aotang, leaving the country is still the new willow shoots&quot; comes from Zhang&#39;s 1944 work &quot;The accumulated rain uses the Du Gongbu Hall to form a rhyme&quot;, the whole poem is: &quot;The accumulated rain and moss cover the grass, and the barbarian suburbs are temporarily stagnated by the smoke. The soldiers are left facing the water of the Aotang, and there are several new willow shoots in the country. The flying kites in the sky are startled by the meteorites, and the Peng in the clouds laughs at the nest. Zilan Ning It has the meaning of curing hunger, and the spirit of Yanjian Mountain is full of laughter.&quot; However, in the &quot;Poem Manuscript&quot; version, &quot;Yue Kun&quot; was changed to &quot;Ji Kun&quot;, which made the emotion even more intense. Zhan Antai said that &quot;it is pure and healthy, and it is extremely admirable for workmanship&quot; and &quot;it is still painful to recite it over and over again.&quot; Of course, he has the ancient etiquette of the older generation of scholars, but he also has a gaze like a torch, which illuminates the advantages of Zhang&#39;s poems. In his letters to Zhang Zhongpu in the 1960s, Miao Yue repeatedly said that &quot;great poems are fresh and elegant, and can integrate new ideas while maintaining the style and charm of old poems.&quot; , &quot;Great poetry can reflect reality, express new thoughts, and be admired after reading it.&quot; The two contrast each other, and the style and characteristics of Zhang&#39;s poetry can be seen better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Yuan Ri Occasionally Small Ci&quot; written in the poem &quot;Begging for Correction on a Separate Paper&quot; also survives in Teacher Zhang Yan&#39;s home. &quot;Yuan Day&quot; is January 31, 1957, the first day of the first month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot; mistakenly refers to New Year&#39;s Day of the &quot;Renshen Year&quot; of Xia Zheng. The full text of the Ci is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qi Tianle&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It would have been twenty years since I had talked with Qu Chan. Guests come from the south in winter, but don&#39;t leave in a hurry. At the beginning of the new year, I have memories, so I wrote this tune and sent it to Hangzhou and Zhongpu, Cambodia. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 20th year, I was sad to see Nan Feiyan (in 36 years, Qu Chan was about to travel to Guangnan, and I had poems to welcome him. ), the reunion suddenly became the present and the ancient. Paying homage to the monument (touring Huanghuagang and Guangzhou Commune with Qu Chan and Zhong Pu), walking on the shallow branches (together in Liwan on the same day), and facing tall sugarcane trees. Drunk and drunk. He also painted a river city with hundreds of dragons dancing. When I saw Fangcun, there were clusters of wild flowers competing with flutes and drums (the plan to go to Fangcun to see flowers did not bear fruit). &amp;nbsp;It’s so wonderful to travel everywhere, old friends are thousands of miles away, can we come again? The ridges and flat pavilions, the lakeside survey, are not wasted time. Thinking about you. It is necessary to make a new start with style and make a grand gesture. Just try your hand at it, and look around with your head raised. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhongpu taught me. My brother An Taichu wrote the manuscript, Ding Youyuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing this word in volume 5 of &quot;Wu&#39;an Ci&quot; collected in the fourth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot;, in the preface, &quot;kuaitan&quot; is replaced by &quot;talk&quot;, and &quot;jianchan&quot; is replaced by &quot; &quot;Bing Cambodia&quot;, the only two sentences in the poem are self-notes of &quot;three and six years&quot;, and the rest are the same. The poem mentioned in the self-note is &quot;I heard that Qu Chan (Cheng Tao) will have a poem to welcome Guangnan&quot;: &quot;Looking at the mountains, I can no longer be proud, and I love you so much that you live next to the raging waves.&quot; (Professor Qu Chan&#39;s River University, the door is opposite the Qiantang River.) It also serves as an adjoining place with Xizi, where I recall Dong Gao from Shuxiao. Touhuang writing can make you healthy, and to read the world, liver and intestine test and show. When will Han Su return to cross the ridge, the spring breeze will scratch the head of the wild clouds.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In the letter, &quot;I have been abandoned for many years, but my hands have grown thorny.&quot; Although this is a modest statement, it is also true. Appendix 3 of Volume 6 of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot; contains Zheng Xiaoyan&#39;s &quot;Chronology of Mr. Zhan Antai&quot;. In 1956, Zhan wrote three words in a row due to Xia Chengtao&#39;s trip to Guangzhou and commented: &quot;At that time, Mr. Zhan didn&#39;t write much anymore.&quot; Read &quot;Wu&#39;an Ci&quot; shows that Zhan Antai wrote very few lyrics after 1949, less than two poems per year on average, so this lost letter and lyrics are extremely precious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Letter from Wang Jisi (pictured on the right) to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Letter from Wang Jisi to Zhang Zhongpu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhongpu:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Seven-day benefit letter received . Master Zhejiang saw off all his works, which were extremely beautiful. Here Huang and Chen Zhulao also have poems to send to comrades going to the countryside. If you can mimeograph them, I should send a volume. I recently wrote a set of Sanqu, please correct me hereby attached. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The draft of &quot;History of Literature&quot; has been put away since its second publication. I don&#39;t know when it will be published. Can finish the manuscript. Notes on the Peach Blossom Fan will be available in February or March. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;CUHK has decentralized 200 cadres, including 13 from the Chinese Department. After that, the work will be heavy, and poetry will be Less writing. This hymn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Jiao&#39;an. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp &amp;nbsp; nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Qi &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This letter is deemed to be dated January 20, 1958. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1957, Zhejiang Normal University began an anti-rightist struggle. It lasted for more than three months. 120 teachers, cadres and a group of students were wrongly classified as rightists. Professor Ren Mingshan of the Chinese Department was even wrongly classified. For &quot;extreme right&quot; elements. After October, it entered the rectification movement, that is, the stage of rectification with the main forms of speaking out, speaking out, discussing, and big-character posters. Then, in line with the policy that &quot;education must serve proletarian politics and education must be integrated with productive labor,&quot; a large number of teachers and students went to work in the countryside. &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot; records that on December 20, 1957, the Chinese Department held a celebration meeting to celebrate the approval of Lu Moye, Gao Houzai, and Yu Shi to go to the countryside. It mentioned that the first batch of 56 people were approved to go to the countryside that day (&quot;Hangzhou University&quot; &quot;History 1897-1997&quot; stated that the first batch of decentralized faculty and staff was 144), and Mr. Xia also wrote a couplet to congratulate him: &quot;If you can go down, you can grow up, and when you go to the countryside, you can reach home.&quot; Wang Jisi said in his letter that &quot;Zhejiang Normal University saw off all his works&quot;. Zhang Zhongpu&#39;s &quot;Yimilou Poetry Manuscript&quot; contains a poem &quot;Sending Friends to the Rural Areas&quot;: &quot;Mountains are moved by nine ridges. It is common, but a fool of a thousand years will not expect anything extravagant. The truth is The barnyard grass is diligent in checking things, and the mulberry trees are planted by hand to make a home. The red rain in the sky turns over the spring waves, and the devotion to serve the country shines in the morning clouds. Why is it useful to ask Tao Ling to find the source? The east wind bursts with strange flowers.&quot; Mr. Xia&#39;s diary on December 12 also contains &quot;Part 2&quot; There are three poems in &quot;Hometown&quot;, with the preface: &quot;Rural work such as herding cattle, raising geese and ducks, harvesting rice and other tasks, I can still do it competently, so I wrote a poem for each to express my determination to go to the countryside.&quot; The poem goes: &lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The cow returns from its back and takes possession of the saddle, and the string singing urges people to eat more. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The prosperity of the countryside depends on you, and you can see the black peonies of every family. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not just to show talent, but to go to the countryside to promote prosperity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bamboo whip in hand is like a military order, and a flock of geese and ducks will come. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xincang Gao Yu Le Qiucheng, Nanmu Dongqian takes advantage of the moonlight. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In those days of hard work, in the dragon battlefield, the vast expanse of green clouds listened to the sound of frogs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 11, 1958, Mr. Xia submitted three pieces of &quot;Going to the Countryside&quot; to &quot;Wen Wei Po&quot;, which was published on the 17th. On the 27th, he met Zhang Taiyan&#39;s wife, Ms. Tang Guoli, in the newspaper. &quot;Three Poems of &quot;He Yu&#39;s &quot;Going to the Countryside&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;799&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sanqu sent by Wang Jisi to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation of Sun Yat-sen University at that time was no less favorable than that of Zhejiang Normal University. Zhan Antai, Dong Meikan, etc. were also misclassified. For the right. Wang Jisi&#39;s letter mentioned that &quot;200 cadres of Zhongda University were sent to the lower levels, including 13 from the Chinese Department.&quot; &quot;Huang and Chen Zhu here also wrote poems to send to comrades who went to the countryside.&quot; Huang was referring to Mr. Huang Haizhang (1897-1989), Mr. Chen It should be Mr. Chen Ji (1900-1976). &quot;A Set of Sanqu&quot; written by Wang, the content is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nanlu A Flower Scattered Set&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Jisi&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Farewell to the first batch of comrades from Sun Yat-sen University going to the countryside&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔Nanlu〕〔Yizhihua〕In the past few days, there has been a gust of wind in Kangyuan Garden, and the honor roll has been hung in the aisle; There is a dustpan with clusters of golden flowers and a large double happiness inscription, with more than ten lines of mud and gold inscriptions in block letters underneath. There was an uproar, and the &quot;Roadside Club&quot; spread the news to see who would be the first to go to the battlefield; you can see that this young man had already prepared his bags, and even the old professor was not willing to give in. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔Liangzhou No. 7〕The whole country is united as never before, and we are happy that China&#39;s national destiny has been great, fifteen years Catching up with Britain is not a fantasy. It connects Guangdong and Guangxi in the south, Longjiang in the north, the East China Sea in the east, and Xikang in the west; forest farms have been opened in the snow-capped mountains, and green rice seedlings have grown in the sand; if the Yellow River is not allowed to have turbulent waves, it has to make the Taihang Mountains get out of the way. Take-off beams are installed on the Yangtze River. Going up the mountain, going to the countryside, and seeing thousands of new people rushing forward, crossing the river, crossing the waves, transforming nature and transforming thoughts, and being tempered into steel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[End] Those who go down must cultivate the crops of the entire village, and those who remain must make peach and plum blossoms. With all the walls opened, Kangyuan Garden has already seen a new look. We want to play and sing and beat the gongs and drums to make those right-wing gentlemen who take pleasure in others&#39; misfortunes feel so angry that their bellies swell. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Note: Kangyuan is the seat of Sun Yat-sen University, and the &quot;Roadside Club&quot; is a rectification movement organized by Sun Yat-sen University students. An express newspaper organization organized during the movement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This song is missing from the sixth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Wang Jisi&quot;, &quot;Collection of Rhymes&quot;. Moreover, the handwriting of this song is very different from that of the aforementioned letter, so it must have been written by two hands. Wang Jisi said in &quot;The Vicissitudes of Half a Study Room&quot; written in 1986: &quot;My former lover Xu Bixia was a wonderful partner in my life. In addition to doing housework, she also helped me receive guests and copy manuscripts.&quot; Just like Mr. Chen Yinke wrote a letter in his later years. The signatures were often ghostwritten by Mrs. Tang Yun, and Wang&#39;s piece may have been handwritten by Mrs. Xu. But in the same article, he wrote: &quot;The good times did not last long. After 1957, due to the well-known facts, I praised the &#39;joy of friends&#39; of the previous generations of poets in class and introduced the &#39;joy of the boudoir&#39; in their love works. &#39;, was criticized. Bixia died of illness soon, and the family lost its joy. Political avoidance caused the alienation of friends. This was another small change in half of the study.&quot; Mrs. Xu found out in early 1957 Suffering from a serious illness, he unfortunately died in September 1958. Therefore, there is still some doubt whether the copyist of this essay was Mrs. Xu or other family members or students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The draft of &quot;History of Literature&quot; has been put away since the second big announcement, and I don&#39;t know when it will be completed.&quot; Wang Jisi was involved in the matter several years ago, and Mr. Xia was slightly involved. According to the &quot;Complete Collection of Xia Chengtao&#39;s Diaries&quot; on September 8, 1953: &quot;I received a letter from Ji Si from Sun Yat-sen University, saying that he went to Beijing during the summer vacation and met He Qifang at the Qing family in Pujiang, Peking University. He said that the Institute of Liberal Arts of Peking University wanted to concentrate its efforts on compiling it within two or three years. The first draft of &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; was completed. Ji Si has been sent to work by CUHK for one year, and He Jun also wants to transfer me to participate in this work. Ji Si hopes that Yu can work for one or two years.&quot; September 30, 1955: &quot;Bu Kui Jiao came to the Song and Yuan parts of the literary history written by Ji Si. After reading and discussing the sections of Su, Mei, and European schools, there are many new ideas.&quot; December 24, 1957: &quot;Received from You Guoen, the editorial board member of the &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; of the Institute of Literature , He Qifang, and Yu Guanying wrote a chapter of &quot;The Rise of Ci&quot;, 8,000 words.&quot; May 25, 1958: &quot;Sent &quot;The Rise of Ci&quot; to Yu Guanying of Peking University in the afternoon. This comprehensive university textbook &quot;Literary History&quot; The first draft was supposed to be due in March, but it was two months overdue.&quot; This &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; was signed and edited by five people: You Guoen, Wang Qi (Wang Jisi&#39;s original name), Xiao Difei, Ji Zhenhuai, and Fei Zhengang. It was published in 1963. Published by People&#39;s Literature Publishing House, it is the history of Chinese literature textbook with the largest circulation in China for many years and the most widely circulated in Chinese departments of colleges and universities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Annotations on the Peach Blossom Fan will be published in February or March.&quot; &quot;The Peach Blossom Fan&quot; annotated by Wang Jisi and others was published by the People&#39;s Literature Publishing House in May 1958, and was newly published in April 1959. The first edition was included in the &quot;Chinese Classical Literature Reader Series&quot;, which had a profound influence and has been continuously reprinted to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[昌邑盐田：大自然的“调色盘”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259292]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南固始执法人员盗剪茅台高粱：执法者犯法彰显农业投资之难丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, the government of Sanhejian Town, Gushi County, Henan Province issued a notice confirming the participation of public officials The matter of stealing sorghum. Although the public officials involved have been detained by the police and may be subject to disciplinary action thereafter, the reflection on this incident cannot stop there. The top priority is for local governments to strictly protect the interests of foreign agricultural investors in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, a video shot by a drone spread online. In the video, a man wearing a hat and plainclothes is cutting sorghum ears with scissors, while a uniformed man stands not far away and watches. After discovering that they had been photographed, the two walked towards a parked vehicle nearby. The man wearing a hat put the bucket containing sorghum ears into the trunk of a family SUV and walked towards a car in front of him with the word &quot;Patrol&quot; painted on it and equipped with police lights. car. The men in uniform got into the family SUV and started the vehicle. The poster of the video questioned that law enforcement officers from Sanhejian Town drove people to steal sorghum in patrol cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the video attracted attention, Sanhejian Town government propaganda staff said in an interview with the media on October 22 that the uniformed person in the video was indeed a public official of the town, but he did not participate in pinching sorghum. He was filmed while patrolling to &quot;stop&quot; people from picking sorghum, which caused a &quot;misunderstanding.&quot; The publicist also said that in order to eliminate everyone&#39;s doubts, the public security organs have intervened in the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public security agency’s investigation results quickly slapped the propagandist in the face. A notice issued by the Sanhejian Town Government on the evening of the 22nd showed that after police investigation and verification, the uniformed person in the video was Yin Moumou, a staff member of the Sanhejian Town Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Brigade, and the other person was Zhang Moumou, a villager of Sanhuai Village. The two went to Gaoliang. The thieves cut sorghum ears on the ground; the two have been administratively detained by the police. Next, the Sanhejian Town Discipline Inspection Commission will seriously hold the party members and cadres involved accountable and deal with them in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public officials who are supposed to patrol to stop sorghum theft, drive patrol cars and lead people to cut sorghum and participate in the theft. It is really magical. What&#39;s even more magical is that after the incident was revealed, local officials immediately defended &quot;their own people&quot;, claiming that public officials were not involved in the theft, but to stop theft by the masses. If it hadn&#39;t been later verified by the police, many netizens might have truly believed this statement: Look, the person who stole the sorghum cuttings walked to the patrol car and was about to be taken back for questioning. The law enforcement officers drove away the car that stole the cuttings. There is absolutely nothing wrong with bringing back stolen goods, crime tools, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, they are not just facing netizens. Because the sorghum they stole was not ordinary sorghum. That is the local raw material production base of Moutai Group. As one of the most well-known brewing companies in China, Moutai Group has a high influence. In order to ensure the supply of brewing raw materials, Moutai Group has established raw material production bases in many places, and Gushi County in Henan is one of them. No matter where Moutai Group builds its raw material base, it will undoubtedly receive great attention from the local government. The Gushi County Government has set up a special Moutai organic raw material base construction office, which shows that the local government attaches great importance to this matter. Therefore, when the theft of sorghum cuttings attracted attention on the Internet, the local government would not dare to fool them. The public official literally hit the steel plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even for agricultural projects that the local government attaches great importance to, public officials dare to participate in theft, which shows that theft of crops is common in the local area. Some netizens said that many local farmers have a large amount of sorghum drying in front of their homes, but they do not grow sorghum themselves. So where does the sorghum come from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant information released by Moutai Group, Moutai uses a specialized sorghum variety &quot;Hongyingzi&quot; for brewing. In Renhuai, Guizhou and other places, Moutai Group has purchased Hongyingzi sorghum at a protective price and will acquire it in 2022. The price is as high as 11.2 yuan/kg, much higher than the price of ordinary sorghum on the market. The sorghum grown at the Moutai raw material base in Gushi County is claimed to be organic sorghum, and its purchase price may be higher. Perhaps each thief may not steal too much, but if many people steal, it will cause huge losses to the growers. Perhaps this is why sorghum farming companies have to use drone patrols to detect and stop thieves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is a common problem faced by foreign agricultural investors. Just a few days ago, news broke out in Dancheng, Henan, that hundreds of farmers were robbing corn. News about people stealing peanuts, pumpkins, watermelons, and fish and shrimps emerged one after another across the country. These incidents all have one thing in common. Most of the people who steal things are local farmers, while those who are stolen are mostly people who transfer land for agricultural investment. Of course, there are also people who return to their hometowns to start agricultural businesses, and they are also stolen. After the incident, the local government often excused the local farmers by saying they were &quot;picking up&quot; crops that their owners had missed and discarded. But in fact, these so-called &quot;pickings&quot; often occur when growers are in the process of harvesting. The owner&#39;s harvesting machinery was still working, and the &quot;picker&quot; ran in front of the machine. Is there such a &quot;picker&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Allowing farmers to steal crops will not only harm the interests of investors, but may also cause serious injuries. Recently, there have been many incidents in which farmers were seriously injured or even killed by large harvesting machinery while &quot;picking up&quot; crops. Propaganda staff from Sanhejian Town in Gushi County also said in response to the media that patrols were organized considering that it might be unsafe for people to pick up sorghum during the sorghum harvest. As for the losses caused to growers by farmers stealing sorghum, the propagandist did not seem to care too much, &quot;Rural people just love to take advantage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is not a trivial matter that some farmers &quot;love to take advantage&quot;. The local government&#39;s &quot;harmony&quot; excuse for local farmers instead of safeguarding the interests of agricultural investors in accordance with the law undoubtedly embolden the thieves and makes agricultural investors feel disappointed. If things continue like this, who will dare to invest? Farmers who steal crops shall be subject to public security penalties and criminal penalties. Only in this way can this trend be stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, an urban management law enforcement team member from Sanhejian Town, Gushi County was arrested for stealing sorghum. He hit a large steel plate. The interests of small agricultural entrepreneurs should also be protected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[神舟十七号载人飞船发射取得圆满成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259342]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 11:46:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/451b72081ad4d31f5e60b2323543aa71.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;1104&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/26/451b72081ad4d31f5e60b2323543aa71.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255595&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office, the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft successfully separated from the rocket and entered the predetermined orbit. The astronaut crew is in good condition and the launch was a complete success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the spacecraft enters orbit, it will conduct autonomous rapid rendezvous and docking with the space station assembly according to predetermined procedures. The astronaut crew of Shenzhou 17 will rotate in orbit with the astronaut crew of Shenzhou 16. While working and living on the space station, the Shenzhou 17 astronauts will conduct multiple extravehicular activities and carry out a large number of space science experiments involving basic microgravity physics, space material science, space life science, aerospace medicine, aerospace technology and other fields ( Test) and complete various tasks such as installation, commissioning, maintenance and repair of equipment inside and outside the cabin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mission is the second manned mission in my country&#39;s manned space program entering the space station application and development stage, and the 30th launch mission since the project was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the space station assembly has entered the docking orbit and is in good working condition, meeting the conditions for rendezvous and docking with the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft and the entry of astronauts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[昆明住烂尾楼的业主住房梦终圆，“别样的烂尾生活”画上句号]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259294]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun and her daughter Feifei walked on the new community trail.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b8d8232dd8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b8d8232dd8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun and her daughter Feifei walked on the brand new community trail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After paying the down payment and paying off the loan for more than nine years, Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping finally moved into their new home - starting from the suspension of work in 2014, they were located in Yunnan The house in Kunming has been unfinished for nearly nine years. The owners are still waiting for the good news. Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; can be handed over and moved into in January 2023, almost 8 years after the original delivery time of April 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun sat in the spacious and bright living room of her new home. In 2020, she was the first to move into a property that was unfinished at the time.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/16500e1cba.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/16500e1cba.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255496&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023, Chen Yanchun was sitting in the spacious and bright living room of her new home. In 2020, she was the first to move into a property that was unfinished at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ping and her daughter were in a beautifully decorated new house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f386496a1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/f386496a1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023, Liu Ping In a beautifully appointed new house with my daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong finally moved into his new home ten years after buying a house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/43516986f9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /43516986f9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong finally moved in ten years after buying a house My new home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, movers unloading trucks in &quot;A Different Kind of Happy City&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/72f37ac63a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/72f37ac63a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023,&quot; Movers unloading a truck in &quot;A Different Kind of Happy City&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The clock is turned back to May 2020. More than 40 owners have moved into their unfinished &quot;homes&quot; one after another after the houses have been unfinished for many years and the delivery is far away. They purchased some second-hand furniture, and some residents installed solar panels to power lights and chopped firewood for cooking in the house. The community has 12 buildings with 18 floors and a total of 1,243 residences. The neighborhood was once the location of Kunming Wujiaba Airport. According to the plan, the new Wujiaba area will be the future urban CBD center area of ​​Kunming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On August 24, 2020, as night fell, an owner of an unfinished building in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; lit up a lamp and stood in front of the window.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b77fb99a8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b77fb99a8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On August 24, 2020, as night fell, an owner of an unfinished building in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; lit up his lights and stood in front of the window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, less than half of the residents of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; are currently occupied.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/bc3f93d88d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /bc3f93d88d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; currently has less than Half of the residents are occupied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, when night falls, the lighting in the community turns on, which is completely different from the previous appearance without water and electricity.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7d5e2b95ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/7d5e2b95ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, night falls, the community’s The lights come on, which is completely different from before when there was no water or electricity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun&#39;s daughter Feifei looked in the mirror in a simple room with advertising plastic sheeting on the floor.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/9e036e4eed.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/9e036e4eed.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun’s daughter Feifei Looking in the mirror in a simple room, the floor of the room is covered with advertising plastic sheeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun&#39;s daughter Feifei finally moved into a beautifully renovated house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/e4edb1596d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ e4edb1596d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun’s daughter Feifei finally moved into the beautifully decorated house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Yanchun was the first owner to live in an unfinished building at that time. She moved her several-year-old daughter into an empty building, spread plastic sheets on the ground, and planted vegetables in the open space outdoors. From time to time, she had to drive away wild dogs and other uninvited guests. Faced with her daughter&#39;s question &quot;When can I live in a beautiful house?&quot;, she could only cry helplessly. One after another, other owners saw that such a single mother could take her daughter to live in an unfinished building with nothing, and many desperate owners also moved in. Liu Ping is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun, the first owner to live in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, reclaimed a vacant land Vegetable patch.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f5e073b552.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f5e073b552.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun, the first owner to live in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, reclaimed a vegetable plot in the vacant land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun took her daughter for a walk in the community and picked vegetables. She placed several foam boxes in the open space below her home to grow vegetables.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6b494d0906.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6b494d0906.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 In October of this year, Chen Yanchun took her daughter for a walk in the community and picked vegetables. She placed several foam boxes in the open space below her home to grow vegetables. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong planted some plants in her new home.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e2a5060a19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/e2a5060a19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong planted seeds in her new home picked up some plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, the owners are satisfied with the environment of the community that is no longer what it used to be.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/0eee253301.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ 0eee253301.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the environment of the community that is now different from the past makes the owners feel satisfy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Different Happiness City&quot; Plot 4 began construction in May 2013, and obtained a commercial housing pre-sale license in May 2014. Liu Ping paid a down payment to buy a 151-square-meter house. The monthly mortgage loan is close to 10,000 yuan. With the hard work of her and her husband, the pressure of repaying the loan is not too great. Later, the developer Kunming Xiaoan Demolition Management Co., Ltd.&#39;s capital chain broke, causing the project to be unfinished and unable to be delivered on time. It wasn&#39;t until 2017 that Liu Ping and his wife realized that the house was really in ruins. In June 2020, she moved into an unfinished house with her 11-year-old daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Liu Ping, the owner of Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, was cleaning up her room. Her room There is only a bed and a table.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/47b6ad4c44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/47b6ad4c44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Liu Ping, the owner of Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, was cleaning up her room. Her room only has a bed and a table. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ping&#39;s daughter was doing homework in her room. There was a big white bear on the bed. This was her birthday gift.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/27c8434fde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/27c8434fde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 , Liu Ping&#39;s daughter was doing homework in her room, and there was a big white bear on the bed, which was her birthday gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, residents of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; walked their children in the recreational facilities provided by the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/be0e0ee3d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/be0e0ee3d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; Residents walk their children in the recreational facilities provided by the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, a child took a selfie in front of the stainless steel dolphin statue in the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/b3411b52b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ b3411b52b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, a child stood in front of the stainless steel dolphin statue in the community Selfie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 27, 2020, Guandu District Guan Guan Sub-district Office announced that after research, the &quot;Different Kind of Happy City&quot; No. 4 is scheduled to be launched at 9 o&#39;clock that day. The construction of the land is resumed and continued, and the house will be completed and handed over by the end of October 2021. In order to ensure construction safety and normal and smooth operation, the owners who have moved into Lot 4 are requested to actively cooperate in moving out of the construction site. Owners who do not have a place to move to the construction site due to living difficulties can promptly contact the sub-district office to apply for temporary transitional housing and handle transitional living matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun was chatting with other owners in the community and sunbathing.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/caf211e348.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/caf211e348. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun was chatting with other owners in the community and sunbathing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, children played on the basketball court provided by the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; community.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7544031d16.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7544031d16.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 10 In August, children played basketball on the basketball court provided by the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping and other owners who lived in unfinished buildings moved into the government&#39;s temporary resettlement housing without any fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, children played in the green square of the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f69c707f85.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/f69c707f85.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, children in the community Play in the green square. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that in order to properly resolve the historical issues left over from the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; project and to deal with claims and debts fairly and equitably, Kunming City, March 10, 2021 The Guandu District People&#39;s Court issued the (2021) Yun0111 Poshen No. 1 Civil Ruling, ruling to accept the bankruptcy reorganization of Xiaoan Company. Since Xiao&#39;an Company entered bankruptcy proceedings, the government has set up a special working group for the disposal of the &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; project to guide and coordinate Xiao&#39;an Company in carrying out bankruptcy proceedings and resumption of work and construction. With the support of state-owned enterprise mutual benefit bond funds and special loan funds for Guaranteed Delivery Buildings, the project fully launched the resumption of construction and construction in May 2021; at the end of November 2022, the main projects of the project were completed and the current housing delivery started; in January 2023, the project was completed After acceptance by five parties, water and electricity were officially connected, and the centralized delivery of houses started on January 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; will be handed over in early 2023, and some owners will move in one after another.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/32bcbddeb4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/32bcbddeb4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255516&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 In October 2020, the &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; was handed over in early 2023, and some owners have moved in one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After taking over the house, Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping decorated the house and moved in smoothly. Liu Ping&#39;s ten-year mortgage was about to be paid off. &quot;My father finally came to live in his new home for two days before he died.&quot; Liu Ping told Southern Weekend reporters that her father passed away not long after he moved into her house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, two children holding balloons walked through the green square of the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/2a8d9c100f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ 2a8d9c100f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255517&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, two children holding balloons walked through the greenery of the community square. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白领因午睡1小时被辞退：为什么只有中国人爱午睡？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259316]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[史地生化移出北京中考：如何理解“选拔”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259183]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many Beijing parents who have children who will take the high school entrance examination in 2025 and beyond have become uneasy recently. In the parent group Various analyzes and discussions. Because Beijing recently issued a new high school entrance examination plan, which will be applicable to students in eighth grade (second grade) this year. The main change is to move the primary four subjects of history, geography, chemistry, and biology out of the examination subjects. They will no longer be counted in the total score of the high school entrance examination. They will be changed into examination subjects, divided into four grades: A, B, C, and D. &quot;The results will be used for graduation.&quot; , for reference in further studies.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, the entrance exams (selective exams) and graduation exams (passing exams) for middle and high schools were separated. The former is the well-known high school entrance examination and college entrance examination. The scores of each subject are counted into the total score. High schools or universities are admitted from high to low according to the total score. The latter is called the Huikao, with passing scores (100 points for the paper-based test and 60 points for the paper-based test). Pass), if you pass the national examination in all subjects, you will obtain a junior high school or high school diploma. The HKCEE in the past was equivalent to the &quot;Academic Proficiency Examination&quot; today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now Beijing&#39;s Primary 4 Course of History, Geography, Biochemistry has been changed to grade-based grades. In essence, this Primary 4 subject has been changed from a selective subject in the high school entrance examination to a subject of a general examination nature. That&#39;s why &quot;the results are used for graduation&quot; &quot; said. As for &quot;use for reference in further studies&quot;, is it left to the high school to decide whether to use it or not, or is it to be used when two candidates have the same total score in the high school entrance examination, and there is no clear statement yet about who has a higher level than the primary four subjects. . The subjects that are still included in the total score of the high school entrance examination include: Morality and Rule of Law, Chinese, Mathematics, Foreign Languages, Physics, Physical Education and Health, a total of 6 subjects, of which Morality and Rule of Law will be changed to open-book examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some parents think this change is good: there are fewer subjects that require high school entrance examinations, and the academic burden on their children is also reduced. This view needs to be looked at in two ways: If parents are not obsessed with their children entering a good high school, that is naturally correct; if parents still want their children to go to a prestigious school, then in the context of a 50-50 split, merit selection It is still inevitable that students will compete for the total score of the remaining six subjects. In order to increase the degree of differentiation, the difficulty of the questions in these six high school entrance examination subjects may be increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other parents disagree and believe that when there are many subjects, if the child cannot learn well in one or two subjects, it can be remedied and he can learn other subjects well. However, now the number of subjects in the high school entrance examination has been reduced. With four doors, there is no room for such remediation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latter believes that kicking the primary school students out of the high school entrance examination will be detrimental to Puwa, who has average qualifications. A netizen said that his distant cousin just took the high school entrance examination in Beijing this year and scored more than 80 points in the math test. She relied on the primary four subjects to get close to the perfect score to bring her total score up, and she was admitted to a city key point. But now this document has Come on, after 2025, children like her will basically have no chance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This view actually makes sense. For subjects like mathematics and physics, even if students memorize every definition, theorem and even every page in the book, it will not help if they do not understand the meaning and connotation. Ultimately, these subjects examine students’ logical thinking (abstract thinking) and pattern (structure, regularity) recognition abilities, which are the core of general intelligence. If you are not talented in this area, relying on experienced teachers to make up lessons may not necessarily have significant results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, in the primary four subjects of history, geography, biochemistry, history is classified as a liberal arts subject, and geography, biology, and chemistry are regarded as science subjects, but the latter are generally regarded as &quot;liberal subjects among science subjects&quot;, especially in junior high schools. At this stage, this Primary 4 exam mainly tests students&#39; memorization. Students with good memory or sufficient diligence will be able to pass the test perfectly and get high scores. Considering that merit-based examinations such as the high school entrance examination and the college entrance examination rank and select students&#39; intelligence and abilities, let subjects such as physics and mathematics remain within the scope of the high school entrance examination, and put Primary 4 subjects within the scope of the passing/standard examination. , is understandable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing wrote in the basic principles of the new high school entrance examination plan: &quot;Cultivate students&#39; scientific spirit, promote the training and selection of talents in basic subjects, and better utilize the role of examination enrollment in improving the quality of the people and serving the strategy of rejuvenating the country through science and education. &quot;It is a basic requirement for a &quot;qualified&quot; merit-based selection examination to allow students with outstanding talents and curiosity to explore the truth to stand out instead of being buried in a pile of high scores without distinction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are also issues worthy of discussion. For example, starting from 2025, Beijing will continue to include sports in the merit-based high school entrance examination, and the score will be increased from 40 points to 70 points. The Beijing Physical Education High School Entrance Examination in 2022 will be changed to a qualifying examination, and reaching the standard will mean full marks, which is a good attempt. Because athletic talent, like intellectual talent, is mainly innate. Sports schools want to select talents with athletic talent, and it is appropriate to conduct relevant merit-based examinations; if they want to go to high school, it is appropriate to conduct passing/standard examinations like Primary 4, otherwise it will affect the &quot;promotion of The goal of &quot;training and selecting talents in basic disciplines&quot; constitutes significant interference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most athletically gifted people and the most intellectually gifted people do not overlap very much. The two kinds of merit-based selection combined will lead to the following: the most athletically gifted and most intelligent people are likely not to go to the best high schools. On the contrary, one type of people will have an advantage: they are not the most outstanding in both talents but The combination is better, the family background is good, the parents are willing to invest, and the individual is willing to work hard. Changing sports to standard examinations can solve this problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media have reported on &quot;junior high school students in the gym.&quot; Parents apply for gym memberships for them and hire private teachers to give them one-on-one tutoring at a cost of several hundred yuan per hour, so that they can strive for the highest possible scores in the physical education high school entrance examination. This is already contrary to the original intention of sports to strengthen the body, and over-training of developing children in adolescence is counterproductive to physical health. There are many cases of knee wear and sports injuries among junior high school students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s high school entrance examination is often regarded as a benchmark. How it is modified may have an impact on the reform of high school entrance examinations in other places. Therefore, it is normal for everyone to be concerned, analyze and discuss a lot. How to take the test will determine how to teach and how to learn. How can the test and teaching truly match the original goals? This is worthy of continuous exploration and reflection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[有人怕狗，有人爱狗，“宠物友好”空间能否消除对立？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259318]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pet Friendly 2&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/4877343745.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/25/4877343745.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255531&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot; >;March 11, 2023, Shanghai Xuhui Riverside, there are many pet-friendly spaces here, and it is regarded as a dog walking paradise by many &quot;poop scrapers&quot;. Photographed by China News Service reporter Yin Liqin Visual China | Picture&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people and dogs meet on a narrow road, there are usually two kinds of fear: fear that the dog will be too enthusiastic and scare the person; fear that the person will be too enthusiastic and scare the dog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of being chased and bitten by dogs in her childhood left a shadow on Luo Youyou. Whenever she encountered an unleashed dog, she would pretend to be calm and leave quickly, but her hands were still shaking and she was so nervous that she couldn&#39;t help but feel nervous. Know which foot to put first.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he went out with his eight-month-old golden retriever Lucky, even though he had a leash on it, Feng Yun still didn’t dare to let curious children touch it. “Lucky is usually very well-behaved, but what if he gets into trouble?” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Youyou and Feng Yun, two types of people who are afraid of dogs and those who love dogs, have a small consensus that human pets should share public places with some separation, but they still have conflicts in the limited space. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, a girl in Chongzhou, Sichuan was bitten by a Rottweiler dog in the community. The police have opened a case for investigation and taken criminal coercive measures against the dog owner Tang Mou in accordance with the law. On October 23, according to Xinhua News Agency, the injured girl had been transferred out of the ICU and her vital signs were currently stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a mother, Luo Youyou is very sad to see such news. When her daughter was under one year old, she was also besieged by pet dogs in the community. She was thankful that her daughter was not injured at the time, and since then she has not dared to &quot;walk her baby&quot; alone in the community. After having a daughter, Luo Youyou discovered that the places for walking babies and walking dogs in the city were highly overlapped. When pushing a stroller into the green space around the community, she often encountered dogs that were not on leashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The habits of dogs determine that they need space to release energy and appropriate contact with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to alleviate the conflict between people and pets, in recent years, Shanghai, Shenzhen, Chengdu and other cities have begun to build &quot;pet-friendly&quot; shopping malls, hotels, parks... allowing pets to enter with conditions, and providing carts, elevators, and toilets. and other “pet-only” facilities and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Opening public spaces is the first step to be pet-friendly, but more importantly, respect and understand the needs of pets: pet owners should walk their dogs in a civilized manner; dog lovers should not tease dogs easily; and ensure the safety of people who are afraid of dogs. Safety and benefits.&quot; Wu Qi, a senior pet behavior expert, founder of China&#39;s PFH (Paw For Heal) therapy dog ​​charity project, and designer of pet-friendly co-creation spaces, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How is a pet-friendly space friendly? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are more and more pet dogs. Some people regard them as companions, while others avoid them. Both those who are afraid of dogs and dog owners feel that the surrounding environment is &quot;not friendly enough&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2022 China Pet Industry White Paper&quot; report released by Paidu Pet Industry Big Data Platform shows that the number of urban dogs and cats in 2022 will be 117 million, and there will be 34.12 million pet dog owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When reminding owners of unleashed dogs, Luo Youyou often hears the answer: &quot;Our dogs are small and don&#39;t bite.&quot; Liu Doudou likes to travel with her Bichon Frize, but she can only choose to drive herself because she is afraid of harm caused by checking it in. In major domestic tourist cities, she found that few hotels allow pets. In Wuhan, where she lives, dogs are almost not allowed to walk on river beaches, greenways, and city parks within the third ring road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some cities are trying to change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paris began allowing dogs into city parks in 2019, with the number of pet-friendly parks rising from 70 to 400. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Shanghai, the Xuhui Riverside on the west bank of the Huangpu River is regarded as a dog-walking paradise by many &quot;poop shovelers&quot;. On weekday evenings, many young people with their furry children also gather for &quot;City Walk&quot;. First let go of the leash in the &quot;Cute Pet Paradise&quot; and let the dog run freely - it is separated by a fence and surrounded by a metal guardrail, which distinguishes the dog walking areas for large and small and medium-sized dogs; after exercising, put on the leash and take the dog with you. Take your dog to a cafe not far away to get a cup of edible pet cream; go to a restaurant marked as pet-friendly to dine outdoors and exchange &quot;pet-raising experiences&quot; with other dog owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Near the Xuhui Riverside Greenbelt in Shanghai, there are many pet-friendly restaurants that allow customers to bring their pets to dine. Photo by Southern Weekend intern Zhao Ruijia&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/84698ab3f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/84698ab3f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255532&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999 ;&quot;>;Near the Xuhui Riverside Greenbelt in Shanghai, there are many pet-friendly restaurants that allow customers to bring their pets to dine. Photo by Southern Weekend intern Zhao Ruijia&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After eating and drinking, we took a walk to the pet-friendly shopping mall &quot;AI PLAZA West Bank Phoenix Nest&quot; two kilometers away. The outdoor third floor here has an area of ​​about 300 square meters. A pet-friendly park that provides pet drinking water, pet poop boxes and pet swings, pillars and other play facilities. You can also use the pet strollers provided for free by shopping malls, take the pet elevator with special signs, and look for stores with pet-friendly signs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pet-friendly shopping malls usually formulate and post pet-friendly rules, restricting pet size, breed and entry methods. / Provided by interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/26ed7b1d47.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/26ed7b1d47.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Pet-friendly shopping malls often develop and post pet-friendly rules that restrict pet size, breeds, and entry methods. Respondents provided&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although pet-friendly spaces are built for pet owners, they are also open to people who are afraid of dogs. Therefore, to achieve &quot;two-way friendship&quot; between people and pets, establishing rules is a prerequisite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that restrictions on pet size, breeds and entry methods are the basic principles of pet-friendly spaces, which are reflected in the &quot;Pet Service Standards&quot; and &quot;Pet-Friendly Convention&quot; posted on site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some pet-friendly restaurants divide the space, isolate special pet-friendly dining areas, and remind customers that &quot;this restaurant accepts pets for dining in specific areas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The front desk of Guangzhou Mandarin Oriental Hotel told Southern Weekend reporters that in order to eliminate the concerns of guests who are afraid of dogs, hotel service staff will remind and supervise pet owners not to let dogs land in public areas, and place them at the door of the room where pets are staying. There is a pet check-in reminder sign. After check-out, the room where the pet has stayed will be deeply disinfected, and an additional cleaning fee of 933 yuan/time will be charged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pet Friendly 3&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b1dbb387db.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2429&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b1dbb387db.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255534&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Pet Friendly Space Rules. Compiled by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Siqi. Drawing by Liang Shuyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even in Shanghai, there are still only a few communities with a strong pet-friendly atmosphere. Feng Yun found that &quot;most parks are still closed to dogs, and Lucky rarely has the opportunity to run free. Living in the city has restricted his nature.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, pet-friendly spaces are not complicated. Zhang Jingyuan, an assistant professor at the School of Architecture of Harbin Institute of Technology (Shenzhen), suggested that it can be carried out around the four levels of food, water, sanitation and activity space, paying attention to the separation of humans and dogs and the isolation of large, medium and small breeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Ling, a professor at the School of Architecture and Urban Planning of Chongqing University, believes that when community space is limited, an area of ​​3-4 square meters can be appropriately divided to build a fence for pets to &quot;have fun&quot;. &quot;The key to a pet-specific activity space is &#39;having&#39; rather than &#39;big&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Allowing pets to enter is only the first friendly step&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Allowing pets to enter&quot; is only the first step For a space that advertises itself as &quot;pet-friendly&quot;, there is also a question mark as to whether its regulations can be strictly followed and truly &quot;pet-friendly&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the AI ​​PLAZA West Bund Fengchao Marketing Department told Southern Weekend reporters that a customer who entered the mall’s pet-friendly restaurant to dine did not put their pet in a cart but on a dining chair. Later, we received complaints from some customers: &quot;You gave people back the chairs that dogs had sat on.&quot; Walking dogs in shopping malls requires the correct use of pet strollers, but there are still a few customers who habitually let their dogs walk. When mall security comes to stop them, sometimes there will be disputes, &quot;Since it is a pet-friendly shopping mall, why can&#39;t you walk dogs?&quot; “Some customers don’t even have leashes and let their dogs roam around the mall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff member said that complying with the pet-friendly regulations of shopping malls mainly depends on the customer&#39;s consciousness. The mall can only provide reminders and suggestions. Fortunately, most customers can adjust their behavior in time after being reminded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is currently no unified standard for pet-friendly spaces. Southern Weekend reporters consulted as consumers and found that the requirements of different hotels vary greatly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Mandarin Oriental Hotel in Guangzhou only allows non-venomous dogs under 10 kilograms and a shoulder height of less than 40 centimeters to stay, and it is not mandatory to check pet IDs. Hyatt Regency Beijing Wangjing allows dogs under 30 kilograms to stay, and there are no breed requirements. Dog licenses and vaccination certificates must be brought when checking in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking her Bichon Frize on a trip, Liu Doudou used to use travel software to filter for &quot;pet-friendly&quot; hotels. Since each hotel has different requirements, she would call the hotel to confirm again before placing the order. Some hotels were labeled as pet-friendly, but after learning that Liu Doudou was traveling with a Bichon Frize, they refused to accept guests on the grounds that “Bichon Frize Frize Frize Frize Frize Dogs shed hair.” “In fact, Bichon Frize Frize Frize Frize Dogs do not shed easily unless they are combed. I pulled hard. The hotel staff didn’t know much about dogs, but I had no choice but to find another home.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pet Friendly 1&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6355cc5c5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;744&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6355cc5c5f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255535&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On December 4, 2022 local time, the International Dog Show was held in Seoul, South Korea. The Bear Dog is undergoing breed standard review. Visual China | Picture&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind pet-friendliness is the pet economy. iiMedia Research data shows that China’s pet market will reach 592.8 billion yuan in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first pet-friendly shopping mall in Xiamen, Xiamen Jianfa Bay Yuecheng has held a cute pet dating party for three consecutive years, including a challenge competition and other activities. Wang Zijia, the professional planning manager of Jianfa Bay Yue City and the person in charge of the pet-friendly project, told Southern Weekend reporters that the Pet Activity Festival held in March 2023 will double the passenger flow to the mall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pet-related activities attract customers, but the professionalism of some activities needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Qi discovered that five or six years ago, the &quot;Pet Big Eater Competition&quot; was popular in shopping malls in first-tier cities in China, where they competed to see who could finish dog food faster. The activity is very popular with dog food manufacturers, but it ignores the damage to the dog&#39;s body. If a dog participates in running and jumping activities after overeating, there is a risk of gastric torsion, which may be life-threatening in severe cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At present, pet eating competitions have basically disappeared, but many pet-friendly businesses still like to hold pet obstacle competitions. The appearance of pets trying to pass through the obstacles can make people laugh, but for pet dogs that have not been professionally trained , the owner’s forceful tugging will only keep them in a state of shock throughout the process,” Wu Qi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Regard pets as equal beings&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When I met a cute pet dog on the road, I couldn’t help but stare into its eyes and touch its head. You think you are showing kindness to your dog, but the feedback you receive may be aggression from the dog, even if it is a breed known for its docility. Because in unfamiliar situations, the behavior of touching the head and looking directly at the dog can easily be interpreted as hostility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be truly pet-friendly, hardware facilities are not enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Ling told Southern Weekend reporters that the premise of creating a pet-friendly space is to conceptually regard pets as equal living individuals that are dependent on humans, and their behavioral habits should be systematically studied. Fully understand and respect their daily needs. Taking the &quot;unity, health and peaceful coexistence&quot; of humans, animals and the environment as the basic principle for creating urban public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data released by the Shenzhen Center for Disease Control and Prevention show that from January to August 2023, the number of people exposed to dog injuries in the city reached 149,000, due to licking, scratching or bites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Qi believes that the problem of human-canine conflict does not lie with dogs, but with people. For dog owners, dogs need to be socialized. Pet dogs that are unfriendly to people or even behave aggressively often have not been socialized and have not received good etiquette education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called socialization training means that during the golden period of 2-4 months of dog age, it is fully exposed to different environments, familiar with different spaces, smells and people, so as to adapt to urban life. &quot;Dogs that have missed the best period of socialization and haven&#39;t gone out for a long time are afraid of the outside world. Even a docile Labrador may bite people.&quot; Wu Qi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Liu Doudou travels with his pet, he always carries the dog&#39;s water bowl, food bowl, food plate and sleeping mat with him. After long-term dog walking and education, the nearly two-year-old Bichon Frize has maintained good hygiene habits and has never peed indoors or soiled the facilities in the hotel room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When walking his dog in the community, Liu Doudou kept the leash on him the whole time. &quot;In places with many people and cars, the leash is also for the safety of the puppy.&quot; When encountering pet dogs without leashes, she would sometimes argue with their owners. “Dogs tend to fight with each other, but some owners don’t take it seriously. They also say that their dogs never bite. If you have a puppy, you should treat a puppy well.” You must be responsible for life to the end, you must protect and guide, and you must also prevent puppies from hurting people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jingyuan believes that pet-friendliness is a progressive process that extends from pet owners to commercial institutions, non-profit organizations and even government agencies, gradually affecting the public and forming a social consensus. The stigma against pets and stray cats and dogs mainly comes from fear of the unknown, and eliminating fear must rely on extensive science popularization and public participation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, her daughter, who has just turned one year old, still likes to get close to puppies on the roadside. Luo Youyou neither wants her to be as afraid of dogs as she is, but also does not dare to let her have direct contact with dogs. Wu Qi said that dogs that have been well socialized are safe in contact with children, but they also need guidance from parents. With the consent of the dog owner, let the child keep a certain distance from the dog first, gradually transition from visual contact to close contact, and provide buffer time for the animal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Respect and love are the prerequisites for urban inclusiveness. More and more cities are building child-friendly, disabled-friendly, and elderly-friendly facilities, and promoting ‘pet-friendly’ on the basis of achieving ‘human-friendly’ &#39;, it is also a reflection of the development and civilization of a city.&quot; Zhang Jingyuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Luo Youyou, Feng Yun, and Liu Doudou are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天才球员涉嫌赌球，意大利足球堕落无止境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259262]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/R7D0tn7A3MRpCWFSffZ5mPIjzpSZUTqJkmfJjHsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/R7D0tn7A3MRpCWFSffZ5mPIjzpSZUTqJkm fJjHsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first round of the new Serie A season, Juventus won 3-0 against Udinese. Pogba, the team’s top star and a world-record transfer fee, was on the bench. After watching the game, he underwent a drug test after the game. On September 12, the Italian Anti-Doping Agency announced that Pogba tested positive for drugs and would be temporarily suspended. Subsequently, his B bottle still detected dehydroepiandrosterone. The only good thing is that this substance is widely used in health products and there is a possibility of accidental ingestion. Pogba is currently still investigating what he took during the summer and is waiting for the final punishment. The most optimistic estimate is that he will be suspended for 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One wave has not subsided, and a bigger wave is coming. This time the protagonists are three young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faccioli, 22 years old, the best rookie in Serie A in the 2022-23 season, comes from Serie A giant Juventus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tonali, 23 years old, is the &quot;Prince&quot; of Serie A giant AC Milan. He will join the upstart Newcastle United in the Premier League in the summer of 2023 with a transfer fee of 70 million euros. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zaniolo, 24 years old, was once praised as Totti&#39;s successor at Roma Club and now plays for the Premier League powerhouse Aston Villa. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that the future is very good, but this is just the glamor on the surface. On the other hand, he is addicted to gambling and even bets on his own team&#39;s games. For this, he has incurred huge debts and has been threatened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the famous paparazzi Corona who started this controversy. In August, he revealed that many Italian players gambled. Because he had so many misdeeds, not many people took him seriously at first. In fact, Fagioli was questioned by Turin prosecutors on June 23, and he subsequently surrendered to the sports prosecutor&#39;s office. He admitted that he had bet on many football games: from the Champions League, Serie A, La Liga, Premier League, to Serie B, Serie C and Turkish Super League, but he had never bet on Juventus. His behavior crossed the line. In Italy, betting is legal, but football players are not allowed to bet on football matches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fagioli said that he lost more than he won when gambling, and owed more and more money to gambling websites. The debt was about 3 million euros. Some of these websites were overseas. The operators forced him to pay back the money and threatened him. Said to break his legs. He also said that when he was in the National Youth Team, it was his teammate Tonali who suggested that he go to those websites to place bets. He heard that Tonali owed a lot of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tonali is currently the most valuable Italian player. At the end of September, the newly appointed Italian team coach Spalletti announced the squad and Tonali was selected. Spalletti&#39;s predecessor, Mancini, originally had a high reputation, but suddenly resigned on August 13, citing interference in his work by the chairman of the Football Association. Soon after, he went to Saudi Arabia to coach the national team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Corona exposed Faccioli, he also revealed the names of Tonali and Zaniolo. When the new Italian team was training, at the suggestion of the Turin prosecutor, the police went to the Covelciano base to question Tonali and Zaniolo. They were accompanied by the team leader Buffon when he played. He has also been accused of illegal betting. According to a report in La Repubblica, the two people almost cried in front of the police, and their mobile phones and tablets were confiscated by the police. The two soon left Coverciano, and the Italian Football Association stated in a statement that the two did not meet the necessary conditions for training and playing, allowing them to return to their respective clubs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faccioli has been suspended for 7 months. Tonali and Zaniolo are still under investigation. Tonali initially denied and then admitted that he had bet on Milan games. Zaniolo The situation is relatively optimistic. He firmly stated that he was only playing cards on an illegal website and no evidence of his gambling has been found so far. According to the whistleblower Corona, there are still many Serie A players on the blacklist. Is Serie A in trouble? Or is it always the same, no fuss? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After World War II, Serie A quickly developed into the most developed professional league in Europe, relying on internal factors such as economic prosperity and people&#39;s love for football, as well as external factors such as English League One&#39;s salary limit and the lack of the Bundesliga. The boss spends huge sums of money on the stars, the income of coaches and players is second to none in Europe, and the team has a brilliant record in European competitions. Starting in 1963, the two teams of Milan City won the Champions League four times in the 1960s. Also in 1963, Italy&#39;s industrial production increased by 209% compared with 1950, with an average annual growth rate of 9.1%, second only to Japan among major capitalist countries. The influx of money, the cruelty of professional football, and the huge interests involved in winning championships, rankings, and relegations have led to a desperate mentality for victory, and a large number of improper behaviors have occurred in Italian football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/uOv9Sbd8cPKJdCCM8B2hEAFZ8VtABp36MZDHtK6L.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/uOv9Sbd8cPKJdCCM8B2hEAFZ8VtABp36MZDHtK6L.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tonali is under investigation for betting on football. He will move from Serie A team AC Milan to Premier League team Newcastle in the summer of 2023, with a transfer fee of 70 million euros &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Buying opponents&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the last round of Serie A in the 1952-53 season, Patria, which had been relegated early, faced Udinese, who needed to avoid relegation. When Patria led 2-0, players Fossati and Manucci told several teammates that Udinese wanted to win this game and was willing to pay. Patria then played poorly, conceding three goals in a row and losing the game. Udinese successfully avoided relegation. Several &quot;cooperating&quot; Patria players received money at a paper mill in Milan, about 150,000 lire each. They continued to play for the next two seasons, and could have played safely until retirement, but Patria&#39;s loss in November 1954 was investigated, which led to the previous match-fixing behavior. Team member Cetambrino admitted what he did during the previous loss to Udinese. In August 1955, Udinese was demoted to Serie B. Several players involved were punished. Some could no longer play football, and some were suspended for 3 years. Setambrino was only suspended for half a year because he cooperated with the judicial department. After retiring, he became a coach. Catania was also relegated along with Udinese. Their crime was to bribe the referee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After less than three years of calm, the &quot;Achini incident&quot; occurred in Serie A in the 1957-58 season. Because of match-fixing, Padua player Achini was banned for life (later commuted), and Atalanta was demoted to the last place in Serie A, thus falling into Serie B. A similar situation soon occurred again, and Genoa was severely punished in 1960. In April 1960, they were in a critical situation of relegation. Retired former international player Gino Capello acted as a broker. Before the game between Genoa and Atalanta, he found his former teammate Atalanta player Catozzo and left 1 million lire. , hope Atlanta loses to Genoa. Catozzo pretended to agree and then immediately informed Vice President Tentorio, who in turn contacted the investigative department. At the end of the season, Genoa ranked bottom with only 18 points and was relegated to Serie B. The bad luck of relegation cannot be avoided. The Italian Football Federation determined that they had committed illegal activities and deducted 25 points for this reason. So Genoa started playing Serie B with minus 7 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/8Bmy8KcXY8HCyNjLApGByXkoYzjOOb9jC0ajP2gN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/8Bmy8KcXY8HCyNjLApGByXkoYzjOOb9jC0ajP2gN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fagioli, who plays for Serie A team Juventus, was suspended for seven months for betting on football&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Doping testing suspicions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;These improper behaviors are the dark side of Serie A. In some aspects, Serie A is very advanced, such as doping testing. The Bundesliga in 1988 Post-match drug testing only began in 2018. In February 1964, Bologna defeated Turin 4-1 and achieved ten consecutive Serie A victories. After the game, five players from each team took drug tests. In early March, the test results were announced. Five of Bologna&#39;s players were all positive and tested positive for amphetamines. For this reason, the win against Turin was changed to a loss, and one point was deducted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bologna is very dissatisfied because the suspicion is obvious: the amphetamine content in the urine sample is too high, so high that it can cause death, and no one can bear it. After three lawyers filed a complaint with the prosecutor&#39;s office, prosecutors ordered the urine samples to be seized. The urine sample was retested, and this time the problem was complicated: amphetamine was not detected, so there must have been some manipulation before; no one knew who did it and what the motive was. Many years later, Bologna&#39;s team doctor mentioned a name: Milan&#39;s technical director Viani. This season, Milan and Bologna once formed a competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, with three rounds left in Serie A, the penalty against Bologna was cancelled, and they were tied for first place with Inter Milan. After the last three rounds, the two teams have the same points. According to the rules, they have to play the play-offs at a neutral site. Before the game, the presidents of the two clubs, Bologna&#39;s Dalala and Inter Milan&#39;s Moratti, came to the league headquarters to discuss the details of the game. When the two were arguing about the game bonus, Dalala suffered a heart attack and died unfortunately. Four days later, his Bologna side beat Inter Milan to win the Serie A title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inter Milan lost the Serie A title this season, won the Champions League, and defeated Benfica at San Siro a year later to retain the Champions League. They have a luxurious lineup and excellent record. They are known as the big Inter Milan, but their reputation is not good: their victory depends on chain defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6XOCslE9MB6cZIao8TIMM5qhnX1wgwmaD3Plp344.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6XOCslE9MB6cZIao8TIMM5qhnX1wgwmaD3Plp344.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255278&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2006, Juventus executive director Giraudo (left) and manager Moggi (right) watched head coach Capello (middle) leading the team to train&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Style and Morality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chain defense originally refers to a line of defense , the method is to set up free men and implement man-to-man marking to protect the safety of the goal to the greatest extent, and then it has become a symbol of a mentality and football style: passive, utilitarian, giving up possession of the ball, only caring about the result, not caring about the scene, and even using any means. The 1965 Champions League final is an excellent example of the chain defense: Inter Milan&#39;s Pizzi played as a free man, with three defenders in front of him, plus a defensive midfielder. Before the end of the first half, Inter Milan scored a goal, and then Benfica&#39;s goalkeeper was injured and came off the field. Since there was no substitution rule, they could only let defender Germano guard the goal. Facing an opponent with one less player, Inter Milan continued to defend, just wanting to maintain its lead, and finally achieved its wish to win the championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This championship is of extraordinary significance, symbolizing that Italian football has formed its own style. Such a process, whether it is established or changed, will take at least 10-15 years in terms of time, championships in terms of performance, the need to get rid of dependence on foreign coaches in terms of coaching, and the creation of a concept in terms of language to cover and present this style, and someone to serve as the Trumpeter and interpreter, this person can only be Mingji Brera. Serie A resumed in 1946; at the beginning of the 1957-58 season, there was no Hungarian coach in Serie A; in 1960, Viani led the Italian team to participate in the Rome Olympics, and the libero tactic took root in the national team and was used for many years until 1994 The Italian team did not give up free agents until the World Cup in 1963; in the 1963 Champions League final, Milan&#39;s Pivatelli fouled Benfica&#39;s Coluna. That kick ended the innocent era of the Champions League and also helped the Italian team. Won the Champions League for the first time; then Inter Milan won the Champions League twice. All this laid the foundation for the chain defense. This name became synonymous with Italian football and is difficult to separate and continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every country has to go through this journey to find, explore and determine its own style of football. Some disgraceful practices are inevitable, and everyone has their moments of embarrassment. The special thing about Italian football is that the aesthetics of football are much inferior when establishing style. Internally, Bernardini, who is very ambitious, is not as influential as Rocco, Herrera and others; externally, it is difficult to match the all-round football of the Netherlands and Brazil. Beautiful football; and not noble enough in terms of morality. In order to win, he will do anything and not care about anything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Z5OZ4tgPFC9VzVqEgaERzBzKs8QzXYZI4IAazdB4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Z5OZ4tgPFC9VzVqEgaERzBzKs8QzXYZI4IAazdB4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zaniolo, who plays for the Premier League team Aston Villa, is under investigation for gambling&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The end justifies the means&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to conservative tactics, the Italian team has also been criticized for taking banned drugs, bribing referees, and using off-the-table tricks. In the 1966 Champions League semi-finals, Inter Milan lost to Real Madrid. Hungarian referee Vadas officiated the second round. He was meticulous and impartial. Real Madrid tied Inter Milan 1-1 and advanced with a total score of 2-1. A few years later, Vardas revealed to reporters that Inter Milan&#39;s agent Solti approached him, but he refused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Solti is also a Hungarian, and he not only serves Inter Milan. In the 1973 Champions League semi-finals, Juventus eliminated Derby County. After the first round, Derby County coach Clough was extremely unconvinced and cursed. His anger was not without reason. Solti gave the referee of the second round, the Portuguese Lobo, $5,000 and a car. Lobo did not accept it and reported it to the referee. He enforced the second round fairly, but the loss in the first round was no longer possible. Redeemable. Later, the famous British journalist Granville went to Portugal and other places to investigate and obtained real and powerful evidence. In 1974, the &quot;Sunday Times&quot; published it to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1974, Italian football was at a low point. The national team only won one game throughout the year, defeating lowly Haiti in the World Cup. In the Champions League finals of the previous two years, Inter Milan and Juventus both lost to Ajax, and they were completely at a disadvantage, with no chance of winning. Subsequently, under the leadership of coaches such as Berzotte and Radice, Italian football began to innovate tactics and reopened the door to foreign aid in 1980. Just when the foreign aid ban was about to be lifted and the future was bright, another match-fixing scandal was exposed in Serie A, namely the Totonero incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/WLN5tfiUnHrWbSO3DhufVC6PWaVo68JzuXmF6bdz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/WLN5tfiUnHrWbSO3DhufVC6PWaVo68JzuXmF6bdz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 11, 1982, in the Spanish World Cup final, the Italian team defeated West Germany 3-1. Paolo Rossi celebrated the victory by lifting the trophy&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The match-fixing was not performed well&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The trigger was the report of two businessmen. The two knew some Lazio players, so they came up with a business opportunity and decided to conspire with the players to make money by fixing games and illegal betting. The Lazio players agreed. The first attempt was a friendly match in November 1979, which ended in a draw as agreed in advance. However, many subsequent games did not result in the preset results, resulting in the two losing a lot of money and being threatened by their creditors. Desperate and unable to bear it any longer, the two submitted a report to prosecutors listing the names of 13 teams and 27 players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Italian Fiscal Guard subsequently took action. On March 23, 1980, during the Serie A match between Lazio and Pescara, the Fiscal Guard drove onto the runway of the Stadio Olimpico in Rome. This scene shocked the country. Subsequently, many players were arrested or surrendered, involving five Serie A teams and two Serie B teams. Milan Club Chairman Colombo was also taken away by the police. In the end, Serie A teams Milan and Lazio were relegated to Serie B, and many players were banned. The most famous of them was Paolo Rossi. He was initially suspended for three years, and then reduced to two years, just in time for the 1982 World Cup. He scored six goals and contributed greatly to the Italian team&#39;s championship. But all those arrested were acquitted because the laws in Italy were weak at the time and they had not broken the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Serie A lifted the ban on foreign players, Roma introduced Brazilian star Falcao, and then recruited his compatriot Cerezo. They reached the Champions League final in 1984, losing to Liverpool in a penalty shootout. There was no controversy in this final, the dirty deeds occurred in the semi-finals. In the first round, Roma lost to Dundee United away from home. Before the second round, they paid famous French whistleblower Michel Utu 100 million lire. They won 3-0 in the end. The third goal was a suspicious penalty kick, which attracted the attention of the outside world. widespread doubts. Within the Roma club, it was an open secret to bribe Utu. Two years later, Roma president Viola was banned by UEFA for bribing referees. His son publicly told the details of sending money to Utu years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1984 Champions League final, Roma lost. A year later, Juventus won, winning this trophy for the first time in team history. It was also the first time an Italian team won the trophy after 16 years. Marking the renaissance of Serie A. Berlusconi&#39;s Milan then became the Serie A champion and European hegemon, reaching the Champions League finals five times in seven years and winning the title three times. With the influence of the Milan club, Berlusconi also became prime minister. One of his purposes in entering politics was to escape legal sanctions. After he succeeded, he blatantly used political operations to protect himself and his company. Everyone knew that he was doing whatever was wrong, but there was nothing he could do except condemn him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/MnezoqJxbx4YwibyOkffjg0V2hr27UmPx95DjVgk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;783&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/MnezoqJxbx4YwibyOkffjg0V2hr27UmPx95DjVgk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2011, former Italian youth team goalkeeper Marco Paolini, a goalkeeper from the Roma youth academy, was arrested by the local police on suspicion of match-fixing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Doping, phone calls and false accounts&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Juventus wins the title for the second time They won the Champions League in 1996, and their physical fitness was amazing at that time. In July 1998, Roma coach Zeman accused someone in Serie A of doping in an interview. He named Vialli and Del Piero, believing that their muscles grew by taking drugs. The Italian judicial department began a six-year investigation. Finally, in November 2004, the Turin District Court sentenced Agricola, Juventus&#39;s medical director, to 22 months in prison with a suspended sentence. The court held that between 1994 and 1998, he made many Juventus players take EPO (erythroblast stimulating hormone), but the players did not know it. Everyone was safe except Agricola. Juventus executive director Giraudo was found not guilty. He said the verdict reaffirmed his innocence. Juventus is innocent, and Agricola will continue to be Juventus&#39; team doctor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Giraudo was not happy for long. On May 4, 2006, &quot;Gazzetta dello Sport&quot; published the contents of a call between Juventus manager Moggi and the Serie A referee assignor, which shocked Italian football. Moggi soon admitted that he had bribed referees and Football Association officials. The Juventus board of directors, including Moggi and Giraudo, resigned collectively, and the president and vice-president of the Italian Football Association also resigned. The Italian Sports Tribunal relegated Juventus to Serie B, deprived them of their two Serie A titles, and punished Milan, Fiorentina and Lazio with point deductions. Giraudo was also punished, and he has not given up since then, hoping for a retrial. In 2020, he appealed to the European Court of Human Rights, and there has been progress in the process recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Giraudo was running for himself, his old club Juventus had already experienced another punishment after the phone call. The crime this time was financial fraud, for which 7 Serie A points were deducted. Like Moggi and Giraudo in the past, the then chairman Andrea Agnelli led the management to resign collectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the turmoil and disgrace in Italian football, some are due to the failure to introduce and amend the law in time, which has led to some people escaping jail and encouraged others; some are due to the advanced measures taken. Unscrupulous people take advantage of it; some are overconfident, unscrupulous, and contemptuous of rules and public opinion; and some behaviors are universal and due to human nature, such as match-fixing and doping. German coach Neuerluhle said in 2007 that he was When coaching Schalke 04, I personally saw players taking Captagon. &quot;This is not a secret, it has become a routine. It has become a part of football, and 50% of the players are using this drug.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The Italian national team won the European Cup in 2021, which brought a brief boost. Then Italian football fell into a trough and suffered a blow. The latest illegal gambling by young players reflects and participates in the current situation in Italy: the economy is facing difficulties, the administrative system is inefficient, and some social problems are hopeless. French scholar Bloch said that a person is better like the era in which he lived than his father. The same is true for a country&#39;s football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[晚明“王学误国”正确吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259199]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/IZqRHIooVi8eeNbCb6YtNanNPdrjN4Vi2W6wkWRD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1061&quot; height=&quot;2141&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/IZqRHIooVi8eeNbCb6YtNanNPdrjN4Vi2W6w kWRD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait scroll of Wang Shouren in the National Museum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Jiajing period, the Ming Dynasty has suffered from internal and external troubles and numerous crises. Some people attribute it to Yangming&#39;s philosophy of &quot;talking about harming the country&quot;. After the Ding Revolution, the survivors of the Ming Dynasty learned from the pain, reflected on the historical lessons of the country&#39;s subjugation, and believed that &quot;Wang Xue&quot; was one of the culprits. The most representative figure among them is Gu Yanwu. In his article &quot;The Master&#39;s Words and the Way of Heaven&quot;, He denounced Wang Xue&#39;s &quot;empty words of understanding one&#39;s mind and one&#39;s nature, replacing the practical knowledge of cultivating oneself and governing others&quot;, which resulted in &quot;the collapse of the Chinese state and the ruins of clans and societies!&quot; Famous Confucian scholars such as Zhang Luxiang, Lu Longqi, Lu Shiyi, and Xiong Cilu all expressed this opinion. , and advocated the revitalization of Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism and the application of practical knowledge to correct the shortcomings of Wang Xue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Chengzhi, a survivor of the Ming Dynasty, said unceremoniously in a letter to Gu Yanwu&#39;s nephew Xu Yuanwen that Gu Yanwu&#39;s denigration of Yangming&#39;s studies was just a remnant of the spit of an old student in Wujiang, and had no factual basis. , very emotional. Some modern scholars have expressed doubts about Gu&#39;s statement. The author believes that the &quot;Wang Xue theory of subjugation of the country&quot; is divorced from the facts and is the product of the party struggle at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/dE644zekk4itpgNoM2BQWeY7aFJ8XwkF3LS0IQYz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/dE644zekk4itpgNoM2BQWeY7aFJ8XwkF3LS0IQYz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of Gu Yan is in the collection of the National Museum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, theoretically speaking, Yangming&#39;s philosophy of mind is not a study of mysterious emptiness and emptiness as Gu and others said, but a study of practical application of the world. In his &quot;Reply to Gu Dongqiao&quot;, Yangming criticized &quot;those stubborn, empty and quiet people&quot; who &quot;cannot govern the country and the world&quot;, and advocated &quot;practicing one&#39;s work&quot; and integrating knowledge and action. He publicly declared that he disdained the study of exegesis, memorization, and verses. He said that practicing verses was &quot;as if he were on the stage of a hundred plays.&quot; It&#39;s shameful.&quot; Wang Yangming had the ambition to help the world since he was a child. He studied riding and archery, and studied the art of war. He once went deep outside the Great Wall to inspect geography. The most outstanding sign of his integration of knowledge and action was the application of the art of mind to military practice. According to his disciple Wang Ji&#39;s &quot;Yu Yu&quot; Recalling the article &quot;Xu Jiang&quot;: When I asked my former master what was the secret behind the saying that he was like a god in using troops, the master said: &quot;I have no secret skills, but I have always believed in conscience. Whenever I take advantage of the opportunity to face the enemy, I only have this little bit of spiritual intelligence and spiritual response.&quot; , I am not moved by the interests of life and death, so my plans are carefully planned, and the enemy does not know where he is coming. I am originally a person who practices my duty, but the world mistakenly thinks that I am a god.&quot; Volume 4 of He Liangjun&#39;s &quot;Siyou Zhaicong Shuo&quot; concludes : Wang Yangming said, &quot;The military is based on lectures and tactics are used, and the administration is based on lectures and political skills.&quot; The mutual complementation of academics and achievements enabled Yangming to achieve great success in the military. During the Jiajing period, in response to the imperial court&#39;s outright rejection of Yangming&#39;s scholarship, Huang Wan pointed out that the essence of Yangming&#39;s scholarship was &quot;to consider what people say and do, and not to just talk in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, from a practical point of view, many disciples of the Wang Sect and their followers have made achievements that will be remembered by future generations. Yangming did not regard knowledge as the only criterion for accepting disciples. Among his disciples were potters, farmers, woodcutter, etc. There were knights who &quot;fighted dragons and snakes with bare hands&quot;, counselors who made plans, and generals who led troops to fight. For example, Hu Zongxian, a disciple of Ouyang De, led the army and people of Zhejiang to fight against Japanese invaders, and planned to capture and kill the great Japanese pirates Wang Zhi and Xu Hai to quell the Japanese invaders in Zhejiang and Zhejiang. Weng Wanda, governor of Shaanxi and governor of Xuanda, was one of the coffin bearers when Wang Yangming was buried. He was friendly with Yangming&#39;s disciples Ouyang De, Luo Hongxian, Tang Shunzhi, Wang Ji and others. Weng Wanda was in charge of the northern border defense for five or six years, and made outstanding achievements in fighting against the invasion of Mongolia. Guo Zizhang, a disciple of Ouyang De, patrolled Guizhou in the 26th year of Wanli (1598). He worked with Li Hualong to suppress Yang Yinglong&#39;s rebellion in Bozhou and was known as the first famous official in central Guizhou. Luo Rufang, a student of Yan Jun, was criticized by people in the early Qing Dynasty for &quot;talking about nothing&quot;. In fact, he visited many places to study and inspect society in his early years. In the early years of Wanli, the imperial court adopted a policy of appeasement against the expansion and aggression of the Burmese king. According to the &quot;Bureau&quot;, Luo Rufang, who was then a right-hand political participant in Yunnan, planned to encircle the Mang clan of the Burmese king. However, his success fell short because someone slandered the governor Wang Ning. Luo Rufang &quot; He threw himself to the ground in anger and cursed loudly.&quot; This caused serious trouble, and the Burmese army invaded Yunnan in a large scale. Li Cai, who had studied under Zou Shouyi, wiped out pirates and Japanese pirates when he was in Guangdong; when he was in Yunnan, he defeated the Burmese invasion. Luo Hongxian, the number one scholar of the Private Shu Wang Yangming, is described in the original &quot;History of the Ming Dynasty&quot; as &quot;leaping a horse and drawing a bow, studying the history&quot;, and the river channels, frontier fortresses, battle formations, offensive and defensive, etc. are not studied in detail. Shunzhi of Tang Dynasty in Huiyuan Dynasty, who &quot;heard the words of conscience from Wang Ji&quot;, is said in the &quot;History of Ming Dynasty&quot; to &quot;know everything about learning&quot; and pay special attention to practical learning. He &quot;never forgot the world and the country in his heart&quot;, and until his deathbed, he still thought about the safety of the country and did not care about his private affairs. In the thirty-sixth year of Jiajing&#39;s reign (1557), Zhao Wenhua, a member of Yan Song&#39;s party, supervised the military affairs of Jiangsu and Zhejiang and recommended him as the chief of the Nanjing Ministry of War. Shun Zhi put the country first, regardless of the tarnished reputation, and resolutely came out of the mountain. He inspected Jizhen, verified the number of troops, and put forward many practical suggestions. He also assisted Hu Zongxian in fighting against Japanese invaders, patrolled the sea to inspect the situation of bandits, formulated strategies to attack, intercept and block the enemy, and personally commanded and won great victories such as Yaojiadang. The famous anti-Japanese generals Tan Lun, Yu Dayou, Qi Jiguang, Liu Xian, etc. were all appreciated and promoted by him. In addition, Yan Jun, Xu Wei, disciples of the Wang family, and Zheng Ruozeng, who was influenced by Yangming&#39;s psychology, all served in the Hu Zongxian shogunate and made their own contributions to the pacification of Japan in different ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many military generals with great military exploits are also disciples of the Wang Clan. For example, Governor Wanbiao got his philosophical ideas from Wang Ji, Luo Hongxian, Qian Dehong and Tang Shunzhi. He once personally led the monk soldiers to fight against the Japanese pirates at Yangjing Bridge in Suzhou, and he was hit by an arrow but did not get out of the line of fire. Yu Dayou followed Yangming&#39;s Xinxue in his early years and later studied under Tang Shunzhi. Qi Jiguang was also &quot;a private person of Shu Yangming and a great expounder of conscience&quot;. He once entered Qian Dehong&#39;s family, and Qian Dehong recommended him to Hu Zongxian. Qi Jiguang advocated taking &quot;sincerity&quot; as the work force, &quot;practicing it personally&quot;, and focusing on &quot;treating the mind&quot; in military training. Deng Zilong learned from Luo Hong before he became an official, and he kept it in mind throughout his life. He fought in all directions and made many meritorious deeds. Later, in the war to aid Korea, even though he was nearly seventy years old, he fought bravely to kill the enemy and sacrificed his life for the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from this that since the Ming Dynasty, everyone in the Wang family has been a person of great achievements. On the other hand, among the Donglin Party members, except for loyal and honest ministers, there are very few capable ministers in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the grim reality of &quot;the sky collapsed and the earth collapsed&quot; in the late Ming Dynasty, the Donglin Party members mistakenly blamed Wang Xue and believed that Zhu Zixue was the panacea to save the world. They criticize the corrupt Confucians for being &quot;ignorant of affairs and current affairs. They harm one person, harm the whole family, harm one country, and harm the whole world.&quot; (&quot;Chronicles of Donglin Academy· Donglin Theory of Learning&quot;) This is precisely the self-portrait of the Donglin Party members. The Taizhou School founded by Wang Gen, a disciple of Yangming, has long pointed out that &quot;human relations physics&quot; and &quot;common people&#39;s daily needs&quot; are Tao, and the disciples of Cheng and Zhu are the corrupt Confucians who &quot;do not understand affairs and are not familiar with current affairs.&quot; In the second year of Duanping in the Southern Song Dynasty (1234), the Neo-Confucian master Zhen Dexiu paid homage to Zhen Dexiu to consult on political affairs. People had high expectations for him, thinking that he could establish peace. However, after Zhen Dexiu took office, Prime Minister Zheng Qingzhi did nothing and could not save the declining Southern Song Dynasty. Therefore, the Yuan people&#39;s cancellation of the imperial examination for a time had something to do with the empty talk of Song Confucianism that harmed the country. Song Lian, the leader of civil servants in the early Ming Dynasty, advocated the use of Confucianism, but he had to admit in the &quot;Biography of Wu Deji&quot; that Song Confucianism could not do much more in promoting Confucianism, but in the end he did not make much difference to the world. By the middle of the Ming Dynasty, Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism was on the verge of &quot;dying to death&quot; because the late Neo-Confucianists &quot;only discussed it in footnotes&quot;. In &quot;Remembering the Past&quot;, Li Zhi mocked the pedantic Confucians who &quot;have nothing to do in their daily lives, only do bows and bows, and sit all day long. They are like clay sculptures and think that they cannot afford distracting thoughts. This is the real great sage and great sage.&quot; And &quot;when there is a police officer, they look at each other with no color, and even blame each other, thinking they can be wise.&quot; In &quot;The Biography of Mr. Yangming, the Confucian Prince of the Ming Dynasty&quot;, the scholar Shen Shixing sharply criticized those who attacked Wang Yangming: &quot;Most of the Confucian officials in modern times take it for granted that they are well-dressed and well-dressed, but when it comes to their daily use, they often suffer from rigidity and nothing.&quot; To make achievements; to study extensively and listen in order to learn, but to find out the actual results, they are often obsessed with what they have seen and heard without experiencing, and the customs have been immersed in them for a long time!&quot; This kind of person may be morally impeccable, but he is mediocre and incompetent, and only knows how to die in literature. Advice, fight to the death. Donglin Party members equate morality with ability, and due to the limitations of the times, it is difficult to give a fair definition of &quot;morality&quot;. In the face of foreign aggression, they do not know how to adapt and are immoral. Zhang Luxiang&#39;s &quot;Yuan Xue Ji&quot; says that &quot;Yangming used troops mostly to win by deceit, which Confucians would not do.&quot; University scholar Wang Xijue pointedly pointed out: Zou Yuanbiao, the highly respected moral benchmark in Donglin, is just a &quot;student with simple wishes and no other extraordinary ideas.&quot; There is a shortage of talents in the temple, and there is an urgent need to break down barriers and recruit talents in any way. Zhang Juzheng had long been dissatisfied with the &quot;conventional and vulgar Confucianism&quot; and called for &quot;heroic and true Confucianism&quot;. Jiang Yingke said in &quot;Ancient Theory on Employment&quot;: &quot;To achieve great things, do not pay attention to details; to achieve great achievements, do not pay attention to small righteousness.&quot; Some people even want to select talents from the grassland. Li Zhi especially praised the pirate Lin Daoqian, Zhong In &quot;Preface to Water Margin&quot;, Xing also lamented that &quot;there are no Li Kui or Wu Yong in the world&quot; and &quot;every time I recite the autumn wind, I think of the warriors and shout madly for them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to corrupt Confucianism, pseudo-Taoism is more harmful. Li Zhi had long criticized the pseudo-Confucianism in &quot;The Theory of the Return of Three Religions to Confucianism&quot; that &quot;yang represents Taoism, yin represents wealth and honor, being subdued by elegance, and behaving like a dog and a pig.&quot; The Donglin Party members adhered to their sectarian views. After taking control of the election, &quot;anyone who disobeys Donglin will be accused of being traitorous.&quot; Later, the society was restored to &quot;hijack the government and control the government from afar.&quot; On the occasion of the change of dynasty, many Donglin Party members &quot;changed their rules and changed their ways&quot;, which was surprising. Therefore, Li Zhi said long ago in &quot;Party Stele&quot;: Secular people &quot;only know that villains can harm the country, but they don&#39;t know that gentlemen can harm the country.&quot; Wei Xi&#39;s &quot;On the Song Dynasty&quot; also said: &quot;The disasters of the country are not caused by villains, but by gentlemen.&quot; They are members of the same party and oppose differences. They do not pursue selfish interests, are interested in fame and profit, and do not hesitate to kill themselves to gain fame. This is what Zhang Tingyu said in &quot;Cheng Huai&quot; It is said in &quot;Yuan Yu&quot; that &quot;killing the remains of parents will lead to the tyranny of the country, loyalty and filial piety, and both will be damaged.&quot; Therefore, some knowledgeable people in the early Qing Dynasty believed that the Ming Dynasty did not fall to rogue bandits, but to Donglin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to partisan factors, &quot;The Theory of Wang Xue Misleading the Country&quot; also has a strong regional flavor. In the Ming Dynasty, the Donglin Party and the Zhejiang Party were at odds with each other. Later, the Zhejiang Party relied on the Eunuch Party, and they even fought to the death. In academic terms, Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism and Lu Wang Xinxue were also on the same page. From the late Ming Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty, those who sympathized with the Donglin Party People have the right to speak, and the mainstream ideology is Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism. During the Daoguang period, Liang Shaoren, a native of Qiantang, expressed strong dissatisfaction with this in his &quot;Essays on Two Kinds of Autumn Rains&quot;. He believed that &quot;Wang Wencheng&#39;s achievements are shining brightly, and he is the best of his generation. He only reveals the world with his conscience, which is a little tired of his cleverness, and the debaters are extremely intent on slandering him. It is said that the world with Ming will not perish by bandits but perish by Yang Ming, how can you say it!&quot; He sighed: &quot;Today the world is all disciples of Zi Yang, no wonder thousands of people gathered together to point it out!&quot; According to Liang Qichao&#39;s &quot;China in the Recent Three Years&quot; According to &quot;A Hundred Years of Academic History&quot;, in the early Qing Dynasty, even righteous men such as Huang Daozhou, Zhang Huangyan, Wang Yi, Qu Shishu, Chen Zizhuang, Zhang Jiayu, etc. who insisted on resisting the Qing Dynasty and restoring the Ming Dynasty did not dare to consider themselves to have &quot;come from the arms of the mother of the Yangming School&quot; &quot;Nurture them out&quot;, but their motivation to resist the Qing Dynasty actually came from the Yangming School. It can be seen that Cheng and Zhu were powerful in the Qing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259304]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Who is Chizuru Ueno? Searching for the topic of the same name on Weibo, there are 100 million views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, three female bloggers who graduated from Peking University had an online conversation with Chizuru Ueno, and the resulting controversy put the latter&#39;s name at the top of the hot search list. So far, the entries for this conversation have been read 580 million times on the Weibo platform alone, and the topic about Chizuru Ueno has &quot;broken the circle.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was launched in 2019. Prior to this, very few of Chizuru Ueno&#39;s books were published in mainland China, and most of them were circulated in the sociology circle. In 2019, Chizuru Ueno spoke at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo. After the video circulated on the Internet, she also gained great popularity in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pbMFkPyJfomiNeKNr1xyLeC0o695DUDJQ7hXLarN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pbMFkPyJfomiNeKNr1xyLeC0o695DUDJQ7hXLarN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno, born in 1948 in Toyama Prefecture, Japan, is a Japanese sociologist and a pioneer in the fields of Japanese women&#39;s studies and gender studies. She is currently an honorary professor at the University of Tokyo. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her speech, she focused on the two incidents of Tokyo Medical University entrance examination fraud and Tokyo University sexual assault. , questioned the widespread gender discrimination in Japanese society, and then pointed out through data that the ratio of male and female students at the University of Tokyo is uneven, but the reason is not that female students are not as good as male students, but that &quot;there are various wrong social concepts and unfair admissions in entrance examinations&quot; question&quot;. Ueno warned the freshmen: &quot;What awaits you in the future will be a society where no matter how hard you work, you may not get a fair reward...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chizuru Ueno was introduced to China in 2015 after a speech at the University of Tokyo sparked discussion. Zi&#39;s ​​old work &quot;Misogyny&quot; was quickly reprinted more than twenty times, becoming an important publishing phenomenon in recent years. Since then, other works by Chizuru Ueno have been introduced and published. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SEwHeYTpgxYro1N6jgVu2AFAc3iQGd594JarO1uR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height= &quot;1621&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SEwHeYTpgxYro1N6jgVu2AFAc3iQGd594JarO1uR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno spoke at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo in 2019. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the influences of the book &quot;Misogyny&quot; is that &quot;Misogyny&quot; ) such an academic term has been successfully transformed into popular vocabulary. Ueno believes that men often show contempt for women, while women show self-loathing: &quot;If I am 100% not misogynistic, there is no need to be a feminist, because I no longer need to fight. Feminism means constant People who struggle with inner misogyny.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, netizens have often habitually incorporated it into their own life situations to explain the underlying causes of many unpleasant events in life, such as secretly filming women Private photos are uploaded online, gender discrimination in the workplace, product advertising creates body anxiety, celebrities &quot;cheat&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Publisher Chen Xiying published a collection of conversations between Chizuru Ueno and manga artist Nagako Tamafusa in 2021 &quot;From &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot; has actual sales of more than 200,000 copies and continues to be printed. In Chen Xiying’s impression, after the word feminism entered China, everyone was still relatively unfamiliar with its connotation and denotation. However, &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot; is a popular work that integrates daily life into Examples are readily available. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue in the book basically revolves around women&#39;s &quot;parental shortcomings&quot;, from the length of the skirts of female students&#39; school uniforms to the fact that women are often accused of &quot;revealing clothing&quot; in sexual harassment cases; from the plots of popular TV series to the dilemma of female childbearing; even when talking about the media&#39;s shaping of teenagers, it makes readers realize that the setting of Shizuka in &quot;Doraemon&quot; both attracting men and rebuking men is also a kind of &quot;misogyny&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese publishing industry published seven Ueno books in 2022, including the best-selling book &quot;Starting at the Limit&quot;. Since 2023, Ueno has published more than ten books in China, including serious academic works, as well as relatively light popular readings and dialogue collections. The content covers Chizuru Ueno&#39;s areas of concern in the past forty years. For example, &quot;Women&#39;s Thoughts&quot;, which combs the ideological context of Japanese women&#39;s studies, &quot;Unpaid Housewives&quot;, which cares about the &quot;unpaid&quot; work of housewives, and &quot;A Man&#39;s Old Queen&quot;, which focuses on the issue of elderly care...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Beijing In an Internet celebrity bookstore that mainly sells best-selling books, Southern Weekend reporters saw that the most conspicuous place at the entrance was Chizuru Ueno&#39;s &quot;Women&#39;s Thoughts&quot;, &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot;, &quot;Misogyny&quot; and &quot;For Survival&quot;. &quot;Thoughts&quot; and other works are placed together with popular and practical books such as &quot;How to Deal with Divorce&quot; and &quot;Common Knowledge of Civil Code in Marriage and Love&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SrcR5l7rtqhN3frsIcAX3tA9Zg3p67jAex2MFCJF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SrcR5l7rtqhN3frsIcAX3tA9Zg3p67jAex2MFCJF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno&#39;s teachings have great influence in Chinese academic circles and the public sphere. Lu Weiwei, a professor at Southeast University who had invited Chizuru Ueno as a visiting scholar, was influenced by her and established a gender research group at the school. The most subscribed female podcast program &quot;Random Fluctuation&quot; on the Xiaoyu App started talking about Chizuru Ueno in the first episode. The picture shows a woman reading a book in the EMI Building in Xujiahui Park, Shanghai, in April 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the focuses of the dispute between the three female bloggers mentioned above and Ueno is that the blogger who is married and has children The Lord asked Ueno, who chose not to get married and have children, &quot;Did you decide not to get married because you were hurt by men?&quot; This type of question is not uncommon in life. It is a misunderstanding that many people have about single women, so it has offended many people on the Internet. Netizens spontaneously posted in defense of Chizuru Ueno, believing that the three bloggers did not understand what feminism was and that such questions were very &quot;misogynistic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I like communicating with people from the bottom of my heart&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On social platforms, Chizuru Ueno shows off her iconic red hair. She speaks softly and smiles, but her remarks are sharp. For example, she once strongly criticized the gender injustice in Japanese society, exposing the reality of how women are coerced by &quot;maternal love&quot; and extracting &quot;surplus value&quot;, and said: &quot;Shout when it hurts&quot; Pain, human dignity begins here.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I got to know Chizuru Ueno through Professor Toyo Suga of the University of Tokyo. Suga is a famous Japanese folklorist. He told me that Ueno plays an important role in the whole of Japan. Her influence in the field of humanities and social sciences ranks among the top five, so I must read more of her works.&quot; Lu Weiwei, a professor at the School of Foreign Languages ​​at Southeast University, told Southern Weekend reporters. As one of Ueno&#39;s earliest researchers and translators in China, Lu Weiwei was originally engaged in folklore research. In recent years, she has also taken gender studies as her main research direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Weiwei has systematically read more than 30 works by Chizuru Ueno. She concluded: &quot;Ueno and his peers established Japanese women&#39;s studies, and things that were not included in academic vision in the past began to be taken seriously. Research, she identified such an academic field.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring from the University of Tokyo, Chizuru Ueno has been very active, and her research has gradually shifted to issues such as elderly care and care. Lu Weiwei recalled: &quot;When I visited Teacher Ueno in Tokyo in July 2023, she also gave me three new books. She is 75 years old and is still actively working and writing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Lu Weiwei planned The &quot;Todai × Todai&quot; (abbreviations for the University of Tokyo and Southeast University respectively) series of lectures invites Ueno to give lectures at Southeast University in 2019. Classes run from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m. every day, and Ueno often takes the initiative to ask for extra classes. From gender studies to aging studies, Chizuru Ueno &quot;teaches everything&quot; in almost all fields of her research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After finishing the course at Southeast University, Lu Weiwei accompanied Ueno to visit several cities such as Xi&#39;an, Harbin, Changchun and Beijing, and gave sharings at different universities. After 18 days of contact, Lu Weiwei got a deeper understanding of Ueno: &quot;She is very curious and very considerate. I praised the umbrella she brought with her for its practicality and beauty, and she gave it to me before leaving.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media person Qing Qingzi planned and published a collection of dialogues between female scholars, which included her in-depth interview with Chizuru Ueno in 2021. During the exchange, Ueno not only expressed her own opinions, but also listened carefully and listened carefully to the interview. The situation in China is of great interest. Since the video interview was very long, Chizuru Ueno even ordered a cake and said, &quot;If we meet, we can eat it together.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingqingzi felt that Ueno was a very candid scholar. Although she said that she did not want to expose her personal side, she was still very willing to expose herself when the conversation was enjoyable. After getting to know each other through interviews, Qingqingzi and Ueno maintained email communication like friends. &quot;Ueno really likes to communicate with people from the bottom of his heart.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, just a few days after Chizuru Ueno’s discussion about being single and getting married became a hot search topic on Weibo, the Japanese media “Shukan Bunshun” published an article titled “Chizuru Ueno, the founder of single education, naturalizes” The article &quot;Marriage&quot; broke the news that Chizuru Ueno and the late historian Shirkawa Daiyoshi had registered their marriage. Some people began to question Chizuru Ueno, believing that her words and deeds were inconsistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 20 days later, Chizuru Ueno responded by publishing the article &quot;The 15-Hour Bride&quot; in the &quot;Woman Public Theory&quot; magazine to clarify the cause and effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seikawa is 23 years older than Ueno. His wife has passed away and his son has lost contact with her. Ueno has taken on the responsibility of taking care of Seikawa and helping him manage his assets. This relationship is exactly what Ueno wants to study for his retirement issues in his later years. Through practice, she hopes to establish an effective mutual-help relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because Ueno is legally not related to Shikawa, he cannot sign the consent form for the operation at the critical moment, nor can he help him handle complex property matters. He is subject to Japanese family law. In order to facilitate the process, Various problems before and after Sechuan&#39;s death forced her to apply for marriage. Their marriage only lasted 15 hours before Sechuan passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t intend to hide this, but there was no reason to disclose it in the first place. Everyone who knows already knows, and my friends are not the kind to sell their friends&#39; privacy. Villain. But if there are outsiders spreading some false rumors, it would be better for me, the person involved, to tell these stories to everyone personally, so I wrote this article.&quot; At the end of the article, Chizuru Ueno wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Chizuru Ueno&#39;s new book &quot;Marry Me&quot; was published. In this book, she analyzed in detail her views on issues such as marriage and childbirth. On the cover of this new book, there is this sentence written: &quot;Towards a society where you can freely choose whether to marry, get married, or have children!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is no longer impossible to live without marriage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you briefly introduce the background of your writing &quot;Marry Me&quot; and what kind of opportunity it was for you to write it? Have you decided to talk specifically about the issue of being single and not getting married? I&#39;m also curious, has there been any change in Japan&#39;s unmarried group since this book was first published? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Among the female population of the same age, I belong to the less than 5% of unmarried people. Japan&#39;s lifelong non-marriage rate has continued to rise. By 2020, the non-marriage rate for men was 28.25% and for women was 18.81%. The government calls this statistic &quot;never-married.&quot; But I call it &quot;not married&quot;. Because &quot;unmarried&quot; means &quot;not yet married&quot;, implying that &quot;sooner or later you will get married.&quot; However, since there are so many people who are not married, it means that &quot;not getting married&quot; is not a stage of life, but a way of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you get married or not, you have children, you don’t have children, you get divorced... There are more choices, which is a good thing. Rather than saying that this book had an impact on society, it is better to say that changes in society created needs that prompted the publication of this book. Because before this, those unmarried men and women have always suffered discrimination and were always asked &quot;Why don&#39;t you get married?&quot; This book aims to encourage those unmarried people to live an upright life, so I chose &quot;Not Married, Again&quot; how? &quot;(Editor&#39;s note: the original title of the Japanese version of &quot;Marry Me&quot;) is the title of the book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The marriage rate in Japan is also getting lower and lower. Do you think that behind the scenes? What is the reason? Are there different reasons why men choose not to marry and why women choose not to marry? If this continues, people&#39;s understanding of marriage will inevitably change. Do you think we have reached such a point now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Not only because marriage is no longer an attractive option, but also because I want to start a family. The cost is simply too high. That&#39;s why the number of men and women who don&#39;t get married will increase. Men and women show an asymmetry in their reasons for choosing not to marry. Men cannot get married, and women do not want to get married. In the past, marriage was a necessity of life for both men and women, and it was impossible to live without marriage. But in today&#39;s Japan, marriage is a &quot;life surplus asset&quot; that makes life richer. People&#39;s expectations for their spouses have also increased a lot compared to the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once said, &quot;Compared to not getting married, I I want to know more about the reasons for getting married.&quot; How do you understand women who enter into marriage? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Having sex because we are in love, having children and becoming parents out of our own will, this experience can make us Life is more abundant. However, many men and women get married and have children when they reach a certain age just for reasons such as obeying traditional customs, &quot;because of parents&#39; requirements&quot;, &quot;because of society&#39;s requirements&quot;. If they have never seen their parents have a happy married life, how can their children be motivated to get married? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If women had more choices, they would not choose to marry against their will. And if their married life is very unhappy, they can also escape from it. For this reason, men must make changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You were also exposed to marriage rumors a while ago, until you later made a statement State the cause and effect of the matter. What impact did this have on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am still opposed to the (Japanese) marriage system. Unfortunately, the barriers to Japanese familialism laws are too thick, so I had no choice but to take advantage of the system to do something. To this day, I still deeply regret it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Marriage will not greatly change a woman’s life, but childbirth will&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When discussing marriage issues, we must also face the issue of fertility. Marriage and childbirth are no longer a must-choose issue in life, but it does not mean that women will no longer be anxious about it. What do you think of this issue? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no inevitable relationship between marriage and childbirth. However, many people get married for the purpose of having children. Marriage itself will not bring about any major changes in women&#39;s lives, but childbirth will greatly change women&#39;s lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marriage by Me&quot; also discusses unmarried childbirth , compared with the fertility and parenting issues within marriage, what do you think is special about fertility issues outside marriage? In China, some cities have begun to provide policy support for unmarried mothers such as settlement. There is a sentence on the cover of the Chinese version of &quot;Marry Me&quot;: &quot;Towards a society where you can freely choose not to marry, to get married, or to have children!&quot; Is this kind of social form possible? What efforts do people need to make? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many unmarried single mothers mostly do not actively choose not to get married, but after learning the news of pregnancy, they make themselves The pregnant man ran away. However, they did not choose to induce labor, but chose to give birth to the child. The background condition is that he has the support of his parents in his hometown. Of course, there are also some women who actively choose to become unmarried single mothers because they have certain financial strength. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The demand of the Japanese women&#39;s movement is to &quot;establish a society where women can give birth and raise children alone.&quot; However, society still does not provide enough support to single mothers, and even assigns &quot;three, six, or nine&quot; categories to widowed single mothers, divorced single mothers, and unmarried single mothers. Only recently has discrimination between these categories been gradually erased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people believe that policies to support single mothers will encourage men&#39;s &quot;irresponsible&quot; mentality. There is indeed a problem at this level, but the government allocating a certain amount of tax money to support single mothers means that our society has a collective responsibility in raising the next generation, and this collective also includes men who pay more taxes. Some Nordic countries will impose mandatory alimony on the man who got the woman pregnant. If the man is unwilling to pay, the state will advance the payment for him and then hold the man accountable. Japan does not have such a system, which is really a headache. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For many women who are married and have children, they have to work, You have to take on housework; but if you don’t work, you can’t gain so-called “independence.” This seems to be a dilemma of modernity? Do you think there is a solution to this dilemma? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four ways to share women’s family responsibilities: First, the first point is that men should also assume the same family responsibilities; the second point is that the state should provide public childcare services (such as providing nurseries, etc.) to reduce the childcare burden of citizens; the third point is to use the income earned by both parties from working together to hire someone to do housework; the fourth point is, Relying on the power of (maternal) grandmothers, but this approach simply shifts the responsibility from one generation of women to another. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, none of the above four methods exist. This is exactly why Japanese women are in so much pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Human beings are fragile&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Your research not only focuses on history, but also radiates to the present, including but not limited to issues such as sexual violence in war, individual sex and love, the situation of housewives, and care for the elderly. I am very curious about the source of your awareness of these issues. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;All my research is based on my own experience. When I was young, I was interested in topics such as &quot;sex&quot; and &quot;love&quot;. As I got older, I began to care about topics such as &quot;old age&quot; and &quot;caregiving&quot;. I also met and talked to many women who were leading different lives. I have experience living in Germany. Both Japan and Germany were defeated countries in World War II, but what kind of relationships did they establish with their surrounding countries after the war? I was struck by the obvious difference between Germany and Japan on this point. To this day, Japan still has not been able to establish full trusting relations with neighboring countries such as South Korea and China, which it has invaded before. For this reason, I feel very sorry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether it is women or the elderly, the support for the weak Attention is a focus of your research. What do you think you have always adhered to in your entire research context? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have dealt with many people, and I have deeply understood the truth that human beings are fragile. . Since it is fragile, it should be treated with caution. By thinking this way, we can be tolerant of others and more tolerant of ourselves. This is also the effect of increasing age. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Japan is an aging society, and now in China This question is becoming increasingly important. What are your predictions for the aging East Asian society? What challenges will the elderly face? Now that you yourself have entered the stage of old age, do you have any new understanding of life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Countries in East Asia are rapidly entering an aging society, and Japan is a developed country with an aging society, so it should be able to use it Just for reference. The long-term care insurance introduced by Japan more than 20 years ago has played a great role in allowing citizens to live with peace of mind in old age. Hopefully we can learn something from it too. For me, growing older is a new experience. If what needs to be protected disappears and there is nothing left to lose, the person will become increasingly free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You emphasized in the documentary &quot;The Last Lesson&quot; &quot;Feminism is about enabling the weak to survive as the weak&quot;, which reverses many people&#39;s misunderstanding that feminism only focuses on &quot;women&quot; issues. Why does feminism naturally care for and affirm the weak? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No matter how powerful a person is, he is also weak at birth. And one day he will definitely become a weakling. Men are no exception. Women often accompany children, the elderly, the disabled and the sick, so they understand the weak and can imagine their plight. And men just forget these, or just pretend to forget. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You emphasize that this is no longer a matter of hard work. A rewarding society, while emphasizing care for the &quot;weak&quot;, once said, &quot;Please don&#39;t show off your strength, but admit your weaknesses and support each other to live.&quot; Can it be understood that people need to build some kind of community and help each other make society a better place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;People cannot live alone in the world, and they cannot die alone when they die. Building a community that supports each other to survive is an important matter for everyone, regardless of gender. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are considered to be Japan&#39;s No. 1 &quot;women&#39;s studies&quot; One person, forty years ago, when you established Women’s Studies in Japan, what was the status of women in Japan at that time? After so many years of development, what achievements has Japan’s “women’s studies” research made today? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Forty years ago, there was no such subject for women in Japanese universities. So we, the pioneer generation, learned women’s studies on our own. At that time, some people still ridiculed us, &quot;Is women&#39;s studies a science?&quot; Later, women&#39;s studies entered all professional fields and was established as a discipline, and relevant courses were also offered in universities. It is a pity that Japanese universities have neither “women’s studies departments” nor “women’s studies directions.” Rather than enclosing territory, it is more important to extend gender perspectives across all fields. As a result, we have accumulated theoretical and empirical research on women’s studies and gender studies in many fields, and have trained many researchers. The website &quot;WAN&quot; (https://wan.or.jp/general/corner/papers) we created has collected a list of more than 1,500 dissertations on women&#39;s studies or gender studies over more than 40 years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a concept that when it comes to feminism, It seems that it is inevitable to discuss love, marriage and family, and some of your research is also related to this, but is this what feminism is all about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, it’s because in human society, no group is independent of gender. So when there are women, we use women’s experience as the research object. When there are no women, we study why there are no women. When focusing on men, we study how this characteristic of men is shaped. Therefore, there is no field that gender studies cannot deal with. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Criticism&quot; and &quot;blame&quot; are different&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marry Me&quot; is a collection of dialogues, and in addition to your serious academic works, you also often have dialogues with people from all walks of life. For example, your previous &quot;Starting at the Limit&quot; caused a lot of discussion in China. What do you think the dialogue means to you? By communicating with people from different generations and backgrounds, what do you want to convey to your readers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I really like talking to people with different life backgrounds. This can stimulate my curiosity, and during the conversation Sometimes the other person will bring out another side of me that I have never noticed. &quot;Others&quot; are an important catalyst for me to know who I really am. Similarly, when readers read a book in the form of a dialogue, I also hope that they can participate in the dialogue and enjoy the joy and joy of &quot;discovering who they are.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As an academic scholar, you actively Intervening in social affairs and advocating feminism, have you ever been questioned because of these? Your speech at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo in 2019 also had a great response in China. Your speech at the time was very sharp and your criticism of the school was very direct. Why did you deliver such a speech at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The University of Tokyo invited me to attend the entrance ceremony as a guest. Although they asked me to submit the original manuscript of my speech, they did not interfere with the speech at all. content of the manuscript. The content of my speech was all planned out in advance. Because the podium at the entrance ceremony also has a &quot;speaker&quot; effect, I think this is a good opportunity to convey what I have been thinking to a larger audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After your speech at the University of Tokyo, you became an internet celebrity. &quot;Celebrity&quot; has attracted the attention of intellectual circles in China. Especially in recent years, a large number of your books have been published in China. What do you think of this phenomenon? Why do you think Chinese readers, especially female readers, admire you so much? Do you think it is a good thing that intellectuals have become &quot;popular&quot; due to the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The goal of feminism is to verbalize and theorize women’s experience. I think it is because the younger generation of women in China have found the language to express their own experiences in my works. One thing that Japan and China have in common is that many girls are carefully raised in a generation with a low birthrate. Under China&#39;s reform and opening up policy, and with the continuous development of marketization, the life experiences of women in the two countries may be getting closer and closer. Moreover, Chinese readers may feel closer to Asian feminism than to feminism in Europe and America. However, I am very much looking forward to seeing the emergence of Chinese-specific feminology and the birth of Chinese feminism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t think there is anything to worry about when intellectuals become popular people. People who write books naturally hope that more readers will read their works. However, it is a bit distressing to praise or condemn on the Internet without even reading it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​view is that the status of women in East Asia is compared to that in Europe and the United States. The situation is not ideal. What do you think is the underlying reason? In 2019, you visited and gave lectures in many cities in China. What impression did you leave on Chinese women? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Although they are both East Asian countries, the situations of women in China, Japan, and South Korea are different. Every country has its own unique circumstances. It needs to be studied separately for different societies. Although I have come to Chinese universities to give lectures, I have only met (mostly) elite women from cities who attend mindful universities, and I know nothing about women living in the vast rural areas, so I cannot answer this question. I think this issue needs to be studied by Chinese researchers. My impression of the elite women living in the city is that they are girls who were carefully raised as only children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have encountered many doubts along the way. How did you respond? Generally speaking, East Asians value &quot;politeness&quot;, but is &quot;quarrel&quot; an effective means for women to fight against injustice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;An argument is not a &quot;quarrel&quot;. I did not take up my position at the University of Tokyo to &quot;teach quarrels.&quot; All kinds of knowledge develop from &quot;dissent&quot;. Women&#39;s studies and gender studies are not afraid of controversy, and to this day and ever since, it has been a field of scholarship that has been hotly debated and thus advanced. &quot;Criticism&quot; is different from &quot;blame&quot;. When facing an object that needs criticism, it is important to present our arguments and criticize the opponent logically and rigorously. I believe that academics are a weapon for the weak. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you feel about your personal influence on social media? various controversies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On social networks, attacks and arguments will be amplified. It is not a place for fair discussion. The world of social networks is not everything, and it’s important to keep your distance from it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>