<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[马云继续减持，阿里巴巴刺向低价]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 15:30:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alibaba Xixi Park. Image source: Alibaba official website&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alibaba Xixi Park . Image source: Alibaba official website&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 16, 2023, is the day when Alibaba’s new quarterly results for fiscal year 2024 are announced. On this day, many important news about this giant company were simultaneously released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jack Ma continues to reduce his stake in the founder of Alibaba; the previous &quot;1+6+N&quot; spin-off plan partially pressed the pause button, and Alibaba Cloud will no longer be completely split; the listing of Hema is also suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes is Alibaba facing? Where will the strategic baton be waved from now on? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jack Ma reduced his holdings and cashed out US$870 million&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 16, Alibaba (BABA.NYSE) submitted two 144 forms to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), indicating that Jack Ma JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited, subsidiaries of the family trust, plan to sell 5 million shares of the founder of Alibaba each on November 21. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Alibaba’s closing price of US$87.07 per share on November 15, Eastern Time, the Jack Ma family can cash out US$870.7 million through this reduction. Alibaba&#39;s market capitalization that day was approximately US$221.75 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Form 144, also known as &quot;Notice of Proposed Sale of Securities.&quot; SEC regulations stipulate that if directors, executives or major shareholders of a U.S. listed company transfer more than 5,000 shares of listed company stock or a market value of more than $50,000 in any three months, they must fill out Form 144 and report to the SEC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Alibaba’s U.S. stock prospectus, before the IPO, Jack Ma held a total of 8.8% of Alibaba’s shares in four ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I hold 0.08% directly, 1.49% each through APN Ltd registered in the Cayman Islands and SymAsia Foundation, a Singapore non-profit organization, and through JC Properties registered in the British Virgin Islands Limited and JSP Investment Limited hold 2.78% and 2.95% of the shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shares sold by Jack Ma in the US stock IPO also came from JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited. After the IPO, his shareholding in Alibaba dropped to 7.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Alibaba was listed on the New York Stock Exchange in 2014, Jack Ma has reduced his holdings many times. The financial report shows that Jack Ma’s large-scale reduction of holdings began in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Jack Ma’s shareholding dropped from 7.8% to 7%, to 6.4% in 2018, to 6.2% in 2019, and to 4.8% in 2020, which is below the 5% disclosure red line. Since then, Alibaba has not disclosed Jack Ma’s shareholdings in its financial reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba has responded that Jack Ma and Tsai Chongxin will donate their Alibaba options, which total 2% of the total equity of Alibaba Group, to support environmental protection, medical health, educational development and public welfare. ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Teacher’s Day 2019, Jack Ma resigned as chairman of Alibaba’s board of directors. A year later, Jack Ma completed his term as director and is no longer a member of Alibaba&#39;s board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 financial report shows that Jack Ma is still a member of Alibaba’s partner committee, and the other five are Cai Chongxin, Zhang Yong, Peng Lei, Shao Xiaofeng and Wu Yongming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba implements a partnership system, in which partners nominate the majority of directors on the board of directors, rather than allocating director seats based on the number of shares. Alibaba currently has 28 partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Refocus on 1688, Xianyu, DingTalk, and Quark&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Also on November 16, Alibaba’s Q2 results for fiscal year 2024 were announced. Alibaba&#39;s fiscal year is not synchronized with the natural year, ranging from April 1 of each year to March 31 of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue was 224.79 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 9%. Net profit was 26.696 billion yuan, compared with a net loss of 22.467 billion yuan in the same period in 2022, and non-GAAP net profit was 40.188 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 19%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Alibaba Group&#39;s performance this quarter was solid, with multiple businesses showing new momentum and vitality, and proactive self-reform achieving remarkable results.&quot; Wu Yongming, CEO of Alibaba Group, said in the performance announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local Life Group’s revenue increased by 16% year-on-year to 15.564 billion yuan, driven by the strong growth of Ele.me and AutoNavi, with orders increasing by nearly 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s revenue increased by 25% year-on-year to 22.823 billion yuan, mainly driven by cross-border logistics fulfillment solutions. Cainiao launched global 5-day logistics services to 8 countries and regions this quarter, including first-leg collection, trunk transportation, customs clearance, sorting and last-mile delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Alibaba Entertainment finally turned a profit in the last quarter, its chances of winning have further expanded. The revenue of Dawen Entertainment Group in this quarter was 5.779 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 11%, mainly due to the offline entertainment business of Damai.com and Alibaba Pictures, and the subscription growth of Youku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, Alibaba Pictures announced the acquisition of Damai.com. Benefiting from the recovery and strong demand of the offline entertainment market during the summer vacation of 2023, Damai.com recorded triple-digit year-on-year growth in GMV this quarter. In August, Damai.com teamed up with Youku to sell tickets for the offline performances and online live broadcasts of TFBOYS’s 10th anniversary concert. This exclusive online live broadcast broke Youku’s online paid performance record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two films jointly produced by Alibaba Pictures, &quot;All or Nothing&quot; and &quot;The Lost Girl&quot; ranked among the top two at the summer box office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 16, Wu Yongming participated in the quarterly financial analyst conference call for the first time as CEO of Alibaba Group. At the meeting, he introduced Alibaba’s first batch of strategic innovative businesses-1688, Xianyu, Nail, Quark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba’s selection criteria for strategic innovative businesses are: having a large enough market space; having unique market positioning; complying with user demand trends and the group’s “AI-driven” strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strategic innovative business will be operated as an independent subsidiary in terms of organization. In terms of business, it will break the previous positioning restrictions within the group and use a more independent strategy to face the broad market. Alibaba Group will make continuous investment in a 3-5 year cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quark is an intelligent search app owned by Alibaba, and DingTalk is an enterprise-level intelligent mobile office platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of online transactions that Alibaba is good at, 1688 is a purchasing and wholesale network, which is often put together with Pinduoduo to compare which one is cheaper, while Xianyu is a second-hand idle transfer platform, which improves the popularity of the two within the group. The importance of Alibaba’s business shows that Alibaba’s baton is tilted towards the low-price market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spin-off of Alibaba Cloud and the listing of Hema will be suspended&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Alibaba’s Q2 financial report also announced the spin-off progress of each business segment. Surprisingly, the spin-off of Alibaba Cloud has been put on hold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, Zhang Yong, then chairman and CEO of Alibaba Group and chairman and CEO of Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group, announced that Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group would be completely separated from Alibaba Group within the next 12 months. Dismantled and completed listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba explained in this financial report that the United States has recently expanded restrictions on the export of advanced computing chips, which has brought uncertainty to the prospects of Cloud Intelligence Group. Its complete spin-off may not increase shareholder value as originally envisaged, so it has decided not to promote its complete spin-off. Instead, it will face an uncertain environment and focus on establishing a sustainable growth model for Cloud Intelligence Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba Group will maintain long-term and resolute investment in the strategic direction of Alibaba Cloud. At the same time, Cloud Intelligence Group will continue to maintain an independent company operation method and adopt a CEO responsibility system authorized by the board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Bloomberg News stated that Hema was cooperating with CICC, Morgan Stanley and others to prepare for listing and prepare to be listed in Hong Kong next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this financial report shows that Hema’s initial public offering plan is on hold. Ali did not explain why. But this may have something to do with Hema’s lackluster performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue from all other segments was 4.8052 billion yuan, which remained stable compared with the same period in 2022. All other segments include Sun Art Retail, Hema, Alibaba Health, Lingxi Interactive Entertainment, Intime, Intelligent Information (mainly including UC Youshi and Quark businesses), Fliggy, DingTalk, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other segments, the revenue of Hema, Fliggy, Alibaba Health and Smart Information has increased, but the overall performance is only the same as last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sharp contrast to Hema, Cainiao Group has applied for an initial public offering in Hong Kong and has submitted an A1 document (listing application form) to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said at the conference call that Cainiao’s core strategies for the next three years are to accelerate the construction of a global smart logistics network, seize the historical opportunities of the rapid development of cross-border e-commerce, and achieve rapid growth in international business. The second is to adhere to the path of differentiation in the country, export scientific and technological capabilities, and maintain the healthy development of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：严厉打击倒买倒卖、伪造出生医学证明等违法犯罪行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:40:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission attaches great importance to the management of birth medical certificates and is supervising relevant places to seriously verify and deal with the trafficking of birth medical certificates. Regarding certification and other related issues, supervision teams have been dispatched to Xiangyang in Hubei, Foshan in Guangdong, and Nanning in Guangxi to urge and guide local governments to conduct thorough investigations, respond to social concerns, and hold relevant responsibilities accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Medical Birth Certificate&quot; is a statutory medical certification document issued in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Maternal and Infant Health Care Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and is an important basis for the public security organs to carry out newborn household registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Health Commission will severely crack down on any behavior that harms the rights and interests of children, harms the interests of the masses, and disrupts the normal medical order, especially the forgery of medical birth certificates. If it is discovered, it will be investigated and punished, and we will actively cooperate with them. The public security organs crack down on criminal activities such as buying and selling birth medical certificates, and severely deal with the medical personnel involved in accordance with the law and regulations. You are welcome to report relevant clues to the local health administration department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the National Health Commission will guide medical institutions to further improve their internal management mechanisms and processes, and conduct special inspections on the standardized management of birth medical certificates across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究发现鲨鱼可以跟人类一样品尝出苦味]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new study recently published in the US magazine &quot;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&quot; stated that sharks and other cartilaginous fish have the same Genes that detect bitter tastes like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258594&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows a photo of a shark provided by the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo courtesy of the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity/Photo by Andrew Fox)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many animals and plants secrete toxic compounds as a defense, a chemical that enables humans to perceive their taste The bitter taste receptor type 2 (T2R) gene helps humans recognize these compounds and avoid poisoning. Many bony vertebrates also have this bitter taste receptor gene, but researchers have never found it in cartilaginous vertebrates before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this study, researchers from the University of Cologne in Germany and other institutions used the latest gene sequencing technology to sequence the genes of 17 species of cartilaginous fish (including sharks and rays) and found that 12 species of cartilaginous fish All carry a taste receptor gene similar to T2R, which they named T2R1. The researchers then implanted the T2R1 genes from two of the shark species into human kidney cells in the laboratory, and then exposed them to 94 bitter substances that humans can perceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results showed that 7 bitter substances activated the bitter taste receptors of two species of sharks, and the other 4 substances only activated the bitter taste receptors of one shark, which means that these sharks can also taste human food. Perceived bitter substances such as colchicine or bile acids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discovery suggests the ability to perceive bitter tastes may be older than previously thought, possibly before cartilaginous fishes and bony vertebrates diverged from a common ancestor nearly 500 million years ago, the researchers said. has evolved. Teleost vertebrates continue to evolve a variety of bitter taste receptor genes. Although the researchers detected only one T2R1 gene in these cartilaginous fish genomes, this means it may be the original form of the bitter taste receptor gene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[台湾观众可能没有我们这么了解侯孝贤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeK nCcAnsCEY3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to A Little Culture. I am Yu Yaqin, the anchor of this issue. Recently, the famous director Hou Hsiao-hsien has to bid farewell to the film industry due to health reasons. For this reason, today I invited Teacher Wang Yinjie from the China Academy of Art and my colleague Teacher Li Heng to talk about this great fan of Chinese films. A very important film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excerpts of golden verses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He lives in southern Taiwan, which is very different from Taipei in our impression. It has more rural character. This rural character is also the way Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some actors have said that he doesn’t even have a script. He is not a person who particularly likes to coordinate actors. A director who is very standard in the film industry, very sophisticated and precise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He provides a very valuable preservation of personal experience and personal memory for the narration of film history. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1700&quot; height=&quot;1132&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #993300;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Yaqin, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Heng, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yinjie, Associate Professor, School of Film, China Academy of Art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #993300;&quot;>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:58 Director Hou Hsiao-hsien’s life and works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:17 Countryside is Hou Hsiao-hsien’s way of looking at the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 05:22&amp;nbsp;《 &quot;Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; established many of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s aesthetic styles&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:23&amp;nbsp;After 2000, Hou Hsiao-hsien moved towards more international cooperation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:08&amp;nbsp;Jia Zhangke is I came into contact with Hou Hsiao-hsien from &quot;City of Sadness&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 14:33 Hou Hsiao-hsien is not a standardized director in the film industry&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 17:52 Hou Hsiao-hsien has always been photographing individuals with a faint light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 19:57 Taiwanese audiences may not know Hou Hsiao-hsien as well as we do&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:14&amp;nbsp;Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films have many long shots and do not pursue a lot of drama&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;► 26:19 The emotions of the characters in Hou’s films are like hearing thunder in silence&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 32:47 Hou Hsiao-hsien holds a very important position in the hearts of a generation of movie fans&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37: 15 A kind of misalignment: The life needs of young people in Taiwan do not come from directors such as Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 41:11 We need to trust the interpretation of the world by creators of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s generation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 43:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at everyone around him in a level-headed manner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 45:06 The use of dialect is a characteristic of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 47:05 Recommended by Wang Yinjie Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Sad City&quot; and &quot;Flowers of Shanghai&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:49 Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Love in the Wind&quot; and &quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;► 55:53 Three movies recommended by Li Heng: &quot;Once Upon a Time in Childhood&quot;, &quot;Goodbye South Country, South Country&quot; and &quot;Dream Life&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 58:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s masterpiece is so dazzling that it... The light of urban youth-themed works overshadowed&lt;br>;► 01:01:52 Director Hou’s films strive for a certain authenticity of the atmosphere of that era&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:06:30 When there are many things that cannot be said Whenever possible, literature is used as a metaphor and movies are used to present it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:08:25 Hou Hsiao-hsien provides a way of retaining personal experience and memory in narrating film history&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:11 :14 Use southern aesthetics to summarize Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:16:09 Hou Hsiao-hsien influenced young directors from Taiwan, China’s sixth-generation directors, Hirokazu Kore-eda, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Audio Clip/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999;&quot;>;Operation Promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这部罪案片，悬疑为壳，人性为核]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The dramatization of crime films often has two levels . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first level is to explore the truth of the murder. Under the sensory stimulation of extreme violence, the protagonist takes the audience&#39;s perspective to reveal the truth bit by bit. The plot has twists and turns and even reversals, providing plot excitement. The other layer is to explore the theme of human nature. The protagonist often has some kind of commonality with the victim and murderer of the case. The story of the detective story is also the protagonist&#39;s growth of exploring himself and &quot;finding himself&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the case was finally solved, the protagonist found the truth of the case and the answer to the confusion in life. They point to an ending in the interweaving, and the audience sees two stories and gets a double plot impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those character arcs in drama theory are actually not complicated. Excellent stories not only reveal the truth about the character&#39;s personality, but more importantly, tell the arc or change of the character&#39;s inner nature during the course of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing this, it is easy to understand the director&#39;s intention. In crime films, these two layers are often intertwined, but with different emphasis. For example, &quot;The Mistake on the River&quot; currently in theaters focuses on the latter layer. The director was afraid of being misunderstood, so he directly wrote &quot;No Answer&quot; on the poster. It just reminds the audience that the main purpose of this movie is to explore the human nature related to the case. The investigation itself is not important. There is no need to worry about who the murderer is. There is no answer at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the new film &quot;Pursuit&quot; directed by Zeng Yingting and starring Junning Chang and Ethan Ruan is not so literary and extreme. Although this movie has some fresh topics, it does not challenge the audience&#39;s entertainment interests too much and is a very regular crime film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1531&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female worker accident He died tragically and was involved in a series of female murders. Finger-cutting, heart-breaking, imprisonment...bizarre cases, cruel murderers, and sensory-stimulating gimmicks are all cut into the trailer. Seasoned genre film viewers are very familiar with this method of publicity, and of course they know that a gimmick is just a gimmick, and its scale will only be safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that &quot;The Hunt&quot; is a movie dominated by female characters, and you can even consider it a female movie (although it is very genre). In the crime genre, very few women lead the investigation. We might as well try to recall the positioning of female characters in crime films. They are often victims or perpetrators (which appears as a reversal card at this time). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this crime movie, the protagonist is the detective Wu Jie played by Junning Chang. She is the leader and the soul of the drama. If you put aside your female identity, Zhang Junning&#39;s role is not special. This is a decadent Matthew Scudder-like character who looks like a professional, capable, and tough detective on the outside, but is broken on the inside. We have seen countless similar male characters. The decadent man finds himself and his original intention through handling cases, which is very cliché. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Pursuit&quot;, we cannot ignore the gender issue, it is the theme of this movie. The audience is first put into a female perspective. Wu Jie, who has experienced pain in the film, is facing the difficulty of how to survive. She tried to commit suicide in the car. This is the starting point of the character&#39;s story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Jie encountered the case of an unknown female corpse. Objectively, the instinct of the criminal police prevented the idea of ​​​​suicide. When she starts to handle the case, the story becomes logical and has two layers: one is that Wu Jie is solving the case of the unknown female corpse and wants to find the murderer; the other is that Wu Jie is also facing her spiritual death and trying to find a way to survive. The answer to go down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Pursuit&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie, detective Wu Jie has a dialogue: &quot;We always say that the corpse will choose someone to handle the case, and she chose me.&quot; Of course the dead would not choose. The fact is that Wu Jie chose this case. She wanted to seek justice for the dead, and her motivation was not only her professional status, but also her responsibility as a woman and her need to heal herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, female identity shows special significance. On the surface of the story, a female detective is investigating murder cases against women. Inside, there is a woman who empathizes with women who have been hurt—both physically and emotionally—and ultimately healed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of empathy is not uncommon, but it is difficult to become the main line. There is a scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot; where a group of male detectives are drinking coffee and talking during an indoor scene involving a woman&#39;s autopsy. Jodie Foster, who was inside, felt uncomfortable and helpless when she saw the naked female corpse. Finally, she mustered up the courage to clear the men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the story itself of &quot;Pursuit&quot; did not give me much new ideas and was very routine. However, the empathy between the female detective Wu Jie and the female victims always reminds me of the scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot;. The female perspective runs throughout, and this amplified empathy transcends the limitations of the screen, which is beyond the expectations of ordinary crime films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; As a category. They are all movies with female protagonists, and women are the protagonists in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is easy for the audience to take a certain unconscious stance, not because of the performance of the two actors, but because of the female protagonist&#39;s genre film, which not only brings freshness, but also brings strangeness. Feeling unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;858&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type films and There is no need for extraordinary acting skills, it is very craftsmanship, it should be performed, it cannot be missing or wrong. In my eyes, the &quot;craftsmanship&quot; of performances in genre films is a compliment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Zhang Junning or Zhang Xiaofei, they provide a fresh sense of crime themes. Although the story still has loopholes and problems of one kind or another, more and more complete and different types of female protagonists appear in On the screen, this is a good phenomenon that deserves applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人机连接走到哪一步了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Neuralink, a brain-computer interface company owned by Musk, officially began recruiting volunteers for its first clinical trial. Ideal volunteer candidates are quadriplegic adults under the age of 40. The trial will see most of the volunteers&#39; skulls removed and implanted with a brain-computer implant, a processing, communication and charging system. The device, which is a chip and wires, has more than a thousand electrodes to receive brain data. By comparison, implants from other rival companies have only about 16 electrodes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thunder that has been ringing has finally turned into raindrops, and the brain-computer interface or human-computer connection will enter the human trial stage. However, implanting a chip in the brain is an invasive procedure that could cause harm to a person if not careful. However, the significance of this research is very important. It can not only decipher the thinking of the human brain, but also make it possible for people to obtain more powerful capabilities with the help of computers and shape the so-called human-machine complex. To this end, we must find a balance between harm and benefits to minimize harm to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a balance is the content of medical ethics intervention. In May 2023, Neuralink said that its first human clinical trial was approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA); on September 19, Neuralink announced that the company had received approval from an independent review committee and would conduct the trial this year. Conducting the first human trial of a brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This shows that Neuralink has done enough homework in terms of ethical review and approval. Before doing this kind of homework, we also followed the procedures of medical clinical trials from animals to humans. Before applying for human clinical trials, Neuralink has conducted relevant tests on pigs and monkeys respectively, and achieved certain results. In particular, the tests on monkeys have proven that it can be applied to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, Neuralink released a video showing a macaque implanted with its device playing video games through telepathy, indicating a major breakthrough in chip implantation in brain control research. The macaque in the video is named Pug, and has a brain-computer interface implanted in his brain. Initially, the research team taught Pug to play games using a game joystick and rewarded him with banana milkshakes through metal straws. At this stage, the brain-computer device records which neurons are activated, models the relationship between Pug&#39;s neural activity and the expected direction of movement, and achieves &quot;brain-computer connection.&quot; Judging from the macaque&#39;s brain thoughts controlling the joystick to play games, the implanted chip shows the preliminary goal of monkey-computer integration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After these results were obtained, Neuralink applied for human trials. Moreover, current human trials also follow the principle that they are only conducted on patients, not healthy subjects. For patients, trials are about balancing benefits and harms. Experiments on patients are to treat their diseases. Even if the process is full of risks, compared with the benefits of giving patients a new life, if the latter is greater or far greater than the former, it is feasible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trial is targeting paralyzed patients and visually impaired people. Through the brain-computer interface, the brain consciousness of paralyzed patients can be obtained, and this consciousness can be received through an external computer, and then the computer can decipher and issue instructions to the corresponding mechanical devices to help patients with cerebral palsy move, at least to take care of themselves. Such as eating, drinking and going to the bathroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the visually impaired, implanted visual chips can help them improve and restore their vision, such as helping patients with retinal dystrophy improve their vision. If successful, it could help more patients. There are currently about 1.3 million blind people and 2.9 million people with low vision in the United States. These two numbers are likely to grow to 2.2 million and 5 million by 2030. If the brain-computer interface can treat visual impairment, this group will also benefit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if an accident occurs in a brain-computer interface experiment or if the damage exceeds the benefits, the principle of putting life and health first will need to be stopped immediately. However, such experiments may also yield unexpected results and new discoveries, helping to reveal more secrets of the human brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, research on brain-computer interfaces in animals has achieved more results. A research team from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute in the United States has developed a new system that combines virtual reality (VR) and brain-computer interface (BMI) to try to detect the thoughts or thoughts in the minds of rats. As in humans, when rodents experience places and events, the hippocampus, an area of ​​the brain responsible for spatial memory, activates specific patterns of neural activity that allow thoughts to wander back in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hippocampus is an important area of ​​the brain responsible for memory and imagination. It possesses a model of the environment called a cognitive map. Therefore, the hippocampus contains a spatial map-like representation of the previously explored environment. to facilitate subsequent recall or simulation. At the same time, the representation of each environment consists of specific place cells, and when the animal passes a specific location in that environment, these neurons fire selectively, recalling past scenes. This situation is similar to people&#39;s memory of the environment and cognition of environmental patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the test, the rats were placed in a specially designed VR system. The brain-computer interface system translated the rat&#39;s brain activity into movement on a virtual reality screen. Rats need to control their hippocampus activity to imagine specific scenes in order to receive rewards, and this thinking process is very similar to humans. When people are asked to go to a certain theater, they may imagine leaving home and going to the theater. Routes and neighborhoods that will be traveled. Afterwards, the rats were asked to move the virtual object from one location to another by imagining it, that is, the rats needed to move the object to the target location in the virtual space by controlling their hippocampus activity. The researchers then changed the location of the target, inducing the rats to produce activity patterns associated with the new location. The process is like the person sitting in the seat imagining picking up the cup next to the water dispenser and filling it with water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that rats can control their hippocampal activity with the precision and flexibility of humans, holding their thoughts in a given position for several seconds, similar to how humans relive past events. event or imagine a new scenario. Moreover, as brain-computer interface systems are increasingly used in prosthetics, the results of this research can be used to design new prosthetic devices to serve people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study on rats once again shows that brain-computer interfaces can know a person&#39;s thoughts and thoughts, just like mind reading. This also means that future brain-computer interfaces can be used for in-depth research on human brain consciousness and thinking, but if they are to be used for healthy people and other purposes, more and stricter ethical and legal supervision is required. Therefore, it is easier to gain consensus by limiting human-machine interfaces to the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海住了18年，这位来自迈阿密的“洋盘”还没打算离开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqYf3c0BPhHY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;607&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqY f3c0BPhHY. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He pointed to a residential building across the street and told the story of his friend who had moved to Singapore; in the next street, the locksmith Master Ji saved him; and further on was He often goes to the small shop where clothes are repaired, and greets him every time he passes by. “If I don’t see them, I might forget them.” He is afraid of losing these living records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combining the life experience of his great-great-grandfather provided him with a new perspective, &quot;Our difficulties are simply incommensurable.&quot; Different from the missionary mission of his ancestors more than a hundred years ago, he has a new perspective on his own mission. The mission becomes clearer, &quot;There is a lot of valuable knowledge here, and I hope it can be seen by more people in the world. I have a visa, can travel, understand the different wisdom of Eastern and Western cultures, and I can do something.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2015, Chris measured Shanghai Xiaolongbao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Where are you in the bubble? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;American Chris has a serious Chinese name - Shen Kaiwei. He said the origin of the name was somewhat boring. When he was working in a hotel in Shanghai more than ten years ago, a colleague in the human resources department named him Shen Jiawei, which he rarely used. When his new book &quot;Yangpan&quot; was published in October 2023, he changed the middle character to &quot;kai&quot;, which happened to have a similar pronunciation to his English name Christopher St. Cavish. Friends who know him well tend to call him Chris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《洋盘》记录了Chris过去18年在上海的生活，包括他机缘巧合来到上海的始末，也有他骑摩托车环游中国西北的跌宕经历，还有他不常与人提起的家族故事。在上海方言中，“洋盘”指不太了解本地习俗的外来人，英文书名“outsider”或许更加直抒胸臆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对一些外国人来说，我太中国了；对许多中国人来说，我又太老外了。我并不是冲着泡泡圈（在华外籍人士建立起的“舒适圈”）来中国的，但当我飘出去、融入圈外时又会想念它。我是为中国而来，但也无法全身心全时段地生活在中国。”Chris在《洋盘》里写道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洋盘-平面封&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《洋盘》是Chris的第一本书。更早的时候，他将定量框架运用到上海的小笼包上，收集小笼包的重量、汤汁的重量、馅料的质量、皮的厚度，计算小笼包的结构工艺质量，写下《上海小笼包索引》，“如果那算得上书的话。”正式写作前，他在迈阿密和纽约做了10年的专业厨师。厌倦了故乡迈阿密一成不变的生活，他决意到亚洲寻找机会，继而环游世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初心仪的目的地是香港。 21世纪初，他以背包客的方式游历东南亚，顺道去香港探望姐姐。他爱极了香港，“既不是彻底的西方文化，也不是彻底的中国文化。”计划里，他要直接杀到半岛酒店的后厨，提出免费打工。但半岛酒店的后厨不需要一个不会讲粤语的美国年轻人。屡屡碰壁，辗转于不同的介绍人，他最后觅得一份在上海的厨师工作。就这么来到了上海。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，Chris24岁，第一次来到上海，计划只待一年。他没想到的是，18年后自己仍生活在这里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在上海工作一年后，他辞掉后厨的工作，骑着改装摩托车环游西北。旅程称得上惊心动魄。摩托车永远在坏，他总是沿途寻找修车铺。有次刹车片坏了，可没有一间铺子有战时德产（没错，就是上世纪30年代）老爷款的刹车零件。他后来骑着刹车坏掉的摩托车穿越甘肃天水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有惊无险，他结束了为期一个月的旅行。 “早上还在兰州，下午就到了西宁。一切都太快了，我习惯了在摩托车上的生活。如果再来一次，我可能会去新疆，可能不安全，但……”总之他后来坐了36个小时的火车回到上海，隔天飞回了迈阿密，“当时不确定要不要回来，我把房子租出去了。”三个月后，他重返上海。就再待一年，他想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多在华外籍人士也是这么想的。抱着“再待一年”的心情游荡和生活，一次只想12个月。等到护照上贴满每年签发一次的签证纸，才恍然发觉生活了十几年。 Chris管这个叫“明天综合症”——“明天永远不会到来。那一年永远不会结束。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chris刚来上海的2005年，上海有10万外籍居民。 10年后，这个数字翻了一倍，近年来有所减少。 “移民和外籍人士会自动创建属于自己的泡泡圈——根据你祖国的贫富程度进行野蛮的一刀切。生病时看外国医生，做饭时花重金去买进口食材。”尽管他对泡泡圈百般嘲讽，其实自己也是圈中人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height=&quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年，Chris在拍摄上海一间著名大闸蟹小笼包饭店的故事。这间饭店于2023年春天歇业&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Sheila Zhao/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泡泡圈里最常见的问候是：你来中国多久了？你会说中文吗？人们根据答案划分谁是这个圈子里的老大。 “在中国生活了六年的外籍人士会看不起在中国生活了六个月的外籍人士，以此类推，在中国生活了六个月的外籍人士又会看不起在中国生活了六周的外籍人士。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诸如此类的比较也适用于工作，在那条等级分明的鄙视链中，教英语的外籍人士处于最底端，最顶端是商人。 Chris认识几位后者，“他们喋喋不休地抱怨阿姨，抱怨西餐，抱怨他们的中国员工。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也抱怨变化。来得久的外籍人士常常感慨昔日上海多么美好，言下之意是眼下都不如从前。 Chris不这么认为，“上海教人接受变化，这有好有坏，如果你发现一间餐厅不错应该今天就去，因为明天未必还开着。如果你不喜欢现在的上海，没关系，再等等，一年后它又会大变样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在泡泡圈待得太久，Chris有时想出去，与友人合作完成的上海小笼包测评便是一次尝试。那之后他常常处于一半一半的状态——“一只脚在圈内，一只脚在圈外。”“就像我的身份认同。有时我早上醒来只想呆在泡泡圈里，于是早餐吃三明治，晚餐吃披萨，待在房间里看一整天YouTube（视频网站）。有时我想出去，和邻居还有朋友聊聊天。我想真正地生活在上海。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2016年，Chris在兰州一家拉面学校学习拉面的制作过程。 《洋盘》中也记录了这段经历&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;在异国写作&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不做厨师后，Chris跳槽到一家英文杂志工作，写给在华外籍人士看的美食报道。从厨师到美食撰稿人的视角转换，他花了几年功夫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“作为食客想要的东西与作为主厨想要的东西完全不同。”2023年10月末，我们约在一间西餐厅见面，Chris以餐桌上的肉桂卷举例，“作为主厨，我不希望它们（核桃和糖霜）洒下来，它边缘的折角要工整。但这些并不影响口感。作为食客，我考虑的是它味道好吗？我享受这一餐吗？它价格合适吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实食物只是他关心人的介质，帮他抵达那些更好奇的问题：“他们的生活是怎样的？我们在哪些方面是相同的，在哪些方面不同？他们的快乐是什么？悲伤呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“写作好像给了我一种许可证，让我可以问人们一些在正常交往中会显得过分或很尴尬的问题。”有些采访流向了更深处，比如他与虹口的手工锅匠陶师傅聊天时，对方自然而然地向他袒露过往的困难和挣扎。另一些就没这么幸运。比如，他从2006年起拜访与陶师傅同为锅匠的岑氏兄弟，十几年过去，对方仍像不认识他一般“从不打招呼”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年，Chris与朋友一同发布了《上海小笼包索引》，他们摒弃掉个人主观意见，从纯粹物理的角度测量了52家店铺的数百只小笼包，“写美食注定会带有主观性，还要搞懂别人迷恋的是什么，但人都是坚持己见的（包括我自己），那让我觉得很累。我想改变一下，想让别人或别的东西来做判断。”他在《洋盘》中吐露心声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2012年，Chris在夜店打碟&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《上海小笼包索引》令他意外收获颇多关注。他被冠名“痴迷小笼包的老外”出现在许多人的朋友圈里、接受媒体采访。甚至有一家专门制作小笼包的企业邀请他做奶酪小笼包的顾问。他拒绝了。上海餐饮协会的负责人在一次采访中说，如果Chris有后续的调查研究，他们会支持他。看到那则新闻后，他走向卫生间，在走廊里哭了。在上海的第10年，他第一次感觉自己被这座城市接纳。尽管后来他打电话给上海餐饮协会想要聊聊时，对方已全然忘了这回事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《上海小笼包索引》之后，Chris意识到自己的写作应该与中国有更多的互动，“这是迈出泡泡圈的第一步。”他的朋友圈里渐渐地出现了越来越多的中国人。徐珺倩就是在《上海小笼包索引》发布后认识Chris的。当时后者在招募一位研究员，她发邮件自荐，但两人都慢热，互通邮件后第二年才见面。像测试般，Chris给了她一个人名，问她能不能联系到。后来两人顺利出发，去了云南采访一位厨师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为与Chris合作，徐珺倩去过阿勒泰采访制作骆驼奶的人，也去过山西采访做面食的人。若非因为工作，她大概不会主动踏足这些地方。 “Chris中文很好，只是一些方言对他来说还是有些难度。”两人合作，徐珺倩往往是采访者，Chris在一旁默默地听，只在最后补充提问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;透过Chris的视角，徐珺倩见识了许多，“脸皮也变厚了。”在她眼里，Chris是一个纯粹的人，“不追求夺人眼球的内容，不刻意煽情。”2023年春夏，他们与摄影师一起去青海采访制作兰州拉面的老人韩录，老人聊到动情处哭了，这个瞬间也被他们用镜头记录下来，但Chris后来没用这部分素材。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兼职之外，徐珺倩在一家外企工作。她喜欢将两份工作做比较，“它们像光谱的两极，外资企业做事追求回报，恨不得给每一件事安排ABCD几种方案，可往往越是小心谨慎，员工越不敢有创意。”而Chris呢，“他保持开放的心态，反而总是会有意外的收获。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去十多年，Chris辗转过几家媒体，其间经历了结婚、离异、搬家和再次抑郁。 2020年从一家网络媒体辞职后，他开了一间咨询公司，为酒店、餐厅提供服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可公司经营得一塌糊涂，“2021年它表现得还不错，去年就完全死掉了。”写作者常常面临的生存问题也越来越困扰着他。与徐珺倩一起的青海之行是他刷信用卡支付的，最近才还上。所以他会“接一些编辑的工作，或是帮一些学校打零工。我没有选择”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他也想过搬离上海，去苏州或是大理，但都不可行。一方面是他离不开上海便利的医疗体系，以防抑郁症再次发作。另一方面，“这里有我许多的记忆。”他指着街对面一栋居民楼讲起已经搬去新加坡的朋友的故事；隔壁街巷里，锁匠季师傅救过他；再往前是他常去修衣服的小店，他每次路过都要问候。 “如果不看到他们，我可能会忘了。”他恐惧失去这些生活印记（living record）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一重困境更为隐秘，是徐珺倩告诉我的。最近两年，她帮Chris找采访对象时总会隐去后者的国籍，只介绍说是一个写美食的外国作者。同样是那趟青海行，他们还采访了另外一位兰州拉面的从业者，对方态度不咸不淡，只要求服务员上了几碗拉面，“有种想让我们吃完面赶紧走人的感觉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们更不友好了吗？”Chris也自问过。 “我不觉得。即使他们讨厌美国，但他们至少对我是礼貌的。如果你这两年去美国，情况可能更糟，针对亚裔的仇恨愈演愈烈。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;第二次见Chris时，我们一起在他熟悉的街区散步。他曾经在华山路的公寓住了四五年，附近每间小店的更迭几乎都了如指掌&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王佳薇/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;我要留下吗？我要离开吗？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2006年，父母与姐姐来中国旅行时，Chris第一次听说家族故事：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1867年，24岁的海勒姆·哈里森·洛瑞从基督教会学校毕业后和妻子离开纽约，作为传教士被派往中国福州。两年后，他们奉命去北京建立卫理公会在中国华北的第一个传教所。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;洛瑞在中国一待就是五十多年，经历了战乱、疾病、强烈的排外情绪、清帝政府的崩溃，以及个人生活的种种困难。他们是可以返回美国的，但他们选择了留下。他们为当时贫穷的中国人建了学校、教堂和医院，还担任了汇文书院（经由复杂的演变，这所书院被纳入燕京大学，再被纳入当今名校北京大学）的院长。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我的祖辈的遗骨就埋在北京的某个地方，在老城墙的西边。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——《洋盘》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初次听说外高祖父与中国的神秘联结时，Chris觉得很陌生。一家人行走在天安门广场附近的胡同里寻找亚斯立堂（外高祖父留下的遗业，现在的基督教会崇文门堂）时，Chris的妈妈开始用磕巴的中文数数。 Chris和姐姐呆住了，“妈妈会说中文？”他隐约知道能讲一口流利普通话的外公“与中国有一种古怪的牵连”，但外公与家人的关系冷淡，信奉1950年代的美国男人哲学，认为女人应该照顾小孩，也从不与子女聊太多自己的事。 Chris的母亲21岁时，外公自杀。线索也就中断。后来Chris问过家族别的亲属，他们尝试联系亚斯立堂，“或许是语言障碍，最后放弃了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这件事一搁置就是16年。直到2022年春天， Chris决心打捞这段历史。他视之为某种家族责任。搜集资料的过程好似侦探挑战，许多日记或遗失或破损，他花了很多精力——“往往是每天12小时的工作”——追寻洛瑞的人生。最终，他在《洋盘》里用两个章节的篇幅、通过详实的史料梳理再现了洛瑞夫妇一百多年前的生命经历。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height=&quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洋盘-立体封&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写完《洋盘》，他不停地问自己，“Do I stay？Do I leave?”一直没有答案。实际上这样的问题他每年都问，在每个农历新旧年交替他去续签的时候。新春长假常常被虚掷于焦虑之中，他担心“签证官觉得自己尽责缴纳的税太少，或嫌弃公司的办公室太小”。焦虑一年比一年更甚，他想守住自己的家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年因为新冠疫情，Chris的许多朋友离开了中国。签证愈来愈难办，飞回国的航班数量不可同日而语，他觉得现在是近年来在华外籍人士数量最少的时期，“留下来的都是更严肃（对待中国）的人，他们可能已经在这里结婚生子，或是经营公司。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚过去的这个夏天，他过得并不好。抑郁与惨淡的经济状况折磨着他的身心，他借钱回了一趟迈阿密。时隔四年回到故乡，许多事他都不再熟悉，比如究竟该给多少小费，还有一些他不大理解的议题及其背后的语境，比如跨性别。他尴尬地发现飞去青海采访一位制作兰州拉面的老人要比驱车10分钟去家附近的哥伦比亚餐厅采访当地人更有吸引力也更舒适，“在青海，人们默认你是外来者。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他觉得自己应该留下来，留在中国。梳理外高祖父的生命经历给他提供了一种新的视角，“我们的困难根本无法相提并论。”有别于一百多年前祖辈的传教使命，他对自己的使命愈发清晰，“这里有很多宝贵的知识，我希望它被世界上更多人看到。我有签证，可以旅行，理解东西方文化不同的智慧，我可以做点什么。”他最近在策划一个视频账号，也在准备一本关于面条的书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到2006年。结束了骑摩托车环游西北之旅，重返迈阿密时，Chris心想，“一年对中国来说远远不够。”十多年过去了，他笑着说，“现在我觉得18年也不够，我不知道怎样算够。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D真实还原早产儿出生后的六重难关丨国际早产儿日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[永聚煤业火灾遇难26人：事发早晚交班时，起火二楼存大量工作服]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 23:50:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;永聚煤业联建楼灾后情况。CCTV+ 视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3bfb49f2de.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3bfb49f2de.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;永聚煤业联建楼灾后情况。CCTV+ 视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月16日6时51分，山西省吕梁市离石区永聚煤业有限公司地面联建楼发生火灾，致26人遇难，38名伤者正在全力救治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据吕梁市人民政府新闻办公室通报，火灾发生在联建楼职工澡堂，吕梁市消防、公安、卫健、应急等部门第一时间赶赴现场救援。8时35分许现场明火扑灭，13时45分现场救援结束。起火原因正在调查中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吕梁市消防救援支队综合指导科相关工作人员告诉南方周末记者，支队接到路人报警电话后立即出警，火险发生地是当地矿上的一栋楼房，但不清楚具体用途。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据官方信息，现场共投入18辆消防车、30余辆救护车、医护人员90余人、救援人员150余人进行应急处置救援。吕梁市第一人民医院相关工作人员告诉南方周末记者，医院正在全力救治伤者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“瞎蒙着跑下去”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;矿工杨旭（化名）从火场逃出后才感到后怕，在接受南方周末记者采访时，杨旭坦言：“害怕自己呛死在里面，四楼啊，跳又不敢跳。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发时，他正在该栋联建楼四楼开班前会。要是没有这场大火，开完会他会到二楼换下井的衣服，再到一楼下井。另一名同在永聚煤业工作的矿工告诉南方周末记者，公司安排井下员工“三班倒”，早班为早上六点多到下午两点多，中班为下午两点多到晚上十点多，晚班为晚上十点多到第二天六点多。起火的时间正是夜班出井和早班进井的交接时间段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;火灾当天，杨旭是早班，6点半开会，7点左右下井。“（班前会）开到6点50分左右，我听到外面有人喊&#39;快出来，着火了&#39;，我坐在窗户边也看到了，我们队里四五十个人就从楼梯往下跑。火太大了，烟太猛，我把手机灯开了，啥都看不见，每天走楼梯，我瞎蒙着跑下去的。下到一楼时前门着火了，走不了，开了后门才出去的。逃出去差点把我给呛死，（烧）塑料的那种黑烟。”杨旭回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨旭34岁，18岁开始下井挖煤，是吕梁当地人，家离永聚煤业仅十多分钟的路程。从火场逃出后，杨旭拍了一段现场视频。视频里，天还没完全亮，明亮的火焰从二楼两个窗口向外冒，伴随着炸裂声，黑色的浓烟沿着外墙向上直冲。另一条视频里，穿着工作服的矿工抱着外墙的排水管往下逃生，三四楼也有人放绳自救。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨旭在永聚煤业工作两年多，他估算在该煤矿干活的矿工有两三千人，年龄多在四五十岁，有本地的，也有外地的。每天早上7点左右换班时，该栋楼里差不多有六七百人。杨旭介绍，发生火灾的大楼共有四层，一楼直通井底，也是灯房，即井下上来放灯充电的地方。二楼是洗澡换衣服的地方，三楼和四楼是工人开会的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名当地受访妇女的姐夫也是永聚煤业的矿工，事发前一天刚从早班调成中班，“很幸运，错开了”。这名妇女告诉南方周末记者，姐夫说联建楼通常起着办公楼的作用，除了开班前安全教育会议和洗澡，下井工人不会在联建楼逗留。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;左侧外墙熏黑处为火灾发生现场。CCTV+ 视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f2e157cf98.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f2e157cf98.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258573&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左侧外墙熏黑处为火灾发生现场。CCTV+ 视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“出事的都是上早班开班前会的”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据央视新闻，此次起火点位于二楼。杨旭称，下井要穿工作服，上井要洗澡换回自己的衣服。“二楼差不多有两三千人的井下衣服，好多是棉衣，在吊篮里放着，吊篮有两层，一个放干净的，一个放脏的。每个工人都有一个吊篮，平常吊篮都吊在天花板上，换衣服时就刷卡，吊篮就会被绳索放下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位从业几十年的吊篮安装师傅告诉南方周末记者：“很多煤矿、钢厂、水泥厂、电厂等大的企业单位，都是装这种（浴室吊篮），山西那边的事故我们厂家也很纳闷。”他解释，如果是线路问题引发火灾，提升吊篮用的是尼龙绳，它会自动烧断，篮子下掉，不会成片燃烧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们家的产品目前还没有说起火的。我们使用的电线是2.5平方铜芯阻燃电线，带一个30瓦的电机，电线接头都是用焊锡焊上的，再用阻燃防水胶布裹了。咱的塑料吊篮也是阻燃的，就是你一直用火烤，它会着，一离开火，立马就灭了。”该吊篮师傅分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这次上夜班的没事，出事的都是上早班开班前会的，都在三四楼，等想出去的时候出不去了。”杨旭说，对于遇难的26人，他在井下都见过，“估计不是一个队的就是两个队的，我们这队四五十人都逃出来了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨旭介绍，每次下矿一个班是200元，一个月6000元，虽然在当地不算低，但“累个半死，拿命挣钱”。杨旭不知道接下来怎么办，出事后矿上就停工了，家里还有两个孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开信息显示，永聚煤业为吕梁东泰集团下属民营企业，核定生产能力150万吨/年，员工总数837人。该矿于2020年11月4日批准开工建设，2021年6月1日兼并重组整合项目通过竣工验收。2021年10月12日，山西省应急管理厅批准该矿井为安全生产标准化管理体系二级矿井。发生火情的联建楼，为钢筋混凝土框架结构建筑，总建筑面积6920平方米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据企查查信息，该企业涉及的78个司法案件中，33.3%为劳动争议。2022年受到两次环保处罚，包括未批先建、污水排放超标问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月16日晚，山西省吕梁市离石区应急管理局透露，目前，离石区各类矿山企业停产整顿，并在全区范围内开展火灾隐患的排查和整治工作。另据新京报报道，此次火灾事故多名相关责任人已被控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[摸清观众口味，老IP也能回春]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;每个经典的恐怖片系列，都离不开一个让人闻风丧胆的杀人魔，比如《猛鬼街》系列里的弗莱迪，《月光光心慌慌》系列里迈克尔·迈尔斯，《德州电锯杀人狂》里的皮脸，《汉尼拔》系列里的汉尼拔，《小丑回魂》系列里的潘尼怀斯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些超级反派，就是“恐怖”的代名词，给影迷们带来数不尽的梦魇。同时，他们的存在，也构成了电影的核心看点，宛如电影里的麦格芬，让人惴惴不安，担心他们何时现身，现身后又会带来怎样的杀戮？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3f399188e77f9505d96543dcd3a96ceb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3f399188e77f9505d96543dcd3a96ceb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258563&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;步入千禧年后，尽管恐怖片式微，但一个叫温子仁的导演却锋芒毕露，塑造了一系列让人印象深刻的恐怖形象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而他梦开始的地方，便是2004年上映的《电锯惊魂》。当时籍籍无名的温子仁和好友雷·沃纳尔突发奇想，用120万美元的成本、18天的拍摄时间，打造出了《电锯惊魂》这部小成本的恐怖片。影片上映后，在全球狂揽1.03亿美元票房，让温子仁名声大噪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/43be6fc791d4d4bf8d8601b789acc251.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/43be6fc791d4d4bf8d8601b789acc251.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258560&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首作的巨大成功，为后续开辟康庄大道。此后6年，该系列以一年一部电影的节奏持续输出，让观众见识到了各种脑洞大开的虐杀机关。截至目前，《电锯惊魂》系列在全球票房已超10亿美元（约70亿人民币），被吉尼斯认证为“史上最成功的系列恐怖片”，其影响力可见一斑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，时隔数年重启的第8部和第9部，却让整个系列坠入了崩坏的深渊。尤其是2021年上映的《电锯惊魂9：漩涡》，口碑溃败，成为系列最差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5a261e8c8d8d72b0db440a2f03dddd75.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height=&quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5a261e8c8d8d72b0db440a2f03dddd75.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在影迷们纷纷惋惜神作晚节不保时，出品方狮门影业调整方向，又推出了《电锯惊魂10》。没想到，这次调整立竿见影，让这个IP又迸发出了蓬勃的生命力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它不再是单纯地展示血腥和虐待，转而从年迈的杀人狂魔竖锯的视角出发，引入人性的剖析。欧美影评人一致认为，相较该系列其他影片来说，《电锯惊魂10》更像是一部电影。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a5f4dfacd6b3d97ff5e192053afa52cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a5f4dfacd6b3d97ff5e192053afa52cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258562&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熟悉《电锯惊魂》系列的观众都知道，该系列主要有两大特点：一是它总是从受害者或警察的视角来讲故事，将极致的险境与道德困境抛给观众；二是它塑造出了竖锯这个恐怖的拼图杀人魔，让受害者笼罩在巨大的阴影下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而《电锯惊魂10》转换了视角，以大反派竖锯为主视角来推进电影。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4630740adca06fc8b01df8a0777e8256.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4630740adca06fc8b01df8a0777e8256.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竖锯本名约翰·克莱默，虽名为变态杀人魔，但他从不亲自动手杀人。大部分时候，他只是在充当一个审判者的角色。他本身是一个身患绝症的工程师，喜欢捣鼓各种精巧的刑具，让受害者在疼痛与死亡之间做选择。在他看来，这种选择“不是惩罚，而是救赎”，让那些有罪之人获得一次改过自新的机会，让他们在痛苦中懂得生命的可贵。这种“用心良苦”，构成了这个角色致命又惊悚的吸引力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竖锯在这个系列里只活了三集，死在了《电锯惊魂3》的最后。接下来他又通过回忆、录像等方式“活”了五集，他的信徒们继承他的意志，继续给他人设置挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8bcc0ec65647f883c8df9c7fe6434c8a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8bcc0ec65647f883c8df9c7fe6434c8a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258564&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;抓住了竖锯这个角色，就相当于抓住了该系列的灵魂。由于竖锯缺席《电锯惊魂9》，该片直接口碑溃散，观众普遍认为，没了竖锯那标志性的嗓音和发人深省的台词，这个系列仿佛被掏空，失去了让人毛骨悚然之感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，片方聪明地把《电锯惊魂10》拍成一部前传，时间线设置在第一部和第二部之间，好叫竖锯还活着。彼时，竖锯正饱受癌症困扰。偶然间，他从病友那里得知墨西哥有一个地下医疗组织，能够有效根治癌症。在粗略了解这个组织后，竖锯带着最后一丝希望，只身前往墨西哥。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ad85b2d10fce5915bcc1d7952ea9d6ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ad85b2d10fce5915bcc1d7952ea9d6ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在医生塞西莉亚的帮助下，竖锯接受了所谓的“清醒开颅手术”。术后医生告诉他一切顺利，休息静养。几天后，待竖锯重返机构想要表达谢意时，却发现此地已人去楼空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在手术中看到的开颅视频，只是一段提前录好的教学视频。原来，他遇到的是一个专门坑害抗癌患者的诈骗集团：医院是假的，医生是假的，手术是假的，他的病压根没有被治愈。&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f4d7a40ca514959917e38f18dfb5e61e.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f4d7a40ca514959917e38f18dfb5e61e.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;258568&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了复仇、也为了惩治这个诈骗集团，竖锯开启了又一轮的虐杀。他把诈骗链上的所有成员都抓了起来，从司机到护士、麻醉师、医生一个不落。随他们一起登场的，是熟悉的竖锯酷刑：刮骨剃肉拆炸弹、断腿抽骨髓、开颅取脑组织……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了这些血腥酷刑外，《电锯惊魂10》最突出的贡献，就是它最大程度上的丰满了竖锯这个角色，放大了他的软弱，让他看上去更像是一个“人”——一个病入膏肓、病急乱投医的老人，且这个老人也会为劫后余生而哭泣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这种丰满，也是有遗憾的，就是容易使角色“降智”。一直以来，竖锯都是一个神秘、残忍的高智商反派，他就是一个邪恶的符号。而《电锯惊魂10》的“深度解读”，损害了他符号时期的冷酷与高明。让人不禁怀疑，这么拙劣的诈骗技法，竟然能够骗过鼎鼎大名的竖锯？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e962fca1bdb9a682032b0406e409ffe0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e962fca1bdb9a682032b0406e409ffe0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，从竖锯的视角切入，也大大削弱了该片的反转与悬疑。尽管竖锯为了揪出幕后黑手，在片中以身犯险设置了一个反转高潮，但与《电锯惊魂》系列里的极限反转比起来，都只是小巫见大巫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，该系列从受害者和警察视角切入，悬疑点的设置往往很有层次：一层是受害者的闯关模式，或单人破关，或合作破关，试炼的过程中，充满了各种各样的不确定性；第二层是探员对案件的锲而不舍，与竖锯及其信徒的斗智斗勇，观众不禁为探员捏一把汗，好奇他能否成功缉凶、保住性命。《电锯惊魂10》只保留了第一层悬疑，对第二层悬疑完全摒弃，使其悬疑性大打折扣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b8fd0f4e9f37091626ad3cb526d3cc9b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b8fd0f4e9f37091626ad3cb526d3cc9b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，为了迎合好莱坞反精英主义的大潮，《电锯惊魂10》还加重了竖锯的“英雄气质”。由于竖锯面对的是唯利是图、草菅人命的女医生，所以该片比以往任何一部都更强调他执行私刑的正义性。他从过去道德模糊的大反派，摇身一变成了为病患挺身而出的平民英雄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，从某种意义上来说，《电锯惊魂10》的这次回春，投机、讨巧，也是当下好莱坞续作的风向标：只要攥紧故事灵魂、把握时代思潮、摸清观众口味，老IP就能找到新出路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>