<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[多名培训机构人员组织研究生考试作弊获刑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258489]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 11, 2023, the Beijing Haidian District People’s Court prosecuted the defendant Zhang and others for using wireless Transmission method, in the 2021 and 2022 National Master&#39;s Degree Admissions Examination, the first instance verdict was issued on the cheating case of candidates in the examination. The court sentenced Zhang and nine other defendants to fixed-term imprisonment ranging from 5 years and 6 months to 2 years for organizing examination cheating, and fines ranging from 50,000 yuan to 20,000 yuan; at the same time, in order to prevent them from committing such crimes again For committing a crime, nine defendants were declared career-barred in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/092024160194962a6d825a8493f855d6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/092024160194962a6d825a8493f855d6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The court found after trial that the defendants Zhang, Du, Niu, Wang, Zhang, Jiang and others were engaged in education consulting, examination training and other businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2020, the defendant Zhang designed a method of transmitting examination answers using radio equipment to organize candidates to cheat in the 2021 National Master’s Degree Admissions Examination. The defendants Du and Niu acted as Zhang’s Someone introduces candidates and obtains benefits from them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1713fa72ea20a1748b27ff669b9c3b5f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1713fa72ea20a1748b27ff669b9c3b5f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253951&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;From October to December 2021, the defendant Zhang organized candidates to cheat in the 2022 National Master’s Admissions Examination in the same way. The defendants Du Moumou, Niu Moumou, Zhang Moumou, and Wang Moumou XX and Jiang recruited candidates for Zhang and obtained benefits from them. During this period, Zhang was responsible for recruiting candidates, purchasing cheating equipment, registering rooms near the test site and installing signal transmitting devices, contacting examination questions, making and sending answers; Lu helped Zhang organize candidate information and candidate feedback questions, organize answer formats and send them , Xu trains candidates, tests equipment, recruits &quot;mules&quot; (i.e., signal amplifier caregivers), and sends answers to candidates during exams; Xu sends and receives express delivery, repairs equipment, and directs &quot;mules&quot; to switch equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64db816c9fe5e43c7325015799d0dff8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64db816c9fe5e43c7325015799d0dff8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253952&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of December 25, 2021, Zhang organized many candidates to cheat in the 2022 National Master&#39;s Degree Admissions Examination, and arranged for personnel to place signal amplifiers near many universities in Beijing to send answers to the candidates. On the same day, the police received reports from the masses and arrested the caregiver of the signal amplifier near the test site. Later, based on clues, they arrested the nine defendants and seized the radio equipment used in the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/e25da2523f24c43c3b07a9dc26ae4127.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/e25da2523f24c43c3b07a9dc26ae4127.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;After hearing, the court held that the defendants Zhang, Lu, Xu, Xu, Niu, Du, Zhang, Jiang, and Wang passed the national postgraduate entrance examination. Using wireless transmission to organize multiple candidates to cheat, the circumstances are serious, and their actions have constituted the crime of organizing exam cheating. Among them, the defendants Zhang, Xu, Niu, Du, Zhang, Jiang, and Wang were the principal offenders; the defendants Lu and Xu were the accomplices. The court made the above judgment in accordance with the law based on factors such as the defendant&#39;s criminal facts, nature, circumstances, degree of social harm, attitude of confession and repentance, and circumstances of returning stolen goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the verdict was announced, the defendants did not clearly indicate whether they would appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;The judge’s interpretation: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheating in exams undermines the exam system and talent selection system, hinders fair competition, and undermines social integrity. Corrupting social morals has serious social harm. In particular, organized examination cheating activities using information technology means are particularly harmful. To this end, the &quot;Criminal Law Amendment (9)&quot; has added provisions such as the crime of cheating in organized examinations, the crime of illegally selling and providing test questions and answers, and the crime of substitute examination, to severely punish the crime of cheating in examinations. Since then, the two top universities have issued the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in the Handling of Criminal Cases such as Organized Exam Cheating&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Interpretation&quot;), which further provides specific provisions on the conviction, sentencing and application of laws for the crime of examination cheating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Postgraduate Admissions Examination involved in this case is a national education examination stipulated by law. It is an important channel for selecting high-level professionals in our country. It has high social attention, great influence, and wide coverage. It is of national importance. take an exam. Article 2, Item (1) of the &quot;Interpretation&quot; directly stipulates that &quot;organizing cheating in the admission examination of ordinary colleges and universities, the admission examination of graduate students, and the recruitment examination of civil servants&quot; is directly defined as &quot;serious circumstances.&quot; The defendants in this case clearly knew that the candidates were participating in the national master&#39;s degree admissions examination, but still participated in it and organized cheating, which is a &quot;serious circumstance.&quot; According to Article 284-1 of the Criminal Law, anyone who organizes cheating and the circumstances are serious shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years but not more than seven years, and shall also be fined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a practical point of view, the crime of cheating in exams has the possibility of re-offending to a certain extent. In order to prevent criminals from &quot;returning to their old careers&quot;, this case is based on the provisions of Article 12 of the &quot;Interpretation&quot; and Zhang is punished in accordance with the law. The nine defendants were declared occupationally prohibited, that is, the nine defendants were prohibited from engaging in occupations related to education, examinations, and training within five years from the date of completion of the sentence or the date of parole; at the same time, the defendants who were sentenced to probation were prohibited from engaging in occupations related to education, examination, and training within five years from the date of completion of the sentence or the date of parole; at the same time, the defendants who were sentenced to probation were prohibited from engaging in occupations related to education, examination, and training within five years from the date of completion of the sentence or the date of parole; A prohibition order is issued in accordance with the law, which means that he is prohibited from engaging in activities related to education, examinations, and training during the probation period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ten years of hard work, but one day of hard work&quot;, examination fairness is a bottom line that cannot be touched in society. Cheating in exams not only undermines exam fairness, but also affects social fairness and seriously harms individual candidates and national interests. &quot;The French Open will be open without any omissions,&quot; organizers should not take any chances. They also hope that every candidate will strictly abide by the law, take the exam with integrity, refuse to cheat, and use their hard work to obtain satisfactory answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[透视银行半年报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258551]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Commercial banks are not only the transmission system of macro-control policies, but also an excellent window for observing the micro-economy. Therefore, by studying the 2023 interim report data of listed banks and comparing them with their past financial reports and surveys, we gain insight into macro and micro economic phenomena and reveal their essence. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[著砚楼头朵云来：潘景郑与沈燮元交往补记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258188]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among the research works of modern bibliophiles, one of my personal favorites is &quot;Modern Book Collection&quot; published in 1983 Thirty Homes&quot;, which is almost the same age as me. The experience of Mr. Su Jing, the author of &quot;Thirty Collectors of Modern Books&quot;, is also very legendary. For details, please refer to Zou Zhenhuan&#39;s &quot;The &quot;Paradigm Shift&quot; of Chinese Book Publishing - Reading Su Jing&#39;s &quot;Casting to Replace Engraving: Missionaries and the Changing Situation of Chinese Printing&quot; 》, I won’t go into details here. Going back to &quot;Thirty Modern Book Collectors&quot;, when the Taiwanese biographical literature edition was published, only two biographers of the thirty names recorded in the book were still alive. One of them was Zhou Shutao (1891-1984) who passed away the following year, and the other It was Pan Jingzheng (1907-2003) who passed away 20 years later. It is unknown whether Mr. Zhou Shutao has seen &quot;Thirty Collectors of Modern Books&quot;. However, Mr. Pan Jingzheng did read the Taiwanese version of &quot;Thirty Modern Book Collectors&quot; and commented on it in a letter to Mr. Shen Xieyuan. In 1995, the first issue of Nanjing Normal University&#39;s &quot;Cultural and Educational Materials&quot; compiled an album of information on Pan Jingzheng. In addition to Xu Xiaoman&#39;s article &quot;Mr. Pan Jingzheng, the bibliographer&quot;, the other two articles were &quot;Pan Jingzheng&quot; signed by &quot;Shu Lu&quot; &quot;Biography of Mr. Jing Zheng&quot; and &quot;Catalogue of Writings of Mr. Pan Jingzheng&quot;. From Mr. Pan Jingzheng&#39;s letters, the author quite doubts that &quot;Shu Lu&quot; is a temporary pen name created by Mr. Shen or him and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently sorting out the remains of Mr. Shen Xieyuan, I found more than ten handwritten notes from Pan Jing and Zheng Zheng to Shen Xieyuan, mainly written from the late 1970s to the early 1990s. Most of them were written with brushes and paper. , seal, which are identical to the letters collected by &quot;Pan Jingzheng&quot; (edited by Wang Guichen and Wang Dawen), the first volume of the &quot;Scholar&#39;s Ink Collection&quot; published by Guangdong Education Press in June 2022. I would like to select Shutong and briefly reveal his abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Previously, the author wrote in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/255656&quot; title=&quot;Old friends smile more than the trees in the courtyard: Shen Xieyuan and Qu Fengqi As mentioned in the article &quot;An old friend smiled more than the tree in the atrium: A brief account of Shen Xieyuan and Qu Fengqi&lt;/a>;&quot;, Gu Tinglong, Pan Jingzheng, and Qu Fengqi all once collected the &quot;Er Golden Butterfly Hall Seal&quot; for Mr. Shen Xieyuan. inscription. Letters from Mr. Qu Fengqi were also forwarded through Mr. Pan Jingzheng. In an existing letter from Mr. Pan Jingzheng dated October 13, 1982, he once mentioned a sentence: &quot;It belongs to the seal of Uncle Bazhuo, and is compiled into short words for correction. If it is not applicable, throw it into the toilet for correction.&quot; This was related to this matter. Mr. Pan Jingzheng inscribed &quot;Er Jindie Hall Printing&quot; and first filled in the words &quot;Unforgettable&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Before the wind and rain, I am afraid of chasing after others and looking for claws, and check the confusion. The wealthy family destroyed the painted building, and the swallow curtain replaced the beam. The lonely traveler&#39;s thoughts, caressing the broken bag. Early calamity dream. A hundred years old, the shadow of two golden butterflies has gone through many vicissitudes of life. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The long grace is protected now, and the iron pen is overflowing with fragrance. Wherever you hit, look at the pear. It’s a good companionship and the fragrance of the heart. I only feel ashamed and graffiti, which detracts from my appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Repost &quot;Unforgettable Meaning&quot;. Send the poet&#39;s manuscript. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/AxdvQw1pGBelAJoXZleKTVDhh4X5or1uEHyr5VJU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 539&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/AxdvQw1pGBelAJoXZleKTVDhh4X5or1uEHyr5VJU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253223&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Mr. Pan Jingzheng’s study of the phonology of writing was personally taught by Zhang Taiyan, and his study of poetry was personally taught by Wu Mei (Qu An), and he learned poetry before studying under Zhang Taiyan. He relied heavily on sound throughout his life, and he continued to do so until he was old. Mr. Wei Li obtained a kind of &quot;Inscriptions on Letters Written by Qing Dynasty People in Inkstones&quot;. Mr. Pan wrote a line of words for almost every letter, which is a good proof. Especially in his later years, Mr. Pan Jingzheng preferred to write lyrics in rare ancient books instead of inscriptions and postscripts. This tendency of using rhyme instead of prose is somewhat similar to that of Gu Wenbin, the owner of Guoyun Tower. Gu Wenbin said that rhyme is better than prose, so he exploits his strengths and avoids his weaknesses. The reason why Mr. Pan Jingzheng is like this, I think, he considers himself a poet with romantic feelings and literary temperament from beginning to end. The poem &quot;Unforgettable&quot; is prefaced by Zhu Wenfang Yin - &quot;I am also a lyricist in Wuzhong&quot;, which can be called a portrayal. Mr. Shen Jin recalled that the title of Mr. Pan Jingzheng&#39;s article was &quot;A Piece of Ice Heart in a Jade Pot&quot;, which was really appropriate and can be said to be insightful. There is a long postscript after the poem &quot;Unforgettable Meanings&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;My friend Shen Junxieyuan came from his old home in Yuyi to acquire the work of Mr. Zhao Shushu. The inscription is eighty-two, the dress is in a bow, and the treasure is left in the office of Qian Wu Hufan&#39;s uncle. Compared with Shanghai, it is a metaphor, which means &quot;Hongzhao&quot;. Most of the prints in the book were engraved by Shen Yunchu and Wei Jiasun, and some were engraved and consumed by themselves. There are two seals carved by the ancestor of Zheng&#39;an, one is a large square seal with three characters &quot;Pang Xizhai&quot; and the other is a rectangular seal with three characters &quot;Hanxueju&quot;, both of which are exquisite works. Shen, Wei, and Mr. Xiang are all in perfect agreement, and all the seals should be perfect. I have collected fifty or sixty stones of Mr.&#39;s seals, and they have all been returned to the Shanghai Museum. The collections of Shen and Wei are no longer traceable. Hundreds of years of vicissitudes, gathering and dispersing smoke and clouds, make me feel sad. The word &quot;Yuan&quot; is added to &quot;Wu&quot; to repay one&#39;s fate. In his declining years, his writing and writing are desolate, and I feel ashamed. In the eighth month of Renxu, Zheng Shi, Pan Jing, Wu County, was seventy-six years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ItRTBT8LILpgcO8CZQa2l3odtDKoYp1KAZoIShjL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 756&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ItRTBT8LILpgcO8CZQa2l3odtDKoYp1KAZoIShjL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Mr. Pan Jingzheng mentioned above that the fifty-six stones of the seal carved by Zhao Zhiqian for Pan Zuyin in the Pan family&#39;s collection have been returned to the Shanghai Museum. This is proved by the fact that the seal used by Pan Zuyin is on display in the Seal Hall of the Shanghai Museum. The seal &quot;Pang Xizhai&quot; is clearly visible, which is true. In the past, the Suzhou Museum held a special exhibition &quot;Planning the Ancient World: The Collection of Pan in Suzhou during the Qing Dynasty&quot;. They tried to borrow the giant seal &quot;Pang Xizhai&quot; for the exhibition but failed. They had to replace it with a seal titled &quot;Wuxian Pan Boyin&#39;s Life and Authentic Appreciation&quot;. Breathless. As far as the author knows, there are at least four giant seals of the Zhai name used by Pan Zuyin. In addition to &quot;Pang Xi Zhai&quot;, there are also three seals of &quot;Pangu Lou&quot;, &quot;Zheng&#39;an&quot; and &quot;Plum Blossom Happy God&#39;s Pavilion&quot;. According to Mr. Shen Xieyuan&#39;s recollection, after Mr. Pan Jingzheng wrote the postscript for &quot;Er Golden Butterfly Hall Yin Cun&quot;, he gave a piece of paper with the seal number of Pan Zuyinzhai as a gift, which was not found in the &quot;Yin Cun&quot;. It was bound. I wonder if it is still in the book? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have heard from Mr. Shen Xieyuan more than once before that in addition to the ink ink of Mr. Pan Jingzheng in his collection, there are also two handwritten lyrics written by him. It was not until September 2012 that I had the opportunity to see them in Shen Zhai, Xitang North Lane. However, within a few years, these two pieces were scattered among the people. Now that I think about it, I still feel very regretful. The two poems are self-composed, one horizontal and one vertical. The vertical ones are made of plain paper, and are signed: &quot;The book &quot;Qingmen Yin&quot; was presented to Xueyuan&#39;s brother-in-law Jiaozheng. In the first month of Wuchen, Pan Jingzheng was eighty-two years old.&quot; Also sealed are the four seals of &quot;Xingyang Zonglao&quot;, &quot;Prime Minister Shaozai&#39;s great-grandson Hanlin&#39;s grandson&quot;, &quot;Pan Jingzheng&#39;s seal&quot; and &quot;original name Chengbi&quot;. The word cloud is:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mengying Liutufu. The flow of ordering business is flowing. Many gentlemen are inundated with elegance and indulgence in beautiful things. They have forgotten their love for each other, and their silky silk fabrics are entrusted to Fangdu. I have collected all the relics of the Song Dynasty, and looked at the traces of the threads. Famous mountains look up to the declining old man, and the slang chants are unworthy of the Ba people&#39;s sentences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/EvJIfw1OrT5p5JcgzZH2qikCWgCXREERHxAHyKNa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 460&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/EvJIfw1OrT5p5JcgzZH2qikCWgCXREERHxAHyKNa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Wu Chen is 1988. In a letter signed on May 3rd (no year), Mr. Pan Jingzheng once mentioned that &quot;Xueyuan Marriage Brother&#39;s Dajian, the previous order document has been drafted. Weizunzhu If no one comes to take it, it’s okay to give it up later.&quot; Judging from the time, it is likely to be this &quot;Qingmen Yin&quot; dated January 1988. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The banner is decorated with vertical red silk columns, and the inscription is &quot;Send to &quot;Eternal Life Joy&quot;, in June of Jiazi, the in-laws of Feng Xueyuan celebrate their sixtieth birthday. Pan Jingzheng was seventy and eight years old.&quot; , and seal the three seals of &quot;Zuo Inkstone&quot;, &quot;Guihai Flowers and Candles Reunion&quot; and &quot;Jing Zheng Yisheng&quot;, word cloud:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Wu Huixiu, a talented artist in the art field, has long been famous among the public. Shaofen&#39;s hairpin leaves are inherited from Sutai. The fifth generation has a simple family style and a professional heart. Linlang Divine Deed, check Danhuangjiu Bookstore. &amp;nbsp;Double cultivation of Buddha&#39;s birthday, healthy and long life. Lifting the case and serving the phoenix chick with a glass of wine, Zhou Jia added extra time to celebrate his age. The redundant chanting of slang sentences weakens the old man, and the fragrance of dill is fragrant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/EMfTwXK1jL7qQU1qJmd7cO0Vj6ZCvE8VT9zIgrHv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;727&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/EMfTwXK1jL7qQU1qJmd7cO0Vj6ZCvE8VT9zIgrHv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253225&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The year is 1984. Obviously, &quot;Eternal Life&quot; is four years earlier than &quot;Qingmen Yin&quot;, but both are later than &quot;Unforgettable&quot; in 1982. However, among the three, &quot;Longevity&quot; was written to celebrate Mr. Shen Xieyuan&#39;s 60th birthday, so its significance is naturally extraordinary and comparable. Although the three poems were created at different times and have different names, they all use the word &quot;Linlang&quot;, which makes people sigh involuntarily. This is a coincidence, but I believe it is not an accident! &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The relationship between Mr. Shen Xieyuan and Mr. Pan Jingzheng may have started in the 1940s and ended after 2000, about half a century ago, but the existing Pan Jingzheng Mr.’s letters only include part of the last twenty years. The earliest one is from January 16, 1976:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xie Yuan About my brother: I have learned from you over a long period of time, and have a deep connection with you. But the daily life is Sui Sheng, the business is diligent, and the talisman is chanted. My brother is recovering from his illness, and he is still working in the ancient books group in the picture above. Recently, the 721 University has been established, and he is looking for some teaching materials in terms of editions. I know that your library has compiled a book called &quot;Knowledge of Ancient Book Versions&quot;, and I would like to make great efforts to find a copy for you to study. You need to pay a certain amount of cost and postage. Please let me know and send it to you immediately. You are welcome. I hope that my brother will be able to show me what kind of studies he has recently devoted himself to, and that he will be able to make some achievements in order to enlighten his ignorance. I also heard that Nan Tu compiled a &quot;Bibliography of Rare Books&quot;. Was it the result of great efforts? Return to Yuwu and beg and send it to our apartment at No. 1, Lane 181, Xikang Road, Shanghai. Because there are so many departments in the library, there may be a loss in mail delivery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, in the suicide note of Mr. Shen Xieyuan, I found a set of mimeographed copies of &quot;Knowledge of Ancient Book Versions&quot; from Beijing China Bookstore. It has the same name as the book Pan Zhazhong requested. Is it this book? , cannot be determined at this time. Since the original signature does not have a year, we relied on the records in &quot;Haineng Baichuan&amp;nbsp;Knowledge Navigation: Collected Works to Commemorate the 60th Anniversary of the Establishment of the Shanghai Library&quot;. On December 26, 1975, after three months of preparations, the Shanghai Library established the &quot;Seven 21 &quot;The university offers four classes: basic library knowledge, English, Japanese, and ancient books. The ancient books class has been out of work for one year. &quot;Most of the ancient books students have stuck to their majors and have become the ancient books management and research team of the Shanghai Library. For example, Chen Xianxian became an ancient books expert at the Shanghai Library, and Yan Zuozhi became the director of the Ancient Books Research Institute of East China Normal University. &quot;. Regarding the situation of the &quot;721&quot; University, I once called Mr. Shen Jin who was far away in the United States. According to his recollection, there were 15 students in the ancient books class at that time, and the class leader was Zhu Binyong, who later worked in the library of Fudan University. The teachers who teach include Gu Tinglong, Pan Jingzheng, Qu Fengqi, Ruan Henghui, Chen Shiming, Chen Bingren, Ren Guangliang, Wu Zhi and Shen Jin. Among them, Mr. Pan Jingzheng teaches the most frequently. The course lectures he is responsible for include &quot;Engraved Editions of Song, Yuan, Ming and Qing Dynasties&quot; and &quot;Manuscripts&quot;. &quot;History&quot;, &quot;School-based Lecture Notes&quot;, &quot;Stone Carving Lecture Notes&quot;, &quot;Dharma Notes Lecture Notes&quot;, etc. It is unknown whether the mimeograph version of &quot;Knowledge of Ancient Book Versions&quot; was used for reference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that as early as 1957, when Xinhua Bookstore in Jiangsu Province held a training class for managers of Xinhua Bookstores in the province, Mr. Shen Xieyuan was invited to teach the history of Chinese books. In May 1965, he was invited to teach the ancient part of Chinese calligraphy history to a training class for amateur university library staff in Gulou District, Nanjing City (mainly librarians in colleges and universities). Since then, related activities have been suspended due to various reasons. In 1975, Jiangsu Province re-organized a study class for ancient books staff, and he was invited to teach about the Song and Yuan editions. After entering the 1980s, he was invited to teach ancient book editions in 1985 as a national training course on ancient book restoration commissioned by the National Library Administration and organized by the Shanghai Library. In June 1986, the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Culture commissioned the Nanjing Library to hold a seminar on the regulations for recording Chinese ancient books in Jiangsu Province, and he was invited to give lectures on the cataloging of ancient books. Since then, he has taught edition bibliography courses to students majoring in related majors at Nanjing Normal University and Nanjing University. Although we have not seen the complete lecture notes left by Mr. Shen Xieyuan during this period, among his belongings, we still found some manuscripts of lecture notes on edition and bibliography, some written with brushes and some with hard pens, and they are not too long. It is very large. If I have the opportunity to sort it out in the future, it can be used as a supplement to the &quot;Collected Works of Shen Xieyuan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time that Mr. Shen Xieyuan and Mr. Pan Jingzheng were invited to teach versionology in the ancient literature major of Nanjing Normal University, Mr. Pan Jingzheng was hired as a part-time professor by the Ancient Books Department of East China Normal University and taught graduate students. On February 2, 1983, Mr. Pan Jingzheng wrote in a letter saying:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I would like to ask the director of Tianzhen Museum on my behalf. I was given a volume of the great work &quot;Yangzhou Poetry Bureau Examination&quot;. Since my brother is giving a lecture for postgraduate students, I can use it to supplement the materials. I am particularly grateful if I can send it immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is to ask Mr. Shen Xieyuan to ask Mr. Pan Tianzhen for the article &quot;Miscellaneous Examination of Yangzhou Poetry Bureau&quot; newly published in the 1983 issue of &quot;Library Science Newsletter&quot; as a reference for teaching edition science . On January 17, 1990, Mr. Pan Jingzheng sent a letter to inform him that &quot;after my retirement this year, I will not be able to go out. Recently my blood pressure is high and I have to take a rest. Four people have graduated from the Normal University this year and they will no longer be Feng&#39;s wife.&quot; &quot;Exactly.&quot; It can be seen that when he retired from the Shanghai Library, he no longer served as a graduate tutor at East China Normal University. At this time, Mr. Pan Jingzheng was already eighty-four years old. Among the graduate students taught by East China Normal University, the student that Mr. Pan Jingzheng admires most is Lin Shenqing, the editor of &quot;Seals of Ming and Qing Bibliophiles&quot; and &quot;Seals of Chinese Bibliophiles&quot;. The publication of the 1989 edition of &quot;Seals of Ming and Qing Bibliophiles&quot; was the result of strong recommendation from Mr. Pan Jingzheng. Among the letters written by Pan&#39;s inkstones and friends, only &quot;The Letters of Zhang Taiyan&quot; have been compiled and published in the 17th volume of &quot;Xue Ji Lin&quot;, and the letters of Guo Moruo have been included in the article &quot;The Posthumous Letters of Guo Moruo and &quot;Guanzi Collection&quot;&quot; Library Journal, Issue 3, 1999, the authors are all Lin Shenqing, which shows that Mr. Pan Jingzheng held him in high esteem. Unfortunately, Lin died young and was unable to complete the collection and research of the letters written by friends in Yanlou. , which is regrettable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;三&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Pan Jingzheng, like Gu Tinglong and Qu Fengqi, are very supportive of Mr. Shen Xieyuan’s collection and arrangement of Huang Pilie’s inscriptions and postscripts. He once mentioned in his letters that &quot;it will be beneficial to write Huang&#39;s postscripts. I hope Mr. Gu can help me with my essays such as those on the Bo.&quot; It is undeniable that &quot;the previous letter of courtesy is based on the information of Huangxunpu. Because the matter is too long and nothing has been gained, it cannot be replied.&quot; If you see anything, you will be notified in a letter, such as the letter on October 18, 1981:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xie Yuan My brother asked: I sent you a copy ten days ago, and I want to go to the record room. The information on Xicheng Garden published in Taiwanese publications has been borrowed from Yang Junkanen of the Academy of Social Sciences on behalf of him, and was copied by Comrade Shen Jin, who agreed to receive it that morning. If you are sincere, I would like to order &quot;Jiangsu Library Work&quot;. I hope that I can arrange it on my behalf. It is best to start from the first issue last year (it has been published to the seventh issue now). Because it is issued internally, there is no way to place an order here. If you need a certain amount of money, please ask for instructions and it will be remitted immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person mentioned in the above letter as &quot;the information on Xicheng Garden has been included in Taiwanese publications&quot; should be Hong Kong scholar Luo Bingmian&#39;s &quot;Research on Huang Pilie&quot;. This article was included in the 1976 edition of Taiwan Food Publishing House. Luo&#39;s &quot;Collection of Qing Dynasty Scholars&quot;. In Mr. Shen Xieyuan&#39;s case, there is a copy of the article, which has been bound into a volume with a kraft paper cover. There is a &quot;Shanghai Library Reproduction Fee Receipt&quot; in the volume, and the payment unit is filled with &quot;Shenjin&quot;. Next to it is Mr. Shen Xieyuan&#39;s ink note &quot;Printing on behalf of &quot;Research on Huang Pilie&quot;&quot;. On September 18, 1981, he copied 57 pages of A4 paper for a total cost of 14.25 yuan. It seemed very expensive at the time and the price was not small. It can be inferred from the time and the person who made the printing that Mr. Pan Jingzheng was referring to this immediately when he mentioned copying. It can be seen from the letter that Mr. Pan Jingzheng borrowed Luo&#39;s &quot;Academic Treatise on the Qing Dynasty&quot; from Yang Kangnian of the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences. Yang Kangnian is the same age as Mr. Shen Xieyuan and also graduated from Wuxi National College. However, he graduated a few years earlier and the two were not classmates. For his life, please refer to Ma Jun&#39;s &quot;Information&quot; published in &quot;The Paper·Private History&quot; on August 6, 2017. &quot;There is a Yang Kangnian in the room&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, Mr. Shen Xieyuan sent Mr. Pan Jingzheng and Mr. Qu Fengqi respectively the &quot;Yongfeng Township People&#39;s Travel Chronicles&quot; compiled by Gan Ru (Luo Jizu) published by Jiangsu People&#39;s Publishing House. Both elders believed in it. Thanks. Mr. Pan Jingzheng’s letter of thanks was written on November 24, 1981:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;My brother Xieyuan: To the letter, I also express my gratitude to you for the gift of &quot;Yongfeng Township People&#39;s Travel Chronicle&quot;. I am deeply sorry to express my gratitude to Qiong. I have also received the journal of the society and would like to express my gratitude on my behalf. If the order for 1982 is awarded, the order fee will be remitted immediately. I feel so relieved and refreshed. Attached are two lost poems by Xun Weng, whose dates can be traced. If you have any income after that, you should continue to send it. My brother caught a cold in the winter and his cough has not healed yet. His symptoms are getting worse day by day, and he is also quite tired and lazy in writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;two poems copied from Xun Weng&#39;s lost poems&quot; mentioned in this letter should be &quot;Wu Chen Sui Dynasty&#39;s test writing with the title Mr. Guxiang sitting alone in Xishan to seek government&quot; ：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Being in the mountain spring is clearer than the mountains, and the rock valley is quiet and peaceful. There are rugged mountain roads and dangerous roads, and the sound of waterfalls and springs can&#39;t be heard despite the storm. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking up, you can see the mountains and listen to the spring, and the skylight, clouds and shadows are leisurely. The movement and stillness here are all true, and the joy can last forever. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/yxbjqte7aoUaK4DWRs9L53Dsf7X72lvB1E6oODmW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 600&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/yxbjqte7aoUaK4DWRs9L53Dsf7X72lvB1E6oODmW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The two poems were written on a piece of jade-buttoned paper, which has long been separated from the original letter. If it were not for the Zhu Wen long seal of &quot;Xinyou Qiwuweng&quot; in the left corner, which can be inferred from the year and content, it is very likely that it will be different from the original letter. letter separation. Although the main text of Huang Pilie&#39;s poem on painting has been included in Volume 5 of the newly published &quot;Xipu Poems&quot; by Zhang Xiaolu, the title of &quot;Xipu Poems&quot; follows the previous one and is changed to &quot;Picture of Sitting Alone in Xishan&quot; For the ancient fragrance (Wuchen)&quot;. Omitting the word &quot;Sui Chao&quot; seems innocuous, but I don&#39;t know that these two words have a great influence on the reorganization of &quot;Huang Pilie Chronicle&quot;. There are two words &quot;Sui Chao&quot;, and the two poems are dated to the first day of the first month of the thirteenth year of Jiaqing (1808). There is no doubt that without these two words, they can only be attached to after this year. This is what Mr. Pan Jingzheng specifically mentioned in his letter. There is a saying that &quot;it can be traced over time&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人类文明史的两大基石：对偶家庭+市场经济的自然进化史]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258297]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the field of public opinion, there are two abstract things that are discussed more. One is father, marriage and family; It is private property rights and market economy. Because these two constitute the two indispensable cornerstones of human civilization. Our ability as humans to enter a civilized society really depends on this. This article explores the origin and evolution of these two species from the perspectives of historical genetics and natural evolutionary history. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Father&quot; is a product of cultural construction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Scholars in the pre-Qin era realized that in the distant &quot;ancient&quot; period, there was no such role as a father. &quot;Zhuangzi: Robber Zhi&quot; states that &quot;in the days of Shen Nong, the people knew their mothers but did not know their fathers.&quot; &quot;Lu&#39;s Spring and Autumn Annals: Reliance on the King&quot; said: &quot;In ancient times, there were no kings. The people lived in groups and knew each other.&quot; &quot;The mother does not know the father&quot;, that is, there was no father&#39;s role in the &quot;ancient&quot; period, so there was no stable dual family and the corresponding ethics between various relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Wu Fei said that in &quot;Etiquette·Mourning Clothes Biography&quot;, &quot;Shang Jun Shu·Kaisa&quot; and &quot;Lu Shi&quot;, as well as &quot;Jiao Shi Yi Lin&quot;, &quot;Baihu Tong·Hao&quot; and &quot;Lunheng&quot; in the Han Dynasty • Documents such as &quot;Qi Shi&quot; and &quot;He Tu Ting Zuo Fu&quot; all record the situation of &quot;knowing the mother but not knowing the father&quot; in ancient times (Wu Fei: &quot;The &quot;Disintegration&quot; of Human Relations: Anxiety about Family and Country in the Tradition of Moral Theory&quot;, Sanlian Bookstore , 2017, pp. 163–166). As a kind of collective memory, as well as field observations of &quot;savages&quot; in the pre-Qin era, we all realize that the role of fathers comes with the development of civilization. This is a consensus among people since the pre-Qin and Han Dynasties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Book of the Later Han Dynasty·Xunli Biography&quot; also noted from the perspective of field observation that the people of Luoyue in the south at that time &quot;had no wedding ceremony laws, and they had no suitable match due to their promiscuity and lust.&quot; This state of no stable duality obviously does not produce the role of a father (in a social and cultural sense). Through civilized discipline and education, biological men in nature are transformed into fathers who fulfill family and social responsibilities, thus forming a stable family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a stable family structure, bloodline inheritance is clearer, which can encourage fathers to be more actively involved in family and parenting responsibilities. With the father&#39;s active participation, the child&#39;s survival probability is higher, a stable parent-child relationship is formed, and the child can be with the child for a longer period of time. As a role in this pole of civilization, knowledge that requires longer education and accumulation, including hunting, martial arts, farming, and even a large amount of &quot;tacit knowledge&quot; such as managing a tribe, will be taught to students in the original &quot;family learning&quot; way. child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To borrow the terminology of the Austrian school of economics, the emergence of the father&#39;s role and the dual family, as well as the imagination of the patrilineal ancestral community formed on this basis, are actually the product of super overcoming time preference. In an era without father figures, people consider the time dimension more briefly and often make judgments based on moments or short-term passions. The emergence of the role of fathers and the continuation of stable families and families have made the lines of time extremely long, and people&#39;s investment and gaming models also tend to consider the longer future. At this point, savings become more valuable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People saved grain and raised livestock instead of consuming it immediately. Through savings, children can obtain stable property inheritance. The continuation of private property allows people to &quot;have perseverance and perseverance&quot;, overcome time preference, and develop the virtue of accumulating the future. Whether it&#39;s working hard to save wealth, or doing good deeds to build a family&#39;s reputation, these are the foundations of civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blood relationship between children and their mothers is natural and does not need to be demonstrated through cultural imagination, but the father is a product of cultural construction and imagination. To imagine community through &quot;patrilineal&quot; requires both the ability to imagine beyond time and abstract cultural construction. Through this model, people who were destined to forget each other in the past can be formed into an imaginary community, creating a close division of labor and collaboration. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Patriline and Aristocracy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Once this kind of family organization is produced, it is destined to have an extremely powerful advantage among the scattered people everywhere who &quot;know their mother but not their father&quot;. Many archaeological materials can show that the first to establish a stable dual family order was the earliest aristocratic class. Not only did they create the means of imagining and sustaining community through the patriline, but they also created the earliest surnames. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;生&quot; in &quot;surname&quot; is a phonetic symbol. The ancient sound of the word &quot;surname&quot; is in the heart mugeng part, and the archaic sound of the word &quot;生&quot; is in the birth mothergeng part. The dental sounds overlap and the pronunciation is basically the same. Therefore, the word &quot;surname&quot; is not interpreted literally as &quot;born by a woman, representing the maternal line.&quot; The &quot;female&quot; is only used to label women in the paternal family, and &quot;surname&quot; is used for men in the family. The &quot;生&quot; in the surname is just a phonetic symbol, and the &quot;surname&quot; is just a function of distinguishing between patrilineal families with the same origin and non-intermarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paternal surname creates a long family tree, which can connect different distant family branches, forming a greater ability to mobilize and cooperate. Therefore, it can be seen that early nobles often prohibited civilians from establishing surnames and did not allow them to establish family trees. For example, in ancient Hawaii, &quot;ordinary civilians were not allowed to record their lineages, and they were prohibited from approaching the supreme chief who was a professional person who recorded the noble lineage. This made the chief and the A sharp separation line was formed between civilians&quot; (Chen Chun: &quot;Exploring the Origins of Civilization and Early States: A Comparison of Chinese and Foreign Theories, Methods and Research&quot;, Shanghai Bookstore Press, 2007, p. 246). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The aristocrats and civilians in the Shang Dynasty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From an archaeological point of view, many people in the early days did not have stable paired families, and it was a common phenomenon to not know their mother but their father. For example, in tomb K82.5 at the Wajiaping site of Lintao of the Qijia Culture, an adult woman was buried with a baby under her breast, and the remains of a seven or eight-year-old child. The Qinghai Minhe Lajia F4 abandoned house burial tomb of the Qijia Culture also contains a single woman buried with a child in her arms (Li Xinwei: &quot;Rediscussing the Abandoned House Burial in Prehistoric Period&quot;, &quot;Archaeology&quot; 2007 Issue 5, No. Pages 50-56). These single mothers buried alone with their children are a vivid portrayal of the early era of &quot;knowing your mother but not knowing your father&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Xiajiadian Dadianzi tombs, there are no couples buried together, and mothers and young children are often buried together. For example, in tomb M30, a mother was buried with two young children, and in M205, a mother was buried with a child. Young children were buried together, M358 was buried with a mother and a child, M675 was buried with a mother and children, M787 was buried with a mother and two infants, and M1246 was buried with a young child (Institute of Archeology, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences: &quot;Dadianzi: Lower Xiajiadian Cultural Sites and Cemetery&quot; Excavation Report&quot;, Science Press, 1998, pp. 228-231). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the ancient sarcophagus burials of southwestern Yi, there are also tombs in which couples are buried together (Luo Kaiyu: &quot;Research on Sarcophagus Tombs in Western Sichuan and Yunnan and Eastern Tibet&quot;, &quot;Acta Archeology&quot;, Issue 4, 1992, p. 426 ). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering early civilization, nobles had stable couples buried together, but civilians still did not have stable couples buried together.如殷墟大司空M303、M225夫妻墓东西并排，相距2米，并排合葬，均为殷墟四期，上层有夯土建筑共压（中国社会科学院考古研究所安阳工作队：《殷墟大司空M303发掘报告》，《考古学报》2008年3期，第388页），这一贵族墓葬，有明确对偶关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孟宪武指出，殷墟有三分之二的墓主生前没有法定配偶，真正一夫一妻的家庭不多，多数人还过着不稳定的对偶婚和乱婚状态，所以死后没有专一配偶一起埋葬（孟宪武：《殷墟南区墓葬发掘综述》，《中原文物》1986年3期，第80页）。也有学者指出，稳定对偶婚姻“异穴合葬”的现象在殷墟并不多见，整个先秦时期都是以男、女单身葬为主要埋葬方式（杨宝成：《殷墟文化研究》，武汉大学出版社，2002年，第80-83页）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这些综合来看，商代平民阶层仍然主要是过着没有稳定对偶婚的状态，而贵族阶层则显示出较为稳定的对偶家庭。换言之，商代贵族家庭是有清晰“父亲”这个角色的。 《史记•殷本纪》中的商王家族谱系，以及甲骨卜辞中所呈现的商王家族谱系，乃至甲骨中所见其他的贵族家谱迹象，如著名的“商三句兵”家谱铭文等，都显示出当时贵族以父系这一文化想象的方式构建共同体组织的能力。虽然当时古老氏族社会的联系尚未完全解体，甲骨卜辞中商王家族子弟将生父的同辈兄弟，即叔伯们也都称“父”和诸父。此外，殷墟的商王与王后也是分别埋葬在各自不同的家族墓地中，“这大概与氏族的血缘纽带尚未完全解体有关”（中国社会科学院考古研究所安阳工作队：《1976年安阳小屯西北地发掘简报》，《考古》1987年4期，第374页）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但无论如何，商王室和其他贵族家族中，其实都是能明确各自的生父，且越往后越是以父死子继为主，兄终弟及的情况在减少。而祭祀中，对于亲生父亲的祭祀也更为隆重。这也就表明，商代王室、贵族阶层文化中“父亲”的角色变得越发清晰，而与之相对的则是面目模糊的平民阶层，其中主流的生存处境仍是知母不知父。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;周文明与孔子&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;到了周代，平民阶层的情况变化不大，而贵族阶层的文明程度则进一步演化提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时所谓“礼不下庶人”，即贵族阶层通过文明的“礼”，保持着父亲和稳定对偶婚家庭结构，而平民阶层则继续知母不知父。如山西临猗程村晋墓，第三等级的平民墓中，极少发现夫妇并穴合葬墓。 “这说明夫妇并穴合葬这种葬俗并没有在较低的社会阶层中流行”（中国社会科学院考古研究所等：《临猗程村墓地》，中国大百科全书出版社，2003年，第258页）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学者指出，相比于商代，周代贵族的夫妇合葬墓情况更为普遍（张明东：《商周时期合葬墓的考察》，《古代文明》第7卷，文物出版社，2008年，第185页）。这也表明，随着礼乐文明的发育，“礼”所承载的文明成果，更普遍地覆盖了当时贵族阶层的家庭，稳定而明确的对偶婚姻，以及父亲的角色，是周代文明进一步发育的重要成果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一背景其实也有助于更深刻地理解，为何自幼丧父的孔子，要在母亲颜徵在去世之后，先在五父之衢大张旗鼓行殡礼，然后将她埋葬到防山，与父亲合葬（《史记•孔子世家》）。因为通过这一行为，才能公开展现自己是贵族孔氏的孩子，不是没有父亲的“野人”阶层，而是有明确父母合葬墓的低级贵族——士。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为孤儿，孔子从未见过自己的父亲。实际对他影响最大的，恰恰是自然血脉联系的母家，即姥爷颜襄、母亲颜徵在这些母家人。孔子的学生中，有“孔门八颜”，即颜路、颜回、颜幸、颜高、颜祖、颜之仆、颜哙、颜何。其中颜路很可能是他母亲的侄儿，即孔子的母家表兄弟，而颜回作为颜路之子，也就是孔子在母家的侄儿。孔子对颜回的感情，很多时候也是与母家的深厚情感交织在一起，而颜回也将孔子视为父亲一样亲近的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从自然情感而言，孔子其实和母家人关系最为密切，但他深知文明阶层不能只知其“质”，不知其“文”。 “尔爱其羊我爱其礼”，父亲虽然遥远，但却是礼和文明的象征。如果没有父亲这一符号，他将停留在知母不知父的这一层次。因此，孔子选择了公开将母亲与父亲合葬，宣示了自己是陬邑大夫叔梁纥的继承者，并继承和延续了父亲的“孔”氏。父系想象共同体的渊源，也因此可以追溯到古代宋国君主，乃至更为遥远的商王室，并一直追溯到古老神话时代的帝喾等人物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔子的认祖归宗，恰恰打开了一条鼓励平民阶层模仿贵族，走出知母不知父，而像贵族一样建立明确父亲家庭的道路。孔门不但大量招收平民精英子弟，而且向他们传播贵族知识，后世之儒也鼓励平民学礼，成为文明人，成为合格的父亲，模仿贵族建立姓氏和家谱、家庙。对父亲符号的确立与认同，便是跃向文明的重要跳板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;小共同体与私有产权&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;通过明确父亲角色和家庭的文化构建，进而为共同体和私有财产的发展提供了积累的基础。家庭是私有产权的基础，私有产权又是文明的重要基石。只有在这个基石之上，储蓄和发展未来才是有意义的。正是在私有产权的基础之上，“爱有差等”的原则才能发挥出不同圈层共同体的交互作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;私有产权其实并不是杨朱那种原子个体理解的“私”。在私有产权社会，在家庭内部，实行的其实还是各种形式的财产共有。西欧传统的长子继承制，保留了家族财产的完整，虽然次子只能领取兄长提供的年金，或甚至没有财产只能外出闯天下。但家族的财产，也并不是长子这个原子个体的“私有”，而是在祖先、后代这个血脉共同体之间的代管人，因此财产仍然是属于共同体的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与之相比，中国人更倾向于分产，诸子之外，宋代法律中“女得合男之半”，女儿也能得到继承家产的权利。儒者一方面鼓励不分家，形成更多层次财产分布的宗族共同体，或通过建立“范氏义庄”一类的家族共同财产信托，以及华南地区常见的“族田”“祭田”“学田”之类，保有多种形式的小共同体共有财产。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;私有产权的含义，主要是面对代表大共同体的公权时，要具备的防卫机制。即不能以大共同体或陌生人社会的各种名义，去侵害家庭、家族之类的小共同体财产权。私有产权面对公权，体现为“私”，而在小共同体内部，却又多呈现为各种温情脉脉的“公”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使是被一些人诟病的英国维多利亚时代，在市场经济和工业化高度发展的同时，家庭价值仍然坚挺，是提供温暖和逃避社会残酷的港湾。约翰•潘恩（John Howard Payne）在1822年所作那首《家、甜蜜的家》，在英语世界流行了一百多年，其中唱道：“家，家，甜蜜、甜蜜的家！天下没有比家更好的地方”。这首歌的流行，恰恰表明当时市场经济的高度发展，并没有摧毁家庭价值，反而更加凸显了家庭作为小共同体之“私”，对保护人们的积极作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;市场经济的发育&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;私有产权的基础之上，尤其是随着工商业经济的进一步发展，各地陌生人之间就需要丰富的交流合作。而这时，以私有产权为基础的市场经济便得以孕育发展，通过以财产权为基础的多种博弈、合作等商业模式，实现复杂社会中陌生人之间进行合作的最低成本方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由市场经济中，各种不同小共同体之间更有效地进行分工协作。随着市场秩序的扩大，所吸纳群体的进一步增多，分工也得到不断细化，效率上升而成本降低，形成正和博弈效应，人们得以共同受益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在市场经济的协作模式下，人们也学会以超出传统小共同体的方式进行交易与协作。随着生活的提升与商品的丰富，让更多普通人能够低成本有机会接触到过去精英的文化、艺术。米塞斯（Ludwig von Mises）谈到：“如果需要论证的话，只需要指出严肃音乐在过去几十年里如何变得流行起来，尤其是在那些在生意场上忙得团团转的人中间流行起来就够了。历史上从未有过这样一个时代，使艺术如此接近这么多人的心灵”（[奥]路德维希•冯•米塞斯：《社会主义：经济与社会学分析》，王建民等译，中国社会科学出版社，2008年，第406页）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去的中国，古典书籍极其昂贵，文献中多有“家贫无书”的记载。 《北齐书•杜弼传》中，其祖父为淮南太守，父亲为县令，但仍然“家贫无书”。 《颜氏家训•勉学》中就专门强调，“若能常保数百卷书，千载终不为小人”，只要家庭能保有一些珍贵的书籍，就不会发生阶层跌落，而是能一直维持在精英阶层。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是随着进入宋代，市场经济的推动下，商业刻书开始崛起和兴盛，高高在上的古典书籍开始大量进入普通人的生活。苏东坡就提到：“余犹及见老儒先生，自言其少时，欲求《史记》《汉书》而不可得。幸而得之，皆手自书，日夜诵读，惟恐不及。近岁市人转相摹刻诸子百家之书，日传万纸学者之于书，多且易致”（《李氏山房藏书记》）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此，正是因为“市人”们在商业利益的推动下“转相摹刻”，引起了古典书籍的迅速普及，古典书籍大量进入了普通人的世界。在过去的欧洲，斯多葛学派的书籍与洛可可艺术，都仅限于数量有限的贵族精英，普通平民难以企及。但随着市场经济和工业化的发育，生产成本极大降低，普通工人也可以在家中悬挂一幅达芬奇或梵高画作的印刷品，或者收藏一部工业生产的古典书籍。市场经济让过去高高在上的贵族文化、精英礼乐，得以更为高效地进入普通人的家庭与生活，提升着文明社会的平均水位线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以说，从历史发生学与自然进化史的角度看，稳定对偶家庭、（文化意义上的）“父亲”角色的产生与婚姻制度，以及在此基础之上产生的私有产权、市场经济，正是孕育出文明社会的两大基石。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列外交人员家属遇袭，北京警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258597]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 20:54:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At about 14:00 on October 13, 2023, in front of a supermarket in Zuojiazhuang, Chaoyang District , a family member of an Israeli diplomat (male, 50 years old) was stabbed by a foreigner. At present, the suspect has been captured by the police. After preliminary examination, it was found that the foreign criminal suspect (male, 53 years old) was engaged in small commodity business in Beijing. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉大学通报学生图书馆性骚扰事件：给予涉事学生记过处分]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258595]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 20:25:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Handling notification&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After investigation and verification, according to According to relevant regulations, the school has studied and decided to give Xiao Moumou, an undergraduate student in the class of 2022, a demerit penalty. Wuhan University has always had zero tolerance for violations of regulations and disciplines, and will never tolerate them once verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Student Affairs Department October 13, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/ Gtii9ysi2Cdi475BuHJgMcWWVKlirT5IQXF4rwc2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1815&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/Gtii9ysi2Cdi475BuHJgMcWWVKlirT5IQXF4rwc 2.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;254048&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西方军火商为何纷纷将亚洲总部迁至日本？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/13/X9yJZc2fwfFQxD6fjp3XeeU0ncr0aG0plnBPa7b4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1140&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/X9yJZc2fwfFQxD6fjp3XeeU 0ncr0aG0plnBPa7b4. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, according to People&#39;s Daily Online, many large Western weapons suppliers recently announced that they would move their Asian headquarters to Japan. Japan has also high-profilely promoted its equipment in the United States and its allies. The role of logistics support. Foreign media said that the measures taken by Western military industrial groups are almost synchronized with the introduction of Japan&#39;s defense budget for the next five years, and they intend to prepare in advance within the framework of a quasi-alliance and cut the budget &quot;cake&quot; to the maximum extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, British Aerospace Systems has established close ties with Japan and plans to move its Asia-Pacific headquarters from Malaysia to Japan within the year to prepare to supply Patriot PAC-3 missile defense systems to Japan. France&#39;s Thales will cooperate with Japan&#39;s Mitsubishi Heavy Industries to develop and produce equipment such as mine detectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the combined influence of commercial and political factors, Japan suddenly became a &quot;hot potato&quot; sought after by arms dealers in the United States, Britain and France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent times, the United States has frequently held offensive and defensive exercises with Japan, South Korea, and Australia, which has made the situation on the Korean Peninsula, Taiwan Strait, and South China Sea tense in Northeast Asia. Western arms dealers have a keen sense of smell. On the one hand, they are concerned about changes in the geopolitical situation, and on the other hand, they also fancy the business opportunities brought by Japan&#39;s substantial increase in defense spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that as tensions in Northeast Asia escalate and Japan increases its defense spending, the changes made by these arms giants in order to cooperate with Japan&#39;s major adjustments to its defense strategy indicate that Japan hopes to further achieve cooperation with the United States and Europe. &quot;Military binding&quot; supports its ambition to expand its military power. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Opportunity to take advantage of&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Western arms dealers have moved their Asia-Pacific headquarters to Japan, selling arms nearby, and launching &quot;face-to-face&quot; in-depth cooperation with Japan , a win-win situation can be achieved. From a deeper analysis, this is the reason why the United States uses Japan and Japan hopes to &quot;borrow ships to go to sea.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Biden administration has established many &quot;small circles&quot; in the hope of using, controlling and arming allies. Through the research and development of various advanced weapons and equipment, frequent military exercises with deterrence and actual combat significance, fighting &quot;proxy wars&quot;, testing the effectiveness of weapons and equipment and strategies and tactics, making huge fortunes by promoting arms, creating conflicts and conflicts, undermining regional stability, and maintaining it. In the global hegemonic position, it achieves the goal of &quot;killing many birds with one stone&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with Japan, South Korea, Australia, and the Philippines do not have advantages in military and technology. The United States&#39; selection and use of Japan is also &quot;a no-brainer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the Korean War and the Vietnam War, Western arms dealers had a history of moving their Asian defense contractor headquarters to Japan, allowing Japan to reap the benefits of its rapid economic rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the outbreak of the Vietnam War, Japan&#39;s heavy industry restarted. As Japan is the rear area for US military war supplies, a large number of orders for military supplies continue to fall on Japan&#39;s military production lines. Mitsubishi Heavy Industries is a long-established military industrial enterprise of Japanese manufacturers. It has a complete production line of F-4 fighter jets. The F-4 Phantom fighter jets it produces have played a huge role as the main fighter aircraft of the U.S. Navy and Air Force, helping the U.S. military win 277 wars. The victory helped the US military save some face in the Vietnam battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the United States still wants to use Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of the Cold War, European arms dealers basically did not develop much. Therefore, European countries are also optimistic about Japan&#39;s funds and technology. At the same time, Japan also hopes to develop weapons and equipment instead of just relying on the United States. Before this, it was difficult for the United States to allow Japan to extend its olive branch to other countries in the research and development of weapons and equipment, especially heavy weapons and equipment. Now, the United States is opening up and hopes to arm Japan and allow Japan to provide assistance to the United States in the Western Pacific. assume more defensive obligations. Therefore, after the United States gave the green light, Japan and European countries moved forward in cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Japan’s security strategy has shifted from self-defense to auxiliary offense. At the end of 2022, Japan adjusted its security strategy. From the so-called self-defense in the past to the current auxiliary offense, it is expanding its military preparations in all aspects. Whether it is technology, funding, or procurement, Japan&#39;s own military production capacity alone is obviously not enough. . Therefore, Japan&#39;s turning its attention to European countries also reflects changes in its security strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There is money to be made”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 27, 2023, “Nikkei Asia” reported that “the world’s largest defense contractors Businesses are transferring their business operations in Asia to Japan, because in the face of the deteriorating security situation in East Asia, Japan is preparing to significantly increase defense expenses.&quot; Japan&#39;s &quot;business&quot; with Western arms dealers is conducive to dividing the cake and achieving strong alliances. , each takes what he needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From fiscal year 2023 to 2027, Japan’s total defense budget will reach 43 trillion yen, 1.6 times that of the previous five years. The latest defense budget finalized by the Japanese Ministry of Defense for 2024 has reached 7.7 trillion yen, equivalent to more than 380 billion yuan, once again setting a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, 900 billion yen will be used to purchase various ammunition and weapons and equipment, including new ship-to-air missiles and long-range cruise missiles. For example: the mass production costs of the &quot;performance-enhanced version&quot; of the Ground Self-Defense Force&#39;s Type 12 land-based anti-ship missile with a range extending to about 1,000 kilometers, and the production costs of &quot;high-speed gliding missiles&quot; used to defend islands such as the Southwest Islands. In addition, there are 64 billion yen for a new generation fighter aircraft project jointly carried out by Britain, Japan and Italy, and 75 billion yen for a new anti-missile interceptor jointly developed by the United States and Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Japan held the largest international defense exhibition, attracting more than 250 arms companies from more than 60 countries and regions. European and American companies participating in the exhibition have shown great interest in the Japanese market. The Japanese government has planned to allocate more than 200 billion yen to purchase approximately 400 Tomahawk cruise missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan plans to deploy two Aegis system carrier ships by 2028, establish a new permanent &quot;unified headquarters&quot; in Tokyo Ichigaya, and uniformly command the three self-defense forces of land, sea and air; purchase long-range missiles and improve the Aegis system Carrier ships; develop new fields such as drones, space and the Internet, and ammunition support to improve sustained combat capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kishida government&#39;s sharp increase in defense expenses has allowed European and American arms dealers to smell business opportunities. Behind the increase in Japan&#39;s military expenditures, it reflects that Japan and the United States have cooperated more frequently at the strategic and tactical levels in recent years. This is reflected in the fact that the US-Japan alliance is undergoing subtle and profound changes. The alliance system has gradually changed from the past &quot;American master and Japanese slave&quot;. Shifting to &quot;US-Japan coordination&quot; means that the United States needs Japan to step up to the forefront in a series of regional disputes, including regional hotspot issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relocation of Western arms dealers to Japan may further fuel Japan&#39;s maritime ambitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has proposed that it should shift from the past &quot;marine defense governance&quot; to &quot;marine defense governance&quot;. Japan&#39;s ambition to become a maritime power is fully reflected in each phase of the basic marine plan. In addition, Japan plans to launch a series of maritime security assistance and increase strategic attention to Indo-Pacific countries, which will also bring certain complexity to the regional situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s ambition has always been demonstrated. Today, Japan plans to build the so-called largest warship after World War II - a modern version of the &quot;Yamato&quot; ship, which is 1.7 times the size of the U.S. Burke destroyer and exceeds the average tonnage of U.S. combat ships in terms of displacement and comprehensive combat power. This also shows that Japan can achieve great progress and development in its ocean strategy and offensive strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of weapons and equipment configuration, the United States’ Standard 6 (SM-6) air defense missiles will be used on this ship, and Japan’s air defense and anti-missile capabilities will be further improved. If the &quot;Yamato&quot; ship is equipped with a ground-attack version of the Type 12 anti-ship missile, its range can reach 1,000 kilometers. Japan&#39;s future maritime platforms will have powerful ground attack capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s military spending is rising and it wants to expand its military preparations. Western arms dealers see business opportunities and flock to them. Fundamentally speaking, this will allow the United States to better utilize and control Japan with the help of arms dealers and maintain the United States in the &quot;Indo-Pacific&quot; regional” and even global hegemony. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Japan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Arms Upgrading&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan has introduced the core business of the Western military industry and is also trying to intentionally introduce Western technology into its own arms production chain. middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 28, the Japan Defense Equipment Agency issued the &quot;Defense Technology Guidelines 2023&quot;, reaffirming the strategy of &quot;building a nation through scientific and technological innovation&quot;, focusing on strengthening defense capabilities and developing weapons and equipment that are ahead of other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, within 5 to 10 years, Japan will produce weapons directly related to future combat methods, and after 10 years, it will realize the equipment of important technologies. Japan has listed 12 key technologies such as unmanned technology, new energy, new materials, instant communications and data processing as pillar technologies for the future defense industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Japanese military-industrial complex giant said that the entry of Western arms companies will increase the number of orders from small and medium-sized parts suppliers. There are currently 1,100 companies engaged in the production of fighter jet parts, 1,300 companies engaged in the production of tank parts, and 830 companies engaged in the production of warship parts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has reached an agreement with the United Kingdom and Italy to jointly develop sixth-generation fighter aircraft, and recently jointly developed high-performance missiles with the United States for intercepting hypersonic weapons. Companies established in the UK, France, Italy and other countries plan to increase the number of employees and will mainly recruit local Japanese personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The American L3 Harris Technology Company is an aerospace company in the United States. It has begun negotiations with the Japanese Ministry of Defense on cooperation in drones and other fields, which provides a favorable opportunity for Japan to improve its military production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the support of European and American arms dealers, Japan follows or coordinates with the United States and the West. During this sensitive period, Japan&#39;s defense budget is also increasing year by year. If this continues, Japan will fall into an endless cycle of arms race, which will bring serious danger to the regional situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another situation is that in order to make money, Western arms dealers may use the power of capital to bribe Japanese media, add fuel to the flames, and deliberately create conflicts. Western arms dealers have moved their Asian headquarters to Japan to cooperate with Japan in military research and development and sales. The Japanese government claims that the purchase of weapons and ammunition is a &quot;defensive measure.&quot; If the United States, the West and Japan intervene in hot geopolitical issues through arms exports, it will provoke conflicts and confrontations among relevant countries and make the situation in the Asia-Pacific region even more tense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, six European and American arms dealers have moved to Japan and signed an agreement to &quot;carry out large-scale arms modifications in Japan&quot;. They are suspected of shifting arms to prepare for war, making it easier for Japan to obtain offensive weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan plans to rely on its military cooperation with the United States to gradually realize its so-called military ambitions in the context of great power competition and the Indo-Pacific strategy. Once the devil of militarism is released from its cage, it will have , the impact on the world will further increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the United States openly and covertly supports Japan to increase its defense budget. Japan&#39;s past &quot;exclusive defense&quot; has turned to &quot;active defense&quot; and it emphasizes the ability to attack enemy bases. The United States has adopted an attitude of encouragement and even support. Under this general premise, it is possible that the regional arms race will become more and more unfavorable, which is also caused by the United States and Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一观众从三楼看展坠亡，广东美术馆通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 19:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Situation Briefing&lt;/strong>;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 8, Ms. Yang, a visitor, visited the Guangdong Museum of Art and accidentally fell from Exhibition Hall 12 on the third floor of our museum to Exhibition Hall 6 on the second floor at around 11:50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, our library immediately activated the emergency plan and quickly dialed 120 emergency hotline and 110 police hotline. At around 12 o&#39;clock, emergency personnel arrived at the scene for rescue. At around 12:25, Ms. Yang unfortunately passed away after rescue efforts failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By accessing the on-site surveillance video, listening to the statements of eyewitnesses and surveying the scene of the incident, it was found that before the incident, the spectator was holding a SLR camera, crossed the warning protection rope set up in Hall 12, and fell from the guardrail to 2 In the No. 6 exhibition hall of the building, there were shoe prints left on the guardrail platform. It was initially determined that the audience had an accident while looking for a shooting angle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our museum is deeply saddened and sorry for the unfortunate death of Ms. Yang, and expresses deep condolences to her family. Next, our library will continue to fully cooperate with the public security organs and the family members of the deceased in the investigation and aftermath. At the same time, we will further strengthen safety management and actively perform our duties as public cultural venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Guangdong Museum of Art&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>; October 13, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[银行经营策略转向：贷款倾向制造业，“商投行”一体化加速]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258550]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When the real estate and related industries are sluggish or even risky, commercial banks facing interest rate pressure, How to adjust your own business strategy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By comparing the mid-term and annual report data of 20 listed banks vertically and horizontally in the past three years, and combined with the relevant information disclosed in their 2023 interim results conference and exchange meetings, a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center The study found that in recent years, 20 commercial banks have been intensively adjusting their business strategies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of credit investment, 20 commercial banks are gradually shifting from leasing and real estate to the real economy, focusing on manufacturing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investment business has become the focus of the investment business of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks in recent years, and has achieved certain results. The integrated development strategy of &quot;commercial and investment banking&quot; is progressing steadily, and the benefits of investment-loan linkage are gradually reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strategic &quot;digital transformation&quot; of commercial banks has begun to shift from &quot;quantitative growth&quot; to &quot;qualitative improvement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Loans tend to be in the manufacturing and technology industries&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sorted out the 2023 interim results conferences, 2023 interim results conferences of 20 commercial banks The interim report and 2022 annual report found that 20 commercial banks all mentioned in the 2022 annual report the strategy of benefiting the real economy and providing financial support for manufacturing and national key areas. This strategy was emphasized again in the 2023 interim reports of each bank: each bank has proposed the goal of continuing to improve the quality and efficiency of serving the real economy in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the analysis of the distribution of corporate loan industries disclosed by 20 commercial banks in the 2022 interim report and the 2023 interim report, the above strategies mentioned by each bank in the 2022 annual report have achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The year-on-year growth rates of corporate loan balances in the national key strategic fields of manufacturing and technology services were 25.02% and 64.35% respectively. Judging from the absolute value of corporate loan balances, in the first half of 2023, the loan balance of manufacturing companies in 20 commercial banks reached 15.86 trillion yuan, becoming the industry with the highest corporate loan balance, surpassing companies in the leasing and business services industry with 15.35 trillion yuan. Loan balance. The industry with the highest corporate loan balance in the first half of 2022 is the leasing and business services industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that within one year, the credit structure of commercial banks has changed from the original &quot;three pillars&quot; of leasing, real estate and manufacturing to a model dominated by manufacturing. This also echoes China’s current economic form in which the old triangular cycle of “real estate, infrastructure, and finance” is moving to the new triangular cycle of “technology, industry, and finance.” At the same time, this also reflects the current new phenomenon of bank funds flowing into the real economy and supporting the development of manufacturing, scientific research and technical service industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/N9oJ5kvONawBpMQ3lLRpiKdDJJ8PVPk9WsUhQisL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height= &quot;1352&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/N9oJ5kvONawBpMQ3lLRpiKdDJJ8PVPk9WsUhQisL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main force that tilts credit towards the manufacturing industry is There are five major state-owned banks: industry, agriculture, China, construction, and diplomatic relations. In the first half of 2023, the total loan balance of manufacturing companies from the five major state-owned banks was 10.84 trillion yuan, accounting for 68.36% of the total loan balance of manufacturing companies from 20 banks. The three joint-stock banks Industrial Bank, China Merchants Bank and Shanghai Pudong Development Bank followed the five major state-owned banks with loan balances of manufacturing companies of 669.412 billion yuan, 549.976 billion yuan and 542.672 billion yuan respectively, higher than the Postal Savings Bank&#39;s manufacturing company loans of 495.732 billion yuan. Corporate loan balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also found that loans to companies in the scientific research and technical service industries have gradually become areas of concern for joint-stock banks and city commercial banks, which may be related to the misaligned competition strategy of state-owned banks. Among them, state-owned banks and some joint-stock banks did not disclose this balance. Among the city commercial banks, Bank of Shanghai did not disclose this balance in its 2022 interim report. However, from the 2022 annual report to the 2023 interim report, the bank disclosed it. the balance of this loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In absolute terms, in the first half of 2023, Industrial Bank and Shanghai Pudong Development Bank had the highest balances, at 36.536 billion yuan and 32.944 billion yuan respectively. In terms of year-on-year growth rates, Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Beijing have the highest year-on-year growth rates, 92.67% and 83.11% respectively. It can be seen that joint-stock banks are the main lenders in this industry, while city commercial banks are gradually paying more and more attention to this field. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Investment business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;becomes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;an important growth point&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As the loan business turns, 20 The bank is developing its investment banking business, financial market business and “commercial investment banking” integration strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center sorted out the 2023 interim reports of 20 banks, their interim results conferences and investor exchange meetings and found that most banks mentioned strengthening investment banking business and financial markets. sector and build an integrated development strategy of “commercial and investment banking”. From the analysis of the bank&#39;s revenue structure and asset structure in recent years, this strategy has achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For financial investment business, the three indicators of investment income, net income from changes in fair value and net exchange income are particularly important, and the three indicators are highly correlated. In order to explore the actual benefits of various banks&#39; strengthening financial investment business strategies, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center conducted statistics on the sum of the above three indicators as a proportion of revenue for 20 banks in the past three years. Statistics show that, regardless of whether it is a state-owned bank, a joint-stock bank or a city commercial bank, the ratio is on the rise, and the upward trend is the most obvious for city commercial banks. With traditional credit business unable to take advantage, city commercial banks are using investment business as a breakthrough point to expand their balance sheets. Take the Bank of Nanjing, which was shortlisted for China&#39;s systemically important banks for the first time on September 22, 2023, as an example. In the first half of 2023, the bank&#39;s three income indicators accounted for 32.15% of its revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/Ofc6345KnFX3DOnrAT9TLvvgUBlY7MNjsr8GXJAv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;796&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/Ofc6345KnFX3DOnrAT9TLvvgUBlY7MNjsr8GXJAv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HV5COF9Saq3kPHkt94b31busBbhVHgCZjn2Wv1V6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height=&quot;1852&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/13/HV5COF9Saq3kPHkt94b31busBbhVHgCZjn2Wv1V6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the above three income indicators are highly correlated with trading financial assets. In recent years, the proportion of trading financial assets to total assets of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has also shown a growth trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/RKL1YucI0TOTVGgvItL317nTxA6jNIjeJJ9bYVcj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;796&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/RKL1YucI0TOTVGgvItL317nTxA6jNIjeJJ9bYVcj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the 2023 Interim Report of Bank of Nanjing, 2022 According to data from the interim report, 2022 annual report, 2021 annual report and 2020 annual report, at the end of June 2023, the end of December 2022 and the end of December 2021, the year-on-year growth rates of its trading financial assets were 40.32%, 39.28% and 77.41%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to conduct an in-depth analysis of the composition of each bank’s investment business, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sorted out the trading transactions disclosed in the 2023 interim reports of the five banks with the highest three income ratios among the 20 banks. Financial asset data. According to statistics, the largest trading financial assets of these banks are funds, followed by bonds or asset management trust plans. The funds invested by commercial banks are generally bond funds and currency funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By studying the types of bond funds invested by banks, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that some banks’ bond investment strategies are to purchase fixed-term bond funds issued by the bank’s fund management subsidiaries. This strategy may have the effect of reducing bond investment costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Industrial Bank as an example. According to the 2023 interim report disclosed by the fund products issued by Industrial Fund, the bank holds the Industrial Jiarong one-year regular open bond-type initiative issued by its subsidiary Industrial Fund Management Co., Ltd. The shares of securities investment funds and Industrial Jiafu one-year regular open bond-type sponsored securities investment funds are 99.87% and 99.88% respectively. According to Article 2 of the &quot;Notice of the Ministry of Finance and the State Administration of Taxation on Certain Preferential Policies for Enterprise Income Tax&quot;, the income obtained by securities investment funds from the securities market includes income from price differences from buying and selling stocks and bonds, dividends and bonus income from equity, and income from bonds. Interest income and other income are not subject to corporate income tax for the time being. That is to say, compared with direct investment in financial bonds, banks can be exempted from paying 25% income tax if they invest indirectly in financial bonds through fixed-term debt funds, thus reducing investment costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the debt investment subjects of direct investment bonds, 10 of the 12 commercial banks (only 12 of the 20 commercial banks disclosed this data in their 2023 interim reports) maintained year-on-year growth increase. Among them, the two banks with year-on-year decreases were Bank of Nanjing and Ping An Bank. Although the amount of debt investment of these two banks decreased by 11.49% and 1.96% year-on-year, their trading financial assets increased by 40.32% and 17.81% year-on-year, and the proportion of funds and bonds among their trading financial assets was relatively high. The increase in the total amount of bonds in the debt base or trading financial assets is sufficient to cover the year-on-year decrease in the bond investment account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, whether it is direct investment in bonds or indirect investment in bond funds, the financial investment business targets of various banks are mainly bonds. Judging from the overall scale and income level, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks are indeed still in the established strategy of strengthening investment business, and this strategy has also achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investment banking business of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has also improved in the past two years. Take Industrial Bank and Bank of Nanjing as examples. According to the 2022 bond underwriting rankings of the wind database, Industrial Bank ranks 6th with a total underwriting amount of 947.746 billion yuan. The top five are Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Bank of Communications. State-owned banks. Bank of Nanjing ranked 14th with 284.505 billion yuan. As of September 27, 2023, the 2023 bond underwriting rankings of the wind database show that Industrial Bank ranked fifth with a total underwriting amount of 798.374 billion yuan, surpassing Bank of Communications. Bank of Nanjing moved up one place to 13th place with a total underwriting amount of 273.62 billion yuan. Therefore, judging from the changes in the amount and ranking of the above two banks, the bond underwriting strength of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has indeed improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysis of the bank&#39;s bond underwriting business found that the bank&#39;s investment banking business strategy and credit business strategy are similar, and the overall flow of funds shows the flow of funds to national key areas such as science and technology innovation and green, achieving the effect of investment and loan linkage. Take Industrial Bank as an example. According to the bank&#39;s 2023 interim report, the scale of its underwriting of debt financing instruments for green non-financial enterprises reached 13.72 billion yuan, ranking first among joint-stock banks, and it has launched its first science and technology REITs business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of income, investment business is a more important growth point for various banks. Each bank may achieve the goal of stable balance sheet expansion through the strategy of continuing to increase the proportion of this business. However, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the above three income indicators are all related to trading financial assets, and the increase in trading financial assets will directly lead to an increase in risk-weighted assets, thereby reducing the core tier one capital adequacy ratio. Therefore, there is limited room to increase income through investment business. And&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314?source=147&amp;amp;source_1=238&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;The net profits of 20 banks account for more than 1/3 of A-shares,&quot; Wang&#39;s &quot;Fighting against the Increasing Differentiation of Interest Margin Pressure&quot; also mentioned that &quot;among the joint-stock banks, CITIC, Hua Xia and Zheshang Bank, their core tier one capital adequacy ratios are approaching regulatory red lines.&quot; Therefore, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that while vigorously developing investment-loan linkage strategies, banks should also pay attention to the tier-1 capital adequacy ratio and avoid blindly expanding their balance sheets, which could lead to regulatory red lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Abandon quantitative growth&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Digital transformation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Transform into quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While the linkage effect of investment and lending has emerged, the attitudes of various banks towards financial technology have changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the 2023 interim reports, interim results conferences and financial technology job recruitment information of 20 banks, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that in terms of digital transformation strategies, compared with previous years, funding And with the increase in human investment, all industries will pay more attention to quality presentation in 2023. According to China Financial News Network, judging from the recruitment situation in the autumn of 2023, the financial technology positions of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China have experienced a &quot;reduction in recruitment&quot; for the first time. According to data from the 2022 annual reports of the four major state-owned banks, the four banks of &quot;Industry, Agriculture, China, and Construction&quot; each have more than 10,000 technology employees, and the number of employees in financial technology positions has approached &quot;saturation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some banks’ capital investment in the financial technology field is also not as strong as in previous years. Among the 20 banks, only China Merchants Bank and Everbright Bank disclosed information technology investment data in the 2023 interim report, which were 5.206 billion yuan and 2.043 billion yuan respectively, a year-on-year decrease of 2.87% and 4.44%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in terms of quality improvement, various banks have provided many specific cases on the effectiveness of digital transformation. For example, ICBC completed the feasibility assessment of the application of quantum technology in scenarios such as bond investment portfolios and option pricing based on quantum simulators; China Merchants Bank used models to automatically review loans, and &quot;Zhaoqidai&quot; realized the entire process of corporate loans online, and customers The fastest time from application to loan disbursement is 0.5 working days; Ningbo Bank takes advantage of WeChat banking in reaching customers and product promotion, enriching voice, video and other service methods to provide customers with a more efficient and simpler financial service experience business process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can also be found through vertical quantitative comparison that compared with 2022, various banks have achieved more actual results in the field of financial technology and digital transformation. For example, as of the end of June 2023, ICBC has deepened the construction of an enterprise-level corporate digital operation and management platform, and the platform has reached more than 1.6 million customers; China Merchants Bank&#39;s &quot;AI Tips&quot; has served 11.7288 million users, a year-on-year increase of 140.84%; Bank of Beijing The &quot;Intelligent Strategy&quot; retail digital operation system has launched more than 1,200 strategies, reaching more than 170 million customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through quantitative horizontal comparison, it can be seen that ICBC’s digital transformation and technological capabilities are the best among the 20 banks. In terms of financial technology, as of the end of June 2023, ICBC had 1,878 new public patents, and the cumulative number of patent authorizations was 2,941, ranking first among its peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effects of technologies in various industries empowering the field of risk control are also more significant than before. Take the digitally empowered inclusive finance risk control system disclosed in ICBC’s 2023 interim report as an example. The report describes in detail the entire process of digital access, intelligent risk control, and online and offline cross-validation. Its non-performing rate has increased year-on-year. The decline also demonstrates the benefits of digital transformation. Among them, &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314?source=147&amp;amp;source_1=238&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;The net profits of 20 banks account for more than 1/3 of A-shares,&quot; &quot;Profit King&quot; Fights Increasing Differentiation Pressure on Interest Margins&quot; &lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>; has stated that &quot;in the first half of 2023, the non-performing loan ratios of 20 banks have almost all declined, and only Ping An Bank&#39;s non-performing loan ratio has increased. 1 BP.&quot; Bank of Beijing, whose non-performing ratio has dropped by 30 BP year-on-year, even emphasized the construction of a unified risk control platform in the digital transformation section of its official report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the above analysis that technology-enabled risk control, mobile banking and technology-enhanced investment strategies have achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the road to digital transformation is still long. Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recently found through actual measurements of different bank counter services and surveys of practitioners in different industries that most bank counter services still take a long time to process. Although robots and intelligent counters are placed at the entrance of every bank, in terms of customer experience, the robots are more like decorations, and the services that the intelligent counters can handle are also quite limited. The business process at the manual counter is quite complicated, and the waiting time for bank staff to operate is also long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that compared to the past, the current application of information technology in online business has been more extensive and is supported by actual data. If banks can increase the application of technology in the field of over-the-counter services, such as moving more over-the-counter services online, it may be able to reduce labor costs to a great extent and improve efficiency at the same time. In fact, some banks are already trying to take this step. Postal Savings Bank disclosed in its 2023 interim report that it is exploring digital operations and innovatively launching a &quot;cloud cabinet&quot; intensive operation model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子相亲后被诬强奸，五年方还清白：强加于己的巨大冤屈如何洗刷？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a retrial verdict has brought an old news back into public opinion. According to &quot;Dafeng News&quot;, Di, a native of Luannan, Hebei, who had been sentenced to three years in prison for rape, finally waited for a fair verdict from the court on October 10, 2023: The Tangshan Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled that &quot;the facts are unclear and the evidence is insufficient.&quot; &quot;The original verdict was revoked and Xiao Di was found not guilty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The timeline of this case is not complicated. On February 22, 2018, a dating agency in Luannan County introduced a woman to Di. After the two met, &quot;both were quite satisfied.&quot; That night, Di invited the woman and Wang, the owner of the dating agency, to dinner. After dinner, Di drove the woman in question and invited her out to play. They had a &quot;very good chat&quot; and had sex in the car. Afterwards, Di drove the woman back to the dating agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The owner of the dating agency called Di that night and said, &quot;The woman no longer wanted to have sex after having sex&quot; and &quot;asked Di to compensate the woman with tens of thousands of yuan.&quot; In desperation, Di had no choice but to return to the dating agency and work with the boss to find the woman involved to coordinate, but they did not reach an agreement on the &quot;compensation&quot;. On the second day after the incident, Wang took two people to Di&#39;s home and formally made a &quot;compensation request&quot; of 20,000 yuan. Di thought Wang was extorting money and was unwilling to accept it. Wang called the police that day. In the next few days, Di gave Wang several thousand yuan and received the assurance from the other party that &quot;it will be fine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 1, a week after the incident, Di was detained on suspicion of rape and arrested 12 days later. On June 1, 2018, the Luannan County Procuratorate prosecuted Di for rape. On December 29 of the same year, Di was sentenced to three years in prison for rape, and his second-instance appeal was also rejected. During his sentence, Di insisted on not pleading guilty and asked to appeal. He waited until February 28, 2021, to be released after serving his sentence. After being released from prison, Di requested a retrial. After more than two years of judicial proceedings, he finally won a not guilty verdict recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case has been delayed for five years. After many twists and turns, there are still many unanswered questions about the case. A retrial should not be the end of this case. Although the parties involved have been avenged, there are still many aspects of this case that deserve further questioning and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved are suspected of extortion and should be held legally accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you examine the case carefully, it is not difficult to see the absurdity of the &quot;rape&quot; charge. I would like to ask, if &quot;rape&quot; really exists, can &quot;paying 20,000 yuan&quot; be exchanged for not calling the police? How is this different from prostitution? The woman involved “no longer wanted to have sex after having sex.” Could it be that the so-called “consent” could be revoked at any time afterwards? If this is the case, the evidentiary standards for rape cases handled by public prosecutors and prosecutors are too low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the client is not found guilty of rape, the behavior of the dating agency owner is an out-and-out extortion, and there are both completed and attempted circumstances. According to Article 1 of the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in Handling Criminal Cases of Extortion&quot; promulgated by the two high authorities on April 23, 2013, extortion of public and private property worth more than 2,000 yuan to 5,000 yuan should be deemed as Article 274 of the Criminal Law The specified &quot;amount is relatively large&quot;. According to the standards of Hebei Province&#39;s two highs, the starting point for &quot;larger amounts&quot; is 3,000 yuan. In this case, the successful extortion amount by the owner of the dating agency was &quot;several thousand yuan&quot;, and the attempted extortion amount was 20,000 yuan, which fully meets the standard of &quot;large amount&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved in this case are also suspected of false accusation and frame-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the public opinion offensive of &quot;Internet essays&quot; in recent years, the false accusation method in this case can be described as simple and crude, and the case was reported directly to the public security organ. Judging from the results, the false accusation and frame-up caused the client Di to be imprisoned for three years, and it took a lot of time and energy to get justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of the parties involved in this case is undoubtedly worse than that of those &quot;victims of Internet essays&quot;. Since the false accusation has caused serious consequences for him being wrongly imprisoned, Di has more reason to obtain corresponding judicial relief. Article 243 of the Criminal Law stipulates that fabricating facts to frame others with the intention of subjecting others to criminal prosecution, if the circumstances are serious, shall constitute the crime of false accusation and frame-up. If the circumstances are serious, he shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or surveillance; if serious consequences are caused, he shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years and not more than ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The client’s acquittal is only the starting point for him to seek judicial relief, and should not be the end. Di has the right to file a criminal private prosecution with the court, requesting public authority to hold the owner of the dating agency and Wang accountable for criminal liability, and bear the accompanying civil compensation obligations, to relieve the heavy losses he has suffered in the past five years, and to clear up the huge injustice that has been imposed on him. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the dating agency and the woman involved may have serious suspicions of &quot;fairy dancing&quot; and organizing fraud. This is also something that the police should investigate in depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the dating agency and the woman involved showed a situation of &quot;cooperating with each other and playing tricks skillfully&quot;. The woman&#39;s words and deeds were inconsistent, and the owner of the dating agency acted as a &quot;middleman&quot; to negotiate &quot;compensation&quot; with the client. Combined with the &quot;reverent&quot; attitude of the dating agency owner, this case has been cast into layers of suspicion of fraud. The suspicion that the dating agency owner and the woman involved colluded to commit the crime cannot be ruled out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the suspicion of collusion is established, then this case can be called a &quot;dating agency fraud&quot;. The method is more sinister and vicious than the previous marriage agencies that &quot;only seek to make money&quot;, and is more sinister than &quot;conspiracy&quot;. &quot;Property&quot; marriage fraud is more crude and direct. It can be regarded as a &quot;fairy jump fraud&quot; disguised as a matchmaking agency, and is suspected of constituting the crime of fraud. Article 266 of the Criminal Law stipulates that whoever defrauds public or private property and the amount is relatively large shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or public surveillance, and shall also or solely be fined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of public interest, the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved in this case also deserve to be severely punished by the law. If the result of this case is that one person, Di, is not guilty and the two are not punished, it will be tantamount to institutional incentives for similar acts of extortion, false accusations and frame-ups, leading to a situation where &quot;one will not be held responsible no matter what if the blackmail and false accusations fail.&quot; This situation is obviously not conducive to curbing similar illegal and criminal activities and puts more potential victims at risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, Di, the party involved in this case, certainly has reason to seek state compensation and compensation for the various losses caused by being wrongfully imprisoned. At the same time, he will launch a criminal private prosecution against the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved to pursue their various criminal responsibilities. They are required to fulfill their accompanying civil compensation obligations and seek justice for themselves. It is also necessary for relevant departments to intervene and conduct an in-depth investigation into the suspicion that the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved have committed gang fraud, so as to deter similar people who are lucky enough to get involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[猫狗鸟蛇……每年五十多万只动物命丧公路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258541]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/13/rdNvCtUMWcYoDaCM7cWfhM9jc5aX1oAK7AVNT30h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;870&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/rdNvCtUMWcYoDaCM7cWfhM9jc5aX1 oAK7AVNT30h. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Roadkilled cat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the research team)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blackbird (dōng), which is black all over and has a yellow beak, is a common bird in the city. It is good at imitating the calls of other birds and likes to move in the woods. Street trees and shrubs on both sides of the road provide ideal habitats for blackbirds, but they also pose fatal risks. Li Zhongqiu, a professor at the School of Life Sciences of Nanjing University, encountered blackbirds that suddenly appeared several times while driving, and almost became a &quot;murderer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Animal-vehicle collisions that result in fatal accidents are known as &quot;road kills.&quot; Nowadays, wheels have replaced shotguns as one of the main threats to animals, whether in inaccessible reserves or traffic-filled cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of animals killed on the roads is unimaginable. A research paper with Li Zhongqiu as the corresponding author was recently published in the academic journal PeerJ: More than 570,000 birds and mammals may be roadkilled in Nanjing every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been few systematic studies on road killing in China before. The study by Li Zhongqiu’s team evaluated the background data of road killing in Nanjing, a large city. &quot;Road killing is a very serious threat, but there is insufficient awareness among both the academic community and the public.&quot; Li Zhongqiu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cats, dogs, blackbirds, and sparrows are at the highest risk&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;my country’s total road mileage has reached 5.28 million kilometers, which can circle the earth more than 100 times. The transportation network extending in all directions has provided convenience for human life, but it has become a natural barrier for many wild animals. Every time you cross the road, it is like experiencing a journey of life and death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Academic research shows that 340 million birds die on the road in the United States every year, about 335,000 hedgehogs die on the road in the United Kingdom every year, and about 9 million large and medium-sized mammals die in traffic accidents in Brazil every year. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhongqiu told Southern Weekend reporters that road killing is one of the research contents of the interdisciplinary &quot;road ecology&quot; and there are many academic studies in the United States, Europe and other countries. However, currently, road killing is systematically carried out in China. There are not many studies, and the existing studies are mostly conducted in protected areas and lack analysis of urban environments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2020, Li Zhongqiu’s team has carried out a one-year monitoring of 9 roads in Nanjing. These 9 roads include 3 national roads, 3 provincial roads and 3 county roads. The roadside habitats cover residential areas, farmland, mountains, waters, open lands, forests, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/jHJGDj2QDMJyU4a0y9f3ok1ynq3BEws2c2vzFxAb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height= &quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/jHJGDj2QDMJyU4a0y9f3ok1ynq3BEws2c2vzFxAb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A research team observes roadkill in Nanjing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(paper screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every two weeks, the researchers walked the entire route at a speed of no more than 40km/h. Record dead animals found on the road. The total mileage traveled is 5,831 kilometers, which is equivalent to the round-trip distance from Beijing to Urumqi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 26 monitoring activities, researchers found a total of 293 roadkill animals. There are 136 mammals among them, the most common ones are cats and dogs, as well as wild mammals such as weasels and hedgehogs, and a kind of reptile - the tiger-spotted snake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 143 birds, the most common ones being blackbirds and sparrows, which is related to their large population and wide distribution. Other birds include pearl-necked doves, gray magpies, white-headed bulbuls, etc., most of which are common species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;May to July is the peak period for road killings. The number of road killings in these three months accounts for about 1/3 of the whole year. Li Zhongqiu explained that this period is the breeding season for many animals. The baby animals lack survival experience. Adult animals increase the frequency of foraging to raise their children, and the probability of road kill increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locations where road kills occur are closely related to the animals’ habitats. For example, road sections with a high proportion of farmland, forestry and wetland areas have a higher risk of roadkill; the smaller the distance between the road and the river, the higher the risk of roadkill; roadkill is more likely to occur in areas far away from urban main roads ; Compared to curvy roads, the risk of roadkill is higher on straight roads because vehicles travel faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the model, researchers calculated the number of animals that are killed on the road in Nanjing every year - more than 110,000 mammals and more than 450,000 birds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The model is constructed based on the on-site monitoring of the retention time of animal carcasses, the probability of discovery, and the composition of different roads in Nanjing. Since the carcasses of roadkill animals do not remain on the road for too long, the researchers placed frozen chicken heads and frozen whole chickens on multiple road sections to represent small and large animal carcasses respectively, monitored the retention time of the simulated carcasses on the road, and calculated the number of roadkill animals. The probability of detection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/ctOxUfPfW7fH3pxoUlBEeQxIpnJsRrjlm6UaHUNb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;303&quot; height= &quot;203&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/ctOxUfPfW7fH3pxoUlBEeQxIpnJsRrjlm6UaHUNb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Roadkilled bird. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the research team)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Common species also have important value&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to help animals reduce traffic accidents risks of? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many protected areas establish ecological corridors for animal migration along transportation routes. For example, the Qinghai-Tibet Railway has set up 33 wildlife crossings for sheep migration, benefiting Tibetan antelopes and other wild animals; Hubei Shennongjia National Park has built 25 animal crossings of three types: upper-span type, lower culvert type and gentle slope type. , making it easier for Sichuan snub-nosed monkeys to cross; Yunnan Province&#39;s Si Xiao Expressway has set up bridges and tunnels for Asian elephants, and the utilization rate of 25 wildlife passages by wild Asian elephants reached 72%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ecological corridors can also be established on busy urban highways. For example, in 2020, the Paiya Mountain-Qiniang Mountain Ecological Corridor in Dapeng New District, Shenzhen was completed, connecting the two mountains and spanning the highway. It is the first animal-only overpass in Guangdong Province that was completed and put into use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Staff from the Dapeng Administration Bureau of the Shenzhen Municipal Planning and Natural Resources Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2018, Dapeng New District conducted a survey on road deaths of wild animals. In July and August, A total of 383 road kill incidents were recorded, killing more than 40 species, mainly amphibians and reptiles such as black-orbited toads, Hong Kong newts, anoles, etc., with a small number of birds and mammals also recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff member said that ecological corridors not only reconnect fragmented habitats, but also effectively reduce the occurrence of road kills. More than 40 infrared cameras arranged on the ecological corridor bridge have recorded that more than 60 species of animals breed, forage, and move within the ecological corridor. Wild mammals such as ocelots, wild boars, porcupines, and macaques have been recorded. A good animal habitat is formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhongqiu believes that whether cities build ecological corridors should focus on cost and local species. There are also some effective methods, such as setting up signboards in roadkill hotspots to remind drivers that animals are often found here, slowing down and observing more road conditions, or setting up speed bumps, building animal fences, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhongqiu admitted that the current understanding and research on road killing is still relatively rudimentary, and “it is difficult to assess the impact of road killing on the local ecosystem.” But at least from the data, road killing is The problem deserves more attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Li Zhongqiu’s team’s research on road killing is only carried out in Nanjing. He hopes that in the future, the regional scope can be expanded to a national scale to conduct more in-depth research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the animals that encounter roadkill in cities are common species, they still have a unique status in the ecosystem. Li Zhongqiu gave an example. The common bird, the white-headed bulbul, is a bit annoying in daily life - vehicles parked under the camphor trees are often attacked by the bird droppings &quot;bombs&quot; of the white-headed bulbul. But the Bald Bulbul is an important functional bird in the ecosystem, and its excrement can help plant seeds spread several kilometers away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We always focus on humans and talk about whether a species is useful to us.” Li Zhongqiu said, “Every species living on the earth has its function and value. The more common it is, the more common it is. The more valuable a species is, we cannot ignore them living around us just because they are common.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>