<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[尹学芸：故乡是一枚爱人丨月是故乡明⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257348]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/21/09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Reading Yin Xueyun&#39;s &quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot; for the first time, readers may feel a little confused. His novels always &quot;talk right from the beginning, without any pretense&quot;, like green seedlings growing in the ground, simple and pretty, with a fresh earthy smell. A writer who is used to writing about villages, counties, officialdom, and wine shops, How did you come up with the idea of ​​writing an urban romance novel that looks like flowers in the fog? The 2021 novel collection of the same name includes several novellas such as &quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot;, &quot;Wanghu Tower&quot;, &quot;Feeding the Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Apple Tree&quot; and &quot;Faster Than the Wind&quot;. Continue reading, this &quot;strange&quot; novel The origins of the story are gradually revealed, and a Yin Xueyun familiar to old readers slowly emerges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The origin of Yin Xueyun’s writing is Jizhou in the northernmost part of Tianjin City&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (formerly known as Ji County before 2016) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. There is an artificial lake in the small town, which was once an important water source for Tianjin. In the past, people often fished, took boats, and swam in the lake, but in order to protect the water source, these projects were canceled and many buildings around the lake were demolished one by one. She walked along the lake when she had nothing to do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot; tells the story of two women, Xue Xiaoli and Su Mei, and a young man who went to an abandoned manor to search for her in &quot;pairs&quot; several times. The story of a reclusive master. The novel originated from an encounter with Yin Xueyun himself. During a stroll, she walked into an abandoned manor and saw different flowers and plants inside, as well as swings, a sports field, a fish pond, and a lake-view pavilion. The old luxury was clearly visible, and she even saw something familiar to her. man&#39;s inscription. There used to be many well-decorated sanatoriums in the small town. They were built by various departments in places close to mountains and rivers. It was difficult for ordinary people to enter, and they were later demolished. Such a manor could be hidden in the small Jizhou, and even the locals would find it difficult to find it. She guessed that this garden was also one of those sanatoriums. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159102&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are only a few scenes in the small town. One scene can be looked back and forth, guessed, and used. This secret manor has been written by Yin Xueyun in &quot;Wanghu Tower&quot; and &quot;Looking for the Lake&quot;. Hidden people are not seen&quot;. When it is prosperous, the garden is the Wanghu Tower where retired workers from the county town spend all their money to treat guests to a meal; when it is desolate, the garden has become an elusive place for veteran cadres who are walking in official steps with their hands behind their backs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It seems to be her writing instinct to repeatedly salvage, wash and chew her own life without wasting a grain of inspiration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; data-key= &quot;159097&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;From Hancun to Xuncheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Jizhou is the only semi-mountainous area in Tianjin. It is high in the north and low in the south. Mountains, plains, large depressions and reservoir areas gather here. The earliest history can be traced back to the Spring and Autumn Period. There is a poem in the Ming Dynasty that goes: &quot;When you come to the west to reach the end of the mountains, you will see the city of Jizhou.&quot; Life in the mountainous areas rarely changes, and people are not good at adapting. The characters in Yin Xueyun&#39;s works all have a persistent background. Color: Sisters Li Xun and Li Quan who persisted in love and pursued light in the war-torn years in &quot;The Wind and Dust&quot;, Feng Nuo who persisted in searching for her missing friend despite opposition in &quot;The Ballad of Cai Gen&quot;, and firmly believed in the power of the apple tree in &quot;The Apple Tree&quot; Suspicious Liu Ping... Some historians told Yin Xueyun that when the Qing army entered the Pass, the people of Ji County refused to surrender until death, and were massacred three times. The character of the people here was to be cruel, sluggish, and twisted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Jizhou is a place where obsession arises, and Yin Xueyun’s literature is also the fruit of persistence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some people went to visit Yin Xueyun’s village after reading her works, but were disappointed to find that the river was not that clear, the streets were not that long, and there were not always cows braying when entering the village. and fried grasshoppers. Yin Xueyun has actually seen these beauties, but the rare village she writes about is neither a peach blossom garden nor a foreign land where strange legends are born, but a place of life, with all kinds of villagers passing through, providing three meals a day. Running around and calculating, the relationships between people are intricate and intricate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;To be precise, the village where Yin Xueyun was born and raised is in the lowest depression in southern Jizhou, surrounded by water on three sides, with only one road on the south side. The &quot;Uncle Li Hai&quot; who won her the Lu Xun Literature Prize followed this road every year and came to &quot;my&quot; house empty-handed, bringing the family a glory that only existed in their imagination, and then loaded up with everything they had cobbled together. Food and supplies go back. The friendship that never returned lasted for more than 20 years and finally overdrawn. The family kept a secret about Uncle Li Hai. Only then did &quot;I&quot; know about the humiliating life history of my uncle. He did not live in an urban community with gardens and high-rise buildings, but in a remote place. In the barren Kuli Valley, the family is extremely poor, and several members of the family wait for Uncle Li Hai to bring flour from &quot;my&quot; house every year to make dumplings for the New Year. The two families looked up to each other and secretly compared each other to get through the difficult period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When Yin Xueyun was a child, the days in the village moved at an almost solid speed. The only changes were who died and who got married. Some people wear the same clothes in winter and summer, but they take out the cotton wool in summer and stuff it in in winter. The village is nicknamed &quot;Nagging Village&quot; because there are many people who are not doing their job properly and enjoy good food and drink. Meat that cannot be sold in other villages will be sold here. Her parents are both farmers, and there is no one around her who is involved in writing work. She looked for the source of her literary genes, which was her grandfather who could read scripts, sing operas, and shout trumpets. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many writers remember their reading history. She also wrote down in her notebook: &quot;Wild Fire and Spring Wind Fighting in the Ancient City&quot;, &quot;Fighting Youth&quot;, &quot;Golden Avenue&quot;...from elementary school She had memorized 147 titles of books she read from first grade to junior high school graduation. This number made her wonder if she had remembered it wrong. But in her words, these books are all about war, which may not be very nutritious for literature. When she was a teenager, she didn’t even know there were magazines in the world, let alone come into contact with foreign literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Even so, you must read, read one book at a time, and come out bit by bit. Because of scarcity, the memory of books is strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is not easy for rural children to get access to books, and sometimes they have to &quot;match wits and courage&quot; with their brothers and sisters. When she was a child, her sister, who was seven years older than her, loved reading and would often bring books to the house but would not read them to her. Once my sister hid a book that was said to be &quot;not suitable for children&quot;. She turned the house upside down and finally found it in an old cotton shoe. When she took the book out, she only smelled the smell of feet. When she was not at home, she took it out and read it, stuffed it back after reading it, and secretly finished reading the book about &quot;sexual intercourse&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (later she found out it was &quot;Song of Youth&quot; 》)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159107&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When she was not at school, she was reading a book while herding sheep. There was a lamb beside her and a copy of &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; without a book cover on her lap. The book was written in traditional Chinese characters. , she couldn’t understand it at all, but she could still remember the plot of “Second Sister You swallowed her own gold and died by herself”, and the stories in the book took root in her mind. On the way to school in the town, she walked in the wheat field with the children in the village. The children rushed to her side. She held a spindle in her hand and spun the cotton randomly pulled from the cotton field into thread, while talking about Mix books and memories with imagination to make a story, and tell it to your friends. She began to dream that one day her writing would be turned into type. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After graduating from high school, Yin Xueyun went to work as a seamstress in a village-run garment factory. As long as she had a day off, she would go to the county town and buy ten magazines and read them all night long. She also started to contribute articles to publications after work. At the beginning, she didn&#39;t pay attention to the differences between different publications. She couldn&#39;t remember the names of the writers she read, didn&#39;t understand anything, and her manuscripts were rejected many times. Sometimes, the editor criticized her in the rejection letter for imitating a certain writer. She was confused and didn&#39;t know who the writer she was &quot;imitating&quot; was. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At heart, she is still a farmer who relies on the weather. If it rains too much, the seedlings will grow wildly, and if there is a severe drought, there will be no harvest. The same is true for writing. There is no chance of winning awards or becoming famous. My ambition is to work step by step and write whatever comes to my mind. During this period, she relied on her innate spirituality and affection to write about life in the countryside and the ecology of the countryside, expressing those around her who were &quot;thinking of ways to live&quot;. She published publications ranging from &quot;Jixian Literature and Art&quot; to &quot;Tianjin Literature&quot; &quot;Tianjin Daily&quot;, the efforts are slowly paying off. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the late 1980s, Yin Xueyun’s novel &quot;A Woman Called Suyue&quot; was adapted into a TV series and broadcast on CCTV. The background music of this TV series was composed of a song called &quot; Yin Xueyun was deeply moved by the sound of Xun&#39;s musical instrument and decided to use &quot;Xun&quot; to name the cities in her future works. From then on, &quot;Xun City&quot; became another literary landmark of hers. At that time, she was helping the county write county chronicles. Due to the influence of CCTV, the county party committee specially gave her a quota, and she was directly transferred from a temporary worker to a national cadre. Speaking of this, Yin Xueyun couldn&#39;t help but sigh: &quot;Literature changes destiny, it is really literature that changes destiny.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159106&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Emerging from deep waters&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From a farmer to a cadre, Yin Xueyun worked in many different departments such as the Cultural Center, the Tourism Bureau, and the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee, and her work exposed her to She kept a distance from all kinds of people, observed how people think and act at work, and what kind of relationships needed to be coordinated, and wrote down each and every image of grassroots cadres. In the early years, someone from her workplace warned her not to write a novel about herself. She secretly asked, &quot;Which single character can constitute a novel?&quot; She likes to let the characters wash away in the long river of time, washing away their temporary moments. They are high-spirited and disgraced, leaving behind their usually faint but real humanity, and then weave a story frame for them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is different from the countryside is that the government divides people into many levels. Leaders and non-leaders, older people and younger people, and even the background behind them will be deliberately divided. Measurement and speculation, in the workplace, people always have to face many different people and deal with many different relationships. In such a complicated and tame daily life, she expands the depth of people&#39;s soul introspection. &quot;Ten Years of Farewell&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(published in 2015)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is a typical story about the transformation of human nature in agency work. This novel I started writing very early, and was left on the computer for ten years. During these ten years, Guo Yingzi, a young literary and artistic woman who &quot;always sees things with wishful thinking, cannot see any formalism, and cannot tolerate a grain of sand in her eyes&quot;, He learned to watch people&#39;s words and restrain his sharp edges, and became a well-rounded director in the office and an all-rounder at the bar. Chen Danguo, who was in a very similar situation to Yingzi at the time, could not bear the harassment from his boss and the isolation from his colleagues, so he committed suicide by jumping off the building. Chen Danguo&#39;s death made Yingzi realize that he had sunk into Accomplices also poses a thought-provoking question to readers: Does worldly success come at the cost of losing common sense and normal life? This novel resonated with many people and was recognized by the Hundred Flowers Literary Award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before the novel came out, Yin Xueyun also experienced a period of &quot;boiling a frog in warm water&quot; in literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She has always been insensitive to fame and fortune. In her words, the author in the remote mountainous area is far away from the city and away from the vanity fair. Therefore, people are always in a state of submerging in deep water, and it is difficult to float even if they want to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the 1990s, Yin Xueyun gave the impression that her writing had stopped for several years. She was still young at that time, publishing novels and essays from time to time, and running a small magazine. She went around admiring flowers, playing cards, and picnicking with authors she knew, and had a lot of fun every day. But soon she felt tired. Although there are always works being published, there are only a few publications that I regularly contact, and the novels are bumping around in a small circle, without any upward momentum. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After walking out of the valley, as she grew older, she thought of things that she had never thought of before. &quot;You live in a place where the mountains are high and the emperor is far away. The advantage is that you are relatively free. The disadvantage is that you are relatively free and there is no one to supervise you. Later I met some writers in Hebei and I was particularly envious of them for having such a small group of three or five people who knew how to write. What&#39;s good and what&#39;s bad is. But at that time, no one saw it when I posted it in some places, and no one told you how to go.&quot; Yin Xueyun said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fortunately, the goodwill among grassroots writers &quot;caught&quot; her. When her novel was tepid, experienced writers gave her guidance - to publish it in an evening newspaper that was more life-oriented and had more readers. So she began to write novels for the Evening News, as well as prose and essays. The content became richer, including talking about football, reminiscing about the countryside, talking about family life, and everything in between. During that time, she went hiking every evening, thinking about writing while climbing. “Sometimes a series of topics are lined up at the back, and there is always a lot to write about. It is such a feeling that makes you feel that life is very interesting. &quot; Yin Xueyun described. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The newspaper column has a large volume of publications, and she has to publish several articles at a time. She thought of writing about the words that were slowly disappearing in the countryside where she lived. As urbanization continues to accelerate, some scenes of historical significance and local color in rural areas have become blurred. As rural people moved into the city, many dialect words that existed between the 1950s and the 1970s disappeared from people&#39;s communication, and a considerable part of them became history by the early 1980s. In order to prevent these words from disappearing quietly, she visited villages large and small in the county and dug out those words from the local population. Some words are spread over a wide area, some words are used differently in the south and the north, ancient and modern times, and some accents are difficult to imitate with words. When encountering difficult-to-grasp parts, she also discusses them with netizens from all over the world. This experience of searching on the field ridges left many memories such as &quot;opening the circle&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (the team had finished harvesting all the sweet potatoes, peanuts or wheat in the fields and allowed The members dig up the leftover sweet potatoes and peanuts or pick up the wheat ears left on the ground)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &quot;Shinjuku&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (occasionally stay overnight in other people&#39;s homes)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &quot;watch the green&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(watch the crops when they are about to mature and turn from green to yellow to prevent others from stealing them. Grain)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and other hundreds of rural words were recorded, and later became a book &quot;The Slowly Disappearing Rural Words&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (published in 2009)&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After writing essays and columns for several years, she gradually found her own writing style, and people in the entire city also knew about her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2014 was a special year for Yin Xueyun. She published five novellas and wrote &quot;Uncle Li Hai&quot; and &quot;Ten Years of Farewell&quot; , entering the blowout period of the work. To this day, the fate of her and these works still makes her sad. At that time, a novella &quot;Linglong Tower&quot; was rejected. She could not figure out the reason for the rejection, so she gave the manuscript to Harvest magazine. Within a week, the editor called and suggested revisions. She did nothing during the months waiting for the final trial, and she doesn&#39;t know how she got here. She told herself that she would start writing after the final review, and she would stop writing after the final review failed. She was 50 years old that year, the age when female cadres leave their posts. If the manuscript had not been submitted to Harvest and had not been reviewed, she might have changed her life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The final review was passed. After &quot;Harvest&quot; published &quot;Linglong Tower&quot;, editors approached Yin Xueyun one after another to invite manuscripts. The first thing she wrote was &quot;Uncle Lehi,&quot; but it was shelved because of space issues. She brought another manuscript to the editor for comments, but was asked to publish it. This one was &quot;Ten Years After the Farewell&quot;. &quot;I always tell my writer friends, don&#39;t worry, write slowly. When you have the chance, the work will come when it comes. Sometimes you can&#39;t find it no matter how hard you look for it. This is not just a work. What kind of era.&quot; Yin Xueyun said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the second year, Yin Xueyun continued to work hard and published 10 novellas, and by 2016, he had published 14 novels. She still finds the productivity of that period to be incredible. &quot;Although it was no longer the best time for creativity, you would feel that literature suddenly opened a window for you and you could seize such an opportunity. In fact, no one told you what to do at that time. But I really feel that way,” she said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; data-key= &quot;159104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Thirty Years of Separation&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; In recent years, Yin Xueyun’s vision has crossed from the countryside to the city, focusing on the involvement, entanglement and pain between urban and rural areas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thirty years after she left her hometown, she wrote a horrifyingly titled &quot;Feeding the Ghosts&quot;. The protagonist Yun Ya in the novel ordered her to hide from her hometown godmother before she died. There was a &quot;ghost feeding&quot; ceremony for him at the funeral, and he hurriedly made an appointment with netizen A Xiang to travel to Yunnan. Along the way, she kept receiving urgings and entreaties from her godmother&#39;s eldest son, which made her uneasy. When she returned to Xuncheng after the trip, she followed her godmother&#39;s last wish to feed ghosts, only to realize that feeding ghosts was just a simple Buddhist ritual&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(&quot;Feeding ghosts&quot; Also called &quot;flaming mouth&quot;, it actually means giving relief to ghosts and giving them food to keep them full.)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; More than three months later, Yunya received a call that her friend Axiang had died in a car accident three months ago. It was a futile exodus. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When talking about the creation of this novel, Yin Xueyun said: &quot;Many times, hometown is like a lover. Sometimes it makes you think about how to escape, but more often , and it makes you think about ways to return. Only with contrast can there be contrast, and with contrast can there be expression of different emotions.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although as a grassroots worker, Yin Xueyun still I need to interact with the countryside frequently, but it is no longer the state of living in it like when I was a child, but living as a guest. As she gets older, the distance from the countryside is also widening, and there is an increasingly annoying barrier between her and the people and things in her hometown. In the past, she liked to use familiar people repeatedly in multiple works, depicting different aspects of the characters, and filling the story with details, but now it is difficult to find such people in her life. In &quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot;, the dragon of modern people has its head but not its tail, and the weak and alienated feelings between people are expressed through a large amount of blank space. The spiritual connection that lasted more than twenty years in &quot;Uncle Lehi&quot; is no longer found. &quot;Then you discover that you are actually separated from all hometowns and villages. In fact, it is not them that change, but you. Many times it is your eyes that change, or your heart that changes. I go back less and less and interact with them less and less,&quot; Yin Xueyun said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a writer who specializes in rural themes, she has to be wary of this estrangement: &quot;The temperature in the works is actually receding, and the background color is fading. . I think this is a common problem among writers. Maybe every once in a while, you have to reflect on how to find a breakthrough in life. This is very important.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Reference materials: &quot;Impression of Yin Xueyun&quot;, &quot;Yin Xueyun: No period of life is in vain&quot;, &quot;Yin Xueyun: I have been illuminated by this lamp&quot; Liang also looks forward to it illuminating more people.&quot; &quot;Exclusive Interview&quot; Yin Xueyun: The lowest author is far away from the literary world. No matter how many novels he publishes, he is still not a famous writer.&quot; &quot;Yin Xueyun: Order in the Countryside&quot;, thanks to Yilin Publishing House and Deng Yu for assistance with the interview)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这个假期，打工人流行去围观山姆盒马“小学生打架”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the National Day holiday, some young people who did not travel and stayed at home , they will choose to go to warehouse membership stores to purchase the food they need during the long vacation at one time. Sam’s Club and Hema X membership stores have become the first choice for many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, these two warehouse membership stores can not only meet consumers’ shopping needs, but also meet their needs to join in the fun and gossip, because since August, The &quot;schoolboy fight&quot; between Sam and Hema never stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;High-end business wars often adopt the simplest method, that is, my product is 1 yuan lower than yours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, Sam and Hema had a &quot;fight&quot; over a piece of durian layer cake - the durian layer cake was first sold by Sam, priced at 128 yuan per piece. Hema directly lists the price at 99 yuan per piece. Sam refused to admit defeat and raised the price of durian mille-feuille to 88 yuan, Hema to 86 yuan, and Sam to 85 yuan. After several rounds, the price of the cake dropped to 79 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, everything from moon cakes and watermelons to egg snacks were involved in this business war. Many people wondered why Sam and Hema had a &quot;primary school student fight&quot;? Can price wars allow them to successfully attract middle-class consumers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The giants have their own troubles&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Legitimate traditional supermarkets When operations are generally in trouble, warehouse membership stores with wholesale properties are developing in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Warehouse membership stores adopt a mass sales model, with large packages, many categories, and favorable prices. Consumers only go for large purchases every once in a while. iiMedia Consulting data shows that the market size of the warehouse membership supermarket industry will reach 30.43 billion yuan in 2021, 33.5 billion yuan in 2022, and is expected to be close to 40 billion yuan by 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the leading brands of warehouse membership stores in China, Sam’s Club and Hema X stores have their own successes and worries, so they have to compete vigorously. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sam&#39;s Club has become an important growth point in Wal-Mart&#39;s performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Walmart’s second quarter data, total revenue in the second quarter was US$161.6 billion, a year-on-year increase of 5.7% or 5.4% (affected by exchange rates). Profit increased by US$500 million year-on-year, with a growth rate of 6.7%. Among them, Walmart China’s net sales were US$4.1 billion, a year-on-year increase of 21.7%, and its warehouse membership business and e-commerce business grew brilliantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sam&#39;s Club has firmly taken the top spot among domestic warehouse membership stores. On the one hand, in 1996, Sam opened China&#39;s first warehouse membership store in Shenzhen, transmitting the model and concept of warehouse membership to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, as a perennial number one among the world&#39;s top 500 companies, Wal-Mart has established a large and stable supply chain system around the world. Sam&#39;s Mart under Wal-Mart Member stores can get higher quality products at lower prices and pass the profits on to consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sam&#39;s Club opened its first store in the United States in 1983 and has a history of 40 years. Its accumulation and experience are unmatched by other warehouse club stores. It’s hard to compare even half a century ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Sam also has troubles, that is, there are too many imitators, competitors and even &quot;imposters&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Costco, also born in the United States, focuses on the warehousing membership model and is an old rival of Sam&#39;s. Foreign brands such as Metro and Carrefour are also chasing after it. As for domestic, Just like Yonghui, Hema, etc., are coming fiercely, especially the rising star Hema X store, which has gradually formed a serious challenge to Sam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For Hema, which was founded in 2015, although its history is not long, it has gone through many detours. In addition to its signature Hema fresh products, Hema Most of the previously launched Hema Station, Hema MINI, Hema Market and Hema Neighborhood have failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently Hema has formed three relatively stable businesses, one is Hema Fresh Food, the other is Hema Outlet Store (discount store), and the other is warehousing membership Model Hema X store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year, Alibaba launched the &quot;1+6+N&quot; organizational reform. Hema is only part of the &quot;N&quot;, and its status in the group has declined. , Hema is still one of Alibaba’s most promising businesses for listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is definitely not enough to make profit from Hema Xiansheng. Therefore, the X store has become Hema’s top priority and has high hopes. In addition to opening more stores quickly, we also need to seize market share and improve profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Aim at the middle class and seize the middle class&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Warehouse membership store The target customers are China&#39;s emerging middle class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sam&#39;s Club opened its first store in mainland China as early as 1996. However, as of 2016, there were only 16 stores in 20 years. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the rapid rise of China&#39;s middle class, Sam&#39;s Club has experienced explosive growth. In less than 6 years since 2017, Sam&#39;s Club has 29 new stores have been added, and there are currently 45 Sam&#39;s Club stores in mainland China, and it is expected to reach 48 by the end of this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another sign of the middle-class nature of a warehouse membership store is its not-cheap annual fee. For example, Sam’s ordinary membership fee is 260 yuan, and Hema X gold membership annual fee is 258 yuan. It is worth noting that the membership fee is only valid for one year and cannot be redeemed for cash. In other words, you have to spend 260 yuan before you can enter Sam&#39;s for consumption. Even if you don&#39;t buy anything at Sam&#39;s for a year, the 260 yuan is not refundable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The membership fee threshold naturally blocks a large number of consumers, and will undoubtedly increase the shopping stickiness of paying consumers. Of course, if you apply for a membership card here, you will Come here to shop frequently so that you don&#39;t waste your membership fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With its strong supply chain and bargaining power, warehouse membership stores will also strive to provide consumers with &quot;good quality, comprehensive and reasonably priced&quot; products. The membership fee is well spent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sam and Hema are aimed at the middle class, especially middle-class families, who have a good economic foundation and a high pursuit of quality of life. Their users Highly coincident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Yuehu iAPP, the user overlap rate of Sam and Hema reached 43.1%. In February this year, Walmart China CEO Zhu Xiaojing said in an internal speech that Sam’s only competitor may be Hema. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This time Hema also took the lead in launching a &quot;price war&quot; against Sam. Hema&#39;s best-selling activity is called &quot;Mountain-Moving Price&quot;, a pun, which means that the Foolish Old Man Moves Mountains , also to remove Sam. This name has a strong connotation of &quot;primary school students fighting&quot;. What’s funny is that Meituan also joined the fray at one point and launched a price called “tug-of-war price.” Isn’t this “river” the same as “Hema”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Who can &quot;win&quot; this group of fights&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Who can &quot;win&quot; in this group war in the warehousing membership field? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Price war alone is not the optimal solution. Not only because it is unsustainable, but also because the price war only targets a few product categories, and not all products are cheaper than the other party. More importantly, what the middle class cares about is not the difference of one or two yuan. Many people are willing to pay a higher price to buy better quality products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, warehouse membership stores still have to go back to the basics: &quot;good quality, complete products, and reasonable prices&quot; - this still tests the strength and resilience of the supply chain. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Can we purchase high-quality products at lower prices globally? How long does it take from purchasing to putting it on the shelves? How to ensure that popular products on the shelves can be continuously supplied? How quickly can consumers purchase goods online and have them delivered to their doorsteps? Can you continue to provide hot-selling self-operated products? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are all related to the supply chain. At this point, Sam and Costco have been established for many years and have deep roots. Hema really needs to keep catching up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a local brand, Hema’s advantage is that it has more distinctive “localization” characteristics and is more in line with some of the consumer needs of Chinese people. For example, China is entering a single society, and there are more and more single middle-class people. The super large-volume sales model of Sam’s Club is not suitable for these single middle-class people. Hema’s X membership store places great emphasis on selling small packaged goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China&#39;s e-commerce economy is highly developed. Hema relies on Alibaba&#39;s sound and mature logistics system, and its door-to-door delivery speed is extremely fast. On the contrary, Costco not long ago The launch of home delivery service is really long overdue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For another example, the sinking market is still an underdeveloped territory for warehouse membership stores. Hema’s outlet stores, which focus on discounted products and last-dated products, can be found in Taking root in first-tier cities, there is also a lot of room for imagination in sinking markets...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How Sam&#39;s, Hema and other warehouse membership stores should make use of their strengths and avoid their weaknesses? The best is yet to come. In any case, it is a good thing that they are fully competitive. They can help drive down prices for consumers, and consumers can also take advantage of the gossip, so why not do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:26:35 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子诬告强奸在新加坡被判入狱：世界性难题如何破解？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258118]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A case that occurred abroad has attracted attention. According to reports from Singapore&#39;s &quot;Lianhe Zaobao&quot; and &quot;The Straits Times&quot;, a Chinese woman Zhang Lutian (22 years old) pleaded guilty in court on October 2, admitting that she provided false information to civil servants. The judge ultimately sentenced him to five weeks in jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case is not complicated: the woman involved met the man Liu Dongyang through social software in April 2021, met a month later and established a relationship in August of that year, and then lived together with Liu Dongyang. On March 9, 2022, the two had a fierce argument at Liu Dongyang&#39;s residence, and the woman involved called the police at 00:38 midnight. Facing the ten police officers, five investigators and four forensic personnel who attended the investigation, the woman in question claimed that she had been abused by Liu Dongyang and had been raped by the latter three times, and she repeated the accusation to the medical staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Dongyang was questioned for a total of 44 minutes, and his two mobile phones and passport were also detained by the police. However, one month after reporting the crime, the woman involved changed her story and admitted that she had lied and withdrew the false accusation. &quot;The purpose is to get the man into trouble.&quot; The woman involved also revealed that she tried to close the case about a week after the incident, but failed. Prosecutor Kevin Liew said the defendant wasted public resources by providing false information and wronged an innocent victim, so he proposed that the judge sentence the defendant to jail for at least six weeks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the prosecution&#39;s accusations, the woman involved choked up her voice in her defense, saying that she had just turned 21 at the time of the incident, her cognitive abilities were not yet mature, and she made the mistake on impulse. Except for the victims, his actions did not cause great harm to the public interest. At that time, because she was being treated roughly by her ex-boyfriend, she was anxious to seek help so she lied about being raped by him. She has regretted the incident and has been forgiven by her ex-boyfriend, and hopes the judge will give her a lighter sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case has been settled, and the judge did give the woman a &quot;lenient sentence&quot; as she wished, changing the sentence from six to ten weeks to five weeks. However, there are still some unanswered questions in this case that deserve in-depth analysis and comment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the case itself shows that there are contradictions in the woman’s statements, and her defense is not convincing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;cognitive bias&quot; argument of the woman involved revealed a sense of black humor, especially the sentence &quot;Inadequate understanding of legal provisions, and very poor understanding of the seriousness of her own crime.&quot; Immature&quot;. So, why did she accuse her boyfriend of rape since her &quot;cognitive immaturity&quot;? You know, rape in Singapore is a felony with a maximum prison term of 20 years and a maximum of 12 strokes of the cane. Therefore, the words and deeds of the woman involved can only be interpreted as her awareness of the consequences of the crime of rape, but are not sufficient to understand the legal consequences of falsely accusing others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the term &quot;cognitive bias&quot; is also commonly used in the self-defense of domestic rape or sexual assault false accusers after their secrets are revealed. In the controversial &quot;Luo Guanjun case&quot;, Liang Ying claimed that &quot;her own understanding of the legal definition of rape was skewed, which is why she wrongly accused Luo Guanjun on the Internet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The false accuser’s self-defense of “cognitive bias” is actually unjustifiable. Judging from the &quot;little essay&quot; public opinion offensive launched by Liang Ying and the judicial offensive of the woman involved in this case, the false accuser actually has a clear understanding of the consequences of publicly accusing &quot;rape&quot;, and the purpose is to &quot;make the other party social.&quot; Death” and “causing trouble for the other party”. In other cases, false accusers have made explicit threats to “send you to jail.” Don’t the false accusers know the seriousness of the “crime of rape”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine the mental process of the false accuser: publicly accusing the other party of sexual assault or rape, the best result is to force the other party to give up benefits or allow you to enjoy the traffic bonus, or even actually send the other party to prison. , at least destroy the other person&#39;s life; the worst result is that &quot;I remember it wrong&quot;, using reasons similar to &quot;cognitive bias&quot; to justify the false accusation, and the &quot;offensive and defensive&quot; state is enough to make oneself stand on the invincible position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely for this reason that after the woman in question spent a lot of public resources and the false accusation was confirmed, she used &quot;cognitive bias&quot; to defend the false accusation, and tried to escape from reporting the false accusation with the help of &quot;mental immaturity&quot; crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this case also shows that &quot;false accusations of sexual assault or rape&quot; are a global problem. The burden of proof and the civil and criminal liabilities that the false accuser needs to bear are all related to the possible profits of a successful false accusation. Grossly disproportionate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the woman involved was ultimately charged with &quot;providing false information to public servants&quot;, and the prosecutor only emphasized her behavior of &quot;wasting a large amount of public resources&quot; in the accusation. Under Section 177 of the Penal Code of Singapore, anyone who provides false information to a public servant will be punished with a jail term of up to six months or a fine of S$5,000. However, comparing the false accusation made by the woman involved and the severe punishment that the man will face if convicted, this is seriously disproportionate to the principle of proportionality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If similar false accusations can always achieve &quot;zero cost and high returns&quot;, and even if you report a false case and commit perjury, you will only be jailed for six weeks, then the &quot;system incentives&quot; it brings will still be Creating more false accusation cases will also harm public interest in the long run. Could it be that society can only choose one or the other between &quot;tacitly acquiescing to or even condoning false accusations&quot; and &quot;guaranteeing that real victims dare to report crimes&quot;? This is another &quot;false dilemma&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the person who was falsely accused failed to stand up to assert his rights and accuse the other party of criminal behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singaporean law does not include the crime of false accusation and frame-up, but there is the crime of defamation. According to Section 499 of the Singapore Penal Code, if sufficient evidence is found, the police can take action to arrest the defamation offender. The victim can also choose to file a civil lawsuit under the Defamation Act, or report the case to the police for criminal prosecution. If it can be proven that the slanderer intended, knew or had reason to believe that his words would damage the victim&#39;s reputation, he or she can initiate a complaint and recover damages. losses caused by infringement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the evidence of defamation by the woman involved is conclusive, and there is suspicion of perjury. The direct harm to the man involved was dozens of minutes of interrogation, the confiscation of his passport and mobile phone, and damage to his personality and reputation. The potential harm was a severe sentence of &quot;fixed-term imprisonment plus caning package&quot;. However, the man involved did not counter-sue the woman, but &quot;forgave her for that.&quot; In practice, this increases the risk of harming the public interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Singaporean anesthesiologist Yang Shaonan as an example. It took him four years (2017-2021) to clear his name after being falsely accused of sexual assault by a woman. However, the lengthy legal process cost him his job. Her position at the hospital cost her huge financial losses and suffered a devastating blow to her reputation. In the end, winning the lawsuit was of no help. The prosecution has yet to take any action against the woman for providing false evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as early as September 13, 2021, members of the Singapore Parliament jointly proposed that while formulating new laws to increase the penalties for sexual assault crimes, we should also seek to punish those who have been wrongly accused. protection of. To strengthen the protection of victims of false accusations, we first need to intensify the crackdown on those who falsely accuse criminals and encourage victims to come forward and make counter-complaints. We can no longer let false accusations of sexual assault become a &quot;low-cost, high-yield&quot; game and let &quot;cognition &quot;Deviation&quot; has become a shortcut for false accusers to escape guilt and reduce their crimes. As Dr. Yang Shaonan said after the truth came out: the legal system should be able to exert sufficient deterrence on those who abuse the law, while not preventing real victims of sexual crimes from coming forward bravely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[礼盒混装、糕点伪装……月饼何时“包装有度”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8 tDTuhfG52. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The implementation of the new national standard can encourage manufacturers to focus on the innovation of mooncakes themselves and ban overly elaborate and complicated ones. packaging, but there are still some businesses that take advantage of loopholes, and relevant departments need to strengthen supervision. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people have mooncakes for breakfast during this Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday? How many people have noticed changes in the piles of mooncake gift boxes at home? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you happen to have a mooncake gift box on hand, you might as well take a little quiz: Open the gift box. In addition to the mooncakes, does it also come with knives, forks, plates or other products? Counting outward from the packaging bag where the mooncakes are placed, can you count the four layers? If the answer is yes, then the mooncakes in front of you are very likely to violate relevant national standards due to &quot;excessive packaging&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This standard is the &quot;Restrictions on Excessive Packaging of Goods Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021) revised and issued by the State Administration for Market Regulation (National Standards Administration), and will be officially implemented on September 1, 2023. The No. 1 revision of the standard further proposes regulations to restrict excessive packaging of moon cakes from four aspects: packaging void ratio, number of packaging layers, packaging cost, and mixed packaging requirements. It has been implemented on August 15, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Modification Order No. 1, mooncakes should not be mixed with other products, and the packaging should not exceed three layers. For mooncakes with a sales price of more than 100 yuan, the proportion of packaging cost in the sales price shall not exceed 15%. At the same time, precious metals, mahogany and other precious materials must not be used in packaging materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a one-year transition period, are mooncakes still over-packaged? Southern Weekend reporters randomly surveyed the mooncake gift box products on e-commerce platforms and found that the phenomenon of mixed packaging was the most prominent. Some merchants also played tricks on product descriptions to avoid relatively strict mooncake management standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Mengjiao, an engineer at the Beijing Haidian District Metrology and Inspection Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that mooncakes, as a traditional Mid-Autumn Festival food, evoke images of family reunions rather than exquisite packaging. Although mooncakes have certain social attributes, Gift recipients also hope that mooncakes will be worth their money. The implementation of the new national standard can encourage manufacturers to focus on the innovation of mooncakes themselves and ban overly exquisite and complicated packaging. However, there are still some businesses that &quot;take advantage of loopholes&quot; and the relevant departments need to strengthen supervision. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The hardest hit area of ​​mixed mooncakes: cultural and creative and co-branded gift boxes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mooncake gift boxes contain plastic knives and forks, which was once a &quot;routine practice&quot; for Cantonese-style mooncakes , after the introduction of new regulations prohibiting mixing, except for food deoxidizers and ice packs used to protect mooncakes, all products including knives and forks are not allowed to appear in mooncake gift boxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investigation by Southern Weekend reporters found that there are still many mixed products in the mooncake market in 2023, with the mixed packaging of cultural and creative products and co-branded gift boxes being the most prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the well-known food brand Daoxiangcun launched a mooncake gift box co-branded with Xiaotu Shuner IP. The gift box contains Daoxiangcun mooncake filling package and DIY mold, and provides tutorials on making mooncakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;774&quot; height= &quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 5, 2023, Daoxiang Village and Chen Xiaotao launched mooncake gift boxes with mixed DIY molds. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Tmall Daoxiangcun flagship store/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some catering brands have also launched mixed gift boxes, and have repeatedly explored the upper limit of 500 yuan. In June 2022, the National Development and Reform Commission, the State Administration for Market Regulation and other four departments jointly issued the &quot;Announcement on Curbing &quot;Sky-High Price&quot; Mooncakes and Promoting the Healthy Development of the Industry&quot;, proposing to implement key supervision on boxed mooncakes with a unit price of more than 500 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-end chain brand Dadong and Liu Qingyang, a scholar of fine-brush painting in the Song Dynasty, jointly launched the &quot;Dong Zhiyue·Lixiang Collection&quot; mooncake gift box. The gift box contains seven mooncakes and a hanging painting, with a marked price. 468 yuan (398 yuan after discount). There are two options under the product category. Although it is called &quot;Mooncake Filling Type&quot;, Dadong e-commerce customer service told Southern Weekend reporters that the mooncake types in the two gift boxes are the same. The difference lies in whether the painting received is &quot;Hundred Species of Peonies&quot; or &quot;Hundred Species of Peonies&quot;. &quot;Wu Tong Double Moon Rabbit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to food brands, some cultural and creative customization businesses are also testing the bottom line of excessive mooncake packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a store on the Taobao platform that specializes in customized holiday souvenirs has launched a Mid-Autumn gift box that is divided into different combinations of packages. The package comes with 2 herb-flavored mooncakes as standard, and consumers can also choose aromatherapy. Various contents such as tablets, oolong tea, perfume, greeting cards, etc. are mixed and packed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height= &quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A cultural and creative custom shop sells Mid-Autumn Festival souvenirs that are a combination of &quot;mooncakes + cultural and creative&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Taobao store/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Cultural and creative products managed in accordance with mooncake standards, as long as they contain products other than mooncakes, they are Mixed packaging. If a gift box uses creative packaging, and the packaging itself can be used for other purposes (such as a storage box with a mirror, a board game board with toys), you also need to confirm whether the gift box is managed according to mooncake standards.&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Confusing pastries and mooncakes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;A new way to avoid punishment&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Restricting Excessive Packaging of Goods Requirements for Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021) National Standard Modification No. 1 sets out requirements for mooncake packaging, but not all mooncake gift boxes are &quot; Real mooncakes”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters discovered that the &quot;Moonlight City&quot; chocolate mooncake gift box launched by the local chocolate brand Novan contains a mix of knives, forks and plates, and the monthly sales volume on the e-commerce platform exceeds 4,000 pieces. However, the product packaging provided by the brand&#39;s customer service to Southern Weekend reporters showed that the product&#39;s food name is &quot;mooncake-type chocolate products&quot; and is managed with reference to chocolate and chocolate products standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;787&quot; height= &quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 2, 2023, Novan e-commerce customer service told Southern Weekend reporters that except for two styles, other chocolate mooncake gift boxes contain mixed knives, forks and plates. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Tmall Novin flagship store consultation page/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters randomly selected 10 different brands on the e-commerce platform There is a problem with the mixed packaging of mooncake gift boxes. Although three of the gift boxes are marked with the word &quot;mooncake&quot; during marketing and the food is in the shape of a traditional mooncake, in fact the products are in compliance with pastry standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Yandan, Standardization Section of Beijing Haidian District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, told Southern Weekend reporters that the sales packaging of all food (including bulk food) and cosmetics produced, sold and imported in my country is subject to the &quot;Restrictions&quot; Requirements for Excessive Packaging of Goods Food and Cosmetics” (GB 23350-2021). Southern Weekend reporters found out that according to the No. 1 amendment, the packaging requirements for moon cakes and rice dumplings are more stringent. Except for moon cakes and rice dumplings, there are no restrictions on the mixing of other foods and cosmetics. This means that although foods such as pastries and chocolates are subject to the new national standard’s restrictions on excessive packaging, they can still be mixed with other products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current recommended national standard for mooncakes (GB/T 19855-2015), mooncakes are defined as using wheat flour and other cereal flour or plant flour, oil, sugar (or no added sugar) as the main raw materials It is processed into a pie crust and wrapped with various fillings. It is a traditional festival food mainly eaten during the Mid-Autumn Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In this case, if it is actually judged to be other pastries but sold as mooncakes, then the actual product may not match the description. It is necessary to further confirm whether the food sold is consistent with its labeling.&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said , usually, the product name, implementation standards, food production license number, etc. on the label of pre-packaged food can be used as the basis for judgment, or the competent department can make a comprehensive judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that there is also a type of merchants who deliberately blur the concepts of mooncakes and pastries in their product descriptions, disguising &quot;real mooncakes&quot; as pastries in an attempt to circumvent the new national standard&#39;s requirements for mixed packaging of mooncakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Yandan, Standardization Section of Beijing Haidian District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, told Southern Weekend reporters that according to the provisions of Article 27 of the &quot;Standardization Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, &quot;Enterprises should organize production and operation activities in accordance with standards. The products produced and services provided should comply with the technical requirements of the company&#39;s public standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to judge whether mooncakes are over-packaged? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Inspired by &quot;The Jade Rabbit in the Toad Palace&quot;, the gift box uses hollow patterns on the front and back, and is decorated with lighting, like holding the bright moon into your arms.&quot; This introduction comes from a new Chinese-style packaging. The highlight is the mooncake gift box containing keywords such as &quot;high-end&quot; and &quot;gift-giving&quot;. The product is priced at 358 yuan and has attracted hundreds of people to buy it on the e-commerce platform. There are many buyers recommending &quot;the outer packaging is beautiful&quot; in the comment area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an ordinary consumer, how should we judge whether the mooncakes we buy are over-packaged? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Standard Modification No. 1 of the &quot;Restricting Excessive Packaging of Goods Requirements for Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021), four indicators can be used to determine whether moon cakes are over-packaged: number of packaging layers, packaging Cost, mix, and packaging voids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height= &quot;1503&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of packaging layers refers to the number of layers that completely wrap the contents The number of layers of packaging that can be physically separated, where complete wrapping refers to a packaging method that prevents the package from falling apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If it is an open handbag, a half-pallet that fixes the contents or packaging, or a girdle outside the packaging box, it does not meet the definition of a complete package and cannot be counted as a layer. And the drawer type Packaging, even if there are two layers of drawers, is only counted as one layer of packaging. For creative mooncake packaging with exquisite and complex packaging but the number of layers meets the requirements, you can further determine whether the packaging cost is in violation,&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The packaging void rate is calculated based on the net content of the mooncake. The greater the net content of a single piece of mooncake, the smaller the void rate specified by the standard. For mooncakes with a single piece of net content greater than 50g, the void rate must be ≤30%. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mengjiao said that due to the complicated calculation method, packaging void ratio is generally tested by technical institutions in the laboratory on random samples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Municipal Administration for Market Regulation told a reporter from Southern Weekend that since August 2023, the Shanghai Municipal Administration for Market Regulation has carried out excessive packaging supervision and spot checks on mooncakes sold in the city’s market, involving supermarkets and bakery chains. A total of 80 batches of mooncakes were randomly inspected at 52 production and business units, including hotels and restaurants. The main reason for mooncake packaging violations was that the packaging void rate was unqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPG China Chief Economist Bai Wenxi told Southern Weekend reporters that cracking down on excessive packaging will help reduce consumers’ purchase costs and improve shopping experience. It can also reduce consumers’ behavior of buying high-priced mooncakes, thus reducing the price of mooncakes. Social waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the Shanghai Municipal Bureau of Market Regulation that consumers can use the WeChat applet &quot;Packaging Youdu&quot; developed by the Shanghai Municipal Bureau of Market Regulation to enter simple information about product packaging in just 1 minute. That is, it can be preliminarily determined whether the product is suspected of excessive packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“异域星球”墨石公园丨指尖华夏⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257593]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Moshi Park is located at the junction of Kama Village and Zhonggu Village, Daofu Bamei Town, Garze Prefecture, Sichuan Province. &lt;span>;5&lt;/span>; square kilometers, with an altitude of about &lt;span>;3500&lt;/span>; meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With its unique mylonite forest landscape, Moshi Park is like an &quot;exotic planet&quot;, attracting many tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[绝杀日本队，中国女篮亚运会夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 5, in the women’s basketball final of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, the Chinese team finished with &lt;span>;74- 72 defeated the Japanese team and won the gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253066&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253067&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雨林中的玛雅遗址：“巴黎”与霸主丨古国多少事⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257360]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As one of the three ancient civilizations in the Americas, the Mayan civilization once had many city-states in the tropical jungle, but it was restricted Due to the development of the natural environment and technology, just like a string of small oasis countries in the deserts of the Western Regions in ancient China, they were unable to unify and grow. In the end, they were vulnerable to an ecological crisis and withered at the same time. They were covered in dust by the returning tropical rainforest for thousands of years... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been fortunate enough to travel to Central America to visit nine Mayan city-state ruins located in three countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for Mexico and El Salvador, the other Central American countries where the Mayan ruins are located - Guatemala, Honduras and Belize - have not yet established diplomatic relations with our country, and relatively few Chinese have been there, but this area is precisely The hinterland of the Mayan civilization in its heyday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copán&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Copán)&lt;/span>; was my first stop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The ancient town of Flores, Guatemala, the last religious center of the Mayan civilization. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Paris of the Mayan World - Copan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Copan ruins are located in western Honduras The border is about five kilometers from Guatemala and no more than fifty kilometers from El Salvador. Not far to the west of the ruins is a border town called Copán Ruinas &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Copán Ruinas)&lt;/span>;, which is Spanish and means &quot;Ruins of Copan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan was the heyday of the Mayan civilization &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (250-900 AD, also known as the Classical Period)&lt;/span>; The most important city-state in the southeast. During the Classic Period, the Maya experienced Tikal&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Script_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Tikal)&lt;/span>; and Calakmul&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体,楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Calakmul)&lt;/span>;A long-standing confrontation between two powerful city-states, both located in the Yucatan Peninsula&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体,楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Yucatan)&lt;/span>;In the central part, one south and one north, separated by dense jungles, there have been continuous battles. Perhaps in order to expand its territory and resources, Tikal expanded to its rear in the early fifth century and established the city-state of Copan in a river valley in the middle of the Mesoamerican isthmus. The two sides formed a solid alliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan was placed in the twelfth place in the mid-seventh century &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (roughly corresponding to the period of Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty in China)&lt;/span>; It entered its heyday under King Chan Imix K&#39;awiil (r. 628-695)&lt;/span>;. Yanbao ascended the throne at the age of 15 and reigned for 67 years, the longest among the seventeen kings of Copán. His successor Uaxaclajuun Ub&#39;aah K&#39;awiil (reigned 695-738)&lt;/span>; in that era He is also considered a birthday boy, and he reigned for 43 years &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (same as Tang Xuanzong Li Longji)&lt;/span>;. The two kings ruled for a total of 110 years. During this period, Copán was transformed from a river valley city-state into an emerging empire, controlling a number of vassals and opening up trade routes to the Caribbean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the good times did not last long. Due to the large-scale construction and militarization of the Eighteen Rabbits, Copan, which had limited strength but overexpansion, quickly fell into crisis. In the middle of the eighth century, a rebellion similar to the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot; broke out: Batu was attacked by his cronies who had been placed in the small vassal state of Quirigua&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Quirigua)&lt;/span>;. -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(K&#39;ak&#39; Tiliw Chan Yopaat)&lt;/span>; Switched sides and rebelled. He was caught off guard and lost the battle. He was captured alive and taken to Quirigua, where he was captured in the main square. Beheading as a sacrifice - modern historians have noticed that two years ago, the monarch of the city-state of Calakmul made a special visit to Rainy Day, thus speculating that Calakmul may have planned and funded the rebellion behind the scenes. , the purpose is to cut off the right-hand man of the feuding Tikal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of Eighteen Rabbits, Copán, which was countered by Quirigua, has since gone downhill, although it once had a close relationship with Palenque, a large city-state in the west&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Palenque)&lt;/span>;The marriage tried to make a comeback, but the decline of the national destiny was irreversible. At the beginning of the ninth century, the history books of Copán stopped updating, and the river valley city-state suddenly declined and quickly disappeared into the resurgent rainforest vegetation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thousand years later, the American archaeologist Stephens &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(John Stephens)&lt;/span>; and the British painter In 1839, Frederick Catherwood &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Frederick Catherwood)&lt;/span>; found the Copan ruins in 1839 based on the legends of the Mayan indigenous people. He made this comment on the ruins in the jungle:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is laid out in front of us, like a broken ship in the ocean. The ship, its mast is gone, its crew is gone, no one knows when it came or what destroyed it, everything is a mystery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Grand Plaza of Copan, with the &quot;Stairs of History&quot; covered by a canopy on the right. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Copan ruins we see today are only a small part of the core area of ​​the city-state of Copan. It is around the large square that served as the political, religious and cultural center of the Mayan city-state. There is a small pyramid in the center of the square. On the north side are eight stone statues more than two meters high, six of which are carved with eighteen rabbits. These stone carvings are reminiscent of the architectural decoration style of South Asian temples: the details are extremely complex and gorgeous, but overall they lack highlights and personality. Perhaps it can be called Mayan Rococo style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the southeast side of the pyramid is a kickball court. Cuqiu is a unique sports competition of the Mayans and a noble sacrificial activity. Due to the lack of literature, it is not yet fully understood how it is played. It is generally believed to be a bit like today&#39;s volleyball. Players from both sides take turns hitting a solid rubber ball that symbolizes the sun. They are not allowed to touch the ball with their heads, hands and feet. Instead, you can only hit the ball with your elbow, hip or knee, hitting the ball behind the opponent, or causing the opponent to be unable to save the ball and lose points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the annual Quidditch game at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry in the &quot;Harry Potter&quot; novels has a sure-fire setting for capturing the Golden Snitch, the kickball game also has a sure-fire rule. The kickball court is rectangular, with a high wall on each side of the long side. There is a stone ring at the top of the center of the high wall, which is similar to the &quot;basket&quot; in the basketball court, except that the basket is not horizontal, but vertical. , and the position is quite high, it is absolutely impossible for players to take off and dunk; the holes in the ring are also very small, only slightly larger than the diameter of a rubber ball. In the kickball game, if the player successfully passes the ball through the stone ring, he wins and the game ends immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the outcome of the kickball players, historians are still debating. Some people think that the loser will have his heart disemboweled and sacrificed to the gods. The other side has the opposite opinion and believes that only the winner can obtain this supreme thing. of glory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cu stadium we see today is the third-generation stadium in the history of the city-state of Copan. It was built under the edict of the Eighteen Rabbits. Its two predecessors have been buried under its feet. This golf course is also the second largest golf course excavated in the Mayan world so far, second only to the Chichen Itza Stadium in Mexico. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The court is played, and the high platform in the background is the royal temple of the King of Copan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the southeast side of the Cui Stadium is a spectacular &quot;Historic Staircase&quot;, which consists of 2,500 half-meter square There are 63 stone steps, about 30 meters high and 10 meters wide, with a slope of nearly 60 degrees, very steep. Each stone is engraved with Mayan hieroglyphics - the entire stone step records the history of the city-state of Copan from its establishment until Eighth century history. In order to protect the cultural relics from the sun and rain, a plastic canopy was erected above the &quot;Historic Stairs&quot;, which affected its appearance and internal lighting. Visitors are also unable to climb and can only look up from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Directly south of the main square is a hill. The top of the mountain was once a temple. When kickball games and sacrificial ceremonies were held, the royal family of Copan looked down on the people from here. In its heyday, Copan had 27,000 people. Thousands of residents are indeed worthy of the title of “ten thousand peoples”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entire Copan ruins are not very big and can be browsed in two hours. Any place that is fenced with ropes or covered with plastic sheets is worth a closer look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan is known as the &quot;Paris of the Mayan World&quot; and is famous for its exquisite carvings and developed culture. So why did it suddenly fall during its heyday? Was it just because it suffered a rebellion? According to the results of archaeological excavations, the decline of Copan is actually the inevitable result of ecological deterioration, and the wasted national power of the Eighteen Rabbits only accelerated this process. The city-state is located in a fertile and narrow river valley, surrounded by steep mountains and low soil fertility. With the rise of city-states and rapid population growth, the limited farmland in river valleys could not sustain their food needs, so people went to the mountains in droves to clear up wasteland. The royal family also cut down a large number of mountain trees for fuel and made plaster to smear on palace buildings for waterproofing. As a result, local Vegetation has dropped sharply, the ecology has deteriorated, and mountain landslides have occurred repeatedly, submerging fertile farmland in river valleys and further reducing crop yields. Eventually agricultural production collapsed, and the city-states were abandoned and turned into large rainforests again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The stone macaw sculpture above the court&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is dusk , the few tourists dispersed one after another, and I sat on a high platform beside the golf course, with a stone sculpture of a macaw head above my head. Quietly watch as the large square gradually becomes a paradise for macaws. They either glide in groups and chirp freely, or perch in pairs on branches, preening each other&#39;s feathers lovingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen hundred years ago, the Mayans used macaws as their totems and held fiery and bloody kickball games under their curious gaze. Nowadays, the Mayan civilization has disappeared, but the macaw is still the master here, and it has never changed for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The overlord of the Mayan world - Tikal&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Tikal ruins are located in the Mayan rainforest in northern Guatemala. To the north and west is Mexico, a large country in Central America, and to the east is Central America. The only English speaking country is Belize. Due to the deep grass and forests, the borders between the three countries were drawn using latitude and longitude lines, and a square rectangle was drawn on the map of the Yucatan Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far south from Tikal is Lake Petén Itzá, which is shaped like a hammerhead shark. )&lt;/span>; and its south coast island Flores &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Flores)&lt;/span>; - the last religious center of the Mayan civilization , it was not destroyed by the cultural genocide atrocities of Spanish colonists until the end of the seventeenth century. The closest airport to Tikal is built on the land southeast of Flores Island: Mayan World International Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I took a Saab 340 twin-turboprop plane from Guatemala City—probably the smallest commercial airliner I have ever flown in, with only thirty seats—under the intoxicating sunset over the lake and sky. We landed here and drove 70 kilometers to the Tikal ruins early the next morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tikal Temple No. 1&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tikal is a Mayan temple One of the two unparalleled heroes who stood side by side with Calakmul during the classical period of civilization. The surrounding terrain is low-lying and densely covered with swamps, and Tikal is a low hill with neither drought nor flooding. It has become a rare livable place in the Yucatan Peninsula, which is generally short of water. It has been there since at least the seventh century BC. Inhabited by the Mayans. About a thousand years later, the Maya world entered the Classical Period. With the rich local obsidian resources, Tikal could not only build sharp weapons to improve its own combat power during times of war, but also sell them to other city-states for profit in times of peace, so its national power grew rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through international trade, Tikal originated from Teotihuacan, a large country located in central Mexico There, I learned how to fight with spears. I no longer need to fight with the enemy face to face. Instead, I surround the enemy and kill them by throwing spears. This achieves a &quot;long-range strike&quot; to a certain extent, thus significantly reducing our own casualties and more effectively reducing our own casualties. Become the overlord of the Mayan world with advanced military ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Teotihuacan sent an expeditionary force to raid its students at the end of the fourth century - the straight-line distance between the two places is more than a thousand kilometers, which is equivalent to the Tang army relying entirely on boats and walking&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Teotihuacan and Mayan civilizations failed to invent wheels and vehicles)&lt;/span>;, carrying all weapons and equipment and food and grass supplies on their shoulders, starting from Chang&#39;an Expedition to Tuyuhun on the Qinghai Lake - and once fully controlled the political and military power of Tikal. But the two places were too far apart after all. Teotihuacan, which started out on the Mexican plateau, could not establish itself in the humid monsoon rainforest of the Yucatan Peninsula for a long time, so Tikal eventually regained power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of the Copan ruins is the beautifully carved stone statues, while the highlight of Tikal is its tall pyramid. Although limited by ancient construction technology, the pyramid of Tikal cannot reach the sky, but at least it can tower through the forest. Standing on the top of the pyramid, you feel as if you are standing on the tip of a sharp sword, piercing through the endless mountains. Rainforest canopy. If you imagine the lush forest canopy as clouds, then these pyramids are like Shushan Mountain breaking through the clouds and coming out through the clouds, giving people a very majestic feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tikal Temple 1-3&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;mentioned Are there any differences between pyramids, Mayan pyramids and Egyptian pyramids? The Egyptian pyramid, as its name suggests, is similar to the Chinese character for &quot;gold&quot;. It is a square pyramid composed of a square base and four isosceles triangles. The Mayan pyramid looks similar to the Egyptian pyramid at first glance, but if you look closely, you will find that it is not the same. A pointed cone without a top, its cross-section is an isosceles trapezoid, as if a small pyramid was cut off from the top of a large pyramid. The base is not always square. For example, several large pyramids at the Tikal site have rectangular bases, and the Uxmal site in Mexico also has the Warlock Pyramid with an oval base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are there no pointed cones on the top of the Mayan pyramids? This is related to the different functions of the two types of pyramids. The Egyptian pyramid is a pharaoh&#39;s tomb, with a hollow interior, and a tomb chamber is built to store the pharaoh&#39;s mummy; the Mayan pyramid is the base of the temple, and the purpose of building it is to highlight the sublimity of the temple. Therefore, the Mayan pyramid is generally solid, in order to leave To build a temple in space, a platform must be left at the top, so there is no top cone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the different functions, the shapes and sizes of the two types of pyramids are also quite different. There is a temple on the top of the Mayan pyramid, and the priests need to go to the altar to perform rituals or observe the stars at night. Therefore, there are stone steps on both sides of the Mayan pyramid or on the central axis of the front, rear, left, and right sides; while the Egyptian pyramid is a pharaoh&#39;s tomb and does not require climbing to the top. , so there is only the entrance to the mausoleum at the bottom, and there are no stone steps leading to the top cone. Also due to sacrificial needs, Mayan pyramids are generally not high. The tallest Tikal Temple IV is only 64.6 meters, which can be said to be dwarfed by the Egyptian pyramids: Egypt&#39;s tallest Pyramid of Khufu was 146.6 meters high when it was built. After 4,500 years, Due to the erosion of wind and sand, it is still 138.8 meters high, more than twice the height of Tikal IV Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the amount of construction earthwork is proportional to the cube of the size, the Mayan pyramid is an order of magnitude smaller than the Egyptian pyramid, so the amount of building materials and engineering required is much smaller than the latter, and the number of constructions is much higher. the latter. According to incomplete statistics, there are more than 100,000 Mayan pyramids in Mexico alone, while there are only more than 100 pyramids in Egypt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are four most important pyramids in Tikal, including one on the east and west sides of the main square, which means a couple looking at each other. Temple No. 1 on the east side was built in the mid-eighth century and is 44 meters high. It is a rare mausoleum-shaped pyramid in the Mayan world. It is the burial place of the famous Zhongxing master of Tikal, the Double Moon King _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil I, reigned 682-734)&lt;/span>;, he led the city-state through the jungle to defeat the old enemy Calakmul in 695, leaving the latter unable to recover, and could only rely on Small tricks such as secretly fomenting rebellion and weakening Copán were used to relieve military pressure from Tikal, and Tikal entered its second heyday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;210475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shuangyuewang Stone Stele Relief&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. 1 The stone steps of the temple are narrow and steep, causing at least two tourists to slip and fall to their deaths. Tourists are now prohibited from climbing. Temple No. 2 on the west side is also a mausoleum, where the queen of the Twin Moon King, Lady Twelve Macaw, is buried. >;. Her mausoleum is six meters shorter than her husband&#39;s pyramid, and the stone steps are wider. However, direct climbing is prohibited. Instead, wooden steps are built behind it for visitors to walk up to the top of the tower and overlook the elegant and quiet grand square. There are more than twenty stone pillars erected in the square. They have the same function as the stone statues in the main square of the Copan ruins. They are used to commemorate the achievements of the previous kings. However, the stone carving art of Tikal is far inferior to that of Copan, so there are no stone statues here but only stone pillars. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tikal&#39;s Temple No. 3 is located on the west side of Temple No. 2. The front of its base has been covered by vegetation, and it is like a slope, buried in the dense jungle, but it is 55 meters high. The top of the tower stands majestically, far higher than the surrounding trees, giving viewers a strong shock with the tenacious struggle between nature and manpower across the vicissitudes of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the Tikal temple we see today is the product of archaeological excavations, stripping away its trees, cleaning up its soil, and repairing its stone steps. When the European archaeological expedition first came here in the early 19th century, all the pyramids looked like Temple No. 3 now. At first glance, they were nothing more than steep mountains that suddenly rose up from the flat ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Temple No. 4 is located at the western end of the core area of ​​the site. It was built in 741 by the son of the Twin Moon King. It is the tallest temple in Tikal and the tallest building in the Mayan world. Looking eastward from its top platform to Temple No. 1, No. 2, and No. 3, it is easy to get the illusion that the continuous tropical rainforest trees under your feet are just a patch of low bushes, while the three temples are like three stone monuments, rising from the bushes. The bushes stretched out tenaciously - the scale of everything suddenly shrunk here, and I seemed to have entered a miniature world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A temple in &quot;The Lost World&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Starting from Temple No. 4, I continued south deep into the rainforest, looking for the ancient pyramid &quot;The Lost World&quot; which was built in 700 BC &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;( El Mundo Perdido)&lt;/span>;. The number of tourists gradually decreased, and only me, a group of white-nosed coatis walking happily with their long tails wagging high, and the low roars echoing in the forest were the only ones left in the dense forest. At first I thought it was just the background sound played by the park through the loudspeaker - because if any carnivorous beast really made such a loud noise, it meant that it had arrived around me and could start hunting at any time - and I was surprised by the unique interest of the player, and later I realized that the breathtaking roar came from the branches above my head: two medium-sized howler monkeys were crawling back and forth anxiously, announcing the territory of their group with continuous roars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prosperous age created by the Twin Moon King lasted for nearly a hundred years. After entering the ninth century, the entire Mayan world entered a drought period that had not been seen in seven thousand years. Starvation was everywhere and the city-states were in ruins. As the largest city-state at the time, with a population of nearly 200,000 at its peak, Tikal declined rapidly after facing famine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last king of Tikal who went down in history reused the name of the Twin Moon King and called himself Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil II, but this did not allow him to defeat nature and revive the country&#39;s destiny. By the end of the 10th century, Tikal was reclaimed by nature, the cornfields no longer existed, and the majestic temples and tombs of the ancestors were covered by dense forests. From that time on, the howler monkeys established their homes in the center of the former city-state, making powerful sounds that could be heard several kilometers away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么全国大部分打印店都“姓”湘？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Walking into the university campus, if you find the print shop owner saying Don’t be too surprised when you hear the rich modulations of “Shapu”, because if you continue to pay attention, you will find that this accent can even be found in print shops in the streets and alleys across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hunanese are not only the leaders in the spicy food industry, but also have great confidence in the literary and printing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Xinhua County, located in central Hunan, has shouldered the heavy responsibility of the &quot;Wenyinxiang Army&quot;. According to statistics, Xinhua&#39;s printing and printing industry has captured more than 95% and 70% of the market share in the national universities and the national printing and printing industry respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks have opened stores across the country, but also Xinhuaren’s Wenyin Shop. Today, Xinhua Printing Industry has opened more than 150,000 picture and text express printing shops, more than 3,000 copier remanufacturing and distribution companies, and more than 2,000 consumable production and sales companies in more than 660 cities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason why Xinhua Wenyin has swept the country has to start with the small town of Yangxi. Many years ago, a Peking University doctoral thesis &quot;The Life History of Xinhua Copying Industry&quot; became popular on the Internet, which revealed the secret of how Xinhua people turned a piece of graphics into a 100-billion-dollar industry through &quot;teaching and mentoring&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This small town located in a corner has a tradition of &quot;supplementing agriculture with technology&quot; since ancient times. Yangxi people accidentally learned mechanical typewriter repair technology, then united a group of repair technicians to go nationwide, and then relied on repair technology to develop the second-hand copier business, gradually realizing iterative upgrades in the text and printing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the complete industrial chain of typing, copying, drawing, printing, printing equipment and remanufacturing, and consumable manufacturing and operation, more than 300,000 people Xinhua printing technicians have traveled all over the country. Under the impact of &quot;paperless office&quot;, Xinhua printing industry is still booming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From &quot;introduced manufacturing&quot; to &quot;independent intelligent manufacturing&quot;, Xinhua Wenyin is getting rid of the shackles and building the world&#39;s business card of &quot;Xinhua Wenyin&quot;. Today, independent intellectual property products such as high-speed inkjet blueprint machines are accelerating industry changes; Xinhua Printing has gone abroad and has settled its printing products in more than 80 countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mobile phone cases, stationery, mouse pads, background walls... These DIY personalized printings that are popular among young people have also become the &quot;get rich&quot; for Xinhua Wenyin people &quot;High-gloss&quot;, new printing products represented by Meow Meow Machine, 3D printing products, etc. have created more possibilities for Xinhua Printing. Today, Xinhua, known as the &quot;Chinese Capital of Printing and Printing&quot;, is still domineeringly declaring its own &quot;printing&quot; strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will take you to learn about the &quot;Hunan&quot; font size business that &quot;dominates&quot; print shops across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 21:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九华山：气象万千的水墨丹青丨眼睛在旅游⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257609]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在土耳其， 探访亚美尼亚的古都丨古国多少事⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257362]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 10/23/q1dtyKAs2YKSFdfv9IKNw2fhrYaiFkUwOMWBNhNQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/q1dtyKAs2YKSFdfv9IKNw2fhrYaiFkUwOM WBNhNQ. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Looking at the ancient city of Ani from a distance, there are three obvious buildings from front to back: a mosque, Cathedral, Church of the Savior. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;A European-style town in the Islamic world&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Kars is the Silk Road A quite alternative city in the western section. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After traveling in Pakistan and Iran for more than a month, I have already become accustomed to the mountains and the Gobi, the minaret and the Grand Bazaar, the call of dawn and dusk with black gauze and white hats, the lively markets and winding alleys... Enter Although the landscape in eastern Turkey changed to gentle slopes and the language changed to Turkic and Kurdish, the strong imprint of Islamic civilization has not weakened at all. But when you come to the northeastern border town of Karls, the cool and elegant cityscape, the streets with a checkerboard structure, the neat and straight stone roads, and even the bank branches shining warmly in the bleak autumn wind make people suddenly feel like they have traveled to a Nordic town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The unusual origin of Kars comes from: it was occupied by Tsarist Russia for 40 years from 1878, and was planned, built and managed in a European style. of Soviet Russia was ceded to Turkey. Before that, Kars was the capital of the middle Bagratid dynasty. It was successively occupied by the Byzantines, Seljuks, Mongols and Turks in the more than 800 years after the fall of the dynasty. The Bagratid Dynasty was a mini-version established by the only remaining nobles who took advantage of the gap between the Byzantine Empire and the Arab Empire after the once vast Kingdom of Armenia, which controlled hundreds of thousands of people, was divided by the Roman Empire and the Parthian Empire. The Armenian country has been a country for 160 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no Armenians in Kars today, but just a hundred years ago, 84.1% of the population here was Armenian. Because the Tsarist Russian government was relatively friendly to Armenians, people from Western Armenia (generally referring to the former Armenian territory in Turkey, corresponding to Eastern Armenia, which is now the Republic of Armenia and part of Azerbaijan) who suffered discrimination and abuse from the Ottoman Turkish Empire at that time migrated to Kars , especially during World War I, the Ottoman Turkish Empire implemented a genocidal policy against the Armenians in its territory, resulting in the deaths of 1 million to 1.5 million Armenians. This is known as the Armenian Genocide in history, and even prompted Western Armenians to flee to Kars for refuge. Unfortunately, the good times did not last long. After Soviet Russia ceded Kars to Turkey, the Armenians here had to embark on a journey of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My companions and I found a small hotel to stay in - the hotel sign on Turkey Street is easy to recognize, written as otel, which comes from the French word hotel with a silent h - we were preparing to take advantage of the sun yet. Go down the mountain to see the landmark here, the Seljuk Castle built in the 12th century AD, and Celil, the famous old fox of Kars, comes to visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey is a big tourist country, but tourists mainly go to the Aegean coast in the west, the Mediterranean coast in the south and Cappadocia in the center. Even the quiet and elegant Black Sea coast in the north is rarely visited. Not to mention eastern Turkey, which is adjacent to &quot;high-risk areas&quot; such as Syria, Iraq, Iran and the Caucasus. The rare few who make the long journey to Kars are undoubtedly to have a look at the ruins of Ani, and Celil, who has a keen sense of smell, specializes in these people&#39;s business. He can track every first-time tourist, and even the backpackers who spend a lot of money can be killed by him before they know the east, west, north, and south. Having said that, the number of tourists here is limited and it cannot support more tourism operators. The tourism transportation in Ani is not developed, so Celil has become an unavoidable broker for tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Celil speaks fluent English, and this skill alone is a talent that can only be encountered within a few hundred miles. He was going to personally take a group to Ani the next day, and he had no control over the two of us. He just wanted to find a car for us and a young man from Melbourne we met on the road to go to Ani, and charged 20 lire per person - I asked about the price for chartered cars, which was 40 lire. The Turkish lira has experienced a 50% plunge in 2018 and a 20% depreciation since the COVID-19 epidemic this year. Now it is only 85 cents in exchange for RMB, but at that time, 1 lira could be exchanged for more than five yuan. This chartered trip was equivalent to three hundred yuan. For the first time, Celil took a third of it - only after we were on the road did we learn that Celil actually asked the simple Melbourne boy for 5 liras more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, another Chinese tourist came to Karls, and he also got three people to charter Celil’s car to Ani. Celil has entered middle age from a young man, and has worked hard to innovate. He originally negotiated a charter price of 100 lire, but after the journey, he charged 50 lire per person. He actually wanted to ask the simple German guy for another 50 lire tip. He was evaluated as &quot;Malicious greed&quot; - I accidentally read this on the Internet and couldn&#39;t help laughing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/22/b2DP79UXKCZMTxHbuShKPAOxXNV7e2wIj5lSlXk8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/22/b2DP79UXKCZMTxHbuShKPAOxXNV7e2wIj5lSlXk8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;115783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Turkish breakfast in the European-style small town of Karls. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;A dynasty growing in the cracks&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Early the next morning, sitting In a small restaurant full of locals, I ate a basket of bread with a large bowl of soup made from mutton hamstrings - this is the Turkish version of Runan mutton soup breakfast, and then drove to the ancient capital Ani, 45 kilometers away. This place is located on the Armenian Plateau that connects the Iranian Plateau and the Anatolian Plateau. Along the way is still the typical temperate grassland in Central Asia. The herdsmen are stacking hay into pyramids five or six people high to prepare for the winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani, the destination of this trip, is the fourth and last capital of the Bagratid dynasty. It was the capital for the longest time, lasting 84 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking of the revival of the Bagratid dynasty in Armenia, Robert I, who led Scotland to regain its independence, is comparable to Robert I, who was capricious and devoted to family interests in the movie &quot;Brave Heart&quot;. The English invaders betrayed the leader of the rebellion, William Wallace, and then rebelled against the independent Scottish nobleman Robert the Bruce. This man was truly a generational hero known as &quot;Braveheart&quot; in history. Ashote I, the founding monarch of the Bagratid dynasty, was also such a figure. After the fall of the Kingdom of Armenia, the Romans and Persians fought on its territory for many years and were severely weakened. As a result, the newly rising Arabs came from behind and became the conquerors of the Armenian Plateau. In 705 AD, the Arab governor sent by the White-coated Food (Umayyad Dynasty) almost killed all the remaining Armenian nobles, and the Bagratid family survived; more than 40 years later, the White-Coated Food changed dynasties and became the Black-Coated Food (Abbasid Dynasty), sent troops to bloody suppress the uprising launched by the Armenians who took advantage of the chaos, eradicated the local civil resistance forces, and the Bagratid family, who had long been friends with the black-clad Caliphate, once again survived, and they have been together ever since. With its strong support, it became the most powerful political and military force on the Armenian Plateau, and also became a local force that foreign Arab rulers must rely on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was at this time that Ashuote I succeeded him as the family governor. On the one hand, the Arab Caliph supported him to neutralize the surrounding separatist forces and became the King of Armenia, hoping to use him to calm down the instability in the Caucasus Mountains so that he could concentrate on dealing with the Byzantine Empire to the west; on the other hand, the Byzantine Emperor Basil I hoped to win over the Armenian nation. They shared the belief in the Kingdom of God, thus forming a siege on the Black Era from the northern flank; on the other hand, Ashot I not only wanted to use the Byzantines to drive away the Arabs, but was also worried that the Byzantine Empire, which believed in Orthodox Christianity, would force the Armenian Apostolic Church to convert. , thereby threatening the legitimacy of his regime. Therefore, Asot I strictly adhered to the principle of keeping a low profile and double-dealing throughout his life. At the same time, he formed alliances with Byzantium and Arabia and watched the two empires fight in front of the Caucasus Mountains. He devoted himself to making Armenia bigger and stronger, and did not let the Arabs He had time to intervene in his own country&#39;s affairs and prevented the Byzantines from obtaining practical benefits from the Caucasus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first capital of Ashote I after the founding of the country was Bagaran, the base of the Bagratid family. After his son ascended the throne, he moved the capital to Shirakavan. Both places are on the east bank of the Aras River. Today, due to geopolitical changes, the Aras River is the boundary river between Armenia, Turkey, and Iran. More than a thousand years ago, it was the mother river of Armenia. The Bagratid dynasty located its first two capitals on the east bank of the Arras River in order to use the defensive function of the river to keep foreign enemies west of the river. When Abbas, the grandson of Asjot I, came to the throne and the Bagratid dynasty became more powerful, it moved its capital to Kars west of the Aras River to better protect the trade route from the Caucasus to the Black Sea and resist Byzantine aggression. Encroaching eastward. After Abbas&#39;s son Ashot III came to the throne, he moved the capital to Ani on the west bank of the Arras River. It never moved the capital again until the demise of the dynasty in 1045 AD. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/bPBS8zxe6WU5Oh5XfTtuJ7wW3oemOJsmjEPCCkip.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/bPBS8zxe6WU5Oh5XfTtuJ7wW3oemOJsmjEPCCkip.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Haystacks in Armenia&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian./Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Civilized Transfer Station&lt; /h3>; &lt;p>;The Kingdom of Armenia was the first Christian country in the world. After the resurgence, the Bagratid Dynasty continued the status of the Armenian Apostolic Church as the state religion and consolidated the legitimacy of its regime by sending large amounts of donations to the church. As a result of this approach, the ancient capital Ani was once dotted with churches and was known as the &quot;City of One Thousand and One Churches&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another title of Ani is the &quot;City of Forty Gates&quot;, which refers to its vast area and abundant business travel. But today there is only one north gate left in Ani. The later conquerors, the Seljuqs, built an outer wall around the north gate to form a corridor-like urn city, which improved the defensive function of the city gate. This only remaining city gate was named after the Seljuk Sultan Arslan who captured Ani in 1064, and was called the Gate of Arslan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to defend the city of Ani with only one gate left? Out of the way. The terrain of Ani is very similar to the Jiaohe Ancient City in Turpan. It is located on a platform formed by three deep rivers. There are almost dry deep valleys to the east and west, and the steep Alas Valley to the south, forming a natural moat. Only the north has a road leading to the outside world. In the era of cold weapons, it was really a great pass that was easy to defend but difficult to attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani is located at the crossroads of the Caucasus Mountains to the south, Persia to the west, Mesopotamia to the north and Asia Minor to the east. Its location is very important. In addition, it is adjacent to the Arras Valley and has abundant water resources. The trade routes in the Volga River Basin that crossed the Caucasus Mountains merged into the junction of the Silk Road, thus witnessing the rise and fall of ancient civilizations one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Armenians, the Byzantines attacked Ani three times in history until they captured the city in 1045. Afterwards, Ani became an important eastern town in the Byzantine Empire equivalent to the capital Constantinople. , there were 100,000 residents living on this platform in its heyday, marking the Caucasus entered its commercial heyday under Byzantine rule. Unfortunately, the good times did not last long. With the decline of Arab power in Central Asia, the Seljuqs rose rapidly and occupied the ecological niche of the Arabs. They then defeated the bloated Byzantine army in the west and captured Ani in 1064, starting from there. Asia Minor turned the Caucasus into its own backyard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Seljuks left, Ani was successively occupied by the Georgians and Kurds. It was not until 1239 that the short-lived Mongols conquered Ani. This was the last time the city was captured—— A major earthquake 80 years later destroyed most of the buildings in the city, forming the ruins we see today. In addition, the Ottoman Turkish Empire straddled the east coast of the Mediterranean and the Balkan Peninsula, cutting off the Silk Road between Western Europe and East Asia. As a result, Ani&#39;s status as a trade center no longer existed and it declined rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Ottoman Turkish Empire gradually declined in the 19th century, Ani and Kars fell into the hands of Tsarist Russia for a time, and only returned to Turkish hands after World War I. During the Cold War era, this was the border between the Warsaw Pact and NATO in Asia. Once the Soviet armored forces broke out of the Caucasus mountains, they would flood into the Anatolian Plateau. This has become Turkey&#39;s nightmare for many years. Both Turkey and the Soviet Union stationed heavy troops along the Arras Valley, and Ani was under military control for 40 years as an important border defense area. It was not until the collapse of the Soviet Union, Armenia&#39;s independence, and the disappearance of the military threat faced by Turkey that control policies were relaxed. But at first, tourists still needed to apply in advance before entering the ancient city of Ani, just like my country&#39;s border permit system, which was canceled after Erdogan came to power in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/M7uFh32a7tGHPnbFFt1BeaF1sF8obd5ei15Qulmt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/M7uFh32a7tGHPnbFFt1BeaF1sF8obd5ei15Qulmt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The ruins of the ancient city of Ani can overlook the rocky village on the opposite cliff, giving you a sense of Cappadocia. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The city of one thousand and one churches&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The ancient city of Ani has been abandoned for several years For centuries, the landform has basically returned to its original appearance in ancient times. Only a dozen of the most magnificent and solid ancient buildings remain, which have withstood the test of time and natural disasters and stand quietly in the grass, silently displaying the civilizations left by different eras. imprint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;St. Gregory was the founder of the Armenian Apostolic Church. He was imprisoned in a dungeon for 13 years by King Tiridates III of Armenia. Finally, he used miracles to convert the king and established the world&#39;s first Christian country. , so he is regarded as the patron saint by the Armenians. There are three churches named after St. Gregory in Ani. Among them, the one near the north gate is also called Abughamrents. It was built in 994 AD and has a conical roof and 12 walls on the facade. The niche is a typical Armenian architectural style and is very eye-catching on the withered yellow grassland. From here, you can overlook the rocky villages on the opposite cliff to the west, giving you a sense of Cappadocia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another Armenian-style church is the Church of Redeemer. Although it is small in size, it is the most fascinating place in the city of Ani. This church was built between 1034 and 1036 AD to store the &quot;True Cross&quot; gifted by the Byzantine Empire, which is the legendary fragment of the cross that crucified Jesus Christ. The &quot;True Cross&quot; is like the Buddha&#39;s relic in Buddhism. It is not uncommon in the Christian world, and its authenticity is doubtful. The Church of Our Savior is fascinating because it has stood for more than 900 years and has survived wars and earthquakes. It is the only well-preserved ancient building in the entire ancient city of Ani. However, it was accidentally struck by lightning in 1957, leaving only half of the outer wall. Standing among the rubble with the vault, it looks like a warrior whose skin has been eroded but whose skeleton is erect, showing a unique desolate beauty in this thousand-year-old ruins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/AnOBp9f1cSPaiSZ0p20VdlU05RZgqZof8D9x9qNt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/AnOBp9f1cSPaiSZ0p20VdlU05RZgqZof8D9x9qNt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Church of the Saviour&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most magnificent church in Ani is The Byzantine-style Ani Cathedral was designed by Trdat Mendet, the master architect who presided over the reconstruction of Hagia Sophia in Constantinople. Construction started in 987 AD and took 24 years to complete. This cathedral looks inconspicuous from a distance, like a magnificent mansion. When you walk into the church and take a closer look, you will find that it combines grandeur and exquisiteness: the grandeur is reflected in the tall red and black basalt columns inside - Byzantine style architecture. The main purpose of the architect is to use height to create a gap in a limited space, so that believers will feel awe; the exquisiteness is reflected in the meticulous carvings everywhere in the church, making believers sigh for the perfection of heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hagia Sophia, Ani Cathedral was converted into a mosque by the Seljuq conquerors who believed in Islam, named &quot;Victory&quot;. After the Seljuks left, the Georgians and Armenians turned it back into a church, and after the Turks came, they turned it into a mosque again... After several rounds of sawing, the vault, which was the soul of the Byzantine church building, collapsed, and so No one cares about this cathedral anymore, and it stands alone overlooking the rushing Aras river below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/lfbdpmz14PYzPWK93qkeod9h4xfYb7bYbF7rJJBv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/lfbdpmz14PYzPWK93qkeod9h4xfYb7bYbF7rJJBv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cathedral&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another St. Gregory the Great in the west of the city The church was also built by Trdat Mendet, which makes me suspect that this is a character similar to the water conservancy engineer Zheng Guo at the end of the Warring States Period, who was sent by the Byzantine Empire to consume the national power of the Bagratid Dynasty. Its vault design is exactly the same as that of Hagia Sophia. Unfortunately, it collapsed not long after it was built, and now only a huge circular base and a pile of rubble remain. On its northeast side is a Georgian church, and on its east side is the Zoroastrian temple left by the Persians, which is the oldest architectural remains in the entire city of Ani. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third St. Gregory the Great Church in Ani was built in 1215 and was funded by a wealthy Armenian businessman. It witnessed the final glory of Ani. Just over twenty years later, the Mongols came over, slaughtered all the civilians, and turned the castle into a camp. Later Turks called this church Resimli Kilise, which means mural church. It is hidden halfway up the valley and is not easily visible from the mesa. There are long Armenian inscriptions on the outer wall of the church, and a large number of early Christian murals are preserved inside. The lines are elegant and smooth, and there is no dullness in such religious propaganda paintings of the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/E4yrX2ktkjLLaMKgpJm3Usst2dieC7leGjLqgIt2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/E4yrX2ktkjLLaMKgpJm3Usst2dieC7leGjLqgIt2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116066&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fresco church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/4LIZWpuDi030WkfHTln9fYPMfPNCJBPE0YEv4FpA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/20/10/23/4LIZWpuDi030WkfHTln9fYPMfPNCJBPE0YEv4FpA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116067&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mural church preservation The murals &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, let’s talk about the marks left by the Seljuks. The first is the Church of Holy Apostles built by the Armenians. The Seljuks actually opened a new arch in it, which is transparent from north to south, and turned into a large car shop for resting caravans. But because of this, the church escaped the war and fire, and its internal structure and decoration are well preserved. Its rib arches, carvings and mosaics can still be clearly seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a red-brown building on the cliff south of the ancient city. From a distance, it looks like a rectangular factory building with a large chimney. The architectural style is very different from the surrounding Armenian or Byzantine churches, but the color scheme is similar. This is actually the first mosque in Turkish history. It was built by the Seljuqs in 1072. It adopts the Armenian red and black color scheme. The &quot;big chimney&quot; is a minaret, but the top of the tower has collapsed. . The mosque overlooks the Arras Valley. There is the Monastery of Our Lady and the Broken Bridge at the bottom of the valley. Armenia is on the other side of the river. Since Turkey and Armenia are feuding countries, they have not yet established diplomatic relations, and the borders between the two countries are naturally closed to each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/B8ZQc7lMGZjtNY5ZNJBgRpcHaIH7tvYTzzZCJw8j.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/B8ZQc7lMGZjtNY5ZNJBgRpcHaIH7tvYTzzZCJw8j.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ancient city of Ani was listed as a A world cultural heritage, it is not only a witness to Armenia’s long civilization, but also a shining pearl on the Silk Road. Austrian art historian Josef Strzygowski once commented on Ani: Only the genius who built Hagia Sophia (Byzantium) and St. Peter&#39;s Basilica (Rome) can truly understand the importance of the Armenian pioneers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, blocked by ethnic hatred and geopolitics, Armenians are only separated from this thousand-year-old capital by a river, but they cannot visit it. Coincidentally, Mount Ararat, the spiritual totem of Armenian civilization, has also been assigned to Turkey. Armenians can only look up from outside the border at the foot of this perfect cone-shaped volcano. Although they are close at hand, they cannot take a step closer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani and Ararat are the cultural roots of the Armenian nation that are elusive! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[关注 | 2023诺贝尔奖揭晓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258135]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 18:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>; Starting from October 2, the list of 2023 Nobel Prize winners will be announced one after another. This year’s prize will be increased to 11 million Swedish kronor, approximately A total of RMB 7.23 million. The scientific highlight of the year, when human stars shine, from mRNA vaccines to attosecond pulsed light to the discovery and development of quantum dots... Behind some esoteric terms, the next future of the world may be hidden.</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>