<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[过度加工食物可能成瘾并严重影响健康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCyJ69RpVgzEp0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCy J69RpVgzEp0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over-processing of food refers to industrial production and the addition of at least 5 or more ingredients, additives (usually sugar, stabilizers, preservatives, preservatives, pigments), etc., in this way Processed foods are called ultra-processed foods. Their purpose is to make them delicious and convenient, and more importantly, manufacturers can earn higher profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessively processed foods include soft drinks such as cola, bread, cakes, potato chips, pizza, biscuits, candies, burgers, instant noodles, ice cream, spicy sticks, etc. More and more research results show that the intake of overly processed foods may be harmful to human health and increase the risk of various diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recent study by Brazilian researchers suggests that overly processed foods may harm brain function. The reason is that overly processed foods contain many added and unhealthy ingredients such as sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors and preservatives. Past research has shown that overly processed foods are directly linked to an increased risk of heart disease, metabolic syndrome, and obesity, and now research is linking overly processed foods to a risk of decreased brain function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers collected data on nearly 11,000 men and women in Brazil with an average age of 52 who participated in the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health. The researchers followed them for a long time, with a median follow-up time of 8 years. The results found that participants who consumed more than 20% of their daily calories from ultra-processed foods experienced a 28% faster decline in overall cognitive function and a 25% faster decline in executive function compared to adults over 59 years old. In other words, the decline in cognitive function and executive function is more obvious among adults aged 35-59. Overall, overall cognitive functions include learning ability and memory, while executive functions include language fluency and behavioral agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the researchers admit that they cannot yet explain the mechanism by which excessively processed foods lead to reduced brain function, and there is no neuroimaging to confirm their results. Therefore, future research is to explore which overly processed foods lead to cognitive decline in the body and the molecular mechanisms behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation, however, is that when people regularly consume overly processed foods, they are less likely to get the fiber, microbes, minerals, and plants they need to stay healthy, fight off disease, and reduce inflammation. Nutrients. Ultimately, this may affect a person&#39;s brain function and functioning, as the brain requires a steady supply of these nutrients to function properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed foods have also been linked to cancer. Researchers from Imperial College London have found that high intakes of ultra-processed foods may increase an individual&#39;s risk of developing cancer and dying from cancer. Previously, a large number of studies have revealed that consuming large amounts of overly processed food will increase the incidence of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Now, British researchers have used the British Biobank to collect dietary information from 200,000 young people to study the relationship between body health and diet. This is the first such study to be conducted in the UK. The researchers monitored the people&#39;s health for 10 years, analyzing their risk of developing any cancer and 34 types of cancer, as well as the participants&#39; risk of dying from cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers conducted the most comprehensive assessment to date of the link between overly processed foods and people’s risk of developing cancer, including soda, industrially produced bread, and more. Ready-to-eat meals and most breakfast cereals. These foods often contain high levels of salt, sugar, fat, and artificial additives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that people who eat a lot of overly processed foods are at a greater risk of developing cancer. Overly processed foods are particularly related to ovarian cancer and brain cancer. They also increase an individual&#39;s risk of death from cancer, most obviously. of ovarian and breast cancer. For every 10% increase in a person&#39;s intake of overly processed foods in a person&#39;s diet, the overall risk of cancer increases by 2%, and the risk of ovarian cancer in particular increases by 19%. It is associated with a 6% increase in overall cancer mortality, a 16% increase in the risk of death from breast cancer, and a 30% increase in the risk of death from ovarian cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The association between excessively processed food intake and cancer remained after adjusting for social, economic, behavioral and dietary factors such as smoking, physical activity and body mass index (BMI). Furthermore, previous research has shown that British adults and children consume the highest amounts of ultra-processed food in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the study by British researchers cannot explain the causal relationship and mechanism between over-processed foods and cancer, they believe that existing research evidence shows that reducing the intake of over-processed foods in the daily diet may avoid Higher cancer rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed food has become widespread around the world and is addictive. A research report published in the British Medical Journal on October 9, 2023 by researchers from the United States, Brazil, and Spain pointed out that an analysis of 281 studies in 36 different countries found that 14% of adults and adults worldwide 12% of children are addicted to over-processed foods, and 1/7 adults and 1/8 children may be addicted to over-processed foods. These foods include ice cream, carbonated drinks and convenience foods, which can lead to cancer, obesity and Increased risk of heart disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the consumption of ultra-processed foods is soaring around the world, and now more than half of the daily energy intake in the UK comes from ultra-processed foods. In the United States, ultra-processed foods account for 58% of Americans’ energy intake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that so many people eat over-processed foods suggests that they are addictive. Researchers explain the addiction to over-processed foods as higher levels of dopamine secretion may lead to over-processed foods. of addiction. Extracellular dopamine levels in the brain&#39;s striatum caused by refined carbohydrates or fats are similar to those of addictive substances such as nicotine and alcohol, thus creating a craving similar to alcoholism. Therefore, foods that contain high amounts of refined carbohydrates or added fats are likely to be addictive substances. The speed at which these overly processed foods deliver carbohydrates and fats to the intestines may also play a role in their addictive nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Symptoms of addiction to over-processed foods include: strong desire to eat, withdrawal symptoms, difficulty controlling food intake, and obesity, overeating, poor physical and mental health, and reduced quality of life. Despite this, he continued to eat without restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of this suggests that the relationship between overly processed foods and health, as well as the addictive nature of such foods, should be further studied, and appropriate measures should be taken to protect people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京香山论坛：大国小国，平等对话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 10:06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Ten&#39; means maturity, perfection, harvest, and also indicates a new starting point and renewal. Let’s go.” On the morning of October 30, 2023, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, told officials from the defense departments of many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held from October 29th to 31st, reaching the highest level and largest scale in history - more than 90 official delegations from countries and international organizations participated, including 19 defense ministers , 14 military commander-level representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the podium at the opening ceremony, the &quot;ten&quot; in &quot;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum&quot; was painted in red. In the audience, foreign defense ministers, representatives of international institutions and experts are looking forward to an &quot;international security event&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/01/7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01 /7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256571&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Great powers play a more important role”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nine o’clock in the morning on October 30, the main venue on the second floor of the Beijing International Convention Center was packed with seats. Dozens of defense ministers and senior representatives from various countries in military uniforms sat in the front row of the auditorium; the back row was divided into two floors and filled with nearly a thousand experts, observers or media members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot; is marked with white letters on a blue background inside and outside the venue - this is the theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum and the core idea of ​​the Global Security Initiative in February 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Youxia pointed out that without mutual respect, it will be difficult to coexist peacefully, and common security will be out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 19 defense ministers participating in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu was the first speaker. Before the opening ceremony, Shaoyigu and Zhang Youxia walked into the main venue side by side and sat in the center of the first row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Russia-China relations are exemplary and are increasingly attractive to other countries.” Shoigu mentioned, “The circle of friends between Russia and China who do not want to be involved in the Western confrontation agenda is constantly expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a country involved in the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Shoigu’s attendance attracted much attention. He mentioned that after Russia countered NATO&#39;s eastward expansion, the United States was using Ukraine to attack Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Russia will only use nuclear weapons when it is attacked by a nuclear attack or when its national survival is threatened.&quot; Shoigu said in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the second time that Shaoyigu has attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The last time was in 2019. After the meeting, Zhang Youxia held talks with Shaoyigu at the Bayi Building in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/c2f75269a6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/c2f75269a6.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256572&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speeches of the guests at the first plenary session all closely followed the theme of &quot;Responsibility of Major Powers and Global Security Cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is important to strive for peace. In promoting global peace and security, major powers play a more important role.&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong said in the second half of the first half that major powers promote peace and make war a Obsolete things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“From Asia-Pacific to the Global”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening ceremony, defense ministers and representatives from various countries arrived in Beijing one after another. As the organizer, Zhao Xiaozhuo, deputy director of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum Secretariat, is extremely busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 21:00 on the evening of October 29, when Southern Weekend reporters met Zhao Xiaozhuo, he had just finished the welcome dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the first forum, Zhao Xiaozhuo still has fresh memories. &quot;At that time, most of the participants were scholars, and the total number of participants was only a few dozen, so it was very small.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Xiangshan Forum was founded in 2006 and is hosted by two think tanks from the Chinese military, the China Society of Military Science and the China Society for International Strategic Studies. In 2014, the forum was upgraded from track two (private) to track one and a half (semi-official, semi-private). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since then, military and political leaders and national leaders will appear every year, and the conference has been adjusted from once every two years to once a year.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to online meetings during the epidemic, the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum attracted official delegations from more than 90 countries and international organizations including Russia, the United States, Saudi Arabia, and Iran, with more than 1,800 participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 9 forums, there have been as many as 6 forums with the theme of &quot;Asia-Pacific&quot;. With the major changes in the nature of the forum, the scope of topics has also expanded from Asia-Pacific affairs to global issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xinbo, Dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University, is a frequent visitor to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. Since the first forum in 2006, he has attended the forum almost every year. He said, &quot;The theme of the forum is increasingly consistent with China&#39;s core concepts and basic principles of international security, and the topics of the sub-forums are also increasingly consistent with the current actual international security situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256573&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30 On the same day, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 30, ten small closed-door seminars were held simultaneously, covering topics such as global security governance, artificial intelligence security, and Sino-US crisis management and control. &quot;It has never happened before that ten meetings can be held at the same time.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;It is up to the participating representatives to choose which forum they want to go to, who they want to talk to, and how much they want to talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Chande, a researcher at the Institute for Defense Analyses and former deputy assistant secretary of defense, is an &quot;old friend&quot; of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and a well-known &quot;China expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I pay attention to China every day, and my understanding here may be deeper than that of the United States.” He told Southern Weekend reporters with a smile before the “Northeast Asian Order” sub-forum. The United States first sent official representatives to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum in 2015. Four years later, in 2019, then-U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense Shi Chande led a team to attend the meeting. It was the first time that a current senior U.S. military official appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the early days, the U.S. delegation’s participation in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum was relatively low, and basically only the military attache from the embassy in China was sent to participate.” Wu Xinbo recalled that as the importance and influence of the forum increased, the United States began to start from domestic Send some mid-level delegations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Similar to the Shangri-La Summit and the Munich Security Conference, an official&#39;s rank determines his stage. This is a common international practice.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;After lower-level officials arrive, they are often only responsible for collecting information. Various opinions and information.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the U.S. military delegation was led by Owen Lewis, dean of the Joint Forces Staff College of the U.S. National Defense University; previously, the president of the U.S. National Defense University also led a delegation to Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Carles, senior director for China affairs in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense of the United States, took over the &quot;baton&quot; from the head of the delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The levels of Carles and Shi Chande are almost the same, but in terms of specific ranking, Shi Chande is higher.&quot; During the welcome dinner, Zhao Xiaozhuo specially analyzed the level setting of U.S. officials to the U.S. Navy Feng Dewei, vice president of the center, asked for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calles, the official leader of the US delegation at this forum, kept a low profile and rarely appeared in public. On the evening of October 30, she appeared at a small seminar on &quot;China-U.S. Crisis Management&quot;, but did not speak. She only briefly communicated with the participants after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;the level of the participants in the forum is not the most important matter. The communication between the two parties focuses on the substantive content.&quot; Wu Qian, spokesperson of the Ministry of National Defense, pointed out at a press conference held before the opening of the forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;International Issues &quot;Desktop Collision&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:00 on October 29, half an hour before the official start of the meeting, the conference room with less than 100 people was packed with people from all over the world. Representatives, experts and media, etc. This is a dialogue titled &quot;China&#39;s Role in Maintaining Asia-Pacific Security.&quot; Under the chairmanship of Wu Xinbo, experts from China, the United States, Russia and South Korea took their seats in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why can the Asia-Pacific maintain stability for thirty years?&quot; The host first asked the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, a former Chinese diplomat, shared &quot;the reasons for the Asia-Pacific economic miracle&quot;: peace and stability, focus on regional cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She gave data from the Bank of Asia, &quot;In the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown seven times. Nearly half of it was created by China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the United States&#39; GDP has grown seven times. Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Project at the Western Institute of National Affairs, believes that &quot;the change of power between China and the United States will bring huge uncertainty to Asia. In the next 10 to 15 years, the process of peace and stability in Asia may be disrupted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen&#39;s view was refuted by Fu Ying: &quot;Today, China is the driving force of the development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited greatly from it, but now this has become a problem?&quot; Fu Ying said, The United States has launched a &quot;China-US trade war&quot; that has more gains than losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen during the celebrity dialogue on October 29. (Photo by Yao Yijiang/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256574&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the celebrity dialogue on October 29, Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen. (Photo by Yao Yijiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Russian expert Karaganov mentioned that &quot;Russia wants to create a peaceful and stable Eurasia and Asia-Pacific.&quot; Karaganov is the dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This scene better reflects the current international security situation.” After listening to the whole process, Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Northeast Asia Security Trends and Shaping&quot; parallel forum on the afternoon of the 30th, explosive scenes took place one after another. American scholar Shi Wen and Director of the Asian and African Studies Department of the Japanese Defense Research Institute Masuda Masayuki were criticized by Chinese scholars one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Northeast Asian issue depends on the interaction of multinational relations between China, Japan, the United States, and South Korea.” Shi Wen said. He was the third speaker at this forum, and there were also scholars from China, Russia, South Korea and the UK. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen flicked the tablet on the armrest of his seat, trying to regard the North Korean nuclear issue and the Taiwan issue as the same type of regional conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the moderator of the sub-forum, Vice President of the China Institute of International Strategic Studies, and retired major general Du Nongyi made his point clear, &quot;The core of the Taiwan issue is China&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity. It has nothing to do with North Korea.&quot; Nuclear issues and other issues cannot be compared with each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half, Japanese scholar Masuda Masayuki became the target of public criticism because he blamed China for regional security problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang, senior adviser to the China Institute for International Strategic Studies, took the microphone and changed his original speech. He said that Masuda Masayuki was trying to teach the Chinese people &quot;a lesson&quot;. &quot;It is true that I am a little speechless.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang pointed out that the crux of the problem between China and Japan is rooted in Japan&#39;s psychological imbalance, trying to regard the Sino-US game as a &quot;rare opportunity&quot; to take action, and constantly pointing fingers at the Taiwan issue. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the rebuttal, Masuda Masayuki sat on the stage and smiled awkwardly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let developing countries have a voice&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the international public opinion field dominated by European and American countries, the voices of developing countries are rarely heard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although it is a global village, every country has its own goals.&quot; At the &quot;Chinese and Foreign Young Officers and Scholars Seminar&quot; on October 29, Chief Executive Officer of the Pakistan Balochistan Research and Development Think Tank Official Jawariya Tareen said frankly. The young American scholar next to her had a serious expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than seventy years, the India-Pakistan border issue has remained unresolved, and Kashmir has always been like a thorn in the relationship between the two countries. Jawariya mentioned that every time Pakistan wanted to have dialogue, India did not respond positively, and the relationship between the two sides only stopped at the think tank level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Developing countries face two major problems, one is development and the other is security.&quot; Lieutenant General He Lei of the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences told Southern Weekend reporters that in a sense, developing countries are the most important problems in today&#39;s world. The security demands of the &quot;vulnerable groups&quot; should receive more attention and reasonable concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, internationally renowned security forums include the Shangri-La Dialogue, the Halifax International Security Forum, the Munich Security Conference and the Seoul Defense Dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“These forums have obvious ‘circle’ attributes, and developing countries do not have much room to speak out.” Zhao Xiaozhuo mentioned that only the Beijing Xiangshan Forum clearly provides a stage for developing countries to fully express themselves. safety concerns and demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Representatives from various countries at the main venue (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256575&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Main venue representatives of various countries. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters observed that among the parallel group meetings and seminars, 5 of them were themed on developing countries and the &quot;Global South&quot;, and more than half of the speakers were from the development community. Chinese home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Global South&quot; is not a new concept. The term was first used by American political activist Carl Oglesby as early as 1969. &quot;European and American countries are using the Global South to exclude China from developing countries and isolate China to the maximum extent.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China occupies a very critical or even core position in the global South. China&#39;s success has become the most important driving force for the global South at the international level...China has been promoting peaceful development through the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; initiative, which can What is the United States doing?&quot; Zheng Yongnian, President&#39;s Chair Professor of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), asked on the morning of October 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With concerns about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, Selchuk Chorakkoglu, the founding director of the Asia-Pacific Research Center of Turkey, came to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused nearly 10,000 deaths on both sides, and there are also hidden dangers of spillover.&quot; Selchuk told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes to discuss how to discuss the &quot;new Middle East security architecture&quot; Providing new solutions to Palestine and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessio Patalano has participated in the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore and the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing for many times. He believes that the Beijing Xiangshan Forum is more &quot;pragmatic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This professor at the Department of War Studies at King&#39;s College London is very talkative. As soon as the forum began, Alessio was interviewed for an hour by the media who came to ask for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters that providing a platform for developing countries to speak out is one of the greatest advantages of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Defense ministers and representatives from various countries came to Beijing Xiangshan Forum with the vision of seeking peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Common security and lasting peace are the basis for the common development of all countries.” Itizal Khadim, director of the Afghanistan Development and Peace Research Center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Afghanistan, Itizal is a former government official who is now a professor of modern political history. He joked to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;I came to the meeting wearing two &#39;hats.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36 million people in Afghanistan are suffering from extreme poverty and hunger. &quot;Only by creating jobs for the people, they will not turn to war.&quot; Itizal hopes that China can participate in the reconstruction of Afghanistan. &quot;China can help developing countries promote economic and social development instead of distributing gunpowder.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Liu Yaqi, Lin Xi, Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi, Feng Jiayi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4 P4YXsf2grzoKpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (third from right) in his later years with friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu ended his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; with an encounter in middle age. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At night, he was driving on a narrow highway with only one car in front of him. He lacks confidence in his driving skills, so he uses the taillights of the car in front of him as a guide to gain a sense of safety and comfort. Suddenly the car flashed its right turn signal and turned into a country road. Visible to the naked eye, he was the only one driving on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;So, only my own headlights are left to guide the way. This light can only illuminate a very small area. It is a short road, but this road, farther away, is swallowed up in darkness.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Tuan is a famous geographer and the founder of humanistic geography. One of the people. He intellectually understands the relationship between people and place and considers himself a cosmopolitan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; was written in 1999, when Duan Yifu was 69 years old, and mankind was about to enter the new millennium. He sees &quot;Who am I&quot; as the fashionable question at the dawn of the new millennium. This issue actually received increasing attention as early as the 1960s, &quot;In order to generate a solid sense of self, a person needs the past, not just the present and the future.&quot; It is worth mentioning that &quot;Silent Spring&quot; combined poetry and science in the 1960s to jointly examine the relationship between man and the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu continued to think about it and wrote important works in the next twenty years. &quot;who I am? 》 is a good stage summary, showing sincere self-examination. He seems to be getting closer and closer to a location, but he is not sure when he will arrive, or even further away. The ideal position always changes with time, space and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early 1940s, Duan Yifu and his family were preparing to move from Chongqing to Australia. During the group photo, Yifu Duan (third from left) tried to squeeze away from his younger brother and stay close to his mother to gain more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The world in his eyes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is shrinking inward &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, Yifu Tuan quoted the words of Socrates: An unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before middle age, Duan Yifu had never lived in any city for more than five years. After leaving China, he continued to move around until he moved to Minneapolis at the age of 38 and stopped to engage in academic work. Migration is inseparable from both my father&#39;s work and historical events. He believed he was rootless and &quot;born to examine himself.&quot; He never married and could not fully integrate into American society, and his identity issues were always there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He considers himself an optimist and &quot;often places the golden age in the future.&quot; He knows that he gained his confidence early, having been relatively unscathed by racism while living abroad, and that later in life he began to question its source. His various ways of dealing with the world are closely related to the events he has experienced and the environment in which he lives. The book reveals his own “sense of place”—emotions and judgments about specific places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his first interview at Indiana University in 1956, an Asian history professor was surprised by his family background. Duan Yifu recalled his childhood memories and was sure that the other party was not joking. According to what he heard, the Duan family was divided into two branches in modern times, both in Anhui. Duan Yifu&#39;s family belonged to the poor branch, and his father Duan Maolan relied on his uncle Duan Qirui from the Hefei branch to fully fund his studies at Nankai Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu was born in Tianjin. From the age of 7 to 10, he lived in a village on the outskirts of Chongqing due to the war. His family was financially distressed. The school is a single room belonging to a power station. The place smelled sour and rancid, and the fetid mud dragged at his shoes. He was disgusted and horrified. Occasionally he encountered a funeral procession, with the bodies of the guards wrapped in bamboo mats. There is a rooster tied to it, which will crow if the corpse is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1954, Yifu Duan conducted field research in Arizona, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small schools are different places, where students learn about the history, Culture and Technology. Wilde&#39;s work &quot;The Happy Prince&quot; left an indelible mark on him, and he knew: &quot;&#39;Good&#39; can no longer be limited to fulfilling social obligations.&quot; These realizations inspired Duan Yifu to think, and he was always exploring how to determine a person&#39;s position in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu mentioned some important historical figures in his narrative. Duan Maolan and his alumnus Zhou Enlai wrestled with each other&#39;s arms to test whether the other&#39;s injured arm was healed. Zhang Boling, the principal of Nankai Middle School, had a rare refrigerator and distributed trays of ice cubes to everyone. In order to save them for him, his father used the folk remedy of spreading salt to delay melting. The adults are still thinking about how to treat their distant relative Wang Jingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu has conflicting emotions about his father. He longs for love, but is disappointed by his father&#39;s preference for his brothers; he remembers the tenderness of the difficult times, but is also traumatized by his father&#39;s severity or anger. The most profound memory of my father is even just a childhood nightmare, and the scene in the dream has remained for many years:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;I opened my arms and wanted to hug him... What happened? But a ghost stood in front of me. It could be seen that it was my father, but he was covered in mourning clothes. This ghost was in the ever-changing airflow It was moving in the middle, weightless. It was an evil ghost, a corpse, with yellow light in its empty eyes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impression his mother left on him was warm and tough. , it’s a pity that she passed away prematurely. At the same time, Duan Yifu became increasingly sensitive due to his physical condition, and he became very ill for a time. He confessed his cowardice and unwillingness to participate in social change activities. Even in the face of racism and rude boys who treat him as a &quot;little girl,&quot; he has no motivation to actively fight back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world in Duan Yifu&#39;s eyes is shrinking inward. When he was a child, he was exposed to all kinds of extraordinary events. When he grew up, the war ended and he had to face many personal problems. He summed up this growth experience as moving from the universe to the stove, and used beautiful writing to integrate life and academia. He quoted the words of the poet TS Eliot:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All of us, in our lifetime, have heard and seen , why does everything you feel (a bird singing, a fish leaping, an old woman walking on a mountain road) be reproduced with emotion, but other things are not?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;Youth Yifu Tuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you willing to be a lonely captain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Poetry can break through the barriers or boundaries of language logic.” Liu Su told Southern Weekly. He used this to describe the beautiful words written by Tuan Yifu. He translated &quot;Love Land Complex&quot; and &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;Two books by Yifu Tuan, and I am currently translating &quot;The Divided World and Self&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student around 2010, Liu Su often suffered from having no books to read. Many times he was attracted by the ideas mentioned in the book, but could not find relevant Chinese or even English translations. He tried his best to find the original work, went to Douban to ask Douban friends who had read the book, and also went to the library, but he might only be able to make half a copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I might as well translate it myself!&quot; Those experiences inspired Liu Su&#39;s enthusiasm. He thus embarked on the path of academic translation, and future college students will no longer face the dilemma of reading. At the same time, many scholars have also participated in the translation and introduction of geography classics. The Chinese translations of scholars such as Tuan Yifu and David Harvey are enough to be compiled into a collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2021, in the crowded Chongqing subway, Liu Su received a WeChat message from another translator Zhicheng, asking him if he was willing to translate &quot;Who Am I?&quot; 》. Even though the air conditioning was sufficient, he still broke out in a hot sweat: &quot;This book will finally be translated into Chinese!&quot; He had seriously considered that he was not willing to live a lonely life as a &quot;foreigner&quot; in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; ” resonated with Liu Su’s heart. He experienced a long single life. When he got married, the children of his classmates were almost in junior high school. He may have experienced Duan Yifu&#39;s loneliness and his self-statement: &quot;I spent a lot of time in poems and essays about the sadness of spring and autumn, and spent them in places like libraries and coffee shops.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su finished class, said goodbye to the students, and went to the library for a while after walking out of the teaching building. Even if I don’t write anything, I would still like to sit in the corner and experience what Yifu Duan said: “Living on campus almost all my life, surrounded by young people, makes me feel happy physically and mentally.” He sometimes goes to a nearby coffee shop and sits by the window, looking at the pedestrians, vehicles and street lights, feeling that loneliness is far away. The sensibility of exquisite language gathers together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, Yi-Fu Tuan wrote &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;The previous year&#39;s work &quot;Escapism&quot; asked: What is the greatest escape? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you lower your head and manage the environment around you with a heart that loves your neighbor, you can also look up at the vast starry sky.&quot; Liu Su talked about his understanding of this sentence and added a more realistic side, &quot;As a scholar, like him, I often look up at the starry sky of metaphysical thoughts and theories. However, whenever I look down at my single life, I often feel like I&#39;m in a mess.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot; 1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (1930-2022), an internationally renowned Chinese geographer, was born in Tianjin and graduated from Oxford University. He returned to China in his later years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su is looking for descriptions of single life in books. Yifu Tuan made his apartment simple and warm, dressed modestly and appropriately, maintained good health and longevity, had good interpersonal relationships, and gained precious friendships. However, &quot;he once dreamed that he died alone at home, and no one found his rotting body.&quot; Duan Yifu always writes about his loneliness, a complicated feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps the reason is that loneliness is the most authentic way of human existence. The state of not being lonely is actually the product of escape.&quot; Liu Su quoted the saying of &quot;Escapism&quot;. There are three questions surrounding Yifu Duan&#39;s life: &quot;I am mortal&quot; that has lingered since childhood; &quot;Who am I&quot; related to individual consciousness; and &quot;What is a good life&quot;. Yifu Tuan wrote &quot;Geography saved me&quot;. Geography was like a road that led him to understand himself and the problems of human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Translation of &quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; also allowed Liu Su to gain &quot;a friendship worth cherishing.&quot; After the book launch, he, Zhi Cheng, editors and readers friends braved the heavy rain and went into a noodle shop to chat. Five people each signed five books and kept them. He also wanted to write his feelings into a longer email and share it with Duan Yifu. Before the email was finished, Duan Yifu passed away in August 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tuan Yifu published a new book that year, and finally wrote: &quot;I would like to advise you again, young traveler! You must be full of courage to operate your own ship like a captain, even though it is only Life&#39;s puzzling clues and stars serve as your guide.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su was devastated by his mistake, but would continue to translate classics of humanistic geography. He also asked himself if he was willing to be a lonely captain and walk on a narrow road. No matter what the answer is, Tuan Yifu&#39;s book &quot;will always be projected into the heart of every reader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where is the real home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu recalled in the preface of &quot;Going Home&quot; that people often asked him where he thought the real hometown was. . He answered lightly: &quot;In general, it&#39;s the earth.&quot; &quot;Where on earth is it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the meaning of the question is probably: there must be a place where he is most comfortable, The most yearning, can form the deepest sense of belonging. &quot;Some specific landscapes do have great appeal to me, such as a landscape that transcends aesthetics - the desert. I feel that I am very close to the desert psychologically, and I can even regard it as my home.&quot; Yifu Duan again and again Once I wrote about my love for the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in the winter of 1954, Yifu Tuan was conducting field research for his doctoral thesis in southeastern Arizona. The research object was the desert terrain called the foothill erosion surface. When optimistic British student David Harris joins the group, the physical and spiritual hardships of the wilderness thin out and are gradually replaced by friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This relationship brings me satisfaction, but it also causes insecurity—almost all relationships of any depth involve both. Why? Is there something wrong with me? ?&quot; Duan Yifu asked in the book. In 1962, they collaborated again. He remained single and became a teacher; David married and had two daughters. &quot;The David today is a broader, more elusive personality than I knew before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following description is sensitive and stinging, and such feelings appear repeatedly in the book . They each drove to Chaco Canyon to investigate, with Yifu Duan leading the way and David&#39;s family following behind. At dusk, maybe David knew the route, maybe the children needed care, David&#39;s car honked, kicked up dust and drove ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The distance between us became wider and wider, and soon, all that was left in front of my eyes was the raised The dust was gone, and in the end, even the dust was gone. I fell into a lonely shadow... When I tried to catch up with the Harris family, I felt lonely and painful for the first time. What&#39;s worse, I I even feel ridiculous. What on earth was I doing on a dirt road in New Mexico? Chasing a young family in a car?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yifu Tuan&#39;s eyes, friendship must meet two basic requirements: The conditions—like-mindedness and sympathy—should be balanced in an ideal friendship. &quot;If overly oriented toward shared interests and interests, these two people may become more like colleagues than friends; conversely, they may be more like lovers, staring into each other&#39;s eyes rather than into the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Shy people, unsociable people, or people like me who have their social needs suppressed by eccentric pursuits, perhaps should devote themselves to Nature...maybe only by staying in an inorganic environment, such as deserts and icebergs, can people feel relaxed and happy, and forget the good and the bad.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Duan also wrote about the German Alexander von Humboldt. Humboldt was the founder of modern physical geography. He “made outstanding contributions to the development of geodesy and was the first to use painting and poetry to develop human geographical experience-feelings, emotions and concepts, which are the core of humanities. The starting point of socialist geography”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt lived to be 90 years old and was full of energy throughout his life. In his sixties, he could still travel through Siberia and Central Asia. He enjoys socializing, but has never been married, and has been trapped in emotional entanglements with men three times. He wrote in a letter to the married soldier Reinhard von Haften: &quot;Even if you reject me and look at me coldly, like a stain, I still want to be with you. ...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I leave the universe, or to be precise, leave the harmony of nature and the joy brought by human beings&#39; ultimate achievements, my life will become miserable and I will not be able to survive.&quot; Yifu Duan listed He felt all kinds of human misery, &quot;But, I don&#39;t want to stay in those shadows for a long time...&quot; He believed in the light, the beauty of the universe, and the beauty and kindness of events. The next chapter is &quot;Geography Saved Me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, taking the opportunity of attending an architectural conference, Yi-Fu Tuan returned to China after 60 years of absence and deliberately stayed for a while. He wrote a book called &quot;Going Home&quot;, which was translated into Chinese by Zhicheng. During the trip to Chongqing, he once again mentioned the nightmare that had plagued him throughout his life. When his father passed away in Taipei in 1980, he did not go back to see him for the last time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the autobiography is the contrast between the dim light of the car lights and the vast darkness. That is not despair. Duan Yifu is still looking at himself. He asked the translator to attach his speech notes in 2012 as an updated understanding of &quot;who I am.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no so-called ordinary people in the world. The people you talk to every day are actually people with immortal souls... They joke with us, work together, and get married, but they are also ignored and exploited by us. All people are actually people with immortal souls. Among these people, some are immortal and terrifying, and some are immortal and brilliant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Maybe it has been too long, he I really forgot&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot;Yu Shiyi, the editor of &quot;WeChat,&quot; appeared somewhat silent - just like when communicating with text on WeChat - but soon opened up the situation, became talkative and humorous. His daily schedule was very regular and he even added a short period of time that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later he added that he should not talk too much about his own story, and autobiographers should be given more space. So, this part is an extra chapter of this article. People are always faced with questions such as &quot;Who am I?&quot; The questions and answers constantly change with the situation, each covered with attractive colors. For example, the great director Bergman claimed that he knew less about himself than he did ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi has unique feelings about discrete events. In early 1949, the Taiping shipwreck occurred in the waters west of Daishan Island where he was born. When he was a child, he had no idea about this tragedy. He only learned about it through documentaries when he left his hometown to attend college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, approximately 125,000 young men, soldiers, and 25,000 civilian personnel and civilians moved to Taiwan from Zhoushan, later forming the first generation of Zhoushan people of 20,000 to 30,000 people. The initiators of Taiwan’s Veterans Return Movement in 1987 were Zhoushan people. Before the “Three Direct Links”, it was very difficult for them to contact their homeland. The local historical materials exhibition hall uses an entire wall to display letters forwarded by the Red Cross at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Islands shape cognition. Yu Shiyi left Zhoushan for Ningbo ten years ago, and then went to Shanghai to study. When I was growing up, there was no cross-sea bridge in Zhoushan. When a typhoon came, the island became an isolated island, physically and psychologically isolated from the rest of the world. Compared to county towns, provincial towns, and cities, visitors from small islands seem to be “small” and marginal. At first he longed to merge from the margins into the mainstream, but now he wants to have subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As an immigrant, your regional identity is the first thing that is mentioned when you arrive in a new environment.” Yu Shiyi has a friend who was born in Hubei and grew up in Shenzhen, and later moved to Shanghai. He asked: What is the local accent of “other”? In 1973, 43-year-old Yifu Duan officially became a U.S. citizen. He has been living in the United States for nearly two decades, debugging himself as a &quot;cosmopolitan and a thinker writing about discrete subjects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the little grandpa - my grandfather&#39;s younger brother - talking about the past during the Chinese New Year. He claimed that he once drove a simple diesel-powered boat from Qushan Island to Dongjiadu, Shanghai, in one night. Alone, without a GPS, all I have is experience and a compass. Yu Shiyi could not imagine the plight of the fishermen. Wouldn&#39;t they be scared if they were wandering around without land? He wrote down his boundless imagination in his notes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The lanky man drove a small sampan from the island Set off and drive northwest, through night and day, to Dongjiadu. The lighting system at that time was not perfect, and there was no positioning system. Some waterways were almost dark at night, but he arrived at his destination safely without saying a word about the wind and waves he encountered. I think maybe too much time has passed and he has long forgotten the ups and downs along the way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I remember that there is a famous lighthouse on Flower and Bird Island. I wonder if he passed by it. Under certain conditions, There will also be the wonder of the fluorescent sea. I always feel that the waterway from my hometown to Shanghai is full of mysterious powers. I once took a ferry from the island to Shanghai. I landed ashore at dusk and landed at dawn. It was the first time I saw the waves gurgling like spring water and seagulls soaring in the sky. Looking out from the small round glass of the third-class cabin, there are faint lights. Maybe I have seen the lighthouse of Flower and Bird Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked the tribesmen, have you gone ashore? He said he had unloaded the goods but did not go up. I was so sorry. I wanted to get the secrets of Shanghai in the 1980s from him, but he said, it’s nothing. The Bund is just across the Dongjia Ferry Road. I can’t understand those Western things. At that time, everything could be bought by ticket, and the people were people on the water. , naturally cannot be obtained. He drove the sampan up the Huangpu River and finally reached Jiangyin. This was undoubtedly an adventure. As for what to do there and how to get back to the island, he stopped talking without saying a few words. Maybe it&#39;s been too long and he really forgot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Memories and narratives form fragments one after another, embedded in life. More than thirty years after my grandfather left Shanghai, Yu Shiyi also arrived in Shanghai. During the National Day holiday in 2022, he took a boat to the island with his father. The father was hesitant at first, after all, the house was no longer theirs. Many places are different. Old houses and new ones are popping up one after another. Fortunately, the road remains where it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi returned to the lane where he was born. The commercial house he bought more than 20 years ago was still there, but it was older. The back door was open, he went in and saw the washboard from many years ago. After all these years, it&#39;s still there, like a miracle. There was someone living nearby, and he was too embarrassed to disturb him, so he just wanted to go to the front door to take a look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the resident saw the stranger, he became alert and asked: &quot;Who are you?&quot; Yu Shiyi was stunned, silent for a few seconds, and instinctively replied: &quot;This is my home.&quot; He walked to the front door and took a photo Teru then left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have become the &#39;other&#39;.&quot; He recalled, &quot;There are physical things, and it used to be my home.&quot; He didn&#39;t know how many hands the house had changed. I felt relieved that I could finally say goodbye. For almost twenty years, he always thought of this home, worried about it, and was afraid it would be demolished. Now all the playmates and neighbors have left, leaving only photos and washboards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recognition and memory of your hometown, in turn, become the means for others to identify you. Not long after being asked &quot;Who are you?&quot;, in December 2022, Yu Shiyi took over &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;, the book will be launched at the Shanghai Book Fair in August 2023. The above is always a bit of an unexpected fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天安门下半旗悼念李克强同志]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259779]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:28:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKj lN5UvkjG6D. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Huanzong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 2, in memory of Comrade Li Keqiang, flags were flown at half-mast at Tiananmen Square in the capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”：是一种可鄙的价值观吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There are many serious and serious rumors circulating on the Internet. Some are old ones that have been refurbished and some are new. of. A relatively recent one is: The Chinese student&#39;s thesis &quot;You must endure hardships to become a superior person&quot;. As a result, the New Zealand professor gave a zero score and asked the soul question, &quot;Why should you become a superior person while others are inferior?&quot; What do people do? Why do you divide your compatriots into three, six or nine grades? Shouldn’t everyone be equal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you do some Internet archeology, it is not difficult to find that this is A piece of three-nothing news concocted by a certain self-media, with no specific time, university, or person. The motive of the fabricator is to use the words of foreigners who regard them as authoritative to show how low some Chinese people&#39;s words, deeds, and values ​​are, and how high their own preferred values ​​are. However, there are still many people who believe in this rumor that &quot;foreign monks like to chant sutras&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original version of &quot;Only when you have to endure the most hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The original version should be &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chapter 32 of &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. Tang Monk said: &quot;Disciples, be careful. If you encounter a high mountain ahead, you may be blocked by tigers and wolves.&quot; Sun Wukong said: &quot;Master, as a monk, don&#39;t talk at home. Do you remember the &quot;Heart Sutra&quot; written by Monk Wuchao, which says, &#39;If you have no worries, you will be free from worries.&#39; No fear, stay away from words that confuse dreams? But it is just to sweep away the dirt on the heart and wash the dirt on the ears. If you don&#39;t suffer in the suffering, it is difficult to be a good person. You should not worry, but there is an old man, even if the sky falls, you can Be safe. What are you afraid of?&quot; This was an education for the master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also from &quot;Warning Words to the World&quot;, &quot;It&#39;s Hard to Meet Your Husband after Spring Falls in the Yutang&quot;. I saw a couplet hanging on the door: &quot;After ten years of suffering in front of the window, he became famous all over the world.&quot; &quot;This is the couplet written by my father-in-law. He passed the national examination and became a minister: Later, our father was When I study here, I will become a minister. I am studying here now, and I also want to climb the dragon and the phoenix to carry forward the ambitions of my predecessors.&quot; I also saw a couplet on the second door: &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the hardships, it is difficult to become a master.&quot; The young master hurriedly returned. Study room...with my mind turned around and my determination to study diligently. This is a lot of self-motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between the two versions is: &quot;Only when you endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The first sentence is a necessary condition for the latter sentence; &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people&quot; is the probability. Expression. The latter seems more rigorous and allows exceptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this kind of saying? If you regard &quot;You must endure hardships to become a master&quot; as a full judgment, then it is not difficult to find counterexamples. In a logical sense, this proposition has been refuted. However, after that, everyone thought this was wrong and discarded it? Obviously not, everyone will just think you are making excuses, because this is not the correct way to open the proverb. The use of proverbs is inherently situational: only when specific preconditions are added or placed in a specific context can the proverb be established and can be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a large number of sayings in various languages ​​with completely opposite meanings. Here is an example of Chinese: &quot;A powerful man cannot bend&quot; vs &quot;A man can bend and stretch&quot;; &quot;I will not offend others unless they attack me&quot; vs &quot;Strike first to gain strength, but to attack later will suffer&quot;; &quot;It is better to be broken into pieces than to be left intact&quot; vs &quot;to stay intact&quot; With the green mountains there, you are not afraid of running out of firewood&quot;; &quot;Take a step back and the sky will be brighter&quot; vs &quot;The brave will win when you meet on a narrow road&quot;; &quot;Tolerate a moment of calm&quot; vs &quot;It is tolerable, but what is intolerable&quot;; &quot;Everything is inferior, only reading is good&quot; vs &quot; Three hundred and sixty lines, he will be the number one scholar&quot;; &quot;The blue is better than the blue&quot; vs &quot;The hair on the lips is weak, and the work is not solid&quot;; &quot;Three cobblers are better than Zhuge Liang&quot; vs &quot;Three monks have no water to drink&quot; ...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me, which sentence before and after is right, which sentence is wrong, or are they both wrong? In fact, as long as they are put into the appropriate context, these common sayings with opposite meanings can be used correctly. This is the correct way to use common sayings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become the best&quot; or &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, can you become the best among others&quot;, there are also common sayings that have the opposite meaning or different emphasis, such as &quot;One life.&quot; &quot;Second Movement and Three Feng Shui&quot;, &quot;Choice is more important than effort&quot;, &quot;Don&#39;t use tactical diligence to cover up strategic laziness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, success is determined by many innate and acquired factors. 1. Fate: when you were born in which country and family, this constitutes your initial conditions and boundary conditions; 2. Wisdom: intellectual endowment, the computing power and algorithm of the brain, which are also innate; 3. God: you Your knowledge system and values, as well as your vitality, motivation, courage and patience, have both innate and acquired components, but the acquired component is greater, because you can always choose your values ​​and choose to be a courageous person; 4. Luck: Factors you have no way of knowing or controlling because you are in a complex random system. In a specific process, &quot;god, wisdom, fate, luck&quot;, which factors are more important cannot be generalized. A person&#39;s success always resonates with the trend of history and personal destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, among the many factors that determine success, hardship, diligence or patience are certainly important, especially for people without background. Other statements such as &quot;The sharp edge of a sword comes from sharpening, and the plum blossoms bloom from the bitter cold&quot;, &quot;There are roads in the mountains of books, and diligence is the path, and there is no limit to the sea of ​​learning, and the boat is made by hard work.&quot; Do they sound more pleasing to the ear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What many people don’t like is “people superior to others”. This needs to be looked at twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, from the perspective of rights or rules, of course everyone should be equal. No one is above anyone else, and no one is subordinate to anyone. It is against anyone&#39;s privileges or slavery. , which is the basic principle of civilized society. In this sense, there should be no &quot;people superior to others&quot; and &quot;people inferior to others&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, there are always certain professions that are more respected in society and have higher social evaluation or reputation. For example, professionals such as surgeons enjoy a higher social status and are not considered &quot;human beings&quot;. What about &quot;Master&quot;? Also, some people are respected and admired by everyone because of their ability, knowledge or virtue, and they even have many followers. For example, people like Xinxiang Xian are the core of society. If neighbors come to him to resolve disputes, does he count? What about &quot;people superior to people&quot;? In a company or organization, whether it has a strict hierarchy or a relatively &quot;flat&quot; management, there is a chain of command and a superior-subordinate relationship. The subordinates must obey the instructions of the superiors to do things. Can senior executives and superiors be considered &quot;superiors&quot;? &quot;Woolen cloth? In a nutshell, from the perspective of power or influence, elites or those with higher social status are often called &quot;dragons and phoenixes&quot;, and there is nothing wrong with being considered &quot;superior&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if you want to be &quot;superior&quot; and pursue the privilege of overpowering others or trampling others under your feet, it is naturally a despicable value; What&#39;s the problem if you deepen your field, improve your talents and virtues, become popular, and gain a higher social status? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[书城伏案的侧影：写在刘世南先生百年诞辰之际]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259765]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3AasqhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;916&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3Aasq hT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Shinan took a photo in front of the Chongshao Library of Jiangxi Normal University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Taosheng)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;People who long for friends who fear friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Shinan Mr. (1923-2021) was a fighter. This is the first impression of him by people who are familiar with him and those who are not familiar with him. He dared to criticize various scholars, including those older than him, those of his generation, and those younger than him. His articles were scattered in various books and periodicals from the late 1970s to the new century, making readers People who feel the enthusiasm and persistence of his criticism are of course embarrassed by the critics, but they do learn from him, and many criticized scholars express their gratitude to him and respect him even more. His criticisms were actually aimed at problems, especially the style of study. His straightforward writing style contained a profound call for sincerity, simplicity, seriousness, and a down-to-earth style of study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not many people know that he is very eager to be criticized. He criticized Mr. Liu Mengfu (&quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; page 301), and Mr. Mengfu also criticized him. He invited Mr. Mengfu to write a preface to his &quot;Daluo Ju Shi Cun&quot;. Mr. Mengfu wrote a long preface in which he included his own critical opinions. He criticized it with real swords and guns. Mr. Shinan did not think that Sorry, let it remain in the preface as it is. This is the style of sincerity and magnanimity. He said in a letter to me on July 26, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Mengfu is middle-aged and a poet. Learn the art of poetry and achieve the best of both worlds. He looks down upon him as a servant, looks down upon his followers, and is sincerely afraid of his friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He respects and looks forward to his &quot;fearful friends&quot;. When he heard Mr. Tao Wenpeng mention that some parts of his &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; were a bit &quot;old&quot;, he wrote a letter asking Mr. Tao to point out his shortcomings in detail. Mr. Tao replied, and Mr. Shinan made a copy of the letter. Send me a copy and write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send me a copy of Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s letter, to be compared with Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s book review Although Mr. Yun and Mr. Tao made many mistakes in their compliments, Mr. Tao was able to correct their flaws. I hope Mr. Yun can do the same. In the past, Chen Si once said: &quot;The writings of the world cannot be without disease. I always have good people to ridicule my writings, and if there are bad ones, I should revise them in due course.&quot; He also quoted Ding Jingli and said: &quot;Who in future generations will know that my writings are evil?&quot; I hope that Mr. Zou Zhen, as the editor-in-chief of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, will be able to rectify the shortcomings of my book and inform future generations of those who govern Qing poetry about what to avoid. This is the meaning of an academic public instrument. (January 12, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he is still not satisfied with Mr. Tao&#39;s criticism and hopes to get more and more real criticism. He regards criticism as an &quot;academic official tool&quot;. &quot;To look at it. This allows us to understand more clearly that the reason why he carried out academic criticism with all his might was because he really had no selfish motives and was only dedicated to the healthy and mature development of the academic world. His attitude towards criticism is not only aimed at others, but also aimed at himself, which is conducive to his own improvement and is conducive to clear understanding in the academic community. He sets an example and has a bright mind, which is admirable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan and his &quot;Detailed Notes on Three Hundred Qing Poems&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was very moved by others&#39; corrections to him and expressed his gratitude repeatedly. Our publisher was planning to launch chronological anthologies one after another. Considering that Mr. Shinan was familiar with Qing literature, editor and editor Zhou Xuanlong, then director of the Classics Department, sincerely invited him to annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Considering that time was tight, he asked his Student Professor Liu Songlai assisted. After the manuscript arrived, Ms. Wen Lichen, a graduate student at Beijing Normal University, intern, reviewed it for the first time under my guidance. Then I reviewed it again. After writing two revisions, I sent it to Mr. Shinan for review. He said in a letter written in the Provincial Library on October 1, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 22 and Review comments and copies of book reviews have been received. Please read them. After reading it, I feel ashamed and excited! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the articles of Kuangzheng and Supplement, we can also see that Mr. Wen Lichen and Wen Lichen have made profound achievements in the study of female history, and their admiration for them cannot be overstated! I secretly say that the &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; will be of some benefit to this world in the future. It shows that the cooperation between the four of us is not caused by Song Lai and me. I plan to add a few words to the preface of this book to clarify the meaning and to show that we do not dare to take advantage of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He later insisted on adding words of praise to me and Xiaowen in the preface of the book, which shows that he was happy after hearing about it and had an open-minded and sage mind, which was like a spring breeze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan’s two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Mr. Shinan&#39;s fighting spirit is mainly reflected in his diligent reading and writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He does not have many books, mainly because the collections of two generations of his were destroyed during the special period, which made him extremely sad, and he generally stopped buying books (&quot;Odd Records of Masters and Friends&quot;, page 117). He mainly visits the library. He is a frequent visitor to the provincial library and school library. In 1994, after fourteen years of arduous reading, research, and writing, he finally completed &quot;History of the Qing Poetry School&quot;. When proofreading the manuscript the following summer, he reviewed the process with joy:&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reminiscent of the past, when every year passes, the bookstore is still busy with calligraphy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wan Jiaqing Tuanluan, sitting alone and smiling. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The box is full of cards, and there are more than delicious meals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fourteen years of hard work, the book is finished with a pen and inkstone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Appendix to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; &quot;Proofreading in the Midsummer of Jiaxu&quot; &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; Manuscript...&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Note: &quot;Every Spring Festival and New Year&#39;s Eve, I sit in the library, facing the administrator from a distance.&quot; Our publisher is preparing to publish the simplified version, and I am honored to be responsible. The editor, during the editing process, greeted him and mentioned this impressive scene. He wrote me a reply in the sample library on the evening of December 30, 2003 and the next day:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Thank you for your attention. You still remember that I was still sitting in the library on New Year&#39;s Eve. If school maps were still open, I would indeed do that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;, this is how I have been here all my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, he still couldn&#39;t let go every day. One New Year&#39;s Eve, the curator and he &quot;faced each other from a distance&quot;, which was quite a scene. He wrote to his student Professor Guo Dan: &quot;It is now nearly 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon on New Year&#39;s Eve. Director Zhang and I are the only two people left in the library reading hall; Director Zhang is on duty in person and will accompany me until 4 o&#39;clock with a smile. The bell closes the door.&quot; (Guo Dan&#39;s &quot;The Realm of Scholarship and the Style of Personality - A Note on Mr. Liu Shinan&quot;, &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 237) Such a curator is really a good curator, and such a reader is really a good reader. This is called It is a good story in the contemporary reading world. The postcard he sent me on December 31, 2006 said: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bookstore is sitting at the desk, cocooning and feeling pity, forgetting Time passes in a hurry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If Hua Yan was not drunk this night, who would have known that the day after tomorrow would be the New Year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Still reading on New Year’s Eve, it is indeed the style of reading seeds. Of course, he didn&#39;t just focus on New Year&#39;s Eve. In fact, every day was precious to him. Letter from June 4, 2004:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; is very busy, I have never been so nervous , because the school will be closed during the summer vacation, so I have to finish this before the vacation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the scene when I was rushing to select and annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; with Professor Song Lai. Later, when there was no urgent work, I still went to the library unremittingly. In the past, revolutionaries had a heroic saying: &quot;Sit through the prison.&quot; Mr. Shinan, in his old age, still insisted on going there regardless of his illness. He really had the spirit to penetrate the library. The letter dated January 10, 2013 said:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​year has passed and I was recently hospitalized for removal of nasal warts. Medical advice It was basal cell carcinoma and had been completely removed. I am already ninety years old and have lived and died for a long time, so after I was discharged from the hospital, I still sat in the library. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Professor Guo Dan called Mr. Shinan to wish him a happy New Year on the morning of the first day of the Spring Festival in Year Yiwei in 2015, the answer he heard was &quot;I am already reading in the provincial library&quot;! (Postscript to the reprint of &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;) Mr. Li Taosheng has been accompanying Mr. Shinan for many years. He said in the article &quot;Unforgettable words from the bottom of my heart&quot;: &quot;Books are all his spiritual sustenance.&quot; &quot;No matter the wind, frost, rain or snow, he always He would always show up at the library on time like a staff member. He said he hoped he could die at his desk in the future.&quot; (&quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 249) This shows how obsessed he is with books. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;From thousands of books&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan has read extensively and is particularly familiar with classics and history, so he can read many treatises We are sensitive to misunderstandings, misjudgments, and corrections and can provide corrections. In addition to helping others publish absurdities, he mainly devoted his energy to the research and writing of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;. In addition, a lot of study was done on the annotations of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. After taking on this task, he devoted himself wholeheartedly to the selection of articles. Although Professor Song Lai was invited to participate in the annotation work, he still did everything personally:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From text selection to punctuation to the comments, I will read them all and revise them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At these times, I was busy selecting articles, mainly from &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot; and &quot;Continued&quot; Choose from &quot;Xiu Siku Quanshu&quot; and &quot;Cunmu Series&quot;, and a few have to be found separately from the thread-bound library. For example, Jiang Shiquan has no text in &quot;Continued Cultivation&quot;, but &quot;Pictures of Night Classes with Sound Machines&quot; must be selected. Others can be deduced by analogy. The selection of the text is time-consuming. After selecting it, it must be photocopied and then hand-copied into simplified Chinese characters. (December 16, 2003) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to concentrate on the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, he served as the chief academic consultant for the compilation of &quot;Yu Zhang Series&quot; in Jiangxi Province universities for several years. (that is, final check) also resigned. This shows his determination to devote himself wholeheartedly to the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Because he was familiar with the collected works of the Qing Dynasty, and he read them day and night, by December 30, 2003, he had &quot;read page by page the Qing Dynasty Collection of Continuing the Complete Collection of Siku Quanshu&quot;, and had reached 154 of the 188 volumes. , there are still 30 volumes left, I can finish them before the winter vacation,&quot; and said, &quot;Then I will read &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot;, there are not many collections. I haven&#39;t read &quot;Cunmu&quot;, so I don&#39;t know how many.&quot; In selecting articles, &quot;Be sure not to show off your hands and eyes, and don&#39;t be attracted by people&#39;s enthusiasm&quot; (letter dated December 30, 2003). In this letter, he still could not hide his critical eye and expressed his opinions on several books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I was reading the collected works of Zeng Guofan today, and I found four books that were annotated by modern people. Take &quot;Yuancai&quot; as an example , Tu Xiaoma&#39;s version, Lai Xinxia&#39;s version, and Guo Yuheng&#39;s version all concluded: &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; On the contrary, Zheng Zhenduo&#39;s &quot;Late Qing Dynasty&quot; &quot;Selected Works&quot; concluded: &quot;Is it true to say that the accusation is not false?&quot; That&#39;s right. Tu, Lai and Guo...I don&#39;t know that the &quot;ye&quot; in &quot;Ke Hu Ye&quot; is actually &quot;ye&quot;. Books such as &quot;Jing Zhuan Shi Ci&quot; make it very clear, and the ancient prose written by Han Yu and Ouyang Xiu is swaying and often colorful. There is this aria. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;king&quot; in &quot;Everyone is king and is ordered to do so&quot; has been misunderstood. &quot;Mistakenly changed to &quot;must&quot;, it is also analyzed. He did not deny your contribution, he just wanted to explain that he would learn from their achievements, but would never simply plagiarize:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Even if we refer to this kind of annotated version, we must analyze every detail, never make vague and influential remarks, but strive to be clear and accurate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are actually very few similar works that we can rely on. Even if we refer to them, they must be adopted with discernment. This is in line with what Mr. Shinan has always advocated: &quot;Speak from the heart, never tamper with a single word.&quot; academic spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By June 26, 2004, it was the final stage of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. He wrote to me to introduce the writing situation of the preface of the book:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The preface can prove that the two of us have a slightly new understanding of Qingwen and do not follow what others say, precisely because we have put a lot of effort into the annotation of the works. For example, &quot;the genre is single but the styles are diverse&quot;, we not only pointed out &quot;how it is&quot; but also explained &quot;why it is so&quot;. This is the characteristic of our learning. It is also aimed at traditional Chinese literary criticism. The traditional method is improvisational and perceptive, and only points out &quot;how it is&quot; without analyzing &quot;why it is so&quot;. We have accepted the influence of Western academics and always like to pursue a &quot;why&quot;. Therefore, with regard to the emergence of the Tongcheng School (including the later Yanghu School and the Xiangxiang School) and the praise of &quot;all the articles in the world can only be found in Tongcheng&quot;, we try to find out its logical inevitability through this phenomenon. There are always laws to follow in phenomena, among which the law of cause and effect is most worth pondering, and the results of pondering are also the most thought-provoking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Tao Wenpeng heard about this preface and immediately asked Mr. Shinan to publish it in &quot;Literary Heritage&quot; in advance. Mr. Shinan said in his letter on January 12, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tao Jun asked to rewrite the preface of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; For the thesis, I have cooperated with Song Laijun. However, Huamei may not be fashionable and Zhu Yi may not nod. But I can be confident that the words and sentences of these two people come from their hearts and come from thousands of books. There is no suppression or similarity. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confidence reflected here comes from his steady reading and long-term cultivation. This spirit is reflected in his works and critical articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The method of popularizing culture through book selection is traditional, but it is an effective method of cultural communication for thousands of years. However, few people are willing to take on such work now because it requires Investing a lot of energy requires a high level of appreciation, extensive knowledge reserves and profound cultural heritage. The art of annotation is extremely difficult to learn, and it can easily lead to mistakes. However, Mr. Shinan resolutely agreed to do the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, which shows his confidence and responsibility. After the publication of this book, readers responded very well. Mr. Shinan was very happy and wrote a letter saying:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What will your company do next year? If there is a new topic that is suitable for me to work with, I hope it will be successful. Although Gai Pu is already old, his spirit has not faded, but he is itching again and again, and he is unhappy and unprepared to do anything. (Written in Provincial Map on October 1, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he has the ambition of &quot;being an old man, but aiming for a thousand miles&quot;. Considering that he is old and cannot be overworked, we did not invite him to do another one. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Young Thinker&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan seems to be a bookworm while sitting in the library, but he is actually a &quot;young thinker&quot; ( Chen Ji&#39;s &quot;Mr. Forever Young&quot;, &quot;Occasionally Diary of Teachers and Friends&quot;). In addition to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; and &quot;Daluoju Poetry and Essays&quot;, Mr. Shinan also has &quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; revised and reprinted, and &quot;Occasional Notes of Teachers and Friends&quot;. These two books are not &quot;pure&quot; books. , the collection is relatively mixed, the form is very random, but the theme is clear, they are all academic texts, and they are all &quot;dry information&quot;. It preserves a large number of academic correspondence, collects some book reviews, talks about academic methods, and more importantly, the academic spirit. It is interesting. We also collected some opinions that differed from those of Mr. Shinan. He said in the preface of &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;: &quot;&#39;The dispute is between gentlemen&#39;, and it is by no means a dispute of will. For me, it is &#39;I love my teacher, and I especially love the truth.&#39;&quot; He once again praised Mr. Mengfu, Praise him as a &quot;critical friend&quot; and &quot;admire his courage to stick to the truth.&quot; Regarding this book with the theme of &quot;I and the Intellectuals I Understand&quot;, Mr. Shinan said: &quot;The nature of this book is similar to &quot;The Inheritance of Sinology Teachers in the Kingdom of China&quot;. It is academic and can be used as a modern and contemporary book. Materials on academic history and intellectual history.&quot; Indeed, its content is more than an independent paper. It contains rich materials for contemporary scholars&#39; ideological exchanges and even confrontations. It has great academic value and is undoubtedly a breakthrough in form. and pioneering. The letter dated July 18, 2004 stated:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You will feel that this is a picture of the times, which reflects the The vigorous fighting of the soul. It can leave a valuable legacy to future generations and let them know how intellectuals in our era are searching. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;External Edition&quot; of this book includes an article &quot;How do contemporary intellectuals inherit and carry forward the fine traditions of ancient Chinese scholars?&quot; &quot;&quot; embodies his exploration on the ideological and spiritual level, letting people know that he is not a nerd, and his active mind and body surpass many young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In academic research, he has direct and in-depth discussions. In terms of poetry creation, it also has profound meaning and is worth appreciating. On January 12, 2005, he wrote a letter to talk about his &quot;Da Luo Ju Shi Cun&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. , you will know that the humble poems are not works criticizing the wind and the moon, but are all words of crying and sighing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said in the preface to &quot;Shi Cun&quot;: &quot;Any poem must be written for a purpose. It will never lament the old age and humbleness, but only the worries of the people, the country and the world.&quot; Many of his poems directly record reality, which makes people sigh and impress him with his broad mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I felt that it took Mr. Yu fourteen years to write &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;. After the book was edited and published, I wrote a book review and published it in &quot;Hainan Daily&quot;, which was later revised and published. In Guangming Daily. I sent it to Mr. Wang for review. He said in the letter dated June 4, 2004:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;is busy working on &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; , I usually put the letter aside and reply later. I didn’t expect to receive your letter today, let alone read your book review. After reading the book review carefully, I burst into tears. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You may be wondering: Why am I so easily excited? There are about seven or eight book reviews about &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, but I have never been so excited. As for you, as the editor-in-chief, you obviously read &quot;History of Qing Poetry School&quot; carefully, so you also carefully read &quot;Outside the Academic Palace&quot;. In addition, you have superb appreciation, rich life experience, and correct ideological understanding. , can I write such a book review that makes me excited. The masterpiece is not long, but it all hits the point, especially the point of humanistic care, which only you dare to point out. Frankly speaking, when I wrote &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, I really had the mentality of Confucius writing &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot; and Ma Qian writing &quot;Historical Records&quot;. This point was only pointed out in a book review by Professor Wang Qizhen of our school, but the article seems not to have been published yet. But you coincide with Mr. Wang, which is the most gratifying thing for me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Yunbo, please let me say a word of sincere gratitude: &quot;Uncle Bao, you know how to take care of me. I am proud that Yu Qing will not be a guest.&quot; This is a couplet made up at random, all using &quot;Historical Records&quot;, and I feel it is very relevant. Some people may question: How can people deal with things? Then I have to say it without any shame: Just consider yourself dead. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My husband affirmed the book review I wrote. I have this confidence, but I never expected that it would make him &quot;cry with emotion&quot; and write &quot;Uncle Bao knows how to manage&quot; and so on. words of thanks; he directly confided his ambitions and pursuits, which shows that he didn&#39;t take anything for granted. In 2011, he recorded a super-star academic video, talking about &quot;Me and the History of the Qing Poetry School&quot; (later included in &quot;Occasional Notes of Teachers and Friends&quot;), and mentioned that &quot;Mr. Ge Yunbo is really my close friend.&quot; All of this moved me very much, and made me feel the power of the seniors to inspire the younger generations. It also made me feel the glory of being a down-to-earth editor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above experiences have undoubtedly increased our closeness. When our family went to Nanchang for the first time to visit Mr. Shinan on October 6, 2018, the host and guest were delighted. He held my hand forcefully and held on for a long time. It was not like the hand of a 96-year-old man at all. He can support himself. He also often goes to the library. We all believe that he can easily survive his old age. We look forward to visiting him again. But unexpectedly, I received a text message from Professor Song Lai on August 2, 2021, and learned that Mr. Shinan passed away the night before. I originally wanted to write a sentimental article after learning from the pain, but I was burdened with publishing projects and was unable to do so. This year marks the 100th anniversary of Mr. Shinan&#39;s birth. I made up my mind to write a brief statement of my admiration and gratitude for him, so I came up with the above immature commemorative text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[娄底7岁女孩遭性霸凌疑云：到底是夸大其词还是轻描淡写？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen in Loudi, Hunan claimed that his 7-year-old daughter was raped by more than a dozen female classmates in her class during lunch break at school. Bullying and even injuries to the private parts have attracted great attention on the Internet. The local report stated that an investigation confirmed that a female student was involved in a brief brawl, but no intentional harm was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 28, a parent from Loudi, Hunan Province posted on social media, saying that his 7-year-old daughter was studying in the second grade of a primary school in a township in Loudi, Hunan Province. During lunch break on October 20, she was raped by 16 or 17 girls in her class. The classmates bullied her on the playground. These female classmates not only beat her daughter, but also sexually bullied her, causing injuries to her lower body and causing unbearable pain. Both the school and the parents of the bullying students have a negative attitude toward solving the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Little girls in the second grade collectively bullied their female classmates, especially sexual bullying, which was appalling. People can&#39;t help but think of the sexual bullying incident of a 9-year-old primary school student in a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi that came to light a few months ago. Therefore, the incident quickly became a hot spot on the Internet and attracted great attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, Lengshuijiang City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Loudi City), where the incident occurred, issued a situation statement in the name of a joint investigation team, saying that after discovering the relevant video, it immediately established a joint investigation team led by the Municipal Education Bureau , the Public Security Bureau and other departments. After preliminary investigation by the public security department, it was found that the girl involved Zhang and six other female classmates were classmates in the second grade of a primary school in the city; at noon on October 20, because of an incident while skipping rope on the playground There was a dispute and &quot;mutual fighting&quot; occurred for about 1 minute, during which Zhang was &quot;briefly surrounded and slapped&quot; by several other classmates; after monitoring and monitoring was obtained, the girl involved was questioned &quot;protectively&quot;, and the witnessing teachers and students were investigated, but no evidence was found. Intentional injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The characterization of the incident in this official report is completely different from the accusation made by the victim’s mother. The description of the incident process is also vague and unclear, and there is no clarification on the key issues of the accusation. If the official has sufficient evidence that the girl&#39;s parents are exaggerating, they should publicly refute the evidence. Otherwise, not only will it fail to eliminate public doubts, but it will arouse greater doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first question is whether the girl Zhang’s lower body was injured. According to information released by Zhang&#39;s mother, Zhang had multiple soft tissue injuries on his body and his lower body was also injured. He was in unbearable pain when urinating and was forced to hold in his urine. However, although the official report confirmed that &quot;mutual fighting&quot; occurred, it did not mention whether Zhang was injured. This is also the aspect that attracts the most attention from netizens and makes people the most angry. Officials should not shy away from this, they should investigate this and make the results public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Zhang’s lower body is indeed injured, then this is a very serious violation of minors. The cause of the injury must be found out. If it involves criminal behavior, he must be severely punished. If Zhang was not injured, then enough credible evidence must be produced to refute the accusations made by the girl’s parents. For example, Zhang can be taken to a tertiary hospital outside Loudi City for examination accompanied by his parents, and the examination results can be announced. If Zhang’s mother exaggerates or lies, she should not avoid it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, it is necessary to release the relevant video of the incident that occurred on the playground to set the record straight. Zhang’s mother said that Zhang was beaten by 16 or 17 girls in his class on the playground. The official statement stated that except for Zhang, only six students were involved in the incident, and that several girls were &quot;fighting with each other&quot; for only about a minute, while Zhang was only &quot;briefly surrounded&quot; and &quot;swatted&quot; by several classmates. According to the two sides, not only the number of participants is hugely different, but there is also a huge difference in nature between &quot;beating&quot; and &quot;fighting with each other.&quot; Since the official statement mentioned that the police obtained the school&#39;s surveillance video, it means that the incident was recorded, and it was not the &quot;aging surveillance&quot; mentioned by the school in Zhang&#39;s mother&#39;s post. Since there is a video, it should be made public in its entirety so that the public can judge for themselves whether it was a &quot;beating&quot; or a &quot;fighting&quot;, how long it lasted, and whether there was any &quot;intentional harm.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, for the sake of protecting minors, minors who can be identified in the video can be treated with protective techniques, such as mosaic, blurred faces, etc., but it should be ensured that several minors can be seen. The individual&#39;s involvement in the incident, and the extent of the &quot;ruffling&quot; involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems a bit incredible that a 7-year-old girl would bully her classmates and also be sexually involved. But it&#39;s not impossible. In a bullying incident at a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi, the bully was only 9 years old. This was not the first time that bullying had occurred, it had also started in the second grade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a stereotype that bullies in school are boys. In fact, this is not the case. Among school violence incidents, the proportion of women committing violence is not low. In March 2023, a bullying incident broke out in Hainan in which a 13-year-old girl was beaten and humiliated by a group of same-sex peers. When the Datong incident attracted great attention, criminal law teacher Cai also received news that a female classmate was bullied by other female classmates in the dormitory, and also engaged in sexual behavior, and the perpetrator even took a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, CCTV reported on a study and found that more than 80% of the perpetrators of school bullying videos posted on the Internet were women. Of course, this may be related to the fact that female bullies are more likely to take videos and upload them online to humiliate their victims, but it also shows that female perpetrators of school violence are by no means uncommon. Moreover, among the campus bullying committed by women, many of them are a group of people bullying one person, and the targets of their bullying are mostly women. Also, among the bullying committed by women, a high proportion involves sexual humiliation, such as being forced to strip naked and take photos. This may be because it creates a stronger sense of shame for the victim. These characteristics of female bullying are consistent with the accusations made by the mother of the victim in the Loudi incident that more than a dozen girls beat and sexually bullied her daughter. This is one of the reasons why netizens are more willing to believe victims’ accusations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter has attracted great attention on the Internet, and the official understatement of the situation is obviously difficult to convince the public. This reminds people of the sexual bullying incident at a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi. The school and the authorities tried to turn the incident into a minor matter, but in the end, the bullying incident was confirmed. The same is true for this suspected bullying incident in Loudi. If the authorities have sufficient evidence to support their account of the situation, they should make it public promptly to refute the accusations made by the girl&#39;s parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTp OzxQVWlMy0o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009), a contemporary master of rituals and a famous Confucian scholar, dedicated his life to Studying the study of the three rites, he has made outstanding achievements in many fields such as etiquette, history of Confucian classics, philology, inscriptions on oracle bones, bibliography, and compilation of ancient books. In particular, the study of the &quot;three rites&quot; has solved many problems in the history of etiquette and Confucian classics. Many unresolved problems were highly praised by Gu Jiegang. The picture was taken in May 1986. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009) was an &quot;invisible man&quot; at Hangzhou University. In October 1978, I entered the Chinese Department as an undergraduate student. He once gave us a few lectures on &quot;Common Knowledge of Ancient Culture&quot; in the &quot;Ancient Chinese&quot; class, but no one had much impression of him. When I was in graduate school, he was a member of the mentor group, and I started to get to know him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The headquarters of Hangzhou University (today’s Xixi Campus of Zhejiang University) in the early 1980s was small in area. Tall plane trees stretched out towards the boulevard, forming domes, showing the history of this campus. years. In the southeast corner are several rows of four-story buildings made of blue-grey bricks. The teachers&#39; dormitory and the graduate student dormitory face each other. Between the two floors is the boiler room, where the fire roars in the morning and we go there every day to turn on the water. In autumn and winter, the sycamore leaves have faded to gray, and the walkways of the boiler room are covered with finely crushed coal ash. Against the blue-grey brick walls, the vision is gray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Mr. Shen lived in a room on the first floor of the first unit of Building No. 1, about fifteen or six square meters, opposite the public toilet. It was humid in spring, sultry in summer, and cold in winter. . There was no kitchen, so he could only light a fire in the corridor, so for more than 20 years, he had been eating in the canteen, occasionally cooking hoof bones and the like to improve his life. It wasn&#39;t until 1986 that he was assigned a two-bedroom house and moved out of here (in July of that year, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor by the State Council&#39;s Discipline Review Group). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have never entered his residence, but every time I pass by, I will stop for a moment. Later, I visited his door many times in my dreams. Through the glass above the door, I seemed to see the banners on the wall, but I couldn&#39;t always see clearly what was inside. It was like his personality and education were very mysterious and hard to see clearly. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I often meet him on the way to the cafeteria. He was over sixty years old at that time, with a broad forehead, sparse hair, and a gray beard, but his face was very rosy. He is not tall, but very strong. In winter, he put on an old gray smock over his old cotton-padded jacket, and carried a shallow bamboo basket in his left hand, which also looked like a dustpan. His big hands had thick knuckles. He always had a smile on his face and seemed to be moving as he walked on the road, making a slight &quot;huffing&quot; sound in his mouth. If he encounters the gaze of others, he responds with a smile in his eyes, his mouth seems to be moving, but he does not speak. He looked gentle and calm, yet as deep as the ocean. He beams with energy when he smiles, inspiring passers-by. So I think he was in a good mood at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we &quot;new&quot; graduate students often talked about at that time was our own supervisors and each other&#39;s supervisors: which field we mainly worked in, what books we published, where we published papers, and what we heard about them. What are the requirements for students, what are the mantras, what new things were said in class...proudly introduce the findings of the instructor, share with each other, and listen carefully to other people&#39;s additions and discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Roommate Chen Shenyong is the first graduate student led by Mr. Shen Wenzhuo. My understanding of Mr. Shen gradually enriched through classmate Sheng Yong’s admiring explanations and everyone’s discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Fang Jianxin, Mr. Shen, Li Jiemin, Wang Yunlu (photographed in 1997). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo, whose courtesy name is Fengsheng and nickname is Yinan, is from Wujiang, Jiangsu. He entered a private school when he was young, and studied by himself when he was older, without obtaining any diploma. In his early years, he studied ancient Chinese poetry from Shen Chang, and studied literature and history from Jin Tianhe and Yao Tingjie. In the early 1940s, he specialized in the study of &quot;Three Rites&quot; from Cao Yuanbi and became his close disciple, teaching and mentoring him for nine years. Cao Yuanbi (1867-1954), known as the last outstanding Confucian scholar of the Qing Dynasty, was already in his seventies, so he placed high hopes on Shen Wenzhuo: &quot;If you observe well, you can expect success.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1946, he published He wrote articles such as &quot;Shuo Gao Le&quot; and &quot;Wax&quot; and &quot;Wax&quot;, which attracted Gu Jiegang&#39;s attention, and he was hired as the deputy editor and reviewer of the National Translation and Translation Center. He was mainly responsible for proofreading classics, compiling summaries, and drafting classics dictionaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, he was sent to study at the Political College of North China People&#39;s Revolutionary University in Beijing. In June of the following year, he was assigned to Shanghai Library as deputy director of the Cataloging Department. The &quot;Zhongshu Zonglu&quot; we often consult, which is three very thick volumes and is more than a foot high when stacked, was compiled under his leadership. In 1960, the editorial team of &quot;Zonglu&quot; was rated as an advanced collective in Shanghai. As the team leader, he attended the Shanghai Heroes Meeting as a representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 1963, at the invitation of Professor Jiang Liangfu, he was transferred to the Language and Literature Research Office of the Zhejiang Branch of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (located at Hangzhou University, with Xia Chengtao as the director) as a full-time researcher and went to Hangzhou alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March, as soon as I arrived in Hangzhou, I went to pay a visit to Mr. Ma Yifu; in late April, I went again. &quot;From now on, we will learn to pay homage to our predecessors and scholars, and when we meet each other, we should treat relatives with respect and be harmonious.&quot; I had some enlightenment and thought, and wrote &quot;Jiangzhuang Wen Xue Ji&quot; to record it. After autumn, he went to the Northeastern Institute of Literature and History in Changchun to teach &quot;Etiquette&quot; and returned to Hangzhou in the winter. I wanted to visit again, but I couldn&#39;t. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following year, &quot;the trend of talking about ancient studies came to an abrupt end, and the interest was greatly reduced.&quot; Soon, I went to the countryside to participate in the &quot;Social Education Movement&quot; and stayed in a commune in my hometown of Zhuji County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, he had published many papers in &quot;Archaeology&quot; (1961, 1963). It is said that Mr. Guo Moruo, then president of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, spoke highly of him after seeing him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; occurred, the research office was disbanded, and he transferred to the Chinese Department of Hangzhou University and worked as a document clerk in the department&#39;s reference room. Because of his extensive knowledge and strong memorization, his colleagues were shocked to call him a &quot;walking dictionary&quot;. He lived alone in silence, but never stopped studying etiquette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1974, he was arranged to go to Anji to participate in the &quot;Agricultural and Forestry Class&quot; of the last &quot;May 7th&quot; Cadre School of Hangzhou University. He worked as a &quot;Duck Commander&quot; during the day and explored the secrets of etiquette at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 1975, four types of works, including the &quot;Review of the Han Bamboo Bamboo Bamboo Slips Unearthed in Wuwei&quot;, were sent to Mr. Gu Jiegang for review. Gu Fuxin said that &quot;Taituan is actually the first person in the contemporary world to organize the Book of Rites&quot;, but at the same time he lamented that he didn&#39;t know when these results would be available. The above words were only circulated within a small circle at that time and were not known to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gu Jiegang replied to Shen Wenzhuo&#39;s letter. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, the situation had changed again. In 1979, he transferred to teaching position. The following year, he was rated as an associate researcher at the age of 64. Our 1982 graduate student is his first enrollment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Hangzhou University highly regarded the &quot;Literature and History&quot; of Zhonghua Book Company and the &quot;Chinese Literature and History Series&quot; of Shanghai Ancient Books as the top journals in the field of ancient literature and history, and Mr. Shen was a frequent reader. Among them, &quot;A Brief Discussion on the Practice of Rituals and the Writing of Books on Rituals&quot; (Wenshi, Series 15 and 16, 1983) states that &quot;the practice of rituals existed earlier than written records&quot;, thus clarifying the relationship between rituals and ritual books. Mr. Yang Xiangkui later called this article &quot;a monumental work with unprecedented achievements.&quot; Another example is the article &quot;The Enrollment of the Twelve Doctors of Huanglong and the Establishment of the Taixue Prefecture and State School&quot; (1983), which analyzes the complex historical facts of the establishment of the Doctor of Confucianism in the Han Dynasty, corrects the mistakes in Pi Xirui&#39;s &quot;History of Confucian Studies&quot;, and corrects Wang Guowei&#39;s &quot;Han and Wei&quot; &quot;Doctoral Examination&quot;, thus making a detailed analysis of the rise, fall, increase and lack of doctorates in the three dynasties of Wu, Zhao and Xuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Referred to as a later scholar, Mr. Shen&#39;s articles have a very broad vision. They have both macroscopic concerns, covering ancient and modern times, and microscopic research, and are as meticulous as hair. At the same time, various methods are used to contain materials, and the amount of information is huge. He has unique insights into almost any issue in traditional etiquette, and almost every sentence in his article embodies the result of his thinking. His narrative language is very elegant and can be almost seamlessly connected with the cited documents, which is a state that is difficult to achieve. I also deeply agree with this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, I did not seriously read Mr. Shen’s works and papers at that time, and I was afraid to read them because they were too profound. I have only read his column in &quot;Chinese Literature and History&quot;, titled &quot;The Secret of Rituals&quot;. Sometimes several articles are published in one issue, and the length is only one or two pages, and the explanation is one word or one thing. , are all explanations of difficult issues, and are of great relevance to the study of literature and history. The elegant and concise writing impressed me endlessly. He has been writing this kind of short essays since 1946, and he has accumulated a lot of copper from the mountains. Many years later, he compiled it into a book, still named as a column. It was only a thin volume with more than 100,000 words, but it was well received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo is in the study. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I started learning to write papers, I knew that short papers were the most difficult to write because they were hundreds of words long. , more than a thousand words, how difficult it is to ask a real question, list the materials and explain it clearly! It is said that Mr. Shen&#39;s other book, &quot;An Interpretation of Different Texts on Chinese Bamboo Slips of &quot;Li&quot;&quot;, had more than 400,000 words when it was written. He was not in a hurry to publish it and repeatedly compressed it. When it was finally published, it only had 160,000 words. When we were graduate students (1982.9-1985.6), except for some papers, he had no published works. His first monograph, &quot;An Examination of Zongzhou Rites and Music Civilization,&quot; is actually a collection of his essays. It was only published in 1999. The writing spanned more than 40 years, and the total number was only 14 articles. He was already an octogenarian by then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen has always been indifferent to fame and fortune. He said: &quot;It is not easy to manage the classics and rituals. Only when the mind is clear of &#39;devil obstacles&#39; and the mind is as clear as water, can one focus on learning and become more general.&quot; In fact, he did not write much in his life, but scholars praised him as &quot;the master of rituals.&quot; , because his articles do not rely on accumulation of quantity, but win on quality. Each of his articles solves an unsolved problem in history. Cumulatively, it is breathtaking and even more admirable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We are very fortunate that Mr. Shen opened a class specifically for us. At that time, we were five graduate students, guided by five tutors. Each of them taught three classes, which constituted a semester&#39;s graduate course. Even Teacher Guo Zaiyi attended his three classes and sat in the back row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen has suffered from a severe stutter since he was a child. It is very difficult for him to even speak a complete sentence. This is why he rarely attends classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The content the teachers taught at that time was self-selected and derived from years of deep thinking. In my impression, Mr. Shen Wenzhuo talked about issues related to various schools of thought in the pre-Qin period and ancient and modern texts. In my limited knowledge at that time, &quot;Lun&quot;, &quot;Mencius&quot;, &quot;Lao&quot; and &quot;Zhuang&quot; were independent writings, and I had a little dabbling in them. I had never read &quot;Mozi&quot;, and I dared not touch &quot;Li&quot; and &quot;Shu&quot;. As for each There is no understanding of the relationship between families. Mr. Shen&#39;s class revealed the intricate relationships between various schools of thought, especially the Jixia School and the famous schools. These schools, which had few works handed down to the world, used to dominate the competition with other schools, making other schools Each school had to respond and adjust; some schools that disappeared had their doctrines integrated by other schools and passed down to later generations. This made me suddenly understand that each argument was not a complete and systematic explanation of a certain theory, but an expression of its own views on the opponent. If you don&#39;t know the background of this debate, you will feel that its argument is extremely biased, like It&#39;s fighting against the air, I don&#39;t know why. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very much like when I play center on the basketball court. Every time I hit hard, I have to push the person behind me away so that I can turn over and score the ball. You have to know how powerful the &quot;top&quot; is to understand how much effort it takes for me to &quot;rely on&quot;. If the person behind me is blurred, and people only see me turning backwards and forward into the air, they will definitely laugh at me for using too much brute force, which is the so-called &quot;biased approach&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our classroom, Mr. Shen burst out each word from his mouth vigorously. Some words took him two or three times to complete, so he wiped the sweat with a handkerchief. Still mouthing. When he talks about happy things, he will also chuckle. He first used his own research and explanation to redefine the old concepts, and then extended them to put forward new definitions for a series of issues. As a result, the related characters, events, schools and theories were swept away from the long-accumulated dust and revealed. A completely different appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all listened attentively, lest we miss a syllable. Because the words that burst out one by one were like formation symbols flying in the air, forming a wonderful formation from which the truth of history emerged. The formation was so turbulent, with forces coming and going, waves vying with each other, sounds and principles echoing each other. This was the era of a hundred schools of thought contending! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than forty years have passed, and Mr. Shen’s specific explanation left only a few impressions on me. For example, “Book of Rites” is later than “Lidian”; &quot;Jinwen&quot; refers to Han Li, who explains the inheritance of various texts in the Han Dynasty from the perspective of the characters used in writing the texts; someone&#39;s interpretation is established as an academic official, which is &quot;learning from the law&quot; before it is established. , it is &quot;Family Law&quot;... Most of the other specific knowledge has been forgotten now. Only his &quot;chichi&quot; voice occasionally still rings in my ears, so the feeling caused by his explanation came again. It flowed through my brain like a tide, making me feel an inexplicable shock. More importantly, through these explanations, I understand that I must look through the surface of documents to feel the &quot;forces&quot; and their interactions behind the times, in order to vaguely see the &quot;invisible hand&quot; of God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After meeting Mr. Ma Yifu, Mr. Shen wrote a poem:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Confucian Classics and Interpretation Canon 1 Furnace melting, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Prove that the mind is the same and the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Goodness, beauty, depth and subtle appearance can be understood in different ways,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shu Xu&#39;s rituals and music are harmonious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also recorded: &quot;Mr. (Ma) knew about Yu&#39;s etiquette for treating Ji Dan, and he expressed the purpose of the etiquette, kindness and beauty, and was amazed by it. I also introduced the meaning of &#39;Shu Xu&#39;, No matter how hard you look at Mr. Shen, don’t dismiss him with different opinions.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now I recall Mr. Shen’s three classes, record every bit of what I saw and heard at that time, and respectfully take his last sentence as title to express my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解聘247名自聘科级干部：萍乡经开区“瘦身”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPA zbx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone was established in 1992 and upgraded to a national-level economic and technological development in 2010 district. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a major choice in my life.&quot; In April 2023, Zhang Shichun chose Give up his status within the system and stay to work in a large state-owned enterprise in Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone, Jiangxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, he had worked in this state-owned enterprise for 4 years, but retained the establishment of a public institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone announced the cancellation of 19 self-established institutions and the dismissal of 247 self-employed section-level cadres based on the personnel system reform plan adopted by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A considerable part of the dismissed personnel were originally on-staff personnel. After their self-employed positions in the Economic and Technological Development Zone are dismissed, they can choose to retain the establishment and have the Economic and Technological Development Zone coordinate the arrangement of new jobs, or they can Give up the establishment and work in an enterprise. The dismissed persons who were originally non-staff personnel can participate in the full-scale competition for recruitment, or they can choose to resign. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun is a department-level cadre self-employed by Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. Facing the reform, he has two choices. Abandon the establishment.&quot; After a family meeting, he decided to stay in the business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons why Zhang Shichun became a self-employed cadre are not complicated. As one of the earliest economic development zones established in China, after 31 years of development, the population of Pingxiang Economic Development Zone has increased from the initial 10,000 to about 250,000 now, and its functions have also expanded from solely economic development to taking into account social management and public affairs. Services, etc., have set up their own management agencies, established their own positions, and hired their own personnel during the development process. This has both objective reasons and subjective reasons such as previous organizational establishment management was not standardized and personnel were highly arbitrary. This is also a common phenomenon in domestic development zones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot;, clarifying that both the central and local governments must streamline their staffing. On this basis, many places have begun to clear out non-staff personnel. Harbin City in Heilongjiang Province, Shiyan City in Hubei Province, Chuxiong Prefecture in Yunnan Province, Huizhou City in Guangdong Province, Zhuzhou City in Hunan Province and other places have introduced plans to clear out non-staff personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingxiang Economic Development Zone has comprehensively standardized personnel management. Among the 247 dismissed cadres, 63 people who were illegally borrowed were dismissed, 17 people were dismissed, and another 8 people gave up their business establishment to work in enterprises. After the reform, all employees will implement &quot;host management&quot; (a personnel management method in which staff and non-staff staff are hired as hosts at all levels), rather than simply &quot;throwing out&quot; non-staff staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fired deputy minister&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun, who was born in 1970, worked as a teacher for 10 years after joining the workforce. His original identity was in the professional establishment. After leaving school, Zhang Shichun worked in the Education Bureau. In 1997, he was transferred to Pingxiang Economic Development Zone and later became deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department of the Economic and Technological Development Zone Party Working Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, due to work needs, Zhang Shichun was adjusted to a large state-owned enterprise in the Economic Development Zone as deputy secretary of the party committee and secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission, and the establishment was still retained in the Party and Mass Work Department of the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There were quite a lot of situations like Shichun at that time.” Yu Zhifeng, deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department, explained that from the economic development zone agencies to working in enterprises, there are still such personnel established by the agencies. , seven or eight in total. State-owned enterprises do not have public institutions, but they still retain the status of public institutions and are self-employed department-level cadres in the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-employment means self-employment. Without filing with the superior organizational department, the superior organizational department will not recognize it. If a civil servant or public servant is appointed as a deputy section-level cadre through normal organizational procedures, the superior organizational department needs to register for it, but the Economic Development Zone hires him to a full-section level without filing with the superior organizational department based on work needs. In fact, His rank is still deputy section level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020 and 2022, the Jiangxi Provincial Party Committee inspection team pointed out this problem during its two inspections of Pingxiang. Take 2022 as an example. In April of that year, the Fourth Inspection Team of the Provincial Party Committee inspected Pingxiang. On July 28, the Fourth Inspection Team reported the inspection situation to the Party Working Committee of Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. The third of the four main opinions was on the economic development. In the organizational work of the open area, “there is a big gap in improving the organizational system that is connected from top to bottom and has strong execution.” The inspection team put forward suggestions and suggestions for rectification, &quot;focusing on solving key issues in the personnel field of the institution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Zhifeng introduced that the more prominent problems in the personnel field of the Economic Development Zone are that there are too many self-established institutions and too many self-employed cadres: after years of development, the number of self-employed section-level cadres in the Economic Development Zone has reached 247. There are three main categories: on-staff personnel in the Economic Development Zone, cadres transferred from higher-level agencies or brother districts and counties, and self-employed non-staff personnel in the Economic and Technological Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the personnel reform work was launched, the Economic Development Zone organized relevant leading cadres to conduct one-on-one interviews with the 247 self-employed cadres, led by the main leaders of the Economic Development Zone Party Working Committee. Yu Zhifeng said that the one-on-one conversations lasted for several months, mainly to explain the urgency of policies and reforms, and to &quot;patiently and meticulously do the ideological work of the dismissal target.&quot; For self-employed cadres who are already on staff, we should give them the right to choose whether to give up their staff and choose to work in enterprises or retain their staff and work in government agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun prefers to give up his official position and stay in the company, but he also made it clear to his family the risks of working in the company: once the company encounters difficulties in its development, his income will also drop, and may even Unemployment, &quot;After discussion, we finally decided that I would stay in the company. I also believe that the company will develop better after the reform of the Economic Development Zone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yu Zhifeng, who carried out the dismissal work, was also a self-employed cadre. Before his dismissal, he served as party branch secretary and deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department. After his dismissal, he remained the business editor, but only retained the position of deputy director of the Party and Mass Affairs Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Little horse and big cart&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;While dismissing 247 self-employed cadres, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone also dissolved and merged 19 self-established institutions , including the District Political and Legal Committee, District State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, District Letters and Calls Bureau, etc. Yu Zhifeng explained, “In the course of the development of the Economic Development Zone for many years, with the continuous increase in social affairs and service population, the Economic Development Zone set up its own institutions and hired a large number of cadres in violation of regulations without obtaining the consent of superiors.”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone was established in 1992. It was upgraded to a provincial development zone in 1995 and a national economic and technological development zone in 2010. After the area adjustment and expansion at the end of December 2021, the total area under its jurisdiction is 119 square kilometers. The permanent population is about 250,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of June 2021, there are 230 national-level economic and technological development zones. The GDP of Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone has been ranked among the top 100 economic and technological development zones in the country for five consecutive years, ranking 62nd in the country in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like other economic development zones across the country, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone is also a dispatched agency of the municipal government and is a functional area rather than an administrative district. &quot;At the beginning of its establishment, the functions of the economic and technological development zone were single, mainly economic development tasks, so the higher-level departments approved a small establishment for the economic and technological development zone.&quot; Zhu Min, director of the Party and Mass Department of the Party Working Committee of Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Materials provided by the Economic and Technological Development Zone to Southern Weekend reporters show that the specific regional scope was not delineated at the beginning of the economic and technological development zone. After it was upgraded to a provincial development zone in 1995, the Pingxiang Municipal Government decided to divide the six The administrative village is designated as a direct development area with a development area of ​​10 square kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“With such an area and population, the Economic Development Zone did not need much establishment at that time.” Zhu Min said, but in the process of development, the area of ​​Pingxiang Economic Development Zone gradually expanded, and with the agglomeration of industries , Pingxiang City’s old urban area population relief and other factors have led to a sharp increase in the population of the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to official data released by Pingxiang City, the permanent population of the Economic Development Zone has increased from 110,000 in 2011 to 250,000 in 2021. In the same year, the permanent population of Luxi County under the jurisdiction of Pingxiang City was 260,000, and the permanent population of Lianhua County was 210,000. This means that the population managed by the Economic Development Zone is equivalent to that of an ordinary county town in Pingxiang City. In terms of economic scale, the 2022 New Year&#39;s message of the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone shows that the economic development zone completed a regional GDP of 22.3159 billion yuan in the first three quarters of 2021, ranking first in Pingxiang City. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many establishments does the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone have, which manages a population of 250,000? Zhu Min introduced that in 2022, the superior establishment department re-examined the establishment of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee. There are currently 102 public employees and 138 business employees, for a total of 240 employees. Southern Weekend reporters learned from authoritative channels that a certain district in a surrounding city has more than 700 civil servants and more than 1,000 public servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to cope with the increasing social management functions as the population and regional area continue to increase, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone began to set up its own institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that there are basically two situations when economic and technological development zones set up their own institutions: population growth creates social management needs, and they must set up their own institutions to provide public services; municipal functional departments have vertical management needs , requiring the Economic and Technological Development Zone to set up corresponding institutions for work docking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Economic and Technological Development Zone has set up five social work bureaus, each of which manages several administrative villages. In fact, it performs the functions of the township government or city sub-district office; the Urban Management Bureau of the Economic and Technological Development Zone, The establishment of the Garden Management Bureau was because the Pingxiang City Urban Management Bureau and the Garden Management Bureau required the Economic Development Zone to also set up a management agency to facilitate the unified planning and implementation of urban management and gardening work in Pingxiang city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some self-established institutions set up by the Economic Development Zone to coordinate line work. The Public Security Bureau of the Economic Development Zone is the Development Zone branch established by the Pingxiang Municipal Public Security Bureau. The prosecutorial functions are performed by the Procuratorate in the Development Zone established by the Pingxiang Municipal Procuratorate. The judicial institution is hosted by the Anyuan District Court and the Development Zone Tribunal is established. In order to coordinate the work of public prosecutors, prosecutors and law enforcement as well as petitions, inspections and comprehensive management, the Economic Development Zone has set up its own political and legal committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 31 years of development and construction, the Economic Development Zone has become a functional area with a high degree of industry-city integration. The functions of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee have shifted from single to comprehensive, and in fact are performing functions similar to those of district and county governments. . During an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, a major leader of the Economic Development Zone analyzed that with the current establishment and number of personnel, the Economic and Technological Development Zone&#39;s ability to perform all management functions is a bit like a &quot;small horse and a big cart&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Lock the entrance and keep the exit smooth”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although there are too many self-established institutions and self-employed cadres, it is necessary for actual work, but it is also a matter of organizational personnel management. Caused by insufficient standards, too many agencies and cadres have also produced many adverse consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In terms of cadre team building, the superior organizational departments do not recognize the self-employed cadres of the Economic Development Zone, which has a negative impact on the growth of cadres. This is objectively not conducive to the training of cadres.” Yu Zhifeng explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Min served in the Organization Department of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee before being transferred to the Economic Development Zone as the director of the Party and Mass Work Department. In 2019, Zhu Min went to work in the first cadre section of the Organization Department of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and was responsible for contacting the Economic Development Zone. “At that time, I raised the issue of irregular organizational work in the Economic Development Zone and too many self-established institutions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and the Municipal Government vigorously promoted the reform of the personnel system of the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. The Municipal Party Committee Organization Department, the Municipal Party Committee Editorial Office, the Municipal Development and Reform Commission and other departments took the lead in organizing outings to learn from the experience of personnel reforms in economic development zones in other regions. . By 2022, the advancement of personnel reform will be significantly intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 11th issue of &quot;China Institutional Reform and Management&quot; magazine in 2021 published a signed article &quot;Pingxiang promotes standardized management of non-staff personnel&quot; written and edited by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee. The article summarizes Pingxiang City’s work experience in cleaning up non-staff personnel. The overall principle is to integrate non-staff personnel and on-staff personnel into total management. The institutional establishment department shall approve the number of non-staff personnel based on the department’s functions and staffing situation. We must resolutely clean up the non-staff personnel employed in the post, and standardize the management of the non-staff personnel employed within the post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The article also summarizes the direction of the use of non-staff personnel. It is prohibited to use non-staff personnel for administrative examination and approval, administrative law enforcement, archives management, political personnel, letters and visits, and confidentiality-related positions; insisting on &quot;doing things without hiring people&quot; In principle, employers are not allowed to use non-staff personnel for property management, security, greening maintenance, canteen services, information network services, public building facilities and equipment maintenance, etc., except for primary and secondary schools and kindergarten canteens, and all use market service outsourcing, The government purchases services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the cleanup of non-staff employees in the Economic Development Zone is also carried out within the framework of the above principles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the personnel system reform in April 2023, the Economic and Technological Development Zone implemented overall control of posts based on the personnel system reform plan approved by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government. On this basis, the Economic Development Zone further stipulated that in accordance with the requirements of the general staff control, no new non-staff personnel will be added in the future, and only personnel within the establishment quota will be recruited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Lock the entrance of non-staff personnel into the Economic Development Zone, strengthen the assessment and management of existing personnel, implement the last elimination system, and smooth the exit.” Zhu Min said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is by no means “sweeping out”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When dismissing self-employed cadres, the Economic Development Zone’s main concern is causing excessive reactions from the dismissal targets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Min reported on the reform plan to the main leaders of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee, &quot;The leader emphasized the general direction: the purpose of the reform is not to destroy your Economic Development Zone, the Economic Development Zone is still the engine of Pingxiang&#39;s economic development .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dismantling and merging 19 self-established agencies, the work was reorganized and the functions of the dismantled agencies were merged into 8 offices including the Party and Government Office of the Economic Development Zone, the Economic Development Bureau, and the Social Development Bureau. It has internal institutions and 8 public institutions including the park enterprise service center and social governance center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Economic Development Zone breaks down the identity boundaries and implements a unified &quot;sponsoring system management&quot; for both staff and non-staff personnel. It does not distinguish whether they are on staff or not, only based on the position. The sponsorship is divided into 12 levels. Each level is divided into 12 levels. Levels correspond to different salaries. The host has a promotion and downgrade mechanism, and has set an annual assessment failure rate of 5%. It is clear that those who fail the assessment for two consecutive years will be eliminated directly, so that the host level can be moved up or down, and the salary and performance can be improved or reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Min’s view, the economic development zone’s gradual digestion of non-staff personnel is by no means simply “sweeping them out”, but using a sponsorship system to allow the remaining staff and non-staff personnel to compete on the same track, “Whether it is Whether within the system or outside the system, opportunities must be given to these young people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Southern Weekend reporter’s interview, the Economic Development Zone was conducting a survey. The theme was to explore a new mechanism for motivating cadres, and to build a competitive system through competition, job transfer, waiting for job, demotion, dismissal, etc. selection mechanism. Southern Weekend reporters asked several organizers of the Economic Development Zone for confirmation. They said that after the organizational reform, the work pace is faster, the work intensity is higher, and the work pressure is greater. After the National Day holiday in 2023, many organizers have been working continuously and can basically only take half a day off on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another reason is that after the organization was dissolved and personnel were eliminated, the social management functions of the original organization were not completely divested, and various functions were divided into newly established public institutions. Therefore, the overall work The amount has not decreased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the arrival of the next round of reforms, economic and technological development zones across the country may usher in a functional &quot;downsizing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;High-Quality Development Plan for Development Zones in Anhui Province&#39;s &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot;&quot; released in March 2022 has a special chapter discussing the reform of the development zone system and mechanism, focusing on the rational division of development zone management agencies , territorial governments, and development and operation companies have real power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the &quot;Regulations on Promoting High-Quality Development of Development Zones in Henan Province (Draft)&quot; was submitted to the Standing Committee of the Henan Provincial People&#39;s Congress for its first review. The draft clarified that the Management Committee is mainly responsible for policy formulation, development planning, Administrative management functions such as administrative approval, investment promotion, and corporate services do not mention social management functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statements in both places send a signal: the functional positioning of development zones at the provincial level may still be economic development. So, how to deal with the social management functions that are gradually increasing in the development process of development zones in various places? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that in the national overall plan for the next round of institutional reform of development zones across the country, straightening out the relationship between development zones and administrative regions and gradually stripping away social affairs management functions is one of the trends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际足联：沙特是2034年足球世界杯唯一申办方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:55:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;FIFA announced on October 31 that the Saudi Arabian Football Association was the only one to submit a proposal to host the 2034 Football World Cup before the deadline. Apply to the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FIFA confirmed that it has received Saudi Arabia’s application to host the 2034 World Cup, and Saudi Arabia is currently the only country that has expressed interest in hosting the 2034 World Cup to FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256476&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, FIFA announced that the only application for hosting the 2030 World Cup was jointly submitted by the football federations of Morocco, Portugal and Spain. Currently, these three countries have confirmed their intention to bid. Since the centenary celebration of the World Cup will be held in 2030, FIFA plans to hold a World Cup match in Uruguay, Argentina and Paraguay. These three countries have also confirmed their intention to host FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saudi Arabia, like Morocco, Portugal and Spain, still needs to pass the review of FIFA. If these bidding countries can meet the requirements put forward by FIFA, complete the entire bidding process and pass, then FIFA will determine its hosting rights at the FIFA Congress at the end of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总部人去楼空，国美无力回天？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT9aftX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT 9aftX. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, the Gome headquarters was empty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pengrun Building, located at No. 26 Xiaoyun Road, East Third Ring Road, Beijing, was once a The top-level office building with the largest single area in Asia is close to the Embassy District and Chaoyang Park. This is also where the headquarters of Gome Electric Appliances is located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its opening in 2000, this 36-story light blue building with an apron on the top floor has witnessed the founder of Gome Huang Guangyu become the richest man in China three times, and now it has witnessed the rise of Gome The embarrassing situation of electrical appliances due to losses, payment arrears, and wage arrears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, on the lottery page of the Gome APP, a pop-up window targeting Gome founder Huang Guangyu and current Gome Chairman Huang Xiuhong appeared, including &quot;arrears of wages and arrears of payment.&quot; In fact, issues such as wage arrears at Gome have already emerged as early as 2022, and angry employees clashed with Huang Guangyu in Pengrun Building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;To what extent have employees been forced to do pop-up windows? Now Gome is in a state of no one&#39;s supervision, and employees can only find windows by themselves.&quot; Leaving Gome in Beijing in March 2023 Zhao Qiang, an employee at the headquarters, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Headquarters&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Empty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Gome Retail (0493.HK) Financial report data shows that Gome Group has a total of approximately 32,000 employees in 2021. As of the first half of 2023, the number of Gome Group employees is 3,609. This means that in one and a half years, Gome has lost 90% of its employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pengrun Building used to be full of American people. There was no place to park in the morning, and the cafeteria was full of people at mealtime.&quot; Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters, but when he left , most floors of the building were deserted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of Monday, October 30, Southern Weekend reporters came to Pengrun Building. It is divided into two buildings, A and B. The 3rd to 36th floors of Building B are the offices of Gome Electric Co., Ltd., and the only building in Building AB is The difference is that only Building B has strict access control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I walked into the Gome headquarters, the corridor lights were still on. The biggest feeling was that it was &quot;empty&quot;. Conference rooms, office areas, and reception rooms of all sizes were locked, and there were only a few staff members. Walking around with the cleaning staff, I saw strangers visiting me, but no one came up to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 18th floor of Pengrun Building, banners hanging on both sides of the elevator read &quot;Become a trusted world-class retail enterprise&quot; and &quot;Lead the survival and development of enterprises with &#39;faith&#39;&quot;. The black background wall in the middle is printed with &quot;Gome&quot; is two big words. On the right side of the background wall is the publicity room of Gome Group, which is densely packed with various certificates and trophies from Huang Guangyu, Du Juan and Gome Group in the past. But the time is mostly concentrated before 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conflicting with these past honors, there are now A4 papers posted everywhere here saying &quot;No entry for non-staff members of this floor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The 18th floor is the place where Gome receives merchants and suppliers. There are several large VIP conference rooms, and there used to be many people every day.” Zhao Qiang said. Southern Weekend reporters observed this floor for nearly half an hour, but no one came except one or two cleaning staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gome supply chain companies responsible for providing support to merchants and suppliers are concentrated on the 16th floor. They used to include Gome Customization Company, Ningbo Gome Zhenxuan Technology Co., Ltd., etc. The original office areas of these companies have been locked. And was removed from the floor guide board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. He made a high-profile statement that he would strive to restore the company to its original market position in the next 18 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His biggest move after his return was the launch of the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP, which represents Gome&#39;s retail strategy. The financial report shows that in 2021, Gome spent 962 million yuan on advertising on this APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Traces of &quot;True Happiness&quot; appear intensively on the 17th floor of Gome&#39;s headquarters. The red banner of &quot;Let&#39;s fight for a better career together and create a better life together&quot; is still hung in the office area, and the words &quot;12.24 9 :00-12:00 The room for the scheduled meeting of &quot;Home Appliances Division, Life Electrical Appliances&quot; has been locked. Zhao Qiang lamented, &quot;&#39;True happiness&#39; is earned by how many Gome employees work hard, work overtime and stay up late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth floor of the headquarters includes the national third-party logistics company established by Gome Group in 2012.&quot; The office area of ​​&quot;Anxun Logistics&quot;, a logistics company that had previously been rumored to be planning an IPO. It&#39;s pitch dark here now. At the end of 2022, news has emerged that Anxun Logistics and its subsidiaries owed more than 3 million in freight to multiple carriers in Henan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be said that after 2023, the entire United States will fall into a state of deathly silence.” Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The traces of &quot;really happy&quot; are still there. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where did the money go&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The top 36 floors of Pengrun Building were Huang Guangyu’s office in previous reports. However, a former employee of Gome who had successfully &quot;climbed&quot; told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Boss Huang also lives here, and there is a villa on the 36th floor that he renovated in a Chinese and Western style.&quot; If you want to climb to the 36th floor, You need to take the exclusive elevator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past, many employees came to ask for their wages and climbed up one level at a time, causing trouble twice. Later, in order to prevent people from going there again, we couldn’t enter that level.” Zhao Qiang remembered that there had been The supplier came to ask for payment, and squatted at the door of Pengrun Building until Huang Guangyu, and &quot;followed Boss Huang to the 36th floor, but I don&#39;t know how to deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, many media reported the news that Daqing Gome suddenly closed down and nearly 20 home appliance dealers begged for payment but &quot;didn&#39;t know who to ask for it from.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Judgment Documents Online, Gome was involved in 268 lawsuits in 2022, and this number reached 1,219 in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year’s lawsuits include an electrical equipment company in Foshan City, Guangdong Province requiring Foshan Gome Electric to pay a payment of 1.26 million yuan, a company in Zhejiang requiring Zhejiang Gome Electric to return rent and liquidated damages totaling 2.2 million yuan, and a construction company in Ningbo The decoration company requires Gome Electrical Appliances and Gome Retail to pay 2.4 million yuan for the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was March and April 2022 when employees who resigned began to discover problems in the company. &quot;The biggest problem is the funding problem, which means we can&#39;t settle the account,&quot; Zhao Qiang told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former employee who was directly involved in Gome’s sales and purchase still remembers that in the past, his work did not require consideration of billing issues, but starting in 2022, he was in a “pay here, then that” situation. I just can’t pay” situation. &quot;It&#39;s very intuitive to feel that cash flow is very tight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, he checked Gome&#39;s daily sales. &quot;I remember that the daily sales at that time could still reach tens of millions to 100 million or even higher, so I personally felt that it would not be overwhelming, but I don&#39;t know where the money went when it came back.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2022, &quot;employees&#39; basic salary is still there, but the performance part is rarely paid&quot;, and the situation gradually becomes more and more serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, at an all-staff meeting held in Pengrun Building, Huang Xiuhong, chairman of Gome Electric Appliances, publicly stated, “The company will only provide social security to employees and will not pay wages until the end of December. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome also requires employees to sign a commitment letter, which mentions that “starting from October 2022, we understand that the company may delay the payment of employee wages in the next six months to one year... Commitment adjustment Have a positive attitude and believe in the company... As employees, we promise to work hard, deliver business results on time, with high quality and quantity, and achieve performance goals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I also read this commitment letter at the time. If I don&#39;t sign it, does it make sense that I still owe back wages?&quot; Zhao Qiang said that some employees have already had zero income for a year. After his salary appeal failed, Zhao Qiang also filed for arbitration. According to the judgment, Gome owed him more than 200,000 yuan in salary plus provident fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another manager of a relevant Gome department told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;I am not owed wages, but all the children under me are owed wages. 200,000 yuan is a lot.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more unacceptable to Zhao Qiang is that starting from May 2022, Gome will no longer pay social security provident funds for its employees. &quot;But our personal contribution was deducted, and the company did not hand it over to the Provident Fund Management Center. This is the case for all employees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is equivalent to using our money, but we don’t know where it was used. .&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee of the Lianyungang branch of Gome Electric Co., Ltd. told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Since October 2022, we have realized that Gome has begun to have financial problems because wages have not been paid on time. , it was postponed until the store closed in March this year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employees all filed for arbitration, but they did not have much confidence. &quot;There is no money in Gome&#39;s account, so it will end in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome Electric Appliances has 3,895 chain stores and more than 200 million members across the country. However, starting in 2023, news of Gome store closings appeared one after another. In October, some media reported that all Gome stores in Guangdong were closed. Later, the company responded that not all Gome stores were closed. However, published data showed that Gome reduced its self-operated stores in Guangdong Province by 12 in the third quarter. There are 74 franchise stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome employees and consumers in Beijing, Shanghai, Lianyungang and other places also told Southern Weekend reporters that Gome stores in their cities are also gradually closing. Many interviewees said, “Gome stores across the country are basically closed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the process of store closures, situations that were unacceptable to consumers emerged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A consumer in Shanghai purchased a 7,200 yuan washing machine at the Shanghai Gome Changning Head Office in December 2022. Gome did not deliver the goods and did not refund the money. The consumer sued Gome and then mediated. Gome promised Refunds will be issued before August 2023, but there has been no news so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although I know that Huang Guangyu has been in and out of prison, it does not affect my shopping at Gome. I have never thought about not shipping the goods after paying,&quot; the above-mentioned consumer told the Southern Weekend reporter. Among the thousands of lawsuits involving Gome in 2023, there are a large number of similar sales disputes, employee wage arrears lawsuits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the funding problem, in Zhao Qiang’s impression, the second change in the company is the frequent changes of direct leaders, which means that there is a problem in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, dozens of core executives including the former Gome Online CEO, Gome Electrical Appliances CEO, and Gome Retail President have resigned since 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How did you get to where you are today&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Huang Guangyu was born in Chaoshan, Guangdong, and is 54 years old. According to official information from Gome Group, Huang Guangyu established the first &quot;Gome Electrical Appliances Store&quot; with an area of ​​less than 100 square meters on Zhushikou Street, Qianmen, Beijing, in 1987. Gome&#39;s retail road officially started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Gome tried a new supply and marketing model, breaking away from middlemen and directly underwriting customization with manufacturers, launching a &quot;direct sales&quot; home appliance model. In 1993, Gome unified its store names, product display methods, store after-sales services, and publicity, becoming the prototype of China&#39;s retail chain model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Gome Electric Appliances was successfully listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange through a backdoor approach. Huang Guangyu used this to reach the top of the Hurun Report as the richest man in mainland China with a net worth of tens of billions, and he aspired to the top spot again in 2005 and 2008. , personal wealth once reached 45 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2008, Huang Guangyu, who was at his peak, was detained by the police on suspicion of economic crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, Huang Guangyu was sentenced to 14 years in prison for illegal business crimes, insider trading and unit bribery. In June 2020, the Beijing No. 1 Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled that Huang Guangyu should be paroled in accordance with the law. In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huang Guangyu’s past honors are still on display at the Gome headquarters. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang joined Gome the second month after Huang Guangyu was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have some understanding of Gome’s glory days, and I think its foundation is pretty good and its market share is huge. At that time, I thought that after Boss Huang came out, he would definitely have some new measures and methods that would bring Gome to the forefront. After vigorously developing it again and combining it with my resume, I joined.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Huang Guangyu returned in 2021, he first renamed Gome APP &quot;True Happiness&quot; as the &quot;total platform&quot; of Gome&#39;s retail ecosystem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to past media reports, when Huang Guangyu was in prison, he still communicated with company executives by writing letters. Gome executives even used drawings in their letters to try to make Huang Guangyu understand intelligence. The principles of mobile phones and APPs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhao Qiang said frankly, &quot;Until the day I resigned, I didn&#39;t know what the positioning of this APP was.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the &quot;True Happiness&quot; platform, there are three major scenes: competition venues, shows, and entertainment venues, as well as multiple sections such as content sharing communities, short video live broadcasts, event lists, and e-commerce shopping platforms. gather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang doesn’t know how to position this APP. Is it a community e-commerce, a hobby e-commerce, or a traditional e-commerce? In his opinion, this APP, which the boss has put all his efforts into, has no core and focus from design, product production to experience, which has a negative impact on communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a problem for decision-makers.” However, Zhao Qiang also mentioned that by the beginning of 2022, the basic functions of the “True Happiness” platform will already be in place, and consumers can buy things and return goods normally. . As long as there is a burst point in one plate, this route can still be followed after the overall tilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The serious internal friction within Gome made him begin to doubt the company&#39;s prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gave an example. Generally, the supply chain of e-commerce platforms is relatively concentrated, but within Gome, there are several companies that are engaged in supply chain at the same time. The same product of a brand may cooperate with many supply chain companies in Gome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These supply chain companies have only one output port, which is the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This brings a huge waste of manpower. Each supply chain company has dozens or even hundreds of people, but multiple teams do repetitive work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Every team must survive. Everyone is constantly asking for money from the group and dividing it up. The boss may want to compete, but this kind of competition is not external, it is scattered and internal.&quot; Zhao Qiang Speaking to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome has also built a shared and co-construction platform internally that is not open to the outside world. Small businesses and suppliers can access this system after paying a certain usage fee. &quot;The biggest problem with this platform is that no one uses it. If merchants want to open a store, they can just open a store on another platform.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;True Happy&quot; APP, Huang Guangyu has also continued to It has launched a number of apps such as &quot;Decorate Home&quot; and &quot;Zheshangzhe&quot;, which puzzled the market. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A mid-level person from Gome Group told Southern Weekend reporters, “In addition to the decision-making issues of company leaders and lack of understanding of the market environment, they are also affected by the epidemic.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Chinese Enterprises Home&quot; reported that in late October 2021, on the 36th floor of the Pengrun Building, Gome held high-level meetings for five consecutive days. Huang Guangyu was sitting in the main seat, but staring at the iPad lying flat on the table, playing the game &quot; angry Birds&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang said, &quot;Sometimes Boss Huang sleeps during the day, and meetings are held late at night, and the executives go crazy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Can it still be &quot;resurrected&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted a retired vice president-level executive about Gome’s current situation, but the other party refused to discuss the matter. In addition, all members of the public relations department of Gome Group have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the domestic official website of Gome Group cannot be opened, and the “Dressing Home” and “Zheshangzhe” apps have been removed from the Apple App Store. After spending a huge amount of promotion fees, in January 2023, “True Happiness” changed its name back to “Gome” APP. At present, some brands of Gome APP have been withdrawn, and some categories such as TVs and refrigerators have been removed from the shelves. In addition, the live broadcast sales list is blank, the cleaning, repair and other services that could have been provided have been deactivated, and no one has responded to customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the financial report, in the first half of 2023, Gome’s retail revenue was 415 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 95.74%; it achieved a net loss attributable to the parent company of 3.539 billion yuan. During the same period, Gome Retail&#39;s current assets were only 5.326 billion yuan, and cash and cash equivalents were 146 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Gome Retail’s total liability balance is as high as 37.313 billion yuan, with an asset-liability ratio of 106.55%, making the company insolvent. Among them, current liabilities were 36.106 billion yuan, accounting for 96.78%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, starting from the second half of 2021, Huang Guangyu and Du Juan have frequently reduced their holdings of Gome retail stocks, from 60.98% of their holdings at the end of 2021 to the current 10.79%. Cashed out nearly HK$2 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, when Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence, Gome’s stock price experienced a surge. It was once nicknamed the “release concept stock” by the market. As of press time, Gome’s retail stock price was only The remaining price is 0.037 yuan per share, which is 97% lower than when he was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the past ten years, Gome&#39;s development strategy has been mainly reflected in two words - conservative, and try not to spend as much money as possible. This is Du Juan&#39;s point of view.&quot; Liu Buchen believes that in e-commerce, In an era of dominance, the decline of traditional home appliance chains is inevitable. It is just a matter of speed or slowness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of former employees, the decline and end may be more dignified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang sighed, &quot;Looking back, I feel regretful. We joined Gome in the hope of helping the former myth to reshape another myth. You gave me the opportunity and I contributed my ability, but now it is difficult to come back to life. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gome&#39;s headquarters office remains in the Christmas atmosphere of 2022. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(should At the request of the interviewee, Zhao Qiang is a pseudonym in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>