<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[黄仕忠：怀念郭在贻老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDVbVt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDV bVt. png&quot; data-key=&quot;256610&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi (1939-1989). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi is fundamentally a very proud person. More than thirty years after his death, I read a long letter he wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi on November 21, 1977. He talked freely about calligraphy schools and famous calligraphers at that time, and criticized Fang Qiu. in this way. The depth of calligraphy attainments seen in the handwriting astonished me. Because he knew what he said, it flowed out naturally from his mind. To him, it was just a normal conversation with his brother. Since it was a private letter, there was no need to be restrained, so he spoke frankly and heartily, rather than pretending to make shocking remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256609&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1988, Teacher Guo worked with students to complete the first draft of &quot;Review of the Dunhuang Bian Anthology&quot;. A friend wrote in a letter: &quot;This manuscript is devoted to our own opinions. We are confident and not without inventions. There are many unique secrets in the research and interpretation of common words and proverbs.&quot; It is also full of confidence rather than boasting. This tone can be seen or heard in his letters and conversations with friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo and I only exchanged words occasionally. He is not tall and his eyes are not big, but they are bright and bright. When he glances past with slightly squinted eyes, he seems to be condescending, which makes me feel uncomfortable. Health shrinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, he had just passed his forties, and his body seemed to be condensed with infinite energy, shining so brightly that it was impossible to look directly at it. Especially in the field of Chinese history, he is the person who carries the banner after Jiang Liangfu and Jiang Lihong. In July 1986, with the approval of the Discipline Review Group of the State Council, the Chinese Department of Hangzhou University welcomed a new group of doctoral supervisors after Mr. Jiang Liangfu. They are: Shen Wenzhuo, Jiang Lihong, Xu Shuofang, and Guo Zaiyi. The first three are all over 60 years old, and Mr. Guo is only 47 years old. He was the youngest doctoral supervisor in the field of humanities and social sciences at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was an undergraduate (1978-1982), he offered elective courses for the 1978 and 1979 students. I didn’t choose them at the time, but I have looked up to him for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, several students in Grade 77, influenced by Teacher Guo’s ancient Chinese class, spontaneously formed an interest group to carry out research on word exegesis. One of them is named Bian Xincan, who is from my hometown, and we are the same age, so we have a lot of exchanges. He said: &quot;Teacher Guo is knowledgeable and humorous in class. One of the sentences touched me very much: &#39;Discovering a new meaning is like discovering a planet.&#39; It can be said to illuminate my soul.&quot; So he dived into ancient books. In the pile, I made cards and copied words. By the fourth grade (1981), I published papers in &quot;Hangzhou University Journal&quot; and &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. He was only 21 years old that year. His graduation thesis was also supervised by Teacher Guo. I have read his paper published in &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;. The words he explained are well-documented and convincing. They are exactly the same as Mr. Jiang Lihong&#39;s &quot;Explanation of the Meanings of Dunhuang Bianwenwen&quot;. He said that after the article was written, he cautiously submitted it to Mr. Jiang Lihong, and received enthusiastic guidance and recommendation to &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;; the article in &quot;Chinese Language&quot; was accepted by his own submission. At that time, many teachers were struggling to write papers and therefore could not be promoted, so this incident left a deep impression on me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yimin, Zhang Yongquan, and Ji Weiqiang in the interest group also published papers in influential professional journals when they were in college or early after graduation. Yimin said that he was slightly excited when he saw his name listed with Mr. Ni Baoyuan, a teacher from Hangzhou University, in the catalog of &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. Yongquan re-entered Hangzhou University two years after graduation and studied for graduate school with Professor Guo, opening up a new world in the field of Dunhuang colloquial word research. Behind this, you can see the figure of Teacher Guo Zaiyi. They were just undergraduates, but under Teacher Guo&#39;s guidance, they achieved such outstanding results. As a student at the time, I admired him very much and could not imagine how great he was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was in the autumn of 1982 that I was admitted to the graduate school of ancient literature at our university after graduating from my undergraduate degree. Teachers Guo Zaiyi, Zhu Hongxi and others recruited six graduate students in ancient Chinese, including Fang Yixin, Chen Baiye, Jin Xiaochun, Guo Xiaowu, Wang Yunlu and Ye Qing. The boys&#39; dormitory is next to each other. Yixin, Baiye and I are undergraduate classmates, so I often visit them and listen to their discussions. Teacher Guo asked me to read through the paragraph notes of &quot;Shuowen&quot; first with punctuation. At that time, there was a photocopy of the notes, with a purple cover and a large format. Each of them had it open on the table. It was very solemn and quite showing off, because &quot;our Teacher Guo&quot; believed that this was the right way to get started, and Teacher Guo himself ordered Read it three or four times. This made me very envious, and I bought a copy. However, I hesitated repeatedly on whether to read it through, and finally gave up, because at that time I was working on &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Han Dynasty&quot; under the guidance of Master Xu Shuo. There is not enough time for comparison of books. In the second academic year, I returned to opera from &quot;History&quot; and &quot;Han&quot; and systematically read through the basic literature on Yuan and Ming opera. In fact, I was indirectly influenced by Teacher Guo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave his graduate students a course on &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, and I also took the course. This was the first time I walked into his class. It was an eye-opener and I was hooked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256607&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;When Teacher Guo was young, he was full of sunshine. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo is from Zouping, Shandong, and has a strong accent. For me, a Zhejiang native, it sounds a bit strange. The pronunciation of the characters is quite difficult to distinguish. Even so, his lectures were engaging. He first put forward examples and listed different theories, and then laid out his evidence, one, two, three, four, as if he were doing vertical arithmetic problems for primary school students, with clear layers and a clear view. In fact, it is extremely difficult to select examples for exegesis. Unless you are very familiar with the semantics of words and their origins, you will not be able to find accurate examples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, I only thought that it was enough to understand some &quot;methods&quot; of exegesis. I only had a superficial taste of Mr. Guo&#39;s thesis, and my understanding was not deep enough. Teacher Guo is based on his own years of research and combines the results of his predecessors to provide supplementary extensions and demonstrations in class. The core content has been published. One article is &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, published in &quot;Literary History&quot; (6th and 14th series, 1979, 1982); the other is &quot;Explanation of Vernacular Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, published in &quot; Chinese Language, Issue 6, 1983. In 1984, with these two papers, he won the second prize of the first Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (a total of three people won the award, the other two being Li Jiahao and Jiang Shaoyu from the Chinese Department of Peking University). This award was established after the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; by Mr. Lu Shuxiang with a donation to commend young scholars (limited to those under 45 years old). There was no first prize in the &quot;first edition&quot;, so this is the highest award. Two years later, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor. It is said that Mr. Xu Fu greatly appreciated his research and strongly recommended him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have mostly forgotten many of Mr. Guo’s incisive explanations, but some of the “methods” he taught played a real role in my subsequent academic research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Teacher Guo introduced the concept of continuous words, which are mostly double-sounding rhymes, and the sound must be emphasized. There are different writing methods with similar sounds, and they cannot be broken into individual words for explanation. He also said that some of them were discovered by Mr. Jiang Liangfu. Mr. Jiang&#39;s famous work &quot;Collation and Annotation of Qu Yuan&#39;s Fu&quot; was completed when he was only 29 years old (originally written in 1929 and completed in 1931). I looked through the &quot;Chu Ci&quot; and found that dozens of words are continuous words. However, most of the annotated versions of contemporary scholars still use split words for explanation. In other words, just relying on &quot;continuous words&quot; as a trace gave the young Jiang Liangfu many new insights. His graduation thesis at Tsinghua University, &quot;An Examination of Shi Sao Lian Mian Zi&quot;, was supervised by Wang Guowei. Wang Guowei keenly listed the discussion of Qing Confucianism as a special topic. He only pointed out the problem in one article and gave the topic to the students. The students followed this and expanded it to open up their own fields. This allowed me to see the necessity of mastering &quot;academic principles&quot; and &quot;criteria&quot;, and at the same time I also learned the importance of &quot;family law&quot; and &quot;teacher-to-teacher inheritance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave a wonderful explanation in class on the difficult words in Chu Ci, as well as the words that scholars in the past considered &quot;unexplainable&quot;. From Wang Yi, Zhu Xi, Hong Xingzu, to Guo Moruo and other contemporary famous Chu Ci scholars, they all revealed certain weaknesses in the face of his exquisite &quot;exegesis&quot;. He stands on a high platform in this field and gives guidance to the country. In addition to explaining the exegesis, he also told us some tidbits, with a proud tone. He said that he would buy any new annotated version of the Songs of Chu that came out, look through it, and then throw it away because he didn&#39;t see anything new. At the same time, he would write to some annotators to express his congratulations, indicating that I have read your book, and also giving a hint: &quot;If you use Guo Moruo and Wen Huaisha, you will specify it; in my explanation, I will use Even if you don’t tell me, I actually know it!” After saying this, he tightened his lips, tilted his head slightly, and raised his chin, leaving a freeze in my mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——I then knew that for a scholar to be recognized, it requires a process of accumulation of qualifications. This gives me the peace of mind to face the same thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi was one of the most dazzling young scholars at that time. This also makes us very curious, how does he stand out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that he was a &quot;Xiaoyao sect&quot; during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. He brought books about &quot;Chu Ci&quot; from the reference room and read them one by one. His &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot; was written after reading hundreds of relevant materials. The obsession and fascination during this period can be evidenced by a story told by himself: Once when he went to buy meat, there was a long queue. He was holding a book and was fascinated. When he woke up, he found that it was dark and the market had already dispersed. , he was the only one, standing there reading for a long time. But at that time, &quot;the more knowledge, the more reactionary&quot;. Reading these things only had negative effects, so many people laughed at him. An old classmate of his, who may or may not be inferior to him in terms of talent, but far surpasses him in terms of &quot;shrewdness&quot;, actively participated in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and once dominated the world. After the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, he became one of the &quot;three types of people&quot; under inspection. When he returned to teaching, Guo Zaiyi had already shone in the academic world. Only then did he realize his past mistakes and start over. This led to a consensus that scholars should stay away from the “movement.” At the same time, there are also vague rumors that Teacher Guo is not in good health because he studies too hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1985, after I graduated as a graduate student, I stayed at the school to teach. I was assigned a faculty dormitory and shared a room with my classmate Jin Xiaochun. Xiaochun’s graduation thesis was supervised by Teacher Guo. In the following year, I heard many stories from him about &quot;our teacher Guo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, I have a story related to Teacher Guo. In the autumn and winter of this year, Teacher He Chunhui and I went to Shanghai to deliver review materials for the promotion of teachers in our department, involving teachers such as Wu Xionghe, Cai Yijiang, Guo Zaiyi, and Ni Baoyuan. I am responsible for serving the experts in literature, and Chunhui is responsible for serving the experts in language and philology. She said that she was very enthusiastic when she met Mr. Shi Cunzhi from East China Normal University, and spoke highly of these teachers at Hangzhou University, especially Teacher Guo. I have participated in the promotion of several of my respected teachers to professional titles, and I feel quite &quot;honored&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaochun got married before the Chinese New Year. His wife was from Hangzhou and her family was very well off. He moved to a new house and seldom came back. But when I come back, I always share the story of &quot;our Teacher Guo&quot; with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring and summer of 1986, because of his professional title promotion, Teacher Guo improved his salary and purchased some new furniture. He was in a very happy mood, playing with his newly purchased items for Xiaochun. Xiaochun and the teacher are both teachers and friends, and sometimes they deliberately quarrel with the teacher. I remember that Teacher Guo was proud of his newly bought double sofa, so Xiaochun said jokingly: My sofa is a three-person sofa! Teacher Guo was speechless for a moment and said, &quot;Hey, I&#39;m not going to compare with you.&quot; He looked left and right, appreciating it for himself, unable to contain his inner joy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listening to Xiao Chundao telling such short stories, the common feeling in our hearts is one of indescribable bitterness. However, fortunately, all this will be a thing of the past, and the teacher’s vision has been filled with sunshine! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fall of this year, I was admitted to Sun Yat-sen University to study for a Ph.D. Soon after, Xiaochun also went to the United States for academic exchange, and I rarely heard from Teacher Guo. More than two years later, in mid-January 1989, the news suddenly came that Teacher Guo Zaiyi had passed away. I was simply shocked! Is it fate? I have no words to say, I can only pray silently, may he be well in heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, I learned about Teacher Guo’s final condition from Zhang Yongquan’s article. On the afternoon when the B-ultrasound examination showed that he had liver cancer, Teacher Guo endured great mental pain and wrote a suicide note to his students:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic script, italic script_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yongquan, Huang Zheng:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Farewell in a hurry, extremely melancholy. You must work hard to complete our scientific research plan and strive to publish all three books to comfort my soul in heaven. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have a favor for you:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Please collect my articles that have not been included in the &quot;Exegetical Series&quot;, compile a sequel, and try to publish it in a few years (of course it is impossible now), for I just want to earn some royalties to support my family, but I personally have nothing to ask for. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;zaiyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;November 5, 1988&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a proud man, at that moment, he did not forget his &quot; &quot;Scientific research plan&quot;; and for the sake of my family, I can only say humbly that I hope to &quot;earn some royalties to support my family&quot;, but still declare: &quot;I personally have nothing to ask for.&quot; After reading this &quot;will&quot;, How can it not make people cry! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo endured the pain and entered 1989, but in the end he was unable to save himself and passed away on January 10th. There is still one day left before his fiftieth birthday! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I later read the memories written by Fu Jie: &quot;In the last days of his life, Master Zai Yi spoke less and less - both because of lack of energy and because of depression. More than once, he was silent or even He was lying numbly, his eyes not looking at us around him, only looking at the ceiling, and suddenly he started sobbing loudly, which made us who were still young at the time panic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day when the illness was confirmed, He said to Yongquan: &quot;The situation is not good. I have been mentally prepared. I only pity their orphans and widowers...&quot; But even two days before his death, he also said to Yongquan: &quot;Fang Yizhi&#39;s &quot;Tongya&quot; is a good book. If you come here, buy me a copy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How nostalgic he is for this world! Because he has too many things to do, he has recently planned the &quot;Three Books of Dunhuang&quot;, which is being implemented with his disciples. He also has a pair of young children who are still in middle school. However, his frail body is no longer able to support him. Even though he is extremely Unwilling to do so, but helpless, and with no one to talk to, I would &quot;just stare at the ceiling with my absent-minded eyes&quot;, and &quot;suddenly sob&quot; &quot;more than once&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;This photo was probably taken on the last summer day. The brows are slightly furrowed, which is not without melancholy. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi passed away more than thirty years ago. He is only eighty-four years old this year, but what a world that will open up for the study of Chinese history! His classmate later made great achievements in academic studies and is now in good health. If people could choose again in life, how would they choose? Xia Chengtao said to his friend Wang Jisi: &quot;Ji Si, knowledge depends on longevity, not hard work.&quot; However, in life, it has nothing to do with the times and society. How can you really have your own choice? Moreover, &quot;Articles hate destiny.&quot; No matter how proud you are, you can&#39;t resist the tricks of fate! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“无级别”5年后，国家消防救援指挥机构明确为副部级丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259954]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 23:06:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3HQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1126&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3 HQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the morning of August 29, 2023, the Zhejiang Mobile Team of the National Fire Rescue Bureau was established The move-in ceremony was held in Tonglu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten months after the listing, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; were finally announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 31, 2023, the establishment regulations released by the China Institutional Establishment Network clearly stated that the National Fire and Rescue Bureau is a national bureau managed by the Ministry of Emergency Management and is at the deputy ministerial level; the leadership pattern is &quot;one director and four deputies&quot; , with a political commissar; a total of 275 administrative staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Ministry of Emergency Management, since October 2023, the Central Organization Office has intensively announced information on the adjustment of the responsibilities of multiple other ministries and commissions, involving the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, and the National Health Commission , People&#39;s Bank of China, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An important reason why the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; have attracted attention is that after integrating the former Fire and Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management and the Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, since their establishment in October 2018, There has been no clear administrative level. The two agencies merged in January 2023 to form the National Fire and Rescue Service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this calculation, the leadership and command organization of China&#39;s fire rescue team has been in a &quot;levelless&quot; state for the past five years, until this time it was clearly defined as deputy ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management system and organizational structure of the fire brigade have changed several times. In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and became part of the Ministry of Emergency Management to establish a national comprehensive fire rescue team. Among them, the management organization of the Public Security Fire Force was changed to the Fire Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and the management organization of the Armed Police Forest Force was changed to the Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year later, in November 2019, the Central Organization Office issued a notice clarifying that the Fire Rescue Bureau and Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management are the leading and commanding agencies of the fire rescue team and forest firefighting team respectively, but &quot;temporarily The administrative level of the team is unclear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice also shows that starting from August 22, 2018, there will be a three-year &quot;trial running-in period&quot;; during the running-in period, issues such as the number and allocation of leadership positions will be standardized in a timely manner based on the running-in situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the running-in period has expired, the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan National Emergency System Plan&quot; issued in February 2022 further clarified that it is necessary to &quot;integrate the fire rescue team and the forest firefighting team into a formalized, A professional and professional national comprehensive fire rescue team.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another year has passed since then. On January 6, 2023, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, which was formed by integrating the Fire and Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management and the Forest Fire Bureau, was officially launched. Another 10 months have passed since the National Fire and Rescue Bureau was listed and the administrative level was clarified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau clearly state that the National Fire and Rescue Bureau will have a first political commissar who will concurrently be the main responsible comrade of the Emergency Management Department, and the director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau will be concurrently served by the Deputy Minister of the Emergency Management Department. The political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau is concurrently served by the director of the political department of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, news on the website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security showed that Wang Xiangxi, secretary of the Party Committee and Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, has concurrently served as the first political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, and Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management, has served as the director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau. Xu Ping, a member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Management, serves as the political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot;, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau Command Center will also be hung on the Emergency Command Center of the Ministry of Emergency Management. The director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau Command Center will be the deputy director of the Emergency Command Center of the Ministry of Emergency Management. concurrently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time as the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Fixed Plans&quot; were announced,&amp;nbsp;the functions of the Emergency Management Department were also adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsibilities of the Fire Rescue Bureau and Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and the responsibilities related to the education and training of the national comprehensive fire rescue team undertaken by the Education and Training Department are transferred to the National Fire Rescue Bureau; the Ministry of Emergency Management manages the national fire rescue Bureau, and added the responsibilities of formulating firefighter exit and resettlement plans, organizing their implementation, and guiding local governments to establish and improve a comprehensive emergency joint command platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Emergency Management Department will continue to perform related tasks such as appointment and dismissal, deployment, commendation, rewards, punishment, and martyr assessment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in accordance with the principle of decentralization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ The Ministry of Civil Affairs has changed its leadership. Lu Zhi was originally appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and Tang Dengjie was transferred to Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Before taking up his new post, Tang Dengjie served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. The post of Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee was previously held by Lan Fo&#39;an, who has succeeded Liu Kun as Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Tang Dengjie took over, Lu Zhiyuan has been appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. Lu Zhiyuan has worked in Shaanxi Province for many years, serving as deputy secretary of the Yulin Municipal Party Committee and mayor, and secretary of the Weinan Municipal Party Committee. In January 2018, he was promoted to deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. In September 2018, he was transferred across provinces to serve as member of the Standing Committee of the Liaoning Provincial Party Committee and Organization Minister. In September 2021, Lu Zhiyuan was transferred to the Standing Committee of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee, and later served as Deputy Secretary of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Director of the National Development and Reform Commission Zheng Shajie takes on a new position]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November According to news from Qiushi.com on the 1st, the 21st issue of &quot;Qiushi&quot; in 2023 published an article signed by Zheng Shajie - &quot;Through hard work over a long period of time, we will solidly promote the high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;&quot;. The author&#39;s introduction at the end of the article shows, Zheng Shanjie, director of the National Development and Reform Commission, has been appointed as the director of the office of the leading group for promoting the “Belt and Road” construction. &lt;p>; >;Recently, the Personnel Department of the State Sports General Administration issued an announcement stating that based on work needs, Chen Ruolin plans to be deployed from outside Beijing to work at the Swimming Sports Management Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ruolin, female, born in December 1992, has a bachelor&#39;s degree and is currently a coach at the Swimming Academy of Nanjing Institute of Physical Education. Chen Ruolin joined the Jiangsu Provincial Diving Team in 2000 and was selected for the National Diving Team in 2005. She won the women&#39;s single and synchronized 10-meter platform championships at the 2008 Beijing Olympics, the women&#39;s single and synchronized 10-meter platform championships at the 2012 London Olympics, and the 2016 Rio Olympic Games. Olympic women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform champion. She is also Quan Hongchan’s coach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Law: Liu Shaoyun is a first-level justice of the People&#39;s Republic of China]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On October 28, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Court issued an announcement indicating that in accordance with the &quot;Judges Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and other relevant regulations, Liu Shaoyun is a first-level justice of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ From January to September 2023, a total of 405,000 people were punished nationwide]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission on October 29, from January to September 2023, the national discipline inspection and supervision agencies received a total of There were 2.617 million petitions and reports, including 819,000 reports and accusations. 1.283 million clues were handled, including 266,000 interviews and correspondence. 470,000 cases were filed, including 54 cadres at the central management level, 2,480 cadres at the department and bureau level, 20,000 cadres at the county and division level, and 65,000 cadres at the township and section level; the current or former village party branch secretary and village committee director were registered. 46,000 people. 405,000 people were punished, including 331,000 party disciplinary sanctions and 108,000 government affairs sanctions; 34 provincial and ministerial level cadres, 2,244 department and bureau level cadres, 16,000 county and division level cadres, 54,000 township and section level cadres, and general There are 56,000 cadres and 277,000 other personnel in rural areas and enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[He Zehua, the former deputy director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was prosecuted after retirement]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the WeChat public account of &quot;Procuratorial Daily Justice Network&quot;, the former deputy director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, He Zehua, was suspected of accepting bribes and using his influence to accept bribes. The investigation was concluded by the National Supervisory Commission and was designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Dalian City, Liaoning Province reviewed and prosecuted. Recently, the Dalian People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Dalian Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zehua was once Ling Chengxing&#39;s deputy. In May 2013, when Ling Chengxing was appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, He Zehua had been a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration for nearly 10 years. On October 23, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission issued a notice that Ling Chengxing, the former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was suspected of serious violations of disciplines and laws and was undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Children of leading cadres in Hunan’s rectification ask each other to do things]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Hunan The Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision held a meeting to promote the special rectification work of leading cadres in the province who used their power or influence to make profits for relatives and friends. The meeting emphasized that it is necessary to further expand the focus of supervision, not only focusing on the 21 key contents in three categories such as illegal business operations, &quot;branding&quot; and &quot;carrying baskets&quot;, but also paying close attention to the tasks that the children of leading cadres ask each other to do 6 This is a typical performance, strengthen education management supervision, and resolutely put an end to unhealthy tendencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hunan information shows that the cases of Yi Pengfei, former vice chairman of the Hunan Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, and other cases have exposed the problems of children of leading cadres asking each other to do things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[For accepting bribes of nearly 50 million yuan, Wang Xinghua, former secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee, was sentenced to 13 years in prison]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 31, 2023, the Rizhao Intermediate People&#39;s Court publicly pronounced the first instance verdict on Wang Xinghua, former member of the Standing Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee and former secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee, for accepting bribes. The defendant Wang Xinghua was sentenced to 13 years in prison for accepting bribes. A fine of RMB 4 million was also imposed; Wang Xinghua&#39;s property obtained from bribery was confiscated in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Ministry information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ National Health Commission: Promote the establishment of infant care service majors in secondary vocational schools, higher vocational colleges, etc.]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2023, Wang Bin, Director of the General Office of the National Health Commission, It was introduced at the press conference that it will promote the addition of infant care service majors in secondary vocational schools, higher vocational colleges, and higher vocational undergraduates, promote medical institutions to support the development of childcare services, and gradually improve the policies, regulations, standards and service supply of childcare services. , to further promote the continuous optimization of population policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Culture and Tourism: Suspension and cancellation of the qualifications of some national-level intangible cultural heritage protection units]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News, recently, 2,981 conservation units have passed the assessment through self-inspection of conservation units, local inspections and evaluations, soliciting opinions from project inheritance groups, and review by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism; 1 conservation unit has passed the assessment If the evaluation fails, the qualification to apply for national intangible cultural heritage protection funds will be suspended, and rectification will be carried out within a time limit; 3 protection units failed to perform their duties well, and their protection unit qualifications will be revoked and the protection units will be re-identified; 619 protection units have problems with the nature of the unit, organization, etc. In case of major changes, such as failure to meet the basic conditions of a protected unit, the protected unit will be re-identified; 3 previously vacant protected units will be recognized; 12 declared areas or units will not be recognized as protected units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ Since 2017, more than 4,200 cases of illegal cultural relics have been handled]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2023, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the State Administration of Cultural Heritage stated at a joint press conference that since 2017, A total of more than 4,200 cases of cultural relic violations were handled across the country, and more than 650 people were administratively held accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The standards for land acquisition compensation and resettlement for &quot;married girls&quot; are not uniform, and the procuratorial organs issued procuratorial recommendations]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problems such as inconsistent resettlement standards in the land acquisition and compensation process for &quot;married women&quot;, the procuratorial organs issued procuratorial recommendations and promoted the administrative agencies to formulate unified compensation standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate stated that whether &quot;married women&quot; should be compensated and resettled, and whether the compensation and resettlement standards are consistent, is related to the vital interests of women. In land expropriation compensation and resettlement, &quot;married girls&quot; who are registered separately by rural collective organizations shall have equal rights to resettlement and compensation, and shall be compensated and resettled as a single household according to unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After being detained for 902 days and found not guilty, the former richest man in Hubei, Lan Shili, received a compensation of 590,000 yuan from the state]&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, 2023, Lan Shili received the &quot;Criminal Compensation Decision&quot; from the Guangzhou Municipal Procuratorate. &amp;nbsp;On December 17, 2021, the Guangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the charges against Lan Shili could not be established and ruled that Lan Shili was not guilty. Three days later, Lan Shili was released. The &quot;Criminal Compensation Decision&quot; determined that Lan Shili was detained and restricted his personal freedom for a total of 902 days and should receive more than 590,000 yuan in state compensation. &lt;br>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Public reports show that Lan Shili, born in 1960 in Wuhan, Hubei Province, was on the Forbes list of richest people in 2005 with a net worth of more than 2 billion yuan, becoming the &quot;richest man in Hubei&quot;. He is also a member of Dongxing Group and founder of Eastern Star Airlines. In 2008, the global financial crisis broke out, East Star Airlines was also affected and eventually went bankrupt, and Lan Shili was involved in litigation. In 2010, Lan Shili was sentenced to four years in prison for evading the collection of owed taxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ Hangzhou Municipal Education Bureau: Will carry out risk-taking research on on-campus cultural and sports activities]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to news from the Hangzhou Municipal Party Committee and Hangzhou Municipal Government websites on November 1, the Hangzhou Municipal Education Bureau recently responded to the Hangzhou Municipal Recommendation No. 146 of the Second Session of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference on &quot;Ensuring that schools have the courage to implement physical education from court rulings&quot; and &quot;multiple guarantees to prevent parents from excessive accountability&quot; and other contents stated that it will conduct research on self-restraint in school cultural and sports activities, and at the same time adhere to The voluntary principle encourages parents to purchase comprehensive student (child) insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Guangdong Provincial Department of Education: Harmful toys such as &quot;carrot knives&quot; are strictly prohibited from entering campus]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Recently, a new toy called &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; has become popular among primary and secondary school students (young children). Recently, the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Education and Management of Hazardous Toys&quot; (referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), requiring all primary and secondary schools and kindergartens to strictly prohibit such dangerous and harmful toys from entering the campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[It is rumored on the Internet that Wei Dongyi was fired, Peking University refutes the rumor]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently , information about the dismissal of Wei Dongyi, assistant professor at Peking University, circulated online. On November 1, China News Network sought verification from the School of Mathematical Sciences of Peking University, where Wei Dongyi works, for the above information. A staff member of the General Affairs Office of the school said that Wei Dongyi is still employed. A staff member of the Publicity Office of the college said, &quot;We have not received any news of any changes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, on the official website of the Department of Mathematics, School of Mathematical Sciences, Peking University, the name Wei Dong is still listed in the column of &quot;All Faculty&quot; Yi&#39;s resume information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ The Xinjiang Pilot Free Trade Zone was established]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2023, China’s 22nd pilot free trade zone, the Xinjiang Pilot Free Trade Zone, was established, becoming China’s first free trade zone in the northwest The first free trade pilot zone established in border areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Kunming: Cancel sales and purchase restrictions on commercial housing]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&quot;Kunming &quot;Release&quot; news shows that on November 2, the official website of the Kunming Municipal Government issued the &quot;Notice of the Office of the Kunming Municipal People&#39;s Government on the Abolition of a Group of Real Estate Policy Documents&quot;, deciding to abolish the relevant real estate policies issued in 2017 and 2018, which means that the relevant real estate policies issued in the past All sales and purchase restrictions on commercial housing have been cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Changchun three-child child care subsidy plan launched: local household registration required, one-time subsidy of 10,000 yuan]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to news recently announced on the Changchun Municipal Government website, families where couples legally have three or more children will receive a one-time subsidy of 10,000 yuan per child. The conditions are: both husband and wife have permanent residence in Changchun City (including one spouse has a permanent residence in Changchun City and the other is an active military member, or both spouses are active military personnel). From the date of issuance of this plan (i.e. October 25), it is legal. Families that have three or more children and have settled in this city must have completed birth registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&amp;nbsp ; Lou Yangsheng: Today’s Henan attaches more importance to innovation than ever before and is more hungry for talents than ever before]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, at the 6th China·Henan At the opening ceremony of the Talent Recruitment, Innovation and Development Conference and the Third China·Henan Open Innovation and Transnational Technology Transfer Conference, Lou Yangsheng, Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, delivered a speech: &quot;Henan is an important birthplace of the Chinese nation and Chinese civilization, with outstanding people since ancient times. , Talents are emerging in large numbers, inventions and creations are gleaming, and respecting talents and loving them has become a common practice.&quot; &quot;Today&#39;s Henan attaches more importance to innovation than ever before and is hungry for talents more than ever before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from Xinhua News Agency, CCTV News, Shangguan News, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, the &quot;Kunming Release&quot; WeChat public account, CCTV, China News Service, Guangzhou Daily client, The Paper, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃货文人”梁实秋丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:31:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男性没有情绪价值需要”是偏见：互相取暖才能行稳致远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among the many values ​​that one person can provide to another person, emotional value is the most embodying &quot;interactivity&quot; &quot;A kind of. If two people interact and lose the &quot;reciprocity&quot; of emotional value, and the emotional value only becomes the supply of one party, it must mean that the power and status between the two people are not equal, and the person in the lower position needs to pay attention to the person in the upper position. Continuously provide emotional value, the so-called &quot;lower and smaller&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relationship between the sexes should generally be an equal relationship. Respecting each other and pleasing each other is a normal relationship. In this sense, men&#39;s need for emotional value is often ignored, which is an unavoidable issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger said that men actually need emotional value very much. He mentioned a typical example: an old man on the Internet complained on Weibo, talking about his mid-life crisis and his emotional breakdown. For a moment. This old man on the Internet usually appears as a &quot;friend of women&quot;, so he has accumulated a certain number of female fans. As a result, when he started to complain, he did not gain sympathy and comfort from his female fans, even though he usually provided emotional value to his female fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger lamented: Some women seem to truly believe that men must be very happy and should not complain. And they themselves complain all the time. Even if they look very happy to outsiders many times, they can always find something to complain about. These women seem to have a collective consciousness, &quot;You must never let men feel happiness, and you must never let men gain emotional value. As for why, I can&#39;t understand it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very close to my heart. Of course, there are always many examples of couples treating each other as guests or pleasing each other. However, according to my observation, men are always more likely to be frustrated in the process of obtaining emotional value from women. It is this kind of frustration that Fang Hongjian encounters in his wife in &quot;Fortress Besieged&quot;. Before getting married, the relationship between the two was okay, and Sun Roujia gave him a special kind of psychological satisfaction in the face of adversity. But after marriage, Sun Roujia seems to have changed into a different person, which makes readers feel a little incredible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger believes that men and women are not all interested in sex. If a woman talks about her emotional value every day and tries to squeeze her to the limit, any man with some self-respect will eventually leave - for example, Fang Hongjian had this intention. Of course, there are different ways to leave. Many men find that &quot;the emotional value that women cannot give, brothers can give, games can give, and even fishing can give.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very &quot;straight man&quot; statement. It not only explains why there are many &quot;fishing guys&quot; gathering at the nightclub by the river in front of my house all day long, but also explains why some middle-aged men The reason why they always play some games or wait quietly downstairs for a while before going home after work: they know that there are endless complaints and endless mental wear and tear inside the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is, as the blogger said: In the past many years, men’s demand for emotional value has been suppressed. So many women think that men only need to pay. The reason why this kind of abnormal relationship can barely be maintained is because a kind of ideological stamp called &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; restrains men - whether it is to society or to the family. Traditional thoughts and values ​​tell men that you must get married and have this baby. And should suffer for it to be sucked out of any value including happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These words must have hit the hearts of many men who cannot feel happy in their marriages. Many ladies often say that they need to find someone who is &quot;emotionally stable&quot; to get married. Why? The main reason for this choice is probably not only to eliminate those men who are emotionally unstable and like to get angry, but in a deeper and more practical situation, to allow &quot;emotionally stable&quot; men to work hard for the family and regard endurance as the highest pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, as a human being, who should be emotionally stable more than whom? This is clearly a false proposition. Emotional stability is always relative. No one is born with an &quot;emotionally stable&quot; person, and there is never any instability - if such a person exists, it must be made of plastic and steel. It is worth noting that when this requirement becomes a matter of course, it will inevitably lead to the emergence of unfair situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why get married? I&#39;m afraid everyone has their own ideas, but in general, it&#39;s nothing more than these points: continue to write about love, get stable sex, and raise children. When it comes to responsibilities after marriage, in most cases, men often become the main or even the only source of income for the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The twists and turns in the marriage of Fu Seoul and Lao Liu fully demonstrate that emotional value is affected by family economic relations. Once a man takes care of his children at home, the outcome is often not optimistic. Because society has different tolerances for stay-at-home wives and stay-at-home husbands, if a man wants to maintain his dignity and not be discriminated against or feel cowardly, he can only try his best to earn as much money as possible - preferably more than his wife. After all, a man who wanders around the world is more likely to be looked down upon by public opinion than a woman who only takes care of her children at home, and may even be regarded as a &quot;good-for-nothing waste.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It stands to reason that under the male-domestic model, men have great hope of gaining emotional value in the family. But interestingly, the theoretical connotations are often broken in reality. Some men work so hard outside that when they get home they are told that they only know how to play games but don&#39;t know how to do housework. It is sometimes labeled &quot;widowed parenting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, the so-called emotional value is &quot;coaxing&quot;. When a woman feels sad, a man will coax her, and vice versa. If men are always forcibly given a &quot;strong&quot; and &quot;rigid&quot; persona, and are made into a character insulated from emotional value, and they blindly give in a wider range; or in other words, men must take care of women&#39;s emotions, in contrast, It won&#39;t work if you come over. Even if the man has troubles that he can only solve on his own, then the relationship will change and the emotional foundation of sharing weal and woe will be lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t men have emotional needs, or shouldn’t they seek emotional help? Of course not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the issue of emotional value, men and women should be equal. Acknowledging that men and women alike have emotional value needs and giving them respect and care is the normal way of getting along. Based on this, caring for each other and solving each other&#39;s problems is the way to balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A family must not become a quagmire where one party enjoys absolute power and the other party can only make concessions. No one would be willing to marry a slave or a &quot;slave owner&quot;, so both men and women hope that their rights and spirit will be respected by the other party, and refuse to kneel down and make endless unilateral contributions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current marriage rate is plummeting, the divorce rate is rising, and the number of unmarried people is increasing. To a certain extent, it shows that young people have a more rational and strict examination of the connotation of &quot;home&quot;, and thus take the initiative to make their own The body and mind escape from an invisible shackles. This cold fact tells us that marriage and family are &quot;non-material&quot; subjects that two people manage together with love and sincerity. If we want to make marriage and family last longer, and if we want everyone to have more confidence in marriage and family, we must treat the emotional needs of both parties fairly, create a loving and reciprocal relationship, and especially abandon the prejudice that &quot;men have no emotional value needs&quot; , so that each other can maintain the consciousness of understanding and tolerating each other to the greatest extent, and only by providing warmth to each other can we move forward steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戛纳金棕榈获奖影片，一场对亲密关系的审判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcO ZC4eqXITmA884bPF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie, after the husband fell to his death from a building, the court began a trial to determine whether it was murder or suicide. , while also unveiling an analysis of family relationships. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a cabin under the French Alps, an interview is taking place. The female writer seems to be good at avoiding questions, and once turned into the guest and became the questioner. The young reporter sitting opposite her seemed a little overwhelmed and had no choice but to follow her wishes and start chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly, the music played by the writer&#39;s husband came from upstairs, which was deafening, and his dissatisfaction was obvious. The interview was terminated and the female reporter left. Shortly after she left, the writer&#39;s husband was found dead in the snow outside the cabin by their son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, who is the murderer? According to previous suspense narrative strategies, the plot always has to go through multiple reversals before the truth comes to light. The film &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot;, which just won the Palme d&#39;Or at the Cannes Film Festival in 2023, provides another solution. Director Justine Trier does not seem to care whether the plot is reversed, and it does not even matter who the murderer is. unimportant. Putting aside the cloak of suspense, Trier is more interested in how people use their own narratives to complete the analysis of a death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film cleverly sets up the court trial, so that the intimate relationships that should be in the private realm are laid bare and presented to the public. One party wants to prove murder, and the other wants to prove her innocence by proving that her husband committed suicide. Both parties are trying to use their own narratives to get closer to the truth, and all clues may become evidence in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novelist, Sandler Voight&#39;s writing has become the object of scrutiny by the prosecution. &quot;Her life is in the book, especially her relationships.&quot; In the novel, the wife&#39;s disgust for her husband, the possibility of her husband&#39;s death, and the imagination of how to kill are all understood as reflections of the real motivations for killing. Under this kind of scrutiny, the narratives in the book are no longer complete. They are cut into fragments or even sentences, and then the narrative is reconstructed using human will to connect it with reality in the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the key pieces of evidence in the film is the recording of her husband Samuel before his death. Samuel is a former teacher who also enjoys writing. Out of guilt for being partially responsible for his son Daniel&#39;s permanent vision impairment, Samuel spent a great deal of his time on various family matters and on Daniel&#39;s company. He seemed unapologetic and willing, but the recording revealed another side of the family&#39;s close relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recording, Samuel asked his wife to reconsider the division of labor in the family, believing that he had sacrificed too much personal time on family affairs and that he wanted more time to write. After listening, Sandler mocked him coldly, saying that a writer would not stop writing just because he had children and housework. No one forced him, and he did not owe him anything. The director seemed to have intentionally reversed the genders. What Samuel experienced was actually the helpless and struggling situation of many women in married relationships in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the dispute between the two in the recording became more intense. Sandler&#39;s bisexual identity, cheating and other private information were revealed one by one from Samuel&#39;s mouth, and fell into the ears of everyone in the trial. In the view of the prosecution, these are the motives and reasons for the unbalanced relationship between husband and wife and the wife to murder her husband. Here, the recording, which originally only recorded a certain dimension of the relationship between people, is also used to refer to the whole picture, helping the prosecution complete the deduction and reconstruction of the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandler attempted to deny this ever-reconstructed narrative, telling Samuel&#39;s psychiatrist, who was one of the witnesses, &quot;You&#39;re only telling a small part of the whole situation. A pair of Husband and wife are like a mess...&quot; She believed that this did not prove that she was the murderer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradox is that Sandler himself is also consciously or unconsciously self-narrating the truth, including her husband&#39;s unusual behavior in taking medicine six months before his death, seeing a psychiatrist, and being depressed in writing, etc. , all became her reconstruction of the reasons for his suicide during the defense process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the evidence fragments presented by both the prosecution and the defense are real, perhaps no one dares to confirm that the suicide or homicide story reconstructed based on these fragments is the truth itself. As director Justine Trier said, &quot;This is very modern, this is how we live today. In the trial, various things change and are given extra weight, resulting in new fictions.&quot; &quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evidence was not only presented in front of the prosecution and defense, but also slowly unfolded in front of his son Daniel, who also began to look at his parents again. At first, he had no doubts about his mother, but as the two sides narrated at the trial, his attitude gradually became swaying, and he even had an image in his mind of his mother hitting his father hard and pushing him downstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, he also tried to give medicine to the dog to verify the fact that his mother said that his father had vomited after taking medicine. He also recalled the conversation his father had with him when he sent the dog to the doctor. He thought This revealed his father&#39;s suicidal tendencies. From various swings to his own selection of factual fragments after review, Daniel finally constructed his own narrative version of the truth in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A still from &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; (also translated as &quot;Judgment of a Fall&quot;). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier once mentioned in an interview, &quot;These trials have a profound impact on people.&quot; It&#39;s a nightmare to say because your own life is being taken away from you. Everyone is creating a fiction and not really trying to get to the truth. I&#39;m very fascinated by truth and trying to find it through stories and I find that very interesting .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the director also wants to draw the audience into the search for the truth and the construction of the narrative. Under the shell of suspense, we as the audience have naturally been thinking about who the murderer is since Samuel fell from the building. In the battle between the prosecution and the defense, every time they list new evidence, make new statements and excuses, we, like Daniel, can&#39;t help but turn our eyes to Samuel and Sandler, trying to learn from the evidence provided by both sides. Find your own narrative from factual evidence and their narratives to deduce the truth of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But outside the film, we are more passive. All narratives are always based on the characters&#39; interpretation of the truth in the film, which also means that our perception of the truth is more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film ends with Sandler being found not guilty. Since there are elements of fiction on both sides, why does one narrative prevail over the other? Perhaps it was the emotional power of it - Daniel&#39;s monologue about his father moved the judge and helped his mother win. After Sandler came home, Daniel hugged and kissed her. In the silence of the room, a rare warmth lingered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this the truth? Not really. In the previous narratives from all parties, the director has successfully planted the seeds of doubt in the hearts of the audience. Even if Sandler was found not guilty, people&#39;s hesitation and uncertainty about the truth have not disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandra Wheeler, who plays the heroine, once asked the director about the script, whether her character was guilty or innocent. Trier told her, &quot;I don&#39;t know, but I hope You act as if she is innocent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She could be responsible but not guilty, or she could be guilty but not responsible. She could be responsible for driving him to suicide but not guilty of killing him, or she could be guilty of killing him without wanting to. to kill him - either in an impulsive way or in a way that we can try to imagine. The truth is there, but it is too complex to grasp here.&quot; Director Justine Trier said in Said this in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But looking back, the truth may no longer be important. Fiction is a human talent. As long as you are willing, you can construct your own narrative with the help of a few keywords. However, if the relationships between people are like this death, being scrutinized and reconstructed, then in fact, no relationship can withstand such rigorous and detailed analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚太安全专家谈：中国发展红利被周边国家共享]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the end of the Cold War, despite some geopolitical tensions or regional hot issues, the Asia-Pacific region has still maintained peace Stablize. In Europe and the Middle East, wars broke out one after another. How to interpret such an international situation? Why has the Asia-Pacific region been able to maintain peace and stability for decades? How to continue to maintain a prosperous and stable Asia-Pacific? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 29, 2023, at the &quot;Dialogue of Chinese and Foreign Experts&quot; at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, former vice minister of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the People&#39;s Republic of China and founder of the Tsinghua Institute for International Security Strategy, said at the meeting that after the Cold War, the Asia-Pacific region seized the opportunity, quickly opened up to the outside world, and quickly entered regional integration. In the past few decades, there have been no major wars, political conflicts, or major social unrest in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Asia-Pacific region has enjoyed peaceful development for more than 40 years. In this process, China has played a central role. The dividends of China&#39;s rapid regional development have been shared by neighboring countries. China is also the largest international player in most Asia-Pacific countries. trading partner country,&quot; Fu Ying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 29, 2023, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 29, 2023 , many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining security in the Asia-Pacific.&quot; (Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Economic Development Miracle&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t know if you remember that in the 1980s (of the last century), when the Asia-Pacific region began multilateral cooperation, China also joined the regional integration At the time of globalization, many countries are still walking on the edge of development and poverty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying said in her speech that over the past long period of time, the Asia-Pacific region has achieved extremely rapid economic development, surpassing There are many countries and regions in the market. Citing data from the Bank of Asia, she said that in the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown sevenfold. This phenomenon is also called the &quot;economic development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying believes that peace and stability, regional focus on cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization are important reasons for the economic development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the unique driving forces behind decades of stability and security in the Asia-Pacific region? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In order to maintain long-term stability and security in the Asia-Pacific, we need to discover a unique &#39;Asia-Pacific model.&#39;&quot; Chen Dongxiao, president of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, said that &quot;open regionalism&quot; is an important driving factor , and this concept contains many contents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;First of all, economic development cooperation is the focus. It transcends ideologies and government differences. Secondly, under regional openness, no matter big or small, all countries need to abide by relevant rules and regulations and should Follow social rules in an equal way. It is very important that we should not have double standards,&quot; said Chen Dongxiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast to the peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region, wars have been raging in Europe and the Middle East in recent years. During the forum discussion, two European and American scholars also expressed their thoughts on the &quot;differences between China and the West.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Why is the Asia-Pacific region different from Europe? There are many reasons behind it.” Michael Swain, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs in the United States, believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergei Karaganov, dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics, agreed with Shi Wen’s point of view, saying that “it is still in the early stages and we still have to remain cautious.” . At the same time, he also emphasized the &quot;cultural factors&quot; in Europe that were different from Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;European history is filled with many wars. European peace or war is always closely related to Europe&#39;s internal problems.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The risks of U.S. leadership are growing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As for the role of the United States in Asia-Pacific security, Huang Jae-ho, director of the Center for International Studies at Hankuk University of Foreign Studies, said, &quot;Although there is no perfect leadership in the world ( model), but the risks of U.S. leadership are growing.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the U.S. policy toward China as an example, he said that from the Trump administration to the current Biden administration, the United States has undergone many changes in overall strategy and economic details. &quot;The United States has not seen the overall situation clearly, and its strategies and tactics are unclear. Therefore, the United States lacks a consistent vision and policy, which has caused instability in the current international order.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs, mentioned in his speech that &quot;China&#39;s ultimate security role in Asia is still uncertain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying directly refuted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t quite agree with this type of view. Mr. Michael Sven&#39;s logic is very confusing.&quot; Fu Ying said that China has actively promoted economic development in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited a lot from it. . This &quot;unconvincing&quot; logic probably originates from the theory of power change in the international community for hundreds of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, you know that China’s development background is completely different.” She said that there are big differences between China and the United States. But it does not affect China and the United States in pursuing their own development and supporting and benefiting from each other. If you think that China&#39;s strength has become a &quot;threat&quot; in the Asia-Pacific region, how should you view the rise of emerging countries such as India and Indonesia in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying also pointed out that the United States is currently anxious about its declining global influence, but this is not a problem caused by China, but the result of &quot;economic globalization and the United States itself making too many mistakes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The United States&#39; own problems make it difficult. Look at what benefits the United States has gained from the trade war? The trade war has caused the U.S.-China trade deficit to continue to increase, but has it reduced China&#39;s exports to the United States? In fact, it is not, on the contrary, the data is still increasing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She proposed that the United States should be an active contributor to the development of the region, rather than trying to use competition to prioritize and define the region&#39;s agenda and &quot;hijack&quot; A long-term agenda for successful cooperation, dialogue and economic development in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Finding balance and crisis management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In their speeches, many scholars unanimously stated that the old balance in the international order may be broken and new changes are about to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergey Karaganov said that as the United States and Western society began to exert influence to change globalization, the so-called era of globalization has ended. He said that we must have a new theory or a new global governance model, and this model must be decided by all partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For so many years, we have been saying that we want to achieve a win-win situation and that we want to benefit all parties involved. But unfortunately, we do not live in an ideal world. Sometimes we need to be shocked and we need to and reach a balance with different countries,” Sergey Karaganov said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Michael Swan said that any international system must balance the needs of different countries and cooperate after balancing. (Countries) need to seek common interests, have the same demands for economic development, and whether there are the same issues left over from history that need to be resolved, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He insisted that the current uncertainty still exists between countries and cannot be controlled. Countries large and small will be affected by changes in power, and there will undoubtedly be uncertainty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It cannot be said that China believes that all countries are unified and we can do this. It cannot solve many basic problems. Moreover, this is not caused by the United States, but due to structural changes. Yes, it will also trigger changes in the international order.&quot; Shi Wen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to maintain security and peace in the Asia-Pacific region before the new international order is formed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao proposed the &quot;three no&#39;s&quot; principle - that is, not to divide the group camp, not to initiate military war, especially nuclear war, and not to use double standards. &quot;In the past few years, the Chinese government has repeatedly reiterated on many occasions that war is not a good way to deal with differences between countries. On the contrary, it brings more crises.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao believes that Sino-US relations are an important factor in regional security. At the same time, the role of small countries in the Asia-Pacific region cannot be ignored, and they should not be divided into any faction. &quot;Some neutral countries, such as ASEAN countries, can play an important role in dealing with differences and achieving related cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Zaihao pointed out that compared with other regions, the Asia-Pacific region is relatively stable and China and the United States can maintain a relative balance. There are currently outside voices claiming that China and the United States have entered a &quot;new Cold War,&quot; but he believes this is more like a &quot;complex competition.&quot; Moreover, the two major countries have now begun crisis management and set up communication channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, there is no war now, only fighting, so it can still be controlled.” Huang Zaihao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九名市州长“进京检讨”：自然资源部组建以来首次高规格集中、公开约谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259895]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZylf9D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZ ylf9D. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, at the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, there were still flowers placed on the edge of the land Potted plants for sale. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Li Gui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the largest fresh cut flower trading market in Asia, Dounan Flower Market in Kunming City, Yunnan Province It is crowded all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the north side of Dounan Flower Market, across the road is another flower-related market - Yinlian Potted Flower Market. Unlike Dounan, which mainly sells fresh cut flowers, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, built in 2012, sells mostly green plants and potted plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, there was a potted flower market where various seedlings and succulents were grown in the greenhouses, and now some vegetables are also grown there. This has to do with natural resource inspectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 15, 2023, on Funei Street in Beijing, the Ministry of Natural Resources reported on the main violations of laws and regulations discovered during routine inspections in 2023. Among them, the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Yinlian Potted Flower Market was named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to reporting on typical issues, the Ministry of Natural Resources also held an interview meeting: Entrusted by the Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, Chen Chenzhao, the full-time Deputy Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, reviewed the violations of laws and regulations discovered by the inspectors in 2023. The main leaders of 9 municipal (state) governments held face-to-face interviews when the problem was highlighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nine cities (states) are Shijiazhuang City in Hebei Province, Harbin City in Heilongjiang Province, Wenzhou City in Zhejiang Province, Chuzhou City in Anhui Province, Linyi City in Shandong Province, Hechi City in Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, and Qianxinan Guizhou Province in Guizhou Province. Prefecture, Kunming City, Yunnan Province, and Lanzhou City, Gansu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the mayors of the cities (prefectures) who represented these cities (states) in the interviews, the deputy secretaries-general of the provincial (autonomous region) governments where these cities and states are located, and the &quot;top leaders of the natural resources departments at the provincial and municipal levels&quot; ” was also asked to attend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published by the Office of the General Inspector of Natural Resources stated that the interview was to “face-to-face point out the outstanding problems discovered by the inspector, urge the local government to increase rectification and investigation efforts, resolutely curb illegal activities on farmland, and firmly guard the Cultivated land protection red line”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first large-scale, high-level centralized and public interview held by the Ministry of Natural Resources since its establishment in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;Illegal occupation of cultivated land&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;77 acres&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Enter from Gate 1 of Yinlian Potted Flower Market , the first thing that comes into view are various shops with the words &quot;flowers&quot;, &quot;seedlings&quot; and &quot;horticulture&quot; printed on them. In October, osmanthus, bougainvillea and various camellias are still in bloom at the entrance of some shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of these shops exist in the form of greenhouses: the open air outside the house and the roof made of transparent film are covered with a black sunshade net; there are few cement and ceramic tiles on the floor inside the house, and most of them are smoothed. Yellow soil - the flower pots with plants are placed on the ground, and the roots come out from the bottom of the pot. The soil will provide them with moisture and nutrients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Go northwest along the main road for about 300 meters. The shops, greenhouses and sunshade nets have all disappeared, and both sides of the road have become empty and open spaces. There were many bulging white woven bags lying on the open ground. The word &quot;feed&quot; was printed on the outside of the bags. You could smell the stench of feces if you got close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers wearing sun hats tore open the bags and spread the black fertilizer on the yellow mud ground, and someone else opened it with a hoe. An excavator in the distance was working in another open space, and there was a rumbling sound. If it weren&#39;t for being in a city, the scene here would look no different from autumn sowing in the countryside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before it became a vacant lot, it was also a greenhouse selling green plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About a month ago, in September 2023, the greenhouse was demolished after an inspection by leaders of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City. On October 25, 2023, a greenhouse owner who once opened a shop here said that before the shed was demolished, he moved to the current greenhouse in August 2023. The two places are about 500 meters apart, and both are managed by Yinlian Community The established Kunming Qiding Economic and Trade Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Kunming Qiding) is responsible for leasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greenhouse owner said that although the lease contract between the two parties was signed once a year, he had been operating the original greenhouse for nearly ten years. Talking about the reason for moving the store, he thought it was &quot;policy adjustment&quot;: &quot;That piece of land was not approved for commercial use at the time, so it was demolished.&quot; When signing the contract, Kunming Geding &quot;wasn&#39;t sure&quot; about the nature of the land. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, in a notification from the Ministry of Natural Resources, the aforementioned open land was classified as cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that in February 2019, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Chenggong District, Kunming City was included in the scope of rectification of the &quot;big shed house&quot; problem and passed the rectification acceptance; in July 2022, the Yinlian Community will have been reclaimed The agricultural greenhouses were rented to 76 merchants for selling potted flowers, agricultural supplies, pesticides and other business activities, illegally occupying 77 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strictly speaking, the focus of the &quot;big shed house&quot; issue is not the form of building the house, but the nature of the land where the house is built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Agricultural Engineering Technology&quot; magazine, which is under the supervision of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, once explained in an article that the &quot;big shed&quot; problem refers to the illegal construction of agricultural facilities or agricultural parks by some industrial and commercial enterprises, individuals and organizations. The essence of illegally occupying cultivated land or even permanent basic farmland for non-agricultural construction is to change the nature and use of the land, change the agricultural production function, and touch the red line of cultivated land protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Information released by the WeChat public account of the &quot;Chenggong District Natural Resources Bureau&quot; shows that in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Supervision inspected the cleanup and rectification of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Kunming City in 2019. It was found that two cases involving the rebound of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Chenggong District were involved, one of which was the Yinlian Potted Flower Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, a staff member of the Chenggong Branch of the Kunming Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;responsibility for rectification of the &quot;greenhouse&quot; problem involved lies with the street, and he can report it to the Street to understand the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yinlian Potted Flower Market is located in Dounan Street. On October 25, 2023, a person in charge of the Dounan Street Office said: “(The contents in the shed) were vacated before, but last year due to the epidemic and villages were demolished, some green plants for sale were placed in the shed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the street said that during the inspection in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Inspection pointed out the existence of Question: &quot;According to the (inspector&#39;s) requirements, it is required to see loess inside the shed, but if there are things on the soil, it is considered a violation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Chenggong District Natural Resources The Planning Branch and the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau jointly issued notices ordering rectification of illegal acts and time-limited rectification notices to multiple land users. The person in charge of the aforementioned street stated that in accordance with the requirements of the rectification notice, they need to &quot;restore the problematic greenhouse to the state of 2019&quot; before the end of September 2023, that is, empty the contents of the shed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the specific implementation stage, the rectification requirements have been repeatedly refined. The person in charge of the street remembered that in June 2023, after the things in the shed were vacated, the soil was also loosened, but the relevant departments “will put forward different requirements for every different inspection.” “So we have repeatedly asked, and today we have to Remove the house number, and tomorrow I will tell you that there is still an advertisement on the door and I want to remove it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of August 2023, only the empty shell of the greenhouse remained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Jing (second from left), Secretary of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City, is at the rectification work site of the &quot;greenhouse&quot; at Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Dounan Street. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(&quot;Chenggong Release&quot; WeChat public account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Multiple common issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nearly a month after the greenhouse was vacated, on the afternoon of September 15, 2023, 9 cities (states) including Kunming were interviewed by the Ministry of Natural Resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Natural Resources has 9 local natural resource inspection bureaus in Beijing, Shenyang, Shanghai, Nanjing, Jinan, Guangzhou, Wuhan, Chengdu, and Xi&#39;an. At the interview meeting, the directors of the nine local inspection bureaus reported the violations of laws and regulations discovered by the inspectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The information disclosed on the official website of the Ministry of Natural Resources shows that the inspection found that the responsibilities for protecting cultivated land in some areas have not been implemented in place, and prominent problems that hit the red line such as &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grain conversion&quot; of cultivated land still exist. Non-agricultural construction problems such as parks, development zones, and urban municipal roads without approval are more prominent. The problem of illegal occupation of permanent basic farmland and general farmland for turf planting exists in some provinces to varying degrees. The problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; continues to be prohibited and illegal. The problem of occupying farmland, digging lakes and landscaping still occurs in some places. In some places, minerals are illegally approved and illegal mining violates the ecological protection red line control requirements and seriously damages the ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The briefing disclosed more details. Taken together, the number of illegal land use problems in the nine cities (states) interviewed ranked high in the provinces where they are located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Shijiazhuang, Harbin, Wenzhou, Chuzhou and Lanzhou &quot;ranked first in the province&quot; for problems with laws and regulations, Linyi and Guizhou Qianxinan Prefecture &quot;ranked first in the province&quot;, and Kunming &quot;ranked first in terms of the number of problems&quot; Ranking first in the province and second in the province in terms of cultivated land area.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, this inspection also found a number of common problems in many cities. Such as the &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grainization&quot; of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that there are 51 &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Harbin, involving 900.68 acres of cultivated land; there are 111 &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Linyi, involving 1,065.56 acres of cultivated land; and there are &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Hechi. 150, involving 2,629.55 acres of cultivated land; 207 &quot;non-agricultural&quot; problems exist in Qianxinan Prefecture, occupying 1,649.65 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specific manifestations of the &quot;de-agriculturalization&quot; of cultivated land include the problem of &quot;greenhouse houses&quot;, the indiscriminate occupation of cultivated land to build houses in rural areas, and the construction of some engineering projects and infrastructure without approval. Not only in Kunming, but also in Harbin, Wenzhou, and Hechi, the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; has appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, among the 9 cities (states) notified, 6 places including Shijiazhuang, Harbin, Chuzhou, Linyi, Qianxinan Prefecture, and Lanzhou all have illegal mining problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wuchang City, which is managed by Harbin, failed to supervise the illegal mining of granite for construction by Yingze Sand and Stone Co., Ltd. from January 2022 to May 2023, and failed to promptly file a case to investigate and stop it. Reporting illegal mining activities as &quot;false changes&quot; and reporting false information should be subject to inspection. Harbin City has failed to supervise Wuchang City’s untruthful reporting practices, and the audit control is not strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 9 cities (states), Wenzhou, Zhejiang is the only city that has been notified of &quot;continuous frequent petitions in the field of natural resources.&quot; The report shows that since 2021, Wenzhou has been ranking high in the province in terms of the number of petitions in the field of natural resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rectification outside the meeting&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the director of the local inspection bureau reported the violations of laws and regulations in 9 cities (states), the city (state) chiefs spoke separately , &quot;State your position one by one.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Voice of China report, Kunming Mayor Liu Jiachen said that the problem of &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grainification&quot; of cultivated land in Kunming is very prominent, and he &quot;feels deeply self-blame and guilt&quot; for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the speech session, many mayors also said that some problems have been rectified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the problem that the Lai’an County Government in Chuzhou City illegally acquired land for the construction of the supporting landscape water system for the Jinling Water Town Project and occupied 400.4 acres of cultivated land to dig out lakes and landscape, Wu Jin, mayor of Chuzhou City, said that the Lai’an County Government The key issues of the illegal land acquisition to build the supporting landscape water system of the Jinling Water Town Project have been rectified and reclaimed in place on June 30, 2023. They have been upgraded in accordance with the requirements of &quot;concurrent personnel management&quot; and handed over to the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision for accountability. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, several city (state) mayors held meetings to deploy relevant work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, September 17, 2023, Hechi Mayor Wang Jun presided over a government executive meeting, demanding that the bottom line of farmland protection and food security be resolutely maintained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, Wenzhou Mayor Zhang Zhenfeng emphasized at the city&#39;s farmland protection and food security work conference that we must tackle the rectification of problems reported by inspections and follow &quot;one problem, one plan, and closed-loop promotion to the end.&quot; According to the requirements, we will formulate targeted rectification plans, promote the elimination of problem accounts within a time limit, and simultaneously carry out &quot;look back&quot; on rectified problems and draw inferences from one example to make rectifications of the same standard and quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Kunming held a city-wide rectification meeting on illegal land use and farmland outflow. Kunming Municipal Party Committee Secretary Liu Hongjian presided over the meeting and delivered a speech. Mayor Liu Jiachen conveyed the spirit of the Ministry of Natural Resources’ centralized open interview meeting. At the meeting, the Kunming Municipal Natural Resources Planning Bureau reported on the city’s rectification of illegal land use and farmland outflow issues and made a review speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five days later, on September 23, 2023, Chen Jing, secretary of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City, led a team to conduct an on-site investigation on the rectification of &quot;greenhouses&quot; and the rectification of farmland outflow problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published on the WeChat public account of &quot;Chenggong Release&quot; shows that at the rectification work site of the &quot;greenhouses&quot; in the Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Dounan Street, Chen Jing learned in detail about the overall rectification work of the &quot;greenhouses&quot; in the district situation, work progress and existing difficulties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the article published by &quot;Chenggong Release&quot;, there is a photo of Chen Jing standing in a greenhouse. Behind him is the greenhouse that has been demolished to only its frame. Shortly after Chen Jing&#39;s investigation, the frame of the greenhouse was also demolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of Dounan Street mentioned above said that they had already made plans to dismantle the greenhouses before, “mainly some details and standards (not yet determined), which were formulated just after the leaders arrived. We It was rectified quickly and thoroughly.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about the reason for demolishing the greenhouse, the person in charge said that it was to avoid the problem from recurring again. &quot;If the shed is still there, whoever moves the things in next time will say (there is a problem) during the inspection.&quot; He explained, &quot;In the end, we have done the work of the community and the masses, just to make it one-time The renovation is in place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the land where the potted flower market was located was managed by Yinlian Community. After the problem of &quot;big sheds&quot; rebounded, due to &quot;inadequate community supervision&quot;, more than 70 acres of land have now been returned to the streets. Now, the land planted in the place where the greenhouse was demolished is a third-party company commissioned by the street. The person in charge added: &quot;Our street cadres don&#39;t know how to farm and have a lot of work, so we currently entrust a third party to complete the planting task first, and then discuss the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The street person in charge also It said that in May 2023, after it was discovered that the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; had rebounded, relevant street officials were also transferred from their original posts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height= &quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256896&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, workers were handling the fertilizer shipped in the Yinlian Potted Flower Market. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Li Gui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Core functions are still related to land&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Natural Resources interviews the person in charge of the prefectural and municipal governments, which is related to the inspection of natural resources. This is one of the forms of administrative supervision of lower-level governments by higher-level governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Land Inspectorate is the predecessor of the National Natural Resources Inspectorate. In order to curb land violations and implement farmland protection, the State Council formally introduced a land inspection system in 2006. The main inspection targets are provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government, and municipal governments under separate state planning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2018, the Ministry of Natural Resources was established. &quot;With the transformation of natural resource management functions and in order to adapt to the needs of natural resource management,&quot; the National Land Inspectorate was transformed into the National Natural Resources Inspectorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2019, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Regulations on the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Supervision&quot;, which clarified the institutional composition, procedural specifications, and procedures of the central ecological and environmental protection supervision in the form of intra-party regulations. In terms of authority and responsibilities, a two-level inspection system at the central and provincial levels has also been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Chen Haisong, a professor at the Institute of Environmental Law of Wuhan University, even though the Ministry of Natural Resources has integrated the functions of multiple departments, land-related functions are still the core. “The core of natural resources is land resources,” Chen Haisong said. Therefore, natural resource inspections should focus on the most mature land inspection business and continue to develop in depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Implementation Regulations of the Land Management Law&quot; that came into effect on September 1, 2021 clarified the scope and working methods of natural resource inspection for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The regulations stipulate that the national natural resources inspection agency shall, according to the authorization, monitor the protection of cultivated land, the economical and intensive use of land, and the preparation and implementation of land spatial planning by the people&#39;s governments of provinces (autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government) and the people&#39;s governments of cities determined by the State Council. Supervise the implementation of major national decisions on land management, the implementation of land management laws and administrative regulations, and other land use and land management situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national natural resources inspection agency may also interview the relevant person in charge of the local people&#39;s government under supervision, and may make recommendations to the supervisory authority, appointment and dismissal authority and other relevant authorities in accordance with the law on holding the relevant responsible persons accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike this time when nine city (prefecture) governors were called to Beijing for interviews, most of the interviews conducted by the national natural resources inspection agency were conducted locally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October to November 2022, the national natural resources inspection agency conducted on-site inspections of cultivated land protection and mineral resources in 31 provinces (autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government) and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, and discovered some illegal and illegal issues . In response to the outstanding problems discovered by the inspectors, with the authorization of the National Natural Resources Chief Inspector, the national natural resources inspection agency stationed in the local area conducted interviews with some municipal governments that had serious violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Chengdu Bureau interviewed Dali, Yunnan, the Beijing Bureau interviewed Xingtai, Hebei, and Jinzhong, Shanxi, the Nanjing Bureau interviewed Jiujiang, Jiangxi, and the Guangzhou Bureau interviewed Qingyuan, Guangdong, and Nanning, Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Chen Haisong’s view, the profound meaning of this interview with the main person in charge of the local government in Beijing is still related to food security. “For a long time to come, the protection of cultivated land and food security will be very important. The problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the interview, Chen Chenzhao, the full-time deputy chief inspector of national natural resources, said: &quot;The task of protecting cultivated land has not been eased, but has become more difficult. Resolute and powerful measures must be taken to continue to strengthen the protection of cultivated land. Firmly hold on to the red line of 1.8 billion acres of cultivated land.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部：中小学校要确保学生课间正常活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:11:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the problem of &quot;restraint for 10 minutes between classes&quot; among primary and secondary school students in some places has attracted widespread attention from the society. Xinhua News Agency &quot; A reporter from Xinhua Viewpoint interviewed the relevant responsible comrades from the Ministry of Education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsible comrade said that it is very important and necessary for primary and secondary schools to arrange breaks between classes, which is helpful for students to regulate their emotions, relax their body and mind, enhance their physical fitness and prevent and control myopia. The Ministry of Education attaches great importance to students&#39; recess. The &quot;School Protection Regulations for Minors&quot; (Ministry of Education Order No. 50), which will be implemented on September 1, 2021, clearly states that legitimate exchanges between students during recess and other non-teaching time are not allowed. Unnecessary restrictions are placed on the freedom of speech and behavior such as games, activities outside the classroom, etc. In actual work, primary and secondary schools are required to arrange 30 minutes of physical activities between classes every day, and students should be arranged to go out of the classroom for appropriate activities and relaxation during each class break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsible comrade pointed out that the Ministry of Education will further urge local governments and schools to strictly implement relevant national regulations, follow the laws of education and the laws of students&#39; physical and mental development, and resolutely correct the simple restriction of students on the grounds of &quot;ensuring student safety&quot; Necessary recess breaks and activities will be implemented; localities and schools will be guided to scientifically implement management and safety precautions, strengthen inspections of outdoor facilities and personnel on duty, strengthen students’ safety knowledge education, minimize the risk of safety accidents, and make children happy Activities with confidence. At the same time, schools will be required to work closely with home-school communities, strive for parents&#39; understanding and social support, and work together to ensure students&#39; normal activities during class and promote students&#39; healthy growth and all-round development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽武校投毒致7死案开庭：“26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the incident, seven families of the deceased took a group photo. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;After the incident, seven families of the deceased took a group photo. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I thought to myself that this case could not be solved, but I didn’t expect it to be solved.” On the afternoon of October 31, 2023, 61-year-old Diao Shanyun told a Southern Weekend reporter on the phone. 26 years ago, his son Qian Min was poisoned to death at the age of 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xiping learned that the murderer had been captured in June 2023, and her brother Yang Changwei died in the same poisoning case. &quot;It&#39;s been 26 years, and I finally have an explanation for my brother.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened at about 7:00 on June 30, 1997, after about 130 teachers and students from the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County, Ma&#39;anshan, Anhui Province had eaten breakfast. Symptoms such as vomiting and convulsions occurred. Seven students, including Qian Min and Yang Changwei, died due to ineffective rescue efforts. An investigation by the public security agency found that they were all poisoned by poisonous 424 ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-six years later, on October 29, 2023, the Ma&#39;anshan City Public Security Bureau held a briefing meeting on the collective poisoning case at the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts Schools in Hexian County, and announced the arrest of two suspects in the case, Fu Moujie and Zhu A certain forest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9:00 in the morning on November 1, the case was heard in Maanshan Intermediate Court. The Ma&#39;anshan City Procuratorate requested that Zhu Moulin and Fu Mojie be held criminally responsible for poisoning. More than 40 relatives of the defendant and the victim attended the trial, but the verdict was not pronounced in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Poisoning more than 130 people in retaliation for the director of the museum&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the lunch recess, Yang Xiping told Southern Weekend reporters, “The person who was interrogated in the morning was named Fu, and he said that he had taken someone named Zhu. 500 yuan was poisoned, and I am confused and still have something to say.&quot; Yang Xiping said that the court will continue the trial of Zhu Moulin in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to upstream news reports, in court, the two defendants denied premeditating the crime. The public prosecution recommended that the two be sentenced to more than ten years in prison, life imprisonment or the death penalty. The families of the seven victims proposed nearly 7.7 million yuan in civil compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before the trial, Yang Xiping took out the photo of his younger brother that he brought with him and looked at a little boy wearing a red sportswear. He looked thin and was forever frozen at the age of 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are four Yang Xiping sisters. Yang Changwei is the youngest son and the only boy in the family. As the eldest son of the family, Yang Xiping went out to work early in order to support his younger brother in school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She loved this younger brother and took him with him wherever he went while working at home. His younger brother loved to fight, so his family sent him to the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County to learn boxing. Yang Xiping only remembered that the tuition was not cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We made seven or eight thousand at one time.” Diao Shanyun said that in the past, he and his husband Qian Farong were in business and could not take care of their youngest son Qian Min, so they settled in the martial arts school and planned to wait until his son was 18 years old. So he joined the army, &quot;he served for less than two years, and finally brought back an urn.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The blow was too big and I couldn’t bear it.” 62-year-old Qian Farong still uses Qian Min’s photo as a WeChat avatar. He remembers that after receiving the news that his son was poisoned on the day of the incident, , I rushed to the hospital, but it was already too late. At 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon on July 1, 1997, Qian Min suffered from convulsions and passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Qian Min squatting on a wooden stake. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;256828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qian Min squatted on the wooden post. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Qian Farong and his wife did not expect that the murderer was Fu Moujie, a coach who taught at the martial arts school. &quot;The coach surnamed Fu likes my son the most. They live in the same room. Every time we go to see my son, we have to thank him.&quot; Diao Shanyun said that his son often talks about how good Fu is, &quot;Why does he not like my son?&quot; My son lived in the same room with him. I heard from my son that Teacher Fu was very good and had a good character. How could he do this?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The indictment from the Ma&#39;anshan City Procuratorate shows that this case The poisoning case originated from a competition between two martial arts gyms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 1994, the defendants Zhu Moulin and Peng Mouwei ran the He County Shaolin Martial Arts Gym in Buji Town, Wujiang Town, He County, with Zhu Moulin as the director and Peng Mouwei as the head coach. During the business process, the two had conflicts. Peng Mouwei left the martial arts hall and reopened Hexian North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in Xibu Town, taking most of the teachers and students with him. Zhu Moulin therefore harbored a grudge against Peng Mouwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1996, the defendant Fu Moujie went to teach at the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County run by Peng Mouwei. While teaching, he gradually became dissatisfied with Peng Mouwei due to trivial matters. Zhu Moulin and Fu Mojie met after being introduced by others. During the process of getting along, they both expressed their dissatisfaction with Peng Mouwei, so they decided to retaliate against Peng Mouwei together and bring down Peng Mouwei&#39;s martial arts school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June of the following year, Fu Jie and Zhu Moulin discussed and decided to use poisoning to retaliate against Peng Mouwei. After Fu Jie implemented it, Zhu Moulin paid Fu Jie 50,000 yuan. Lin paid a certain order 500 yuan on the spot. At the end of the month, Fu Moujie resigned from the martial arts school and returned to his hometown in Jianli, Hubei Province to buy two packs of rat poison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the night before the incident, on the evening of June 29, Fu Moujie ran from the south of the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County to the kitchen of the martial arts school, and put two packets of rat poison in a red plastic basin on the table on the south side of the kitchen. After mixing the salted cowpeas inside, he fled from the original road and left Hexian County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 7 o&#39;clock the next morning, more than 130 teachers and students in the martial arts school developed vomiting, convulsions and other symptoms after eating breakfast. Yang Changwei, Wang Jun, Xing Tao, Liu Wenbao, Tian Dan, Tang Yuye, Qian Min, etc. 7 students died. During the on-site investigation, items such as salted cowpeas and gauze masks were extracted, and the ingredients of Toxin 424 were detected. In addition, the causes of death of 7 students were identified. After identification, the 7 students died of 424 rat poison poisoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Fu Mojie and Zhu Moulin were missing, and it was difficult for the police to solve the case for a while. The Ma&#39;anshan Municipal Public Security Bureau introduced at the briefing meeting that after the case occurred, the public security agency set up a task force to conduct visits and investigations around the crime scene and analyzed that Fu Moujie and Zhu Moulin were suspected of committing major crimes. On July 14, 1997, the public security organs listed Fu Jie and Zhu Moulin as fugitives on the Internet, offered a reward for their arrest, and continued to pursue them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo of Fu Moujie playing with students. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A photo of Fu Moujie playing with students. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Finally we can give an explanation”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“We don’t know who to look for. The person who poisoned him has run away. What do you think we should do?” Yang Xiping received the news from her neighbor half a month after the incident. When she returned home, she saw a coffin in the yard. She remembered clearly, &quot;The moment I knelt on the ground, I saw that my father&#39;s hair was all white and he was so thin.&quot; It doesn’t even look like it anymore.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diao Shanyun still can’t figure out why his son was poisoned to death by his favorite coach. After the couple buried their son, they bought a tombstone with the words: &quot;My beloved son Qian Min, unfortunately died unjustly in the June 30 massacre in 1997.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the second half of 2022, this case that had been silent for many years There was a breakthrough in the poisoning case. The task force discovered traces of Zhu Moulin in Guizhou and basically locked his hiding place in early 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early May 2023, the police in Jinjiang, Fujian Province used big data analysis and found that a man working in a tannery factory had similar physical characteristics to the suspect Fu Moujie. After repeated comparisons and confirmations by the police in the two places, they immediately Keep it under control. The task force rushed to Jinjiang, Fujian Province on the evening of May 6. After preliminary interrogation, Fu Moujie explained the crime to the public security organs. On May 9, Fu Moujie was escorted back to He County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time as Fu Moujie was captured, in the early morning of May 7, the task force went to Guiyang City, Guizhou Province. With the assistance of the local police, Zhu Moulin, who had concealed his identity and opened a local bottled water production company, was arrested at the factory. Successfully captured. When he saw the police who came to arrest him, Zhu Moulin froze in place and was surprised. He didn&#39;t expect that the police would come to his door after so long. In the early morning of May 8, Zhu Moulin was escorted back to He County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, at the press briefing on the martial arts school poisoning case, the Maanshan City Public Security Bureau task force introduced: After interrogation, Fu Moujie confessed that after committing the crime, he had been hiding in Tibet with no fixed residence. He moved to Xinyu City in Jiangxi Province, Dehua County in Fujian Province, Putian City, Jinjiang City and other places to make a living by doing odd jobs. Because he was afraid that his identity would be exposed and investigated by the public security organs, he did not dare to register his identity information, and did not dare to get vaccinated or take nucleic acid tests during the epidemic. When applying for a job, I never choose a position or negotiate salary, just to have a place to hide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhu Moulin&#39;s account, in order to avoid attacks by the public security organs, he concealed his true identity and wandered alone during his absconding period. He first hid in Poyang County, Jiangxi Province for 2 years, and then moved to Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province to work. When I opened a bottled water production company in Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, and Guiyang City, Guizhou Province, I have been living a life of fear for so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In June, my dad received a notice saying that the murderer had been found, and I came back immediately.&quot; Yang Xiping said that when he heard that the murderer had been found, both he and his father cried on the phone. &quot;Finally, I can give him some help.&quot; My brother gave me the explanation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xi often thinks that if his brother is still here, this family must be different. She asked her sisters not to marry far away, &quot;because there is no younger brother and my mother is not in good health.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xiping said that his mother became seriously ill due to the loss of his son, and his father suffered a neurasthenia after suffering a shock. As a result, his third sister no longer wanted to study. &quot;My father often couldn&#39;t find anyone at night. He would either go to his brother&#39;s grave and cry, or he would go to the river or the bricks. We would search everywhere.&quot; Yang&#39;s father has been blaming himself for hurting his son and can&#39;t get out. Because it was he who sent his youngest son to an expensive martial arts school despite his family&#39;s objections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31, Yang Xiping rushed to He County with his family to prepare for the court session the next day. She hoped that Fu and Zhu would be punished as they deserved. &quot;If nothing happens to my brother, he will be 37 years old this year and it&#39;s time to start a family.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访俄专家安德烈·科尔图诺夫：俄乌冲突越早结束，对大家都越好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今秋的北方，为何又热又霾？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 1, 2023, People&#39;s Park, Luancheng District, Shijiazhuang City , citizens wearing masks went for morning exercises in the haze. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The autumn in North China in 2023 is a bit hot and hazy. On November 3, with the arrival of cold air, diffusion conditions gradually improved, and pollution was gradually cleared from north to south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High temperatures have exceeded 40℃ for many days in a row in summer. At the end of October, temperatures in Beijing, Tianjin, Shandong and other places rarely warmed up again. The highest temperatures in Zhengzhou City, Henan Province even reached 30℃ on November 1st and 2nd. and 29℃. In early November in Beijing, there were still many people wearing short sleeves and shorts on the streets at noon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region and surrounding cities are plunged into smog. According to statistics from the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control, as of October 30, 20 cities in the region have initiated heavy pollution weather warnings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The pollution processes that have occurred in North China in the past two days once again remind us that China still has a long way to go to fundamentally improve air pollution.” He Kebin, academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering and director of the Carbon Neutrality Research Institute of Tsinghua University, said in the speech It was stated at the 2023 Annual Meeting of the China Clean Air Policy Partnership held in Beijing on November 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is it affected by meteorological conditions, air pollution is also inextricably linked to global climate change. Zhu Tong, academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and professor of the School of Environmental Science and Engineering at Peking University, said at the above meeting that as pollutants emitted from anthropogenic sources decrease, climate warming will also aggravate air pollution, such as smoke and dust brought by forest wildfires, near-ground The aggravation and generation of ozone pollution will further affect human health. Solving related basic scientific problems is the challenge and focus in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The overall situation is good, and the performance of key areas is average&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from late October, the haze in the north began to spread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I just came back from Hebei very late yesterday. Some cities have activated orange warnings for heavy air pollution, and some areas have worse air pollution than Beijing.&quot; Li Pei, a first-level inspector of the Atmospheric Environment Department of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment said at the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to monitoring data, at 17:00 on November 2, the real-time PM2.5 concentration in Beijing was 73 μg/m³, which was a &quot;good&quot; level, while Xingtai City, Baoding City, Handan City, and Shijiazhuang City in Hebei Province broke through 200μg/m³, reaching &quot;severe pollution&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39. gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;256942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;Daily changes in PM2.5 concentration nationwide from October 22 to 29, 2023 (Source: China Environmental Monitoring Station, Henan Provincial Ecological Environment Monitoring and Safety Center) National Joint Center for Air Pollution Prevention and Control/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2013 to 2017 and 2017 to 2020, our country implemented the &quot;Air Pollution Prevention and Control Action Plan&quot; (&quot;Ten Measures for Atmospheric Pollution&quot;). &quot;), &quot;Three-Year Action Plan to Win the War to Defend the Blue Sky.&quot; Since 2013, the average annual concentration of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; has maintained a downward trend as a whole, and the number of cities that meet the standards is also increasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, according to &quot;Atmospheric China 2023: China&#39;s Air Pollution Prevention and Control Process&quot; released by the Asian Clean Air Center, in 2022, the proportion of cities nationwide that meet standards will increase from 70.2% to 74.6%; nationwide severe and above The ratio of polluted days was 0.9%, a year-on-year decrease of 0.4 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the overall performance of the country is good, the performance of key regions is average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations in the Yangtze River Delta region remained the same year-on-year; Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding &quot;2+26&quot; cities and the Fenwei Plain both increased year-on-year, with increases of 2.3% and 9.5% respectively. %. Among the 168 key cities, the number of cities with PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations rising instead of falling has increased from 24 in 2021 to 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cold air activity is weak&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Meteorological conditions are the external cause of this round of polluted weather. Li Pei said that although my country&#39;s air pollution control has achieved certain results, the results are not yet stable. Generally speaking, it has not yet gotten rid of meteorological influences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The expert team of the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control analyzed that since October 22, the cold air activity in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas has been weak, and the surface temperature and relative humidity of the lower atmosphere have been higher than normal, which is easy to Form regional pollution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to popular science from the China Meteorological Administration, fog and haze are more likely to occur in autumn and winter, which are related to calm weather. The &quot;quiet&quot; in static and stable weather means that the wind speed in the horizontal direction is small, and &quot;stable&quot; means that the atmospheric stratification in the vertical direction is relatively stable, and there is little vertical exchange between the lower atmosphere and the middle atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The formation of stable weather is related to factors such as topography and circulation. Special terrains such as mountains, hills, and basins can hinder the circulation of air. The Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region is affected by the &quot;dustpan-shaped&quot; terrain of high in the northwest and low in the southeast. Pollutants are easy to accumulate in front of the Taihang Mountains and Yanshan Mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the circulation factor, if there is a temperature inversion in the atmospheric stratification (the lower layer is cold and the upper layer is warm), heavier air will be in the lower layer and lighter air will be in the upper layer. The atmospheric structure is stable and vertically diffused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Air quality is not only affected by short-term meteorological conditions, but also related to long-term climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fang Chong, chief forecaster of the Central Meteorological Observatory, generally speaking, mid-to-late October has entered the active period of cold air, but in 2023 the cold air will be significantly weaker and the temperature will be significantly higher. Currently, a total of 237 national-level weather stations have broken the historical extreme value of the highest temperature in late October, which is a rare situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In 2023, Canada&#39;s forest fires had a serious impact on New York&#39;s air quality. At a time when New Yorkers may have forgotten what air pollution is, the wildfires reminded them that climate change will bring extraordinary consequences. Serious air pollution will cause harm to human health.&quot; Zhu Tong said at the meeting that in addition to cases of wildfires, future climate change will also bring more frequent extreme climate events such as extreme high temperatures, droughts, and sandstorms. The harm caused will also be multiplied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010. JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010.JPG&quot; data-key= &quot;256943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2023, severe air pollution occurred in Toronto due to the spread of smoke and dust from wildfires in Canada. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, CH&lt;sub>;4&lt;/sub>;, N&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O, etc.) and atmospheric pollutants (such as SO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, NO&lt; Sub>;x&lt;/sub>;, PM, etc.), the two are highly homologous, and most of them are generated by mineral combustion emissions. Therefore, when air pollution occurs, it may also represent an increase in greenhouse gas emissions; secondly, Many components of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; will affect atmospheric radiation, thereby affecting the energy balance and causing climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Qianyuan said that aerosol particles may also participate in the formation of clouds and rain, thereby affecting the weather system and climate conditions; on the other hand, climate change itself may lead to increased air pollution, such as rising temperatures may cause Increases in ozone concentration, such as changes in atmospheric circulation patterns, may affect atmospheric stability and diffusion conditions, leading to changes in PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pollution reduction and carbon reduction synergies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;He Kebin said that since 2013, the &quot;Ten Measures for Atmosphere&quot; have &quot;won the battle to defend the blue sky&quot;. , emissions of air pollutants have declined, but the annual emission reduction range has gradually narrowed. This reflects the marginal effect of air pollution prevention and control. “All the good things, the big profits, and the big emission reduction potentials have been done.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The internal cause of this round of pollution in Beijing, Tianjin, Hebei and surrounding areas is still man-made emissions. A team of experts from the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control explained that emissions from motor vehicles, industrial furnaces, etc. are the main sources of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; pollution in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas, and straw burning has a negative impact on local PM&lt;sub>; 2.5&lt;/sub>;Pollution contributes prominently. The activity level of industrial enterprises, heavy trucks and the number of straw fire points in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas increased month-on-month, and pollution emissions showed an increasing trend. In terms of industrial sources, since late October, regional industrial electricity consumption has increased by about 5% compared with early and mid-October; in terms of mobile sources, the traffic volume of heavy trucks in Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas is at a high level since autumn and winter, which is higher than that in October. The early to mid-term prices were about 14% higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Air pollution control needs to find new impetus, and the synergy of pollution reduction and carbon reduction is an important starting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After carbon peaks in 2030, the role of end-of-pipe governance will become smaller and smaller, and it will gradually shift to the adjustment and reduction of the four major structures (energy structure, industrial structure, transportation structure, and land use structure). Pollution reduction and carbon reduction will create synergies.&quot; He Kebin believes that whether it is for economic development or improving air quality, carbon reduction is the recent pressure and the driving force for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the National Development and Reform Commission and other ministries and commissions jointly issued the &quot;Pollution Reduction and Carbon Reduction Synergy and Efficiency Implementation Plan&quot;, stating that &quot;collaboratively promote pollution reduction and carbon reduction to achieve integrated planning and Integrated deployment, integrated promotion, and integrated assessment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Gang, deputy director of the Environmental Planning Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, introduced at the meeting that from the perspective of air pollutants and carbon emissions, two-thirds of cities have not achieved synergy during the &quot;Thirteenth Five-Year Plan&quot; period. Improvement; from an industry perspective, although pollutant emissions in most industries are currently showing a significant downward trend, carbon emissions are still growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Gang said that collaborative governance of pollution reduction and carbon reduction is not like other pollution control work in the past. There is a lot of international experience to draw from. At present, my country&#39;s pollution reduction and carbon reduction collaborative efficiency work faces some challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, there is still a lack of support in the theoretical system, and research on the characterization of pollution emissions should be strengthened to identify the homology and heterogeneity of emissions; in terms of regulation, target allocation, smart regulation, governance technology, etc. still need to be A series of studies will be carried out; relevant policies also need to be further coordinated. The other side of challenges also means opportunities. If we respond proactively, air pollution control and carbon emission control can achieve a win-win situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>