<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[绿色金融榜：哪家银保机构的“绿色”更纯净？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261524]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rapidly developing green finance has been clearly promoted to a national financial strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Central Financial Work Conference listed green finance as one of the &quot;five major articles&quot; that must be done well, the Research Bureau of the People&#39;s Bank of China recently published a report According to the article &quot;Promoting the Effective Connection of Green Finance and Transformation Finance&quot;, as of the end of the third quarter of 2023, my country&#39;s green loan balance and domestic green bond market balance have reached 28.58 trillion yuan and 1.98 trillion yuan respectively, ranking first and second in the world respectively. Bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Central Bank Research Bureau also said that it will draw on its experience in setting green financial standards, gradually launch transformational financial standards that are applicable to all types of financial products, and will strengthen carbon accounting. and environmental information disclosure requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is more worth mentioning is that since the &quot;Green Finance Guidelines for the Banking and Insurance Industry&quot; was implemented in 2022, banking and insurance institutions have increasingly paid attention to green financial services and their own Environmental, social and governance performance. Statistics from the Insurance Association of China show that as of the end of June 2023, green insurance’s half-year premium income was 115.9 billion yuan; the balance of insurance funds invested in green development-related industries was 1.67 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 36%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the efforts of relevant ministries and regulatory agencies, what is the green finance report card of various banks and insurance companies? Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed a green finance indicator system based on the principles of fairness, justice and science to evaluate the purity of green finance of financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The Six&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Big Dimensions of the Green Finance List&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In view of the different business structures of financial institutions in the banking and insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has set up different evaluation index systems to evaluate green finance in the banking and insurance industries respectively. Development status, and explore how various bancassurance institutions can further enhance their green financial business and improve their own ESG performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center conducts qualitative and quantitative inspections and evaluations of commercial banks from the four dimensions of green financial products, environmental contribution, social responsibility and ESG governance. Insurance institutions are evaluated qualitatively and quantitatively based on four dimensions: economic performance, environmental performance, social performance and corporate governance. The quantitative and qualitative scores account for 70% of the total weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. The weight of the two scores is 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank ranking indicator system&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;12&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;second-level Indicators&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;25&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;three-level indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research The center inspected and evaluated 20 commercial banks from six dimensions, and set up 12 second-level indicators and 25 third-level indicators, and then gave different weights to different sub-indicators based on their importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /29/4ca1e1b6b1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;3378&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/4ca1e1b6b1.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;259950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the bank ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(1) Green financial products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is the connotation and extension of green financial products? For commercial banks, in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Green Finance Evaluation Plan for Banking Financial Institutions&quot;, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center will include green loan balance, growth rate, proportion, total issuance amount of green bonds, and underwriting scale into the banks in the 2023 Green Finance List List evaluation indicators. The total weight of the five third-level indicators in this dimension is 16%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2) Environmental contribution. Environmental contribution refers to the actual contribution and performance of financial institutions in environmental protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, in order to promote the realization of the &quot;double carbon&quot; goal, various financial institutions have actively established green and low-carbon operating systems, formulated carbon emission targets for the future period, and established The carbon emission statistics platform calculates its own greenhouse gas emissions and per capita greenhouse gas emissions, analyzes its own carbon emission potential, and provides data support for low-carbon operation management. On the other hand, various financial institutions have established the concept of &quot;green operation office&quot; to reduce the impact of operating activities on the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center combines publicly disclosed information and uses greenhouse gas emissions and per capita greenhouse gas emissions to examine the green and low-carbon operating systems of various financial institutions. Per capita energy consumption and per capita water consumption are used to measure the performance of each financial institution in green operations. Overall, the higher the environmental contribution of a financial institution, the better its green and low-carbon operations are, the less damage it causes to the environment, and the higher its carbon neutrality efficiency and energy utilization efficiency. The total weight of the four third-level indicators in this dimension is 8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(3) Social responsibility. Social responsibility refers to the performance of social responsibilities of financial institutions, social evaluation, and employee development and protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This indicator includes four levels: First, it refers to financial institutions adhering to the original intention of serving financial entities, actively serving the country&#39;s major strategic deployments, and guiding the flow of financial resources to national priorities. Support real economic industries such as advanced manufacturing and technology innovation enterprises, and improve the inclusiveness of financial services. The weight of relevant indicators is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The second refers to financial enterprises implementing the rural revitalization strategy, allocating financial resources to all aspects of rural economic and social development, increasing the supply of agricultural-related credit, and consolidating and expanding The results of poverty alleviation and rural revitalization have been effectively linked with financial support. The weight of relevant indicators is 9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The third refers to financial institutions facing the current situation of China&#39;s aging population, participating in the construction of the three pillars of the pension security system, providing high-quality pension financial services, and developing electronic vouchers for medical insurance and social security promotion and application to optimize social security services. The weight of relevant indicators is 8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fourth refers to the development of financial institutions’ own human capital, which is mainly reflected in employee training coverage and per capita training hours, and the establishment and improvement of a standardized, multi-level talent training system. , laying the foundation for employees’ personal career development. The weight of relevant indicators is 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To sum up, the four second-level indicators under this dimension include a total of 13 third-level indicators, with a total weight of 36%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(4) ESG governance. ESG governance here refers to whether financial institutions have established organizational structures and performance assessments that are compatible with green finance, environmental contribution and social responsibility. ESG performance is an important consideration for financial companies&#39; sustainable development capabilities, and ESG concepts have become an important concept for investors&#39; investment decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More and more financial institutions have established ESG governance structures, set up specialized departments or offices to take charge of green finance and other work, and incorporated ESG-related indicators into their performance appraisal systems to Motivate employees to achieve better green financial performance. At the same time, listed companies are subject to ESG ratings by major rating agencies. This list uses MSCI rating results to measure the ESG governance performance of each financial institution, comprehensively reflecting the ESG performance of each financial institution in authoritative rating agencies. The total weight of the three third-level indicators in this dimension is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated the relevant indicators of 20 commercial banks based on the above dimensions and indicator system, and using 2022 to 2023 as the observation period. Score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The green finance list of banking financial institutions shows that Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China and Industrial Bank rank among the top three. They are also the only three commercial banks with a total score of more than 70 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29 /ffe64333fb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ffe64333fb.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The four major banks: ICBC and Agricultural Bank of China&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;each has its own&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;lead&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;In order to conduct an in-depth analysis of the outstanding performance of different types of commercial banks in the field of green finance, the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center focused on analyzing the green finance initiatives taken by commercial banks with outstanding performance in each sub-category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, the total green loan balance of state-owned banks is much higher than that of other banks. For example, at the end of June 2023, the balance of ICBC&#39;s green loans reached 5 trillion yuan, accounting for more than 30% of the bank&#39;s total loans; state-owned banks are also at the forefront of the total green bond issuance and green bond underwriting amount indicators. For example, by the end of 2022, Bank of China’s green bond issuance amounted to 87.7 billion yuan, and its green bond underwriting amount was 453.9 billion yuan, ranking first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of ESG governance, the six major banks have all set up organizational structures and performance appraisal systems that are compatible with green finance. The latest ESG rating results announced by MSCI also All were A-level and received full marks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the field of social responsibility, the six major banks all performed well in aspects such as aging-friendly services, issuance and promotion of electronic social security cards and electronic medical insurance vouchers, and received full marks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The difference is that the balance and proportion of ICBC green loans, the balance and proportion of agriculture-related loans, and the balance and proportion of manufacturing loans are The indicators ranked first among the four major banks. Although its total greenhouse gas emissions and per capita energy consumption are higher than the other three major banks in terms of environmental contribution, its overall ranking is still first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China’s green loan balance and manufacturing loan balance are second only to ICBC, but the growth rate of green loan balance is the fastest among the four major banks; at the same time, The bank&#39;s county-level green loan balance and proportion rank first among its peers. As of the end of June 2023, the bank&#39;s cumulative scale of carbon emission reduction loans issued and the reduction of carbon emissions it has driven are among the best among its peers. Although the overall score of Agricultural Bank of China is 5.25 points lower than that of ICBC, it is significantly ahead of the other two major state-owned banks, seizing the &quot;second spot&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Joint-stock banks: Xingye stands out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, joint-stock companies The green loan balance of banks is weaker than that of state-owned banks, and the average proportion of green loan balance is about 11%, which is far smaller than the 18% average of large state-owned banks. This shows that joint-stock banks are weak in green loans to support the development of green industries. At the same time, joint-stock banks rarely issue green bonds, and the average size of green bond underwriting is only about 1/10 of large state-owned banks, which also shows that joint-stock banks are weak in green financial products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But there are not no benchmarks among joint-stock banks. Industrial Bank performs well in indicators such as green loan balance, agriculture-related loan balance, manufacturing loan balance, and inclusive small and micro enterprise loan balance, all ranking among joint-stock banks. In Mingsheng ESG Ratings, Industrial Bank also ranks with the four Major banks also received an A grade. At the same time, Industrial Bank&#39;s competitiveness in the field of green finance has also been recognized by most review experts, and its number of votes in the field of green finance tied for first place with Industrial and Commercial Bank of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Industrial Bank’s comprehensive score beat all banks, beating Bank of China with an advantage of 3.32 points, and was rated as the &quot;Green Finance Ranking of the Banking Industry&quot;. Exploring flowers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;City commercial banks: better incremental indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Received Due to the disadvantages of scale and volume, city commercial banks are generally inferior to state-owned banks and joint-stock banks in the green finance rankings, but they generally perform better in growth indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the overall score, Bank of Nanjing, which performed best, ranked 8th. Despite obvious disadvantages in terms of size and scale, Bank of Nanjing not only ranks first among city commercial banks in comprehensive scores by virtue of its share of indicators in terms of green loan balance, agriculture-related loan balance, and inclusive small and micro loan balance. The score even exceeds that of major state-owned banks and leading joint-stock banks that far exceed its own scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Serving the real economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;State-owned banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;do their best&lt; /strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, state-owned banks are members of the first echelon of social responsibilities, and the second and third echelons are joint-stock banks and city banks. commercial Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When examining the services of commercial banks to the real economy, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to measure the services of commercial banks to manufacturing loans and inclusive small and micro enterprise loans. Economic performance; when examining commercial banks’ support for rural revitalization, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to measure rural revitalization by agricultural-related loans. At these two levels, state-owned banks performed relatively well in terms of loan balance, growth rate and proportion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joint-stock banks perform well in pension finance and employee human capital development. Relatively speaking, city commercial banks still do not disclose comprehensive information on employee human capital development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;ESG governance shows obvious echelon characteristics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking at it as a whole, The ESG governance dimension of commercial banks shows relatively obvious echelon characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;State-owned banks have strong ESG governance performance. Most joint-stock banks have set up relevant institutions and performance appraisal systems, but the overall ESG governance performance level is weaker than that of state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;City commercial banks are weak in ESG organizational construction, which is partly reflected in the fact that they have not set up independent departments or offices to manage matters such as green finance, environmental contribution and social responsibility, and The ESG performance rating is &quot;BBB&quot; or &quot;BB&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life Insurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Indicator System&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Fourteen&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Sub&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For commercially operated financial institutions , economic performance is business results and the basis for sustainable development, but the green finance list also considers the effectiveness of E (environmental performance), S (social performance), and G (corporate governance). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the above concept, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center used public information such as financial reports, announcements and promotional releases disclosed by 9 life insurance companies from 2022 to October 2023. As a benchmark, nine life insurance companies were evaluated quantitatively and qualitatively from the four dimensions of economic performance, environmental performance, social performance and corporate governance, and fourteen sub-indicators were set, and different weights were given to each sub-indicator according to the difference in importance. The total weight of the above indicators accounts for 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center comprehensively rated nine life insurance companies from the two dimensions of expert review and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) , to build a green finance list for the insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List Life Insurance List Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /29/086e8a479b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2086&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/086e8a479b.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Life Insurance List Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance ranking index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the economic performance dimension, based on the scale of green investment , operating profit is measured by two third-level indicators. Green investment refers to investing in green industries or conducting green business activities, such as purchasing green bonds, green index funds, etc.; operating profit is used to measure a company&#39;s operating performance. In theory, it should be measured by green investment business income generation indicators. Taking into account actual information disclosure, operating profit replace. The total weight of the above two indicators is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the environmental performance dimension, total greenhouse gas emissions and per capita values ​​are core indicators, echoing the &quot;3060&quot; dual carbon goals. Taking into account the service industry characteristics of the financial industry, natural resources and energy consumption are measured in terms of electricity, water, gas and oil consumption. The total weight of the above five indicators is 25%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The social performance dimension mainly sets three three-level indicators from the three perspectives of consumers, employees and communities: consumer complaint volume, employee turnover rate and charity investment measure. The total weight of the above indicators is 15%. Stakeholders such as governments and partners are not included because the information disclosure standards of each ESG report are different and comparability is poor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corporate governance dimension, set the number of core issues, MSCI rating, scope&lt;strong>;three&lt;/strong>; data disclosure, ESG reporting third party There are 4 third-level indicators of certification status. The total weight of the above four indicators is 20%. Among them, carbon emission scope three data is an important part of carbon emission accounting at the organizational level, including greenhouse gas emissions from upstream and downstream (value chain) activities related to corporate production. For service industries such as finance, business travel and employee commuting are the main components of Scope 3. However, due to greater accounting difficulties in this part, fewer life insurance companies proactively disclose it. In addition, although the insurance industry has paid more attention to ESG reporting, most ESG reports have not obtained third-party certification, so their objectivity and independence are questionable. Based on the above reasons and from the perspective of encouraging standardized information disclosure, corporate governance dimension indicators are set in a qualitative manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance list: Ping An Life takes the lead&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Life insurance According to the green finance list of industrial financial institutions, Ping An Life, PICC Life and Sunshine Life ranked among the top three in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of quantitative and qualitative indicators, Ping An Life, PICC Life and AIA Life are leading, but PICC Life and AIA Life failed to provide any supplementary information in time during the survey. , so the media factor score is 0, which drags down the total score and ranking. It is worth noting that because Taikang Life is not listed and has not disclosed an ESG report or social responsibility report, its quantitative and qualitative indicators rank at the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List - Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29 /81322a3209.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1203&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/81322a3209.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259953&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;China Life ranks first in economic performance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, and &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Sunshine Life has the highest social performance score&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to find advantages and differences and set a benchmark for the insurance industry, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center focused on analyzing the green financial measures taken by the top three life insurance companies in each dimension, with a view to It provides a useful reference for enterprises to achieve green transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of economic performance, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and Ping An Life ranked among the top three. China Life&#39;s total assets rank first in the domestic life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of environmental performance, Xinhua Life has the highest score, followed by Ping An Life and Sunshine Life in second and third place respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of social performance, Sunshine Life has the highest score, followed by PICC Life, and Xinhua Life in third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of corporate governance, AIA Life ranks first, Ping An Life ranks second, and PICC Life ranks third. In terms of ESG organizational structure, compared with other insurance companies, AIA has established multiple functional departments to manage ESG-related matters, and established a relatively complete ESG architecture system from top to bottom to promote the implementation of corporate ESG policies. In terms of ESG performance evaluation, AIA has incorporated environment, society and governance into the salary system of senior managers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life Insurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Company&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;ESG&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The quality of information disclosure needs to be improved&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As problems such as &quot;greenwashing&quot; and &quot;greenwashing&quot; emerge, various stakeholders not only pay attention to the quality of corporate environmental information disclosure, but also pay increasing attention to The authenticity and reliability of environmental data, and hiring qualified, independent third-party assurance has become a key measure for measurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A survey by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found that among the nine life insurance companies, only Ping An Life, PICC Life and AIA ESG-related reports received the independent first Three-party authentication. According to the &quot;State of Sustainability Information Disclosure and Assurance: Trends and Analysis 2019-2021&quot; report released by the International Federation of Accountants (IFAC), after surveying 1,350 companies in 21 countries and regions, it was found that 64% of companies Attest the ESG information disclosed in 2021. During the same period, among the surveyed companies in mainland my country and Hong Kong, only 37% and 52% conducted some degree of assurance in 2021. One of the reasons is that my country&#39;s regulatory agencies are still in the encouraging stage for companies to disclose social responsibility reports and issue assurance opinions, and financial institutions do not have many actions and positive trends in reporting assurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, financial institutions also need to improve their quantitative disclosure of Scope 3 carbon emission data. Research by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that among the nine life insurance companies, only Ping An Life, PICC Life, AIA Life and Taiping Life separately disclosed quantitative data in scope three. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 21:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[短视频时代，短剧异军突起：互联网生态“各领风骚三五年”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;Internet short dramas&quot; have become the focus of public opinion, &quot;Hengdian turns into a vertical store&quot; and &quot;Boss short drama harvests&quot; Topics such as &quot;Europe and America&quot; ​​have been on the hot searches in turn. The former refers to the fact that Hengdian Film and Television Base is now dominated by the &quot;vertical screen short drama&quot; shooting team; the latter refers to the short drama application platform ReelShort, which has begun to conquer overseas markets and even topped the U.S. iOS entertainment list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, the &quot;2023-2024 China Micro-Short Drama Market Research Report&quot; released by iiMedia Consulting showed that China&#39;s online short drama market size will be 37.39 billion yuan in 2023, a year-on-year increase of 267.65%. A total of 481 new short dramas were released in the first half of 2023, exceeding the level for the whole of 2022. It is estimated that the size of China&#39;s short drama market will reach 100.68 billion yuan in 2027. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of short videos has not only reshaped the audio-visual habits of netizens, but also accommodated netizens’ search, shopping, entertainment, and social needs: from search engines to short video platforms, from TV series to Switching to short dramas, switching from playing online games to watching short videos, switching from e-commerce shopping to live streaming... &quot;Short Video+&quot; is profoundly affecting the ecology of the Internet industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, various major Internet platforms have derived new business models of &quot;short video + advertising&quot; and &quot;short video + e-commerce&quot;, which have greatly subverted the traditional profit model: ByteDance recently announced the contraction of its gaming business, Short videos are fully embraced; the time spent watching short videos by netizens has exceeded the time spent on online games; traditional online writers are rushing into new tracks; major film and television bases have turned into &quot;vertical screen versions&quot;... These phenomena show that the short video era has created a new era of short videos. The rise of the drama has also profoundly changed the overall ecology of the upstream and downstream industrial chains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 China Online Audiovisual Development Research Report&quot; shows that among the 1 billion short video users in 2022, about 50.4% of users have watched short dramas within 3 minutes. The size of the short drama market in 2023 will almost reach half of the national movie box office, creating many traffic miracles and myths of sudden wealth. For example, in September 2023, the traffic miracle of &quot;Wushuang&quot; exceeded 100 million in revenue in 8 days, which caused a sensation. , the myth of getting rich &quot;completed in one week, released in one month, and achieving financial freedom&quot; is also widely circulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The success of short plays is rooted in human nature, which is a deep need that people cannot erase. Human nature naturally loves &quot;refreshment&quot;, &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;relief&quot;, seeks emotional catharsis, and longs for emotional compensation. While the audience scolded the stereotyped short drama, they still couldn&#39;t help but finish watching a short drama with dozens of episodes before going to bed and experiencing the excitement of &quot;it turns out that success and love can come so quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Short plays can often satisfy people&#39;s certain &quot;feelings&quot; and &quot;hit&quot; the inherent pleasure mechanism of human nature. Themes such as &quot;Grand grudges between wealthy families&quot;, &quot;Marriage first, love later&quot; and &quot;The domineering president fell in love with me&quot; are everlasting. Revenge, counterattack, the boss&#39;s sweet pet, a golden son-in-law, marrying into a wealthy family... Such plots are also repeated many times. Can&#39;t get tired of watching it. The protagonist of the short drama has either become an alternative Count of Monte Cristo, or a film and television version of &quot;Long Aotian&quot; or &quot;Mary Sue&quot;, or it seems to be the product of pressing shortcut keys on a long and drawn-out urban emotional drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slightly different from the previous Internet ecology, the current industry supervision has become more and more synchronized, which is a new situation worthy of attention. The recent news that &quot;Tik Tok, Kuaishou, and WeChat platforms are jointly cracking down on illegal short dramas&quot; is also consistent with the fact that the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television has &quot;already removed 25,000 short dramas from the shelves. The next step will be to launch a one-month special rectification work on online short dramas.&quot; ” echoed the announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the Internet industry has indeed been &quot;leading the way for three to five years.&quot; Past success may not be maintained for a long time in the face of new trends. The rise of short dramas with the help of short videos fully illustrates this point. At the same time, the &quot;reckless state&quot; of the Internet industry&#39;s barbaric growth and turf racing has passed, and the advancement of technology and industry and the follow-up of regulatory regulations are increasingly showing a &quot;same frequency&quot; state. In compliance with regulatory requirements, the pursuit of high-quality and high-quality content will still be the main focus of the short drama market in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[七百岁村庙的“一生”：东南最早元代建筑被发现]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261520]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/29/9cbb99999f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 29/9cbb99999f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Overlooking Fook Sin Hall. Photographed by “Anonymous”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since I first saw Fook Sin Tong in 2017, I have never forgotten it. &quot;No name for now&quot; is his online name, and acquaintances call him &quot;No name for now.&quot; Even if the discovery of a Yuan Dynasty wooden building in the south was enough for him to leave his name in the history of architecture, he decided not to leave his name for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Walk around the mountains and rivers of Fujian for a while, just like visiting old friends, to look for the historical buildings hidden deep in the ancient villages and scattered along the ancient roads. His &quot;discovery&quot; of Fu Shan Tang was accidental, or it might be inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fushan Hall is located in Zhengwei Village, Dikou Town, Jianou City, Fujian Province. It is a group of vernacular temple buildings, which conforms to the usual orientation rules of Chinese architecture: &quot;sitting Different from &quot;north to south&quot;, Fushan Hall conforms to the mountainous terrain of Zhengwei Village and faces south as a whole. The main hall is dedicated to the Three Treasures, and the left and right side halls are dedicated to Guanyin and King Dongping. It is a blend of Buddhism, Taoism and folk beliefs that are common in village temples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main hall faces a Qing Dynasty stage across the courtyard, and is integrated with the main hall through the corridor. Before the main hall was confirmed as a Yuan structure, the stage was the narrative center of the entire building complex. When people in the village talked about Fu Shan Tang, they would always talk about the story of the stage, but they were completely unaware of the main hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;discovery&quot; of Fu Shan Tang was not to find the existence of this building, but to confirm its identity as being built in the Yuan Dynasty. This time is July 18, 2023. That day, Liu Yan witnessed a &quot;highlight moment&quot; that has yet to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yanhe has traveled almost all over the landscapes of southern Zhejiang and northern Fujian for more than ten years. He studies woven wooden arcade bridges. An amazing bridge structure unique to the Fujian and Zhejiang mountains. The same interests led him to meet each other very early on, and they have been online friends for seven or eight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhengweicun not only has Fushan Hall, but also has two covered bridges from the Qing Dynasty. In July 2023, Liu Yan took graduate students to survey and map in Zhengweicun Covered Bridge, I didn’t hear that they were in Fujian yet, so I drove here from Fuzhou, holding a newly purchased infrared camera in my hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hundreds of years of burning paper and smoke, the beams of the main hall of Fu Shan Tang have been smoked black by the incense of believers. The inscriptions written by the ancients on the beams It is impossible to find it and can only be roughly dated based on its style. Using an infrared camera, it is possible to see traces of writing beneath the smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5e9396e852.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1272&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5e9396e852.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, instead of standing on the ladder, use an extended pole to connect the shooting instrument to observe the details of the components on the beams of Fushan Hall. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Huazhen&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to preliminary observations, the main structure of Fushantang Hall is relatively complete, with shuttle columns, column foundations, humps, and replacement wood etc. The obvious early features, such as the planar column network and frame beams, are quite similar to the main hall of Shunchang Baoshan Temple built in the 23rd year of Yuan Zhizheng (1363) with a stone imitation wood structure. Through rough dating of style, it is not possible to judge that the structure of Fushan Hall is no later than the early Ming Dynasty, and may even be in the Yuan Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On that day, Liu Yan was not taken into Fushan Hall for the time being. While Liu Yan was still looking at the entire courtyard with unfamiliar eyes, he had already gone straight to the point and raised his infrared camera to identify the ink characters on Zhengliang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At first, Liu Yan didn&#39;t know what he saw through the infrared camera, because his expression didn&#39;t change much. He just raised his head to take a picture, and then lowered his head to confirm... Suddenly, he stopped getting excited. He held his breath, got excited, calmed down again, quickly checked on his mobile phone, and cautiously confirmed again. He no longer suppressed the ecstasy in his heart: &quot;Yuan Dynasty! The greatest!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The inscription on the main beam shown in the infrared camera clearly reads: &quot;On the ninth day of the eighth month of Wushen, the first year of Wei Zhi&#39;s reign, Yiwei came to Fucheng... Congratulations for the reconstruction of the city...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 25, 2023, the UNESCO Representative Office in China and relevant government agencies of Fujian Province and Quanzhou City hosted the &quot;East Asian Wood Structure Building Protection and &quot;Utilizing International Academic Exchange Conference&quot;, at which Lou Jianlong, deputy director of Fujian Museum, gave a speech entitled &quot;Early Architecture and Characteristics of Fujian&quot;. During his speech, Lou Jianlong mentioned Fu Shan Tang. This may be the first time that Fu Shan Tang has been officially recognized as a newly discovered Yuan Dynasty building and mentioned at an international conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The existing main structure of Fushan Hall was founded in the first year of the Great Rebellion, that is, 1307. Before it, the earliest known Yuan Dynasty wooden structure in southeastern China was the Yanfu Temple in Wuyi, Zhejiang, built in 1317, the fourth year of Yanyou in the Yuan Dynasty. The newly confirmed Fushan Hall in Zhengwei Village has now become the earliest Yuan structure in the southeast. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cheng - the &quot;hedge&quot; of two time differences&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhengwei Village, where Fushan Hall is located, is located among the mountains in northern Fujian middle. The ancestor of the Zheng family who came to the village was Zheng Hao from the Song Dynasty. Zheng Fawang, secretary of the village branch, took out a photocopy of the &quot;Genealogy of the Zheng Family&quot; compiled during the Wanli Period of the Ming Dynasty, which recorded the story of the Zheng family&#39;s entry into Fujian and their reproduction in Jianzhou. The first ancestor of this Zheng family to migrate to Fujian was Zheng Shu during the Five Dynasties period. By Zheng Hao, it was already the eighth generation. According to the genealogy, Zheng Hao decided to move here after taking a fancy to the Feng Shui of Zhengwei Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Walking around the village, even a person who doesn&#39;t understand Feng Shui can easily see that the terrain of this village is indeed a bit special. Surrounded by two mountains like an armchair, the village &quot;sits&quot; safely in the mountain col between the two armrests. The opening of the armchair faces north, and a small stream flows through the entrance of the village, blocking the village in the mountain col. Fu Shan Tang is located in the west of the village - at the foot of the west armrest of the &quot;armchair&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fdd66b33c4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fdd66b33c4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Looking northeast from Fushan Hall, Zhengwei Village has a panoramic view. Under the setting sun, the rammed earth walls of folk houses in northern Fujian turn golden. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Huazhen&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although the old people in the village do not understand architecture, they have passed down from generation to generation that Fushan Hall was built by a man named Zhang Fushan in the Song Dynasty. Before Zheng came to the village, the main families in the village were Zhang and Wei. I don’t think this legend is likely to be an attachment, but Fushan Hall was probably built in the Song Dynasty, because the inscription mentions “reconstruction”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2021, Zhou Miao first met Foshantang. He stayed in it for a long time, &quot;really beyond imagination&quot;, and he recalled the feelings of the southern weekend. He is a young teacher of the Department of Architecture of Zhejiang University City College. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the &quot;History of Chinese Architecture&quot;, Liang Sicheng described the three periods of ancient buildings in China from the perspective of artistic style history. &quot;&quot; In the early Ming Dynasty, the Song and Yuan dynasties became &quot;alcohol&quot;, while the Ming and Qing dynasties were &quot;straight&quot;. Zhou Miao&#39;s research focused on the transformation of the architecture of the Tang and Song dynasties. As soon as he saw Fu Shantang, his professional intuition told him that the combination of those pillars, beams, and buckets had &quot;Songfeng&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In this era, a meta structure can be found in the wet south. For any architect, it is impossible to find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The ancient construction areas are known as &quot;seeing Shanxi in the north and Fujian&quot;. More than other provinces. But Fujian is more unique than Shanxi. &quot;The overall evolution of the building has remained relatively synchronized with the Central Plains and the capital of the past. The development of the building is lagging. Seeing a style of the Song Dynasty there may be late to the beginning of the Ming Dynasty. &quot;So when we see a style of ancient houses in Fujian, we dare not make a judgment.&quot; Zhou Miao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, Jianqi, located in the upper reaches of the Minjiang River, is the first area developed by Fujian to be developed by the Han immigrants in Fujian. In 206 AD, Sun Wu regime established the first county -level political district Jian&#39;an County in the history of Fujian. Until the Song Dynasty, Jianzhou, centered on Jian&#39;er, was the cultural center of Fujian. At that time, the built -in book was popular, and Zhu Zixue was also bred here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhou Miao later realized that although the northern Fujian mountainous area was developed late, the narrow river valleys in the Fujian River were not too late. Specific to the style of the building, the Jian&#39;ou area may also have a &quot;time difference&quot; with other Fujian regions. This time difference, the time difference between northern Fujian and Central Plains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Strange power&quot;, Liu Yan pointed at the complicated and strange cat beams and Dou hugs on Fu Shantang Liangyu. With this intuition, he also boldly speculated that Fushan Hall was a Yuan Dynasty building. &quot;It feels early than Ming, but it is unlikely to go to Song. Because Song He Ming tends to be orthodox and regular. Strange and weird approach. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/a94ef1b375.jpg &quot;border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;810&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/a94ef1b375.jpg&quot; data- &quot;259940&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; The beams of Fushantang are carved with complicated and strange cat beams and buckets. Photo by reporter Wang Huazhen, a southern weekend &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the time being, I will not write my discovery as a public account article. He felt that he had completed his historical task. &quot;Liu Yan said. In October 2023, Liu Yan ended the surveying and mapping task of the gallery bridge. Before returning to the work unit Kunming University of Technology, he decided to go to Fushan Hall to perform the first surveying and mapping. &quot;Do you want to come? You may come, we may be able to persuade him to be interviewed.&quot; He asked the southern weekend reporter. At the end of October, the reporter from the Southern Weekend saw that Fushantang and its discoverers were not for the time being, and also watching Liu Yan&#39;s team&#39;s short -term survey of Fu Shantang. Impressive is not only the architecture itself, but also these people who are bond due to Fushan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Living-the &quot;growth&quot; in the eyes of architecture and archeology &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; witness the discovery of Fu Shantang with your own eyes, so that Liu Yan feels that there is a kind of fate. The fate is inside. He is writing a series of studies in the building of &quot;Sitting in the South&quot;, which fascinates him with a conventional &quot;conflict&quot; building system. Fu Shantang happened to appear at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan&#39;s doctorate in Germany is &quot;Archeology&quot;, and &quot;fine surveying and mapping&quot; is the core tool in this field. For a large building, complete architectural archeology may be as long as for several years or even decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In Germany Liu Yanqiu, fine surveying and mapping are a &quot;basic disk&quot; for cultural protection work. &quot;Germany&#39;s Wenbao has no level. As long as it is Wenbao, you have to do such a complete, in -depth details of surveying and mapping.&quot; Liu Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A scholar of architecture and archeology may not be able to do several fine surveying and mapping cases in life. Liu Yan&#39;s German mentor spent 30 years of energy on a church. For domestic, &quot;This set of things is too luxurious and can be deeply surveying and mapping into the depth of architecture and archeology. There are only a handful of cases in the country. It is enough to match the surveying and mapping of her identity. &quot;Liu Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Archeology is a discipline in China. Liu Yan vividly described archeology as layers of layers and dug down, &quot;and their strata are spread horizontally&quot;, and architectural archeology discusses the historical layers of overlapping in the ground building. For example, a Song Dynasty architecture was changed in the Ming Dynasty. A certain component and a corridor in the Qing Dynasty ... Like archeology, it is also a layer of &quot;strata&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6c5fd28f5c.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 719 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6c5fd28f5c.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259941 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Inside the Hall of Fushan Hall. Figures/&quot;No name for the time being&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhou Miao described Fushantang as a &quot;growth&quot; building: &quot;Obviously, it is expanded and The rebuilt. &quot;At the scene, the reporter from the south weekend explained this growth in detail: there is a title of Daming Hongzhi Nian under the front of the main hall. There is a title of Qing Kangxi under the porch. The stage shows the late Qing Dynasty style. The main hall itself contains different components and structures of Yuan, Ming, and Qing, let alone the &quot;strata&quot; of the rich &quot;strata&quot; of the entire building complex. &quot;The era of&quot; Yuan to Qing &quot;to describe the age of Fushantang is more accurate, and it is closer to the essence of architectural heritage.&quot; I don&#39;t think it is for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan said that architectural archeology is &quot;architectural detective&quot;. By collectively collected the clues on the scene, architects found the slight changes in the buildings in the river of time, thereby pushing the changes of society and personnel. What he wanted to do to Foshantang was such a thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The early construction of the institute did, it was architectural archeology, but at that time, the focus of scholars still wanted to find the earliest building and find Tang Guo. Looking for Song Gou, I can&#39;t wait to strip all the historical coverage of the Ming and Qing Dynasties. &quot;Liu Yan said. The Hall of Hualin Temple in Fuzhou is such a classic representative. = &quot;Text-Align: Left;&quot;>; Today&#39;s Archeology is different from the pursuit of early scholars. One must pursue more detailed surveying and mapping, and the other pays more attention to one building &quot;life story&quot; -n building complete complete building complete The narrative of life not only focuses on its youthful youthful posture of &quot;first construction&quot; or &quot;original&quot;, but also understands its changes in the past and the state of life until the late twilight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; To understand the &quot;growth&quot; of Fu Shantang, not only must you start with the building itself, but the historical environment where the building is located is also a key factor. Before passing the highway, entering and leaving Zhengwei Village can only pass the ancient post road across the mountains. The ancient post road is connected to the gallery bridge. There is a gallery bridge in the village. There is a gallery bridge at the end of the village. The only channel of the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The ancient post road is paved from wide stone slabs. &quot;The ancient road is so wide that the village itself has financial resources in ancient times.&quot; Liu Yan speculated. There are two gallery bridges next to the village. &quot;Those who have the power to build a gallery must be the position of this village on an important channel. It may be an important business road in ancient times. Such a large gallery. &quot;Zhou Miao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; What surprises Zhou Miao is the Ming dynasty in Zhengwei Village. There may be more than five or six dwellings in the Ming Dynasty, and there are many exquisite Qing dwellings, which shows that this village has been prosperous very early. Its population reproduction and wealth gathering must far exceed other villages in the surrounding surrounding. &quot; In the Yuan Dynasty, a large -scale reconstruction was carried out, and there was the possibility of continuous growth in the Ming and Qing dynasties. : //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/bf8914da2f.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1188 &quot;data-src =&quot;//images.infzmmmmmm .com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/29/BF8914DA2F.JPG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 259942 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; blessing There is a stone monument on the edge of the entrance of Shanntang. The &quot;Yicang Monument&quot; of Qianlong&#39;s fifty years was engraved with a positive discipline and a name on the back. According to this monument, it can be seen that not far from Zheng Wei Village has the original Mingjiao temple. After the deserted deserted, the villagers recycled the land production and set up a righteous warehouse in Fushan Hall. Photo by reporter Wang Huazhen, a southern weekend &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The main industry of Zheng Weicun is wood. The ancient trees around the mountains are the greatest wealth in the village. In ancient times, after the villagers cut the trees, they put the wood into the river and flowed along the water to Fuzhou. Until the reform and opening up, the village has always been an important part of the wood industry chain in northeast Fujian. &quot;There is still our land in Fuzhou, and we were wealthy at that time.&quot; Zheng Fangwang said that his ancestors were also engaged in wood business. His ancestral house was built in the late Qing Dynasty. The house of the deep courtyard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Zheng clan controlled the surrounding large mountains by combining the clan power with the industry. In ancient times, Zheng Weicun&#39;s &quot;sphere of power &#39;.&quot; Zheng Jinlan, staff member of Dikou Town Cultural Station. Her hometown is a village not far from Zheng Weicun. The surname of Zheng, the surname of her family, was breeded from Zheng Weicun. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Bad-as long as someone&#39;s activity, the building will be changed &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Walk in the alley in the village, once the tall ancient residences on both sides are Many, only the broken wall remnants. Shortly after Bai Lu&#39;s solar terms passed, the village notice board was posted with a red paper notice of &quot;Bai Lu Celebrating the Tomb&quot;, which reads &quot;Gui Yinnian and the Eighth Five -Year Cemetery&quot; -the eight -fifth public is Zheng Hao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unlike the general Qingming grave sweeping, Zheng Weicun&#39;s sacrifice scanning the ancestors is arranged in the annual Bailu. This custom has been said to have continued for hundreds of years. According to the villagers&#39; lectures, when the white dew, the water came out of the stone, and the water in the stream was also convenient, so it was set to go to the grave at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Fu Shantang plays the role of faith center in the community of Zhengwei Village as the center. At the age of 60, the woman in the village will go to Fushan Hall and hold a grand ceremony. Wearing special green clothing and bright red flowers, &quot;like elementary school students go to school to register at school.&quot; People call them Tsing Yi Zhai. The daily chanting venues of Tsing Yi Zhai are Fushan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/e2df5f17.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/e2df5f17.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259943 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Tsing Yi Zhai Po has a close connection. General cleaning. The picture shows they were in Fushan Hall in 2023. Photo by reporter Wang Huazhen of the Southern Weekend &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the days when I interviewed Zheng Weicun, I met Tsing Yi Zhai in Foshan Hall every day. Fun, bask in the sun, laugh and laugh, and cover the scriptures. Obviously, the religious space has become a public space. During the days when they read the scriptures, they temporarily left their families and spent a period of time with their sisters without trouble. Fu Shantang is the small asylum of Tsing Yi Zhai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; February 19th Guanyin, the birthday of the eighth day of April, November 17th Amitabha&#39;s birthday ... On these grand days, Qingyi Zhai They will do things in Foshantang. And the most lively day of Fushan Hall in the year is to count the 13th to the fifteenth month of the first month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At the twelfth month of the first month, the people in Zheng Weicun drove more than 80 kilometers to go to Linshui Palace next door. Tour in the village. The name of Lin Shui Niang is Chen Jinggu. She is a popular folk belief in the mountainous area of ​​northern Fujian, southern Zhejiang. There is Lin Mo Niang on the seaside, Chen Jinggu in the mountains, and Gutian Linshui Palace is her ancestral temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At 4 or five in the morning of the first month of the first month, please return from the Temple of the Gutianzu Temple, the truck is carried by the idol, a team of cars follows, and the mighty is mighty. Open back to Zheng Weicun. In the first month of 2023, Zheng Fangwang followed the team to Gutian. The high speed of more than an hour was a difficult mountain road in ancient times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Please go back to Linshui Niangniang, walk across the village entrance, and calm the village entrance in a small temple in the village. The architectural history of this temple has also been more than 200 years. The temple&#39;s beam reads the inscriptions during the Jiaqing period of the Qing Dynasty. In the afternoon of the day, the villagers carried the idols and swim in the whole village. Finally, it went to the Fushan Hall on the left of the village. In the face of the Fushan Hall, everyone put the idol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Fourteen and fifteen days is a lively scene of the drama. The show is for God, of course, the mountain people in Shili and Eight Township can also look at it. The troupe in the village performed hard, the villagers asked God to bless, the firecrackers red candles reflected the sky, and the god of swimming in the first month reached a climax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Few villages in the mountains have their own troupes. Zheng Weicun&#39;s Zhenglong Drama Troupe has more than two hundred years of history. On the wall of the wooden board in the backstage of the theater, there is a title of the seven -year play troupe of Guangxu. If Zheng Fangwang&#39;s grandfather is still alive, he is more than a hundred years old. Zheng Fangwang remembers that his grandfather had been in the troupe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/8d36a45.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1228 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/8d36a45.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259944 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The Qing Dynasty theater opposite the Fushan Hall, the fourteenth and fifteenth day of each year, Zhenglong&#39;s drama team entered the gods here. Photo by reporter Wang Huazhen of the Southern Weekend &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zheng Weicun&#39;s theater group is well-known in the neighboring area. Nanya town next to last month has just invited them to perform. Nowadays, there are more than 20 or 30 people in the theater. The actors and musicians are the uncle and aunt in the village. &quot;Now no young people have joined, there is no fixed income.&quot; Zheng Fangwang told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhou Miao studied ancient buildings in Shanxi in the early years. He found that many temples in Shanxi, especially the older and early, have been controlled by the cultural relics department, and the incense has gradually been cut off. The relationship between local residents and it is getting more and more alienated. &quot;The building and the life of people here are still closely related. The traditional sacrifice ritual, space, and belief habits can still be bound to this settlement and this building.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align : LEFT; &quot;>; In 1951, Zheng Weicun Elementary School was founded in Fushan Hall with dozens of students. In 1960, Fu Shantang was opened as a public canteen. Unlike the Shanxi Village Temple, the policy relaxed after the reform and opening up, and Fushan Hall soon became the center of Zhengwei Village&#39;s belief activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, faith activities and ancient construction protection seem to be a difficult contradiction. After the discovery of the Fushan Hall, the leaders of the Provincial Bureau of Cultural Relics have repeatedly instructed Zheng Fangwang Fushan Hall. Zhou Miao remembered that in the 30th year of 2019, a burst of fire in the ancient gallery bridge of Jian&#39;ou City, &quot;because there are too many people burning incense on the bridge that day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As long as there are people&#39;s activities, the building will be changed. Sometimes this change is slow, growing slowly like Fu Shantang, and human activities are gently scrued like waves. But some fierce changes have been common in recent years. In early November 2023, it was not found that the Village, Gutian County, Fujian, was built in the 12th year of Ming Hongzhi (1499) in the 12th year of Ming Hongzhi (1499). &quot;Donkey is not a monster.&quot; Villagers have money and want to rebuild the ancestral temple. It is common for the ancestral ancestral temple, but I don&#39;t think this is a non -matching level of cultural and economic level. Until before being demolished by the villagers, it was neither cultural relic nor a historic building, and there was no protection identity at all. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;span>; empty-what to leave &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Before the founding of New China, Zheng Weicun was armed by his own forces village. At the most, there are more than a hundred guns in the village, like a small army. Until now, the streets in the village are still posted on the slogan of &quot;hiding guns and not allowing the law&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/1b56481471.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1192 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/1b56481471.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259945 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In October 2023, the slogan posted on the streets of Zhengwei Village. Southern Weekend reporter Wang Huazhen Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zheng Fangwang and the elderly in the village cannot say the reason for this, and various documents and materials have not clearly recorded why there is such a mountain village. Large -scale armed. Many people speculated that at that time, Zheng Weicun controlled the nearby mountains, and Zheng was the local family. In the troubled times, the clan was self -defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the spring of 1936, the Communist Party of China established the Town of Jianqiakou as the center, including Jian&#39;er, Songxi, Zhenghe, Gutian, northeast Fujian, northeast Fujian. Guerrilla base. The villagers were quickly combined with the northeast Fujian guerrillas to become a reliable backup of guerrillas. As the villagers of Zhengwei Village are very familiar with firearms, the Zheng&#39;s Ancestral Hall in the center of the village naturally became the guerrilla firearm repair plant. Today, the pentagram above the main entrance of the shrine was the sign of the firearm repair plant in Northeast Fujian guerrillas at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/16c28ba.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1360 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/16fb3c28ba.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259946 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Zheng Weicun&#39;s Zheng&#39;s ancestral temple. Southern Weekend reporter Wang Huazhen Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft;&quot;>; Fu Shantang also witnessed this red history. On May 13, 1948, Zeng Jingbing, Secretary of the Provincial Party Committee of the Chinese and Zhejiang and Jiangxi Provincial Party Committee of the Communist Party of China, and more than 200 guerrilla members watched Gan opera with local villagers in Fushantang. Later, Fu Shantang became a general cultural relic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1982年，村民对福善堂大殿局部修缮，据暂不观察，当时的用料粗陋细小，“与原构相去甚远”， It may be that the conditions are too limited. In 2017, Zheng Weicun obtained the protection of the &quot;traditional Chinese village&quot;. The Fushan Hall and Porcelain Porcelain were repaired local. In 1982, the components that did not meet the specifications were replaced, and the roof was also renovated. Now in the temple, the light -colored wood is replaced in 2017, and the difference between the dark and old materials is clearly distinguished. It is this cautious repair that keeps many questions in Foshantang in Mo Shu&#39;s titles in mind. Until six years, you will not carry infrared cameras to visit again ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left; &quot;>; Compared to Yu&#39;s Ancestral Temple, the Fushan Hall is lucky. It enjoys hundreds of years of incense, and because of the special identity of the affiliated architectural drama, it has escaped the changes in the 20th century until a group of people discovered it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/728732b.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/728732b.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259947 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Overlooking from the hill behind Fushantang, the Fushantang building group is covered in the green bamboo. Southern Weekend reporter Wang Huazhen Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the current no statistics, the newly discovered early wooden buildings in Fujian Province have been found in recent years. The removal of Yu&#39;s ancestral temple, as well as Anxi Baofengyan (during the Ming Yongle period), Zhangping Longjian Palace (1482), Youxi Zhuo&#39;s Temple (During the Ming Dynasty), Datian Hongnong Temple (Ming Chenghua to Hongzhi period ), Yongtai Xianpu Realm (1513) ... Most of them have no protection identity. &quot;They have a very accurate and complete sorting of historical buildings.&quot; Liu Yan and Zhou Miao have a lot of contact with local ancient building enthusiasts in Fujian. Compared with official statistics, they sometimes rely on these people material. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;One problem now is that many local governments are actually unwilling to bear this risk, knowing that it is a valuable cultural relic, but it is not willing to report it. The situation exists. &quot;Zheng Jinlan told the reporter from the southern weekend. As long as it is not reported as a cultural relic point, no one needs to be responsible after being damaged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Protecting as many ancient architectural samples as possible is the basis for scholars to conduct systematic research. What is the position of Fu Shantang in the Yuan Dynasty architecture? Zhou Miao, who specializes in the Song and Yuan architecture, is difficult to say, &quot;because there are too few Yuan Dynasty architecture in the south.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Yuan Dynasty buildings in the north are relatively retained, and in specific areas, the number can be analyzed as much as possible. &quot;In the north, it can be a level distinction of architecture in the Yuan Dynasty to comment on what different levels look like.&quot; Zhou Miao said. If Fushan Hall is placed in the northern yuan structure, then it is undoubtedly the level of low -level village Buddhist temples, but its hall is much larger than ordinary villages and temples. &quot;After the Northern Yuan Dynasty The combination of the structure of low -level buildings began to become messy, mixed, or messy and not particular about it. But the regulation and order of Foshantang are still pretty good, which is unexpected. &quot; /p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Hall of Foshan Hall has gone through the storm of history, and now it is facing the empty nest of the countryside. Before the 1950s, there were more than 500 households in the village. Nowadays, there are only less than 800 people left in Zhengwei Village, and the entire administrative village (including 6 natural villages in the surrounding are). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Behind ancient buildings are not only discoverers and researchers, but also users who are closely related to them. After the logging industry disappeared, the village was in fact. The entire village costs about 200,000 yuan a year. The salary of the village committees and the village&#39;s sanitary expenses are sometimes difficult to guarantee. There are no young people in the village. After this generation of Tsing Yi Zhai&#39;s death, the daily maintenance and use of Fushantang is likely to lose activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan is also very interested in the rituals and costumes of Tsing Yi Zhai, as well as the village&#39;s drama class. &quot;This village seems to have a kind of magic, which can retain so many ancient things.&quot; He plans to investigate and surveys and mapping again next year&#39;s winter vacation and summer vacation, and &quot;soak&quot; in the local area for a long time to do the field survey of real architecture anthropology. &quot;It is more interesting to combine people and architecture.&quot; He also understands that if he does not record as soon as possible, the whole cultural system around Fu Shantang will disappear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Jian&#39;er&#39;s &quot;upgrade&quot; movement of Fu Shantang is unfolding. Originally, Fushantang was just a general cultural protection point, and even the county insurance was not. Now it is promoted by &quot;cross -level&quot;. You can do a promotion work. &quot;Zheng Jinlan said. The provincial insurance is prepared for the future of the national security. &quot;The southern wood structure of the Yuan Dynasty will definitely enter the national insurance.&quot; Liu Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Qingyi Zhai&#39;s daily lesson will definitely be affected by the upgrading of cultural relics protection levels. Zheng Fawang intends to prepare a tripod for them outside the temple so that the fragrant candle will no longer enter the hall. After bidding farewell to Qingyi Zhai, Liu Yanhe did not continue to drive north to visit Yunfeng Temple in Mountain Mountain. For the time being, it is a national security building in the west and east. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《再见爱人》：婚姻里谁都没错，日子怎么就没法过]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261541]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 18:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/29/92i6yai3L2S2KIC36TXISOT8B4Meqevr9idfu0kz.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/cms/medias/i MAGE/23/11/29/92i6YAI3L2S2KIC36TXISOT8B4MEQEVR9idfu0kz. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260006 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;&quot; Goodbye lover &quot;producer Liu Le &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaaaaaa ; &quot;(Provided by the interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; Goodbye Lover &quot;achieved the third season, producer Liu Le finally realized the dream when he proposed the plan -with the guests Enter the Civil Affairs Bureau for a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Office of the Civil Affairs Bureau of Aheqi County is less than 200 square meters, and marriage and divorce are completed here. The three pairs of guests who did not know whether they would divorce witnessed several binding to local couples and the discrete of the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Le was once a social journalist and squatted in the Civil Affairs Bureau. After deciding to do &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, she asked the team to squat at the door of the Civil Affairs Bureau. Although it was unsuccessful, the members faced the original shock. They couldn&#39;t say anything at the moment. &quot;I want to make sadness and joy in the same place, and the human feelings are not connected. Have you thought about being separated when you promise? Do you remember the promise at the time when you separate?&quot; Liu Le said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2021, the reality show &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, which is closely associated with &quot;divorce&quot;. In the show, the three guests who had problems in the marriage carried out a 18 -day trip, returning to the beauty of Prime Minister love, analyzing the question of marriage, and finding the answer to feelings. The show presented a trivial life in public, and the excavation of the details of marriage and deep contradictions resonated with the audience. In the fall of 2023, the third quarter of &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; was broadcast. Fu Shier and Lao Liu, Ji Huanbo and Wang Shiqing, Wang Sleeping and Zhang Shuang&#39;s lovers who &quot;looked beautiful&quot; to outsiders broke the illusion, faced their own dilemma, and again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again, again. Discussion on intimate relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The core, producer, and director of this program Liu Le has been a social journalist for four years, and the director of &quot;Happy Camp&quot; in ten years. In the past three years, in addition to the &quot;Goodbye Love&quot; series, her The work also has &quot;Spring Days Scene again&quot; -also related to divorce. She has been paying attention to emotional topics for a long time. She likes to send emotional paragraphs from time to time from time to time many years ago. She went to do &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; and &quot;Separate Separation Separation&quot;. Most of the program copywriting was written by her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; is the general general experience of Liu Le&#39;s more than ten years of experience. Among them, the tactile and sensitivity of traditional journalists, the entertainment and dexterity of variety director, the sharpness and sharp edge of the emotion blogger. As a single woman, she promoted many married people to take a step forward in the exploration of marriage and intimacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the program was broadcast, Liu Le got more concern and support than expected. Some colleagues even wanted to get married after watching it. The guest of the observation room, Hu Yanbin, told her: &quot;If the parting is not so terrible, we have such a deep care and such a good wish for each other, and we have such a decent difference, then I also long for marriage.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot; After the third season of the Lover &quot;, Liu Le accepted our interview, telling the joy, bitterness and human nature of the show related to the show since the three seasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Can&#39;t you divorce if you don&#39;t quarrel? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &quot;Goodbye lover&quot; to the third season, still touching can still be touched What&#39;s yours? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Le: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; This season&#39;s most shocked me is the sense of misunderstanding of Seoul and Lao Liu. Before I came, I told me, can I not quarrel, can I do it? I said who said &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; to quarrel, and if you don&#39;t make noisy. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When we went to the Civil Affairs Bureau, the director asked why he couldn&#39;t survive and what happened? Do you not go home? Was it drinking? Do you hit you? He has a lot of &quot;clinical experiments&quot; experience, and these problems he raised are very gold -content. When we hear other people&#39;s divorce in daily life, we will ask what is the problem. If he said that there was no problem, why would he divorce? Good days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The inertia thinking of many people must be derailed. I have to lie to me, and I can divorce. no. So our main concept this season is painful and grows slowly. I can&#39;t tell what it has. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the first few episodes were broadcast, everyone might feel whether it was moaning without illness, is it to say that she was worried, it was to make a set of words on the show. Like Seoul, the first half and the second half of the broadcast, I have seen some public accounts. At the beginning, I wrote that Fu Shouer must be here to make money, and she would definitely not divorce. After a few episodes, there was a public account, and Fu Shier must have been here to make money, because she had already planned to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How do you know her, this is also the most difficult place to persuade Seoul. Everyone will wonder if she is utilitarian. I told her, if you are willing to face your real dilemma, you will come. This sound will not dissipate. The most important point for persuading her is that she has real emotional demands. The marriage of more than ten years has been rooted in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have known her for several years. When I was still in &quot;Happy Camp&quot;, she came to be my guest. She said that I was particularly envious of your state, a state of falling in love at any time. I said, do you encounter any confusion in marriage? I talked to her. After doing &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, she often sent me some look after the first two seasons. I think what she said actually took her with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Seoul&#39;s defense is very strong. She will protect herself and want to talk about it, but she will not speak very thoroughly. It looks like he is, but there must be a sore in her heart that I want to make everyone happy, and I really want to dig this thing. After the second season, I mentioned to her, there must be a process of persuasion. I told her that if you are determined, everything is not a matter. The problem is the problem, but it can be solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; My judgment is that she will face it sooner or later, not to say that she must come to the show, but she has a lot of knots in her heart, and she can&#39;t solve it through chatting with friends. On the one hand, she wants to seek change, and on the other hand, she is also eager to be understood by more people. She still has a large part of the &quot;old script&quot;. I have been married for more than ten years. Everyone has not made any mistakes. We have done our best. Why is it not good? If so, can we choose to separate? I feel that she and Lao Liu are both trapped. In this case, she couldn&#39;t really reconcile, so that she was willing to spread everything to everyone. Can it be understood? She is so eager to be understood, her pioneer is old, active and passive, and is a very charming contradiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I hope that one day she can accept her true trap and not go closer to another kind of life. This may be easier, but Seoul is a person who is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/l2mmkm7vnufwoevollb9gcugv5gjit.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/l2mmkm7vnufwoevollb9gcu4sfugv5gjit.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; 260011&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In the third season of&quot; Goodbye Lover &quot;, six guests celebrate the 14th anniversary of Fu Shier and Liu Yi&#39;s wedding &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Do not separate easily, nor do it dying &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_ GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; How did the other two pairs of guests find it? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Le: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The other two pairs are all registered by themselves. Wang Shiqing signed up in the second season, but at that time, I talked to her. She didn&#39;t have such a big contradiction like this season. This year, I felt much much. After opening the closed state of last year, entering a dynamics will bring a lot of severe impact. If the relationship itself is very good, this dynamics may make you better. If it is not good, it will be accelerated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王诗晴的工作机会多起来了，明显感觉自己好像更强大了，人脉、社会给予的回馈都变得极其具象，实实在在感觉到好像“我正在高飞&quot;.而想要拉住我的人，他的动作也变得更加明显了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王睡睡在第二季之后报名，当时张婉婷和宋宁峰的很多争吵让她想到自己，她觉得自己也喜欢骂人，也过得不开心，就填了报名表。最早看他俩资料，没有像节目中呈现出来这么多的问题，第一轮接触，很多导演都判断是鸡毛蒜皮，问题过于细碎，日常好像不那么值得去剖析，不那么发人深省，不那么有往下延展的空间等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说会不会鸡毛蒜皮的东西才是真正值得延展的东西？ Could the program team be trapped by the so-called desire to pursue quality?是不是我们在对亲密关系的呈现上，太迷恋那些看不见、摸不着、说不清的东西，而那些看得清、摸得着、抓得住、直接就能判断对错的事儿，都被我们排除在外了？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们就反思，第一季里，朱雅琼说了非常多感受，但最后让人记住的是那一分钟的拥抱。还是落实在具体的事件上。具体的事件可以让人有抓手，可以去反思自己有没有这样的行为，更好地去建立一个对比的坐标体系，所以我们定了他们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人说《再见爱人》就是要靠激烈的争吵来吸引人注意，不是，节目组不希望没完没了吵，那个东西让人绝望、让人窒息。但因为是真人秀，一旦他们开始，我们是不能干涉的。我们不可能上去告诉他们别吵了，你们赶紧给我和好，更不可能去跟他们说你俩现在可以开始吵了，这太荒谬了。我们能做的只有如实记录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;飞行嘉宾加入进来带什么话题、可以去做一个什么新的项目，这些我们可以隐形植入到旅程中，触发他们变化。其他的根本不知道他们会在什么游戏就炸了，哪一句话就让他怒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你看张硕当时给伴郎发微信&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（第一期，王睡睡和张硕因婚闹事件吵架，二人不欢而散。后因为别的事情吵架，此时张硕给伴郎发微信试图缓解与睡睡的矛盾）&lt;/span>;，他那一刻最真实的感觉就是那么做是好的，肯定能够挽回：她因为别的事情生我气了，我马上要做一件事情来弥补这个事儿。但正是因为他做了这些事情，让观众直观地感觉到他的模式就是拆东墙补西墙，而且拆的也不好，补的也不好，整个人非常敷衍。这个敷衍是不是社会常态？ yes.所以引发了最大的共鸣。吵架只能让大家来看热闹，但是能让大家在热闹之后留下的一定是吵架背后的痛感。是能共情的点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得张硕还是代表一种很普遍的现象：我不需要把这个事儿做到100分，我永远在控制我的付出，做到10分就可以了，20分就可以了，在任何地方都躺平，无论对他的工作、社交还是爱情。黄执中说得对，他很吝啬他的精力。现在支付了10分精力，你如果不承认我这10分的价值，我就不开心，这是不是自私？ of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以张硕后面上的“社会的镜子”的热搜，我觉得观众也能非常直观感觉到这样的情感模式对于当代的年轻人来说是多么的无力。为什么这么多人不想恋爱了？大家都说我不用那么满了，如果爱都不深爱了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实张硕有很多优点，我们对他是怒其不争，但是恨不起来。他确确实实是一个心地很善良的小孩，非常会照顾到周围情绪。但是为什么偏偏在亲密关系上是这样的模式？节目里一直在探索，观察室也在讲。 （其中一种原因可能是）人都渴望正反馈，这是一个生理机制。如果我做错了，是希望得到一些建议，而不是被质问是不是错了？没有人喜欢一直被鞭子抽，抽了以后我可能做得更不好，这是一种行为机制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;节目弹幕里很多写“睡睡快跑”，大家都理解不了为什么他俩这样了还要在一起。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得观众是直接看到了一个呈现，会觉得都这样了怎么还不分手呢？但是作为睡睡来讲，这个人是我的初恋，在一起10年了，他曾经对我也是很好的，下决心要分开并不容易，在遇到问题的时候肯定还是先想怎么解决，到底是什么改变了呢？我能不能改变呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人得有希望，这是一个很正面的事情。以前的人大多走另一个极端，无论再怎么苦再怎么累，受多少委屈，我们都要把这个日子过下去，死不离婚。现在新的趋势是：稍微有一点不对，马上拜拜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《再见爱人》一直想要找一个中间的平衡，既不要轻易的分开，也不要作死的拖拉。我们希望拥有，既能离开也能修复的能力，可能这是更健全的爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信对王睡睡来说，她决定来上节目的时候，就是想要再给这段关系一个最后的机会，能好就继续，好不了就分开。在这个过程中她的每一次摇摆、愤怒、心软都是极其真诚的，她在努力去重新认知这个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;节目播出后，张硕的行为引起了很大controversy.他的反馈是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他很痛苦。感觉自我被完全粉碎了，被全方位否定了。播出期间他时不时会来跟我们讨论，基本都是自省，我觉得这一点非常不容易。没有人能够真正迅速地承认自己是一个糟糕的人，这是很残酷的事情，也需要时间，但我们看到张硕一直在努力。他还是一个探索的姿态。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张硕在节目里算是一个挺阳光的人，挺能够自己给自己找乐子。这些舆论无论正确与否，对他的冲击很大。他又痛，又不得不承认有些评论可能说得挺有道理。就像人要消化刀子，一个刀子已经在肉里了，它在割我的瘤子，痛得哇哇叫，又必须忍着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nLyveKvA0eqTxGrsUpslEL6wyPrRU1fvAaZcq6UT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nLyveKvA0eqTxGrsUpslEL6wyPrRU1fvAaZcq6UT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《再见爱人》第三季嘉宾王睡睡（左）和张硕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;女强男弱是外界对这一季比较多的评论，这是你们有意为之吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不是有意为之。通常我们都不是冲着有共性去攒素材，是攒的过程中发现能够拎出这个东西。像第一期标题《看上去很美》，就是我们拎出来的共性。三对都是分开前采，在每个人单独的海量的素材里面，我们拎出了这个点，就是我们的婚姻都是外人看上去很好，但实际上不是这样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于女强男弱，我觉得我们只是提供一种讨论角度，可能大家看完会有这样的总结。其实这三对都不是绝对的女强人，也有弱的地方，所以我们讨论了到底什么叫作强，是经济实力吗？如果只有这一个维度，可以算作三对都是女强男弱。但是话语权呢？渴求被爱的需求呢？在婚姻里的存在感呢？自在度、舒适度呢？谁是情感里的上位者呢？回到这些维度，她们未必是强。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你刚刚说希望这个节目是探寻一个平台，这是节目的初衷吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;做着做着才有了这个方向。我们每次遇到一对伴侣，他来到我们节目，他的表现可能多少都有超出阈值的部分：过于操控，过于没有安全感，过于忍耐等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有超出阈值的部分，我们都希望让大家意识到，这个有点超出了，可以回来，我们努力站到一个更安全的区域。但有的时候，有些问题发生的时候，也希望大家不要觉得这个事儿是多大的事儿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在NPD&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（自恋型人格障碍）&lt;/span>;、煤气灯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（一种心理操纵手段）&lt;/span>;、边缘性人格等名词经常出现，大家在遇到什么事情的时候可能会立刻下定论，那这些词真正的、专业的定义是什么？会不会有矫枉过正的部分？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从第二季以后我也在想这个问题，是不是这个人的行为举止一旦有超出我们日常认知的部分，我们就可以断定他是一个疯子？或者一旦我们给一个人下了一个什么判定，那么是不是接下来他所说的所有话都不可信？我觉得不是的。郭老师&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（郭柯宇）&lt;/span>;在第一季就说过：“人有太多面了。”我特别认同这句话.人就是各式各样的，疯狂的、低沉的、高价值的、低价值的人都有，人本身就是复杂而不完美的动物，但他们索求被爱的心都是真的。爱里人人平等，亲密关系人人平等，这就是为什么《再见爱人》没有去严格区分明星还是素人，我们全部放到一个场域来进行讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我看过一个评论，说《再见爱人》像解鲁班锁，让扣得不够紧的扣得更紧，让濒临散架的平稳落地，而不是暴力拆解或者永不解开，所有摇摇欲坠的鲁班锁，我们都给它找一个最后的结局。我很认同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;当谈亲密关系不再羞耻&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当时怎么会想到做这样一个节目？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从行业来说，离婚赛道是一个空缺，那时各大平台都在摸索离婚IP。已经存在的国内外的离婚IP，有一些问题没有真正被解决。比如诉求是什么？如果你已经离婚了，把你们放到一起旅游，那你有没有诉求？还是说这是一个节目的诉求？是一个观看的诉求？如果人物毫无诉求，呈现出来的东西可能会非常空泛，飘荡不落地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离婚冷静期是我想起这个IP的关键，它可以作为一个诉求。我最早锁定的是已经进入了冷静期的夫妻。只有30天，我们就要去看这个单子拿不拿得了。在婚姻里面可能每一个人都无数次想过要离婚，为什么想？想了以后你付诸了什么行动？去修复，还是忽视？ ……这里面有非常多的人物动向可以被讲述，而因为离婚的动作还没有真正完成，所以我们还有探讨的空间。第三季的嘉宾应该说是最贴合我最早的方案，都还没有离完。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前两季也基于这样的一个构想，我们挑选的人至少在我们判断中没有冷透，冷透了就没有故事可讲。离婚太久的也不行，最好是两三年以内，这两个人还时不时有一些来往，甚至有人提出过复合等等，还有牵绊，还有诉求，还有一些困惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日常生活中，看别人的事儿都很清晰，看自己的事儿总是能拖就拖，说不定又好了。没有一个巨大的事件作支撑，人不太容易在一种相对平缓起伏的情绪中手起刀落。大家意识不到深层次的裂痕，哪有力量来觉察这个，谁会没事拿个x光照自己的情感？很多人要么出于恐惧，要么出于懒惰、逃避。差不多行了，老说这些干嘛，多矫情。尤其男性在关系里面更常见的就是这种，有什么可探讨的？我要出去喝酒。我好多同事，公司好多事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沟通和交流很多时候是两个人的事，不是单方面的选择，假如我跟别人讲，我想跟我的爱人聊一聊我们这八年来的婚姻里的问题，但他不跟我好好聊，所以我要跟他离婚，别人可能说你有病。但是放在《再见爱人》这个场域，再细小的问题都会被重视，大家就会来讨论，那你这个要怎么聊啊，你这个婚该不该离啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《再见爱人》把亲密关系里的很多问题做了一个聚焦，我拿放大镜打了这块地方，大家都说你这个问题好像真的值得重视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这至少是给困在婚姻里的人、想进婚姻的人、想要聊这些又不好意思的人一些抓手，我不再羞愧，我今天想要跟你聊一聊，我们沟通你对我的忽视。我不会觉得这非常突兀，我不会觉得羞耻，这是健康的，这也是一种勇气，也是一种勇敢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么选择的旅行目的地多在景色很美、但相对人迹罕至的地方？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;选这些地方一方面是好看。原始、自然的美景很重要，人想不通的时候都应该去接触一下自然，但是很少有人这么做。而我们选的地方，就是希望可以长久地停留，让他们非常艰苦，又极致地感觉天地之大、人之渺小，是一种直观的心理暗示。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然还是有很强的疗愈作用。我们努力创造一个高纯度的（拍摄）环境，让他们放心进入深水区探讨。这个过程并不容易，美景是一种短暂的安慰，无论如何，他们是非常非常勇敢的一群人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/G88G4ZHWNzmH6EHkOGMANJgGwKJAOQbYgcR9CwpO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/G88G4ZHWNzmH6EHkOGMANJgGwKJAOQbYgcR9CwpO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《再见爱人》第二季&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;歌颂爱情，歌颂浪漫&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你没有婚姻经历，婚姻在日常中的甜蜜和痛苦都非常细碎且实在，你如何在一档离婚节目里把握这些幽微之处？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我必须得理解他为什么这一刻要做这样的事。他为什么有这个感受？为什么做这样的判断？肯定不能百分百共情，但在这个过程中，什么是值得提出的问题？这些可以通过训练培养，就是提问直觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得我没结过婚是好事。我接触过一些同行，听说我要做这个题材，特别想跟我聊，聊下来我觉得每个人都太聚焦自我了，很容易下定论，“婚姻就是什么”，像这样的句式我在那段时间听了非常多，千差万别，唯一的共性就是他们都非常相信自己在婚姻里的判断。这个时候我就清空，我不听任何人的话，我只把你们所有人的话当作一个样本来呈现，样本可以有很多内核让观众自己去总结。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我已经有一段婚姻，我不敢保证自己会不会说这个不存在，因为在我的婚姻里没遇到这种情况，这太荒谬了，给他剪了。没有开放性的思维，是很危险的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爱肯定是千奇百怪有不同样子的。做节目的时候我也会回溯自己过往的关系，意识到我也犯过这样那样的错。这是非常有意思的事，看别人都看得很清晰，说到自己，谁又是一个完美伴侣呢？所以反观自我，我觉得爱是一个长久的功课。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我更期待我的感情观从真实的感情中来，而不是从节目里来。我希望《再见爱人》是辅料，它不应该是主菜，你要去感受具体的人真实的人，而不是一些道理。傅首尔已经非常会讲道理，王睡睡也非常会讲道理，但为什么她们还是过得没有那么开心呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;节目进展到现在，观众也感受到了很多欢笑的部分.但欢笑无法抵消婚姻中实质的痛苦。你认为“笑”的意义是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;痛苦就是痛苦。如果痛苦是往下的话，笑就是往上提溜一下。可能增加一点抵御痛苦的能量，或者让人更清晰地俯视痛苦的全貌。笑着应对痛苦就很艺术，木心说的，人从悲伤之中落落大方走出来，就是艺术家。这个笑就是一种落落大方。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fmMsEze0OeD4DDlhxS62rJ0TiM23umaiU2JTGhDs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;872&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fmMsEze0OeD4DDlhxS62rJ0TiM23umaiU2JTGhDs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《再见爱人》第一季&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;节目的口号“再见容易，再见很难”是怎么想出来的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时觉得年轻人太容易放弃了。我以前也很喜欢劝人家要清醒，但是当越来越多的人都在说要清醒、要放弃，这个没什么大不了的时候，我就觉察到这可能是新的风潮，我们在讨论的时候就说再把这些想要分手的人拉到一块。 “再来聊聊”这个行为本身是否有点老土，是否有点不符合年轻人当下“我永远要去找新的人”这样一个现状？所以我们才说再见是容易还是很难，想到了“再见”和“再见”，英文是“see you”和“see you again”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代人太容易看到别人的瑕疵，没有办法进深水区，永远在浅水区打转，接触再多的人，个把月后全都一样，就很怀念会谈好几年恋爱的时候，那个时候好像人收获的滋养不一样。现在短视频都在教你，“他这样做你就要警惕”、“他不这样说就是不爱你”……这样的拆解非常粗暴。感情中还是有很多不可归因的部分。假如大家都被这些粗暴的逻辑影响，觉得咱们都在水面上玩玩就好了，这是很可惜的一件事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在已经不需要谈恋爱就能够获得很多快乐的时代，还要去谈恋爱，这是一件极度浪漫的事情，我希望我能歌颂（这种爱情和浪漫）。以前的人结婚可能还有很多出于现实的需求，我需要一个人来跟我一起面对生活。但现在是，好像手机解决一切了，就算不谈恋爱不结婚，大家也能活得挺好。在这样的情况下，还要去寻找亲密关系，这是一件多么浪漫的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得人在这种情况下还要寻求亲密关系What is the reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘乐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为它真的很好，如果到过那片山，就明白那儿的风景是很好的，但是爬山的过程是很累的，希望大家不要因为这个累就不去爬了，不要觉得在地面上是最好玩的，地面上是安全的，是轻松的，是自在的，是ok的，但是你没有上去过，就不要说山上的风景我不稀罕。 《再见爱人》给大家展示了崎岖的山路，但大家还是可以去爬自己的山。认真付出的人会收获更多的风景，一定是这样的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东最能生但也最多单身，四川离婚人数遥遥领先，趣说人口数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261460]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[保障性住房，如何让城市居民顺利安家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261407]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:26:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Removal, replacement, and acquisition of existing housing... While ensuring the source of affordable housing, in order to revitalize the existing housing supply, various regions A series of explorations were conducted.</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡静林任国家税务总局党委书记，曾在财政部任职20年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261536]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Newly appointed Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation Hu Jinglin. Image source: Official website of the Ministry of Finance&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b4f256f4bd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b4f256f4bd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260048&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >; Hu Jinglin, the new Party Secretary of the State Administration of Taxation. Picture source: The official website of the Ministry of Finance&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the State Administration of Taxation announced that on the morning of November 28, 2023, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Taxation and announced the central government’s decision: Comrade Hu Jinglin will be appointed as the national Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation, Comrade Wang Jun is removed from his position as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking over as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation, Hu Jinglin was Secretary of the Party Committee and Director of the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Served in the Ministry of Finance for 20 years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin was born in 1964 in Shexian County, Anhui Province. He graduated from Renmin University of China and received a doctorate in economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1992, Hu Jinglin has worked in the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau as deputy director of the Policy, Regulations and Judicial Regulations Division. According to the &quot;Historical Dictionary Series of the Communist Party of China&quot;, in order to straighten out the relationship between state-owned assets and establish and improve the state-owned assets management system in the process of reform and opening up, in November 1988, the state established the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information from the Chinese Government website, in 1994, the State-owned Assets Administration became a national bureau (deputy ministerial level) managed by the Ministry of Finance. Its main task is to comprehensively manage state-owned assets within and outside the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 1998, the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau was officially abolished. In the same year, the Large Enterprise Working Committee of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China was formally established. During this period, the management structure of state-owned enterprises changed several times until the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council was established in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the time of organizational reform in 1998, Hu Jinglin entered the Property Appraisal Department of the Ministry of Finance, and then served as Director of the Economic Construction Department of the Ministry of Finance, Director of the General Office of the Ministry of Finance, and Spokesperson of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the official website of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin has long been engaged in state-owned enterprise reform and macroeconomic theoretical research and practical work. He has rich work experience and profound theoretical foundation. He has participated in a number of major reforms of financial and industrial management systems and He is engaged in research on important macroeconomic policies and has authored (translated) many works such as &quot;State-owned Enterprise Reform and Approaches&quot;, &quot;Financial Asset Assessment&quot;, and &quot;U.S. Federal Government Budget&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Hu Jinglin served as Assistant Minister of Finance and member of the Party Leadership Group. Five years later, he was promoted to deputy minister of finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, when he was promoted to Vice Minister of Finance, Hu Jinglin was in charge of the General Office, Department of Agriculture, National Agricultural Comprehensive Development Office, Bureau of Retired Cadres, Information Network Center, and China Finance and Taxation Museum, assisting then Minister of Finance Lou Jiwei is in charge of the Office of the State Council’s Comprehensive Rural Reform Working Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure at the Ministry of Finance, Hu Jinglin repeatedly emphasized the importance of budget management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Jinglin emphasized at the National Financial, Administrative, Political and Legal Work Conference that as far as the budget is concerned, it is necessary to enhance the legality and binding force of the budget and how to solve the problems of inaccurate budget preparation at the beginning of the year and mid-year budget. To deal with the problems of frequent adjustments and excessive budget balances at the end of the year, &quot;we need to work with departments to establish the concept of &#39;budget is law&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Never let the medical insurance fund become &#39;Tang Monk Meat&#39;&quot;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;After four years as Deputy Minister of Finance, Hu Jinglin was transferred to the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2018, the First Session of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress voted to adopt a decision on the institutional reform plan of the State Council, establishing the National Medical Security Administration of the People&#39;s Republic of China (deputy ministerial level) and becoming an agency directly under the State Council. Hu Jinglin became the first director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The institutional reform plan of the State Council at that time proposed that the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security’s basic medical insurance and maternity insurance responsibilities for urban employees and urban residents, the National Health and Family Planning Commission’s new rural cooperative medical responsibilities, and the national The National Development and Reform Commission&#39;s drug and medical service price management responsibilities and the Ministry of Civil Affairs&#39; medical assistance responsibilities were integrated to form the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, during his tenure, Hu Jinglin actively promoted the solution of problems such as difficulty and high cost of medication for ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, during the National Two Sessions, Hu Jinglin said in an interview at the &quot;Ministerial Channel&quot; that more life-saving and emergency medicines should be included in medical insurance by optimizing the directory structure to further alleviate and alleviate the epidemic. It is difficult for the people to use medicine and it is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the State Council Information Office press conference in May 2023, Hu Jinglin introduced that in the past five years, the National Medical Insurance Administration has accelerated the pace of medical insurance negotiations and promoted a large number of exclusive drugs such as camrelizumab and nosinaxin sodium. A variety of anti-cancer drugs and drugs for rare diseases are included in medical insurance at appropriate prices, and after reimbursement, the cumulative burden on patients has been reduced by more than 500 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the official website of the National Medical Insurance Administration published an article written by Hu Jinglin, stating that the next step is to strengthen the management of medical insurance funds, continue to carry out in-depth special operations against fraudulent insurance, and &quot;look back&quot; on some provinces Conduct random inspections and reviews of work. In addition, give full play to the power of the reporting reward system and establish a reporting clue supervision and feedback mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Make good use of the agreement management system. Medical institutions whose agreements have been terminated shall not be included in the medical insurance designated areas within 3 years. Build a long-term mechanism for fund supervision and &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Never let the medical insurance fund Become the new &#39;Tang Monk Meat&#39;&lt;/span>;.&quot; Hu Jinglin introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the above-mentioned press conference of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin said that medical insurance funds are &quot;life-saving money&quot; for the people. The National Medical Insurance Administration has always regarded strengthening the supervision of medical insurance funds and maintaining fund security as its top priority, and severely cracked down on various forms of fraud. Such illegal use of medical insurance funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past five years, the total annual revenue of the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance) has increased from 2.14 trillion yuan to 3.09 trillion yuan, and the total annual expenditure has increased from 1.78 trillion yuan to 2.46 trillion yuan. The fund is running smoothly and has a balance,&quot; Hu Jinglin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Wang Jun has been the director of the State Administration of Taxation for ten years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Chinese government website shows that Wang Jun, the current director of the State Administration of Taxation, was born in 1958. He graduated from Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun served in the Ministry of Finance from 1987 to 2013. In March 2013, Wang Jun, then deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group and deputy minister of the Ministry of Finance, was promoted to secretary of the Party Leadership Group and director of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2023, Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation, held talks with the Director of the Qatar General Administration of Taxation. Image source: Official website of the State Administration of Taxation&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/29/0d9b6d6ebb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/29/0d9b6d6ebb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260049&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation, and The head of Qatar’s General Tax Authority held talks. Image source: The official website of the State Administration of Taxation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 1993, the State Council issued a document stating that in order to adapt to the national tax work, the organizational specifications of the State Administration of Taxation would be adjusted from the deputy ministerial level to the ministerial level. In January 1994, China began to implement the reform of the fiscal and taxation system with the tax-sharing system as the core, which significantly increased the central fiscal revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the reform of the tax-sharing system, the State Administration of Taxation has successively had five directors, namely Liu Zhongli, Jin Renqing, Xie Xuren, Xiao Jie, and Wang Jun. Among them, Wang Jun has served the longest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All five of them have worked in the Ministry of Finance, and four of them have served as Ministers of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zhongli served as Minister of Finance and concurrently Director of the State Administration of Taxation from 1992 to 1998. Jin Renqing, Xie Xuren, and Xiao Jie all served as Ministers of Finance after serving as Directors of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, Wang Jun has served as the director of the State Administration of Taxation for ten years and is 65 years old. In March 2023, Wang Jun was elected as a member of the Standing Committee of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the resumes of Wang Jun and Hu Jinglin, they have worked together in the Ministry of Finance for more than ten years, and both have served as director of the General Office of the Ministry of Finance, spokesperson, assistant minister, deputy minister, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the ten years since Wang Jun served as director of the State Administration of Taxation, China&#39;s tax system reform has continued to deepen, including a series of actions such as replacing business tax with VAT, individual tax reform, merging state and local taxes, and tax and fee reductions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 2018, the &quot;threshold&quot; for personal income tax will be increased from 3,500 yuan/month to 5,000 yuan/month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five months later, Wang Jun said at the &quot;Ministerial Channel&quot; of the National Two Sessions that the personal income tax reform will bring 100% tax reduction to the working class, and about 80 million of them will no longer have to pay a tax. Taxes will be reduced by more than 70% for about 65 million people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same year, the First Session of the Thirteenth National People&#39;s Congress passed the institutional reform plan of the State Council. The State Council will reform the national and local tax collection and administration systems, merge the national and local tax agencies at the provincial and sub-provincial levels, and specifically bear the responsibilities of various taxation agencies within its jurisdiction. Responsibilities such as tax and non-tax revenue collection and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tax-sharing system reform in 1994 established two sets of tax collection and management systems: national tax and local tax. After 24 years of operation, the state and local taxes were merged and a new tax collection and administration system was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the effects of tax cuts and fee reductions, the 2023 State Council Government Work Report concluded, “In the past five years, a cumulative tax reduction of 5.4 trillion yuan and a fee reduction of 2.8 trillion yuan have been achieved.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[考公考研人数一升一降：替代还是互补，如何读懂两者间的关系？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261528]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 26, 2023, the written test for public subjects of the national examination will begin. The number of applicants for the national examination exceeded 3 million for the first time. A total of 2.613 million candidates confirmed their registration before the examination, and 2.252 million actually took the examination, which is unprecedented. Vertical comparison shows that a total of 1.422 million people actually took the exam last year. From 2020 to 2024, the number of people recruited for the national examination will be approximately 24,100, 25,700, 31,200, 37,100, and 39,600, which is rising steadily, but it is far from meeting everyone&#39;s application needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, this year is the first time in eight years that the number of people taking the postgraduate entrance examination has dropped, which may indicate that the enthusiasm for the postgraduate entrance examination has reached its peak. This shows that it is a high probability event that the public and postgraduate entrance examinations will go their separate ways. Because for most people, the purpose of taking the postgraduate entrance examination is to delay employment and postpone the employment decision for two to three years, in the hope that a graduate degree will give them a certain competitive advantage. However, on the one hand, the employment situation is becoming increasingly difficult. Today’s undergraduate degree vs. For graduate students after two or three years, the latter may not have a significant advantage in finding a job. On the other hand, the opportunity cost of obtaining a graduate degree is getting higher and higher. Changing from a master&#39;s degree to a professional master&#39;s degree means higher tuition expenses. The public examination is different. If you use the time and money to take the postgraduate entrance examination and graduate school, you can take the public examination in multiple places in a year. Until you pass the examination, the probability of &quot;getting on board&quot; will be higher. The two go off and on, and it is obvious that more and more people believe that taking the public examination directly is more cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the relationship between the postgraduate entrance examination and the public examination is complex. In addition to substitution, there is also a complementary relationship. For example, some people still want to take the civil service exam after taking the postgraduate entrance examination. This is because there are more civil servant positions that they can apply for with a postgraduate degree. Educational qualifications become higher and more attractive, and there is also an additional channel for selecting students to enter politics. In short, you can expand your options for public examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the recruitment requirements for national examination positions, the threshold for academic qualifications is constantly rising. This year’s national examination recruitment requirements are all for a college degree or above. As the number of recruits increases year after year, the number of positions that require a college degree as a starting point is decreasing year by year. This year, there are 56 positions that college students can apply for, a decrease of 106 year-on-year. At the same time, the number of positions requiring a master&#39;s degree and the planned number of people have increased significantly. According to statistics from China Youth Daily, there are 2,046 positions requiring a master&#39;s degree or above this year, an increase of 814 year-on-year; there are 24 positions requiring a doctoral degree, an increase of 14 year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to explain this phenomenon? A common view is that the demand for highly educated talents in government agencies has increased. This actually amounts to no explanation. Are these positions really only available to those with a master&#39;s degree or above? Probably not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current employment environment, the attractiveness of jobs within the system has been further enhanced: there is a &quot;establishment&quot;, decent salary, complete benefits, high social status, and stable work. As long as you don&#39;t make big principled mistakes, you will not be unemployed. The danger. Therefore, competition for these positions will continue to intensify. The ratio of the number of people admitted to the national examination to the number of people taking the examination was 1:38 last year and 1:57 this year. The ratio of popular positions is even more exaggerated. When competition intensifies, one of the main criteria for selecting talents will naturally be academic qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For employers within the system, when they are recruiting someone, why not choose someone with a higher academic qualification and a better school? Based on purely objective indicators, this is equivalent to obtaining &quot;better talents&quot; with the same staffing and cost, and neither leaders nor the public can find fault. On the contrary, if you do not recruit people with higher academic qualifications and better schools, but recruit people with average academic qualifications, you will most likely need to explain to the public why it is not a &quot;carrot recruitment&quot; and the people you recruit are the most suitable for the position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this logic and mentality, it is not difficult to understand the following phenomena that are hotly debated by the public: Peking University’s Ph.D. in nuclear physics obtained the urban management establishment, Shanghai Jiao Tong University’s M.D. became a middle school doctor, and Harvard University’s master’s degree applied for education Non-career positions in the Overseas Study Service Center of the Ministry of Education. It is not difficult to understand why the academic qualifications threshold for recruitment within the system continues to increase: last year, we required a bachelor&#39;s degree, but we recruited several master&#39;s degrees from prestigious universities; this year, we simply require all master&#39;s degrees, and people are willing to come and don&#39;t have to spend more money, so why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, this is very different from the recruitment logic of free competition industries. Except for the R&amp;D departments of some leading companies, generally the company&#39;s academic qualifications are only a reference when recruiting people. The key is to see whether personal ability and character match the company&#39;s job requirements. If you have too high academic qualifications, you will have the problem of over-qualification. For the same position, undergraduates may do better than those with master&#39;s or doctorate degrees, because from the perspective of the company, everyone must receive vocational training anyway. Being young is an advantage, the mind is not yet rigid, the person has the courage to try and accept new things, and can get started quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, some undergraduates complained that they could not get offers (invitations) when applying for jobs as undergraduates, but they got many offers by pretending to be high school students. The reason why high school students are required rather than &quot;high-achieving students&quot; is because in the eyes of the company, high school students are enough to complete the job. All they need to do is behave in a disciplined manner, follow the procedures honestly, and listen to instructions. They hope that employees can calm down and maintain stable work. ; If you are looking for undergraduates, they may think that they are overqualified and are just making do for the time being, or they may be riding a donkey looking for a horse, and they are not willing to work without peace of mind. Why bother asking for trouble because of a false reputation? After a while, the &quot;top students&quot; leave, and new people have to be recruited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, after understanding the difference in recruitment logic and mentality between the system and the free competition industry, students can decide whether they need to go to graduate school, whether to take the public examination as an undergraduate to get a job, or to go to graduate school to make themselves available. Wider choices. These are factual judgments, not value judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in the long run, encouraging the best students to engage in innovation, create wealth in free competition industries, and create a good institutional environment and motivation mechanism for them will naturally be a blessing to society and a country. blessing. For some time, the government has introduced many measures to stimulate the development of the private economy. Recently, eight departments have introduced &quot;25 specific measures to support the private economy.&quot; This effort is in the right direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雷军向母校武大捐13亿背后：曾领两千奖学金立志万倍还回来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261522]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 29, Wuhan University celebrated its 130th anniversary. Lei Jun personally donated 1.3 billion yuan to his alma mater. . The official account of Wuhan University stated that this set a new record for the largest single donation since the founding of Wuhan University, and was also the largest individual cash donation from an alumni received by universities across the country. Nandu reporters learned that when he was studying at Wuhan University more than 30 years ago, Lei Jun received a &quot;huge sum&quot; of 2,000 yuan and was determined to pay it back ten thousand times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7fb2543f6dfa9e1e8eee615866c61337.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7fb2543f6dfa9e1e8eee615866c61337.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Donation site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned from Wuhan University that Lei Jun is a 1987 computer science alumnus of Wuhan University and the founder, chairman and CEO of Xiaomi Group. This donation mainly focuses on three directions: supporting research in the six basic disciplines of mathematics, physics, chemistry, literature, history and philosophy, supporting scientific and technological innovation in the computer field, and supporting the training of college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lei Jun recalled that more than 30 years ago, as an outstanding student representative, he was awarded the highest scholarship at Wuhan University at that time, which was a full two thousand yuan, sponsored by a company. He said that for a student from an ordinary county family, this is really a huge sum of money. To this day, he still clearly remembers the excitement and pride he felt at that time. At that time, Lei Jun secretly swore in his heart, &quot;No matter how much scholarship I receive today, I will pay it back ten times, a hundred times, or ten thousand times in the future.&quot; In 1997, six years after graduation, Lei Jun started donating to his alma mater. At that time, his salary Only 4,000 yuan. He began his journey to fulfill his vow and donated money to establish the &quot;Lei Jun Scholarship&quot; (then called the &quot;Tengfei Scholarship&quot;) at the School of Computer Science. He has continued to donate for 26 years now. Lei Jun lamented that today he has finally fulfilled his wish to repay 10,000 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 29th, Lei Jun posted on Weibo to congratulate his alma mater on his birthday: Today is the 130th anniversary of Wuhan University. Happy birthday to my alma mater! He said, &quot;Every time I return to my alma mater, I feel very excited.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打造中国版甲骨文：易鲸捷与贵阳银行的双向冒险]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guiyang Bank Head Office Building. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/cc53458590.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/29/cc53458590.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guiyang Bank Head Office Building. Zhao Jilin/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the seventh floor of the head office building of Bank of Guiyang (601997.SH), there is a place where outsiders are prohibited from entering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The computer room covering an area of ​​more than 80 square meters is filled with large electronic display screens and computer terminals. All business operations and accounting processing related to deposits and loans need to be completed here. Supporting the operation of the entire set of equipment is the new core business transaction system that was just launched on November 6, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of banking core business transaction systems, foreign companies such as Oracle and IBM were once absolute monopolies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2020, an unknown startup company suddenly broke in. Guizhou Yijingjie Information Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Yijingjie), founded in 2015, won the bid for the domestic database application project of Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system with a price of 426 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yijingjie plays two roles, one is the supplier of database products, and the other is the general contractor of the entire project. Its purpose is to create a full-stack core transaction system for domestic banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After its official launch, this high-profile trading system did not win praise. Instead, it pushed Yijingjie to the forefront. For a time, the Internet was flooded with comments such as &quot;fake domestically produced products&quot; and &quot;shelling Oracle&quot;, and Bank of Guiyang and Yi Jingjie became the target of public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It may be very difficult for us to build a (database) nuclear weapon for daily use for the country, but we must take this risk.&quot; Li Jing, chairman of Yi Jingjie, spoke quickly He told a reporter from Southern Weekend, his voice was trembling. She looks very capable, with short hair, tattooed eyebrows, and a red coat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the moment, the &quot;nuclear weapons&quot; Li Jing talks about have not yet been put into production. He Xin, general manager of the Information Technology Department of the Bank of Guiyang, revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the current main database of the Bank of Guiyang is Oracle, and Yi Jingjie is used as a follow-up database, which is exactly the opposite of the original plan. &quot;I invested them all at once. To be honest, the risk will be relatively high.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xuerong, Secretary of the Party Committee and Director of Guiyang Big Data Bureau, further explained to Southern Weekend reporters that due to the influence of negative public opinion on the Internet, superior supervision Out of the principle of prudent supervision, the department does not agree to the online launch of Yijingjie database for the time being. &quot;As long as the regulatory authorities relent, it can be launched in any minute.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Delayed launch&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The biggest doubt from the outside world is whether Yi Wingjie, which started with distributed databases, can build a more technically difficult bank core transaction system database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The databases currently used in the financial industry are still mainly centralized, but distributed is the general trend and has computing advantages under massive data and high concurrency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The branch president of a state-owned commercial bank told Southern Weekend reporters that the difficulty in developing the bank&#39;s core transaction system database lies in the large amount of data that needs to be stored for many years and ensure that the system does not go down. In addition, each bank needs to do some customized development according to the needs of customers. For example, it has to open separate interfaces with the credit reporting system and tax system of the People&#39;s Bank of China, which &quot;has strict requirements for security.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years since Guiyang Bank purchased the Yijingjie database, it has not been able to go online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Wingjie was originally relatively optimistic about the launch time. According to the company&#39;s internal documents, the construction goals are divided into three stages:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of June 2020, achieve an average success rate of 99.999%, and successfully implement the &quot;dual database parallel&quot; plan for Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system in 2021. The main database uses the domestic Yijingjie database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the end of September 2021, the Yijingjie database for typical applications such as banking financial core, graphical front-end, process banking, and credit systems will be transformed and put online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third phase will comprehensively plan and transform the information system of Guiyang Bank, and realize the localization transformation of the full-scenario application system by the end of July 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information can also be seen that the launch time of Yijingjie database has been delayed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2021, the evaluation report of Yijingjie’s shareholder China Software (600536.SH) showed that the core transaction main database purchased by Guiyang Bank is planned to be officially launched in the first half of 2022. Apparently it didn&#39;t happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already two years later, in May 2023, that there was any further news. When accepting a survey from investors, the Bank of Guiyang stated that the Yijingjie domestic database application project has entered the testing phase and is advancing various testing tasks in an orderly manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, another investor asked about the progress of Yijingjie’s domestic database at the Bank of Guiyang’s third quarter performance briefing. Chairman Zhang Zhenghai replied, “The development of the new core business system of Bank of Guiyang has been completed. Testing work, the system has entered the online preparation stage, and the system is expected to be online from 17:00 on November 3, 2023 to 8:00 on November 6.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until November 6, Guiyang Bank issued an announcement stating that &quot;the new system has been successfully launched&quot;, but did not declare what database it adopted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the current status of Yijingjie as a backup follower library, He Xin explained that for relatively mature bank core trading systems, it usually takes 18-24 months from research and development to launch. However, the Guiyang Bank project has many innovations, such as the full-stack core business system and the first application of eCas4.0 in the banking industry, so it takes a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also added that as early as the beginning of 2021, Guiyang Bank signed a contract with Oracle to allow Oracle and Yijingjie to run parallel databases to back up each other, creating a relatively safe structure. The performance of Yijingjie database is acceptable, but the database does not only rely on performance. &quot;If it is actually put online, we would like to test it more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yijingjie is located on the 24th floor of Tower C, No. 1 Gaoke. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/7d85715829.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7d85715829. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yijingjie is located on the 24th floor of Tower C, No. 1, Gaoke. Zhao Jilin/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“No city dares to do this”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the top of Building C, No. 1 Gaoke, Changling South Road, High-tech Zone, Guiyang City, the big words “Big Data National Engineering Laboratory” are very Eye-catching, Yi Wingjie is located on the 24th floor of the building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Yijingjie, Internet companies such as NetEase Haowu and Qilin Software have settled here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of big data in Guizhou Province started in 2012. The development of the big data industry is considered by Guizhou as an excellent opportunity to change lanes and overtake. In 2015, the country established the country&#39;s first comprehensive big data pilot zone in Guizhou. One of its important tasks is to solve the security and independent controllability issues of China&#39;s big data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Yi Jingjie, he has never had access to the core transaction system database of a bank before, so he faces great technical challenges. Similarly, for the Guiyang Municipal Government and Guiyang Bank, betting on Yijingjie is also a risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Guiyang State-owned Assets Representative who participated in the investment in Yijingjie revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that at the end of 2015, Guiyang State-owned Assets learned about Yijingjie and visited Yijingjie’s technical team, launching a long-term Half a year of due diligence, interviews included Tencent Music (NYSE: TME), the three major telecom operators, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before investing in Yijingjie, Yijingjie signed an agreement with Guiyang State-owned Assets, stipulating that Guizhou Yijingjie would be the headquarters, and Shanghai Yijingjie and American Yijingjie would be the subsidiaries of Guizhou Yijingjie. &quot;When we invested, we promised to invest 20 million yuan first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person familiar with the Guiyang government revealed to a Southern Weekend reporter that although Yi Jingjie is not well-known, it does distributed databases , the leaders at the time also saw it, the technology was relatively new. &quot;The problem with it is that no one uses it, and there is no actual application scenario verification.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xuerong said frankly that Guiyang&#39;s big data started slowly, but it can attract a database company and regard it as a treasure, or even treat it as a treasure. Unicorns to breed. &quot;No city in the country dares to do this. We take real application scenarios and let them verify the database.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016-2019, Guiyang Industrial and Information Industry Development Guidance Fund Co., Ltd. , Guiyang Service Outsourcing and Call Industry Venture Capital Fund Co., Ltd., Guizhou Provincial Venture Investment Promotion Center, Guiyang Comprehensive Bonded Zone Development Investment (Group) Co., Ltd., Gui&#39;an New Area Emerging Industry Development Fund (Co., Ltd.) and other state-owned industrial funds , successively became shareholders of Yijingjie by increasing capital, with a cumulative investment of 128 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people from the Guiyang Municipal Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the initial investment and introduction of Yijingjie was based on its overseas technology. According to the official website of Yijingjie, the company is &quot;one of the few domestic database manufacturers with independent core technology.&quot; The R&amp;D team originates from Tianteng Company, with 30 years of technology accumulation and a complete team structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yijingjie was initially chaired by Chinese-American Li Weichong, and Li Jing, as his Chinese wife, served as the legal representative. Li Weichong has a glorious resume. He graduated from Carnegie Mellon University and received dual doctorates in finance and computer chemistry. Before founding Yijingjie, Li Weichong served as a senior executive in Lucent, Accenture, HP, China Unicom and other companies. Among them, asking Yao Ming to endorse China Unicom New World has become a classic case of publicity and promotion model, which once caused a sensation in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person close to Li Weichong and his wife described to Southern Weekend reporters that Li Weichong is personable, has extraordinary conversation, and has a gentle personality. Li Jing is on the strong side and has been in the clothing business in her early years. After the establishment of Yijingjie, Li Jing also participated in the daily management of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The original architecture is basically that of a small multinational company.” A former employee of Yijingjie told Southern Weekend reporters that in the early days, Yijingjie was relatively leading in the field of integrated distributed databases, and many people in the team were Colleagues or students of Turing Award winner Jim Gray have a relatively luxurious technical lineup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American Yijingjie was born first in Guizhou Yijingjie, one was established at the beginning of 2015 and the other at the end of the year. In Li Jing&#39;s own words, he is a &quot;father who has his son first and then looks for him.&quot; &quot;My biggest request for the American team is to pass on the technology of database development to the domestic R&amp;D team. This matter is not a secret among the American team.&quot; Li Jing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yijingjie&#39;s headquarters is located in Guiyang High-tech Zone. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 29/056f76c471.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/056f76c471.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yijingjie&#39;s headquarters is located in Guiyang High-tech Zone. Zhao Jilin/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Small companies take on big projects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to verify the technical reliability of Yijingjie, the Guiyang government selected Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Behavior as pilot projects, starting with the sandbox project rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called sandbox refers to a virtual database environment used for development, testing and experimental purposes, which is completely isolated from the production environment database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xin said that the original core business system of Guiyang Bank was built and launched in 2005, using IBM&#39;s Informix database. Because the system is aging, performance has dropped significantly, and operation and maintenance are worrying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An internal document obtained by Southern Weekend reporters also confirms this. The document mentioned, “In March 2020, the core system mistakenly placed the key synchronization program in the day change process, causing the day to be continuously and incorrectly switched at the end of the day, resulting in a large amount of production data disorder that day. More than a dozen engineers repaired it overnight. It took hours to resolve; a production accident occurred in May 2020, and UnionPay and core logic errors resulted in duplicate entries, resulting in a short payment in the bank.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xin further explained that as the customer scale of Guiyang Bank increases, both the database and the application system have obvious deficiencies in business carrying capacity. In addition, in response to the country&#39;s requirements for the development of the credit innovation industry and the self-reliance of the bank&#39;s financial technology system, Guiyang Bank is also making local substitutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Jingjie was keenly aware of this opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a work report to Li Zaiyong, the former vice governor of Guizhou Province, on January 14, 2019, Yi Jingjie said that promoting its database has great strategic significance: &quot;Solving the country&#39;s problems in finance and government affairs , communications and other core fields of information security issues; breakthroughs in the core basic technology of the database will drive the efficiency of the entire industry; replace the international database led by Oracle, which accounts for about 90% of the domestic market, and can be exported to the Belt and Road Initiative and even the European and American markets, from These two perspectives can effectively reduce China&#39;s service trade deficit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zaiyong instructed that from the perspective of institutional support, efforts should be made to build Yijingjie into an innovative platform for the development of Guizhou&#39;s big data industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate on November 21, 2023, Li Zaiyong&#39;s suspected bribery and abuse of power case was concluded by the National Supervisory Commission and transferred to the procuratorial organ for review and prosecution. However, the news did not disclose whether Li Zaiyong&#39;s fall was related to Yi Jingjie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former employee of Yi Jingjie who has worked with Li Weichong and his wife for many years told Southern Weekend reporters that unlike Li Weichong, Li Jing has particularly outstanding planning skills and can grasp the core needs of customers. &quot;She can clearly understand what the Bank of Guiyang, Guiyang Municipal Government and participating manufacturers want, and has a strong ability to make decisions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 2, 2019, the core business of Guiyang Bank&#39;s domestic database construction The sandbox testing system project was sold, with Yijingjie becoming the sole supplier, and the winning bid price was 43.98 million yuan. According to the announcement, this procurement adopts a single-source procurement method because &quot;according to project construction requirements, procurement can only be from a single supplier.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why use single-source bidding? He Xin said that Guiyang Bank&#39;s procurement is based on the &quot;Interim Provisions on the Management of Centralized Procurement of State-owned Financial Enterprises&quot; implemented by the Ministry of Finance on February 5, 2018. &quot;If we violate the law, I think we can be held accountable according to law. If we comply with the law, I think it will be No problem, no further explanation is needed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the project plan, Guiyang Bank uses the Yijingjie database to build a core business sandbox test application system, using the system as a sandbox for the existing core business system, and using the transactions of the core business system on the sandbox Data, carry out the testing and verification work of Yijingjie database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 8 of the same year, Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank purchased another project of Yijingjie - a domestic database application pilot, with a transaction amount of 123 million yuan. This project adopts the &quot;dual database parallel&quot; solution with mutual backup and free switching, and has been officially accepted in May 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A project leader of Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank told Southern Weekend reporters that the dual-bank parallel plan has three stages. In the first stage, Oracle is used as the main database, in the second stage, Yi Jingjie is used as the main library, and in the third stage, Oracle is completely excluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the person in charge admitted that Yi Jingjie has not yet become the main warehouse. “We must first admit the gap, then push our own things up, and let others stand guard for us for a while. , this is a more cautious approach.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee structure of Yijingjie obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that Yijingjie was still a start-up company with a small scale when it received the bank order. From 2017 to 2019, the number of employees was 69, 100, and 144 respectively. Among them, there are 46, 74 and 105 technical personnel respectively. There are less than 20 people with master&#39;s degrees in the company, and only one with a doctorate. In addition, Yi Jingjie has a team of more than 30 people in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, according to the evaluation report of the Chinese software shareholders, from June 2017 to June 2021, the total research and development costs of Yibaijie was 62.922 million yuan, of which in 2017, it was 0.03 million in 2018, and only 1.03 million in 2018 was only 1.03 million. In 2019, it was 19.6471 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Most income outsourcing &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; On the surface, Yibi Jie has received large orders from Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank in the early stage. But in fact, Yibble did not get much benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person familiar with the matter told the southern weekend reporter that among the 123 million yuan orders signed by Yibi and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank, their own products are only 25.9709 million yuan, accounting for 21.11%; Among the contracts signed by 43.98 million yuan, the own product part was only 10.9251 million yuan, accounting for 24.84%. Most of its income is realized through outsourcing, and even partial purchasing income costs inverted, which led the company to a sharp losses in succession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Asset Evaluation Report issued by Zhongrui Shilian Asset Evaluation Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Zhongrui Shilian) in January 2021, from 2017-2019, Yibi Jie operating income (parent company caliber ) 22.858 million yuan, 15.113 million yuan, and 91.5668 million yuan were respectively; net profit (caliber) was -1.8598 million yuan, 4.016 million yuan, and -493,900 yuan, respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Do n’t make money in the early stage, why does Yibijie develop more difficult banking core trading business system? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A shareholder of Yibi Jie told the Southern Weekend that although Li Jing announced a strong sense of mission to information security, the actual situation was that the company was facing the edge of bankruptcy and had to seek transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From October to November 2019, the Yibble Capital Crisis crisis, the company had no money on the account, and could not even pay the salary for a while. Borrowing funds from Yibi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned shareholders revealed that during the early entrepreneurial period of E -whale, although there were customers such as China Unicom and China Mobile, the amount of single orders was not large, hundreds of thousands to millions. Li Jing once not only mentioned at the internal meeting, &quot;When can I do so?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the United States on the other end of the Pacific, the company&#39;s annual sales revenue is only $ 23 million, but the team&#39;s costs need more than $ 5 million a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, the stance of the husband and wife is inconsistent with the matter of doing the core trading system and database of the bank. Li Weichong opposed many times, and the company&#39;s CEO Ding Hong also resolutely opposed it. &quot;But Li Jing saw the market and insisted on doing it.&quot; The above shareholders said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person close to Li Weiyong told the southern weekend reporter that Li Weichong&#39;s personality is very cautious, and the company’s losses are constantly high. big. On October 7, 2019, Li Weichong and Li Jing agreed to divorce. Li Weiyong stepped down as the chairman and handed all the Yibble Jie who was founded to Li Jing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Aiming at the many issues of Yibi Jie, reporters in the southern weekend contacted Li Weichong many times. He declined the interview with &quot;inconvenience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December 2019, Li Jing held a meeting in the underground conference room in Beijing&#39;s home. The company&#39;s backbones and representatives of Guiyang have participated in more than 20 people, but they excluded Li Weiyong and Ding Hong representing the American team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A shareholder who participated in the meeting told the Southern Weekend reporter that at this meeting, Li Jing asked the company to make a comprehensive transformation, based on the core business of the bank, and decided to leave the US team. &quot;This is the company&#39;s direction and the place where money is made.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The more you understand the technology, the more you know the border, the more you don&#39;t understand the technology, the more you dare to rush.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person who has participated in Evilist financing told the Southern Weekend reporter that stripping the US team has a lot to do with Anke (safe and reliable). &quot;Later we learned that if you want to do the core business system, you must pass the Anco first. You can&#39;t get this off, don&#39;t do any bank core.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Later The price has achieved a wholly -owned holding of Yibbles in the United States. Then, the US team disbanded and cleared the last obstacle of Yibi Jie&#39;s localization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 19, 2020, the Guizhou Sunshine Property Exchange announced that the core business system of Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system was transaction, with a total price of 426 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He Xin revealed that the project involves the full business chain, from the front, back to core, disaster recovery system, network, monitoring management platform, security and other related projects, involving more than 20 suppliers. Among them, the amount of the Yibble Jie database project was only over 40 million yuan, accounting for over 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become a &quot;national team&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; For a software startup, sufficient ammunition can maintain this &quot;burning money&quot; game. The method of Yibijie is to marry Chinese software and become the &quot;national team&quot; in the database field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China Software is a large high -tech central enterprise, which is controlled by China Electronics Information Industry Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as China Electronics). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jing took over the end of 2019, and began to contact China Electronics. In May 2020, China Electronics and Yibai Jie reached an exclusive investment intention, which will complete investment in Yibai Jie through two steps: first to acquire part of the original shares of Li Jing&#39;s Yibi Jie, through Chinese software, and then complete further capital increase Expand shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April 2021, China officially invested in Yibius, holding 7.6438%of the equity of Yibi Victoria at a consideration of 56.7897 million yuan. One year later, China&#39;s software decided to increase capital. It is intended to adopt a direct investment+newly -held holding sub -enterprise &quot;China Software Investment&quot; investment to register the capital of 22.91 yuan/1 yuan. According to calculations, the actual capital contribution does not exceed 1,819.213 million yuan), and the subscribed by Yi Yibai has added up to 16.9723 million yuan in registered capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the evaluation report of the Sino -Swiss Shilian, the capital increase of China Software to Yibble Jie is nearly 18 times the book value premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On February 21, 2023, the Chinese Software Board issued an announcement saying that the company had moderate control of actual investment and payment progress in the consideration of prudential and controlling investment risks. As of November 10, 2022, the company had paid 17.91 million yuan in capital increases, and China Software contributed 47.24 million yuan in capital, a total shareholding ratio increased to 11.09%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This investment amount is far from the original plan that &quot;the total contribution does not exceed 389 million yuan, and the total holding of a total of not exceeding the 25%equity of the Yibbles&quot; is far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On August 17, the Beijing Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued a warning letter to the Sino -Swiss Period, and proposed that the &quot;business income prediction data basis was not sufficient&quot; for Yibijie. In the first evaluation project, the implementation of the company&#39;s profit prediction data was not fully analyzed and reviewed. The reason for the second evaluation project did not fully pay attention to the reasons for the extension of the extension of the Easy Whale and the extension of the large order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, the warning letter mentioned that &quot;the&quot; first &#39;and other expressions were used in the two evaluation reports, but there was no sufficient evidence to support related expressions in the draft. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since then, Yibi Jie has no big financing trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person who has worked in Yi Whale Jie for many years told the Southern Weekend that the early integrated distributed database of Yibble Jie was relatively leading, but as other companies rose rapidly, the advantages of Yibi Jie&#39;s technical advantages gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually. No longer, there are some problems with the company&#39;s strategy. &quot;In the final analysis, it must be quickly listed, and then pull to resources to expand the R &amp; D team. A world -class technology, relying on small companies of one or two hundred people, how to get a leading position?&quot; Today, the National People&#39;s Congress Jincang, Dameng, Nanda General and Shenzhou GM are known as the &quot;four golden flowers&quot; of domestic databases. Not only are IT giants such as Alibaba, Tencent, and Huawei, but also small entrepreneurial manufacturers for market segments, such as Star Ring and Pingcap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another former employee who was responsible for Easy Whale&#39;s financing pointed out that even if the company wants to go public, it is difficult to meet the standards. The first is that the income does not meet the standard. Another key issue is a single customer. Except for Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank, Yibi Jie basically does not have large customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A former employee of Yibi Jie revealed to the south weekend reporter that starting in October, Yi Whale Jie has begun layoffs, because of &quot;financing issues and normal optimization of personnel&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[怀念奶奶丨到此的路程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261493]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Art history scholar Xu Xiaohu. Data map &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259891&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Art historian Xu Xiaohu. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;When my parents got married in Nanjing, the capital of the Republic of China, in May 1933, my grandmother invited some Chinese ladies who she thought were not decent. Come and stand with the bride during the ceremony. This is because grandma was shocked when she saw the 20-year-old German girl chosen by her doting third son: brown loose hair, thin and long face, eyes that fell into her head, and was squashed The raised nose is so ugly and perverted! How could this happen? Grandma was frantic, trying desperately to find some uglier ladies to reconcile the horrific situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1933, Xu Daolin and Barbara Schuchard held a wedding in Nanjing, and Jiang Fucong was the witness. Data map&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259892&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;1933 Xu Daolin and Barbara Schuchard held their wedding in Nanjing, and Jiang Fucong was the witness. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The introducer at that time was Mr. Jiang Fuchong, my father’s senior student in Germany, who was cheerful and progressive. Mr. Jiang later became the director of the National Central Library. There are many advanced and effective management measures, and it is advocated that all books should be digitized and permanently preserved for the public. Later, Uncle Chiang became the first director of the National Palace Museum in Taipei, where he implemented many new initiatives. Out of consideration for the benefit of employees, he provided dormitories and welfare facilities for everyone near the museum, which was still a suburb at the time. Wait for facilities. In 1933, he served as a witness at his parents&#39; wedding ceremony in Nanjing. He later told me that he &quot;ate the little tiger&#39;s red egg.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My mother took a boat from Germany, which fell to Nazism, to China to marry Xu Daolin. She found that this ancient country had many traditions that were very difficult for her. At first she refused to kneel and kowtow in front of her grandma like her father did. Growing up in Berlin, Barbara Schuchard had never kowtowed to anyone or any god in her life. In front of many curious viewers, her spine became an unbendable iron bar. At first, the poor father could only run back and forth between mother and wife to explain, and became a master of &quot;diplomacy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The next spring, a huge typhoon hit Nanjing. The young bride went to the Central Hospital to give birth to their first child, and found that the windows of the hospital ward were also covered with debris. Broken by the typhoon. She thought excitedly, ah! This must be a &quot;presidential-level&quot; boy! The father is also waiting for his son, and they have prepared many names - all for boys. When they saw a red and wrinkled little girl, they were completely stunned, indescribable surprise and disappointment. They looked at each other, not knowing what to do. One day passed, two days passed, and I couldn&#39;t think of any girl&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the third day, grandma spoke. She explained to the new parents the ins and outs of the baby. Feng Conghu and Yun Conglong, this descendant is obviously my father&#39;s favorite big cat named Xiaohu when he was a child. The cat was suddenly run over by a car one day. The &quot;three bald boys&quot; of the Xu family (my grandfather shaved the heads of all his sons and refused to wear Manchu pigtails) were so sad that they didn&#39;t eat or sleep. They just felt sad. . Grandma comforted Dad and said, don&#39;t cry, Santuer, your little tiger will fly back to you as soon as possible and stay with you for the rest of his life. Dad felt relieved and slowly returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma hugged the new little girl and said: Look, isn&#39;t this the little tiger you have been waiting for so many years to come back to accompany you? Who did you say? This is the little tiger who came back. My parents had nothing to say, so my grandma looked at my mother’s face and gave her daughter-in-law a title for the first time——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;You say Isn&#39;t it, Hu Zi Niang? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In the summer of 1934, Xu Xiaohu and his parents were in Guling, Lushan. Data map&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3fb66ea181.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1089&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/28/3fb66ea181.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259893&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the summer of 1934, Xu Little Tiger and his parents in Guling, Lushan Mountain. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight years later, we spent the most beautiful time in Geleshan, the suburb of Chongqing, the capital of Chongqing, where azaleas bloomed all over the hills and pine trees danced in the wind. time. From 1938 to 1941, my father served as the Charge d’Affaires of the Republic of China in Italy for four years. When World War II broke out and China and Italy broke off diplomatic relations, my parents took my sister Xiaoyu and me back to China. Grandma also came to Geleshan from her aunt&#39;s house in Chengdu to welcome her third son after four years of separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Our plane landed in Chongqing, and the welcome crowd gathered next to our parents, speaking adult Chinese. I walked down the gangway and stepped onto the land of China. I was extremely moved. This is my motherland! My eight-year-old heart nearly burst. My elementary school classmates in Rome once asked me, Uncle! (This is the pronunciation of Xu Xiaohu by foreigners)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Uncle Stop shouting! Why is your face so flat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I thought about it and answered: This is because I come from a very far away and very ancient country. The Chinese Embassy you saw on Viale Pola has strong guards in front of it wearing beautiful uniforms and tall feathered helmets. That is my ancient and luxurious motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now I kneel on the land of my motherland, bend down and lower my head, passionately kiss the place I have dreamed of for four years, I am happy and moved, and shed tears. Tell the motherland softly, great land, the tiger cub is back, your child is back. I will learn Chinese as soon as possible and become a Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The land at that time was so dirty, not as bright and clean as Rome. I saw dirty children with tattered clothes and scabs on their heads, standing there with bare feet and a runny nose, staring at us. Like adults, they spit out phlegm from their mouths and spit it on the ground. Xiaohu was very sad when he returned to China, but he insisted on thinking that this is my favorite motherland, that far, far away, very ancient motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After several hours of climbing up the hillside in a sedan chair, we finally arrived at the small, dark mud house at No. 15, Bakuaitian, Geleshan. Someone was carrying the luggage in, and my mother and sister went into the house and rummaged through the luggage for something. I stayed on the balcony and watched my father kneel down next to my grandmother who had her head and feet bound. Mother and son hugged each other, and grandma burst into tears, her thin and high-pitched voice reaching to the sky. Dad cried silently, and they held him and cried like this for a long time. I felt sad after reading it. I didn’t understand a word, but I fully understood the emotion in their hearts. I left quietly, walked into the door, climbed on a chair next to the big round table, and saw a pot of tea and a few unattended cups on the table. Don’t know what that drink is, but it must be a drink from my home country. I just poured myself a drink and watched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bitter. Adult taste. taste of China. I love it, I want to love it. Have another drink and taste it. Another glass. I have never tasted this taste in my life. A flavor not found in Italy. I am Chinese and I can drink Chinese taste. Cup after cup, I took in this ancient flavor with love and breathed it into my soul. Xu Xiaohu and her motherland gradually became one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It is starting to get dark. The crying and complaining outside hasn&#39;t stopped yet, but it&#39;s hard to see clearly inside the house. Someone placed a lamp on the big table. It was a green long-handled oil lamp made of ceramics. There was a white wick floating on the bowl of oil, and it was burning with its head exposed on one side, emitting very little light. Is this the only lighting in our entire large room (dining room)? The newly returned Chinese found that she could not see anything, and it was nothing like the light of a Roman electric chandelier. She suddenly felt very ashamed. This is the ancient lighting of my motherland. No matter how bright it is, I will still love it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I don’t remember how I fell asleep on the first night in Geleshan. I just remember that I insisted on going to school right away, learning my mother tongue again, and becoming a Chinese primary school students. I didn&#39;t expect that I was sent to the first grade to learn how to speak Chinese when I expected to continue studying in the fourth grade of elementary school. I went to school happily. I still remember the first class saying &quot;Come, come, come to school, everyone come to school.&quot; All Chinese characters did not have any phonetic symbols - we went directly to understand the ancient Chinese characters. On the way home, my classmates chased me and threw stones, shouting &quot;foreign woman!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My hair is not black and straight. It is brown and curved. When I got home, I scrubbed hard with water and a brush, trying to get it straight and black. No matter how wet it is or how you brush it, it will curl up again as soon as it dries. I had no choice but to face these classmates myself, fight with them, and beat them to the ground one by one. After all, I am already eight years old, a little taller than my first grade classmates. Xiaohu, who never behaved negatively when getting along with his Italian classmates, began to release an inner energy and felt very proud. It turns out that the children of the motherland during the war used physical strength to persuade each other. Well, start learning to speak Chinese and start becoming a Chinese hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Get down from the tree, Hutouer . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;Grandma said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will not come down from the tree. This tree is my home. &lt;/span>;I answered happily and mischievously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma asked you to get down from that tree immediately . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;No, grandma, I’ll sit down at my place. I see the world from here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hutou&#39;er, you are right away Get down from that tree. Grandma tells you to come down from that dirty tree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;No. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;We will not be unfilial now Come on, little tiger, good boy, come to grandma. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why don’t I leave my own Tree? Why do I have to go to grandma&#39;s place? I like living in this tree. Here I can count the enemy planes flying above! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At that time, I already spoke Chinese well. On the pine tree near the dark mud house in Geleshan, I remembered I remembered the free big fig tree that no one had observed or searched for in the large garden of the elegant embassy residence in Rome. My bedroom in Rome had a very high ceiling, and the ceiling to the walls were covered with colorful frescoes of classical mythological characters... There was a two- or three-story dollhouse in the bedroom, and I could play with the furniture inside, a doll&#39;s bed and cabinets, chairs and tables. , and several puppet dolls that can sit and stand. None of this means anything to me. After my nap, I would sneak outside into the garden, find the tallest fig tree, climb up, and hide among its rich leaves that oozed milky white liquid. No one could see me, and no one would come there to find me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the fall months I get to pick the juicy fruits from this huge tree. Even if there are no fruits, I can sit on its big branches and enjoy the breeze, the height and the blissful solitude. For a child with a family nanny, this is a rare blessing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My lovely little sister Xiaoyu is three and a half years younger than me. She has been in the doting arms of a French-Swiss nanny we call Mademoiselle. The Roman years between the ages of 4 and 8 were very free and devoted more to exploring unknown solitude rather than chatting with servants or dolls. In the ever-changing world of trees with cool breezes passing through, I would listen to the sounds of people talking on the ground from a higher vantage point and feel the movements of adults. That perspective allowed me to interact with adults from a wonderful distance. The world is separated by a buffer zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On those generous branches, everything loses the persuasiveness of &quot;adults say&quot;. From an arboreal perspective, everything happening on the ground becomes less urgent and threatening. Observing them from a higher perspective than adults reveals that adults often undermine the bounds of worldly wisdom or common sense. Surprisingly, they are often like this, spending a lot of time engaging in unnecessary words and deeds; making many unnecessary actions, untrue behaviors, and developing a hypocritical mentality. Adults spend days and nights thinking about issues that may seem unimportant or even ridiculous to us (children). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For example, they created clothes that were very difficult to put on. My mom&#39;s outfit for going out had a long row of buttons - but they were all in the back! Walking behind her, I could see that one of the buttons wasn&#39;t buttoned correctly, tilting her head to the side, causing all the other buttons to be wrong, creating a funny-looking sight. The adults would pretend not to notice but would giggle behind her back all day long. No one pointed this out to her, and no one helped her rebutton the row of buttons properly. I could only walk behind and look at them, thinking how stupidly and needlessly all this time was being spent, yet we kids were not allowed to point it out, giggle or laugh; Left to themselves and chalked up to adults&#39; love of spending time talking nonsense, children suffer in silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma tells you to get out of that dirty tree right away Get down from the tree. Did you hear it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why, grandma? Why should I leave my beloved habitat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because I have to teach you now embroidery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Embroidery? With needle and thread? Piercing my finger? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now you must learn embroidery. Time to learn something useful! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;For what? What&#39;s the use of embroidery, grandma? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;All girls learn embroidery. This is an absolute must! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why? I had never heard of embroidery in class! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The thought of sitting in a closed room, holding a thin needle, pricking a piece of cotton stretched in a hoop, in and out Being outside, cutting off all the sounds of the breeze, the fresh air from the sun, the songs of birds, or the voices of people, was to me like cutting off life itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition to sitting on the pine tree at home, I also like to sit on a small square stone under another pine tree. On my way home from school, I passed through the valley. At the corner of the winding mountain path, under the big stone mansion of General Chen Cheng, I slid down a few steps to reach that habitat. I sat there for a long time and stared at the distant plains of the Shapingba Valley. , the Jialing River meanders into the distance under the sunshine. There is the Central University there, and my father teaches there and also works for the Chongqing Central Government. In that habitat, I would listen to the voices of the people living in the plains, selling goods, parents shouting at their children, and the children shouting at each other, and I would think of my dad, working alone with his head like me, for all People serve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Every Sunday, he would take the &quot;double rickshaw&quot; to leave our black mud house and go down the thousands of steps to Shapingba below. The riverside plain, entering his Chongqing and his lonely room, I have been thinking like my dad, I think about my dad&#39;s inner world... He is alone, content with everything he can, making our country a better place Some. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This was at the start of World War II, and Japan was mercilessly bombing Chongqing on a daily basis in hopes of wiping out important government targets. But Chongqing has been in haze, with dark clouds, making it difficult for Japanese aircraft to bomb their targets. Every few days we&#39;d hear sirens whining overhead, and everyone, even those of us on the Gele Mountains, would rush out and squeeze into those dank, dark air-raid caves dripping with condensation. water vapor. Every time I would sneak out alone, sit on the rock under my favorite tall pine tree, count the enemy planes, and try to identify the different brands of the planes based on the black and white photos - those photos were taken from the police station by my classmates and I. Got it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Stop everything now, Hutouer, Come to me immediately. Come and learn embroidery, start today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why? What good was embroidery when the Japanese were bombing us with planes overhead? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because you will get married, You have to get ready to be a bride! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;That’s terrible, grandma! Is this really the case? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Of course, fool. Of course you want to get married! Get married and have kids! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma, please tell me, Is our childhood life also about getting married and having children? ——That is such a painful life, grandma! Each of you has given birth to a baby! Mom and Dad have done it too! Grandma’s baby’s baby has been born and is standing in front of Grandma! Now that our group of children has finally arrived, we must start living interesting lives. We are here to live our special, child-only lives! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I suddenly became crystal clear. The reason we are born is to be born! Become the children of our parents in marriage. Now that we are finally born, our purpose of growing up has been fulfilled and we no longer need to get married and have children! The life Grandma explained was completely unacceptable to my broad, arboreal way of thinking. Is this really the life everyone talks about? So it seems like adults are completely ignorant! The real purpose of life cannot be just for human existence. I saw clearly at that time that humans have obviously not asked this question. The meaning of existence - why we live - this is the question! What did we come to this fun place for? Of course I am here to appreciate this life and play with it thoroughly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Play it to the end - this is what we are here for - isn&#39;t it? This most basic and important test has taken root in my heart since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma told me many stories. There was a large, round metal barrel on a high shelf in her room. Grandma swayed her little feet back and forth, and was able to walk to the elevated shelf, take down the particularly bright bucket, mix it up, open it, and take out the maltose she made. There is nothing in the world that tastes better than the maltose rolled by grandma herself. They are round and flat, with white powder on the outside to prevent them from sticking together and being difficult to separate. Therefore, eating maltose can certainly be considered one of the main goals of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Listening to grandma telling stories is also one of the wonderful purposes, so charming! Grandma’s stories always include our family’s great heroes. For example, my grandma’s surname is Xia, and the Xia family comes from Yue Fei’s hometown. Grandma&#39;s voice was as sweet as honey and as high as a bird, and the stories she slowly told in her Xuzhou accent were all delicious. Xiaohu sat next to Grandma&#39;s knees and listened, forgetting everything else. The whole village loved Yue Fei, who helped the emperor return from the Jin Kingdom to restore the emperor&#39;s throne. However, Gaozong was unwilling to return the throne he had already occupied to his father. This unfilial son called Yue Fei and Yue Fei&#39;s eldest son. , was convicted as a national enemy and beheaded. The little tiger would burst into tears when he heard this, with tears and snot flying everywhere. The villagers who loved Yue Fei were too sad to speak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma also likes to tell the story of grandpa’s trip to Mongolia——&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tiger Head, one day, the country wanted the Mongols to stay in China and not be able to leave the motherland and go out independently, so they invited your grandfather to persuade them. So your grandfather, General Xu at that time, ran to Mongolia alone without any troops or weapons, taking only his flute master and the old lady from Xuzhou who made pancakes with him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In this way, the three of them arrived in Mongolia , found a small hill, went to the top and sat down. Grandpa planted his big &quot;Xu&quot; military flag on the ground and sat there writing lyrics, singing songs, admiring the moon, eating pancakes, and calmly waiting for the Mongolian chief to appear and surrender. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;After a while, the Mongolian chieftain really coming. He looked up and wow! I heard the sound of Kun Opera. I was shocked when I saw the big military flag with the word &quot;Xu&quot; in it. I immediately climbed up respectfully. As soon as I saw my grandfather, I knelt down and kowtowed desperately to apologize. &quot;Oops! The president has come in person. I am so ignorant and incompetent that I dare not take it! I have no intention of disturbing the uncle!&quot; He regretted that it was too late to kowtow and apologize. The confused chief thought that your grandfather was Mr. Xu Shichang, our president at the time, so he surrendered directly. .呵呵呵！ You see, grandpa brought Mongolia back without saying a word. You say how capable your grandpa is. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This is how my grandma narrated the story of the three grandfathers taking back Mongolia, and it has become one of our private family history jokes. Now when the great-grandchildren scattered in various countries gather together, they will perform multiple versions of this story as a &quot;historical drama&quot;, showing the story of General Xu Shuzheng&#39;s recovery of Outer Mongolia from various angles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Of course Dad has never heard grandma say this. In front of dad, no one dared to mention grandpa&#39;s name or past events. Dad would shed tears just thinking about his beloved father. Xiaohu actually liked hearing grandma&#39;s story very much, it was much more enjoyable than Yue Fei&#39;s story. I laughed every time I heard the part where the chief was covered in sweat and had no time to kowtow and surrender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At this time, various ideals of country, struggle, self-sacrifice, integrity, and serving the public took root in my heart. I began to think repeatedly about the purpose of our existence; I felt how important it is and how vast the world of time and space is. But in the deepest part of my heart, I began to have an overwhelming doubt...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>