<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[2023年两院院士增选结果揭晓，共133人当选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 17:35:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Chinese Academy of Engineering announced the list of elected academicians for the 2023 academician election. Among them, China The Academy of Sciences has 59 new academicians and the Chinese Academy of Sciences has 74 new academicians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern+ reporters combed through the list and found that a total of 8 &quot;big names&quot; in Guangdong were newly elected as academicians of the two academies. The specific list is as follows: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Prevention and Treatment Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ning Tsinghua University, Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Hongping Guangzhou Institute of Geochemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zheng Hairong Shenzhen Institute of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Engineering&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Enhou South China University of Technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Qingquan Shenzhen University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xing Feng Guangzhou University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chao Guangdong Drug Experimental Technology Center (National Drug Laboratory Guangdong Branch)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full list is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;3199&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259312&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;3277&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259311&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国最后的狩猎部落，在大兴安岭饲养驯鹿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261075]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:20:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会今日在深圳开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261077]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:41:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 21, the press conference before the Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was held. The reporter learned that the conference will be held at the Shenzhen International Convention and Exhibition Center from November 22 to 23. The theme of this conference is &quot;Stimulating the Momentum of Human Resources and Gathering Power to Build a Strong Country&quot;, including opening and closing activities, &quot;conferences&quot; and &quot;exhibitions&quot;. There are four sections: &quot;Competition&quot; and &quot;Recruitment&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human resources are the first resource of the economy and society. The National Human Resources Service Development Conference is an important platform for exchanges and presentations, supply and demand negotiations, innovation and entrepreneurship in the field of human resources services. The human resources service industry in Guangdong and the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area cherish this exhibition opportunity. The reporter learned from the press conference that there are currently 5,845 human resources service agencies in the province, of which private enterprises account for more than 90%, with revenue of 294.5 billion yuan, and an average annual growth rate of 13.7% since the &quot;13th Five-Year Plan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The activities in the four sections are colorful&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The activities of this conference are colorful, including &quot;meeting&quot;, &quot;exhibition&quot;, &quot;competition&quot; and &quot;recruitment&quot;. sections. Zhang Wenmiao, Director of the Mobility Management Department of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, introduced that the “meeting” refers to a seminar on the high-quality development of the human resources service industry. It has three sub-forums, namely the High-quality Development Forum of the Human Resources Service Industry and the Human Resources Service of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. High-quality industry development forum and a forum to promote the rapid development of key industries. At that time, experts, scholars and business representatives from academia and industry will give speeches, conduct discussions and exchanges, and discuss development plans in the field of human resources services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Exhibition&quot; is a human resources service supply and demand negotiation and display event. 144 leading human resource service companies and key employers in Guangdong, Hong Kong and Macao will be invited to participate in the exhibition and exchange. A large number of high-quality projects will be negotiated and signed, and a series of innovations will be held. Technology and products will be focused on roadshows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Competition&quot; refers to the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition and the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition. Among them, the Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition is divided into two categories: start-up and growth. A total of 1,022 projects across the country have signed up to participate. 145 projects were selected from various regions through preliminary rounds, and semi-finals and finals were held during the conference to determine the final ranking. The participating projects cover promoting employment of key groups such as college graduates, serving the real economy, and protecting workers&#39; rights and interests. The finals of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition will be held during the conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Jin” is the recruitment activity for young talents in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. It organizes 1,395 key employers and leading human resources service companies in the Greater Bay Area to hold special recruitment sessions for domestic college graduates and overseas students. There are special areas for chain master enterprises, Greater Bay Area city enterprises, high-tech enterprises, state-owned enterprises, listed enterprises, &quot;specialized, special and new&quot; enterprises, master&#39;s and doctorate talents, etc., providing more than 50,000 high-quality jobs online and offline. At the same time, services such as live broadcast guidance, employment guidance, school-enterprise negotiations, and government-enterprise roadshows are carried out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong submitted signing projects to the conference&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Achieved an intention of cooperation of 9.7 billion yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“In recent years, the human resources service industry in Guangdong Province has experienced rapid development. development, service products are becoming increasingly abundant, and output value and scale have maintained a high growth trend.&quot; Du Minqi, director of the Guangdong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security, said that as the organizer of this conference, Guangdong attaches great importance to hosting and participating in the conference. &quot;The four sectors of &quot;competition&quot; and &quot;employment&quot; are actively working hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Industry High-quality Development Forum to be held on the afternoon of the 22nd, with the theme of &quot;Bay&quot; image renewal and surging momentum, will be held through video connections, keynote speeches, Through round-table dialogues and other forms, we will conduct in-depth discussions on the construction of a high-level talent highland in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the path to high-quality development of the human resources service industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of negotiation and display of supply and demand for human resources services, more than 50 exhibitors from Guangdong Province submitted more than 80 contract projects and reached an intended cooperation amount of 9.7 billion yuan. At the same time, the Greater Bay Area Achievement Exhibition with the theme of “Talent Gathering in the Bay Area, Industry Prospering the Future” will be held to showcase the development of the Greater Bay Area and the human resources service industry through information, technology, interactive experience and other rich exhibition formats. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition, human resources service innovation and entrepreneurship projects, technologies and products have been collected from all industries across the province. Currently, 6 participating projects in Guangdong have advanced to the national semi-finals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of youth talent recruitment activities in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, more than 1,100 key enterprises and institutions and leading human resources service companies in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area have been organized, and the &quot;Industry-Education Evaluation&quot; skills ecological chain has been introduced. Resources such as recruitment for main institutions and high-level talent recruitment for masters and PhDs will further improve the quality of supply-demand matching and recruitment activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that this conference focuses on integrating into the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and has many Hong Kong and Macao elements. One of the key activities of the conference - the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition invites Hong Kong, Macau and nine mainland cities in the Greater Bay Area to participate. The competition is divided into four parts: personal style display, blind box answering, scene answering, and difficulty challenge. , 22 players will participate in the finals on the 23rd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Zhongliang, director of the Shenzhen Municipal Human Resources and Social Security Bureau, said that the conference will also set up an exhibition on the development achievements of the human resources service industry in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, with key content including the display of talent policies for Hong Kong and Macao. At the same time, an independent booth of the Hong Kong Talent Office was set up, the Hong Kong Labor and Welfare Bureau was invited to conduct a talent policy promotion roadshow, and 20 well-known organizations from Hong Kong and Macau were invited to participate in the job fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[时隔三年，广州国际灯光节再次“光耀羊城”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261069]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:10:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a couple hugged by the Pearl River Enjoy the Guangzhou International Light Festival performance on Canton Tower.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/bfdbe84f95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/bfdbe84f95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 21, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a couple hugged by the Pearl River and enjoyed the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival performance presented on Canton Tower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 12th Guangzhou International Light Festival will be officially held from November 21 to 30, 2023. It will be the first time to reopen offline after 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year&#39;s lighting festival is themed &quot;Dazzle the Bay Area, Shine Yangcheng, and Create a Smart Future&quot; and is divided into &quot;new central axis venues&quot; (Huacheng Square, Haixinsha Asian Games Park, Canton Tower) and &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot; (24 architectural media facades along Yanjiang Road, Haixin Bridge, Liede Bridge), a total of 25 sets of light and shadow art works are illuminated at the same time, combined with AR (augmented reality) ) visual technology to comprehensively display Guangzhou’s gorgeous city night views and cultural charm. The multi-dimensional integration and innovation of light and shadow technology and Guangzhou culture will become an excellent &quot;check-in place&quot; in Guangzhou in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival opened. A tourist took a selfie with the Canton Tower on his mobile phone.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/53631619bb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/22/53631619bb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259171&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023 Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the opening of the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival, a tourist took a selfie with the Canton Tower on his mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, when the Canton Tower met the Light Festival, its shape looked particularly enchanting.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/25e4f463e7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/22/25e4f463e7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, when When Canton Tower meets the Light Festival, its shape looks particularly enchanting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the light-up event on the night of November 21st, the historical heritage of Guangzhou&#39;s thousand-year city, cultural and commercial history was condensed with the help of modern light and shadow technology. The legendary images visible to the naked eye, the five-color five-color sheep coming with ears of ears, the auspicious awakening lion standing with its head held high, the soaring cloud dragon and red bird... In just 3 minutes, the waterfall-like light and shadow images broke through the &quot;dimensional wall&quot; one after another, and they were born. The Canton Tower jumped up, setting off a visual feast dedicated to Lingnan legends on both sides of the Pearl River, and also lit up the &quot;flowers of light and shadow&quot; dedicated to the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival on the central axis of the flower city in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the lighting works display of Haixin Bridge and Liede Bridge belong to the &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7f08bc249e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/7f08bc249e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023 On the same day, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the lighting works display on Haixin Bridge and Liede Bridge were part of the &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a light and shadow art work was displayed at the &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; of the Light Festival. A total of 25 groups of light and shadow art works were lit at the same time.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/802507970e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/802507970e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a light and shadow art work at the &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; of the Lighting Festival. A total of 25 sets of light and shadow art works are illuminated at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that this year’s lighting festival adopts a closed reservation system for entry, and entry must be verified with the original valid ID (certificate used for reservation). If you want to know the reservation channels, lighting time, AR show and other performance details, you can pay attention to the information released by official accounts such as &quot;Guangzhou International Lighting Festival&quot; and &quot;Guangzhou Haixinsha&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival is divided into &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; and &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;, which will become the unique venue in Guangzhou in the future. The best &quot;check-in place&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7aabd19bb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7aabd19bb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival is divided into a &quot;new central axis venue&quot; and a &quot;one river and two sides venue&quot;, which will become the best venue in Guangzhou in the future. The &quot;check-in place&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蹭老式消费兴起：有助于青年与长者互相学习]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261033]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, there have been some intersections in consumer demand between young people and middle-aged and elderly groups, which has attracted attention. For example, young people Signing up for the &quot;Sunset Red&quot; tour group, some office workers who don&#39;t want to order takeout flocked to the canteen for the elderly, and some young people squeezed into various interest classes at the university for the elderly and discovered &quot;really delicious&quot;... These new trends on social platforms, It is ridiculed by the outside world as &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot;. Why has moving closer to the consumption patterns of middle-aged and elderly people become the “life they aspire to” for many young people? How to treat it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, I think the direct motivation for &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is low price attraction. Whether it is a &quot;Sunset Red&quot; tour group, a canteen for the elderly, or a university for the elderly, what they all have in common is the relatively low price. The presupposition is that the elderly retire from their jobs and have no financial resources except pensions. With little other income, the selling price of goods or services targeted at this group is naturally lower than the normal market price. More importantly, as part of the social security system for the elderly, the government pays for some services or items (in this case, there is some controversy about young people taking advantage of the elderly), and some businesses have also started to pay for them in order to promote sales. Give it to the elderly. The fact that young people are &quot;mingling among them&quot; undoubtedly reflects their pursuit of low-priced goods or services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, traveling can be regarded as a relaxing experience. The recipes in the elderly canteen will most likely not be any different. The courses taught by the elderly university cover flower arrangement, painting, calligraphy and other talents and skills. Skills, the quality of these goods or services will not be too bad. In other words, it is not an exaggeration to say that the above-mentioned goods or services have the basic characteristics of &quot;high quality and low price&quot; and good cost performance. Young people have discovered this opportunity and made full use of it to enrich and enrich themselves. I think it is a wise move. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this truly reflects the objective fact that young people are under great pressure to survive. The overall economy is in a downward trend, the population is aging, the subsequent impact of the epidemic has not been completely eliminated, and the number of college graduates is increasing. The competition for employment is extremely fierce and it is difficult to find a job. At the same time, they are also faced with work pressure, promotion pressure, renting and buying a house, pressure to get married and start a family, pressure to have children, etc. To be honest, the overall survival and development situation of contemporary young people Not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering specific activities such as traveling and attending classes at senior universities, we believe that young people’s participation in them is a response to the high-intensity, high-pressure, and fast-paced production that young people generally find themselves in in the context of urbanization and modernization. A kind of resistance, rebellion and temporary escape (escapism) from the way of life. Faced with various production and lifestyles with &quot;involution&quot; as their basic characteristics, which have no way to escape, young people can actively debug, adjust and make some changes, and achieve relief and decompression through travel, study, etc. Purpose, I think it is a pretty good thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; should not be understood in a narrow sense as the field of consumption, but should be interpreted from the perspective of the specific consumption process and the concrete experience in the consumption process, that is, the social nature of consumption cannot or is not easily ignored. feature. The core essence of &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is that young people and the elderly get along and interact with each other for a certain period of time. Travel can be as short as one or two days, as long as three to five days or a week, to eat in the elderly canteen and to attend classes at the elderly university. This allows young people and older people to spend more time together, and such interactions will produce significant learning effects. And this kind of learning is two-way rather than one-way, because through such interactions and exchanges, young people can gain life experience provided by their elders, and the elders can be infected by the vitality or passion of young people. Especially for the elderly, if young people are willing to listen to their stories or sharing, they usually feel happy and satisfied, and their sense of self-worth will be significantly enhanced. In this sense, the precise expression of &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; should be &quot;mutual consumption&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A direct effect of this &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is to repair or improve the relationship between young people and their older relatives in their families or clans. In reality, there are some young people, especially young men, who have little communication with their parents. They often keep a distance from their parents in the name of generation gap. This is the so-called &quot;disconnection&quot; phenomenon, but they have no relationship with their parents outside. Communication among the elderly is tolerant, and some young people often take the initiative or actively communicate with the elderly. Obviously, occasional or regular participation in &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; will undoubtedly have a positive effect on increasing the close relationship between young people and their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot;, some people may think that this will squeeze out the resources of the elderly. A bunch of chattering young people suddenly join the tour group, and the elderly will feel that the young people have somewhat affected their &quot; &quot;The right to tranquility&quot;; when a bunch of young people suddenly come to join in the fun in the seniors&#39; canteen, the old people will feel it is too noisy; when a bunch of young people suddenly break into the classroom to teach, the old people will feel crowded and uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more fundamental doubt is that the above-mentioned various special services or benefits only for the elderly are paid for by the government and are part of the security system for the elderly. Now, young people are flocking to them, and there is obvious The rights or rights of the elderly are suspected of being raided. But the author believes that we should not understand the word &quot;resource&quot; statically. If the elderly or even most elderly people benefit from and acquire it because of the participation or joining of young people, this is undoubtedly another hidden precious resource. It should be noted that resources are not only economic-oriented, but also include social-oriented resources in a broad sense, which mainly refers to the level of social communication and social interaction; resources are not limited to initial static resources, and resources in a broad sense also exist after the initial resource investment. Learned resources, we might as well imagine the latter as the multiplier effect in the field of economics or investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I mean is that a cross-age or mixed-age (fixed structure) population structure usually produces a good comprehensive effect because each other benefits from or benefits from mutual exchanges and learning. We can also understand it as the application or application of economies of scale and economies of scope theories in daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I couldn’t help but think of two things. One is in Japan. During the layout process, some kindergartens or primary schools will choose to be adjacent to nursing homes. At eight o&#39;clock in the morning, the elderly can hear the sound of reading aloud from next door as scheduled; at four o&#39;clock in the afternoon, the elderly will see the school after school at the entrance of the nursing home. The children bowed to themselves and politely said &quot;Hello Grandpa&quot; and &quot;Wish you a happy day, Grandma&quot;; on weekends or holidays, a group of children and their teachers came to the nursing home to perform performances for the elderly, eat together, and Play games, and as feedback, the elderly can occasionally or often go to the school next door to talk about the past and present lives of their city or community. I believe that this is the proper meaning of &quot;being productive in old age&quot; and &quot;being happy in old age&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other is that in recent years, some domestic cities have proposed to build urban development goals for specific groups. For example, Shanghai proposed to build an age-friendly city, Beijing proposed to build a youth-friendly city, and Shenzhen proposed to build a child-friendly city. Changsha proposes to build a female-friendly city. I just wonder, if this kind of special care for a certain group of people is singled out and used as an important part of urban development goals or urban development strategies, isn&#39;t it suspected of &quot;social deprivation&quot; for other groups? ? What do you mean by just being friendly to the elderly? Unfriendly to young people? Not child friendly? Is its essential point that when this kind of preferential policy for specific groups of people is used as an urban development goal or strategy, there will inevitably be a package of follow-up measures in terms of funds, projects, policies, planning, etc. To put it more bluntly, It means that a lot of real money is invested in specific groups of people, which is obviously not fair and reasonable for other groups. In the long run, this move is intended to harm or harm the city&#39;s diversity, inclusiveness and equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, I also disagree with the suggestions or suggestions of some people and even some experts to build special women&#39;s (subway) carriages or children&#39;s (high-speed rail) carriages. Why can’t we build a high-end society that is gender-friendly, gender-equal, and gender-integrated through extensive publicity and innovative practices? Why can&#39;t we be tolerant of children who are active or crying, or even adopt more positive and proactive methods, such as actively chatting with children, playing games, playing poker, etc., so that children can feel the affection of uncles, aunts, brothers and sisters in the carriage? What about warmth? Obviously, whether it is a women&#39;s (subway) carriage or a children&#39;s (high-speed rail) carriage, they are all short-sighted moves aimed at evading and avoiding the problem, and they are all deliberately or deliberately aimed at &quot;distinctiveness&quot; and &quot;community isolation&quot; ” (social segregation), all of which are against or deviating from the basic principles of mixed-age or cross-age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南周x读库2024联合征订，买1得10，错过等1年！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261065]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 15:08:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of this year, we [Nanzhou x Reading Library] joint subscription was launched. After the event, many readers were still asking customer service if there was any event? When will the next event be online? &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4f39e9ed29f243a7b2c88dbc5567123f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;517&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4f39e9ed29f243a7b2c88dbc5567123f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259141&quot; data-mce -width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;So, here we come——&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;If you are an old reader of Nanzhou and Duku and know both companies, you can click directly to place an order👇&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop44174528.m.youzan.com/wscgoods/detail/2ovea0fevflh4ib?dc_ps=3454431088766738433.200001&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /22/350efda899a9d005f6b91ff5e85b1c88.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/350efda899a9d005f6b91ff5e85b1c88 .png&quot; data-key=&quot;259137&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Zhoux Reading Library 2024 Joint Subscription, one yuan per day, you can get:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;1. Southern Weekend one-year membership&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2. &quot;Reading Library&quot; MOOK2024 (all 7 physical magazines)&lt; /span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;3. One-year membership of Duku APP&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Limited time bonus: Joint subscription special Gift a book&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In an era of overwhelming content, the information flow of short and fast news is like a crucian carp crossing the river, but There are fewer and fewer high-quality articles that can restore the original appearance of the incident, and serious and in-depth content is increasingly needed by everyone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Strong Recommended to you, don’t miss this joint subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style =&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;Southern Zhou Dynasty × Reading Library 2024 Joint Subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot; font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Southern Weekend Annual Membership Card&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;can be enjoyed&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal; &quot;>;10 value-for-money rights for news and knowledge&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal; &quot;>;&lt;span>;Get &lt;strong>;more than 10 million words/year&lt;/strong>; original articles and more than 30 years of classic accumulation&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;, no need to worry about where to go Select real and useful key information. You can also see&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Top writers and scholars columns&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;strong >;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dozens of audio and video courses carefully crafted by Nanzhou&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, get Benefit from the lifelong humanistic heritage and no need to worry about your own growth and learning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;《Read Library》Mook&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font- weight: normal;&quot;>;7 volumes per year,&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;one book published every two months&lt;/strong>;. The booklet is small and beautiful, but the content is all-inclusive. Talk about&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;interesting things in the universe, life, human body, art, technology, economy and other fields&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Electronic members of Duku app&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; can read all the contents of each issue of &quot;Duku&quot; in 2024 as soon as possible , you can read &quot;Duku&quot; selected articles from previous years, the author&#39;s exclusive audio and video, behind-the-scenes footage, etc. for free. You can also build a personal treasure house of knowledge that you can use endlessly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, we also give each joint subscription readers will receive a special book as a gift (random, no designation accepted). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Southern Weekend x Reading Library 】2024 joint subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Buy 1 and get 10! &lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; >;&lt;span>;One-year membership of Southern Weekend App&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;(original price 288 yuan)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;One-year membership of Reading Library App&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;(original price 283 yuan)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot; font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&quot;Reading Library&quot; Mook2024&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Full Year&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;7 volumes&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&amp;nbsp;original price 294 yuan）&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>; &lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Add a special book for joint subscription&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Total value&lt;/span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;792 yuan &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;, limited time special offer&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;365 yuan&lt; /strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;👇Click the image below to grab it👇&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop44174528.m.youzan.com/wscgoods/detail/2ovea0fevflh4ib?dc_ps=3454431088766738433.200001&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/22/10c922b2ac8e2f1bb38b66791723dd50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/10c922b2ac8e2f1bb38b66791723dd50.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259140&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不想买到“毒地”房？土壤信息公开还不够]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261043]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/22/e8ed7338d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 22/e8ed7338d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Buyers need to check the land use history. Generally speaking, the original It is safer if it is farmland, residential, public facilities, or green space parks, and there are basically no migration pathways for pollutants from other surrounding areas. If it is a converted contaminated site, you need to pay attention to the results of soil assessment. (Picture and text unrelated) Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;poisonous land&quot; dispute between Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. and Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. Generate attention. Spending two generations&#39; &quot;six wallets&quot; to buy their first home is a price many ordinary home buyers have to pay. How to avoid buying a &quot;poisonous land&quot;? This has also become a topic of widespread concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;my country&#39;s soil pollution laws and regulations were promulgated relatively late. In 2019, the Soil Pollution Prevention and Control Law began to be implemented. Combined with other documents, three situations require soil pollution status investigation: The first is the change of land use to residential, public management and public services (referred to as &quot;one residential, two public&quot;); the second is the construction land plots with soil pollution risks; the third is the change of land use for production and operation of key soil pollution supervision units, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the requirements of laws and regulations such as the Soil Pollution Prevention and Control Law, soil environment investigation reports must be disclosed to the public in accordance with regulations, but the legal provisions on information disclosure are not specific enough. Soil pollution is hidden, and home buyers need to check the land use history. Generally speaking, it is safer if the land was originally farmland, residential, public facilities, or green space park types, and there are basically no other migration pathways for pollutants in the surrounding land. If it is a converted contaminated site, you need to pay attention to the results of soil assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Soil information disclosure is uneven&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Because there are no clear regulations, there are various channels for soil information disclosure, making it difficult to search with one click. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei, a staff member of the environmental protection organization &quot;Guangzhou Green Network Environmental Protection Service Center&quot; (hereinafter referred to as Green Network) told the Southern Weekly reporter that our country&#39;s laws do not provide for soil In what channels should the environmental investigation report be made public, what content should be made public, etc. In actual situations, some reports are made public on the websites of real estate developers, and some are published on industry forums of companies commissioned to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2016, Green Network has regularly collected from hundreds of websites and compiled tens of thousands of reports related to soil pollution investigation and remediation for free public review. However, public awareness of this aggregated information is not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The professional nature of information disclosure content also increases the difficulty for users to access it. The public generally searches for the subdivision or developer name, but reports often use parcel numbers provided by the Department of Natural Resources. Moreover, most of the public reports are simplified and lack location diagrams, making it difficult for the public to correspond their property and plot numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters searched the Green Network database using &quot;Beijing&quot; as the keyword and found that the vast majority of the 15 preliminary investigation reports displayed on the homepage were only Some are about 2 pages long, including a brief description of basic soil conditions, investigation plans and investigation conclusions; some are as long as 130 pages, or the full text and on-site photos are disclosed in detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei said that the simplified report lacks data such as sampling point maps and pollutant concentration distribution, making it impossible for outsiders to conduct detailed analysis. It is easy to judge whether the sampling process was standardized based on the photos, but the report did not present sampling photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There is still a big gap in the information disclosure intensity and quality of soil environmental investigation reports compared with air, water, environmental assessment and other reports.&quot; Guo Lei suggested, Specific information disclosure specifications should be formulated and a unified release platform for information disclosure should be established. Especially for residential buildings and schools redeveloped from land used by heavily polluting industries, developers need to disclose detailed information, and home buyers and parents of students must make careful choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How &quot;poisonous land&quot; can be turned into &quot;treasure land&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If soil restoration is in place, there are many cases where &quot;poisonous land&quot; has been transformed into &quot;treasure land&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2008, the Beijing Chemical Plant No. 2, located in the southeastern suburbs of Chaoyang District, Beijing, ceased production, and the land was transferred to the State Administration for Residential Land Development. Dr. Yang Jin, chairman of Simple Testing Technology (Shanghai) Co., Ltd., has participated in the soil environment investigation and testing work of this project. Yang Jin introduced that the soil investigation and restoration of this project lasted for many years and cost more than 1 billion yuan. On the land Guanghua New City Community was built and residents will move in at the end of 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Transforming a &quot;poisonous land&quot; into a &quot;treasure land&quot; requires a long process of assessment and restoration. The investigation of soil pollution alone will go through three stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first stage is pollution identification, which is mainly based on data collection, on-site surveys and personnel interviews; if possible pollution sources are found in or around the plot, then Entering the second stage of contamination confirmation, it is divided into preliminary and detailed sampling analysis, and the preparation of a soil pollution status investigation report; the third stage is mainly supplementary sampling and testing to obtain the parameters required to meet risk assessment and soil and groundwater remediation. The investigation work in the first stage can be carried out separately or simultaneously during the second stage investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin introduced that the sampling density for the preliminary investigation of soil pollution conditions is small, generally a 40m×40m grid layout, which is equivalent to the area of ​​four basketball courts. For a sample, it usually takes 2-3 months from the formulation of the plan to the release of the analysis results. If contaminants are detected in the preliminary investigation, detailed investigation is required. The sampling density is increased to a 20m×20m grid, which is equivalent to the area of ​​a basketball court to collect one sample. Local key areas may be denser. This step is time-consuming. About 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the soil pollution status investigation and risk assessment are completed, soil remediation must be carried out. Depending on the land area and remediation goals, the remediation work may take as short as one or two years. , the length may exceed ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cb4dd94913.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cb4dd94913.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;In July 2022, Hefei, Anhui, at the contaminated soil treatment and restoration site in the former industrial production area of ​​Yaohai District, The staff analyzed the soil at room temperature. Visual China/Picture&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are currently more than 100 soil remediation technologies, and there are more than ten commonly used technologies, which can be roughly divided into physical There are three methods: chemical and biological. The technical principle is to transfer, absorb, degrade and transform pollutants in the soil, reducing their concentration to acceptable levels, or converting toxic and harmful pollutants into harmless substances. According to the remediation mode, it can be divided into in-situ and ex-situ remediation. The difference lies in whether the contaminated soil is moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The effectiveness of soil remediation also needs to be evaluated. my country implements a soil pollution risk management and restoration list system for construction land. Contaminated plots on the list must pass the review organized by the provincial ecological environment department and meet the established management and control or restoration goals. Only after the risks are controllable can they be removed from the list and developed and utilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is difficult for the public to judge the quality of reports&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if a soil environmental survey has been conducted and the information has been disclosed relatively well, the quality of the reports varies. Qi, the professional threshold is high, and it is difficult for the public to understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These reports are prepared by professional companies and have passed expert review. Let alone the general public, let us look for problems in the reports. In fact, there is no It’s easy to find.” Guo Lei admitted that it is difficult for ordinary residents to judge whether the quality of the report is up to standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pollutants in the soil are different from the atmosphere and water and are not evenly distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Jie, secretary-general of Zhongguancun Zhongxin Soil Remediation Industry Technology Innovation Alliance, told Southern Weekend reporters that soil is multi-phase and heterogeneous, and pollutants are underground , invisible to the naked eye. During the soil investigation process, contaminants may not be discovered in time due to factors such as technology and cost constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soil remediation has certain uncertainties, and there is no guarantee that it will be &quot;repaired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin said that in reality, there is a phenomenon that after soil remediation is completed and then tested, the pollutants still exceed the standard, and even the organic pollutants in some areas &quot;increase as the soil is repaired.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are two main types of pollutants in soil - heavy metals and organic matter. Heavy metals have weak mobility and are relatively simple to repair. Generally, there are chemical curing methods, leaching methods, separation methods, etc. Since organic matter has strong mobility, thermal desorption, chemical oxidation or biological remediation methods are generally used. Organic pollutants may migrate with groundwater and other media. The soil extraction process may cause disturbance to underground pollutants, which may cause them to migrate to a wider range. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Jie suggested that awareness of soil pollution prevention and control should be strengthened during the development process. For example, when digging and turning the soil, pay attention to observe whether the color and smell are abnormal, and be equipped with XRF, Rapid screening instruments such as PID can quickly determine whether soil is contaminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Supervisory authorities should check things in advance. According to GreenNet statistics, since 2019, land use rights holders of more than 300 plots across the country have been punished by the ecological environment department for failing to conduct soil pollution surveys or risk assessments before redevelopment of the plots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Even if the reported problems are discovered, the house may have been built by then, and the difficulty of solving the problem has become more complicated.&quot; Guo Lei said that at present, The ecological environment department is improving the supervision system and requires survey companies to file sampling plans in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment issued the &quot;Guidelines for Preliminary Investigation, Supervision and Inspection of Soil Pollution Conditions in Construction Land (Trial)&quot;, stipulating that municipal ecological environment authorities Carry out supervision and inspection on the sampling and analysis work plan, on-site sampling, and laboratory testing and analysis. For investigation reports that have passed the review, the provincial ecological and environmental authorities can organize random inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to supervision by local environmental protection departments, Green Network will also report similar clues discovered. &quot;It is possible that some plots that should have been subject to soil environmental surveys but were not, were not discovered by either us or the environmental protection department,&quot; Guo Lei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei explained that there are two important reasons why soil pollution surveys were not conducted before development: First, soil pollution surveys are not subject to the same regulations as planning permits and construction permits. It is widely known that many developers do not know that soil pollution surveys are required, and legal education and publicity need to be further strengthened. Second, many local ecological environment departments do not fully grasp land change information and need to share information with natural resource departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is it worthwhile to develop highly polluting land plots?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin observed that when the real estate industry was booming in the past few years, land plots in highly polluting industries Also very popular. &quot;Even if soil environmental investigation and restoration take several years and cost hundreds of millions or even billions, it is still difficult to dampen the enthusiasm of developers because of the huge returns.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Nowadays, local governments and developers are also reflecting on whether it is worth paying such a large cost to repair a difficult and uncertain soil in order to develop residential buildings and bear subsequent risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Regulations on the Prevention and Control of Soil Pollution in Jiangsu Province&quot; that will be implemented on September 1, 2022 stipulates that non-ferrous metal mining and processing, non-ferrous metal smelting, and petroleum shall be strictly controlled. Land with serious soil pollution in mining, petroleum processing, chemical industry, coking, electroplating, tanning, pesticides, lead batteries, steel, hazardous waste utilization and disposal and other industries should not be planned as residential areas, schools, kindergartens, hospitals, Land used for nursing homes and sanatoriums can be used to expand ecological space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, even if you are unfortunate enough to live in a house built on a soil-contaminated land, residents do not need to panic too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei said that if you live on a high floor, you are far away from the surface. Even if there are volatile and semi-volatile organic compounds in the soil, when you reach the high floor, The concentration is also very low. For houses built on &quot;poisonous land&quot;, the basements, gardens and green belts will be most affected. The gas after the pollutants volatilize will slowly penetrate into the underground space and accumulate there. It is not recommended to stay in the basement for a long time, and gardens and green belts are prone to direct contact with contaminated soil. In windy and dusty weather, residents should wear masks. If they are well protected, health risks can be greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川“废弃神话公园”，藏着“七仙女”与“历代帝王”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260960]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the ancient exhibition with &quot;Chinese history and culture&quot; as the core theme The famous scenic spot has many statues of emperors and generals designed in the China Progress Garden.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258918&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot with &quot;Chinese History and Culture&quot; as the core theme was designed in the Huaxia Process Garden There are many statues of emperors and generals. &lt;p>; A man-made &quot;cultural heritage&quot; with a sense of absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, in Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, the gate of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was closed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, The gates of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot are closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main body of this large-scale scenic spot is built in Fengdian Town, Zhongjiang County, with a planned land area of ​​more than 10,000 acres. In 2014, the developer of the scenic spot brought the project to this small county town, claiming that it would help local people get rich. Unexpectedly, there was insufficient funds in the first year of construction. Despite being in arrears with tens of millions of project funds, the scenic spot still barely opened for business at the end of 2019. At the opening, colorful balloons floated in the air, and hundreds of people watched the red-faced Guan Gong perform his machete on the red carpet. The scene was lively. However, the scenic area&#39;s business has been bleak since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, weeds grew on both sides of the road in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/f7a677405f.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/f7a677405f .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the roads in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area were overgrown with weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; standing in front of a chariot looked dilapidated due to long-term disrepair.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Yizun Station The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; in front of the chariot appear dilapidated due to disrepair over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; have solemn expressions, as if people have traveled from Deyang to Xi&#39;an in an instant.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses&quot; His expression was solemn, as if people were transported from Deyang to Xi&#39;an in an instant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; were arranged neatly in the scenic spot.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size statues The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are neatly arranged in the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to encountering the epidemic, there are traces of the failure of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot;. Scenic spots usually attract tourists with beautiful mountains and rivers or cultural history, but the gimmick of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; is the &quot;immersive experience of Chinese culture&quot; brought by nearly 2,000 artificial sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The themes of these sculptures are all-encompassing, interpreting mythical stories such as Chang&#39;e flying to the moon, the Eight Immortals crossing the sea, the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl, and the Seven Fairies, but the production is relatively rough. In order to let tourists experience the feeling of &quot;pointing the country&quot;, the scenic spot has also built thousands of replicas of terracotta warriors and horses. Accompanying the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are nearly 500 &quot;statues of emperors from past dynasties&quot;. However, the imperial appearance, which is far from the common perception, and the text introduction full of errors, made the visitors laugh and cry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot is already a pool of stagnant water.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258924&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was turned into a pool of stagnant water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a statue of an emperor surrounded by wild grass almost as tall as a person.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20 /b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, a statue was surrounded by weeds almost as tall as a person. statue of the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scenic tour line is 19 kilometers long, and sculptures are scattered in more than 20 scenic spots. Some tourists once complained on the review software, which is equivalent to forcing people to spend money to take a sightseeing bus. In early November 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter sat on a villager&#39;s motorcycle and visited less than 10 scenic spots, which took more than 3 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scenic spot was temporarily closed in June 2022, the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, &quot;seven fairies&quot; and &quot;emperors and generals&quot; were left in the barren mountains and ridges without anyone. Take care of it and live next to wind, rain, weeds, insects and ants. When Southern Weekend reporters visited the scenic spot, they only met two or three villagers in the scenic spot. The local villagers did not embark on the road to wealth. Instead, they were owed many years of land rent. Now the villagers are re-cultivation in many places in the scenic area and have planted rapeseed, a local cash crop. They said that this year, rapeseed can be sold for 3 yuan per pound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, an aerial photo was taken of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, aerial photography was taken of the ancient famous scenic spot in the world. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The ticket office, offices, commercial street shops, etc. in the scenic area were all in a mess. Doors, windows, tables and cabinets were smashed, and the floor was littered with scattered documents and broken glass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to arrears in land rent and project payments, &quot;Gumingtianxia&quot; has more than 80 million yuan in outstanding financing. Under the promotion of the scenic area promoters, perhaps investors believe that the scenic area has a bright future. Southern Weekend reporters learned from multiple judgments and on-site construction personnel that the investors attracted by the scenic spot tend to be older. Some retired men were defrauded of 210,000 yuan to buy &quot;health products&quot; and then invested tens of thousands more yuan in scenic spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/cdcad5f48d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cdcad5f48d .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scenes of abandoned scenic spots were spread through the Internet, attracting some explorers. It&#39;s just that all entrances to the scenic area are locked, and you have to overcome some difficulties to enter - climb over the wall at the main entrance, or get in through a patch of weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local villagers sometimes gather outside the main entrance of the scenic spot to chat. They are used to strange visitors with curiosity, and they will always kindly persuade: &quot;The above Nothing to see.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a local resident rode a motorcycle past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, one Local residents rode motorcycles past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都警方：陈某杰涉嫌开设赌场罪，已被依法执行逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261063]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 12:47:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;@ Chengdu Dujiangyan Public Security Bureau issued the &quot;Police Notice&quot; on November 22: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, our bureau found that Chen Moujie (male, 39 years old) was suspected of opening a casino. Currently, Chen Moujie has been arrested in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Related reports&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Douyu issued an announcement stating that the company’s CEO, Mr. Chen Shaojie, was arrested by Chengdu police around November 16, 2023. . The company has not received any formal notification of the investigation into Mr. Chen or the reasons for Mr. Chen’s apparent arrest. Mr. Chen&#39;s continued detention and any subsequent related legal proceedings and enforcement actions against relevant parties could have a material adverse effect on the Company&#39;s reputation, business and results of operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川这个倒闭的景区总长19公里的游览路线埋藏了多少荒诞感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261045]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 12:18:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 12:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有见过需要那么多雕塑的”：四川达州古名天下景区烂尾调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261047]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 11:34:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; are famous all over the world in ancient times. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; The ancient world-famous &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot;. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County in Sichuan Province was once the county with the largest number of people who have not been lifted out of poverty, apart from the national and provincial poverty-stricken counties in Sichuan. There is a scenic spot in the mountains here, spanning three counties and three towns, with a planned area of ​​15.3 square kilometers, equivalent to the size of 15 Forbidden City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is known as &quot;the only imperial cultural area in the world&quot; and includes nearly 2,000 statues, including nearly 500 portraits of emperors and generals, thousands of imitation &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, and more than 3 meters high. Images such as &quot;Seven Fairies&quot; and &quot;Eight Immortals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was not completed. No one cared about it for many years. The statue gradually peeled off and faded, disappearing in the grass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2021, someone asked on the official website of &quot;Ask Politics in Sichuan&quot;: &quot;The ancient Fengdian Town in Zhongjiang, Sichuan is famous all over the world. What is the reason why it has not been completed for many years?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fengdian Town is famous all over the world. The town government responded in November that the capital chain of the scenic spot builder was broken, with about 28 million yuan in arrears in project payments and more than 80 million yuan in arrears in financing, involving more than 2,700 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more surprising is that the judgment document website states that the legal representative of the developer was sentenced at the end of 2019 for illegally occupying agricultural land for the construction of a scenic spot. While he was on probation, he was still actively soliciting investment. In June 2022, the scenic spot announced its temporary closure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How was such a behemoth built? Who is responsible for its failure? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses from Sichuan&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area is affiliated to Deyang City. According to promotional materials, the project was launched in 2014 with a total planned investment of approximately 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its location is relatively remote, more than an hour&#39;s drive from the center of Deyang and surrounding cities, such as Chengdu and Guanghan. Drive from the Fengdian section exit of Zhongjiang County on the Hurong Expressway and turn right. You will see 9 golden bull elephant sculptures, which are the main entrance of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The tour loop is 19 kilometers long. Welcome to take the sightseeing bus.&quot; A line of golden characters at the main entrance reminds tourists of the scale of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance is built in imitation of ancient city walls, with couplets in red letters on a gold background hanging on both sides: North, south, east, west, there is no other place in the world, but this place has existed in the world throughout the ages. After the scenic spot was temporarily closed, the gates were locked and items in the ticket room were smashed. Nearby villagers gather under the &quot;golden elephant&quot; to chat, and occasionally give directions to curious tourists from out of town. &quot;You can climb over the wall.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beside the Jade Dragon Gate at the entrance of the scenic spot, the Fengdian Town Government posted a notice in March 2023, warning tourists not to enter the scenic spot in any way, because the current infrastructure is incomplete and there are major safety risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone opened a trail from the left side of Jade Dragon Gate. If you walk forward for a few minutes against the weeds more than 1 meter high, you will see a statue of an emperor more than 2 meters high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The statue of the emperor in the grass. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;259128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A statue of an emperor in the grass. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three Sovereigns and Five Emperors are making CALL online. Qin Emperor and Han Wu invite you to point out the country together.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion, there are nearly 500 statues here, including Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty, Wu Zetian, Taizu of the Song Dynasty, etc. The emperors of modernization also include the leaders of the &quot;Five Hus and Sixteen Kingdoms&quot; and the &quot;Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hong Hai participated in the construction of about 100 emperor statues from the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty and stayed in the scenic spot for more than two months. He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters on the phone that the developer was inspired by &quot;Pictures of Emperors of the Past&quot; by Yan Liben, a painter from the Tang Dynasty, and wanted to present the emperors of the past dynasties in the form of sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statue is placed in a cement field called &quot;Chinese Historical Process Park&quot;. The scenic spot hopes to allow tourists to appreciate five thousand years of Chinese culture by displaying the emperor&#39;s style and introducing his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if tourists look carefully, they will laugh. For example, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty Yang You (605-619) only lived 15 years old, but the statue of Yang You in the scenic area has a thick long beard and wrinkles on his face, making him look like a mature uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The text introduction is not rigorous enough. For example, in the introduction to Song Taizu, &quot;Zhao Kuangyin practiced martial arts when he was young, and first joined Guo Wei, Taizu of the Northern Zhou Dynasty. Later, he followed Chai Rong, Emperor Shizong of the Zhou Dynasty, to fight in various places, and made many military exploits. There were commanders and envoys in front of the palace, and he mastered ice boxing.&quot; Not only is the sentence incomplete, it also contains typos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Hong Hai said that he and his team were not involved in the coloring and text introduction of the statue. The appearance of the emperor was also built based on the drawings provided by the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that the raw materials of these imperial statues are mainly steel bars and cement, which are cheaper than copper. He did not disclose the total price, citing commercial confidentiality. Due to lack of maintenance and management, hundreds of emperors are now living with dead grass. Under the sun and rain, the acrylic paint on many statues has faded, exposing gray cement, and steel bars are also exposed at the joints of the bases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far from the emperor&#39;s statue, nearly a thousand &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are quietly guarding in the mud. These &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; imitate armored warrior warriors, wearing battle uniforms, armor, and hair tied in high buns. However, compared with the various terracotta warriors and horses in the Qin Shihuang Mausoleum in Xi&#39;an, the &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses Sichuan&quot; are rough in workmanship, lack details in their expressions and costumes, and are weak in momentum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot once attracted tourists with the gimmick that &quot;you can see the Terracotta Warriors and Horses without leaving Sichuan&quot;. Now these replicas are surrounded by moss and wild grass on the edge of the mountain forest, and some have white thatch inserted into their hands. &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot;, who was wearing a dragon robe, had a red ribbon &quot;praying for peace&quot; wrapped around his bun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a sign under the feet of &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot; that reads: &quot;No destruction of property!&quot; However, due to no one taking care of them, these imitations have faded and have cracks in many places. Some &quot;Kneeling Shooting Figurines&quot; were cut off at the waist, and many &quot;Warrior Figurines&quot; lost their arms and even their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early November 2023, Southern Weekend reporters also saw giant sculptures placed in scenic spots such as Seven Fairies, Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea, Mother Earth, Chang&#39;e Flying to the Moon, Queens of the Four Seasons, and Zhuzi Square. They are three to four meters high, but the workmanship is rough when seen up close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity, there are more than 20 scenic spots in the scenic area, such as the Drunken Concubine, the Sifang Wealth Saint, the Yue Laotai, the Nine Fox Fairy Cave, and the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl. &quot;Their huge lineup and magnificent momentum are truly unmatched throughout the ages. Unparalleled.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making emperor statues for Gu Ming Tian Xia, Hong Hai saw the terracotta warriors and horses and other statues being moved into the scenic spot. He has been engaged in the sculpture industry for nearly 20 years and lamented, &quot;I have never seen anything that requires so many sculptures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity of the scenic spot, the ancient name of the world is based on the five thousand years of Chinese civilization as the core theme, integrating the Chinese cultural story line into the natural ecology and cultural landscape, allowing the story to connect, empower and cast the soul of the landscape. Thus forming an internal logical connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Driving local people to get rich&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Developers came to this town in 2014. According to (2019) Sichuan 0623 Xingchu No. 409 Judgment, on March 7, 2014, Sichuan Gumingtianxia Investment Management Co., Ltd. signed an investment cooperation framework agreement with the Fengdian Town Government of Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County is a major agricultural county in the hilly areas of Sichuan. The food crops grown are mainly rice, rapeseed and wheat. Fengdian Town under its jurisdiction is also a typical remote agricultural town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia Investment Company will invest 370 million yuan to build a new wintersweet viewing base and agricultural tourism project in Fengdian Town. The Fengdian Town Government agrees to provide its company with the land for this project within the ownership and land scope of Huangping Village and Hejia Village Committees. The area shall be based on the lease area signed between the company and the village, but it shall not change the land without authorization. Nature of land use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the investment cooperation framework agreement obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, the two parties also agreed that Gumingtianxia Investment Company should register and establish a Zhongjiang branch within the jurisdiction of Zhongjiang County. After the project is completed and put into operation, taxes will be paid in the territory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 21, 2014, Zhou Lizhu registered and established Sichuan Guming Tianxia Tourism Development Co., Ltd. in the name of her daughter Zhou Xiaxia (in 2016, the legal representative became Zhou Lizhu, hereinafter referred to as &quot; &quot;Anciently Famous&quot;), with a registered capital of 100 million yuan, and Zhou Lizhu holds 100% of the shares. The registered address of Gu Ming Tian Xia is No. 5, Huangping Village, Fengdian Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance of the scenic spot is built in Huangping Village. Southern Weekend reporters learned from many Huangping Village villagers that rents in scenic spots range from 400 yuan/mu/year to 1,000 yuan/mu/year. One villager said that the land on the mountain was basically unable to grow food and was originally abandoned with no income. The scenic spot also hired local people to do cleaning, maintenance and other work, providing some jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot also mentioned in its publicity that it will &quot;drive local people to become rich.&quot; The economy of Zhongjiang County is relatively backward. Information disclosed by the Sichuan Provincial Poverty Alleviation and Immigration Bureau shows that there were 92,500 poor people in Zhongjiang County in 2014. From 2011 to 2014, the province allocated 65.642 million yuan in special financial poverty alleviation funds for Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investment cooperation framework agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia plans to invest 370 million yuan, and the project construction period will be 4 years and will be completed at the end of December 2018. After completion, it can achieve annual sales revenue of 200 million yuan and tax revenue of 20 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Lizhu is from Dazhou, Sichuan Province. Local media in Dazhou reported his story twice. In 1980, Zhou Lizhu worked as a cashier in a mining company in Dazhou, earning more than 60 yuan a month. But he felt &quot;so tired&quot; that he resigned after five months and set up a leather factory. Zhou Lizhu was only 17 years old at the time and was called the &quot;Doll Factory Manager&quot; by her 10 workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mr. Zhou Lizhu, who has been in business for a long time, has a heroic spirit between his brows, and his beard makes his outline more subtle and elegant.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion article, Zhou Lizhu has since He has worked in communication equipment, steel manufacturing, real estate, tourism and other industries, and has also studied in the EMBA class of Xiamen University and Peking University Guanghua School of Management. However, according to the verdict, Zhou Lizhu only had a junior high school education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to &quot;well-known entrepreneur&quot;, another label attached to Zhou Lizhu is &quot;philanthropist&quot;. According to the &quot;Dazhou Evening News&quot; report, Zhou Lizhu once used part of Gumingtianxia&#39;s operating income to establish the &quot;Love Weekly Special Fund&quot;. In October 2015, he donated 200 cherry blossom saplings worth 100,000 yuan to his hometown of Dazhu County, Dazhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It took four years of construction before it was found to be illegal&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhongjiang County Government website, in August 2016, the first phase of the Gumingtianxia project was registered, and the scenic area is planned to cover an area of ​​about 3,000 acres. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an investor, Southern Weekend reporters obtained the registration notice for the scenic spot’s corporate investment project from Gumingtianxia’s investment recruiters. The project name is “Gumingtianxia Sightseeing and Tourism Project—Planting Base and Historical, Cultural and Leisure Plaza” Construction Project&quot;, with a total planned investment of 180 million yuan, and the source of funds will be self-raised funds. The planned land area is 2,400 acres, and the construction area of ​​the main buildings is 10,000 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction content includes a planting base, office building, visitor center, exhibition hall, cultural and leisure square and ancillary facilities. The scale of products and services is to plant 100,000 balengang crabapples and wintersweet plants each year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registration notice shall be stamped by the Zhongjiang County Development and Reform Bureau. According to the remarks, the project unit can handle environmental protection, urban planning, land use, construction permit and other procedures in accordance with the law based on the notice. Construction of projects with incomplete relevant procedures shall not begin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice is valid for one year. During the validity period, if there are important changes (including changes in the project investment entity, construction location, main construction content, product technical solutions, and the expected change in the total investment or construction scale of the project by more than 20%, etc.), the project unit should apply for re- Filing. In October 2016, Gumingtianxia applied for re-registration, and the original planned land use of 2,400 acres was changed to 3,590.5 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another document obtained by Southern Weekend reporters showed that in August 2016, the Zhongjiang County Tourism Bureau sent a letter to Gu Ming Tian Xia, &quot;In principle, we agree that your company will invest in the development of Gu Ming Tian Xia Tourism in Fengdian Town.&quot; Tourism &#39;Project&#39;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fourth year of signing the contract, the scenic spot was found to have illegally occupied agricultural land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned judgment stated that, “In addition to planting wintersweet, crabapple and other agricultural planting projects on the rented land, the company also carried out agricultural projects from 2014 to 2018 without obtaining any construction land approval documents and procedures. During the year, the use nature of the original leased land was changed and construction projects were started.&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, through the appraisal led by the former Deyang City Land and Resources Bureau and Zhongjiang County Forest Public Security Bureau, the scenic spot involved the occupation of damaged cultivated land. The area is 140.1595 acres, involving an occupied forest area of ​​18,360 square meters (approximately 27.54 acres). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two parts of the area actually account for a very small proportion in the scenic spot, accounting for approximately 4.67% of the registered planned land area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2019, the Zhongjiang County People’s Court sentenced Gu Mingtianxia to the crime of illegal occupation of agricultural land and was fined 50,000 yuan; Zhou Lizhu was sentenced to two years and six months in prison, suspended for three years, and fined Ten thousand yuan in gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past four years involving illegal construction, the scenic spot has still received support from the local government many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the public account of the scenic spot, in February 2016, the then Secretary of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee brought an inspection team to the scenic spot for guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Zhongjiang County Government, on August 9, 2016, the former deputy county magistrate presided over the Gumingtianxia project construction promotion meeting and listened to the project planning unit’s status report, the project investor’s construction plan report and related Opinions and suggestions from department heads. The meeting requested that relevant departments should work together to coordinate and solve problems existing in project construction to ensure the smooth progress of the construction project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing, one of the original managers of the scenic spot, told Southern Weekend reporters that the scenic spot did not clearly occupy basic farmland at the beginning of its construction. &quot;If he (the government) does not agree, does he dare to touch the land?&quot; Liao Xing said. Since 2014, she has followed Zhou Lizhu to work in Gumingtianxia, ​​mainly responsible for project management. After being owed wages, she resigned in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2017, the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Protection of Cultivated Land and Improving the Balance of Acquisition and Compensation&quot; to implement the strictest cultivated land protection system. According to the official website of the Sichuan Provincial Department of Land and Resources in September 2018, the Deyang Municipal Land and Resources Bureau paid close attention to the protection of cultivated land. In that year, the city carried out 685 dynamic inspections, discovered and stopped 10 land violations, and filed 4 cases for investigation and punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing and the above-mentioned investment personnel said that after Gu Mingtianxia and Zhou Lizhu were sentenced and paid fines, the local government had adjusted the basic farmland and forestland occupied by the scenic spot into general land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity materials of the scenic spot, on April 10, 2020, members of the Standing Committee of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, Director of the County Culture and Tourism Bureau, and Deputy Director of the County Natural Resources Bureau visited the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Spot to guide the work and provide opinions. Or suggest that Zhou Lizhu and others accompany him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Twenty million is owed to build the scenic spot&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2015, the construction team began to enter the site. However, the construction of the scenic spot was carried out illegally at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A judgment shows that in August 2015, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd. signed a contract with Gumingtianxia, ​​agreeing to undertake the construction of anti-corrosion cabin projects for office buildings, hotels, and commercial streets in scenic spots. However, because Gu Ming Tianxia did not obtain the approval procedures for the construction of the office building, the competent authorities prohibited the construction, and Chongqing Jingwu Industrial immediately stopped the construction of the office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, the two parties signed a contract, agreeing to outsource the road pavement projects in the scenic area to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial. After June 2019, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial completed the roadbed construction, but because Gumingtianxia did not provide construction drawings and did not connect electricity for construction, it was unable to continue to complete the road pavement construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong was once one of the management members of the scenic spot. He told Southern Weekend reporters that because the scenic spot is a tourism project for investment promotion by the local government, the policy may be more liberal and construction will start first. He wants to build it first and then build it later. formalities. At present, Wang Rong is still owed about 100,000 yuan in salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong admitted that the scenic spot violated the relevant regulations on temporary land use at the beginning of its construction. &quot;There is no planning or construction report.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Gumingtianxia is facing a shortage of funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned judgment, in October 2016, Guming Tianxia issued an IOU to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial and admitted that it owed 2.6158 million yuan in project payment and 100,000 yuan in deposit. After returning the deposit, Gu Mingtianxia has been in arrears with the project payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from many construction parties that they had agreed with Gumingtianxia to &quot;advance funds first and then settle the settlement.&quot; Li Chengwu, a native of Sichuan, is in his fifties and has been in this business for more than 30 years, mainly contracting earthwork construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He saw that Zhou Lizhu had two companies under his name and thought he was quite strong. By the end of 2016, Li Chengwu calculated the accounts and found that the advance amount had reached nearly 5 million yuan. At this time, Zhou Lizhu still couldn&#39;t get the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Chinese New Year approached, Jiang Tao, who was in charge of the infrastructure project, and Yang Tinghong, who was doing the green sandstone paving project, also went to Zhou Lizhu to settle the bill, but they couldn&#39;t get their money back either. Zhou Lizhu&#39;s arrears to them were 2.9 million and 270,000 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Li Chengwu and others began to report the situation to the government. On September 1, 2017, at the Zhongjiang County Labor and Social Security Bureau, Gu Mingtianxia promised that Li Chengwu would pay off the project payment before August 30, 2018. After Zhou Lizhu signed, she wrote the word &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Li Chengwu and others belong to the &quot;Ancient Debt Collection Group&quot; with 88 people, including construction teams for landscaping, door and window guardrails, hardened roads, and paving bluestone in scenic spots. In November 2023, a boss who made doors and windows for scenic spots compiled statistics in the group. At least 22 construction teams were owed a total of about 20 million yuan in project payments, wages and deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many construction team bosses told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why construction teams continued to enter the site in 2017 was because Gu Ming Tian Xia’s quotations were 5% to 10% higher than the market price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Judgment Documents Network, since the second half of 2017, construction parties have successively sued Zhou Lizhu and Gu Mingtianxia, ​​and won the lawsuit. Several plaintiffs applied for compulsory execution, but the court was unable to find any property or property clues in the name of the person subject to execution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the construction company, but also the villagers of Huangping Village, Fengdian Town, have been unable to get the rent from the scenic spot since about 2017. The investment promotion personnel of the above-mentioned scenic spots said that about 90% of the scenic spots are built in Fengdian Town, and so far the land rent arrears is about 9 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;This scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is the ancient world always short of money? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the verdict, Gu Ming Tianxia initially planned to invest 370 million yuan in Fengdian Town. However, according to the publicity of the scenic spot, the total planned investment is about 3.1 billion yuan, and the scenic spot will be constructed in four phases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He did many things, including running a leather factory, selling steel products, selling communications, and also did crowdfunding.” Qiu Song, a Dazhou native and a fellow villager of Zhou Lizhu, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Zhou Lizhu Lizhu &quot;crowdfunded&quot; a sum of money to start a company in Dazhou, and then went to Fengdian to build a scenic spot. Qiu Song built the steel frame structure for the scenic spot and is now owed about 1 million yuan by Gumingtianxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Dazhou native took Zhou Lizhu to court in 2018. According to the judgment, since December 2013, Zhou Lizhu borrowed a total of 1.2 million yuan from the plaintiff&#39;s father and used three houses in Tongchuan District, Dazhou City to pay off the debt. However, the plaintiff discovered that the owner of the mortgaged property was not Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also heard from Zhou Lizhu that he had a real estate development project in Dazhou. In order to collect debts, Li Chengwu went to the prefecture several times to look for Zhou Lizhu&#39;s property. &quot;Later I found out that he was deceived. He had no projects in Dazhou to draw money from.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also went to Hainan because Zhou Lizhu claimed that there were 16 suites in a certain real estate in Sanya, which he could get. Several sets of money were paid to him. After he went there, he found that the person guarding the property was fellow Zhou Lizhu, and the property had nothing to do with Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong said that Zhou Lizhu once set up a financing company in Dazhou, financing money with 3 cents of interest and lending it to others at 5 cents or 8 cents. But later there were bad debts that could not be recovered, and he squandered some of them, resulting in arrears of hundreds of millions of yuan to investors. So Zhou Lizhu thought of setting up a scenic spot and claimed that all the financing funds had been invested in the construction of the scenic spot. &quot;Write a promise to those who owe money. The scenic spot will give you shares, and after the park opens, it will pay you dividends every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tear down the east wall to pay for the west wall, and the capital hole is getting bigger and bigger.&quot; Nanfang. Over the weekend, reporters learned from an official in Fengdian Town as an investor that Zhou Lizhu initially brought about 40 million yuan to build the scenic spot. After the money ran out, she went to Mianyang, Deyang, Suining, Chengdu, Nanchong and other places to raise funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that from 2017 to 2018, Zhou Lizhu registered companies related to Guming Tianxia in Deyang, Chengdu, Mianyang, and Suining. According to the Fengdian Town Government, Gu Ming Tianxia’s arrears in financing amounted to more than 80 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that he did not know the source of Zhou Lizhu’s funds. He mentioned that due to road construction, the scenic spot received a road subsidy of about 1 million yuan from the local government, but other than that, it did not enjoy other subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Tao, who is in charge of infrastructure projects, said that he saw two tourist buses parked in the scenic spot in 2017, and they were investors attracted by Gumingtianxia. &quot;Cheating the elderly out of their money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the judgment documents website, there are three judgments on private lending disputes related to Gu Ming Tianxia. The three judgments show that in March, May, and June 2019, Gu Mingtianxia borrowed 100,000, 10,000, and 100,000 from three people respectively, all promising an annual interest rate of 24%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the three plaintiffs are all older, and were 71, 60, and 63 years old respectively when they borrowed the money. Two of them are from Mianyang and one is from Deyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Blog China website, an investor who visited the scenic spot in October 2018 recorded the visit. At that time, the construction of the scenic spot was initially completed. The promoter said that the scenic spot was built solely by Zhou Lizhu. The original funds were sufficient. However, due to the continuous increase in raw material and labor prices in recent years, there was a gap in funds, so private funds were borrowed for the construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investor saw a retired man in his seventies investing 30,000 yuan at the scene. The old man had been defrauded of 210,000 yuan for buying &quot;health products.&quot; Seeing that the old man believed in Zhou Lizhu so much, the investor &quot;invested a little more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 13, 2019, Guming Tianxia also announced that it would be listed on the Tianfu (Sichuan) United Equity Trading Center with the code 610161. Tianfu Equity Exchange Center is a regional equity market operating institution that provides financing channels for small, medium and micro enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above three judgments, as of January 2020, Gumingtianxia failed to pay interest to the three plaintiffs as agreed, nor could it repay the principal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where did Zhou Lizhu spend her money? Liao Xing said that all the money was invested in the project. Not all of the project money was paid, but part of it was paid. For example, he said that excluding transportation and installation fees, the production cost of each emperor statue is about 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong said that before 2017, Gumingtianxia’s investment in the scenic spot did not exceed 5 million yuan. &quot;The government did not require capital verification at that time, and in the end he could not get out a penny.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu heard from Zhou Lizhu that the scenic spot was originally planned to open in May 2017. But it was not officially opened to the public until the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that the company’s capital chain was broken because the scenic spot was affected by the epidemic and stopped operating just after it opened, leaving no income. &quot;Roads were built, trees were planted, the projects were all placed there and they were not taken away.&quot; He felt that Zhou Lizhu was &quot;a person who wants to do things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong believed that Zhou Lizhu was using the scenic spot as a guise to make money outside and was not serious about developing the scenic spot. &quot;There is nothing inside except statues, and tourists will not come here a second time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing also had doubts about the development of the scenic spot. “The plan is indeed too big.” He once received other companies that came to visit the scenic spot, and they told him that in order to complete the planning of the scenic spot, at least another 1 billion yuan must be invested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses&quot;, Gumingtianxia originally planned to build a Zen medicine health and wellness ecological park, a low-altitude sports base, a Chinese history and culture study and travel base, a grand theater, an ancient Shaolin Temple and other attractions. Liao Xing said that the purpose of building a large scenic spot is to retain tourists staying overnight. Only when tourists stay there can the income be high. However, until the scenic spot closed, Gumingtianxia had not yet built a hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the scenic spot is not very attractive to tourists. In the East Square, Southern Weekend reporters saw several discarded tickets, priced at 98 yuan. There are 20 reviews of the scenic spot on Dianping. Most of them complain about the high fees, &quot;a bunch of fake sculptures in barren mountains and mountains&quot; and &quot;a waste of time and money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;There are thousands of imitation terracotta warriors and horses here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/22/67491062de.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22 /67491062de.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are thousands of imitation &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;While on probation, he is still running around&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the three years of probation, Zhou Lizhu is still soliciting investment. The Fengdian Town Government stated in November 2021 that it was actively urging Gumingtianxia investors to raise funds and finance from various sources to resolve the debt problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the scenic spot’s promotion, in December 2020, Zhou Lizhu signed a strategic cooperation agreement with the Chengdu Tourism Association Travel Agency Branch on behalf of the scenic spot at the 2020 China (Sichuan) Tourist Attractions and Cultural and Creative Industry Innovation and Development Expo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I must do everything possible to repay your funds as soon as possible.&quot; At the beginning of 2022, Zhou Lizhu wrote a letter to investment members. The letter mentioned that in response to the issue of &quot;expiration of investment member contracts&quot;, under the guidance of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, County People&#39;s Government and relevant superior departments, the company is vigorously promoting investment promotion and adopting a combination of project implantation cooperation + equity cooperation. Mode increases hematopoietic function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the scenic spot announced its temporary closure. In July, Li Chengwu went to the office to find Zhou Lizhu and saw him talking to two or three investors in the reception room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The office of Gumingtianxia is located in the courtyard-style &quot;Guming Courtyard&quot;. When Southern Weekend reporters visited the &quot;Ancient Courtyard&quot; in early November 2023, the office was already empty. The yellowed and wrinkled leaflets of the scenic spot were blown to the corners along with the fallen leaves by the wind and rain. There were sheep dung and insect corpses everywhere on the ground. It looked like the yard had been abandoned for a while. The reception room, financial room and other office areas were in a mess. Overturned office cabinets, broken glass and scattered papers showed signs of fierce conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the foot of &quot;Queen of Four Seasons&quot; is another office location that is famous all over the world. Nowadays, there are renderings of the scenic spot and a calligraphy painting of &quot;Swallowing Mountains and Rivers&quot; hanging indoors. Dust, sheep dung, and corpses of insects and ants are everywhere. There was probably a conflict here. The jewelry cabinet that originally contained sterling silver bracelets and natural Gobi red agate was broken, and the empty jewelry box and price tag fell to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhongjiang County Government website, on the morning of July 23, 2022, members of the Standing Committee of the County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, and Chairman of the County Federation of Trade Unions went to Fengdian Town to hold an on-site coordination meeting for the &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; petition stabilization work. The County Public Security Bureau Bureau, County Culture and Tourism Bureau, County Natural Resources Bureau, County Economic and Foreign Affairs Bureau and other departments jointly participated in the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September of the same year, news about Zhou Lizhu appeared for the last time on the public account of the scenic spot. In his Mid-Autumn Festival message, he continued to convey to the outside world the company&#39;s determination to move forward, saying that it would &quot;fight the tough battle of attracting investment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official account of the scenic spot left an investment phone number, and the contact person told Southern Weekend reporters that he was mainly responsible for updating the official account of the scenic spot and marketing. He had helped receive interested investors, but he had not met &quot;sincere investors&quot;. big investors”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The investment in tourist attractions is large and the return cycle is very slow. If the natural endowment is average, it is difficult to find investors. Other scenic spots have also gone bankrupt. They have no hematopoietic function and the profit model is unclear. Sooner or later, they will go bankrupt. Things.&quot; The contact claimed to have resigned at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from multiple creditors that Zhou Lizhu was admitted to the hospital at the end of 2022. Zhou Lizhu was 56 years old at the time. But Wang Rong believed that Zhou Lizhu had faked the news to avoid debts. On November 11, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter called Zhou Lizhu’s mobile phone number, and the other party denied that she was Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned scenic spot investment personnel and Fengdian Town officials, the scenic spot has not yet found a buyer. In early November 2023, the area near the &quot;Chang&#39;e Flying to the Moon&quot; statue at the entrance of the scenic spot and on both sides of the main entrance have been re-cultivated, and villagers have planted rows of rapeseed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ At the request of the interviewees, Hong Hai, Wang Rong, and Liao Xing are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>