<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[2023年诺贝尔文学奖：约恩·福瑟并非冷门，残雪还有机会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 11:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/6SLqu56bYMVGFKaptupGjpsMsb4T0JCGTjxPcXep.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6SLqu56bYMVGFKaptupGjpsMsb4T0JCGTjxPcX ep. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 2023 Nobel Prize winner in Literature, Norwegian writer Jorn Fosse. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is Jon Fosse? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of the announcement of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Literature, because Chinese writer Can Xue ranked first in relevant odds on the Nicer Odds website, many readers expected her to win the prize. At 19:00 on October 5, Beijing time, the winner was announced, Can Xue lost. But this does not mean that the odds have no reference value. In fact, Norwegian writer Jon Fother ranks second after Can Xue on this odds list. Unlike Gurner, the 2021 winner, Fauser is not an unpopular choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than 100-year history of the Nobel Prize for Literature, only 17 female writers have won the prize, and 8 of them won the prize in the 21st century, including the American female poet Glück in 2020 and French female writer Ernault in 2022. Undoubtedly, the Swedish Academy, which has been questioned by public opinion, is turning its attention more and more to outstanding female authors. Therefore, Can Xue still has a good chance of winning this award in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The citation for the award was &quot;for his innovative plays and essays that give voice to the ineffable&quot;. Fosse&#39;s award &quot;quite reasonably follows the tradition of the Nobel Prize in Literature not forgetting outstanding playwrights, from Maeterlinck, Shaw, and Beckett to Dario Foe, Pinter, and Handke. It is quite brilliant. Even more convincing than the list of novelists,&quot; poet and critic Liao Weitang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eon Fosse is one of the most famous figures in contemporary theater and a popular candidate for the Nobel Prize in recent years. His works also cover poetry, novels, essays, children&#39;s literature and translations. Fother&#39;s plays have been staged thousands of times around the world, including &quot;The Girl on the Sofa&quot; in China in 2004 and &quot;One Summer&quot; produced by the Shanghai Dramatic Art Center. Fosse once watched his own play &quot;Somebody&#39;s Coming&quot; in Shanghai and felt that it was one of the best stage presentations of his work in the world, and he developed a respect for Chinese drama and Chinese culture. Fother&#39;s honors include the Scandinavian National Theater Award (2002), the Norwegian Arts Council Honor Award (2003), the Swedish Academy&#39;s Nordic Prize (2007), and the International Ibsen Prize (2010). ). The work &quot;New Title: Heptata 6-7&quot; was shortlisted for the 2022 International Booker Prize. Anders Olsen, chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature, said his works &quot;touch upon your deepest feelings, anxieties, insecurities, questions of life and death.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse was born in Haugesund on the west coast of Norway on September 29, 1959. He began his creative career at the age of twelve, which he calls &quot;ashamingly early&quot;. Fosse loved to play guitar and at one time was in a rock band. Translator Zou Lulu believes that &quot;his early musical experience brought a unique Fother-like color and style to his later writing - a strong sense of rhythm and musicality in his dramatic language.&quot; Since the late 1970s, Fosse has lived in Bergen, Norway&#39;s second largest city and the country&#39;s cultural capital. In recent years, he has also gone to southern France and Austrian towns on the outskirts of Vienna to write. Fosse is very energetic and often starts writing at four or five o&#39;clock in the afternoon and works until nine o&#39;clock the next morning. When asked if he had any advice for writing, he said: &quot;Write, don&#39;t think! Think before you write, think after you finish, but don&#39;t think about anything while writing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About En Fauser&#39;s earliest reading memory is a small book. In the book, a major felt that his town needed a fire truck, and then he and some citizens built it. It looked more like what children built out of wood. Car. “I used wood to build cars when I was a kid,” Fosse said. He admired Trakl, Kafka and Beckett, and at the same time, Beckett was an important object of &quot;resistance&quot; when he wrote dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse uses a rare language, &quot;New Norwegian&quot;. Even in Norway, which has a population of only more than five million, its speakers only account for one-tenth of the total population. Fortunately, New Norwegian can be easily understood by Norwegian, Swedish, and Danish speakers. But it is with the help of translation that Fosse&#39;s works are known to more readers. Currently, his books have been translated into more than forty languages. At first, he only wanted to write poems and novels. In 1993, he was invited to write his first script because he was short of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are John Fother&#39;s drama selections &quot;Somebody&#39;s Coming&quot; and &quot;Autumn Dreams&quot; published by Shanghai Translation Publishing House. Wenjing is about to publish &quot;Trilogy&quot;, one of Fosse&#39;s masterpiece novels. This work won the Nordic Council Literary Award in 2015 and demonstrates his cold, solemn and concise epic style. The novel contains three closely connected parts: &quot;Awakening&quot;, &quot;Olav&#39;s Dream&quot; and &quot;Tiredness&quot;. The story begins with the young lovers Asle and Alida leaving their hometown for Björgven (the city of Bergen). Alida is about to give birth, but the couple has difficulty finding a place to live. They later found a place to live and gave birth to a son, Sigvald, who began to adopt different names, Olav and Åsta. But someone recognized Asler, and it was very clear that Asler and Alida seemed to be carrying murder cases, although Asler might have acted out of helplessness. Asler was eventually hanged. In the last part, the story time advances to the life of Asler and Alida&#39;s daughter Ales. By this time Ales is already an old woman. She recalls her sister who died young and herself. His brother Sigvald left him when he was young...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wan, the editor-in-chief of &quot;Trilogy&quot;, is a young writer and translator. In her opinion, John Fother&#39;s After the work was introduced to China, it has not attracted widespread attention from readers, and even senior readers rarely know about him. &quot;Fosse is not an issue-oriented writer. He has very consistently inherited the Nordic expressionist drama tradition. His language is concise and full of tension. His profound depiction of the character&#39;s spirit and his analysis of the relationship between people have reached a very high level. He will not write about trivial daily life, but pay attention to people&#39;s mental state.&quot; Li Wan told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The protagonist of Fosse&#39;s work is somewhat similar to himself. He is an alcoholic. He has some mental problems and has many extreme fringe experiences. He faces his own heart very directly and exposes himself. He is a writer who can share with others the most helpless side of a person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;With this, At the same time, Jon Fother has developed a unique style of writing. Periods are rarely used. A sentence is often very, very long. He uses many commas to connect it, giving people the feeling that the inner monologue is constantly rolling forward. This may not be the case. Due to the sensitivity of a playwright, he brings dramatic elements into the novel. In addition, he will use some repetitive sentences in different parts of the novel, but this repetition is not exactly the same, but changes with the changing context and the change of words. Subtle changes produce variations and variations, bringing a rhythm that is cyclical and constantly advancing,&quot; Li Wan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被上司“甩锅”怎么办？当首先秉直做好自己的分内事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Complaining about your boss in the workplace is a long-lasting and endless &quot;program&quot;. Regarding the question &quot;What is the most shameless sentence you have ever heard from a manager?&quot;, some netizens&#39; answers resonated: A subordinate proposed a plan, and the leader said it was no good and must be modified according to his wishes. The subordinate insisted, and the leader was angry, &quot;Listen to me. That’s fine.” There was a problem with the implementation of the leader&#39;s revised plan. The leader went to his subordinates and said, &quot;Why didn&#39;t you insist on it in the first place? You should insist on what you think is right. You have to find a way to convince me. You have no opinion at all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&quot;Why don&#39;t you persuade me properly?&quot; In essence, this sentence represents a kind of shirk of responsibility. Isn&#39;t there a saying, &quot;The merit is for oneself, the fault is for others&quot;, which refers to this kind of person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of leader is indeed the kind that easily arouses public anger. It is clear that his subordinates have opinions but their opinions are &quot;beaten to death&quot;, and they still say that others have no opinions, which is simply a hooliganism. But it’s not too weird, because he at least hinted that the subordinate’s original plan was correct, and it is extremely difficult for a leader to admit this. Leaders who do things like this are really rare nowadays. Leaders who shirk responsibility will not do it so obviously and without skills, because it is impossible to sit in this position with such a simple and crude IQ. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A situation a little more &quot;shameless&quot; than this was mentioned by a netizen: Under normal circumstances, the leader will tell you that you have messed up such a good plan of mine, how to implement it? of? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This sentence really impressed me. Yes, some leaders have this tone and taste. They are &quot;always reasonable&quot; in front of their subordinates. But this is not the best of &quot;pass-and-pass leadership&quot;. The real best is that he never says what his plan is, he just asks you to implement it, and then keeps making changes. Such leaders are either unpredictable and disdainful of mediocre plans, or they are extremely poor and like to &quot;hide their clumsiness&quot; while using their subordinates as &quot;guinea pigs&quot; for plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latter situation is not uncommon in reality. To put it bluntly, some people get into important management positions without knowing how, and then start a happy life of being guided by laypeople. To be honest, I&#39;m most afraid of this. If a lay leader values ​​your talent and ability and therefore chooses to respect your plan, that&#39;s not bad. The worst thing is that he doesn&#39;t know how to pretend to understand and is stubborn and uses a lot of jokes to explain &quot; Management wisdom&quot; to force subordinates to &quot;obey&quot;. When I was young, I encountered bosses who would always say, &quot;You just need to be obedient.&quot; Ninety-nine percent of those who advocate &quot;obedience and learning&quot; are ambitious and talented bosses who love to pretend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relatively speaking, a leader who is &quot;overbearing&quot; but can handle things and take responsibility is much better. Those leaders who want to show leadership authority but have no structure are just &quot;dwarf&quot; leaders. The reason why they dare not take responsibility or take responsibility is because of selfishness and face. They do not have the courage to admit that they are inferior to their subordinates and are jealous of their talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that management is an art. There is nothing wrong with this, but one thing should be added: management must first be about human touch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What follows is what should subordinates do in the face of the aforementioned leaders who love to shirk their responsibilities? In other words, where is the boundary of responsibility between superiors and subordinates in the workplace? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In any unit, superiors and subordinates are the &quot;community of goals&quot;. Considering that most units adopt a project responsibility system, superiors and subordinates should be of one mind, be capable, and be wise. Out of wisdom, in short, judging by talent. But in reality, this kind of situation is rare. In many cases, the game and internal friction between superiors and subordinates fill the time and space of a unit, which is suffocating and sighing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, although the &quot;pass-through leader&quot; bears the greatest responsibility, is there no way for subordinates to reflect on it? it&#39;s not true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a unit, there are always the most &quot;honest people&quot;. They often just want to do things well and get paid on time. But if everything went so smoothly, there would be no such thing as &quot;workplace troubles.&quot; The biggest confusion a dutiful employee encounters is being blamed by his boss or even making things difficult for him. In this kind of environment, no matter what you do, it won&#39;t be satisfactory. Just looking at the leader&#39;s face every day is enough. In this regard, many people&#39;s bad emotions inevitably accumulate in their hearts, and there seems to be no other way except to find reliable people to complain about from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it’s useless to complain behind your back. If the leader can’t hear it, won’t it end up being scattered in the wind? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as a subordinate, after encountering a strange leader, you are not just helpless and let others &quot;abuse&quot; you, but you can deal with it according to the actual situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a matter or a plan, if subordinates are not assigned responsibilities and bear the final consequences, it goes without saying that under normal circumstances, just listen to the leader. If you have a responsibility, it is your duty to do it well. If you do not do it well, you will bear the final consequences. Even if the leader puts forward opinions, they can only be used as a reference. If something is wrong, you will not blindly follow it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the &quot;ultimate person in charge&quot; of this matter is your boss, and you are just an executor, then when you encounter the leader making an obvious mistake, you can do it in two situations. The first is to persuade when necessary, state the interests and harms, and let the leader hear the correct point of view. As for whether the leader adopts it or not, the decision lies with the leader; the second is that if the leader is stubborn, he will not only be unable to listen to different opinions, but will even put forward opinions. If the behavior is not tolerated, then it would be uninteresting to stay in such a department. Instead of being blamed and taking the blame for a long time, it is better to consider changing departments - which is equivalent to changing the leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Persuading leaders is indeed risky. In the workplace, there are leaders who like to put small shoes on those who give opinions, but if you are a decent subordinate, why would you dare not to give opinions? Are you just worried about what your boss will think of you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago, when I was a middle-level cadre in a company, I often gave advice to my superiors, even arguing. Sometimes, my opinions are adopted, for example, to protect employees in my department from being punished indiscriminately; sometimes, my opinions are ignored, such as when the leader handles things unfairly in the elimination of the last place, resulting in people who should not leave. Being &quot;eliminated&quot; but refusing to correct his mistakes. This kind of nest had too much to worry about, and I felt uncomfortable. After careful consideration, I chose to leave. Although I lost some visible &quot;benefits&quot; as a result, I won the respect and understanding of those who knew me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, if a subordinate wants to have a good relationship with his superiors in work and life, and coordinate various affairs well, it is the basic principle to be neither humble nor arrogant, and to stick to the bottom line. Without this principle, the relationship between the two parties will inevitably be distorted. A person with a strong sense of right and wrong cannot really change the adverse effects caused by insisting on the correct position, nor can he be as &quot;well-rounded&quot; as some people, but he should still insist on being an upright and outspoken person. Otherwise, even if we have achieved &quot;maximization of interests&quot;, we have lost our bottom line and character. Can we still have a clear conscience? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[尹学芸：故乡是一枚爱人丨月是故乡明⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257348]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/21/09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Reading Yin Xueyun&#39;s &quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot; for the first time, readers may feel a little confused. His novels always &quot;talk right from the beginning, without any pretense&quot;, like green seedlings growing in the ground, simple and pretty, with a fresh earthy smell. A writer who is used to writing about villages, counties, officialdom, and wine shops, How did you come up with the idea of ​​writing an urban romance novel that looks like flowers in the fog? The 2021 novel collection of the same name includes several novellas such as &quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot;, &quot;Wanghu Tower&quot;, &quot;Feeding the Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Apple Tree&quot; and &quot;Faster Than the Wind&quot;. Continue reading, this &quot;strange&quot; novel The origins of the story are gradually revealed, and a Yin Xueyun familiar to old readers slowly emerges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The origin of Yin Xueyun’s writing is Jizhou in the northernmost part of Tianjin City&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (formerly known as Ji County before 2016) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. There is an artificial lake in the small town, which was once an important water source for Tianjin. In the past, people often fished, took boats, and swam in the lake, but in order to protect the water source, these projects were canceled and many buildings around the lake were demolished one by one. She walked along the lake when she had nothing to do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Hermit Seekers Are Not Encountered&quot; tells the story of two women, Xue Xiaoli and Su Mei, and a young man who went to an abandoned manor to search for her in &quot;pairs&quot; several times. The story of a reclusive master. The novel originated from an encounter with Yin Xueyun himself. During a stroll, she walked into an abandoned manor and saw different flowers and plants inside, as well as swings, a sports field, a fish pond, and a lake-view pavilion. The old luxury was clearly visible, and she even saw something familiar to her. man&#39;s inscription. There used to be many well-decorated sanatoriums in the small town. They were built by various departments in places close to mountains and rivers. It was difficult for ordinary people to enter, and they were later demolished. Such a manor could be hidden in the small Jizhou, and even the locals would find it difficult to find it. She guessed that this garden was also one of those sanatoriums. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159102&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are only a few scenes in the small town. One scene can be looked back and forth, guessed, and used. This secret manor has been written by Yin Xueyun in &quot;Wanghu Tower&quot; and &quot;Looking for the Lake&quot;. Hidden people are not seen&quot;. When it is prosperous, the garden is the Wanghu Tower where retired workers from the county town spend all their money to treat guests to a meal; when it is desolate, the garden has become an elusive place for veteran cadres who are walking in official steps with their hands behind their backs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It seems to be her writing instinct to repeatedly salvage, wash and chew her own life without wasting a grain of inspiration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; data-key= &quot;159097&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;From Hancun to Xuncheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Jizhou is the only semi-mountainous area in Tianjin. It is high in the north and low in the south. Mountains, plains, large depressions and reservoir areas gather here. The earliest history can be traced back to the Spring and Autumn Period. There is a poem in the Ming Dynasty that goes: &quot;When you come to the west to reach the end of the mountains, you will see the city of Jizhou.&quot; Life in the mountainous areas rarely changes, and people are not good at adapting. The characters in Yin Xueyun&#39;s works all have a persistent background. Color: Sisters Li Xun and Li Quan who persisted in love and pursued light in the war-torn years in &quot;The Wind and Dust&quot;, Feng Nuo who persisted in searching for her missing friend despite opposition in &quot;The Ballad of Cai Gen&quot;, and firmly believed in the power of the apple tree in &quot;The Apple Tree&quot; Suspicious Liu Ping... Some historians told Yin Xueyun that when the Qing army entered the Pass, the people of Ji County refused to surrender until death, and were massacred three times. The character of the people here was to be cruel, sluggish, and twisted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Jizhou is a place where obsession arises, and Yin Xueyun’s literature is also the fruit of persistence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some people went to visit Yin Xueyun’s village after reading her works, but were disappointed to find that the river was not that clear, the streets were not that long, and there were not always cows braying when entering the village. and fried grasshoppers. Yin Xueyun has actually seen these beauties, but the rare village she writes about is neither a peach blossom garden nor a foreign land where strange legends are born, but a place of life, with all kinds of villagers passing through, providing three meals a day. Running around and calculating, the relationships between people are intricate and intricate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;To be precise, the village where Yin Xueyun was born and raised is in the lowest depression in southern Jizhou, surrounded by water on three sides, with only one road on the south side. The &quot;Uncle Li Hai&quot; who won her the Lu Xun Literature Prize followed this road every year and came to &quot;my&quot; house empty-handed, bringing the family a glory that only existed in their imagination, and then loaded up with everything they had cobbled together. Food and supplies go back. The friendship that never returned lasted for more than 20 years and finally overdrawn. The family kept a secret about Uncle Li Hai. Only then did &quot;I&quot; know about the humiliating life history of my uncle. He did not live in an urban community with gardens and high-rise buildings, but in a remote place. In the barren Kuli Valley, the family is extremely poor, and several members of the family wait for Uncle Li Hai to bring flour from &quot;my&quot; house every year to make dumplings for the New Year. The two families looked up to each other and secretly compared each other to get through the difficult period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When Yin Xueyun was a child, the days in the village moved at an almost solid speed. The only changes were who died and who got married. Some people wear the same clothes in winter and summer, but they take out the cotton wool in summer and stuff it in in winter. The village is nicknamed &quot;Nagging Village&quot; because there are many people who are not doing their job properly and enjoy good food and drink. Meat that cannot be sold in other villages will be sold here. Her parents are both farmers, and there is no one around her who is involved in writing work. She looked for the source of her literary genes, which was her grandfather who could read scripts, sing operas, and shout trumpets. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many writers remember their reading history. She also wrote down in her notebook: &quot;Wild Fire and Spring Wind Fighting in the Ancient City&quot;, &quot;Fighting Youth&quot;, &quot;Golden Avenue&quot;...from elementary school She had memorized 147 titles of books she read from first grade to junior high school graduation. This number made her wonder if she had remembered it wrong. But in her words, these books are all about war, which may not be very nutritious for literature. When she was a teenager, she didn’t even know there were magazines in the world, let alone come into contact with foreign literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Even so, you must read, read one book at a time, and come out bit by bit. Because of scarcity, the memory of books is strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is not easy for rural children to get access to books, and sometimes they have to &quot;match wits and courage&quot; with their brothers and sisters. When she was a child, her sister, who was seven years older than her, loved reading and would often bring books to the house but would not read them to her. Once my sister hid a book that was said to be &quot;not suitable for children&quot;. She turned the house upside down and finally found it in an old cotton shoe. When she took the book out, she only smelled the smell of feet. When she was not at home, she took it out and read it, stuffed it back after reading it, and secretly finished reading the book about &quot;sexual intercourse&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (later she found out it was &quot;Song of Youth&quot; 》)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159107&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When she was not at school, she was reading a book while herding sheep. There was a lamb beside her and a copy of &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; without a book cover on her lap. The book was written in traditional Chinese characters. , she couldn’t understand it at all, but she could still remember the plot of “Second Sister You swallowed her own gold and died by herself”, and the stories in the book took root in her mind. On the way to school in the town, she walked in the wheat field with the children in the village. The children rushed to her side. She held a spindle in her hand and spun the cotton randomly pulled from the cotton field into thread, while talking about Mix books and memories with imagination to make a story, and tell it to your friends. She began to dream that one day her writing would be turned into type. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After graduating from high school, Yin Xueyun went to work as a seamstress in a village-run garment factory. As long as she had a day off, she would go to the county town and buy ten magazines and read them all night long. She also started to contribute articles to publications after work. At the beginning, she didn&#39;t pay attention to the differences between different publications. She couldn&#39;t remember the names of the writers she read, didn&#39;t understand anything, and her manuscripts were rejected many times. Sometimes, the editor criticized her in the rejection letter for imitating a certain writer. She was confused and didn&#39;t know who the writer she was &quot;imitating&quot; was. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At heart, she is still a farmer who relies on the weather. If it rains too much, the seedlings will grow wildly, and if there is a severe drought, there will be no harvest. The same is true for writing. There is no chance of winning awards or becoming famous. My ambition is to work step by step and write whatever comes to my mind. During this period, she relied on her innate spirituality and affection to write about life in the countryside and the ecology of the countryside, expressing those around her who were &quot;thinking of ways to live&quot;. She published publications ranging from &quot;Jixian Literature and Art&quot; to &quot;Tianjin Literature&quot; &quot;Tianjin Daily&quot;, the efforts are slowly paying off. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the late 1980s, Yin Xueyun’s novel &quot;A Woman Called Suyue&quot; was adapted into a TV series and broadcast on CCTV. The background music of this TV series was composed of a song called &quot; Yin Xueyun was deeply moved by the sound of Xun&#39;s musical instrument and decided to use &quot;Xun&quot; to name the cities in her future works. From then on, &quot;Xun City&quot; became another literary landmark of hers. At that time, she was helping the county write county chronicles. Due to the influence of CCTV, the county party committee specially gave her a quota, and she was directly transferred from a temporary worker to a national cadre. Speaking of this, Yin Xueyun couldn&#39;t help but sigh: &quot;Literature changes destiny, it is really literature that changes destiny.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159106&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Emerging from deep waters&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From a farmer to a cadre, Yin Xueyun worked in many different departments such as the Cultural Center, the Tourism Bureau, and the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee, and her work exposed her to She kept a distance from all kinds of people, observed how people think and act at work, and what kind of relationships needed to be coordinated, and wrote down each and every image of grassroots cadres. In the early years, someone from her workplace warned her not to write a novel about herself. She secretly asked, &quot;Which single character can constitute a novel?&quot; She likes to let the characters wash away in the long river of time, washing away their temporary moments. They are high-spirited and disgraced, leaving behind their usually faint but real humanity, and then weave a story frame for them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is different from the countryside is that the government divides people into many levels. Leaders and non-leaders, older people and younger people, and even the background behind them will be deliberately divided. Measurement and speculation, in the workplace, people always have to face many different people and deal with many different relationships. In such a complicated and tame daily life, she expands the depth of people&#39;s soul introspection. &quot;Ten Years of Farewell&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(published in 2015)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is a typical story about the transformation of human nature in agency work. This novel I started writing very early, and was left on the computer for ten years. During these ten years, Guo Yingzi, a young literary and artistic woman who &quot;always sees things with wishful thinking, cannot see any formalism, and cannot tolerate a grain of sand in her eyes&quot;, He learned to watch people&#39;s words and restrain his sharp edges, and became a well-rounded director in the office and an all-rounder at the bar. Chen Danguo, who was in a very similar situation to Yingzi at the time, could not bear the harassment from his boss and the isolation from his colleagues, so he committed suicide by jumping off the building. Chen Danguo&#39;s death made Yingzi realize that he had sunk into Accomplices also poses a thought-provoking question to readers: Does worldly success come at the cost of losing common sense and normal life? This novel resonated with many people and was recognized by the Hundred Flowers Literary Award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before the novel came out, Yin Xueyun also experienced a period of &quot;boiling a frog in warm water&quot; in literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She has always been insensitive to fame and fortune. In her words, the author in the remote mountainous area is far away from the city and away from the vanity fair. Therefore, people are always in a state of submerging in deep water, and it is difficult to float even if they want to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the 1990s, Yin Xueyun gave the impression that her writing had stopped for several years. She was still young at that time, publishing novels and essays from time to time, and running a small magazine. She went around admiring flowers, playing cards, and picnicking with authors she knew, and had a lot of fun every day. But soon she felt tired. Although there are always works being published, there are only a few publications that I regularly contact, and the novels are bumping around in a small circle, without any upward momentum. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After walking out of the valley, as she grew older, she thought of things that she had never thought of before. &quot;You live in a place where the mountains are high and the emperor is far away. The advantage is that you are relatively free. The disadvantage is that you are relatively free and there is no one to supervise you. Later I met some writers in Hebei and I was particularly envious of them for having such a small group of three or five people who knew how to write. What&#39;s good and what&#39;s bad is. But at that time, no one saw it when I posted it in some places, and no one told you how to go.&quot; Yin Xueyun said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fortunately, the goodwill among grassroots writers &quot;caught&quot; her. When her novel was tepid, experienced writers gave her guidance - to publish it in an evening newspaper that was more life-oriented and had more readers. So she began to write novels for the Evening News, as well as prose and essays. The content became richer, including talking about football, reminiscing about the countryside, talking about family life, and everything in between. During that time, she went hiking every evening, thinking about writing while climbing. “Sometimes a series of topics are lined up at the back, and there is always a lot to write about. It is such a feeling that makes you feel that life is very interesting. &quot; Yin Xueyun described. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The newspaper column has a large volume of publications, and she has to publish several articles at a time. She thought of writing about the words that were slowly disappearing in the countryside where she lived. As urbanization continues to accelerate, some scenes of historical significance and local color in rural areas have become blurred. As rural people moved into the city, many dialect words that existed between the 1950s and the 1970s disappeared from people&#39;s communication, and a considerable part of them became history by the early 1980s. In order to prevent these words from disappearing quietly, she visited villages large and small in the county and dug out those words from the local population. Some words are spread over a wide area, some words are used differently in the south and the north, ancient and modern times, and some accents are difficult to imitate with words. When encountering difficult-to-grasp parts, she also discusses them with netizens from all over the world. This experience of searching on the field ridges left many memories such as &quot;opening the circle&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (the team had finished harvesting all the sweet potatoes, peanuts or wheat in the fields and allowed The members dig up the leftover sweet potatoes and peanuts or pick up the wheat ears left on the ground)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &quot;Shinjuku&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (occasionally stay overnight in other people&#39;s homes)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &quot;watch the green&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(watch the crops when they are about to mature and turn from green to yellow to prevent others from stealing them. Grain)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and other hundreds of rural words were recorded, and later became a book &quot;The Slowly Disappearing Rural Words&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (published in 2009)&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After writing essays and columns for several years, she gradually found her own writing style, and people in the entire city also knew about her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;159100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2014 was a special year for Yin Xueyun. She published five novellas and wrote &quot;Uncle Li Hai&quot; and &quot;Ten Years of Farewell&quot; , entering the blowout period of the work. To this day, the fate of her and these works still makes her sad. At that time, a novella &quot;Linglong Tower&quot; was rejected. She could not figure out the reason for the rejection, so she gave the manuscript to Harvest magazine. Within a week, the editor called and suggested revisions. She did nothing during the months waiting for the final trial, and she doesn&#39;t know how she got here. She told herself that she would start writing after the final review, and she would stop writing after the final review failed. She was 50 years old that year, the age when female cadres leave their posts. If the manuscript had not been submitted to Harvest and had not been reviewed, she might have changed her life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The final review was passed. After &quot;Harvest&quot; published &quot;Linglong Tower&quot;, editors approached Yin Xueyun one after another to invite manuscripts. The first thing she wrote was &quot;Uncle Lehi,&quot; but it was shelved because of space issues. She brought another manuscript to the editor for comments, but was asked to publish it. This one was &quot;Ten Years After the Farewell&quot;. &quot;I always tell my writer friends, don&#39;t worry, write slowly. When you have the chance, the work will come when it comes. Sometimes you can&#39;t find it no matter how hard you look for it. This is not just a work. What kind of era.&quot; Yin Xueyun said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the second year, Yin Xueyun continued to work hard and published 10 novellas, and by 2016, he had published 14 novels. She still finds the productivity of that period to be incredible. “虽然说那个时候都已经不是创作力最好的时候了，但是你会觉得文学突然给你打开了一扇窗，你可以抓住这样一个机会，其实那个时候没有任何人告诉你应该怎么样，但是自己真是有这种感觉。”她说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;士别三十年&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近年来，尹学芸的视野从乡村跨越到城市，投向城乡之间的牵扯、纠结和疼痛。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;离开故乡30年后，她写了一篇名字骇人的《喂鬼》，小说的主人公云丫为躲避故乡的干娘临终前指派她在葬礼上为其“喂鬼”的仪式，急匆匆与网友阿祥相约远赴云南旅行。一路上却不断接到来自干娘的大儿子的催促和央告，令她心神不安。结果旅行结束返回埙城，她还是按照干娘的遗愿去喂鬼，才知道喂鬼只是一个很简单的佛教法事&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（“喂鬼”也叫“放焰口”，其实就是赈济鬼魂，给予法食令其饱满。）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。三个多月后，云丫接到电话，她的朋友阿祥已在三个月前死于一场车祸。这是一场徒劳的出走。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尹学芸谈起这篇小说的创作时说：“很多时候故乡就是一枚爱人，有时候让你想着法地逃离，可更多的时候，又让你想着法地回归。有对比才有反差，有反差才有不同情感方式的表达。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尽管作为基层工作者，尹学芸还是需要经常跟乡村打交道，但已经不是小时候那种生活在其中的状态，而是客居。年龄大了，和乡村的距离也在拉大，她和家乡的那些人、事之间有了一层越来越碍眼的隔膜。过去她喜欢把熟悉的人反复用在多部作品里，刻画人物不同的侧面，把故事写得满满当当，但现在她的生活里已经很难找到这样的人。在《寻隐者不遇》中，现代人的神龙见首不见尾，人与人之间感情的淡薄、疏远，通过大量留白表现出来。再也找不到《李海叔叔》里那种长达二十多年的精神连接。 “再然后你就发现，其实你跟所有的故乡、所有的乡村都是隔膜的，其实变化的不是它们，是你自己，很多时候都是你的眼睛变了，或者你的心也变了，我回去得越来越少了，跟他们的交往越来越少了。”尹学芸说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;作为以乡村题材见长的作家，她不得不对这种隔膜警惕起来：“作品中的那种温度其实都在退，那种底色都在褪。我觉得是作家的通病，可能隔一段就得反思，怎么在生活中找到切口，这是很重要的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（参考资料：《尹学芸印象》《尹学芸：没有哪段生活是白费的》《尹学芸：我曾被这盏灯照亮也期待它照亮更多人》《专访」尹学芸：最基层的作者离文坛很遥远，发再多小说也不是著名作家》《尹学芸：乡村的秩序》，感谢译林出版社和邓郁为采访提供的帮助）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这个假期，打工人流行去围观山姆盒马“小学生打架”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国庆长假期间，一些没有出游、宅在家的年轻人，会选择去往仓储会员店，一次性采购长假期间所需要的食物，山姆会员店和盒马X会员店成为很多人的优先选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如今，这两家仓储会员店不仅可以满足消费者的购物需求，也可以满足他们凑热闹、看八卦的需求，因为8月以来，山姆与盒马的“小学生打架”就没有停止过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高端的商战，往往采用最朴素的方式，那就是我的商品比你低1元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此前，山姆与盒马为一块榴莲千层蛋糕“打”得不可开交——榴莲千层最先由山姆热卖，一块128元，盒马直接标价一块99元。山姆不服输，把榴莲千层的价格打到88元，盒马降到86元，山姆就调到85元，几个回合下来，蛋糕价格一度降至79元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随后，从月饼西瓜到鸡蛋小零食都卷入这场商战，很多人疑惑，山姆与盒马为何要“小学生打架”？价格战能让他们顺利地圈到中产消费者吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;巨头们各有烦恼&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;正当传统商超经营普遍陷入困境时，带有批发性质的仓储会员商店发展得如火如荼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店走的量贩售卖模式，大包装、品类多、价格优惠，消费者每隔一段时间才去大采购一次。艾媒咨询数据显示，2021年仓储会员超市行业市场规模达304.3亿元，2022年市场规模达335亿元，预计到2025年有望接近400亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为中国仓储会员商店的头部品牌，山姆会员店和盒马X店各有风光，也各有烦恼，不得不铆足劲头竞争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店已成为沃尔玛业绩中重要的增长点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据沃尔玛第二季度的数据，第二季度总营收为1616亿美元，同比增长5.7%或5.4%（受汇率影响），营业利润同比增长5亿美元，增长率为6.7%。其中，沃尔玛中国净销售额为41亿美元，同比增长21.7%，仓储会员业务与电商业务增长亮眼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店坐稳国内仓储会员店的头把交椅。一方面，1996年，山姆就在深圳开了中国第一家仓储会员店，将仓储会员的模式与理念传输到国内。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一方面，作为世界500强常年的第一名，沃尔玛在全球范围内建立了庞大、稳固的供应链体系，沃尔玛旗下的山姆会员店能够以更低的价格拿到更高品质的商品，并让利给消费者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店1983年就在美国开了第一家店，至今已经有40年历史，它的积淀与经验是其他仓储会员店一时半会还难以比拟的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;然而，山姆也有烦恼，那就是模仿者、竞争者甚至是“碰瓷者”太多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;同样诞生于美国的Costco，主打仓储会员模式，是山姆的老对手，麦德龙、家乐福等国外品牌也穷追不舍，至于国内，诚如永辉、盒马等来势汹汹，尤其是后起之秀的盒马X店，已经渐渐对山姆形成严峻挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于成立于2015年的盒马来说，历史尽管不长，走过的弯路也不少，除了招牌的盒马鲜生以外，盒马此前推出的盒马小站、盒马MINI、盒马集市和盒马邻里等，大都已经铩羽而归。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前盒马形成三个比较稳定的业务，一个是盒马鲜生，一个是盒马奥莱店（折扣店），另外一个就是仓储会员模式的盒马X店。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今年，阿里巴巴启动“1+6+N”组织变革，盒马只是“N”中的一部分，在集团中的地位有所下滑，盒马还是阿里最有希望上市的业务之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如果只是盒马鲜生盈利肯定是不够的，所以，X店成为盒马的重中之重，被寄予厚望。除了赶紧多开店外，更是要抢占市场份额，提升盈利能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;瞄准中产，抢占中产&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店的目标客户，是中国新兴的中产阶层。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店早在1996年就在中国大陆开了第一家，不过，截至2016年，整整20年时间也仅只有16家店。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;伴随着中国中产阶层的迅速崛起，山姆会员店才迎来爆发式增长，从2017年至今6年不到的时间，山姆会员店已经新增了29家店，目前大陆已经有45家山姆会员店，预计到今年底将达到48家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店的中产属性，另一个标志是它并不便宜的年费。比如山姆普通会员费为260元，盒马X黄金会员年费为258元。值得注意的是，会员费的期限只有一年，并且不能抵现。换句话说，得先花260元才能进入山姆消费，哪怕你一年在山姆什么也没买，260元也是不能返还的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;会员费门槛自然阻隔了很大一部分消费者，无疑也会提高付费消费者的购物黏性，办了这里的会员卡，当然会来这里高频购物，才不会浪费了会员费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;凭借强大的供应链和议价能力，仓储会员店也会努力以“物美又全、价格合理”的商品，让消费者的260元的会员费花得不亏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆与盒马对准的都是具有较好的经济基础、对生活品质有高追求的中产尤其是中产家庭，二者的用户高度重合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据月狐iAPP所示，山姆与盒马的用户重合率达到43.1%。而今年2月，沃尔玛中国区CEO朱晓静在一场内部讲话中表示，山姆唯一竞争对手可能就是盒马。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一次也是盒马率先发起针对山姆的“价格战”，盒马的畅销活动叫“移山价”，一语双关，既是愚公移山，也是要移走山姆。这名称，“小学生打架”的意味蛮浓。搞笑的是，美团也一度加入战局，推出的价格叫“拔河价”，这“河”，不正是“盒马”吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;谁能“打赢”这群架&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在这场仓储会员领域的群架中，谁能“打赢”？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;单靠价格战，并不是最优解。既因为不可持续，也因为价格战只针对少数的商品品类，并非全线都比对方低价。更关键的是，中产在意的并不是那一两块钱的差距，很多人愿意花贵一点的价格购买更优品质的商品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，仓储会员商店还是得回到根本上来：“物美又全，价格合理”——这考验的仍然是供应链的强度与韧性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;能否在全球范围内，以更低的价格采买优质的产品？从采购到上架，需要多长时间？如何确保货柜上的热门商品能够源源不断提供？消费者网上采购，能够以多快的速度送货上门？能否不断提供爆款的自营产品？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;它们都与供应链有关。在这一点上，山姆与Costco布局多年、树大根深，确实需要盒马不断追赶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为本土品牌，盒马的优势是带有更加鲜明的“本土化”特色，更加契合国人的一些消费需求。比如中国正步入单身社会，单身的中产越来越多，山姆会员店那种超大量的贩卖模式不适合这些单身中产，盒马的X会员店，就很注重经营小包装商品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国的电商经济高度发达，盒马背靠阿里健全成熟的物流体系，送货上门的速度极快，反之，Costco不久前才推出到家配送服务，真的是姗姗来迟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;再比如，下沉市场仍是仓储会员商店未充分开发的领地，盒马主打折扣商品和临期商品的奥莱店，可以在一线城市扎根，在下沉市场也有很大的想象空间……&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆、盒马等仓储会员店该如何扬长避短，好戏还在后头。无论如何，它们充分竞争是好事一件，帮消费者把价格打下来，消费者还能顺便看看八卦，何乐不为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:26:35 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子诬告强奸在新加坡被判入狱：世界性难题如何破解？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258118]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一起发生在国外的案件引发关注。综合新加坡《联合早报》《海峡时报》报道，中国籍女子张露恬（22岁）10月2日在法庭上认罪，承认自己向公务员提供虚假资料。法官最终判其入狱五周。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;案件并不复杂：当事女子2021年4月通过社交软件与男子刘栋扬结识，一个月后见面并在当年8月确立恋爱关系，之后又在刘栋扬处同居。 2022年3月9日，两人在刘栋扬住处发生激烈争吵，当事女子在午夜00：38报警。面对到场调查的十名警员、五名调查人员和四名法证人员，当事女子称自己遭遇刘栋扬虐待，也曾三次遭遇后者强奸，并向医务人员重复了指控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘栋扬一共被问话44分钟，两部手机与护照也遭警方扣留。然而在报案一个月后，当事女子就改口承认自己撒谎，并且撤回了虚假指控。 “为的就是要让男方惹上麻烦。”当事女子还透露自己早在事发约一周后就尝试销案，但是并未成功。检察官Kevin Liew表示，被告提供假信息浪费了公共资源，也冤枉一名无辜的受害者，因此提议法官判被告坐牢至少六周。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对检方的指控，当事女子哽咽发表辩词称，事发时自己刚满21岁，认知能力尚不成熟，一时冲动才犯下错误。除了对受害者外，自己行为并未对公众利益造成巨大伤害。当时因遭前男友粗暴对待，急着寻求帮助才会谎称遭到对方强奸。她已追悔莫及也得到了前男友原谅，希望法官从轻发落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起案件已经尘埃落定，法官确实也如当事女子所愿对其“从轻发落”，将刑期从六到十个星期变成了五个星期。不过，这起案件仍有一些未发之覆，值得深入辨析与评论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，案件本身显示当事女子的说辞存在矛盾之处，其辩词并不能服人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当事女子所谓“认知偏差”的辩称透露着一股黑色幽默，特别是那句“对法律条款的认知能力不足，对于自身犯罪的严重性认知也非常不成熟”。那么，既然她“认知能力尚不成熟”，为何却以强奸罪指控男友？要知道，强奸罪在新加坡可是最高刑期20年同时最多鞭刑12下的重罪。因此，当事女子的言行似乎只能解读为她对强奸罪罪名的后果有所认知，却不足以认知诬告他人的法律后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，“认知偏差”的话术也常见于国内强奸或性侵诬告者在露馅之后的自辩。在喧腾一时的“罗冠军案”中，梁颖就声称“她本人对强奸罪法律定义的认知出现偏差，才会在网上冤枉罗冠军”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诬告者自辩“认知偏差”，其实是无法自圆其说的。从梁颖发动的“小作文”舆论攻势与本案中当事女子的司法攻势来看，诬告者对于公开指控“强奸罪”的后果其实有着清晰的认知，目的就是“把对方弄到社会性死亡”“给对方惹麻烦”。而在其它案例里，诬告者还有“把你送进监狱”这样直白的威胁。难道诬告者不知道“强奸罪”的严重性？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不难想见诬告者的心路历程：公开指控对方性侵或强奸，最好的结果是逼迫对方让出利益或者让自己吃到流量红利，乃至真的将对方送进监狱，至少毁掉对方的人生；最坏的结果也不过是“自己记错了”，以类似“认知偏差”的理由为诬告行为开脱，“可攻可守”的状态，足以让自己立于不败之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也正是如此，当事女子才在耗费大量公共资源、诬告已经实锤之后，以“认知偏差”辩称诬告之举，借助“心智不成熟”企图脱逃报假案之罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，本案也显示“性侵或强奸诬告”是个全球性难题，诬告者需要承担的举证责任、所需承担的民事与刑事责任，均与诬告成功的可能获利严重不成比例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本案中，当事女子最终的罪名只是“向公务员提供虚假信息罪”，检察官在指控中也只是强调了其“浪费大量公共资源”的行径。根据新加坡《刑事法典》第177条，向公务员提供虚假信息者将被处以最高六个月的刑期，或者并处罚金5000新元。然而，对比当事女子的诬告之举，以及一旦罪名成立之后男方所面临的的严厉刑责，这是严重不符比例原则的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果类似诬告行为总能实现“零成本高回报”，而且即便报了假案作了伪证也只是坐牢六个星期的话，那么其所带来的“制度激励”仍将制造更多的诬告案件，从长远来看同样会伤害公共利益。难道，社会只能在“默许乃至宽纵诬告”与“保障真正受害者敢于报案”之间或此或彼？这又是一个“虚假两难推理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，被诬告者也未能站出来伸张自己的权益，控告对方的犯罪行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新加坡法律没有诬告陷害罪，但有诽谤罪。根据新加坡《刑事法典》第499条，如果发现足够的证据，警察可以采取行动逮捕诽谤的罪犯。受害者也可以选择根据《诽谤法》提起民事诉讼，或向警方报案进行刑事起诉，如能证明诽谤者有意图、知道或有理由相信他的话会损害受害者的名誉，即可发起控告，挽回自己被侵权的损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本案中，当事女子诽谤的事证确凿，而且不无作伪证的嫌疑。其对当事男子的直接伤害是数十分钟的问话、护照手机被扣以及人格名誉的损害，潜在可能的伤害更是“有期徒刑加鞭刑套餐”的重刑。然而当事男子并没有反诉女方，而是“就此原谅”。实际上，这增加了公共利益受损的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以新加坡麻醉科医生杨绍南为例，他在遭遇一名女子的性侵诬告之后四年（2017-2021）才得以洗脱冤屈，但冗长的法律程序让他丢了公立医院的职位，付出了巨额经济损失，承受了名誉的毁灭性打击，最终打赢官司也是于事无补，控方至今也未对女子提供虚假证据作出任何行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上早在2021年9月13日，新加坡国会就有议员联合提案说，在制定新的法律增加对性侵罪刑罚的同时，也要寻求对那些遭遇错误指控者的保护。加强对诬告受害者的保护，首先就需要加大对诬告犯罪者的打击，鼓励受害者站出来反诉，不能再让性侵诬告变成一种“低成本高收益”的游戏，让“认知偏差”成为诬告者脱罪减罪的捷径。诚如杨绍南医生在真相大白之后表示：法律制度应当能对滥用法律的人施加足够的威慑力，同时不会阻止真正遭受性犯罪的受害者勇敢地站出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[礼盒混装、糕点伪装……月饼何时“包装有度”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;新国标的实施可以推动厂商专注于月饼本身的创新、取缔过于精美繁复的包装，但目前仍然存在部分商家“钻空子”的行为，需要相关部门加强监管。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个中秋国庆长假有多少人的早餐被月饼承包？又有多少人注意到家中堆积如山的月饼礼盒正在发生哪些变化？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你手边正好有月饼礼盒，不妨做个小测验：打开礼盒，除了月饼是否还配备刀叉、盘子或其他产品？从月饼所在的包装袋向外数，能不能数出四层？如果得到肯定的答案，那么眼前的月饼极有可能因“过度包装”违反国家相关标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该标准为国家市场监管总局（国家标准委）修订发布的《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021），于2023年9月1日正式实施。该标准第1号修改单从包装空隙率、包装层数、包装成本、混装要求四个方面进一步提出限制月饼过度包装的规定，已于2022年8月15日实施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据第1号修改单，月饼不应与其他产品混装，包装不应超过三层。销售价格在100元以上的月饼，包装成本占销售价格的比例不得超过15%。同时包装材料不得使用贵金属、红木等贵重材料。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年过渡期后，月饼是否依旧存在过度包装现象？南方周末记者随机抽样调查了电商平台的月饼礼盒商品，发现混装现象最为突出，也有一部分商家在商品描述上玩花样，规避相对严格的月饼管理标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区计量检测所工程师张梦娇向南方周末记者表示，月饼作为中秋传统食物，引人联想的画面是家人团聚而不是精美包装，尽管月饼具有一定的社交属性，但收礼者也希望月饼能够物有所值，新国标的实施可以推动厂商专注于月饼本身的创新、取缔过于精美繁复的包装，但目前仍然存在部分商家“钻空子”的行为，需要相关部门加强监管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;月饼混装的重灾区：文创和联名礼盒&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;月饼礼盒包含塑料刀叉，曾是广式月饼的“常规操作”，禁止混装的新规出台后，除去用于保护月饼的食品用脱氧剂、冰袋，包括刀叉在内的所有产品都不被允许出现在月饼礼盒中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者调查发现，2023年的月饼市场上仍然存在不少混装产品，文创和联名礼盒的混装现象最为突出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，知名食品品牌稻香村推出小兔顺耳IP联名款月饼礼盒，礼盒中包含稻香村月饼馅料包和DIY模具，并提供了制作月饼的教程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;774&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月5日，稻香村联合陈小桃推出月饼礼盒，混装DIY模具。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（天猫稻香村旗舰店/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;部分餐饮品牌也推出混装礼盒，并屡探500元上限。 2022年6月，国家发改委、市场监管总局等四部门联合发布《关于遏制“天价”月饼、促进行业健康发展的公告》，提出对单价超过500元的盒装月饼实行重点监管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高端连锁品牌大董和宋代院体细笔绘画研究学者刘庆杨联名推出“董之月·礼享集”月饼礼盒，礼盒包含七款月饼和一幅挂画，标价468元（优惠后398元）。产品种类下设两种选项，虽然名为“月饼馅种类”，但大董电商客服告诉南方周末记者，两款礼盒的月饼种类一致，区别在于收到的画作是《百种牡丹谱》还是《梧桐双月兔》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了食品品牌，部分文创定制商家也在试探着月饼过度包装的底线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，淘宝平台上一家主营节日定制伴手礼的店铺推出的中秋礼盒分为不同组合的套餐，套餐内标配2粒百草味月饼，消费者还可以自主选择香薰片、乌龙茶、香水、贺卡等内容物进行多元化混装。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;某文创定制店铺，售卖“月饼+文创”组合的中秋伴手礼。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（淘宝店铺/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“按照月饼标准管理的文创产品，只要装入了月饼之外的产品就属于混装。如果一款礼盒采用创意包装，包装本身可以用作其他用途（如带镜子的收纳盒、带玩具的桌游板），也需要先确认该礼盒是否按照月饼标准管理。”张梦娇说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;混淆糕点和月饼&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;逃避处罚的新招&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）国家标准第1号修改单对月饼包装提出要求，但并非所有月饼礼盒装的都是“真月饼”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，本土巧克力品牌诺梵推出的“月光之城”巧克力月饼礼盒混装了刀叉和盘子，电商平台月销量超过4000件。但该品牌客服向南方周末记者提供的商品外包装显示，该产品的食品名称为“月饼型巧克力制品”，参照巧克力及巧克力制品标准管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;787&quot; height=&quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月2日，诺梵电商客服告诉南方周末记者，除两个款式外，其他巧克力月饼礼盒都混装刀叉和盘子。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（天猫诺梵旗舰店咨询页/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者在电商平台随机抽取了10个不同品牌存在混装问题的月饼礼盒，其中有3款礼盒虽然在营销时标有“月饼”字样、食品外形为传统月饼形状，实际上产品却是按照糕点执行标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区市场监督管理局标准化科魏彦丹向南方周末记者表示，在我国境内生产、销售和进口的所有食品（含散装食品）和化妆品的销售包装均适用于《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）。南方周末记者查询发现，根据第1号修改单，月饼、粽子的包装要求更为严格，除月饼、粽子外，对其他食品和化妆品并未做出混装限制。这意味着，糕点、巧克力等食品虽然适用新国标的限制过度包装要求，但仍然可以与其他产品混装。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照现行的月饼推荐性国家标准（GB/T 19855-2015），月饼的定义为使用小麦粉等谷物粉或植物粉、油、糖（或不加糖）等为主要原料制成饼皮，包裹各种馅料，经加工而成，在中秋节食用为主的传统节日食品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种情况下，如果实际判断为其它糕点，但按月饼售卖，那么可能存在实物与描述不符的情况，需要进一步确认其售卖食品与其标签是否标注一致。”张梦娇表示，通常，预包装食品标签上的品名、执行标准、食品生产许可证编号等，均可作为判断依据，或由主管部门综合判断。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，还有一类商家在商品描述中故意模糊月饼和糕点的概念，将“真月饼”伪装成糕点，试图规避新国标对月饼混装的要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区市场监督管理局标准化科魏彦丹告诉南方周末记者，根据《中华人民共和国标准化法》第二十七条的规定，“企业应当按照标准组织生产经营活动，其生产的产品、提供的服务应当符合企业公开标准的技术要求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何判断月饼是否过度包装？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“以《蟾宫玉兔图》为灵感，礼盒采用前后镂空图案，放入灯饰装饰，如揽明月入怀”，这段介绍来自一款以新中式包装为亮点、包含“高档”“送礼”等关键词的月饼礼盒，该产品标价358元，在电商平台吸引了上百人购买，评论区里不乏“外包装好看”的买家推荐语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为普通消费者，又该如何判断购买的月饼过度包装呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）国家标准第1号修改单，判断月饼是否存在过度包装可以从四个指标着手：包装层数、包装成本、混装以及包装空隙率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1503&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包装层数是指完全包裹内装物的可物理拆分的包装的层数，其中完全包裹指的是使包装物不致散出的包装方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果是敞口的手提袋、固定内装物或包装物的半托、包装盒外的腰封，不符合完全包裹的定义，都不能算作一层。而抽屉式包装，哪怕有两层抽屉，也只计入一层包装。对于包装精美复杂但层数符合要求的创意月饼包装，可以进一步判断包装成本是否违规。”张梦娇说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包装空隙率根据月饼的净含量计算得出，月饼单件净含量越大，标准规定的空隙率越小，单件净含量大于50g的月饼，空隙率必须≤30%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张梦娇表示，由于计算方法较为复杂，包装空隙率一般由技术机构在实验室对抽检样品进行检测。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市市场监督管理局向南方周末记者表示，自2023年8月以来，上海市市场监督管理局对本市市场销售的月饼开展了过度包装监督抽查，涉及超市、连锁面包房、酒店等52家生产经营单位，共抽查月饼80批次，月饼包装违规的主因是包装空隙率不合格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPG中国首席经济学家柏文喜告诉南方周末记者，打击过度包装有助于降低消费者购买成本，提高购物体验，也能减少消费者购买高价月饼的行为，从而降低社会浪费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从上海市市场监管局获悉，消费者可以使用上海市市场监管局开发的微信小程序“包装有度”，通过输入商品包装简单信息，只需1分钟时间即能初步判定商品是否涉嫌过度包装。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“异域星球”墨石公园丨指尖华夏⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257593]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;墨石公园位于四川省甘孜州道孚八美镇卡玛村与中古村交界处，面积&lt;span>;5&lt;/span>;平方公里，海拔约&lt;span>;3500&lt;/span>;米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;独具特色的糜棱岩石林景观，墨石公园如同“异域星球”一般，吸引众多游客前来打卡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨石公园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/赵俊超/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨石公园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/赵俊超/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨石公园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/赵俊超/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨石公园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/赵俊超/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨石公园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/赵俊超/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[绝杀日本队，中国女篮亚运会夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月5日，杭州第19届亚运会女子篮球决赛，中国队以&lt;span>;74-72战胜&lt;/span>;日本队，夺得金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253066&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253067&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雨林中的玛雅遗址：“巴黎”与霸主丨古国多少事⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257360]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;作为美洲三大古文明之一的玛雅文明，曾一度在热带丛林中城邦林立，但受制于自然环境和技术发展，就像中国古代西域沙漠中的一串绿洲小国一样，无法统一、壮大，最后在一场生态危机中不堪一击、同时凋零，被卷土重来的热带雨林尘封千年之久……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我有幸去过中美洲探访分布于三个国家的九处玛雅城邦遗址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了墨西哥和萨尔瓦多以外，玛雅遗迹所在的其他中美洲国家——危地马拉、洪都拉斯和伯利兹——尚未与我国建交，去过的国人相对较少，但这片区域恰恰是玛雅文明全盛时代的腹地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科潘&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Copán）&lt;/span>;是我的第一站。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;危地马拉弗洛雷斯古镇，玛雅文明的最后一处宗教中心。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;玛雅世界的巴黎——科潘&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;科潘遗址坐落于洪都拉斯西部边境，距离危地马拉大约五公里，离萨尔瓦多也不超过五十公里。遗址以西不远是座边境小镇，叫做科潘鲁伊纳斯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Copán Ruinas）&lt;/span>;，这是西班牙语，意思就是“科潘遗址”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科潘是玛雅文明全盛时代&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元250—900年，又称为古典期）&lt;/span>;东南部最为重要的城邦。玛雅在古典期经历了蒂卡尔&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Tikal）&lt;/span>;和卡拉克穆尔&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Calakmul）&lt;/span>;两个强大城邦的长期对峙局面，它们俩均位于尤卡坦半岛&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Yucatan）&lt;/span>;中部，一南一北，隔着茂密的丛林连年征战。可能是为了扩大领地，拓展资源，蒂卡尔于五世纪初期向自己的侧后方扩展，在中美洲地峡中部的一条河谷中扶植了科潘城邦，双方形成了坚固的同盟关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科潘于七世纪中叶&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（大致对应于中国的唐高宗时期）&lt;/span>;在第十二位国王烟豹&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Chan Imix K&#39;awiil，628—695年在位）&lt;/span>;的统治下进入鼎盛时期。烟豹于15岁登基，在位时间长达67年，在科潘总共十七位国王中享国时间最久。他的继位者十八兔&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Uaxaclajuun Ub&#39;aah K&#39;awiil，695—738年在位）&lt;/span>;在那个时代也算个寿星，前后在位时间长达43年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（与唐玄宗李隆基一样）&lt;/span>;。这两位国王合计执政长达110年，在此期间科潘由一座河谷城邦俨然升级成为一座新兴帝国，手下控制了一批附庸，还打通了指向加勒比海的商路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而好景不长，由于十八兔的大兴土木和穷兵黩武，导致实力有限却过度扩张的科潘迅速陷入危机，于八世纪中叶爆发了一场类似“安史之乱”的叛乱：十八兔遭到被他安插在附庸小邦基里瓜&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Quirigua）&lt;/span>;的亲信暴雨天&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（K&#39;ak&#39; Tiliw Chan Yopaat）&lt;/span>;倒戈谋反，猝不及防打了败仗，被生俘后解往基里瓜，在那里的大广场上被作为祭品斩首——现代历史学家注意到在此两年前，卡拉克穆尔城邦的君主曾专程拜访过暴雨天，由此推测可能是卡拉克穆尔在背后策划并资助了这场叛乱，目的是为了斩断世仇蒂卡尔的左膀右臂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十八兔死后，受到基里瓜反制的科潘从此走上了下坡路，尽管此后一度与西部大城邦帕伦克&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Palenque）&lt;/span>;联姻试图东山再起，但国运的没落已经无可挽回。到了九世纪初，科潘的史书停更，这座河谷城邦突然衰落，迅速消失在卷土重来的雨林植被中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又过了一千年，美国考古学家史蒂芬斯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（John Stephens）&lt;/span>;和英国画家加瑟伍德&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Frederick Catherwood）&lt;/span>;于1839年根据玛雅土著的故老相传找到了科潘遗址，对这座隐匿于丛林中的废墟作出了如此评价：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;它横列在我们眼前，就像汪洋中一艘破碎的船，它的桅杆不见了，船员也消失了，谁也不知它何时来的，也不知摧毁它的是何物，一切都是谜。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科潘大广场，右侧被天蓬罩住的是“历史之阶”。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天我们看到的科潘遗址仅是当年科潘城邦核心区的一小部分，也就是充当玛雅城邦政治、宗教和文化中心的大广场周边。广场中央有一座小型金字塔，其北侧竖立着八尊两米多高的石像，其中六尊雕的是十八兔。这些石雕让人联想起南亚神庙建筑装饰风格：细节极其繁复华美，但从整体来看却缺少亮点与个性，也许可以称之为玛雅式洛可可风格吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金字塔的东南侧是一座蹴球场。蹴球是玛雅人特有的体育竞赛，也是高贵的祭祀活动。由于缺乏文献资料，目前尚未完全弄清楚它究竟怎么玩，一般认为它有点像今天的排球，双方选手轮番击打一个象征太阳的实心橡胶球，不得使用头部、手部和脚部触球，而只能用肘、髋或膝盖击球，将球击向对手后方，或者造成对方无法救球而失分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如《哈利·波特》小说中霍格沃兹魔法学校一年一度的魁地奇球赛具有捕获金色飞贼的绝杀设置，蹴球比赛也设有绝杀规则。蹴球场呈长方形，两侧长边各有一面高墙，高墙中央的顶端有一个石制圆环，形同篮球场中的“篮筐”，只不过这个篮筐并非水平，而是垂直的，且位置相当高，选手们绝无可能起跳扣篮；圆环的孔洞也非常小，只比橡胶球的直径略大一些。在蹴球比赛中，如果选手成功让球穿过石环即赢得胜利，比赛立刻结束。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于蹴球选手的结局，史学家们至今依然争论不休，有人认为败者会被剖腹挖心，向天神献祭，另一方意见则相反，认为胜者才能获得这一至高无上的荣耀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我们看到的蹴球场是科潘城邦历史上的第三代球场，由十八兔诏令修建，它的两座前身都已被埋葬在其脚下。这座蹴球场也是迄今玛雅世界中发掘出来的第二大球场，仅次于墨西哥的奇琴伊察球场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蹴球场，背景高台乃是科潘国王御用神庙。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蹴球场东南侧是一座壮观的“历史之阶”，它由2500块半米见方的条石垒成63级台阶，高约30米，宽10米，坡度将近60度，非常陡峭，每一块条石上都刻着玛雅象形文字——整座石阶记载了科潘城邦自建立以来直到八世纪的历史。为了保护文物不受日晒雨淋，“历史之阶”上方架起了塑料天篷，影响到其外观和内部采光。游客也无法攀爬，只能从底部仰望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大广场正南方是一座小丘，山顶曾是一座神庙，举行蹴球赛和祭祀仪式时，科潘王室就从这里俯视万民——科潘在全盛时期有两万七千居民，确实配得上“万民”这个称号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个科潘遗址不算很大，有两个小时就可以浏览一遍，凡是用绳子围起来或者拿塑料布盖起来的地方都值得仔细看看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科潘被誉为“玛雅世界的巴黎”，以雕刻精美、文化发达著称。那么它为什么会在鼎盛时期突然覆亡，难道仅仅是因为遭受了一次叛乱吗？根据考古发掘的结果来看，科潘的衰落其实是生态恶化的必然结果，十八兔的虚耗国力只是加快了这个进程。这座城邦坐落于一条肥沃而狭窄的河谷之中，周边山地陡峭，土壤肥力较低。随着城邦崛起，人口快速增长，有限的河谷耕地难以维持其粮食需求，百姓遂成群上山开荒，王室也大量砍伐山地树木作为燃料以及制造灰泥涂抹在宫殿建筑上用于防水，结果导致当地植被骤减，生态恶化，山体反复滑坡，淹没了河谷良田，进一步降低农作物产量。最后农业生产崩溃，城邦遂被废弃，重新成为大片雨林。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蹴球场上方的金刚鹦鹉石雕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时值黄昏，本就不多的游客次第散尽，我坐在蹴球场边的高台上，头顶就是一具金刚鹦鹉头像石雕。静静地观赏着大广场逐渐成为金刚鹦鹉的乐园，它们或成群滑翔，自由自在地高声鸣叫，或两两栖息在树枝上，相亲相爱地互相打理羽毛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一千五百年前，玛雅人以金刚鹦鹉为图腾，在它们好奇的注视下举办火爆而血腥的蹴球赛。如今玛雅文明已然风流云散，但金刚鹦鹉仍是这里的主人，千百年以降，从未改变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;玛雅世界的霸主——蒂卡尔&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔遗址位于危地马拉北部的玛雅雨林中，它的北面和西面是中美洲大国墨西哥，东面是中美洲唯一的英语国家伯利兹。由于草莽林深，三国之间的边界是用经纬线划定的，在尤卡坦半岛的地图上划出了一块方方正正的矩形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从蒂卡尔向南不远是形如一条双髻鲨的佩滕伊察湖&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Lago Petén Itzá）&lt;/span>;及其南岸小岛弗洛雷斯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Flores）&lt;/span>;——玛雅文明的最后一处宗教中心，直至十七世纪末才毁于西班牙殖民者的文化灭绝暴行。弗洛雷斯岛东南方的陆地上建有距离蒂卡尔最近的机场：玛雅世界国际机场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从危地马拉城乘坐一架萨博340双涡轮螺旋桨飞机——可能是我有生以来坐过的最迷你的民航班机，仅有三十个座位——在湖天一色的醉人晚霞中降落于此，次日清晨驱车70公里前往蒂卡尔遗址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蒂卡尔一号神庙&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔是玛雅文明古典期与卡拉克穆尔并立的绝代双骄之一。这里周围地势低洼，沼泽密布，而蒂卡尔是一座低矮的丘陵，不旱不涝，在总体缺水的尤卡坦半岛上成为一片难得的宜居之地，至少在公元前七世纪就已经有玛雅人居住。大约一千年后，玛雅世界进入古典期，蒂卡尔凭借当地丰富的黑曜石资源，既可以在战乱时期打造锋利武器提升自身战力，也可以在和平年代向其他城邦出售牟利，因此国力迅速增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔通过国际贸易，从位于墨西哥中部的大国特奥蒂瓦坎&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Teotihuacán）&lt;/span>;那里学到了投枪战法，不需要再与敌人面对面互砍互殴，而是将敌人包围后掷出投枪杀伤之，在一定程度上实现了“远程打击”，从而显著缩小了己方伤亡，以更为先进的军事思想成为玛雅世界的霸主。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管特奥蒂瓦坎曾于四世纪末派出远征军突袭自己的学生——两地之间直线距离超过一千公里，相当于唐军全靠船只与步行&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（特奥蒂瓦坎与玛雅文明皆未能发明轮子和车辆）&lt;/span>;，肩扛背驮所有武器装备和粮草给养，从长安出发远征青海湖边的吐谷浑——并一度全面掌控了蒂卡尔的政治军事大权。但两地毕竟太过遥远，从墨西哥高原起家的特奥蒂瓦坎难以在地势卑湿的尤卡坦半岛季风雨林地区长期立足，因此蒂卡尔最终夺回了政权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科潘遗址的亮点是雕刻精美的石像，而蒂卡尔的亮点则是其高峻的金字塔。尽管囿于古代建筑技术，蒂卡尔的金字塔做不到高耸入云，但起码做到了高耸穿林——站在金字塔顶端，感觉自己仿佛站在一柄利剑的尖端，刺透了一望无垠的雨林林冠。如果把葱翠的林冠想象为云层，那么这些金字塔就如同蜀山直破云层，穿云而出，给人以极目壮怀之感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蒂卡尔1-3号神庙&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提到金字塔，玛雅金字塔与埃及金字塔有区别吗？埃及金字塔，顾名思义，形同汉字中的“金”字，乃是一个由底面的正方形和四个等腰三角形构成的正四棱锥；而玛雅金字塔乍看与埃及金字塔相似，但细看会发现它并没有顶部的尖锥，其截面是一个等腰梯形，仿佛将一座大金字塔的顶部截去了一个小金字塔而成。其底面也不总是正方形，比如蒂卡尔遗址的几座大型金字塔都是长方形底座，墨西哥的乌斯马尔遗址还有椭圆形底座的术士金字塔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么玛雅金字塔顶部没有尖锥呢？这与两类金字塔的不同功能有关。埃及金字塔是法老陵墓，内部是空心的，建有墓室存放法老木乃伊；而玛雅金字塔是神庙的基座，建造它的目的在于彰显神庙的崇高，因此玛雅金字塔一般是实心的，为了留出空间造神庙，必须在顶端留出一片平台，故而没有顶锥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于功能不同，两类金字塔的外形和体量也颇有区别。玛雅金字塔顶端建有神庙，祭司需要登坛作法或者夜观星相，因此在其正反两侧或前后左右四面的中轴线上均设有石阶；而埃及金字塔作为法老陵墓并不需要登顶，故而仅在底部设有陵墓入口，不设石阶通往顶锥。同样出于祭祀需要，玛雅金字塔普遍不高，最高的蒂卡尔四号神庙才64.6米，与埃及金字塔相比可以说小巫见大巫：埃及最高的胡夫金字塔建成时高达146.6米，经过4500年的风沙侵蚀，现在仍高138.8米，超过蒂卡尔四号神庙的两倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于建筑土方量与尺寸的立方成正比，玛雅金字塔比埃及金字塔的尺寸小一个数量级，故而其所需建材以及工程量远远小于后者，建造数量也就大大高出后者。根据不完全统计，仅墨西哥境内就有玛雅式金字塔十万多座，而埃及金字塔不过寥寥一百多座而已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔最重要的金字塔共有四座，其中大广场的东西两侧各有一座，取夫妻对望之意。东侧的一号神庙建成于八世纪中期，高44米，是玛雅世界罕见的陵墓型金字塔，埋葬的是蒂卡尔的中兴名主双月王&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil I，682—734年在位）&lt;/span>;，他于695年率领城邦穿越丛林战胜宿敌卡拉克穆尔，使后者一蹶不振，只能靠暗地里煽动叛乱削弱科潘那样的小花招来减轻来自蒂卡尔的军事压力，而蒂卡尔则进入了第二次鼎盛时期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;210475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;双月王石碑浮雕像&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一号神庙的石阶又窄又陡，曾造成至少两名游客失足坠亡，如今已禁止游客攀爬。西侧的二号神庙也是陵墓，葬的是双月王的皇后十二金刚鹦鹉夫人&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Lady Twelve Macaw)&lt;/span>;。她的陵墓比丈夫的金字塔矮六米，石阶较宽，但也已禁止直接攀爬，而是在其背后搭建了木制台阶，供游人步行上至塔顶，俯瞰典雅静谧的大广场。广场上竖立着二十多根石柱，它们与科潘遗迹大广场上的石像作用相同，用于追念先王勒石纪功，但蒂卡尔的石刻艺术远不如科潘，所以这里并无石像而只有石柱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔的三号神庙位于二号神庙西侧，其基座正面已经为植被所覆盖，泯然土坡矣，湮没在了茂密的丛林中，但高达55米的塔顶巍然屹立，远远高出周围的乔木，以自然与人力跨越沧海桑田的顽强角力给观者带来强烈震撼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，如今我们看到的蒂卡尔神庙都是经过考古发掘，剥离其树木、清理其泥土、修复其石阶之后的产物。在19世纪初欧洲考古探险队刚刚来到这里的时候，所有的金字塔都是三号神庙现在这副模样，乍一看无非是平地上突然拔起的一座座陡峭土山而已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四号神庙位于遗址核心区的西侧尽头，它由双月王的儿子建成于741年，是蒂卡尔最高的神庙，也是玛雅世界最高的建筑物。从它的顶部平台向东眺望一、二、三号神庙，很容易产生错觉，仿佛脚下连绵的热带雨林乔木只是一片低矮的灌木丛，而那三座神庙仿佛三座石碑，从灌木丛里顽强地伸出来——万物的尺度在这里突然缩小了，我仿佛进入了一个缩微世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“失落的世界”中的一座神庙&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从四号神庙出发，我继续向南深入雨林，寻找始建于公元前700年的古老金字塔“失落的世界”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（El Mundo Perdido）&lt;/span>;。游客逐渐稀少，密林间只剩下我、迎面而来的一群高高摇着长尾怡然漫步的白鼻浣熊，以及回荡在山林间的低沉嘶吼声。起初我以为那只是园方通过扩音器播放的背景音——因为如果真有哪只食肉目猛兽发出如此巨大的声响，那就意味着它已经到达我的周围，随时可以发起猎杀——还很诧异于播放者的独特趣味，后来才意识到那摄人心魄的怒吼声来自头顶的树枝：两只中等身材的吼猴正焦躁地来回爬行，以连绵不断的嘶吼宣示本族群的地界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双月王所开辟的盛世延续了将近一百年。进入九世纪之后，整个玛雅世界进入七千年不遇的干旱期，饿殍遍地，城邦凋敝。作为当时最大的城邦，极盛时拥有近二十万人口的蒂卡尔，面临饥荒后迅速衰落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒂卡尔最后一个载入史册的国王复用了双月王的名字，自称为Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil二世，但这并没有让他战胜自然，重振国运。到十世纪末时，蒂卡尔重新被大自然收复，玉米田庄不复存在，雄伟的神庙和先王的陵墓为密林所覆盖。也就是从那个时候开始，吼猴们在曾经的城邦中心建立家园，发出这几公里之外都能听到的威猛之声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么全国大部分打印店都“姓”湘？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;走进大学校园，如果你发现打印店老板说着一口转调丰富的“塑普”，不必过于惊讶，因为当你继续留意，会发现这一口音甚至遍布全国大街小巷的打印店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;湖南人，不仅是吃辣界的扛把子，在文印界也底气十足。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;事实上，位于湖南中部的新化县就挑起了“文印湘军团”的重担。据统计，新化文印产业在全国高校和全国文印行业分别包揽了95%和70%以上的市场份额。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;把店铺开遍全国的不止兰州拉面和沙县小吃，还有新化人的文印店。如今，新化文印产业在全国660多个城市开出了15万多家的图文快印店、3000多家的复印机再制造与经销企业和2000多家的耗材生产和销售企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新化文印之所以席卷全国，还得从洋溪小镇说起。多年前，一篇北大博士论文《新化复印产业的生命史》走红网络，其中就揭秘了新化人通过“传帮带”将一纸图文开出千亿产业的秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个偏居一隅的小城自古有“以技补农”的传统。洋溪人从偶然学会机械打字机维修技术，到团结一批维修技术人员走向全国，再到依靠维修技术发展二手复印机事业，一步步实现文印产业的迭代升级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在打字、复印、绘图、晒图、文印设备与再制造、耗材制造与经营这条完整的产业链上，三十多万名新化籍文印技术人员闯荡大江南北，在“无纸化办公”冲击下，新化文印产业仍然蒸蒸日上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从“引进制造”到“自主智造”，新化文印正摆脱桎梏枷锁，打响“新化文印”的世界名片。如今，高速喷墨蓝图机等自主知识产权产品正加速行业变革；新化文印走出国门，将文印产品落户到超80个国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;手机壳、文具、鼠标垫、背景墙……这些备受年轻人喜欢的DIY个性化印刷也成为新化文印人的“致富高光”，以喵喵机为代表的新型打印产品、3D打印产品等给新化文印创造了更多可能性。如今，被称为“中国文印之都”的新化还在霸气宣告着属于自己的“印”实力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今天，“知道”带你了解“统治”全国大小打印店的“湘”字号生意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 21:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九华山：气象万千的水墨丹青丨眼睛在旅游⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257609]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>