<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江省人大常委会原副主任宋希斌一审获刑14年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258838]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/8d32eea8c44f27b9b172302b6fc2430a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/18/8d32eea8c44f27b9b172302b6fc2430a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 17, 2023, the Shenyang Intermediate People’s Court of Liaoning Province publicly pronounced the verdict of the Heilongjiang Provincial People’s Congress Standing Committee in the first instance In the case of former party member and deputy director Song Xibin accepting bribes and embezzling public funds, the defendant Song Xibin was sentenced to 13 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 3 million; he was sentenced to three years in prison for embezzling public funds and decided to execute the term He was sentenced to 14 years in prison and fined RMB 3 million; the property obtained from bribery and the interest therefrom shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;It was found after trial: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From 2005 to 2021, the defendant Song Xibin successively used his position as the Daxinganling Prefectural Committee of Heilongjiang Province Deputy Secretary, Administrative Commissioner, Director of the Forestry Administration, Secretary of the Daxinganling Prefectural Committee, Director of the Heilongjiang Provincial Development and Reform Commission, Deputy Secretary of the Harbin Municipal Committee and Mayor, Member and Deputy Director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Heilongjiang Provincial People&#39;s Congress, Chairman of the Heilongjiang Provincial Federation of Trade Unions, etc. With the convenience in the field, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of authority and status, it provided assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, land replacement, project contracting, job promotion, etc., and illegally accepted property from others equivalent to more than 35.32 million yuan. In 2014, Song Xibin took advantage of his position as deputy secretary of the Harbin Municipal Party Committee and mayor to seek personal interests and decided to lend 50 million yuan of Harbin&#39;s special fiscal funds to other units in the name of his unit for profit-making activities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Shenyang Intermediate People’s Court held that defendant Song Xibin’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes and misappropriating public funds. In view of the fact that Song Xibin truthfully confessed his crimes after arriving at the case, and took the initiative to explain most of the criminal facts of bribery and misappropriation of public funds that were not yet known to the supervisory authorities. The crime of misappropriation of public funds constituted surrender; he pleaded guilty and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribes and stolen goods have been recovered, and the misappropriated goods have been recovered. All public funds have been recovered before the first instance trial, and there are legal, discretionary or mitigated punishment circumstances. According to the law, he can be given a lighter punishment for the crime of accepting bribes and a reduced punishment for the crime of misappropriating public funds. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电梯事故频频发生，一图读懂如何自救？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258923]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/19/9849783f0d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;8581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 19/9849783f0d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254649&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（上）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258853]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/bOI8j4tun986ghWujNQdJnuMPrxPcdSK9CR1TImi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/bOI8j4tun986ghWujNQdJnuMPrxPcdSK9CR1 TImi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between 1872 and 1875, initiated by Rong Hong and supported by Zeng Guofan and Li Hongzhang , the Qing government sent four batches of 120 students to study in the United States. The average age of these students when they went abroad was only twelve years old. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Wedge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The exchanges between China and the United States, if we start with the opium epidemic in 1840 It has been almost two hundred years since the war began. The young republic of the United States is making its first cry. In such a long process, the ups and downs, grievances and resentments between China and the United States are a very complicated record. Since China switched to welcoming the world, the entanglement between China and the United States is probably more complicated than the relationship between China and any other country in history, and has far-reaching consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, after receiving the mission of writing this article from Mr. Chen Fangzheng, I thought about it for a long time - I felt that I should write: Because this big topic is not only related to China and the United States, It can almost be said that the fate of the world in the past two hundred years has been inseparable from Sino-US relations in many cases. The turn in Sino-US relations often leads to a turn in world history - of course, China&#39;s destiny also changes accordingly, and similarly the destiny of the United States is also turbulent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason I say this is because the basic pattern of Sino-US relations over the past two hundred years is: there is a host-object relationship between the strong and the weak. Because the United States has its own ideals, policies for founding the country, and choices it made to measure its position in the world at that time, if there are changes in its policy toward China, it will mostly be the United States that takes the initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, when discussing this issue, I often use the above perspective as a constantly changing clue to consider: Why did the United States do this in that specific time and space? In terms of Sino-U.S. relations, given the characteristics of time and space, how will the United States&#39; actions affect its own development direction and the overall international balance? Will the ensuing world situation lead to disaster or peace? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I dictated this article &quot;China and the United States since 1840&quot;, I actually had mixed feelings in my heart. The relationship between China and the United States has its share of grievances and grievances, as well as unavoidable entanglements. Looking around the world, the help we receive from the United States is more significant and far-reaching than that of other countries. However, China is even more constrained by the United States and forced to go in many unexpected directions - this is not what China wants, and it also has a great impact on China&#39;s overall history. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Trade between China and the United States&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1840, Britain and China fought the first Opium War. In fact, the opium traders operating in Hong Kong at that time were not only British, but also Americans. The United States, a recently established emerging country, has also followed the United Kingdom in participating in international trade—China trade is a piece of meat that it must get involved in. At that time, he was following Charles Elliot in planning how to use force to open China&#39;s trade door, and American businessman Thomas Perkins was also involved. To this day, the Perkins family is still an important part of the New England family in the United States. They did the same, bringing opium in ships and taking away Chinese porcelain, tea and other commercial goods. However, this kind of trade is not permitted by Chinese law, which means that Britain is already conducting trade while forcibly opening the door to China. Although it was Britain that launched the First Opium War, its sponsors also included American businessmen in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China was defeated in this war and was forced to sign the Treaty of Nanjing with Britain. In 1844, the United States sent envoy Caleb Cushing to sign the Treaty of Wangxia with Qi Ying, the general representative of China and the governor of Guangdong and Guangxi. Since then, China and the United States established diplomatic relations, and Gu Sheng was the first minister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking office as minister, Gu Sheng said that he was very excited and felt that this was a difficult responsibility. This youngest country, which had just emerged from the civil war and was involved in world politics and international relations for the first time, actually officially established relations with the longest-lived Eastern Empire in the world. He believed this was an important milestone in human history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I live in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA, and I would like to tell you something that is very meaningful to me. On February 2, 1784, the birthday of George Washington, the &quot;Empress of China&quot; sailed from New York Harbor to China. It was the first merchant ship sent by the United States to China. What they brought was not opium, but thirty tons of wild ginseng collected near Pittsburgh (known as &quot;American ginseng&quot; or &quot;American ginseng&quot; in China), as well as leather, pepper, cotton and other commodities; taken from China, It is porcelain, tea, silk and other commercial goods - these are the typical products sold by China to the United States in Sino-US trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On several occasions, as a staff member of Taiwan&#39;s &quot;Academia Sinica&quot;, I visited Harvard University to negotiate cooperation matters, and I stayed in Harvard hotels. This hotel is an old-fashioned New England residence, with a wooden house, ancient wooden beds, and the rooms are filled with Chinese porcelain shipped by American merchants in the early days. In addition to China&#39;s own porcelain, we can also see trade porcelain specially fired for the United States and Britain, and we can also see Chinese silk fabrics used as decoration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a scene made me feel that time and space were reversed: a young Chinese man went to the highest university in the United States to discuss academic cooperation - and in the room where I lived, all the people surrounding me were ancient Chinese objects. . This is something worthy of commemoration and worthy of my lifelong memories and emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, American merchant ships have entered China one after another. Although there were already motorized ships at that time, many of them had a combination of motors and sails. The &quot;Queen of China&quot; is a fairly large mixed-aircraft and sail ship, and the &quot;Chinese Scissor&quot; is even larger and faster. By around 1860, there were three ports for trading ships to depart from North America: San Francisco, Los Angeles, and Vancouver, Canada. They come and go regularly, traveling across the Pacific Ocean between the two coasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of the nineteenth century, the United States experienced the Civil War. The overall development direction has changed from developing new land to entering industrialization. Moreover, the most important projects in the development of the United States are the construction of large cross-state railways to the west, as well as the development of farmland and the construction of cities in the western half of the United States. Hundreds of thousands of Chinese workers provided important help in these tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the reason why the United States became the United States was that it transformed from an old British colony into a major country spanning two oceans. This process is of great significance to East Asia on the Pacific side; Sino-US relations have also gone through a very abnormal process. For example, Chinese workers who have made significant contributions are trapped by the Chinese Exclusion Act and cannot immigrate into the United States like European workers. As the United States has become a big country that spans two oceans, its industrial products can naturally enter the Chinese market more conveniently than Europe. Previously, the trade direction of Chinese daily necessities imported into the United States has since shifted to the direction of American products entering the Chinese market. Europeans competed for the trade markets of this vast and populous empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, these ships have brought countless Chinese young people to the United States for education. The first group of more than 100 Chinese children brought by Rong Hong entered American middle schools and then furthered their studies. After these &quot;young children studying in the United States&quot; returned to China after completing their studies, they worked in various fields such as diplomacy, business, and education. The beginning of this phase of Sino-US relations is of immeasurable significance to the Chinese people. The American influence brought by these people extended to the students who came to the United States under the so-called &quot;Gengzi Indemnity&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Gengzi Indemnity&lt;/span>;) - this Among them, a very important figure is Hu Shi; of course, there are many other figures, including my mentor Li Jizhi. More than half of them have made significant contributions to China&#39;s modernization, are either scholars in pioneering research fields, or are extraordinary people who have created extraordinary careers. They also include the Nationalist Government&#39;s ambassador to the United States and figures in charge of foreign affairs in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Education in the United States and Modern China&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the twentieth century, the world also changed a lot. The capitalist economy, which uses machine industry to produce goods, has swallowed up the entire world quickly and massively. Under this drastic change, white people not only became the masters of the world, but also competed among themselves for the &quot;leading&quot; position of exploiting the world. In Europe, there was World War I. In that war, the capitalist economy faced its first test: the germination and growth of international communism brought the world into the division of left and right; also in the modern Western state system, the communist system and its associated The ideal of symbiotic social good and social welfare. The United States only entered the war in the late stages of the European War. General John J. Pershing led the American war troops and declared to Britain and France: We are back and we are participating in the common affairs of the Old Continent. In Chinese history, the word &quot;West&quot; has since been divided into left and right sides; and this division has made China have to make choices in its struggle to break away from the old empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of importing Western ideas, American missionaries established schools in China, which was an important process. At the same time, the ideas brought to China by American intellectuals, including travelers, journalists, businessmen, and educators, therefore have at least two routes as their own choices, and the Chinese must choose. Similarly, the impressions they brought back from China have since then had two faces and images, left and right, resulting from their subjective choices and subjective descriptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest schools set up by Americans in China were affiliated middle schools run by missionaries to China in churches. It is difficult for us to say which middle school was opened earliest. Peking Union Medical College is the first modern medical school in China, as well as Xiangya Medical College in Hunan, West China Union University in Sichuan, and Qilu University in Shandong, all of which were founded by missionaries from the United States. Union Medical College adopts a method of integrating modern medical education with general hospitals and has become a model in China. Their influence extends to more remote provinces, such as Mingxian College in Shanxi, which was also established by American missionaries. During the Republic of China, in addition to the above-mentioned medical teaching, famous universities such as Yanjing University, Soochow University, Jinling University, and Zhijiang University were all founded by American missionaries and contributed to the development of education in modern China. In the field of history, Yenching University&#39;s Journal of Yenching, Academia Sinica&#39;s Journal of the Institute of History and Linguistics, and Tsinghua University&#39;s Journal of Tsinghua are collectively known as the &quot;Three University Journals.&quot; To this day, Tsinghua University on both sides of the Taiwan Strait is still a very important university, especially Tsinghua University in Beijing, which is the &quot;leading&quot; university in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Jen Middle School, where I study, was built by Chinese Christians in Shanghai who returned to their hometown of Wuxi. They believe that although they are not missionaries, they still set up schools with the service spirit of devout believers and in accordance with the educational level and teaching methods of British and American middle schools. Although these teachers from Furen Middle School only trained me for two and a half years (from the first semester of high school to the first semester of high school), they had a great influence on my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From university education to secondary education, the United States has a profound influence on China. Medicine and education were areas where missionaries focused their attention. In 1937, the American Bureau for Medical Aid to China was established. These people with ties to China were basically missionaries to China. They returned to the United States and advocated helping China during the Anti-Japanese War and donating Chinese medicine, equipment and doctors. When China was under blockade and faced extreme difficulties, plane after plane of U.S. aid supplies entered China via the &quot;hump route.&quot; This includes the newly invented penicillin, the first batch of which was shipped to China after it officially left the factory, which was of great help to China&#39;s wounded soldiers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, we should be grateful to them. Many missionaries stayed in China and stayed here until their old age; many missionaries considered China their hometown, and they said &quot;my hometown is in China&quot;; many missionaries protected Chinese children, Chinese wounded soldiers, and Chinese refugees during the Anti-Japanese War. By. In the case of the Nanjing Massacre, Jinling Women&#39;s University was designated as a &quot;protected area&quot;, and thousands of Chinese women fled there to receive rescue and avoid being ravaged by the Japanese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such things make us deeply moved. However, we also have entanglements. In U.S. trade with China, the U.S. is almost always outperforming and China is outperforming. And it is very regrettable that the United States also played a shameful role in the early opium trade: in terms of the amount of opium transported to China, the United States was not necessarily less than the United Kingdom—the United Kingdom and the United States were the largest opium traders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/nH28zc6Tg2jXZeoIuvq8661q4HgVq1t9k6cqsaER.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/nH28zc6Tg2jXZeoIuvq8661q4HgVq1t9k6cqsaER.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254580&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In January 1945, the first Chinese transport convoy drove through the Burma Highway. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The complex grievances between China and the United States&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The greater grievances between China and the United States Grudges appear in the middle of war. The first time the United States intervened in China&#39;s war was during the Taiping Rebellion. At that time, there were many foreigners in the Shanghai Concession, and there were also many Chinese people who fled there. In 1860, American Frederick T. Ward led the formation of a &quot;foreign gun team&quot;. This group of mercenaries was small in number and very elite. Initially to defend the Shanghai concession, he later left the concession to help Li Hongzhang&#39;s Huai army and the Hunan army Zeng Guoquan&#39;s troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late Qing Dynasty, the revolution led by Dr. Sun Yat-sen used the United States as a model in its early stages - although he did not seriously understand the various internal debates and struggles after the founding of the United States of America, nor did he study the impact of the American Civil War on American politics. Institutional influence. Later, the &quot;civil rights&quot; of the &quot;Three People&#39;s Principles&quot; were only explained in general terms. But after Sun Yat-sen established his government in Guangzhou, he had a most important struggle. He got rid of the influence of the Japanese ronin &quot;Xuanyang Society&quot;, but he also gained support from the new international communism in Europe and accepted some of their ideas. More importantly, the first revolutionary army organized by Sun Yat-sen to build New China received 8,000 rifles from the Communist International in Russia in the name of Whampoa Military Academy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sun Yat-sen&#39;s conception, the prototype of people&#39;s livelihood doctrine is &quot;land to the tiller.&quot; This is also a dream shared by the peasant revolutionary armies in Chinese history, including the aforementioned &quot;Taiping Heavenly Kingdom&quot; rebels. After the establishment of the government in Guangzhou, cooperation with the Communist International led to the emergence of opposition between the left and the right within the Kuomintang, which also fundamentally changed the connotation of his &quot;people&#39;s livelihood doctrine&quot;: &quot;People&#39;s livelihood doctrine is socialism.&quot; Sun Yat-sen&#39;s ideal Changes also caused the blueprint for the founding of the Republic of China to not only cause ideological opposition between the left and right in the future struggle between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party, but also lead to opposition between important party members. After his death, the so-called &quot;Ning-Han split&quot; originated from this. The right wing led by Chiang Kai-shek has since lost the support of the Kuomintang left wing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time the United States intervened in China&#39;s war was during the Anti-Japanese War. At the beginning of the Anti-Japanese War, China lost 800 aircraft within a month and nearly 3,000 aircraft during the entire Anti-Japanese War. Japan had the best aircraft in the world at that time, but China did not have the ability to manufacture them. It could only buy various types of aircraft from foreign countries and form them into an air force combat force. Therefore, China&#39;s airspace was abused by the Japanese at will. When the Chinese army is fighting, the bombs falling from the sky are more helpless than the bullets on the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Claire L. Chennault, an American aerial aerobatic team member, organized American aerial athletes who were not afraid of death and established a Chinese Air Force American Volunteer Group (American Volunteer Group) in a private name. &quot;Flying Tigers&quot;. Their team members are dedicated aerobatic pilots who can climb out of the cabin and walk on the wings of a flying aircraft. They can take off in farm fields, land on barn roofs, do somersaults in the air without falling, and even swing in mid-air from a rope dangled from an airplane. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, they used aircraft that had been retired by the U.S. Air Force. After the &quot;Pearl Harbor&quot; incident, the United States entered the war and reorganized this civilian force into the Fourteenth Air Force, with Chennault as commander. Since the establishment of this aviation force, I remember that starting in 1942, we could finally sleep peacefully in Chongqing. Our troops were fighting the Japanese and were covered by aircraft in the sky. China lost thousands of pilots during the War of Resistance. Slowly, our pilots can also fly the same aircraft as those in the United States and fight side by side with the &quot;Flying Tigers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although these athletes from the United States are not in vain: they are rewarded with five taels of gold for each mission, and ten taels of gold for shooting down a Japanese plane. Everyone returned with dozens of pounds of gold. You know, the value of gold at that time was different from today; but among these young people, there were also a large number of them who left their lives in China. It is now estimated that they lost about 400 men from 1942 to 1945. As for whether they died for wealth or for righteousness, we can ignore it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we particularly want to mention is the commercial exchanges between China and the United States. There are banks from many countries in the concessions of Shanghai and other treaty ports, the largest of which are the &quot;bank group&quot; of the United Kingdom and the United States, especially the British HSBC and the American Citibank. HSBC is still one of the largest banks in the world, and Citibank of the United States is the most involved in China&#39;s financial operations. The reason is that China’s first finance ministers who understood modern finance were Kong Xiangxi and Song Ziwen—Song Ziwen studied at Columbia University, and Kong Xiangxi graduated from Yale University. They brought the most important banking facilities in the United States to China. Therefore, China&#39;s first central bank was designed and operated according to the Bank of America, and regarded Citibank as a friend bank. When it overdrafted, it had Citibank as its backing. Without this backing, Chiang Kai-shek&#39;s central bank would have no credibility; and the central bank was one of the most important factors in Chiang Kai-shek&#39;s rule over China - not just with his army, but with a modern financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Stock Exchange is the first international exchange in the East. Together with the Wall Street, London and Tokyo Stock Exchanges, it has become the four important world financial trading points. This operation involves China&#39;s modern finance and modern economic operations into the world economic network. Few people pay attention to this. During this period, the United States squeezed China&#39;s finances more and less often helped China&#39;s finances. But in terms of importing this system into China, it can be said that no other country in the world can import its entire financial system into other countries, and have its most important bank as its backing. After the success of the Northern Expedition, Chiang Kai-shek established China&#39;s modern government, modern industry, national industry, national defense, etc. so quickly, all of which were inseparable from the financial support behind the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, because the Eight-Power Allied Forces invaded Beijing, defeated the Qing army, and obtained 450 million taels of silver compensation from China - China had a population of 450 million at that time, which was equivalent to one tael of silver per person as compensation. . This reparation was known as the &quot;Gengzi Indemnity&quot; in history. Russia and Germany accounted for the largest proportion, followed by France, Britain, Japan, the United States, Italy and other countries. Japan used this compensation and the previous Sino-Japanese War compensation for domestic business and construction, which became the largest capital for later occupying the three northeastern provinces and even launching a full-scale war of aggression against China. The United States returned part of this compensation to China as a special fund for the latter&#39;s education development; subsequently, Britain, France and other countries returned part of the compensation. Tsinghua University was established with its support. When each new national university was established, funds were allocated from the &quot;Geng Geng Fund&quot; to support its construction - this was the case for the Central University, which was restructured from Liangjiang Normal School, and for national and provincial universities in various places. Until the end, when Tsinghua University in Taiwan resumed school, it still used a very small balance of the &quot;Genggen money&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1909, when the United States returned part of the &quot;Gang money&quot; to support China&#39;s education, to 1964, when Tsinghua University in Taiwan resumed school, the &quot;Gang money&quot; continued to have an impact on China&#39;s education for such a long time. But to put it another way, the &quot;Gengg money&quot; is a huge debt that China has borne. This group of foreign banking syndicates lent money to China - China did not have huge funds to pay the compensation, so it could only borrow money from the World Bank syndicate to pay. When the refund comes, the original loan will still be in the World Bank Group. We can only withdraw interest and deduct what he needs for himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last &quot;geng money&quot; payment was handled by my late father, Boxiang Gong, when he was transferred to the Ministry of Finance as a customs supervisor. After the unequal treaty was terminated in 1942, he was responsible for sorting out the remaining balance of the &quot;Gengg money&quot; and the method of compensation. During the difficult and difficult period of the War of Resistance, the Westerners did not forgive us this debt. My late father was about fifty years old at the time. Every time he came back at night, he would look at the accounts and feel very sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 7, 1941, Christmas Eve, Japan attacked Pearl Harbor and the United States entered the war. Finally, because of its status as an allied member, China canceled all unequal treaties. This is tantamount to lifting the burden that China has carried for decades. Since then, the relationship between the United States and China has entered a new stage. The original civilian identity of the &quot;Flying Tigers&quot; became the Fourteenth Air Force of the United States. The Chinese Expeditionary Force also went abroad from Tengchong to rescue the British army in Burma. This army was incorporated into the command sequence of the Allied Powers, the Chinese, British and American Allied Forces. The United States also sent a representative, General Joseph Stilwell, as the chief of staff of the Chinese theater. Stilwell wanted to be the commander-in-chief of the Chinese theater and command the entire Chinese army, but Chiang Kai-shek disagreed. Since then, the U.S. military has intervened in China&#39;s military, and there have been endless grievances and resentments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last two years of the Anti-Japanese War, American aircraft flew over the &quot;Hump Route&quot; to transport supplies to China and also provided aircraft for the Chinese Air Force via this route. On land, the Stilwell Highway, the road from India to China via Myanmar, was also opened, and truckloads of supplies entered China, all under the command of Stilwell. China needs his permission to call in these troops. When the Chinese army is fighting on the front line and every second counts, it often misses the opportunity because it needs to see the battle plan. On a battlefield thousands of miles away, the battle situation is changing rapidly. How to provide a battle plan? This makes the last stage of China&#39;s battle still very difficult because there are people on the side who are restricting it. Of course, in the last battle in Changde, if American military planes had not transported reinforcements from afar to Changde, we would not have been able to stop the Japanese from marching in. This was a very significant help provided by the United States to China during the Anti-Japanese War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese part of the Stilwell Highway was dug by hand in the mountains of Yunnan by villagers from various ethnic groups. More than 2,000 trucks entered China from Myanmar. In fact, the United States donated about 4,000 trucks to China. Half of them overturned on the Stilwell Highway. These cars were driven in by young overseas Chinese from Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore and other places who went to Myanmar to join the army as volunteers - they had never learned to drive such cars, and more than 2,000 people remained in the ravine forever. They originally wanted to return to their motherland to help in the war of resistance, but they had never even set foot on the land of their motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early days of the Anti-Japanese War, in order to win assistance from the United States, Hu Shi, the Nationalist Government’s ambassador to the United States, gave fifty or sixty speeches across the United States. Chiang Kai-shek&#39;s wife, Ms. Soong Meiling, also made a special speech in the U.S. Congress, which changed Americans&#39; impression of China away from the image of Chinese workers in the United States. At the same time, American journalists and writers, especially Pearl S. Buck and Henry Luce (Chinese name Lu Siyi), publisher of Time and Life magazines, continued to introduce to the American public China’s sufferings. struggle in. On the other hand, as the Japanese front in northern China advanced westward, cadres sent by the Eighth Route Army behind enemy lines took control of the countryside. American missionaries and visitors to China in those areas, and later including John S. Service, a staff member of the U.S. embassy and consulate, conveyed news from the north to the United States. Among them, Edgar Snow&#39;s news reports had an immeasurable influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This divergence of public opinion, coupled with the confrontation between Stilwell and Chiang Kai-shek, caused an important conflict in the relationship and cooperation between China and the United States in the final period of World War II. After World War II, &quot;McCarthyism&quot; emerged in the United States, causing serious divisions between the left and the right in the United States. That rift led to the so-called &quot;who lost China&quot; debate. Going a step further, the United States looks back at post-World War II Europe with the same mentality. The rise of the Soviet Union and the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party in China led to nearly two decades after World War II. The United States tended to resist and contain communist countries in the world it led and its related foreign policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of the Anti-Japanese War, the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party began, and the United States became inexplicably entangled in it. The United States sent the &quot;Dixie Mission&quot; composed of diplomats such as Xie Weisi and others to visit Yan&#39;an. They came back and said: Yan&#39;an is the hope of the future, Chongqing is a dark place; Chongqing is going to decline, and Yan&#39;an is going to rise; help Yan&#39;an , don’t help Chongqing. It’s hard for us to say what’s good and bad between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Compiled by Chen Xinhua, Associate Professor of Shenzhen Administration Institute)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[陕西省政协原党组书记、主席韩勇被查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258925]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Han Yong, former Party Secretary and Chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection Disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 20:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为“被强奸”母亲讨公道的女儿丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cheng Haiyan in the old house. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1479ae442e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1479ae442e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cheng Haiyan is here Old house. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interviewing the suspected humiliation and suicide case of 44-year-old peasant woman Yi Yonghong in Wenchang, Hainan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; For details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/256716?source=131&quot;>;After eight days of struggling in the vortex of being raped, a 44-year-old peasant woman chose to commit suicide&lt;/a>;&quot; &lt;/span>;), after going through certain twists and turns, I was able to interview Yi Yonghong’s husband Cheng Shanzhi, and learned about Yi Yonghong’s experiences during his lifetime, as well as the hardships of this family who immigrated to Hainan from Hunan. But what I want to interview most is Yi Yonghong’s daughter Cheng Haiyan. My intuition tells me that this post-00s girl’s narration of this sad story should be more worth listening to. It turns out that this prediction was correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Cheng Haiyan is the eldest daughter in the family. She also has a younger brother suffering from leukemia. She had just passed the college-to-undergraduate examination and was a freshman in Haikou. After her mother committed suicide by drowning, her grieving father fell into depression, and her younger brother was sick. As the only person in the family who had gone to college, she needed to support the crumbling family in a short time. She feels that the burden on her body is too heavy, and most of the time she carries it by force. &quot;I&#39;m very tired, but there&#39;s nothing I can do about it,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan deliberately stayed away from the extremely simple home in Wenchang, not only because of the poor material conditions of the rental house, but also because she had long recognized the old mentality of favoring sons over daughters in her family. So in addition to studying at school, she will use her spare time and holidays to work in Haikou, &quot;waiter, dishwasher, dishwasher, front desk cashier, banquet waiter, handing out leaflets, event security, militia for epidemic prevention, everything she can do.&quot; . From June 10, 2023, to the day of Yi Yonghong&#39;s suicide on July 23, Cheng Haiyan worked as a cashier in a supermarket in Haikou, earning 2,600 yuan a month, not including food and accommodation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan is also a good hand when helping the family. She bagged and packaged guavas, and could finish at least 2,000 of them in a day, which was equivalent to earning 200 yuan when working for other people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But fate played a cruel joke on Cheng Haiyan. She wanted to stay away from home, but she had to become the backbone of the family without her mother, the sister that her younger brothers could rely on, the daughter who made decisions and ideas, and she had to socialize with relatives as a junior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can clearly feel that although she knows that her mother worked hard and raised her up, Cheng Haiyan does not want to be a woman like Yi Yonghong. Maybe Cheng Haiyan doesn&#39;t necessarily know what kind of person she wants to be, but she is really trying not to repeat her mother&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong also supports her daughter in doing this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days before Yi Yonghong committed suicide, Cheng Haiyan returned to Wenchang to be with her mother. When she was taking a bath in the water room, a &quot;crazy male&quot; in the village put his head under the threshold to peek, muttering &quot;so beautiful&quot;. In panic, Cheng Haiyan hit him with her clothes and called the police, but the other party produced proof of schizophrenia, making Cheng Haiyan angry and helpless. The police told her not to take it to heart, but Cheng Haiyan couldn&#39;t do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her daughter was spied on, Yi Yonghong urged her to return to Haikou quickly. Cheng Haiyan still regrets that she was unable to bring her mother back to Haikou and leave that environment as she wished. If she had left, maybe she wouldn&#39;t have committed suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Throughout the interview, Cheng Haiyan recounted two scenes that were extremely cruel to her. One is the scene after Yoshinaga committed suicide in the reservoir. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Cheng Haiyan rushed home on July 23, she found that the door was locked and her mother was not at home. When she saw her mother’s mobile phone and wallet on the bed, Cheng Haiyan immediately panicked because her mother never Don’t carry your wallet with you. She and her father Cheng Shanzhi searched separately, calling her aunt and uncle while searching. Finally, she rushed over following her father&#39;s cry, &quot;I saw that my father had been crying and his clothes were soaked. My father was already there. I couldn&#39;t stop crying. My mother was so hard that she looked like she was sleeping, with her mouth open.&quot; At that time, Cheng Haiyan &quot;felt very hot, dizzy, dizzy, and couldn&#39;t see.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the whole interview, I think the most painful thing is that Cheng Haiyan recalled the second cold scene in a calm tone - in order to find new evidence, she was also afraid that her mother would be frozen for too long, and she hoped to be buried as soon as possible. , she and her brother decided to perform an autopsy on their mother. Cheng Haiyan stood aside, supporting her crying father, and witnessed the forensic autopsy and the funeral home staff suturing her mother. She wanted to see if there were any injuries on her mother&#39;s body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan mentioned a detail. Before the autopsy, a cockroach crawled out of Yi Yonghong&#39;s trousers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan was crying and picking at her fingernails. She said she didn’t know what to do and was very scared because it was her family members who were being dissected. She majored in nursing, so she could roughly describe the forensic workflow, including the path of the scalpel on Yi Yonghong&#39;s body, and the slight &quot;deformation&quot; of her mother under the scalpel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She left and was stabbed. I feel very sorry for her.&quot; At the same time, Cheng Haiyan was also extremely angry, &quot;I feel hated to the core of my bones.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the report was published, Cheng Haiyan was willing to give her real name. I believe that having experienced and dealt with such a major ups and downs in life, Cheng Haiyan will be stronger than she thinks she is. She was able to go to the police station with seven or eight veteran friends and decided to call the police after being spied on. She bravely questioned the police and confronted the perpetrators. Especially after witnessing her mother&#39;s anatomy, Cheng Haiyan was definitely no longer the little girl she used to be. Now, she will become a different person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老人如何安度晚年？“9073”意味着家庭养老仍是主流模式丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258844]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the &quot;Statistical Bulletin on the Development of Civil Affairs in 2022&quot; released by the Ministry of Civil Affairs shows: As of the end of 2022, 60 There are 280.04 million elderly people aged 1 year and above, accounting for 19.8% of the total population; of which 209.78 million people are 65 years old and above, accounting for 14.9% of the total population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing data from the previous year: As of the end of 2021, the country’s elderly population aged 60 and over was 267.36 million, accounting for 18.9% of the total population, of which 200.56 million were aged 65 and over, accounting for 18.9% of the total population. 14.2%. Within one year, the number of elderly people aged 60 and above and those aged 65 and above increased by 0.9 and 0.7 percentage points respectively. The former had a net increase of 12.68 million people and the latter had a net increase of 9.22 million. The aging of Chinese society has further intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two reasons for China&#39;s aging population. One is the increase in life expectancy; the other is the decrease in the number of newborns. In 2016, the first year of the implementation of the comprehensive two-child policy, there were 17.86 million newborns, which may be the last historical high. It dropped to 17.23 million the next year, and then broke through the one or two million mark every year. By 2022, it dropped to 9.56 million, a decrease of 46.5% compared with 2016, and it was almost halved in just six years. As a result, the issue of how to provide for the elderly has become more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Shanghai took the lead in proposing the goal of the &quot;9073&quot; elderly care service pattern, that is, 90% of the elderly will be provided with home care, 7% will be provided with community care, and 3% will be provided with institutional care. In April 2021, Wang Haidong, director of the Department of Aging and Health of the National Health Commission, said that most of the elderly in our country care for themselves at home and in the community, forming a &quot;9073&quot; pattern, that is, about 90% of the elderly care at home, and about 7% of the elderly rely on community support for their elderly care, and 3% of the elderly live in institutions for their elderly care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a 2023 survey by the Civil Affairs Bureau of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee Social Work Committee found that more than 99% of the elderly in Beijing choose home care, while less than 1% choose institutional care. It can be seen that no matter from the perspective of local and national elderly care strategies or from the actual situation, the overwhelming elderly care model for the elderly is still home care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that raising children to provide for old age has not become a thing of the past as some people imagine. From another perspective, raising children can also be regarded as an investment: not only will the children work when they grow up, they will transfer payments to their elderly parents and provide part of the pension funds; if the parents are seriously ill and need medical treatment and care, the children will be The role of women is irreplaceable: providing money, effort, and hands-on work for children is only one aspect; helping parents who are disabled or even mentally ill to advocate and defend their rights is also an important aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if you pay someone to take care of you, the elderly will have a higher probability of receiving better care if they have their own children with sound physical and mental abilities to supervise them at any time. When a disabled elderly person lies in bed at home and cannot move, the nanny hired has an incentive not to work as hard as he can. If he does not have his own children, it will be difficult for the disabled elderly person to advocate and protect his rights. Confucianism talks about &quot;being cautious about independence&quot;, which is a very high moral cultivation. It is difficult to require nannies or caregivers hired from the market to have such high moral awareness and professional ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, children may also be disobedient and unfilial, but there is an ongoing blood and family relationship between children and their parents. From a human perspective, if you don’t have confidence in taking care of your children and raising yourself, how can you have so much confidence in an outsider who has no blood relationship or feelings with you? This is a logical question as well as a human nature question. Moreover, if you are not confident in educating a child with normal values ​​and respect and respect for your parents, how can you have so much confidence in the retirement arrangements you designed decades in advance? This is also a logical question. Since we are talking about risks, we need to calculate the magnitude of different risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, many people work and live in cities and pay social security, which creates the illusion that &quot;they can provide for themselves in old age and do not need their children to provide for them.&quot; In fact, this pay-as-you-go social security model is essentially an intergenerational transfer payment from young people, workers and the next generation to the elderly, retirees and the previous generation, or &quot;all children support all parents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if we look at a single family, retirement care is not just a question of how much pension there is. No matter how much money you have, whether you hire someone to take care of you at home or live in a luxury nursing home, you must ensure that you can spend the money on yourself so that you can receive good care when you become disabled or even lose your mind. At this time, your sons and daughters, who are physically and mentally sound, are by your side to help you advocate and defend your rights. Their role is irreplaceable. If you have no children, and you have young close relatives with good nature, such as nephews and nieces, to act as children, or have close friends with deep feelings to help, then it is naturally possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investing in financial assets and saving money for retirement may seem like a good choice, but there are still the same problems that cannot be circumvented. When you are able to walk and move, you live in a nursing home because you can advocate and defend your rights, so you can get good care; but when you become disabled or even mentally ill, or you are conscious but unable to move in bed, or You are also unconscious and therefore unable to assert and defend your rights. Whether you can receive necessary medical and care services depends on the conscience of the nursing home operators and caregivers. Of course, there will be supervision by government agencies, but in terms of intensity and meticulousness, I am afraid it cannot replace the &quot;supervision&quot; of one&#39;s own children or close relatives or close friends who are good-natured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above sense, it is not difficult for us to understand why home care and family care are still the main modes of care for the elderly. Behind this is still supported by the concept and practice of &quot;raising children for old age&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine Outside the emergency clinic, parents wait with their children. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254373&quot;>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, parents waited with their children outside the emergency clinic on the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It’s mycoplasma again!” On October 16, 2023, Dr. Ding Guodong from Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine originally planned to see 30 special needs numbers in the morning, but he temporarily I added 10 numbers and it didn&#39;t end until one o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The doctors in our department are basically full every day, and the inpatient beds are also very tight. Some children may have to wait for several days before they can be admitted.” Ding Guodong is the deputy chief physician of the Department of Pediatric Respiratory Medicine. This overloaded work rhythm with my colleagues has started in mid-September. &quot;At this stage, almost 90% of the hospitalized children in the pediatric respiratory department are infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and there are many cases of drug resistance of Mycoplasma pneumoniae.&quot; . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae has a diameter of 50-300 nanometers, nearly one thousandth the diameter of a human hair. It is a microorganism between bacteria and viruses. Pneumonia caused by this microorganism is the most common community-acquired pneumonia in children aged 5 and above in China (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;refers to infectious diseases suffered outside the hospital Pulmonary parenchymal inflammation&lt;/span>;), mostly occurs in autumn and winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of the school season in September, not only Shanghai, but also hospitals in Beijing, Hebei, Jiangsu and other places have seen more children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and they tend to be younger. According to a CCTV News report on October 13, the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases has increased across the country recently, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae has entered the season of high incidence. Children need timely medical treatment and appropriate medication. &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;&quot;There are 246 people in front of you&quot;&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;Before four o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 15, Qin Nannan finally registered her son. At this time, a deputy chief physician at Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital The number has been queued to No. 556. While waiting for treatment, she discovered that someone had already received more than 800 numbers. Finally arrived&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[禁养名单、品种数、体高均有差异，数看15城禁养犬有何不同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258908]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Chengdu girl was bitten by a fierce dog incident&quot; once again triggered people&#39;s discussion on civilized dog breeding. Narada Big Data Research Institute combed through the management regulations and banned dog breeding regulations in the top 15 cities with GDP in 2022 and found that the list of banned dogs and the number of banned dog breeds are different in different places. Rottweilers are used by Beijing, Shanghai, Cities such as Guangzhou are clearly listed on the list of prohibited dogs, while Chengdu and Shenzhen are not prohibited. Moreover, many places have different standards for the shoulder height and body length of banned large dogs. Beijing requires key management areas to prohibit the breeding of aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult height of more than 35 centimeters. Tianjin, Wuhan, Hangzhou and other cities have mentioned bans on breeding. Violent dogs and dog breeds with a body height exceeding 45 centimeters. Nanjing, Suzhou and other cities have clearly banned the breeding of ferocious dogs, large dogs and other adult dogs with a body height (shoulder height) exceeding 61 centimeters as determined by the public security organs and veterinary authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/48466fe39e17ef0662e7a589ea8ea87c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1563&quot; height=&quot;3362&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/48466fe39e17ef0662e7a589ea8ea87c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254636&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;*Relevant management regulations for dog breeding in some cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Beijing, Tianjin, Hangzhou, Hanning and other cities&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Dog management regulations have not been updated for more than 16 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;For In response to incidents of vicious dogs injuring people in cities, each city has now issued regulations prohibiting or strictly controlling dogs, involving dog vaccinations, registration, dog-raising behavior standards, etc., including the types of dogs that are prohibited. Among the 15 cities included in the statistics, each city has issued at least two regulations related to dog breeding management, involving dog breeding management regulations, animal epidemic prevention regulations, or regulations on the promotion of civilized behavior, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The review found that Tianjin has the largest number of dog-raising management regulations, including the &quot;Tianjin Dog-raising Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Tianjin Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot;, &quot;Tianjin Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot; 5 items including Tianjin Dog Registration and Dog Registration Management Measures&quot; and Tianjin Dog Breeding Epidemic Prevention Management Measures. Followed by Beijing and Chongqing, each with 4 items. Beijing has the &quot;Beijing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Beijing Dog Breeding Registration and Annual Inspection Management Measures&quot;, &quot;Beijing City Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot;, and &quot;Beijing Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot;; Chongqing has &quot;Chongqing Municipal Interim Measures for Dog Breeding Management&quot;, &quot;Chongqing Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Chongqing Municipal Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot; and &quot;Chongqing Municipal Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dog management regulations are an important basis and specific reference for law enforcement in many cities. However, after sorting out the latest revision time or implementation time of some cities, it was found that among the 15 cities, Beijing, Tianjin, Hangzhou, and Wuhan Cities such as Beijing and Nanjing have not revised relevant dog management regulations for more than 16 years, and the longest has been 20 years. As early as 2017, the Hangzhou Municipal Urban Management Committee stated in response to a media interview that the revision of the regulations was included in the research project of the Hangzhou Municipal Government’s 2016 Legislative Work Plan. In 2018, the Nanjing Municipal People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee has revised the &quot;Nanjing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; and included it in the &quot;Nanjing Municipal People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee 2018-2022 Legislative Plan&quot;. In 2022, the 22nd meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Wuhan Municipal People&#39;s Congress will review the &quot;Wuhan Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations (Revised Draft)&quot;, but it has not yet been officially announced. Recently, relevant personnel from the Tianjin Municipal Public Security Bureau also revealed in interviews with the media that relevant departments are working on revising the &quot;Tianjin Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with other cities, the &quot;Chongqing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; will be officially implemented on June 1, 2023. Previously, the 2008 version of the &quot;Chongqing Dog Breeding Management Interim Measures&quot; was implemented. Judging from the number of revisions of dog breeding management regulations in the 15 cities included in the analysis, Hangzhou and Suzhou had relatively frequent revisions. The latest revision of the Dog Management Regulations will be in 2022, and the previous revision was in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/66212136c002ea146d35a1cf91703f12.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1563&quot; height=&quot;2358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/66212136c002ea146d35a1cf91703f12.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254635&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Some cities have restrictions on the shoulder height of prohibited dog breeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rongshen has not banned Rottweilers&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Many places have banned large dogs with different physical standards and high standards&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt; p>;The Rottweiler that bit a girl in Chongzhou, Chengdu on October 16. The male dog’s shoulder height is generally 70-90 cm, and the female dog’s shoulder height is 65-80 cm. Generally speaking, it is a large dog breed (generally, the shoulder height of various places is 60 cm). Centimeters and above are considered large dogs), but the &quot;Chengdu Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; stipulates 22 types of aggressive dogs and large dogs, which does not include Rottweilers. In addition, in the Shenzhen Municipal Administration for Market Regulation’s announcement on the list of aggressive dogs, Rottweilers were not included in the list of banned dogs, but Rottweilers were banned in 13 other cities included in the statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nandu Big Data Research Institute found that in the above-mentioned cities that have promulgated dog breeding management regulations, it can be seen from the lists of banned aggressive dogs published in various places, and relevant notices or announcements about permitted dog breeding in key management areas. The rules governing dog ownership and dog ownership restrictions vary. For example, Beijing stipulates that in principle, small toy dogs with an adult height of less than 35 cm (inclusive) should be raised in key management areas, and breeding of aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult height of more than 35 cm should be prohibited; Tianjin has clarified that key dog ​​management areas must Raising small ornamental dogs with an annual body height of no more than 45 cm is prohibited. It is prohibited to raise aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult body height of more than 45 cm. It is especially emphasized that after dog registration, dogs with a body height of more than 45 cm will not be registered; Qingdao requirements Violent dogs not included in the regulations, hybrid dogs containing the blood of ferocious dogs, or hybrid dogs with a height of more than 60 centimeters are prohibited from breeding, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/fd48e977c4b8123be445b7e2553a9449.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1564&quot; height=&quot;2860&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/fd48e977c4b8123be445b7e2553a9449.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254634&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Number of dog breeds banned in 15 cities (unit: breed). &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The breeds of dogs banned in different places are different&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;There are more than 4&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;0 breeds of dogs banned in Tianjin, Beijing and other places&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;After sorting through the lists of banned dogs in these cities, we also found that the number of banned dog breeds varies from place to place. Among the 15 cities included in the statistics, the number of banned dog breeds in Tianjin reaches 49; Followed by Beijing, Qingdao, and Changsha, each have 40 types of banned dogs. In contrast, the number of prohibited dog breeds in Shanghai and Chengdu is relatively small, with only 21 and 22 respectively. It is understood that among the cities not included in this statistics, Shenyang requires that 48 types of dogs are not allowed in key dog ​​management areas, including 39 types of aggressive dogs and 9 types of large dogs; Jinan has made it clear that individuals are prohibited from raising large dogs, There are 56 fierce dog breeds, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the names of prohibited dog categories in these cities, there are also some differences in the names of prohibited dogs. Some use full names, and some use abbreviations. For example, Japanese Tosa Inu, some cities prohibit dogs. The only ones on the list are called Tosa Inu or Tosa Fighting Dog; Italian Twisted Boliton, some are called Twisted Boliton, some are directly called Neapolitan, and so on. Judging from the list of banned dogs in the 15 cities included in the statistics, it is impossible to find a single category of dogs with the same name or all banned dogs. However, Tibetan mastiffs, bull terriers, Newfoundland dogs, Central Asian shepherd dogs, etc. are generally included in the prohibited list, but there are always cities that are not included in the prohibited list. For example, Newfoundland dogs do not appear on the lists of banned dog breeds in Shanghai, Suzhou, and Tianjin. Due to the large differences in the number of dogs in different places, there are problems such as a certain dog breed being allowed to be raised in one place but prohibited in another place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, some experts analyzed that because the power to formulate specific dog-raising rules is left to the people&#39;s governments of provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, this is also the reason why dog-raising regulations vary so much from place to place. It is necessary to keep pace with the times. Policy follow-up, as well as continuous and active improvement of the operating mechanism of the policy system, more standardized management, will close the gap of inconsistent standards for the prohibition of violent dogs, and prevent the recurrence of tragedies of violent dogs injuring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[他们关心大山里的孩子，那么谁来关心他们丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On December 10, 2013, Naituo Village Primary School, the lighting in the classroom was poor and The temperature is relatively low and students have classes outdoors. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/628c28081f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/628c28081f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254426&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 10, 2013, at Naituo Village Primary School, the lighting in the classroom was poor and the temperature was relatively low, so students had classes outdoors. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2013, as a volunteer, I rushed to the Daliang Mountains. During a charity event where we took family portraits for fellow villagers for free, I met Wan Chaohui, a local volunteer teacher. He was 28 years old at the time, from Sanmenxia City, Henan Province, and a typical northerner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wan Chaohui teaches in Naituo Village, Sedi Township, Zhaojue County, at an altitude of more than 2,600 meters. Naituo Village Primary School was built in 1990. It has dark brown tiles and yellow-brown mud walls. It has been in disrepair for a long time. The walls are cracked. There are three large cracks. The widest one can fit into Wan Chaohui&#39;s fist. There are more than ten small cracks. , can fit into the child&#39;s fingers. The windows were sealed with plastic film to prevent the whistling mountain breeze from blowing in. There are three rooms, with the teacher&#39;s dormitory in the middle and first and second grade classrooms on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As school was about to start, the primary school’s flagpole was broken by a pig. Three boys carried firewood daggers on their backs and went up the mountain to cut a 3-meter-long bamboo pole and carry it back to school. Wan Chaohui tied the five-star red flag with nylon rope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 1, 2013, the first class started. Class starts at 9 o&#39;clock. Wan Chaohui gets up at 7:30 and wipes his glasses repeatedly with a tissue. Standing on the podium, Wan Chaohui took out the roster and called the names, but after calling several names, no one answered. Some children grinned and laughed, while others stared at him with blank expressions on their faces. They couldn&#39;t speak Mandarin. Wan Chaohui was so anxious that he circled back and forth in front of the blackboard. Finally, he called Brother Jida, the village party secretary, and Jida came to act as his translator. A class lasts 45 minutes, all of which is used for roll call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the adobe house of the primary school has been transformed into a brick building. The school has toilets and shower rooms, a kitchen and a cement playground, as well as new desks and chairs, basketball hoops, flag poles, Dormitory beds and wardrobes. Worried that the fellow villagers were illiterate, Wan Chaohui specifically asked the construction workers to draw two little figures on the toilet wall to help the fellow villagers differentiate between men&#39;s and women&#39;s toilets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I met Wan Chaohui again in 2019. At the Yi Torch Festival in June, the school playground turned into a playground for students to light torches. More than 20 children surrounded Wan Chaohui in the center of the circle. The torches were lit, and Wan Zhaohui and the students ran around the school holding the torches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the blink of an eye, ten years have passed since my teaching career. In July 2023, I met Wan Chaohui again. He is 38 years old and nearly middle-aged. Over the years, another main storyline of his life has slowly emerged: returning to the secular world, getting married and having children. At this time, a specific topic that had been discussed every time I met him in the mountainous area gradually became important: as a volunteer teacher, his monthly living allowance was less than 3,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2017, Wan Chaohui, who had stayed in Liangshan for 5 years, met his first wife after being introduced by a Yi friend. From the first meeting to the marriage certificate, it only took A week&#39;s time. The boys in the class acted as relatives of the man. According to the Yi people&#39;s habit of marrying a wife, the villagers helped kill two pigs; the girls in the class ran to the mountains to pick Soma flowers, put them on the classroom podium, and wrote &quot; Happy wedding”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the marriage, his wife opened a restaurant in Leibo County, and Wan Chaohui still taught in Gujue Village. The two places are 150 kilometers apart and it takes more than 5 hours to drive. Due to their different cultural backgrounds and living habits, their relationship has become increasingly estranged. In May 2019, the two divorced. In September 2020, Wan Chaohui married a local kindergarten teacher, and their child was born the next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After having a family and having children, I realized the reality of oppression, such as diapers, milk powder, rent, water and electricity and other living expenses.&quot; Once, &amp;nbsp;Wan Sitting in front of me Chaohui told all this calmly. He has wanted to leave the mountainous area and return to urban life many times, but he is worried about his 38-year-old age. &quot;Many employers clearly stipulate that they do not accept jobs over the age of 35.&quot; Speaking of his parents, Wan Chaohui also looked helpless and guilty, &quot;I only go home every winter and summer vacation. Sometimes I feel that I am quite unfilial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He belongs to a special group among the volunteer teachers, not the mainstream, but still worthy of concern. How should teachers who volunteer to teach and are willing to take root in the mountains for a long time stay here? So this short film &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256942?source=131&quot; title=&quot;Standing in the mountains for ten years, with a monthly salary of less than 3,000: A support teacher&#39;s mid-life crisis &quot;How to explain&quot;>;Standing in the mountains for ten years, with a monthly salary of less than 3,000: How to explain the &quot;mid-life crisis&quot; of support teachers&lt;/a>;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While filming, I happened to meet a group of new college students who came to teach. Some have returned from studying abroad and some have graduated from teacher training. Most of them plan to teach for one or two semesters before leaving the mountainous area and returning to normal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿奇霉素上热搜，广东儿科专家紧急提醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the topic &quot;azithromycin&quot; became a hot search on Weibo. At the same time, the increase in children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in the respiratory departments of many hospitals across the country has also caused concern. Huang Huarong, director of the Department of Pediatric Respiratory Medicine at Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University, revealed in an interview with Southern+ reporters that about 90% of the patients she currently treats have respiratory infections, and about 80% of them are Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;593&quot; height=&quot;457&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254629&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As for the use of azithromycin, Huang Huarong said that it is indeed the main drug currently used clinically to treat Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. However, there are many clinical types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. Therefore, it is not recommended to take it by yourself, let alone trust the so-called &quot;strategies&quot; on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is azithromycin the main drug for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, macrolide drugs such as azithromycin, clarithromycin, erythromycin, and roxithromycin are the most popular clinical drugs. The drug of choice for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. New tetracycline antibiotics such as doxycycline and minocycline or quinolone antibiotics can also be used for treatment, but caution should be used in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, azithromycin is the main treatment drug for Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. Take azithromycin once a day, with three days as a course of treatment. It will take effect quickly and relieve acute symptoms. In addition, azithromycin is convenient to administer, can take into account children&#39;s medication compliance, and is conducive to improving the therapeutic effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Under what circumstances is it more appropriate to use azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Patients diagnosed by doctors as having Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can be treated with azithromycin. Generally, patients with mild symptoms will experience relief after taking medications. But that doesn&#39;t mean azithromycin will always work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, different children may have heterogeneous manifestations such as different symptoms, different onset conditions, and different physical indicators. The choice of drug needs to be determined by the doctor based on the specific situation. For example, children with mycoplasma pneumonia are more suitable for treatment with erythromycin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, if severe symptoms such as persistent high fever, wheezing, shortness of breath, and difficulty breathing occur, it may be severe or cause other complications. At this time, just using azithromycin is far from enough. It needs to be combined with other drugs and other treatment methods for comprehensive treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, patients may develop unresponsiveness to macrolide drugs due to self-drug resistance, abnormal immune-inflammatory response, and mixed infections. That is, taking azithromycin cannot be effective, and other drugs need to be identified, added, or replaced in a timely manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can I buy my own medicine and take azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Azithromycin is an antibiotic drug and is a prescription drug. It should be used under the guidance of a doctor. It is not recommended to take it by yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Clinically, there are many types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. In particular, children&#39;s physiques are different from those of adults, and some children have an excessively strong immune-inflammatory response and their condition progresses quickly. If the drug is not suitable for the disease, the best opportunity for treatment may be missed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When using medicines for children, special attention should be paid to the safety, rationality and effectiveness of the medicines. The doctor will determine the dosage, course of treatment, usage, etc. of the drug based on the child&#39;s weight, physique, age and other characteristics. Only by rational use of medication under the guidance of a doctor can children recover faster and reduce complications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many parents are worried about the sequelae of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, children with Mycoplasma pneumonia who receive reasonable and timely treatment rarely have sequelae. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to avoiding sequelae lies in early identification and diagnosis of intra- and extra-pulmonary complications. Some children may have intrapulmonary complications such as plastic bronchitis, pleural effusion, and acute attacks of bronchial asthma, as well as extrapulmonary complications such as damage to the nervous system, circulatory system, blood system, and skin and mucous membranes, and require prompt medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254628&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for the prevention of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly spread through droplets, and the pathogen is carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing and runny nose. Try to avoid going to crowded closed places as much as possible, and wear a mask when necessary. Pay attention to washing hands frequently, ventilating frequently, strengthening exercise, and improving physical fitness. Children with the disease should pay extra attention to rest and improve their immunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, people have been wearing masks for a long time, which has reduced the occurrence of respiratory diseases and also caused people&#39;s &quot;pre-existing immunity&quot; to various pathogens to deteriorate. This is also one of the reasons why there are more infections with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and various types of bacteria and viruses today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents find that their children have persistent fever, cough, headache, sore throat and other symptoms, they should seek medical treatment promptly and do not blindly abuse drugs. Do not relax your vigilance after receiving treatment. You must continue to pay attention to the child, pay attention to severe warning symptoms such as persistent high fever and difficulty breathing after treatment, and return to the hospital in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老无所依丨昼夜有时]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbbQAs4OG6XJf5uUgM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbb QAs4OG6XJf5uUgM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon her pufferfish deflated with a &quot;pop&quot;. He looked sick and hopeless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first she would still think about us, feeling sorry that her sister was not married yet and that I had no children. When staying at her eldest sister&#39;s house, she would ask her eldest sister to invite her father over for dinner. She was afraid that he didn&#39;t know how to take care of herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later she could only think about her own affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She wants to live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to porcupine dates, she also believes that Bentong ginger can cure her gallbladder cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m so lucky to see this by chance.&quot; One day, she showed me a report about ginger&#39;s ability to cure diseases. She soon found a woman selling ginger powder nearby. The woman ground Bentong ginger into powder and put it in capsules. My mother bought five or six bottles of ginger powder capsules and gave me one as a gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then there are the leaves of the durian. We heard at the hospital that the leaves of the solanum pomegranate have miraculous effects. Some people boiled water with it and drank it for a few months, and their cancer was cured. So my father collected a bunch of durian leaves. He stored the leaves in her tailor shop. Day after day, they look fragile and pale in the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most ridiculous thing is the father’s idea. He brought back a brochure from Yiyo, claiming that he had met a Reiki master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pink and purple brochure has a photo of a middle-aged man printed on it. The man was wearing a black tunic suit and was serious in speech. He raised his hands in front of his chest as if he was pushing an invisible thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A gentle natural treatment that brings out the best in your mind, body and soul. When health shines, wealth grows.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also on the brochure are Reiki treatments and Reiki Masters Introduction and testimonials of “reiki benefactors”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father went to my eldest sister’s house carrying a bucket and several empty water bottles. He and the Reiki master agreed to treat his mother at his eldest sister&#39;s house the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Just believe me once, just this once.&quot; He said on the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t know.” My mother said when I repeatedly asked her what she thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe she didn&#39;t dare to say &quot;no&quot; to her father, like before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t know.&quot; She used to say this with fear or impatience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result was that we children rejected the Reiki master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last two weeks, my brother took time off to go home and take care of her. At that time, she could no longer walk. Suddenly her will to live returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I must get better, I must be able to walk, and I cannot let Axiang hold me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We bought various health products for her. Her brother also took her to Kuala Lumpur to see a nutritionist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why did you delay it until now?&quot; the nutritionist said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They brought back a bunch of bottles and cans. We don&#39;t care whether they work or not. But soon she couldn&#39;t swallow the pills anymore. After her death, her brother returned them to the nutritionist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She then survived on morphine. The nurse said morphine is a painkiller. When she was feeling uncomfortable, the eldest sister fed her morphine with a syringe, increasing the dose. All the doctors could do was ease her pain. Administer morphine, pump out ascites, and inhale oxygen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her will to survive is so strong, unlike me, who wants to give up at every turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end I couldn’t see the light either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three days before her death, I had a video call with her on the plane to Tokyo and found that her eyes were so empty. There is no light and no sadness. As if indifferent. She looked at me and said nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;God loves you. I pray for you.&quot; I didn&#39;t let her see my tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why would I say that? Things I’m not even sure I actually believe. In the church, this is what middle-class believers say. Now I am like them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She looked at me blankly and said nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is she tired? Fear? What was she thinking? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those last few days, we were almost scrambling to find explanations for our actions. We found “palliative care,” deliberately avoiding the word “hospice.” We are not preparing for her death, we are living with her illness, and it may be a long, long time, we comfort ourselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact is that we can only care for, accompany and comfort her. We can only watch her in pain and watch her die away bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors know better than anyone else. He called his eldest sister and asked her to invite relatives to visit his mother in the ward. &quot;The more people who come, the better,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The words suddenly came to my mind - &quot;Sometimes healing, often relief, always comfort.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her younger siblings arrived. They came one after another and sat by the bed to talk to her. Her spirits suddenly improved, she was in high spirits, and she talked a lot. At that time, no one thought that maybe it was a comeback. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just a few days ago, she would suddenly become confused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One night on the phone she told me loudly that she had five children and named them one by one. Then she asked me why she couldn&#39;t see her children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No. No, no, no. Why no?&quot; She said to me in Hokkien. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. Didn&#39;t see it. Why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I told her I would go back to see her soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eldest sister told me that she only remembered that the person she had just spoken to was me after hanging up the phone. &quot;That was Ah Hong just now.&quot; She murmured to herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her last days, although her husband and children took turns taking care of her, she also got a maid as she wished (people seem to like to judge a person&#39;s happiness in his later years), her The scene, her appearance, and the photo of her sitting alone on the hospital bed that I have buried deep in my heart always remind me of &quot;No Country for Old Men.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From beginning to end, she struggled alone, carrying her suffering and loneliness alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago, she once asked me what &quot;No Country for Old Men&quot; meant. She told me that a neighbor said that she and her father were homeless because three of their five children were abroad and no longer around. The woman said this in front of everyone while they were doing morning exercise at a nearby gym. My mother wrote down the four words &quot;no place for old people&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, when I watched &quot;Nowhere&quot;, I was no longer thinking of her. I was thinking about Natsuki and myself. Occasionally I would secretly lament that because of her and Xiamu&#39;s illness, I was thrown into such a fate and had to face a distant and unknown future early on. It’s as if our future has already arrived. We stumble, sometimes at a loss, sometimes patient, sometimes unmoved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe I should comfort myself in this way. On the last day, she was not sad or in pain, but had something to look forward to. At two o&#39;clock in the morning, she got up from the bed and told the maid Yuni that she had dreamed of her father and that she was going home. She said this without any sadness or fear. She wanted to go home, she always wanted to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She left during the day. She went to places unknown to us. Maybe she thought she was finally home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Nowhere&quot;, Jessica once asked those homeless people on wheels if they had ever thought about their future. Sylviane said the only thing she could do was to keep going and drive over the cliff like Thelma and Louise in Thelma and Louise. Alice says her body will remain in the desert forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know where my mother went. I don&#39;t know where we will go either. We never knew. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nomadland&quot; also has another name - &quot;Nomad Life&quot;. A long time ago, when talking about nomadic people in class, the teacher said that they &quot;lived in pursuit of water and grass.&quot; Wherever there is water and grass, that is their home. This is a life of constant searching, testing and trying. This is how people live, and so does mother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>