<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[保护网络世界里的未成年人：不能“三个和尚没水喝”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257468]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/23/tKDYjGXe9X2fGmFiWu6wCaVC8KGtXcttVkIFFTJ9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/tKDYjGXe9X2fGmFiWu6wCaVC8KGtXctt VkIFFTJ9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251700&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Minors&#39; Internet Protection Regulation (Draft)&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cyberbullying, Internet addiction, live streaming rewards, star chasing and support... minors often appear when they go online How to solve these problems? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Guide and support relevant enterprises to actively implement the regulations, operate in compliance with regulations, and promote the healthy growth of minors.&quot; On September 20, 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors)&quot; Draft)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Draft&quot;), proposes to promote relevant parties to strictly implement the responsibilities for the protection of minors online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, after seven years of discussion and two public solicitations for opinions, this regulation has finally been implemented&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2016, the Cyberspace Administration of China had issued a Protection Regulations (Draft for Comments)&quot; is open for public comment. In March 2022, the Cyberspace Administration of China issued the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Draft for Comments)&quot;, which set forth requirements for the responsibilities of parents, schools and platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year and a half later, the bill was passed. Sun Hongyan, director of the Children&#39;s Research Institute of the China Youth Research Center, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that there are currently 191 million minor Internet users, and the rate of minors accessing the Internet has reached 96.8%, showing the characteristics of large groups and younger age, and the introduction of special Regulations on the protection of minors on the Internet are inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why is the time span as long as 7 years? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the release of the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Draft for Comments)&quot; in September 2016 to the release of the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Draft for Comments)&quot; in March 2022 》, which spans five and a half years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;21st Century Business Herald&quot; quoted Yao Zhiwei, a professor at the School of Law of Guangdong University of Finance and Economics, as saying that one of the main reasons why the two releases were so long apart is that the higher-level legal minors protection law did not exist at the time. It is of little practical significance to revise and separately formulate and issue regulations on the online protection of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2020, the Law on the Protection of Minors was revised for the second time, adding new provisions related to online protection. This change is of great significance to the introduction of regulations on the protection of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Hongyan believes that the newly revised Law on the Protection of Minors has added a special chapter on Internet protection, which is nearly 10,000 words long, and a large part of it is about Internet protection. This makes the Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors The newly revised Law on the Protection of Minors can be used to provide more detailed provisions on network protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2021, the 30th meeting of the Standing Committee of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress voted to pass the Personal Information Protection Law. The law added a special chapter on network protection to protect minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 30, 2021, the State Press and Publication Administration issued the &quot;Notice on Further Strict Management to Effectively Prevent Minors from Addicting to Online Games&quot;, which aims to strictly implement the real-name system and limit game duration. Solve the problem of online game addiction among minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the seven years it took before and after, Sun Hongyan analyzed, “During this period, experts from different disciplines and fields also conducted multiple rounds of discussions, revisions, and improvements. Regulations cannot just be a call-to-action, so specific requirements are particularly needed. , operable regulations as action guidelines.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the process of legalization of minors&#39; online protection is accelerating. In May 2023, the State Council&#39;s 2023 legislative work plan mentioned the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors&quot;, which was among the 17 draft administrative regulations to be reviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two months later, in July 2023, the Ministry of Justice and the Cyberspace Administration of China conducted a special study and review of the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Draft)&quot; to accelerate the legislative process of the regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, 2023, when the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors (Draft)&quot;, it was pointed out that it is necessary to build a solid legal support for the Internet protection of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to classify user age more scientifically? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 2016 draft had a total of 36 items. By 2022, the draft has been expanded to 67 items. The main content is divided into 4 parts: strengthening the cultivation of network literacy among minors, Strengthen the regulation of online information content, strengthen the protection of minors&#39; personal information, and strengthen the prevention and treatment of minors&#39; Internet addiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Sun Hongyan analyzed that the draft regulations passed this time will have two obvious characteristics: detailed provisions and specific provisions on many problems that minors may encounter on the Internet; and operable The responsibilities of parents, schools, platforms and other entities have been stipulated in detail, so that &quot;three monks will not be left without water to drink.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Ning, director of the Law Department of the School of Cultural Industry Management of Communication University of China, also analyzed the Southern Weekend reporter. Judging from the previous draft for comments, this draft focuses on the improvement of Internet literacy and Internet minors. Issues such as personal information protection, network anti-addiction, etc. In addition, the &quot;youth mode&quot; on smart terminal products has been upgraded to &quot;underage mode&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Hongyan also noticed that although multi-level government departments have relevant requirements, the applicable age threshold for &quot;youth mode&quot; set by many social apps is in name only. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her conclusion is that guardians do not have a strong awareness of protecting minors and do not even know how to set up a youth mode. They always want to put all responsibilities on the major platforms, but the platforms lack good content. pool, resulting in &quot;teen mode&quot; failing to attract teenagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Ning emphasized that the draft regulations passed this time “have also systematically organized and stipulated the obligations and responsibilities of Internet companies in the protection of minors, especially requiring them to carry out corresponding social Responsibility Assessment”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Ning further explained that at present, companies have insufficient motivation to invest in the protection of minors. Only when there is a relatively sufficient supply of content can they divide users by age and provide different content to users of different age groups. &quot;The protection of minors is actually more about fulfilling social responsibilities for companies, which requires a lot of costs. Many companies lack motivation. Objectively speaking, some companies do not have the ability to purchase large amounts of copyrighted content. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新情景喜剧《鹊刀门传奇》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257440]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/qBDTFnpRo1XELhYjuM1A5VRL7zpx5B9x1lsrUzsa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ qBDTFnp Ro1 a series of stories. After 40 episodes, the Douban score was 8.1, and the audience regained the familiar taste of domestic sitcoms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of sitcoms in my country can be summarized into several stages. In the early 1990s, works such as &quot;The Story of the Editorial Office&quot; and &quot;I Love My Family&quot; appeared, winning the ratings at the time and marking the beginning of China&#39;s local indoor sitcoms. The scenes in this form are relatively simple and fixed. The stories and jokes usually unfold between several characters. The language is vivid and rich in philosophy. It was loved by the audience at that time. In the ten years from 2000 to 2009, sitcoms developed rapidly. Well-known works such as &quot;Story of the Cooking Class&quot;, &quot;Wulin Gaiden&quot; and &quot;A Daughter in the Family&quot; are still watched and discussed repeatedly by the audience. They have broad influence and a significant long-tail effect. However, after 2010, there are few similar classic sitcoms on the market, and related creations seem to have entered a period of stagnation. The reasons are, first of all, because the development of the Internet and short videos has profoundly changed the way the public watches, making it easier for the audience to get jokes; secondly, sitcoms are limited to &quot;family-friendly&quot; content and are difficult to expand in other fields. It is also an important reason for his loneliness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The appearance of &quot;The Legend of Magpie Sword&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Magpie Sword&quot; &lt;/span>;) breaks the tradition The sitcom has a single indoor scene, but the scenes in the play are diverse, both indoors and outdoors, and martial arts elements are integrated into it. The high-quality fight scenes and a lot of baggage and plots that follow current events make the audience feel fresh and new. In addition, Zhao Benshan The performance of the comedian doubled the comedy effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aidou Media Screenwriting Studio stated that it has always wanted to create dramas with a strong sense of contrast. The planners and screenwriters in the team are very fond of Jin Yong&#39;s martial arts works. Everyone generally believes that in recent years, there have been no traditional martial arts works that meet the standards they want. And because the team has a high &quot;content&quot; of Northeasterners, everyone joked that they would create &quot;Northeastern literature and art&quot; &quot;Revival&quot;, therefore, the idea of ​​&quot;a martial arts comedy starring Zhao Benshan and taking place in the Northeast&quot; was born. This was the initial idea of ​​&quot;Magpie Sword Gate&quot;. In addition, one of the directors, Wu Di, is a world martial arts champion. He once participated in Tsui Hark&#39;s &quot;Flying Swords of Dragon Gate&quot; and has his own opinions on martial arts and martial arts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of &quot;Magpie Sword Sect&quot;, Zhao Benshan plays a pair of twin brothers, one is Ximen Changhai, the head of the Magpie Sword Sect who is highly skilled in martial arts, and the other is the timid cook Ximen Changzai. He had to go out for important matters, so in order to stabilize the hearts of both people inside and outside, he asked Chang Zai to be his substitute, which led to a ridiculous storyline that followed. This &quot;dual identity&quot; setting is the basis for the dramatic and comedic effects of the opening chapter. But in fact, this setting was not included in the original script, because Zhao Benshan was confused about &quot;how to play a hero well.&quot; The screenwriting team thought about how to make Zhao Benshan feel like a &quot;hero&quot; and make this character more interesting. level, so I thought, let &quot;the characters in the play come to this martial arts world just like Zhao Benshan doesn&#39;t understand martial arts in reality&quot;, so that his performance will be very comfortable and natural. Therefore, the screenwriter designed two brothers who look the same, one is a hero and the other is a cook, with Zhao Benshan playing two roles. The studio explained: &quot;This is very consistent with Teacher Zhao&#39;s current state. He does not need to really know much about martial arts. The real hero is performing the task. The replacement comes to the martial arts world, and the replacement is the state of Teacher Zhao himself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pL2jTW2MAbI8Whm9ea6pDkEx4NiGkE9jgU0IeCdV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pL2jTW2MAbI8Whm9ea6pDkEx4NiGkE9jgU0IeCdV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except Zhao Benshan plays the leader of the Magpie Sect, and his disciples all have different personalities. In the impression of Chinese audiences, martial arts are often romantic, and the protagonists are all fairy-like and beautiful characters. &quot;Magpie Sword Gate&quot; breaks this inertial perception. The hero is an old man, the heroine is an old lady, and the apprentices are all silly, foolish, and stupid in their own way. The studio said that from the perspective of comedy creation, contrast must be set. These characters first contrast with the heroes in the traditional martial arts world. They want to be &quot;people in martial arts&quot; in the real world - they are Reckless played by Song Xiaofeng. The idiot second apprentice Zhao Dezhu and the stupid eldest apprentice Hao Meng played by Cheng Ye; of course, there must be someone who is not so stupid and can take on the audience&#39;s perspective, that is Jiang Yulang played by Wen Song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Magpie Sword Gate&quot; is essentially a sitcom. If you want to do something different, the creator&#39;s approach is: the fight is real, and the funny is really funny. The large story structure and main line of this drama are left to the screenwriters who normally work on drama series. In addition, several screenwriting teams are set up to be responsible for submitting contrasting topics. Then the screenwriters work together to see what interesting topics can be arranged into the story, screen the topics multiple times, and ensure the quality and comedy effect through voting, interpretation, etc. The screenwriter of the selected topic needs to implement the burden of these topics based on the number of episodes he has been assigned and the development nodes and status of the corresponding characters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the barrage when &quot;Magpie Blade Gate&quot; was broadcast, the audience applauded for the satire of domestic entertainment chaos in the play. Many scenes follow hot topics and are spicy and sharp. For example, in order to become famous in the world, the sect in the play seeks the help of a storyteller to help arrange bizarre life experiences, hype up shocking scandals, and gain popularity; Position&quot;, the contestants obtained rankings through secret operations and character design, and immediately cut leeks to make quick money after their debut... All of this satirizes the strange phenomena in most of today&#39;s entertainment industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the final presentation of the series was good, the main creator still remembers some difficulties when looking back on the creative process: &quot;The most difficult thing is communicating with the actors.&quot; Because there are many people in the team Young screenwriters, many of whom are &quot;5G surfers&quot;, will inevitably incorporate the latest hot events and jokes into their scripts. Most of the actors are born in the 70s and 80s, and Zhao Benshan is even born in the 50s. How to make them truly understand the things in the script? A difficult point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The second most difficult part is the martial arts part.&quot; Because the director is a martial arts athlete, he has very high requirements for fighting scenes, but the comedian is not a martial arts actor after all, so the running-in process for this part is also quite intense. In the end, the fighting scenes in &quot;Magpie Sword Gate&quot; received many praises. The action moves are simple and neat, and have a traditional martial arts atmosphere. According to the creative team, this was a firm request from the director. &quot;We must make everyone believe that this world is real, and that is by returning to nature and fighting for real.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of the main creator, the show is made for the audience, and the audience&#39;s laughter is more important than anything else. In addition to &quot;laughing&quot;, what &quot;Magpie Sword Gate&quot; wants to convey and express is probably the word &quot;xia&quot;. As the ending of the play shows, being a hero is not about how much kung fu you know, but about a pattern and attitude towards doing things. &quot;I just want to say this to every ordinary person who is struggling in his or her position. Although we are not heroes in the traditional sense, we are actually already heroes in our own lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“十分审慎”“不宜推广”：“预制菜进校园”，争议彰显哪些问题？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some parents posted videos on social media: A school uniformly delivers pre-made meals, and meat dishes are Semi-finished products, vegetables are washed, cut, sealed in plastic bags, and sent to school the next day. This was strongly opposed by parents. Subsequently, there was a huge discussion and controversy on the Internet about the safety of prepared dishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency’s report on the evening of September 22, the head of the relevant departments and bureaus of the Ministry of Education said in an interview with reporters that in view of the fact that there is currently no unified standard system, certification system, traceability system, etc. for pre-made dishes. The supervision mechanism should be very cautious about &quot;prepared dishes entering campus&quot; and should not promote them into campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Education expressed its position on &quot;prepared dishes entering schools&quot; and responded to many parents&#39; questions. Looking back on the discussions and controversies that have occurred on this topic these days, the views and attitudes of those directly involved, especially parents, should be fully respected. Although some experts say that prepared dishes are as safe as fresh meat and vegetables, many parents do believe that compared to meals made on site, prepared dishes pose more food safety risks. The safety and nutrition of school meals is by no means a trivial matter. Ensuring children’s dietary health is more related to the future. Only based on this premise can our understanding and analysis of this issue have real value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, after this debate, the safety of prepared dishes should be given full attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It must be clear that it is biased to simply draw the conclusion that pre-prepared dishes are safe or unsafe, because pre-prepared dishes are different from pre-prepared dishes. They have the same name &quot;pre-prepared dishes&quot;, but each person The understanding of the denotation and connotation of this concept may vary widely. The pre-made dishes with the same name are obviously different from those produced by small workshops. They also sell pre-made and ready-to-eat beef and salad. Big supermarkets use refrigeration to keep fresh, while roadside stalls allow them to be exposed to the scorching sun. The safety and quality are also guaranteed. different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following are common pre-prepared dishes: 1. Self-heating hot pot, high in oil and salt, stored at room temperature. It is very convenient to eat, but obviously cannot be eaten often; 2. Frozen storage introduced by some manufacturers . Heat-and-eat dishes, such as &quot;Kung Pao Chicken&quot; and &quot;Ma Po Tofu&quot;, are also high in oil and salt, and their taste is obviously inferior to those freshly made in restaurants; 3. From breeding and planting bases to industrialized assembly lines, they are processed into semi-finished products, and then The whole process is uninterrupted cold chain transportation and distribution, and restaurants and canteens purchase it and then make it into finished products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of health and taste, the first two are obviously not eaten frequently, so they cannot become mainstream. The third type is the development direction of prepared dishes worthy of discussion. If they are not stored properly or the cold chain cannot be guaranteed to be uninterrupted, these three types of prepared dishes may have safety issues. Prepared vegetables have a long chain of production process, from breeding and planting to slaughtering, processing, and cold chain transportation and distribution. Every link has safety risks, so scientific management is required to control risks and strictly follow operating procedures. Production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, some parents are opposed to the introduction of prepared dishes into schools, which also reflects parents’ dissatisfaction with school cafeterias and schools for ignoring their rights to know, supervise and choose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some parents reported that the school did not seek their opinions and made a unilateral decision to bring pre-made dishes to campus. To say what parents are opposed to in their hearts, in addition to concerns about the prepared dishes themselves, they also include but are not limited to the opacity of school management in the canteen, which makes their rights to know, supervise and choose missing or in vain, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a parent group in my child’s primary school, which fully described a parent’s experience of supervising the canteen: Because some children reported that the dishes were small and tasted bad, some parents went to try them at noon one day ( This is the right of parental supervision recognized by the school). As a result, the dishes on that day were rich and tasted good. A parent who went to supervise said: &quot;My daughter came back and said that the food was unpalatable in the past two days. On the day I went, I was satisfied. There was plenty of meat in the dishes on the day I went.&quot; This may not have anything to do with the school, but this is how the catering company deals with parents. I believe there are more than one or two parents who are dissatisfied with their children’s meals at school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Think about the fact that the right to operate a canteen in some schools can be sold for millions. Parents often have no say in the selection of catering companies. It is not difficult to understand parents&#39; distrust of schools and school cafeterias. In fact, even if there are no pre-prepared dishes, the meat bought freshly from the market may contain illegally added clenbuterol, and the vegetables may also contain excessive pesticide residues. Therefore, deciding whether it is safe or not based on fresh vs. frozen or pre-made is not the core or the most critical point of the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to build parents’ confidence in schools and school cafeterias? The solution is also simple: take necessary measures to establish or re-establish the trust that should exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, parents should have a certain right to speak and full rights to know and supervise in selecting the dishes cooked by catering companies, canteens or catering companies every day. If every parent wants to understand and participate informedly, they can do so at any time without hindrance. Sunshine is the best disinfectant. Transparency, openness and frankness can dispel all kinds of suspicions, concerns and worries. Schools, canteens or catering companies should be open-minded and act in accordance with conscience, operating procedures and professional ethics, and are not afraid of routine or surprise supervision from parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, all teachers and administrators in the school should eat the same dishes as the students. It can not only demonstrate the equality between teachers and students, but also, if both teachers and principals eat it, any concerns about food safety can be instantly eliminated, killing two birds with one stone. On this basis, parents&#39; trust in the school can be rebuilt. Only with trust can there be healthy and effective communication, and we can clarify various misunderstandings and solve various problems at any time. Children will also have more trust and identification with the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you achieve these two points, many things will be solved easily. &quot;Whether prepared dishes can be brought to campus&quot; should be a matter of public discussion: What are the pros and cons of using prepared dishes or fresh meat and vegetables, and what is the difference in cost? Which catering company should you choose that is more conscientious and has guaranteed food safety? If canteens and catering companies use pre-prepared dishes, which company should they use? etc. Moreover, when parents have the right to speak, know, and participate, I believe that whether it is a catering company or a food production company, the first consideration is how to win the trust of parents, and the school cafeteria will have better safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运运动员村——身在“村里”，如在“家里”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257464]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games Village is the largest non-competition venue for the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou. It is divided into Athletes Village, Technical Officials Village, There are three parts to the Media Village. As the Asian Games draw closer, how athletes from various Asian countries and regions will start their &quot;Asian Games life&quot; during the competition has become a hot topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 22, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters visited the Hangzhou Asian Games Village Athletes Village. The Athletes Village is located in the northeastern area of ​​the Hangzhou Asian Games Village. It can accommodate 10,400 athletes and team officials. It is divided into international area, residential area and operational area. Among them, the International Zone has facilities such as a VIP reception center, village chief&#39;s courtyard, flag square, and commercial street. The delegation welcome center is the &quot;first stop&quot; for all delegation athletes and team officials. It is also one of the daily entrances to the athletes&#39; village during games. At the Flag Square, Southern Weekend reporters witnessed the welcoming ceremony of Hong Kong, China and other delegations entering the Athletes Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the village, athletes and team officials will take the village shuttle bus to their respective rooms. Each building in the Athletes Village ranges in height from 10 to 42 floors and is divided into 22 types of units. In the Athletes Village Cultural House, athletes from all over Asia can experience traditional Chinese culture up close. In a badge exchange center, people can interact with a machine full of badges, put the badges into the machine, and then choose any other badges in the machine. In addition, the athletes&#39; village also has a beauty and manicure center to create various exquisite looks for athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I hope athletes can feel the greenness and intelligence of this Asian Games here, and experience the warmth of ‘home’.” The Hangzhou Asian Games Village construction team told the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/DOXonGqdN0ZcL0jVq8FnB9d6VFdYDJjNrSE38J4f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/DOXonGqdN0ZcL0jVq8FnB9d6VFdYDJjNrSE38J4f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251692&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 22, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, exterior view of Hangzhou Asian Games Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/ITOie7n9OHhGi6yzlzVhJs8hlUu0G7ftj5EUsbUi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/ITOie7n9OHhGi6yzlzVhJs8hlUu0G7ftj5EUsbUi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251694&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a huge and eye-catching sign outside the Asian Games Village Athletes Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/i9maktQTZdYs4Y3YyoVgE9zwKdhqX9Mr7CpZ63r2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/i9maktQTZdYs4Y3YyoVgE9zwKdhqX9Mr7CpZ63r2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251695&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, an Indian athlete was experiencing traditional Chinese rubbings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0gMAGXMuekMPR6OJiceHBTOl53vsEkEhhMrjWOLD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0gMAGXMuekMPR6OJiceHBTOl53vsEkEhhMrjWOLD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251693&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a stylist was styling athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/oORSMXPzfxe06q0IVCaKlmlm0QHl4v8K25yaVSkt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/oORSMXPzfxe06q0IVCaKlmlm0QHl4v8K25yaVSkt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251696&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Hong Kong Asian Games delegation took a group photo at the welcome ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/kGbP4PoXOtEKFPtjzJvQt3NXrd4sR3RK09ybqVGa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/kGbP4PoXOtEKFPtjzJvQt3NXrd4sR3RK09ybqVGa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251697&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, a shuttle bus drove in the Athletes Village in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/SKe1CQFjbF0MIEO9aoXvOSIJMcvkDiBo0ygMhXEH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/SKe1CQFjbF0MIEO9aoXvOSIJMcvkDiBo0ygMhXEH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251699&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Japanese Asian Games delegation took a group photo with the mascot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/xqdty7VpzK0kC6XkjetouwyOJ60TkQrfmE6tB7sK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1616&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/xqdty7VpzK0kC6XkjetouwyOJ60TkQrfmE6tB7sK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251698&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, two members of the Thai Asian Games delegation took pictures in the athletes&#39; village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一桩谋杀案引发外交纠纷：加拿大成了印度头号敌人？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257462]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Indian Ministry of Foreign Affairs announced the expulsion of a senior Canadian diplomat in retaliation for earlier At that time, Canada expelled the head of the Indian intelligence agency who was stationed in Canada as a diplomat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the Canadian government accused &quot;Indian government personnel&quot; of being involved in the murder of Canadian citizen Hardeep Singh Nijjar, but this was firmly denied by India. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nijar is the leader of the Canadian Sikh community. On June 18, he was murdered outside a Sikh cultural center in British Columbia, Canada. The case triggered strong protests from the Canadian Sikh community, demanding that the Canadian government solve the case as soon as possible and bring the murderer to justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, Canadian Prime Minister Trudeau mentioned the matter when speaking in the House of Commons, saying that he had obtained &quot;credible&quot; evidence that the Indian government was involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India and Canada are far apart. Why does a case that happened thousands of miles away involve the Indian government? Why did the latter react so violently? This is related to the &quot;Khalistan&quot; (that is, the Sikh independence movement) movement in India. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to solve the issue of the status of the Sikhs has always been a family scandal that successive Indian governments have tried hard to cover up. The incident of India and Canada expelling diplomats from each other has once again attracted widespread attention from the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you no longer afraid of having your family scandal exposed? &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Successive Indian governments have always been highly vigilant about the return of the &quot;Khalistan&quot; movement. When the governments of countries where overseas Sikhs live show support and condone behavior, India will use various channels to implement measures. pressure, but generally adhere to the principle of low-key handling in order to minimize the opportunity for the &quot;Khalistan&quot; movement to express its claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking office, the Modi government has shown new thinking on ethnic issues, and its domestic and foreign policies and statements have become increasingly stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Domestically, the Modi government’s economic and social development policies continue to sacrifice the well-being of India’s minority groups. Violent incidents against ethnic minorities by Hindu extremist organizations occur from time to time, and the economic and social conditions of the Sikhs in India are deteriorating day by day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abroad, Modi insists on exporting Hindu nationalist ideas among overseas Indians. Whenever he visits foreign countries, he will use Hindu elements to hold large gatherings to build support for the cause of Hindu nationalism among overseas Hindus. . The Modi government&#39;s ethnic policies have successfully brought sharply antagonistic ethnic relations at home to Indian groups overseas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2002, Modi was serving as Chief Minister of Gujarat. The state government led by him was accused of adopting a policy of inaction in response to riots and even condoning attacks, resulting in thousands of casualties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking office as Prime Minister of India, Modi took a very strong position on the issue of overseas Sikhs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is to increase pressure on host governments and require these countries to take practical measures to combat so-called anti-India activities in their own countries. Senior Indian officials have repeatedly accused the United States and Europe of using the &quot;Khalistan&quot; movement to involve issues of Indian sovereignty in public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to support overseas Hindus and rush to the forefront of opposing overseas Sikhs. Overseas, when Sikh demonstrations occur, overseas Hindus are often arranged to hold tit-for-tat activities at the same time. People from both sides exchanged insults, and overseas Hindus and overseas Sikhs even caused conflicts in the streets, forcing the host government to intervene by creating social security incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the United States has deepened its reliance on India, European and American countries have been less concerned about issues such as the status of the Sikhs for some time. The Modi government has emphasized its strong strategy to deal with overseas Sikh issues. It seems to be quite effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Russia-Ukraine conflict, India has not followed the United States and Europe in imposing comprehensive sanctions on Russia. Disappointed, the United States and Europe will no longer tolerate concessions to India&#39;s actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the intention of the United States and Europe to use the status of the Sikhs to attack India has become increasingly obvious. The United States took the lead in attacking India. For example, in May 2022, the state of Connecticut passed a resolution declaring that April 29 was recognized as the &quot;Sikh Declaration of Independence Day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we enter 2023, &quot;Khalistan&quot; gatherings have occurred one after another in the United States, Australia and the United Kingdom, and activists have also had violent clashes with local Indians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Canada, anti-India demonstrations have also occurred frequently since 2023, and India-Canada relations have continued to be tense. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Confrontation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Canada has expressed its views on the Sikh issue from time to time. India has always been quite dissatisfied and regards Canada as the overseas base camp of the &quot;Khalistan&quot; movement. one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the number of Sikhs in Canada is about 770,000, accounting for about 2.21% of Canada’s total population, which is equivalent to the proportion of Sikhs in India’s total population. Sikhs generally develop well in Canada, have higher economic and social status, and have greater political influence in the local area. For example, when Trudeau became Prime Minister of Canada in 2015, his cabinet included four Sikh ministerial officials. Sikhs also have a relatively high representation rate in Canadian parliaments at all levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Modi first took office as Prime Minister of India, he had quarrels with Canada over the Sikh issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2015, when Modi paid his first state visit to Canada, India attached great importance to it. However, some organizations in Canada immediately held protests and marches, demanding that the Canadian government investigate Modi’s 2002 murder in Gujarat. A high-profile state visit was tarnished by his dereliction of duty amid ethnic riots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the United States and Europe begin to revisit this disagreement, India and Canada have had many confrontations over the Sikh issue, adding uncertainties to the already troubled bilateral relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Canada, two incidents occurred in June 2023, exacerbating tensions between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, on June 4, the Sikhs held a parade to protest against the &quot;Operation Blue Star&quot; launched by the Indian government that year, and used a float parade to recreate the scene of Indira Gandhi&#39;s assassination. . The Indian government protests that Canada has violated its sovereignty and dignity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then on June 18, Nijar, the famous leader of Canada’s “Khalistan Independence Referendum”, was shot dead by two gunmen in the street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if Canada’s concerns about the Sikhs in India are not taken into account, the Indian government’s involvement in the assassination of a Canadian citizen has involved Canadian sovereignty and is a serious criminal case. This can be said to have touched the bottom line of the Canadian government. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the G20 summit in early September, the host Modi did not hold a one-on-one meeting with Trudeau. Instead, he expressed &quot;strong concern&quot; about &quot;Canadian extremists&#39; continued anti-India activities&quot;, which triggered strong opposition from Canada. dissatisfied. Then came Trudeau’s latest briefing on the Nijar incident mentioned above, emphasizing that he had obtained “credible” evidence and that the Modi government could not escape its involvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India and Canada not only expelled diplomats from each other, but also interrupted negotiations on a free trade agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Sikh Question&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;India’s&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Thunder&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;India&#39;s &quot;dissension&quot; on the Sikh issue has a lot to do with the historical grievances of ethnic conflicts in India that led to the emigration of Sikhs overseas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the latest census by the Population Registration and Survey Commission of India, there are about 20 million Sikhs, accounting for about 2% of the total Hindu population. The Indian state of Punjab has one of the largest concentrations of Sikhs.旁遮普邦总人口2770万，其中信奉锡克教的人口占57.69%，约1600万人。在旁遮普，锡克人是多数族群，从印度全国范围来看，锡克人又是绝对的少数族群，这种态势造就了锡克人独特的政治地位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;锡克教起源于15世纪的印度，创始人那纳克上师因反对印度教的种姓压迫，提出了“人人平等、平等待人”的口号。锡克教族群内部凝聚力强且有尚武风气，勤劳肯干，在印度有着较高的经济和社会地位，但锡克人政治地位问题，是印度最敏感的内政问题之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自印度独立以来，锡克人一直希望在印度联邦体制下获得更多自治权，在不同时期开展的分权运动也取得一定成果，包括1966年原旁遮普邦被一分为二，这使得锡克人历史上首次成为一个地方邦的多数族群。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20世纪70年代末，印度旁遮普邦的锡克人再次掀起了一场非暴力的地区自治运动，但印度政府采取了强力镇压，其中尤以1984年6月3日“蓝星行动”造成的影响为最大。当时，印度武装部队动用坦克、火炮和直升机在内的重型装备，攻入武装分子盘踞的阿姆利则大金庙，造成巨大伤亡，也对神圣的金庙建筑造成损坏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;锡克人把“蓝星行动”与历史上自身遭遇的外族入侵和大屠杀相提并论，激起了印度国内外锡克人同仇敌忾的情绪，印度多地出现锡克士兵哗变。 “蓝星行动”造成了锡克教徒与印度教徒之间的严重对立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为报复行动之一，1984年10月31日，时任印度总理英迪拉·甘地被自己的两名锡克族保镖刺杀，英迪拉遇刺一事又激发印度国内大范围的印度教徒袭击锡克教徒事件，至少有3000名锡克人遇难。此后，两个族群之间的关系走向完全对立，事件也逐渐演变成锡克人争取独立的武装分离主义叛乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到1993年，这场“卡利斯坦运动”叛乱被认为基本平息，在此期间共造成了21443人死亡，包括11694名平民、1746名武装部队士兵和8003名武装分子。此后，很多锡克人移居海外，主要散落美加英澳等国。如今，约150万锡克教徒生活在印度国土之外，成为海外印度人的重要组成部分，而印度政府在“蓝星行动”中冒犯大金庙以及大规模追铺和杀害锡克民众的记忆，在海外锡克人中一直存续。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至目前，事件仍在发酵，美国、澳大利亚和英国都表达了严重关切。到底是印方笃定特鲁多不会公开案件关键证据，还是特鲁多拿出证据将莫迪钉在持续迫害锡克人的耻辱柱上，目前尚未可知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，整个事件最受伤的，反而是第三方即美国。美国拜登政府近年来倾力打造所谓民主国家联盟，无论是美日印澳四国集团，还是美英加澳新“五眼联盟”，事件的两个当事方都是重要成员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今民主同盟尚未建成已现裂痕，作为盟主的美国是否亲自斡旋？斡旋效果能有几何？我们拭目以待。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为复旦大学南亚研究中心副研究员）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部：对“预制菜进校园”持审慎态度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257458]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期，一些地方“预制菜进校园”话题受到社会广泛关注。近日，记者就“预制菜进校园”采访教育部有关司局负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据这位负责人介绍，学校食品安全和营养健康事关学生健康成长，教育部长期以来会同相关部门，切实落实党中央、国务院决策部署，严格落实食品安全法等法律法规，先后制定实施了《学校食品安全与营养健康管理规定》《营养与健康学校建设指南》等制度规定，不断加强对学校食品安全和营养健康的管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食品安全法第五十七条规定，学校等集中用餐单位的食堂应当严格遵守法律、法规和食品安全标准；从供餐单位订餐的，应当从取得食品生产经营许可的企业订购，并按照要求对订购的食品进行查验。供餐单位应当严格遵守法律、法规和食品安全标准，当餐加工，确保食品安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位负责人指出，党和政府高度重视学校食品安全，十分关心学生健康成长，广大家长期望孩子在学校吃得既绿色安全又营养健康。经研究，鉴于当前预制菜还没有统一的标准体系、认证体系、追溯体系等有效监管机制，对“预制菜进校园”应持十分审慎态度，不宜推广进校园。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成为全职儿女，是双向奔赴还是逃离社会？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/1JE8T6YwMwSf39ignBvAWz6wqusEAeMivHPOMl8t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;930&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/1JE8T6YwMwSf39ignBvAWz6wqusEAeMivHPOMl8t.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人一生下来最不费力就能得到的社会身份是“儿女”，随着人生进程的发展，会得到各种各样新的社会身份，包括职业、头衔、人际关系、政治身份等等。当一个人打断进程，偏离主流观念所预设的人生轨迹，从社会退回到家庭，他可以用什么样的词语来定义自己？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20世纪80年代，英国社会将不就业、不升学也不进修的人概括为NEET（Not in Employment, Education or Training），这个词语传入日本和中国台湾地区时采用了音译“尼特族”，在中国大陆则被翻译为“啃老族”。但“啃老行为”并不仅限“啃老族”，根据北京大学的一项中国家庭追踪调查数据，我国适龄劳动人口的“啃老”比例从2010年的不足2%跃升至2018年的40%以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本学者山田宏昌在1999年提出“单身寄生族”一词，比NEET更具体，用来指代一直拖延着不结婚，日常生活如居住和吃饭等，都依靠父母，而自己的收入则拿来当“零用钱”的人。日剧《我的事说来话长》的男主角就是一名“单身寄生族”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论是“啃老”还是“单身寄生”，词语本身就带有一定的贬义色彩，并且仅以社会价值为衡量标准。在难以躲避的污名化语境中，一部分退回家庭的人选择用“全职儿女”来定义自己。除去所有外在的社会身份，他们至少是父母的儿女。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全职儿女不算多，也并非一个可轻易复制的选择，但却引起了网络上极大范围的讨论。比起全职儿女是什么，如何做全职儿女，我们更关心他们为什么放弃其他身份。他们成为全职儿女，原因不只出在他们自身，也跟他们所面临的这个时代的普遍困境有着很大关联，只是他们暂时没能克服，或放弃了抗争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jv6s6VVx0pKS8P6lINgiWhE5nOKQqLExILl63Ng2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jv6s6VVx0pKS8P6lINgiWhE5nOKQqLExILl63Ng2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;单身寄居&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在豆瓣小组“全职儿女工作交流中心”，交流的热度已经退去，以前的旧帖不断被新闻学、社会学的学生和记者翻出，显示出对“全职儿女”浓烈的探究意味。这样的探究有时候招致反感，有人不禁发帖问，“为啥突然间大家关注全职儿女”，回复的人大多认为是炒作和追热点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小组最活跃的时期是2023年1月至4月，很多选择以“全职儿女”描述自己的人公开分享故事。这些故事中，快乐和轻松是少见的，焦虑和迷茫才是主调：“感觉自己价值感很低”“面对亲戚尤其疲惫，父母有时候也会流露不满”“第三周已经开始焦虑了”……有人还提到，部分成为全职儿女的人处在同辈压力中，容易受创伤——他们脱离了社会主流的发展道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小组简介中对全职儿女的定义与“单身寄生族”有些相似：单身青年，寄居父母家，享受父母的经济援助。不同在于，全职儿女会通过付出一定的劳动来换取经济援助，且并非放弃就业，而是保持学习，等待机会重回职场，或考公考研。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一定义对于大多数20-30岁年龄阶段的全职儿女而言，是符合的，尽管对30岁以上的群体不太适用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西西今年26岁，她的情况正符合这些对全职儿女的定义。2022年12月海外硕士研究生毕业后，她经历了申请博士和找工作的种种考量，最终选择在家专心备考公务员。她的朋友圈背景是罗素的一句名言：“不要因为睡懒觉，而感到自责，因为你起来，也创造不了什么价值。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西西认为专业对她的职业选择影响最大，她学的是教育学，“我熟悉的两个学习财会和市场营销的同校同学，很快就入职了，一个进了普华永道，一个进了奔驰，但这些大厂不会要教育学的学生。”她原本的职业规划是读完博士后进高校，但2022年申请的4个月里，她感受到巨大的压力，12月份感染新冠疫情是压垮她的最后一根稻草，她放弃了申请。后来无意中打开邮箱，西西才发现收到了英国伯明翰大学的offer，但那时她已错过申请奖学金的期限，“自费百万去读一个文科博士，性价比太低。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一个985的文科硕士，不如一个三本的计算机本科。”西西从薪资感受到了这一点。她的一位朋友计算机本科毕业后入职互联网公司，几年后年薪涨到60万元。她在申请硕士时短暂地找过一份工作，月薪只有3000元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次考公务员，西西没有像申请硕士时一样一边工作一边备考，她发现现在的竞争太激烈了，近几年考公务员的人数明显上升。以国家公务员考试为例，自2021年以来，报考人数每年增长50万左右，2021年为151万，2023年已突破250万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西西的父母支持她在家待业的决定，她爸爸对她说：“不着急，可以慢慢找一个你自己比较满意的工作。”她的一名同学没有这样幸运，即使家庭经济条件不错，但硕士毕业后父母非常希望他尽快就业，他只能匆忙找一份本地中专院校辅导员的工作，月薪两三千，工作非常累。“他想考一个编制，但下班之后完全没有精力复习，于是陷入了两难境地：放弃现在的工作，舍不得，怕之后找不到别的工作；不放弃吧，又累又不快乐钱又少。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了同学的前车之鉴，西西安心在家准备省考。她家的财务由父母和她共同打理，她可以自由支配存款的零头，足以覆盖她的生活花销，但她不用承担家务，“我主打一个陪伴。”上大学后，西西很少这样长时间和父母住在一起，妈妈珍惜她在家的日子。每天晚上，父母在客厅看电视，西西在一旁跳健身操。有一天西西回自己房间运动，妈妈很不习惯地问：“你今天怎么不在外面跳？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西西家里不缺她上班每个月赚的几千块钱，父母也不催她工作，但她还是会感到焦虑，她觉得在家的日子一事无成。“我们在一个结果导向的社会里，我没办法坦然接受人生不是赛道是旷野的观点，还是被社会主流价值观裹挟了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;职业价值&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;豆瓣小组里有一个提问帖，“为什么会成为全职儿女？”16个回答中，“不想工作/找不到工作”这一理由占了11个，其中包括毕业即失业的年轻人。2023年，年轻人失业率持续上升，根据国家统计局的数据，全国16-24岁人口城镇调查，失业率在2023年4月至6月均突破20%，自8月份开始，这一数据暂停发布。当部分找不到工作的年轻人退回家庭，他们就成了全职儿女。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰琪是16-24岁失业青年的一员，她明白，全职儿女不是一种正常的就业方式。“我在家也有薪水，但不能和去外面闯荡相比，任何一种工作都应该和外界沟通。”兰琪被迫待在家里。她本科毕业后有过一份工作，却被父亲否定了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他的担心是过于保守的，女孩子出差几天，就不安全吗？何况同行的还有女同事。他的观念，我嫁出去以后就和他没关系，在那之前，要保护好女儿的名誉，处女的价值胜过成长的一切。”兰琪没有试图说服父亲，辞职回家。她为父辈的固执荒谬和自己的软弱而感到痛苦，没有勇气再去找新的工作。“我感觉我废了，我在同龄人里掉队了，与社会脱节，像《家》里的觉新，也像《玩偶之家》里的娜拉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我看过的所有全职儿女的故事中，兰琪的例子非常特殊，我一度不确定她是否属于这一群体，但她自己选择了这个词，她看中其中的职业属性。“只要有劳动，就是职业。一些人认为全职儿女是&#39;啃老&#39;，我不认同。&#39;啃老&#39;是衣食全靠父母而不付出半点劳动，意味着失去自己的价值，我想做家务也是有价值的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰琪让我意识到，大多数对于全职儿女的描述中，应该是儿女占据主导的一方，要求父母给予经济援助，为自己的人生兜底，而实际上，父母也有可能是掌控的一方，他们的态度和观念塑造了家庭的样貌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰琪的父母认为，对于女性而言，做家务比外出工作是更好的选择。兰琪说，“他们好像在培养一个家务机器，干家务、做饭炒菜都是为了嫁出去的将来，所学的技能都是为了后代，比如我母亲认为我学游泳是为了以后孩子更快上手。”有一次我和兰琪聊天，她说当天晚上她做饭，母亲对她说，“你代替了我。”她感到很心酸，“原本可以在社会打拼的，却在家里干繁重的家务，心能甘、情能愿吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰琪父母的观念来自于祖辈，“爷爷把女儿们&#39;保护&#39;得相当好，在那个年代难能可贵，面子有光，街坊四邻相当认可。”兰琪父母希望她是一名待字闺中的女儿，她自己选择成为全职儿女，现代的和传统的，融合在这一个词语里，于是它让人既能够理解，又觉得新奇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0HS9ni4yQzkUz8L7e5v5VxyjTfDi9SPGBnIha9zC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0HS9ni4yQzkUz8L7e5v5VxyjTfDi9SPGBnIha9zC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;提线木偶&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;成为全职儿女的理由中，岳杭的答案给我留下很深的印象，她是第一个接受我采访请求的人，采访前我并未意识到她是多么地有勇气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳杭的讲述把我拉到闷热潮湿、夏天长到漫无止境的深圳。2017年，25岁的岳杭留学归来，父亲给她在深圳找了一份工作，这份工作让她一直处在不快乐的状态。2020年底，她失去了嗅觉，之后皮肤问题加重，痤疮流血，她排解不愉快的尝试全都失败了。2021年春，父亲找的第二份工作给她的生活带来转机，但三个月的试用期后她被劝退。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“等我点一根烟。”岳杭说，但她一共没抽几口。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳杭的第一份工作是一家家族企业，老板是广东潮汕人，办公室不到10名员工，大部分是老板亲戚。岳杭连潮汕话都听不懂，直到离职她也听不懂，在办公室仿佛局外人，只能闷头做事。薪资基本上没涨过。2020年，公司效益不好，开始拖欠工资，其他非亲属同事都离职了，岳杭还在坚持——她也投过几份简历，但没有得到回音。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这家公司不配宿舍，岳杭初来乍到时，对生活还有期待，工资5000元，花3500元租房。后来她租房的价位降至800元，“不是什么好房，贪便宜啊，我一毛钱都不想花在这份工作上。我也跟自己较过劲，我吃苦了，然后没有用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，公司终于分配宿舍，尽管没有安装空调，岳杭还是入住了。她承认当时的心态有点蠢，“好不容易公司提供免费住房，我一定要住回本。”深圳夏天的最高气温能超过40摄氏度，岳杭一边热到绝望，一边计算盈亏，后来她才意识到自己亏大了，把身体健康亏了进去。“我讨厌那家公司，所以要从财务方面找回心理落差，就是拿着那么点工资，觉得不公平。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二家公司让岳杭心情好了很多，直到上司质问她：“你父母怎么教你的？”甚至当众批评她，给她父亲打电话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在深圳工作的四年，岳杭像机器上的一颗螺丝钉，一直紧张，无法松弛。每周的工作时间是星期一到星期六，只在周日有一天休息，她会去吃很多甜品，吃到想吐还要往嘴里塞，只为了获得一点快乐。尽管这样的快乐不长久，但她不知道还能去哪里找到快乐。晚上失眠时，她会通过自慰让自己快速睡着，“我要有足够的睡眠，才可以服务于我的工作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从第二家公司离职的那天晚上，岳杭一直趴在书桌前，回想离职前的一周都发生了什么。整个人如同提线木偶一样僵在原地，如果想要动，身体能动起来，但她没有驱使身体的意志，她第一次陷入了木僵症状。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月，岳杭代表家庭去外地参加亲戚的婚礼——父母都要工作，她是唯一的闲人。婚礼上，岳杭突然昏迷。父母来接她回家，第二天把她送进了精神科病房。她又变成提线木偶，有意识，却怎么也无法离开黑暗，几天后才醒来。她的抑郁症已经很严重了。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;透支的一代&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2021年11月，岳杭出院，开始了回家休养的生活。她几乎闭门不出，和父母也很少交流。他们看见她坐在沙发上“游手好闲”的样子会生气，所以她总是一个人待在房间里。像是对以往上下班规律生活的一种反弹，她的睡眠时间变得无序，也会放任自己失眠，“我就哄自己，不焦虑，反正也不用上班。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年2月，发小回家乡，岳杭才恢复了社交，开车去见朋友，吃美食，逛景区……她喜欢自驾出行，只是在深圳的几年几乎没机会碰车。她的生活多出许多工作时期没有的活动：尝试种植花草，赶着阳光去天台晒衣服，攒快递的纸箱卖废品。她喜欢收纳纸箱的过程，先选出一个最大的纸箱，再把其他的小纸箱拆封、压扁，在固定空间里塞进更多的东西，尽管收集几个月的纸箱只能卖得十几元钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在家乡小城，除了交纳社保，岳杭其余的生活开销在一千元左右。父母给了她一笔生活费，她也通过兼职赚零花钱——她去一家摄影工作室当临时助理，半天的薪酬50元。2023年起，她还在一家酒店当临时洗碗工。这两份工作让她感到舒适，来拍摄的客人想要美的照片，对工作人员都很客气；洗碗的工作结束后，她能分得一些没被动过筷子的菜。“这种体力活，不需要动脑，还有成就感，只要把面前的工作做完，下班后也不用加班。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做这两份工作是她少有的独立决策。从小到大，岳杭的生活都听从父母的安排，初中毕业时，父母建议她出国读书，她同意了，在国外念完了高中和大学，专业选择了比较好找工作的经济学。现在，父母对她的教育投入都成为了她的负担和压力。“即使父母不在你面前流露出失落，但养了很久的孩子找不到工作，那么久都没办法去赚钱，不符合他们的期望，这种心情很难不被小孩发现。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳杭觉得自己资质普通，尤其不擅长考试。回国后，父母让她去考初级经济师，她考不过，也不愿意去考其他的证书。她同样不擅长社交，回家后心态才逐渐变得更加开放。她不习惯去争取什么，之前想换工作时简历写得不好，最近找工作才改出正式一点的版本，她会把洗碗工的经历也写上去，让履历丰富一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，岳杭面对时代也有一种挫败感，“我不可能赚到比我父母更多的钱了，他们那个年代是只要努力就有钱，但是我努力，我加班，我也没有钱。”岳杭觉得，她在深圳看到的许多同龄人，都比她父母的工作辛苦，他们这一代人更拼了，得到的却更少了。“我们好像提前透支了人生，从小学开始就忙着上补习班，不知道在赶什么进度，我们赶不来一套房子，甚至赶不来一个放松的假期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做全职儿女的这两年，是岳杭近年来最快乐的时光，她考虑过一直做下去。2022年，奶奶做了一个手术，期间，岳杭向父亲提出想去当奶奶的护工。“之前我住院的时候，我父母给我请护工，一天两三百（报酬），我想赚这个钱。当然，只要管我饭吃就好了，不会说非要他们以一个护工的价格请我。但父亲不同意。”岳杭觉得自己可以在亲戚之间作为保姆一样的存在，除了祖辈，父母辈也将面临照料需求，因为他们都只有一个孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳杭的病情稳定了许多，最近在尝试找一份新工作，例如宜家的食物部或搬运部，“要体力活，不加班，有运动量，不用考虑那么多人际关系，兼顾身体健康和心理健康。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5pnGTNAYzfxYTyw3tMlHgbRtlytjPo5Ob5t5BLlp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5pnGTNAYzfxYTyw3tMlHgbRtlytjPo5Ob5t5BLlp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;疯狂的工作&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;岳杭认为，全职儿女最大的制约是经济来源，她不想一直靠父母给予，只能继续工作。而对于37岁、有过10年工作经历的青田来说，她没有太多经济负担，所以能坦然地裸辞，退出劳动力市场。她以“躺平废物”来称呼自己。2022年底，朋友们给她转发全职儿女的话题文章，附带一句话“你太典型了”，她翻翻白眼，认可了这个新称呼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全职儿女让青田想起以前看过的一篇关于日本三四十岁啃老族的报道，其中一个故事是，一名40岁的女儿陪着60岁的母亲去国外旅行，女儿很羡慕母亲高额的退休金。她在《身为女性的选择》里，看到上野千鹤子在2003年也有类似的讨论，“&#39;60代&#39;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指60-69岁人群&lt;/span>;）的父母在经济不景气和大范围裁员之前就已退休，并拿到了丰厚的退休金，可以说，他们是第一代、也是最后一代完整享受到了经济高度成长利好的人。而下一代人并没有那样的保障。正因为这一代的家底雄厚，才给儿女啃老提供了可能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辞职之后，父母给青田打了一笔不小的钱款支持她的生活，她拿出大半放进了股市，虽然目前亏损了很多，但她对股市有信心。“我们家90年代开始炒股，牛市熊市也经历了几次，相信总会回来的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青田原本是一家中型互联网广告公司的中层干部，让她放下职场的，是工作中感受到的徒劳与荒诞。2020年，公司提倡降本增效，员工降薪15%，且不发奖金，然而那一年公司业绩并不差。年底公司高层去澳门开年会，青田的领导回来私下向她炫耀，“刚买的劳力士手表不好看，想换一块。”青田想到她手下的员工，“都是985、211的好学生，勤勤恳恳加班，担心失业，大半夜被客户叫起来也没有怨言，可是一个月就几千块，他们有什么错呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年青田的一位同事因胰腺癌去世，在葬礼上，入职某头部互联网零售公司的前同事绘声绘色地讲他们办公室里挂着一排AED，新人入职第一件事就是练习做心肺复苏，但因为工资高，内部很多人都想转岗去他们部门。她感慨，“企业文化和我们之前的公司完全不同，不会磨磨唧唧地走流程、开会，就是干！非常有冲劲。”青田觉得价值感受到了冲击，“人没了就什么都没了，大家为什么这么疯狂？这个行业为什么这么疯狂？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去一直信奉的“努力工作”“自我实现”的价值感，在青田心里逐渐变成了“自我剥削”“自我洗脑”。她见证过互联网行业大爆发的成功叙事，也经历过对公司利益分配严重失衡的愤怒和失望，她不再去工作中找寻意义。“工作对普通人的意义就是挣钱养活自己、养活家人，如果家庭有一定的积累，为什么不做一些不一样的选择，让自己和家人都舒服地生活呢？”青田想起那个离世的同事，最后一条豆瓣广播是吐槽和家里的关系，“她到死都没有跟父母和解。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为是独生子女，青田和父母关系紧密，又因之前有过一段失败的婚姻，她不打算再组建家庭，想维持跟父母一起生活的平衡和快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青田常住广州，父母住在惠州的乡村，她会经常回村小住。以往工作时只能在中秋和春节回家，看到的是金黄色的稻谷和割剩下的稻茬。现在，她可以完整见证稻田的灌水、插秧、抽穗、收割等各个阶段。她会带上父母一起出游，沿途打点一切，安排参观博物馆和自然风景，哪怕只是逛逛当地菜市场，一家人也很开心。她帮父母拍照，剪辑视频，发现他们其实更希望“被看到”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母不干涉青田的选择，她跟父亲交流种花养鸟、书法绘画，跟他说现在生活的丰富程度是过去的五倍。母亲偶尔会焦虑青田离再就业越来越远，但是看到她过得开心，就没有多说什么，还建议她再去攻读学位，经历更多不同的体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们唯一担心的是，当他们“走了”以后，青田一个人无依无靠。这也是青田担心的问题，但她还没有找到解决办法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O0LCKe0HfmalBlPeoiPfuD5lEnPky2BXcSD6JJJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O0LCKe0HfmalBlPeoiPfuD5lEnPky2BXcSD6JJJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;你的职能是什么？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在豆瓣小组，大龄全职儿女的生活状态明显比年轻人更加轻松而自洽，在一众焦虑和迷茫的标题之间，“37岁全职儿女每天都很快乐”格外醒目。青田回复了这个帖子，表示认同。不过，青田认为全职儿女有两个共同点，一是家庭经济条件好、父母有高额退休金，二是家庭关系融洽。发帖人花匠的情况并不完全与此符合，她不认为全职儿女是独属于殷实家庭的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花匠是辽宁大连人。2022年中，花匠的父母退休了，他们的退休金加起来七千多元。当年底，他们又都再找了一份工作，另外有四五千元的收入。花匠说，钱虽然不多，好在一家三口物质欲望都不高。花匠对支出进行了记账统计，每个月，家庭生活费约1000至1500元，父母的零花钱加起来1000元，她的零花钱是1500元，总共三四千元，收入足够覆盖日常支出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每周的工作日，花匠负责买菜做饭。她会在前一天下午买好菜，上午9、10点做饭，照例是每天两个青菜，荤菜会在周一做好，比如烧一份红烧肉，一顿吃几块，吃完了再做。母亲中午11:30会回家装饭带走，父亲中午在单位吃，晚上父母吃中午剩下的菜。下午，除了买菜，花匠会动手做面包和点心，给父母做零食。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我妈她是不会做饭，从小就不会做饭，所以打小是我爸做饭。不过我爸只会老一套那种，做的饭也不怎么好吃。”花匠认为父母让她做菜就是他们两个觉得她更适合在家里做饭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花匠对这份“工作”有认同感，“我在家做饭好处很多，会按照膳食指南给他们科学的搭配，比如水果、青菜、碳水、牛奶。如果不是我做饭，他们的健康可能没有现在好。”她认为自己和大多数全职儿女不同，她是真的在照顾父母。一位网友回复她帖子，“跟露珠（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;楼主&lt;/span>;）差不多年龄和状态，不过家里主要还是妈妈给做饭，该准备好好提升下烹饪技能了。”花匠问她，“那你的职能是啥？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你得体现价值嘛，不能只有拿快递是你的职能吧？像我，我管家里的财务，做一家人的未来规划，存钱啊，交房贷啊，买东西啊。我现在不工作了，会想尽一切办法花更少的钱过更好的生活。”买东西前，花匠会想，生活中有什么替代品，例如，她用小苏打来代替洗洁精。如果确实要买，她会首先去二手网站上找全新的商品，或者精打细算地利用电商平台的优惠券。“你赚钱的时候，计算这些是浪费时间，但是不赚钱的时候，计算就是在挣钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便在家，花匠的生活也很自律，每天晚上9点睡觉，早上6点起床，白天的时间大多在忙碌。她从来都不是一个懒惰的人，在当全职儿女之前，她换了十几份工作，每次辞职后，她都会努力再找一份工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她之前的工作大多是文职，例如旅游咨询、酒店前台接待、办公室行政等，辞职的原因几乎都是“跟领导不合”。“我缺乏情商，讲话直接。刚毕业的时候，完全不懂社会上的事情。我爸爸是工人，妈妈自己做小买卖，他们也教不了我什么。后来我慢慢能看懂眼色了，但在酒桌上这种需要圆滑的场合，我还是不明白。不过我也不想改，情商高可能是在放低自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年底，花匠辞去了最后一份工作，打算自己开面包店。她在业余时间自学了烘焙，中西式点心都会做，甚至能做生日蛋糕。2019年11月，她租下一间门店。装修两个月，2020年1月正式营业，但开店仅二十多天就遭遇了新冠疫情封控，再次营业是在2020年5月。2022年，大连自6月起疫情封控严格，直到11月都没什么生意，花匠不再续租，“不干了，开业三年，赔了十几万。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我问花匠，关店后不久，疫情防控就结束了，后悔吗？她虽然对关店时机感到懊悔，但还是很平静，“我知道我赚不了钱，我做不大，因为我不想雇人，从挑选原材料到制作，到交给顾客，都必须我亲自完成。”她关店也不只因为疫情，她觉得跟顾客打交道很烦，“在服务行业，你会遇到很多奇形怪状的人，我做工作没做够，但我应付人有点受够了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;店关了，花匠的生意还在做，她会通过微店接一些老顾客的单子，赚回自己每个月的社保费。“挣一千多块钱，不会影响到我生活上的情绪，不会耽误我多少时间，如果多了就不行了，开始烦了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我不想随大流儿”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;花匠的父母对她不工作而回家的决定很支持，认为他们一家三口是各司其职，母亲不会做饭，父亲做饭不好吃，且两人都是在家待不住的人，喜欢在外工作，家里的事刚好交给花匠。有时候花匠跟母亲汇报她这个月花了多少零花钱，母亲安慰她，“行啊，这些钱从外面找一个做饭的人还不够呢。”她跟母亲说，“我不想上班，你养我。”母亲爽快地说，“养呗，还养不了了？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在花匠看来，父亲比母亲更单纯，有一次她提议，“要不我们把房子都卖了，三个人一起全国旅居，看哪个地方好就在哪个地方住。”父亲说，“那你快点行动起来吧。”有时候花匠觉得，她是家里考虑最多的人，更像个家长，“他们俩经典的一句话是，&#39;你别想那么多，走一步看一步&#39;，根本没有下一步的打算。我做什么他们都支持我，相信我的做法没错。没有我的话，他们俩还在镇里待着，日子肯定过得不如现在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花匠和父母在同一个小区买了两套小房子，她先买，后来看到父亲的公积金足够凑一套房子的首付，又建议父母在隔壁的楼栋买了一套。父母不会办理贷款，不会用网上支付，一切手续和还贷计划都由花匠负责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母的健康管理也是花匠在操心，她每年体检，也会安排父母体检。母亲就是在体检的时候筛查出早期宫颈癌，做手术住院期间，花匠一个人全程陪同照顾。后来她还在个人公众号上写了一篇照顾住院病人的指南，“从头到尾非常详细，我是处女座，做事很细心，就算病人瘫床上我都不会让她长褥疮。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“上哪儿找第二个像我一样的孩子？把父母照顾得无微不至，而且我又不结婚生孩子，不让父母六十多岁还要为儿女操心，帮带孩子。”花匠没有结婚生子、组建家庭的打算，所以在生活上一直都与父母紧密相连。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;退回家庭后，花匠有更多时间回归到自己身上，闲暇时爱看电影和书籍，“我一个月能看60部电影。”她尤其喜欢杨德昌的《一一》和西恩·潘的《荒野生存》，最喜欢的小说则是毛姆的《刀锋》，她欣赏男主角拉里的特立独行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从“随大流”中抽离，摆脱了外界的声音和主流的观念，她能更清醒地认识自己，“原来我是一个不能处理亲密关系的人，我是一个不适合社交的人，我对朋友特别好、特别真诚，但我也想活得自我一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/AnfmnE77VwgCr3DKzeklQ7SH0wCHSQ2p80KkNGZC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/AnfmnE77VwgCr3DKzeklQ7SH0wCHSQ2p80KkNGZC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（陈志彤/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;候鸟归巢&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对全职儿女中的“全职”的另一重理解与“兼职”相对，重点是形容在承担“子女”这一角色上付出的时间，而非强调职业和经济属性。根据国家卫生健康委发布的数据，我国90%左右的老年人选择居家养老，仅有7%左右的老年人依托社区支持养老，3%的老年人入住机构养老。当居家养老的老年人有照料需求却无法被养老市场满足的时候，子女就要做出选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减今年42岁，北京人，多年在外地工作。5年前的深圳，减减有一天上班时忽然接到父亲的电话，父亲那会儿在公园散步，走累了坐在路边，想儿子了。减减听到电话那头传来的“想你了”，眼泪一下流了出来。自打毕业后，他就没有和父母住在一起，即使在北京工作，和父母的联系也不多。后来他去天津、上海工作，又追着前妻来到深圳，婚姻没有挽回，离父母却更远了。“我发现自己追求事业，追求爱情，却一直忽略了父母，我开始想回北京了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还没等减减完全下定决心，他就得知了父亲突发心肌梗塞住进CCU（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;心脏重症监护室&lt;/span>;）的消息，“我脑子&#39;嗡&#39;的一下，心乱如麻，缓了好一阵。”减减当即辞职，买了机票回北京，在病房见到了父亲。父亲心梗堵塞90%，且伴有严重的心衰，命悬一线，又因肺部有炎症不能立即做手术，整个人瘦到脱相。“他看见我说，&#39;这回是不是我得把银行卡密码都告诉你了？&#39;我差点又哭出来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那段时间，减减每天变着花样做饭、熬鸡汤，给父亲送去医院，他明显感到父亲心情好多了，还发短信说病友们都羡慕他，其他人想吃饺子，跟儿女说了好几天才叫来一个外卖。一个月后，父亲做完手术出院，减减也想明白了对他来说什么是最重要的，“不是在事业上取得多大的成绩，因为事业总会有波峰波谷，不是和爱人卿卿我我，因为婚姻不过是利益的结合。只有父母才是真正一辈子对你好的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减毕业于北京大学广告学系，传播最广的广告作品是哈药六厂的新盖中盖高钙片。2014年他尝试写剧本，但碰上资本寒冬，剧本写完拍不了，又进了企业工作。现在回家，他重新拾起了写剧本的活儿。“虽然收入比起以前差很多，也极不稳定，但是我总算有时间陪伴家人了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;减减跟父亲一起生活，父亲退休工资五千多，家里日常开销都由父亲负责。他写剧本的平均收入是一个月5000元，负责缴纳社保、汽车保险、汽油费、物业费和取暖费等，一年大约3万元。他认为自己和父亲在经济支出上是互相帮助，并非啃老，而是全职儿女。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前工作时，他赚得多，但消费也多，离婚后基本没有剩下多少积蓄；现在，不稳定的收入降低了他的消费欲望，他不旅游、不逛街、不在外吃饭，省去不必要的社交，还学会了理发，很多原本需要花钱才能得到的服务全由自己做，反而存下了一些钱。“我的养老金肯定没他们高，所以得努力攒钱为将来打算。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲不能完全接受减减的选择，也不支持他写剧本，有时候会对着他说教，“天天窝在家里不是个事。”减减考虑到父亲心脏不好，不想惹他生气，和导演打电话时都躲在房间避开他。有一次实在受不了，出去住了一个星期，回家后发现父亲说话嗓子很别扭，他意识到那是因为父亲一个星期没和人说话了，“我一下子体会到他的孤独，心又软了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“选择做全职儿女放弃了很多东西，我觉得值。”减减回想过去的生活，发现从上幼儿园开始，他就没有好好陪伴父母生活过，“上班的上班，上学的上学，回家后也就是一起吃个饭，然后又各干各的了；等工作了、结婚了就更不用说。”现在，他陪父亲一起散步、研究菜谱、看热播的电视剧、聊天南海北的新闻，最喜欢做的事是给父亲理发、修脚。他获得了一种前所未有的踏实感，“我在拉萨待过半年，心情远比现在浮躁。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他把这些感想化成剧本中的一段台词：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“有时候我真觉得咱们这些北漂挺可怕的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“怎么可怕了？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“哪个北漂不是为了自己的事业把年迈的父母丢在老家？春去秋来，回家看望父母的次数比候鸟还少。有媒体曾经统计过，一个25岁的北漂，按照一年回一次家的频率来计算，他这辈子还能陪伴父母的时间就剩下一个月。现在想想，咱们的心还真是够狠的！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护受访者隐私，西西、兰琪、岳杭、青田、花匠、减减均为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[盗用上亿公款打赏主播：“榜一大哥”的名头，何以如此引人入歧途？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257456]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，“月薪6000小伙为见女主播打赏9000万元”上了热搜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘明胜（化名）在江苏张家港一家私企做会计，下载某聊天软件后进入了女主播K宝的直播间，只看一眼便迷上了。根据平台游戏规则，只有成为“榜一大哥”才能取得会见主播的资格。他月薪不过6000元，遂利用职务便利，偷偷转公款打赏。成为K宝直播间“榜一大哥”之后，他如愿和K宝成为线下情人，并发生两性关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年初，集团公司对账时，发现刘明胜掌管的账目有大笔的资金亏空。据公安机关调查，他从公司的账上一共挪走公款约1.23亿元，先后打赏K宝9000万元，给另两名主播也分别打赏了几百万元。最终，被他挪用的约1.23亿元巨额资金大部分得以追回，共计追回1.2268亿元。刘明胜以职务侵占罪被判14年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这“过把瘾就死”的劲儿令人咋舌。其实，此类出纳挪用公款打赏主播的案例还不少，并且男女出纳都有。如银某为广西某房地产开发集团出纳，从2020年起，她爱慕抖音APP的某男主播，疯狂打赏，自己没钱了便动用公款。警方调查发现，她的抖音号2020年下半年充值500多万元，有430万余是用于打赏男主播，其中144万余系公司公款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又如，李某担任珠海某公司济南大区出纳，2018年12月至2020年4月，利用公司财务管理漏洞，将4826.4303万公款转至个人账户，用于打赏女主播、游戏充值、娱乐消费、谈女朋友等，其中直播打赏2000余万。事发后，这位“榜一大哥”被判12年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这类事件的一大共性是出纳收入不高，但过手的钱多，如果个人没有很好的品性与职业伦理，很容易陷入心态失衡，而出纳最明白公司的财务漏洞在哪里，所以他们一旦“有心算无心”，公司财务制度至少一段时间内都形同虚设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个值得思考的方向是：网络直播究竟是一个什么样的行业，主要满足了谁的什么方面的需求？那些人挥霍自己的钱、父母的钱甚至公司的钱，打赏异性主播，究竟是何种心态？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网络直播包含了若干种不同的业态，其中之一是至今方兴未艾的直播带货。如果将其仅仅看成一种新的分销渠道就错了，因为与线下渠道或其他“传统”电商渠道相比，主播卖的可不仅仅是货。尤其是那些做得比较成功的主播，同时贩卖“人设”、提供情绪价值，有类似明星-粉丝的关系存在，往往满足了异性粉丝对另一半的最好想象，甚至性幻想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者，甚至可以这么说，那些红得发紫的主播，明明做好静好安暖或美美哒的“人设”就可以向粉丝收钱，竟然还额外附送一些还能用得上的商品，真是太“厚道”了。于是，沿着这条路径，“直播带货”的一部分会进化成“直播打赏”，既然不带货也能挣钱，那就不带货、不卖货，直接向粉丝卖“人设”就行了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，“直播打赏”也有多个不同的来源，受众与性质迥异，所以需要分开讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，其另一条进化路径是过去天桥杂耍、街头卖艺及卖惨乞讨从线下转到了线上，其主要受众或是草根阶层或是不特定公众，本文不再赘述。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一条进化路径是，分享欲与窥看欲的互联网化并进一步视频化。一些人把自己的工作、生活、爱好或技能通过视频与大家分享，有直播的，也有录播的，也不乏成功的案例，如钓鱼能手、套圈王、“手工耿”之类，让大家增加了对自己陌生领域的了解与知见，或让大家身临其境感受到自己向往的生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们这里重点讨论的“直播打赏”，有显著的主播-粉丝关系，并且一般是男主播-女粉丝、女主播-男粉丝关系，这就不可避免多少带有性意味&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“饮食男女，人之大欲存焉”“食色性也”，毋庸讳言，人的生命力很大一部分系于性能量或性欲望上。让无数中老年女性倾倒的“秀才”，让无数中老年男性倾倒的“一笑倾城”，让无数青年男女如痴如醉的明星，本质并无二致，说到是这些主播或明星的长相、气质与“人设”满足了异性对另一半最好的幻想，这才是这类“纯直播打赏”的发生学与动力学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鲁迅说，不满是向上的车轮。很少有人对自己目前的生活是完全满意的，对工作不满，对男女朋友或配偶不满，遂期望一种理想的生活，包括理想的配偶，也是人之常情。但是首先要明白自己的能力边界，明白自己在这个社会中是什么样的排序，这样就会对自己目前的生活是否“配得上自己”、人间是否“值得”有一个挤去水分的客观判断，自知者明。然后对于现状，该改变就改变，该接受就接受，这就是跟自己和解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而如果为了精神上的满足，把家中的大额财物甚至不是自己的财物打赏给异性主播，那实质上不是在提升而是在毁掉自己的生活。上述男女出纳挪用公款打赏异性主播正是此类情形。总之，每一个人应该把自己旺盛的生命力用在提升自己上，这样配得上的好东西就越来越多，这是正向利用自己生命能量的方法，而不是消耗自己的所有资源乃至生命力去满足自己的幻想。置个人的荣誉与前途不顾，只为“过把瘾就死”，枉费了人世间走一遭的好机缘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美成立经济领域工作组]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;为落实中美两国元首巴厘岛会晤重要共识，根据国务院副总理、中美经贸中方牵头人何立峰与美国财政部部长珍妮特·耶伦达成的共识，中美双方商定，成立经济领域工作组，包括“经济工作组”和“金融工作组”。“经济工作组”由中美两国财政部副部长级官员牵头，“金融工作组”由中国人民银行和美国财政部副部长级官员牵头。两个工作组将定期、不定期举行会议，就经济、金融领域相关问题加强沟通和交流。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《红色天空》：在侯麦与王家卫之间]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256843]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPhaaMY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPhaaMY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250592&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;概念至上的佩措尔德&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在当代德国电影导演中，克里斯蒂安·佩措尔德可能是最受瞩目的一位。之前的“幽灵三部曲”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《心的居所》《幽灵》《耶拉》&lt;/span>;）和“移民三部曲”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《芭芭拉》《不死鸟》《过境》&lt;/span>;），让他在国际影坛收获了良好口碑。于是他趁热打铁，继续推出以“元素精灵”为主题的系列作品。以水女神为主题的《温蒂妮》（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020&lt;/span>;）是系列首作；在2023年柏林电影节斩获评审团大奖，以火之精灵沙罗曼达为主题的《红色天空》，则是这个系列的第二弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过梳理佩措尔德的创作轨迹，我们能发现一些明显的特点。他的作品知识分子气较重，会围绕某些特定主题，进行近乎论文式的阐释。同时他非常强调概念所占据的核心位置，在如此创作观念的引领下，古典神话角色的命运与现代德国人的处境相交叠（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《不死鸟》&lt;/span>;），二战时期犹太人的颠沛处境，也和当代欧洲阿拉伯裔难民的流离命运相互对撞（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《过境》&lt;/span>;），激荡出奇妙的化学反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我们也不得不指出，佩措尔德的电影虽然概念迷人，却在血肉与肌理上略显刻板，缺了些真实可感的生命力。这个问题在《温蒂妮》中暴露得尤为明显：将一位古典神话中的水精灵与一位当代德国工业潜水员的生活结合在一起的尝试，在纸面上非常有趣，却在转化为影像后很容易堕入在形而上与形而下两端疯狂摇摆、最终却两边都不靠的窘境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;佩措尔德一定是意识到了他在《温蒂妮》中的失策。于是在拍摄新作《红色天空》时，他寻求着一种更轻盈的笔触：形而上的神话元素被隐藏得更深，形而下的日常生活则被推向前台。剧情设定在一段夏日假期中，心事重重的年轻作家莱昂受邀来到朋友费利克斯的海滨度假屋，试图在安静环境中为小说收尾，同时等待出版商的裁决。但在这段本应令自己平静的时光里，他却被动结识了美丽活泼的女孩娜迪亚，和与她关系若即若离的情人德维。莱昂的内心被搅起涟漪，但逐渐临近的deadline（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;截稿日期&lt;/span>;）和知识分子的包袱，让他对娜迪亚的情愫变得纠结扭曲，这为4个人的生活制造出了一系列的喜剧和戏剧性。与此同时，一场山火则在内陆蔓延，成为整个故事令人不安的背景音，没有人知道，这段轻盈的假期，最终会不会结束于熊熊烈焰中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与佩措尔德诸多前作的片名一样，“红色天空”同样充满了潜能。它既在具象层面指代着被山火染红的天空，也在隐喻层面影射着几位主人公之间呼之欲出的性张力，以及在新约《圣经》“启示录”一卷中扑面而来的末世景象。但影片的故事，最终还是没能兑现其片名的全部潜能。山火的巨大破坏力，几乎是被一段野猪在森林中奔跑的镜头和两个辅助性角色的画外死亡一笔带过；而“Memento mori”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;终将死去&lt;/span>;）式的死亡警诫，也没能和人物的欲望互为表里地结合起来。归根到底，《红色天空》仍然讲述着一位以自我为中心的男性主人公追逐女主角，并在追逐过程中觉醒的故事。不论是他的好友、出版商，还是那场大火与死亡，甚至包括女主角本身，似乎都是引领他通往自我觉醒的工具。而在佩措尔德高超诱人的概念构建能力和他只能说是勉强高于平均水准的叙事表意能力之间，依然存在一道巨大鸿沟。 《红色天空》与其前作相比已有进步，但这道鸿沟仍需填补。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250590&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;隐而不发的情节剧大师&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与其在叙事和表意方面的温吞表现相比，佩措尔德对浪漫关系的书写和对情爱氛围的烘托能力，却堪称杰出。德国人向来以严肃著称，这容易让人忘记，不论是歌德和荷尔德林这样的浪漫派诗人，还是道格拉斯·瑟克和赖纳·维尔纳·法斯宾德这样的情节剧大师，都是在莱茵河的滋养中长大的。在某种程度上，佩措尔德也是前辈们浪漫衣钵的继承人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但佩措尔德的可贵之处在于，他对爱情关系的书写，不仅有着德国式的绝望浪漫，同时也带着一丝在欧美创作者中难得一见的含蓄气质。与占有爱慕对象的身体相比，佩措尔德的男主角们似乎总是对他们爱慕之人的灵魂更感兴趣，但他们在追求对方的过程中，又总是那么羞涩、笨拙，以至于幸福的终点看上去永远遥不可及。与之相对应的，佩措尔德的女主人公总像游移的精灵一般飘忽不定，无法被定义，无法被把捉。她们是自由的灵魂，毫不掩饰对倾心之人的情感，却又总是拒绝被定义为一成不变的符号，也永远拒绝成为客体。于是在佩措尔德的电影中，追逐与躲闪相交替的错位游戏一直进行着，这游戏仿佛自从男性女性诞生之时便一直在进行，也必将持续至世界的尽头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《红色天空》中，夏日假期、乡间度假屋的设定，与佩措尔德前作相比更为轻盈的调性，和角色们具有艺术家和知识分子气息的谈吐，都会或多或少让我们想起在埃里克·侯麦的电影中，那些对举棋不定的直男角色怀有善意的讽刺调侃，以及那些在喜剧基调之下，对情感百态不动声色的透视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一方面，佩措尔德制造浪漫情境的天赋，他对女性角色的浓烈爱意，以及他电影中男女角色因躲闪和克制而变得更加激烈的情感关系，都会让人想到另一个擅长制造浪漫氛围的电影大师——王家卫。或许，《过境》《温蒂妮》和《红色天空》的女主演葆拉·贝尔，已经悄然成为佩措尔德的张曼玉。这些电影的剧情，可能很快会从我们头脑中消逝，但葆拉·贝尔的明媚微笑和一袭红裙，却会久久留在我们的记忆里，透过男性导演那道无法彻底理解其所思所感，却依然（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;或者说——正因为如此而&lt;/span>;）充满倾慕的目光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[餐厅员工发顾客打娃视频后赔1万离职，警方如此调解令人费解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to reports, on September 19, a Western restaurant stopped a mother from beating her daughter and posted the relevant video online. The employee, Mr. Jiang, resigned and left Changsha after compensating the other party 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surveillance video that Mr. Jiang previously posted online showed that the woman involved, Hu, was holding a shopping bag and yelling at the little girl. Later, she took her child to the Western restaurant where Mr. Jiang worked and asked her child to explain to her the process of causing trouble. At this moment, Hu lost control. He put down the shopping bag in his hand, lifted the chair next to him and tried to hit the girl. Mr. Jiang and his colleagues stepped forward to stop him. A nearby merchant revealed in an interview with a reporter from Hunan TV that when the mother and daughter passed by his store, the girl suddenly fell down and the ice cream in her hand spilled on the floor, causing her clothes to be stained. Immediately, Hu lost control of his emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Jiang said that after the incident, Hu came to the restaurant many times, saying that he should not have spread the video online and threatened to die in the restaurant. After mediation by the local police station, Mr. Jiang paid the other party 10,000 yuan in compensation for mental losses and medical expenses, and then voluntarily submitted his resignation to his boss. Netizens expressed: &quot;Those who hit people are fine, but those who stopped them will be punished&quot;, &quot;I really feel sorry for this doll when I see this video&quot;, and some netizens said, &quot;It&#39;s really chilling.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The restaurant employee got into trouble when he prevented the woman Hu from beating her daughter in public and uploading the video to the Internet. This matter involves many aspects, including domestic violence, public supervision, privacy rights and law enforcement issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it must be clear that Hu’s behavior of beating his daughter in public is a typical act of domestic violence. It not only violates public order and good customs, but also violates relevant laws. According to Article 2 of the Anti-Domestic Violence Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, domestic violence refers to physical, mental and other violations committed by family members in the form of beating, binding, mutilation, restriction of personal freedom, regular verbal abuse, and intimidation. Article 5 stipulates that minors, the elderly, disabled people, pregnant and lactating women, and seriously ill patients who suffer domestic violence shall be given special protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the duty of the police station to deal with Hu’s illegal behavior as soon as possible. Article 33 of the Anti-Domestic Violence Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China stipulates that if the perpetrator commits domestic violence and constitutes a violation of public security management, he shall be subject to public security management penalties in accordance with the law. It can be seen that when parents beat their children, law enforcement agencies cannot turn a blind eye on the grounds that &quot;honest officials cannot handle household matters.&quot; In this incident, Hu publicly beat his daughter, which caused a very bad public perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the restaurant employee Mr. Jiang’s behavior of publishing the video, from a legal perspective, he did not infringe on Hu’s portrait rights. Because this is an exposure of illegal activities in public places, Mr. Jiang is exercising the citizen’s right to supervise. Article 1020 of the Civil Code stipulates that the following acts may be reasonably carried out without the consent of the portrait right holder: other acts of making, using, or disclosing the portrait of the portrait right holder in order to safeguard public interests or the legitimate rights and interests of the portrait right holder. By exposing his video, Mr. Jiang obviously hopes to draw social attention to the phenomenon of domestic violence and jointly protect the rights of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a step back, even if Hu believes that his rights and interests have been violated, he should protect his rights and interests through legal means such as litigation, rather than through improper means such as making trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu made trouble in the restaurant many times. However, the police station did not hold him accountable. Instead, through mediation, Mr. Jiang was asked to compensate 10,000 yuan for mental damages and medical expenses. This move not only chilled Mr. Jiang&#39;s heart, but also sent a wrong signal: If illegal acts can be resolved through mediation, or even reverse compensation can be obtained, wouldn&#39;t it condone more people&#39;s willful behavior? In this way, the law loses its majesty and justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a law enforcement agency, it should be based on the law, focus on protecting the rights and interests of minors and the courageous behavior of citizens, and have zero tolerance for illegal activities, so as to form a legal deterrent and guide social atmosphere. Improve the quality of citizens through legal education. Regrettably, the police station allowed the parties’ emotions to influence the outcome of the case, acquiescing to the woman’s behavior of “getting more and more unreasonable”. Such mediation is inconsistent with legal principles. Netizens generally questioned this mediation and expressed their simple view of justice. Law enforcement agencies should re-investigate the matter and hold the offenders accountable, rather than letting those who bravely act for justice lose money and jobs. Only in this way can people&#39;s faith in judicial authority not be damaged. After all, the majesty and credibility of the law are often reflected in the daily actions of law enforcers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>