<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[为保住工作买公司产品？企业与员工间应建立合理边界丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261008]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nio’s layoffs have been a hot topic recently. First, there were rumors in the industry that on November 3, 2023, Li Bin, the founder, chairman and CEO of NIO, stated in an internal letter &quot;Organization Optimization and Two-Year Priorities&quot; that in order to further improve execution efficiency and ensure sufficient resources for key businesses To invest, the company will reduce its positions by about 10%, and specific adjustments will be completed in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to NIO’s 2022 ESG report released on September 25, it has a total of 26,763 employees. According to this estimate, more than 2,600 people or more will be laid off this time. Regarding NIO’s layoffs, the mainstream narrative on the market revolves around the situation of the electric vehicle industry or the company itself. This is of course a meaningful perspective. Here we can also get into the perspective of employees. According to China Business News, we learned from NIO’s internal employees that the compensation plan is N+3, which should be good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, a user with the online name &quot;Tangbao&quot; posted on Xiaohongshu, saying that he had worked at NIO for 5.5 years (also known as &quot;became a full-time employee more than a year ago&quot;), which seemed to imply that it was not official before. Worker), nearly 40 years old, with seniors and juniors. He cherishes this job very much. &quot;I often work overtime and stay up all night, all on my own volition. There is no overtime pay and I never complain.&quot; Suddenly, he was told that he was on the layoff list. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TA alleged that &quot;almost 80%&quot; of Weilai employees have been explicitly or implicitly told that they must buy a Weilai car if they want to keep their jobs. In order to avoid unemployment in middle age, I replaced my Mercedes-Benz CLA, which I bought only two years ago, with a Weilai ET5 before the end of last year. At the end of last year, this person wrote a post titled &quot;One Month of Picking Up the ET5 Car&quot; and said, &quot;In terms of putting users first (the car owner&#39;s father), Weilai is second and no one dares to say that it is first.&quot; This seems to confirm the authenticity of TA purchasing an ET5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then he wrote: &quot;My boss talked to me and said that if he wants to be promoted, he must mobilize his friends and relatives to buy a car together.&quot; Then he recommended his cousin and cousin to buy them separately. I bought Weilai ES7 and ES6; at the beginning of this year, in order to get a promotion, I took out a loan to buy an ET5. Attached is a certificate of successful purchase and loan, which shows that the total price of the ET5 purchased is 345,200 yuan, of which the loan is nearly 300,000 yuan and the monthly payment is 8,150.56 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He claimed that the monthly payment for his first car, an ET5, was 3,000 yuan, so the monthly car loan was more than 10,000 yuan. This person spent more than 600,000 yuan to buy two ET5s, just to keep it. Job and promotion? Does a family need to buy two ET5s? And the time between two purchases is very short. Therefore, some netizens expressed doubts, and some netizens found it credible and believed that &quot;Nio has a hidden culture of mobilizing employees to buy cars (even linked to performance).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, NIO should clarify: Is this a laid-off employee of NIO? Have you bought two ET5s? This person claimed that &quot;in order to support the company and to stabilize his position, he sold dozens of cars to his relatives and friends, and almost became part-time salesmen.&quot; Is this true or false? Does the company have explicit or implicit rules that require employees to link the purchase of NIO cars to performance, retention and promotion? The media can also investigate these issues to set the record straight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the products produced by the company are good and employees need them and buy them voluntarily, there is no problem. However, if employees are required to purchase a certain number or amount of the company&#39;s products in order to stay and be promoted and receive salary increases, that would be a big problem: to put it mildly, it would be ugly and violate the public-private boundary between the company and its employees, because the company It has no right to interfere with employees&#39; private consumption choices; to put it more seriously, this is a &quot;pyramid sales&quot; of the business-profit model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real money-making routine of MLM organizations is to drain each participant&#39;s personal money, and through brainwashing, let the participants cash in the trust and love of their relatives and friends, that is, to drain the participants of their important interpersonal relationships. monetary value and then throw it away. A large number of systems destroy the social capital of individual participants, and this is the greatest social harm of MLM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the fact that most people will work in a company or organization after leaving school, there is a question worth discussing: above employees, we are human beings first, how can we keep our job? Basic human principles? Is it because it is difficult to find a job, or you are worried about losing your job, or you want to be promoted, so you can take the initiative to do anything under the explicit or implicit instructions of the company or your superiors? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an employee, especially if you are engaged in a free competition industry, the best strategy to keep your job is always to improve your own strength. I have something that others don’t have, and I have advantages that others have, so that I have some indispensable qualities. Substitutability creates irreplaceable value for the enterprise or makes the substitution cost of the enterprise very high. This strength may be your technical ability, your ability to analyze and judge, or your ability to explore and expand customers. In short, it is best to have the ability to stand alone and give up on others, and to cultivate and maintain your ability to choose. Only in this way can you have the confidence to refuse unreasonable demands from the company or your boss and maintain reasonable boundaries with the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, if your ability, courage or self-confidence are insufficient, and the company or your boss does not insist on using you, then in order to keep your position, you may eat some &quot;flies&quot;, such as asking you to spend a huge amount of money. Use the money to buy the company&#39;s products, allowing you to borrow money or lend to the company. If you go all out and do it, will you definitely get what you want? First, the company or your boss may break the contract, uninstall, or burn bridges; second, you may not be able to win over your colleagues in such a competition to please the company or boss; third, companies that do this often have operational problems, and you are You were using your own salary to save the company, but in the end you were still laid off. Wouldn&#39;t it be a loss of both human and financial resources? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He who knows others is wise, and he who knows himself is wise. The beginning of a person&#39;s wisdom and courage is the courage to face one&#39;s own weakness. Facing a problem head-on is always the first step to solving a problem; a person without courage cannot have a strong core of values ​​and will often be at a loss when encountering difficulties. Even in order to survive, you don&#39;t need to be mentally attached to anyone or anything external. This is a manifestation of weakness and incompetence; you need to inspire inner courage, cultivate courage based on strength, and then develop, work, and go. fighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列内阁投票同意与哈马斯达成临时停火协议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261041]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 09:23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to Israel&#39;s &quot;Haaretz&quot; news, the Israeli cabinet voted in the early morning of the 22nd local time to agree with Palestinian Islam Resistance movement (Hamas) reaches temporary ceasefire agreement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[三季度罚没金额145亿，近七成罚金来自第三方支付丨金融合规榜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261039]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the third quarter of 2023, the third-party payment industry became the field with the highest amount of administrative fines and confiscations in the financial industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found that in the third quarter of 2023, 1,105 institutions and 2,881 individuals were fined a total of 14.531 billion yuan, of which the third-party payment industry accounted for about 70% of the financial penalties. However, the banking industry ranks first in the number of institutions punished, with rural commercial banks being the hardest hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong police station&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The amount of the fine is far away&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in each&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;province&lt;/strong>; >;&lt;strong>;City&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Head&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot; has now publicly released the information of the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision and the local agencies of the two. Administrative penalty information is collected in real time and manually verified simultaneously, with completeness and accuracy reaching 100%. Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center conducted a data mining analysis of the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; and found that from July to September 2023, the above-mentioned institutions issued a total of 3,203 penalty information, and 1,105 institutions and 2,881 individuals were fined; the total fines were 14.531 billion yuan. 53 people were banned from work for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zUN9IEvFHMkUT9Wgcy2yJU5yJip45ymSKxBz5dV3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;658&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zUN9IEvFHMkUT9Wgcy2yJU5yJip45ymSKxBz5dV3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259083&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vroZcRg0RtVGKZ8PorjRM0B7G7h34qotmyoTuiq.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;1045&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vroZcRg0RtVGKZ8PorjRM0B7G7h34qotmyoTuiq.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which regulatory agency issued the largest fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics, the People’s Bank of China and the State Administration of Financial Supervision issued the largest amount of fines, exceeding 6.25 billion yuan. From the perspective of the police agencies, the amount of fines issued by the Guangdong police agencies of the above two agencies ranked first among the 31 provinces and cities, reaching 3.717 billion yuan; the amount of fines issued by the Shandong and Henan police offices ranked second and third respectively. were 54 million yuan and 53 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/OiAAEKo0FuZNhyQAdLxuIJwIDeri8FWGDdoeh6Uq.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/OiAAEKo0FuZNhyQAdLxuIJwIDeri8FWGDdoeh6Uq.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259085&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Shandong has the largest number of penalized financial institutions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Which region has the largest number of penalized financial institutions? The &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; shows that from a regional perspective, the Shandong branch offices of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Financial Supervision Bureau ranked first in the number of financial institutions punished within their jurisdiction, and far exceeded the second place Shanxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/blDNLvOEXm1OwIEMdOJTLX20v5W4kWuv8HeQaD9O.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/blDNLvOEXm1OwIEMdOJTLX20v5W4kWuv8HeQaD9O.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259086&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The top two financial institutions in the list of fine amounts are consistent with the &quot;Total list of fine amounts in the third quarter of 2023&quot;. They are both the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Financial Supervision and their Guangdong branches. The amount of fines imposed is much higher than that of other branches&lt; strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wlLzLX5v528TyUU0kaG46g6A2T8M6dNqwZPfXMIm.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wlLzLX5v528TyUU0kaG46g6A2T8M6dNqwZPfXMIm.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259087 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of industries, the top three places with the highest number of fines issued by banking institutions are Shandong Province, Jiangxi Province and Henan Province. However, the amount of fines imposed on banking institutions in Guizhou ranks first among all provinces and cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/aZOlPtUV5kAzU0CTojqIvdiFOf3g5ORNktHATi4X.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/aZOlPtUV5kAzU0CTojqIvdiFOf3g5ORNktHATi4X.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259088&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkAGZAhy5xATo9EffL19rlzZeJFO0S5wMS.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkAGZAhy5xATo9EffL19rlzZeJFO0S5wMS.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259089&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the insurance industry, &lt;span>;the number of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;institutional fines&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the amount of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;institutional fines of Shandong Province dispatched offices&lt;/span>;&lt; span>; are ranked first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgv7VSfgpsu2HRItbr2Ll8vNlApWiDIrbMEzXzXC.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgv7VSfgpsu2HRItbr2Ll8vNlApWiDIrbMEzXzXC.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259090 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/CD7DKKAP9oD7dHneNikFmr2VN8KJ6c159gbmqKyQ.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;669&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/CD7DKKAP9oD7dHneNikFmr2VN8KJ6c159gbmqKyQ.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259091&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Third-party payment fines are the highest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among all financial institutions that have been fined, which field has the most institutions? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Statistics found that among the 1,105 institutions that were punished, 647 banks and 366 insurance companies were fined 585 million yuan and 78 million yuan respectively. In terms of quantity composition, it is consistent with the &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;Half-year Forfeiture Amount&lt;/u>;&lt;u >;1.4 billion, three banks &quot;taken the top three&quot; Financial Compliance List&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;023 announced &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The data for the first half of the year&lt;/span>; are consistent, with banks still accounting for the most, followed by insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the amount of penalties imposed in various fields in the third quarter was significantly different from that in the first half of the year. In the third quarter, although only 15 non-bancassurance financial institutions were fined, the amount of fines was as high as 9.82 billion yuan, far exceeding the banking and insurance industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of the 15 non-bancassurance financial institutions that were punished, 12 were third-party payment companies. The amount of fines imposed on 12 third-party payment companies reached 9.77 billion yuan, accounting for 67.53% of the fines and confiscations of all institutions. It is worth noting that among the top ten fines in the third quarter, four fines were related to violations of payment account management regulations. It can be seen that the payment field is the area where fines are concentrated in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qOmi7srKErjexw58fw1WuTIxrxdk6COAC1ymJlOC.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;1205&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qOmi7srKErjexw58fw1WuTIxrxdk6COAC1ymJlOC.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259092&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Behind the sky-high fines in the third-party payment field is the collective punishment of the two major platforms, &quot;Ant System&quot; and &quot;Tencent System&quot;. &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; shows that among the top ten fines and the top ten individual fines in the third quarter, the companies and payment business leaders or department managers of the &quot;Ant Group&quot; and &quot;Tencent Group&quot; are on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1SrGuY5P3FwfSnwnsR9nAV5iHDP9S4xMSZyCzXJL.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;391&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1SrGuY5P3FwfSnwnsR9nAV5iHDP9S4xMSZyCzXJL.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259094&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Wg5HI1uOYhMBcX208JNRn3S8dehETaV7e6MwjnEs.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Wg5HI1uOYhMBcX208JNRn3S8dehETaV7e6MwjnEs.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259095&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rural commercial banks have the largest number of fined institutions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the banking industry with the largest number of fines, there are 192 state-owned banks and joint-stock banks and branches, with fines of nearly 238 million yuan. , accounting for 40.6% of the amount of fines imposed on the banking industry; there were 435 rural commercial banks, city commercial banks, rural credit cooperatives, village banks, private banks and rural cooperative banks, with a total fine of 327 million yuan, accounting for 55.94% of the amount of fines imposed on the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the number and amount of fines imposed on rural commercial banks exceeded that of state-owned banks, becoming a prominent phenomenon in the third quarter. The &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; shows that there are 206 rural commercial banks that have received fines, and the total fine amount is as high as 140 million yuan, which is higher than the 119 state-owned banks and 97.54 million yuan. In &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;The half-year penalty amount&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;1.4 billion, Three banks &quot;swept&quot; the top three in the Financial Compliance List&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;. The number of institutions fined and the amount of fines imposed by rural commercial banks are close to those of state-owned banks. This shows that the compliance level of rural commercial banks has always been at a low level, and violations are on the rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zDJeuXU1NpgKSMYlKj9Teqlx5rFjMDIvIXFGwyer.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;811&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zDJeuXU1NpgKSMYlKj9Teqlx5rFjMDIvIXFGwyer.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259093&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bNUZXmpjX0x1ssT1zwLydHHGMwIauPb4Wq9iiEGm.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;811&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bNUZXmpjX0x1ssT1zwLydHHGMwIauPb4Wq9iiEGm.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259096&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of the amount of fines imposed on individual banks, joint-stock banks and state-owned banks still occupy the top three spots. Ping An Bank, China Minsheng Bank and Postal Savings Bank rank among the top three. Among the three banks, except for Minsheng Bank, which was fined for loan violations, the other two banks&#39; fines related to &quot;failure to perform customer identification obligations as required.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, there were 164 bank penalty messages involving &quot;illegal use of identity information&quot; or &quot;transactions with unidentified customers&quot; in the third quarter, with a total penalty amount of 142 million. Yuan, accounting for 24.3% of the amount fined and confiscated by banking institutions in the third quarter. The number of loan violations reached 325, and the total amount of fines and confiscations was 280 million yuan, accounting for 47.9% of the fines and confiscations of banking institutions in the third quarter. This shows that these two major problems are more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/aBp2ZaQCF5Tu1zV43NVEI0fBYqyMGIAILhPlfOli.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;1345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/aBp2ZaQCF5Tu1zV43NVEI0fBYqyMGIAILhPlfOli.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259097&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Property and Casualty Insurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Institutions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The number of fines&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is still the highest in the insurance industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>; >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the banking industry, the amount and number of fines imposed on the insurance industry are lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The penalty situation of the insurance industry in the third quarter of 2023 is related to &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>;&quot;The amount of fines and confiscations in half a year&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;1.4 billion, three banks &quot;taken the top three&quot; in the financial compliance list&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;&quot;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>; announced The situation of fines imposed on the insurance industry in the first half of 2023 is similar. Whether it is a comprehensive insurance group or other insurance companies, property insurance institutions have the largest number of fines and the largest amount of fines. A total of 113 property insurance companies under comprehensive insurance groups were punished, with a total fine of 32.463 million yuan; a total of 65 other property insurance companies were punished, with a fine of 18.04 million yuan. Life insurance business follows closely behind. The number of life insurance companies of comprehensive insurance groups that were fined was 88, and the amount of fines was 10.968 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fOTZzz5qCoiFywxoCubNcCSnaVRhlKVlF6PdFg.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;1167&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fOTZzz5qCoiFywxoCubNcCSnaVRhlKVlF6PdFg.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259098&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/lHUs1ff1UbXCTDLZSfU6u4twU1ArO5rRkzIIwyyf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;811&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/lHUs1ff1UbXCTDLZSfU6u4twU1ArO5rRkzIIwyyf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;Half-year Forfeiture Amount&lt;/u>;&lt;u>; 1.4 billion, three banks &quot;taken all&quot; the top three | Financial Compliance List&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>; List of fines imposed on insurance companies in the first half of 2023, PICC and China Life are still among the top three on the list, while Ping An is ranked sixth on the list. Although the business scale and number of institutions of PICC, China Life and Ping An are relatively large, the amount of penalties imposed on Ping An is much lower than that of the former two. It can be seen that in the third quarter, Ping An’s compliance level improved compared to the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Md7yRKeYFArKmeZmVnpg7VaRtIB6MabZwo20AJws.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;791&quot; height=&quot;1396&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Md7yRKeYFArKmeZmVnpg7VaRtIB6MabZwo20AJws.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259100&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, in the third quarter of 2023, among the 384 pieces of insurance company penalty information, there were 199 pieces of penalty information involving the provision of false information, with a total fine of 52.1375 million yuan, accounting for 10% of all insurance companies. 66.66% of the total fine. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Don’t touch the red line&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Don’t step on the bottom line&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In summary, the third quarter financial Bank violations are mainly concentrated in three areas: payment, loan business and fictitious documents. The latter two are both &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;Half-year Forfeiture Amount&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;14 billion, three banks &quot;taken the top three&quot; in the financial compliance list&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;023&lt; mentioned /span>;&lt;span>;Key violations in the first half of the year&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;areas&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are also &quot;old problems&quot; in the banking and insurance industries. All financial institutions urgently need to eradicate the &quot;old problems&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Third-party&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Payment&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The highlighted problem in the industry&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is related to online payment business&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;span>;The rapid&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;development&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is related to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the financial innovation of platform enterprises. Online&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;third-party&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;payment&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has brought great convenience&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; to people&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; At the same time, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; also &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;provided &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;lawless elements&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; with &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; “taking advantage of loopholes to launder money”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Channel&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that when conducting financial services, financial institutions and platform companies should not only consider innovation and inclusiveness, but also always pay attention to regulatory policies and not Touch the red line and don’t step on the bottom line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(All drawings in this article: Feng Qingchao)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[控诉菊花被偷采之后：公安出警、村干部下田维持秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261037]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tourists picking flowers in the chrysanthemum patch of Zhang Liang&#39;s home. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/a2f4d2c512.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1197&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/a2f4d2c512.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;In Zhang Liang’s chrysanthemum patch, tourists are picking flowers. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In mid-November 2023, when the chrysanthemums were in full bloom, Zhang Liang, a chrysanthemum farm in Nanyang City, Henan Province, released a video saying that the chrysanthemums grown at home Four to five hundred acres of chrysanthemums are picked and stolen by many people every day. In the video he posted, three people were picking chrysanthemums in the field. Zhang Liang pretended to be a passerby and asked the person who had picked half a plastic bag of chrysanthemums: &quot;This is quite a lot. You are not afraid of others showing up when you pick it here.&quot; ?” The other party replied: “Pick less and pick as you go.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 19, 26-year-old Zhang Liang told Southern Weekend reporters that he was Villagers in Zhangxiu Yuzhuang, Kuofeng Village, Qinghe Town, Fangcheng County, Nanyang City, began contracting land near their homes to grow chrysanthemums in 2017 to process them into chrysanthemum tea. It is now the time when chrysanthemums are blooming and being harvested. Zhang Liang said that there are dozens of cases of stealing every day, and &quot;hundreds of kilograms are lost every day. Like last year, the drones shouted and cursed, and people couldn&#39;t drive them away, which has caused a lot of losses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the video shot by Zhang Liang was posted online, it quickly aroused controversy. Two days later, Zhang Liang deleted the video. He explained: &quot;Some netizens felt that I had discredited Henan people, so I deleted the video. It had nothing to do with anyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Lose the face of Henan people&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Liang introduced that the main crops in Fangcheng County are wheat and corn. In 2017, &quot;I saw others planting chrysanthemums, and the profit point was relatively high at the time, so I followed suit.&quot; In July 2021, Zhang Liang established Yicheng Family Farm in Fangcheng County, which mainly grows chrysanthemums. The annual income of chrysanthemums such as Golden Thread Emperor Chrysanthemum, Wuyuan Emperor Chrysanthemum, and Little Emperor Chrysanthemum depends on the market. If the market is good, you can sell more. &quot;But the market has not been good in the past two years.&quot; Zhang Liang&#39;s parents have always taken care of the chrysanthemum field. Zhang Liang, who works outside during the busy farming season, will also come home to help. &lt;p>; At that time, because there were not many chrysanthemums planted in large areas in the local area, many people wanted to do something new. Zhang Liang said that most of the people who came to see the chrysanthemums were people from the surrounding area, and almost all of them were strangers. There were more people on weekends, but he couldn’t estimate how many people there were. “Anyway, they sell noodles, steamed buns and cabbage. , sugar cane juice and other snacks are all set up stalls around here.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are more people looking at flowers, so people are climbing and picking chrysanthemums at will. In a previous video, Zhang Liang said that dozens of incidents of stealing chrysanthemums occurred every day. In the past, fences were built at major intersections, but &quot;gentlemen are blocked, not villains.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters that he reported to the police for stealing chrysanthemums in 2022. &quot;The police also came, educated him, and fined him 200 yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Liang believes that the reason why so many people come to his chrysanthemum patch is inseparable from the &quot;propaganda&quot; of some local self-media bloggers. Those who make short videos, they spread the word to ten, and then spread the word to hundreds.” In the online world, Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum field has a name. It is called &quot;Fangcheng Qinghe Chrysanthemum Garden&quot;, and the hundred-acre chrysanthemum garden is also exaggerated into &quot;thousand acres&quot; and &quot;ten thousand acres&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A blogger with the online name &quot;Xie Laoer&quot; once recommended Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum field on November 12, &quot;Why go to Kaifeng to appreciate chrysanthemums? There are acres of chrysanthemums at your doorstep, and you don’t have to pay for it.” An employee of the “Xie Laoer” account told Southern Weekend reporters that “Xie Laoer”’s job is a tour guide, and he usually posts beautiful views of various places in his account. &quot;Let others know where to hang out.&quot; After the video of picking chrysanthemums caused controversy, the comment section of &quot;Xie Laoer&quot; was not peaceful. Some netizens accused him of &quot;bringing misery to other people who grow flowers.&quot; &quot;Xie Laoer&quot; declined the interview from the Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;I don&#39;t want to explain too much. The more trouble there is, the more trouble there is and it won&#39;t be interesting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above-mentioned employee told the Southern Weekend reporter that she felt that &quot;Xie Laoer&quot; did not guide everyone to pick flowers. &quot;He just thought that the flowers were strange and the scenery was beautiful. Ask others to see it. There are only a few people picking flowers, but there are still many qualified people.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;At the end of &quot;Xie Laoer&quot;&#39;s recommendation video, he emphasized to tourists that &quot;you must not pick other people&#39;s chrysanthemums indiscriminately, cherish the fruits of other people&#39;s labor, and don&#39;t step on them in the fields.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a native of Nanyang, the above-mentioned employee believes that people who randomly pick other people&#39;s flowers can be found everywhere. &quot;It&#39;s not that only Henan has such people.&quot; After learning that the incident was on the news, she became even more angry, angry that those who did not realize it had &quot;lost the face of Henan people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A tourist squatting in the field to pick chrysanthemums. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /21/89e2fbf9bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/89e2fbf9bc.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;259065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A tourist squatting in the field to pick chrysanthemums. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Defloration exists, but it is very rare”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Liang felt that he had embarrassed the people of Henan and brought shame to the people of Henan. Henan people smeared it. &quot;As a Henanese, I should add glory to Henanese, but I didn&#39;t expect that (posting the video online) would cause so many negative effects.&quot; Zhang Liang explained that only a few people who came to see the flowers picked the flowers. No serious economic losses were caused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 18, Zhang Liang released a clarifying video, &quot;My purpose in shooting the video was to persuade everyone to enjoy the flowers in a civilized manner when they come here to check in and take photos. Unexpectedly, It will cause such a big misunderstanding.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In interviews with Southern Weekend reporters, Zhang Liang had a back-and-forth attitude. He sometimes admitted that all this was his personal fault and he would bear the consequences&lt;span>;,&lt; /span>;Sometimes he is full of anger: &quot;To be honest, sometimes I really don&#39;t want to speak out of conscience, and I&#39;m right.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For my own chrysanthemums to be picked , Zhang Liang’s attitude was equally vague. Sometimes he feels that &quot;people come all the way here, just for fun, picking some is nothing.&quot; &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; Sometimes he feels that &quot;someone really shouldn&#39;t pick it, this is my private property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of November 19, a staff member of the Propaganda Department of Fang&lt;span>;cheng&lt;/span>; County Party Committee told a Southern Weekend reporter, “Whether the local government is It is impossible for our propaganda department to put pressure on people. But the local government immediately went to understand the situation after seeing the video.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This The staff said: &quot;Their land is a base integrating sightseeing, picking, processing and sales. On weekends or when the weather is good, tourists will come there to check in, but some citizens have some uncivilized behaviors, such as If you want your children to smell the fragrance of flowers, or out of curiosity or as a thought, there are a few people who pick other people&#39;s chrysanthemums. This does exist, but it is definitely a very small minority. It is impossible to say that we &lt;span >;One million people in the city&lt;/span>; county are so unqualified, it’s impossible, robbery or theft simply doesn’t exist.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is said , after the incident, the local police intervened and dispatched police officers to the chrysanthemum field to maintain order. &quot;The local government has asked village cadres and party members to go into the fields and inform citizens who go sightseeing to check in that they can check in here, but they cannot go into other people&#39;s fields to pick or trample on them. It is necessary to ensure that the chrysanthemums contracted by farmers are not damaged. This is the most important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Liang denied that his chrysanthemum field can be used for tourism, &quot;We just farm our own land and don&#39;t need anyone to promote it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Looting&quot; or &quot;picking up&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The incident of stealing chrysanthemums is not an isolated incident. Southern Weekend reporters found out that during the autumn harvest period in 2023, looting incidents occurred in many places. On October 3, the property of many music fans at the Nanyang Music Festival was stolen; on October 14, a &quot;hundred acres of corn field was robbed by more than a hundred people&quot; in Dancheng County, Zhoukou City; on October 31, an incident occurred in Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City &quot;Hundreds of people looting medicinal materials&quot; incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 19, Qiu Jun, the person involved in the &quot;hundreds of people looting medicinal materials&quot; recalled in an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend that on the afternoon of October 31, the machine was in progress The second time the medicinal materials were harvested, when two-thirds of the harvest was received, the machine broke down and could not work. At that time, one or two hundred people had gathered around the field, mostly elderly people. After the machine failed to harvest, some villagers went into the fields to pick. Later, more and more people came to collect. Qiu Jun and the more than 20 people he hired &lt;span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; gave up after trying to dissuade them to no avail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jun is a major grower of the traditional Chinese medicinal material Atractylodes in Dailou Village, Fengtang Township, Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City. This year is his sixth year of growing Atractylodes. According to previous It is customary for villagers to pick up one or two thousand kilograms of Atractylodes that cannot be harvested by machines in hundreds of acres of land. After the incident, Qiu Jun felt uncomfortable but was powerless to dissuade him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jun told Southern Weekend reporters that after the incident was reported by the media, the local police recovered about 800 kilograms of Atractylodes macrocephala, and village cadres also went door-to-door to educate villagers. &quot;They won&#39;t let you enter the land, but you go in. If it sounds good to you, you go pick it up. If it doesn&#39;t sound good to you, you are robbing.&quot; The loudspeaker in the village also broadcasts to educate everyone that &quot;this kind of picking up behavior is bad behavior and violates the law.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking back at this incident, Qiu Jun believes that &quot;the common people cannot be blamed.&quot; The villagers who picked up were all elderly people, many of whom were illiterate. They don’t understand the law, so they think they can just pick it up if it falls on the ground. Regarding the public opinion caused by the incident on the Internet, Qiu Jun believed that it had a bad impact on the local reputation. During the interview, he constantly corrected the reporter&#39;s wording, changing &quot;looting&quot; to &quot;picking up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Shaohua, senior partner of Beijing Deheheng (Guangzhou) Law Firm, is worried that this approach may make most offenders think that their actions will not be punished. Penalties encourage illegal activities and cause more growers to suffer losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Shaohua said frankly that it is still difficult to classify this type of behavior as climbing, breaking, and picking other people&#39;s crops without the consent of the farmer as an illegal act. First of all, it is difficult to fix and collect evidence. Because large-area crop planting fields are generally in the suburbs and the site area is large, it is difficult to directly fix and collect the direct behavior of the perpetrators of climbing, breaking, and picking. It is often found that the crops were damaged afterwards; subjective identification is also difficult. Difficult, because some rural areas do have the habit of allowing local villagers to pick up small amounts or defective crops left after harvesting in planting fields. In terms of legal evaluation, it is &lt;span>;judge&lt;/span>; whether the perpetrator has illegal possession There are difficulties with subjective purposes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Shaohua suggested that law enforcement in rural areas should break through the misconception that &quot;the law does not punish the public&quot;. &quot;If some thefts and plundering of crops reach legal levels, law enforcement actions should be taken strictly in accordance with the law, rather than continuing to deal with it vaguely based on &#39;custom&#39;. We should let local villagers know that those who steal, rob or destroy other people&#39;s property will be held accountable in accordance with the law. Legal responsibility, the law does not hold the public accountable and will not be a protective umbrella for anyone.” The Property Rights Section of the Civil Code of the Republic contains special provisions on land contract management rights. The relevant provisions of the Criminal Law and the Public Security Administration Punishment Law are explained to the villagers, and the villagers are informed that their actions are illegal and they will be punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (At the request of the interviewee, Zhang Liang and Qiu Jun are pseudonyms )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 08:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么晚清的改良派、维新派、革命派都推崇黄宗羲？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260980]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxRmek3qIAAc6Lhq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxR mek3qIAAc6Lhq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zheng Guanying (center, front row) wrote for the booklet &quot;Yuan Jun·Yuan Chen&quot; introduction. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first Guangzhou Uprising failed in the autumn of 1895. Sun Yat-sen went into exile in Japan and developed the Xingzhonghui organization in Yokohama. Feng Jingru, the proprietor of the literary shop, became the first president of the Yokohama Xingzhong Association. His son Feng Ziyi, who was only 14 years old, also joined as a member. The booklet &quot;Original Lord·Original Minister&quot; copied and prefaced by Zheng Guanying was printed by Yokohama Bunkyo Store. The preface of Feng Ziyi&#39;s &quot;Revolutionary History&quot; states: &quot;There are only two types of propaganda materials for the current Zhonghui: one is &quot;Ten Diaries of Yangzhou&quot;, at the end of which are attached the two books of Dorgon, the regent of the Qing Dynasty, and Kefa, the history of the Mingge Ministry; It is the chapter &quot;Yuanjun·Yuanchen&quot; from the selected edition of Huanglizhou&#39;s &quot;Mingyi Waiting Records&quot;. They were all printed by Yudian.&quot; Feng Ziyi also said: &quot;In the early days of the Xingzhonghui, the literati felt extremely lacking in the propaganda tools they used. , there are only &quot;Ten Diaries of Yangzhou&quot;, &quot;The Jiading Massacre&quot;, and several &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot; selected from &quot;Mingyi Waiting Records&quot;.&quot; In 1896, the Qing Consul General in San Francisco sent someone to sneak into Sun Yat-sen&#39;s residence to peek , and then reported that &quot;after consulting two books of the prisoner, one series excerpted two chapters of &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot; from Huanglizhou&#39;s &quot;Mingyi Waiting for Interviews&quot; in Ming Dynasty. A small quotation was added to the end of the volume and he called himself Mr. Qiyou. In June 1897, when Sun Yat-sen was in England, he presented the pamphlet &quot;Yuanjun·Yuanchen&quot; to his Japanese friend Nan Xiongnan. &quot;Yuanjun·Yuanchen&quot; is an abbreviated version of the two chapters &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot; in Huang Zongxi&#39;s &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;. It was printed in Japan in the winter of 1895. There is a short note written by &quot;Young Master Qiyou&quot; on the front of the volume. Quote: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The ruler has always been born to serve the people, so he is a civilian servant. A ruler cannot rule thousands of people by himself. Therefore, the ministers and workers were built to divide and rule the country, and all those who assisted the emperor were civilian servants. Mencius said: &quot;The people are the most valuable, the country is the second most important, and the king is the least important.&quot; This universal meaning through the ages was spoken by the early generations and tabooed by later generations. They all do not know the meaning of the king and his ministers, who are all born to govern the people. If the earth is deserted and has no living people, how can there be a king? How come there are ministers and workers? However, if you don’t know that you are setting up a king for the people, so if one person is in peace, the people will lose their place; but if you don’t know that you are setting up ministers for the people, then all the officials will be obedient, which will harm the people below and benefit the people above. Wow! The disadvantages of this are that everyone&#39;s heart is wrong but no one can fully understand it or express it clearly. It has been deeply feared by Lingyi to this day. Only Mr. Huang Lizhou of the Ming Dynasty had a family tradition of loyalty and filial piety, excellent writing ability, and far-sightedness that transcended the ages. I tasted a compilation of &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;, which was entrusted to Jizi&#39;s hardships and hardships. There are two treatises on &quot;Yuan Jun&quot; and &quot;Yuan Chen&quot;, which are particularly important for grasping the key points of the whole book and will be remembered for generations to come. The excerpts of this book are published in the hope of enlightening the younger generations and revealing the foundation of China&#39;s self-improvement. Confucius said: &quot;Whoever knows me is from the Spring and Autumn Annals, and whoever offends me is from the Spring and Autumn Annals?&quot; I follow this order to inform those who want to be rich and powerful in this world. At the beginning of summer in Yiwei, Qi worried about Young Master Xiaoyin. &lt;/span>; (Quoted from Sun Weihua&#39;s &quot;An Examination of the Authors of &quot;Short Quotes of &quot;Yuan Jun Yuan Chen&quot;&quot;&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is &quot;Mr. Qiyou&quot;? There are different opinions in the academic circles such as Wang Tao and Sun Yat-sen, Ono Kazuko, Li Ao Think it is Zheng Guanying. Sun Weihua of South Central University for Nationalities conducted in-depth research and determined that the author was Zheng Guanying based on the content of &quot;Wei Yan in the Prosperity&quot; and the use of the pseudonym &quot;Qi Yousheng&quot; in his early work &quot;Yi Yan&quot;. The argument was strong. The author searched &quot;Shenbao&quot; and found that Zheng Guanying also published poems under the pseudonym &quot;Tiecheng Qiyousheng&quot;, and &quot;Tiecheng&quot; is the nickname of Shiqi, the seat of Xiangshan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Tao once wrote a postscript for Zheng Guanying&#39;s &quot;Yi Yan&quot;: &quot;Qi Yousheng didn&#39;t know who he was, but he later learned that he lived in Tiecheng, his surname was Xingyang, he traveled all over the north and south, and he stayed in Shanghai for the longest time. . The place is visited by crowns and merchants, and Qi Wensheng lives there. He is neither an official nor a secluded person, and he is also an official and a scholar. Every day, he makes friends with the virtuous and powerful elders, and chats with them about world affairs. Sometimes he bursts into tears and strikes. Broken saliva pot. Today, Guo Yunxian, the minister of Xiangxiang, and Chen Liqiu, Secretary Xian of Wuchuan, all appreciate it. They often want to wipe it away and plan to recruit Xingjin to prepare for a visit. However, Qi Wensheng insists on saying goodbye, and only sends his love to Xiangsu every day. , Si Zhi Lin Quan, Mo Huang and Yu, just reading for self-entertainment.&quot; Scholars who are familiar with Wang Tao and Zheng Guanying can easily find that the writing style of Xiaoyin is very similar to &quot;Warning Statements in the Prosperity&quot;, heavy and slightly clumsy, and rhythmic with Wang Tao&#39;s ups and downs The sophisticated writing style is completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1894, Zheng Guanying worked hard for Sun Yat-sen to write a letter to Li Hongzhang. After Sun Yat-sen&#39;s &quot;rebellion&quot;, Zheng Guanying destroyed the materials on the close contact between the two. According to Yi Huili&#39;s research, before Sun Yat-sen launched the Guangzhou Uprising in the autumn of 1895, &quot;Zheng Guanying was in Guangdong in May and June.&quot; The news that Emperor Guangxu requested the printing of 2,000 volumes of &quot;Warnings in the Prosperous Age&quot; &quot;prompted Zheng Guanying to interrupt his activities in Guangdong and return to Shanghai. &quot;. This time coincides with the date when Xiaoyin was signed, &quot;Yiwei Lixia&quot; (May 6, 1895). A bold guess is that Zheng Guanying gave the abbreviated copy of &quot;Yuanjun·Yuanchen&quot; to Sun Yat-sen together with the small quotation. After Sun Yat-sen went into exile in Japan, he handed the manuscript to Feng Jingru for publication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two chapters &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot; are from Huang Zongxi&#39;s &quot;Mingyi Waiting for Visits&quot;. &quot;Yuan Jun&quot; criticizes the monarch for &quot;taking my selfishness as the great prince of the world&quot; and &quot;bringing great harm to the world&quot;. &quot;Yuan Chen&quot; points out that the responsibility of ministers is &quot;for the world, not for the king; for all the people, not for one surname.&quot; also&quot;. The democratic ideas expounded in the two chapters were very suitable for Sun Yat-sen to use to criticize the Qing court, and also met the needs of radical reformists and reformers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Between 1895 and 1898, Kang Youwei and Zheng Guanying had in-depth cooperation. On December 1, 1895, Zheng Guanying wrote to Wang Tao: &quot;Kang Changsu, the governor, was ordered by Nanpi to go to Shanghai to set up Qiangxue Bookstore. I asked my brother to visit Mr. Wang at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon...&quot; Zheng Guanying once accompanied Kang Youwei to visit Wang Tao. Zheng Guanying was also one of the main persons in charge of Qiangxue Bookstore, and his role was deliberately downplayed by Kang Liang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao later commented on &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot; in &quot;The Academic History of China in the Past Three Hundred Years&quot; and said: &quot;During the reign of Emperor Guangxu, a group of our friends privately printed many copies and gave them away as a way to promote democracy. Tools.&quot; In the book &quot;Introduction to Qing Dynasty Academics&quot;, Liang Qichao also said: &quot;Liang Qichao and Tan Si, their contemporaries, advocated the theory of civil rights and republic, so they copied it, printed tens of thousands of copies, and spread it secretly. Change is extremely powerful.&quot; Yu Guolin wrote a long &quot;Revision Note&quot; for the new edition of Zhonghua Book Company&#39;s &quot;Introduction to Academics of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, which pointed out that &quot;the excerpts of &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot; from &quot;The Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot; were printed. The pamphleteer is actually Mr. Qiyou&quot; and &quot;this section is actually a propaganda tool for the revolutionaries.&quot; Liang only mentioned &quot;Ming Yi Waiting for Visits&quot; but did not mention &quot;Yuanjun&quot; and &quot;Yuanchen&quot;, perhaps intentionally. Before the 1898 Coup, in a written conversation with Japanese strategist Miyazaki Toten (Miyazaki Toten), Sun Yat-sen said that he and Liang Qichao had a &quot;secret language&quot; and they were not afraid of leaks when communicating with each other: &quot;My brother wants to send a letter to Shanghai, please ask Liang Qichao Or one of his close associates came here for a visit.&quot; This shows that Sun and Liang had been in contact for a long time, and they did not start dating after Liang Qichao went into exile in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao and Sun Yat-sen shared the pamphlet &quot;Yuanjun·Yuanchen&quot; compiled by Zheng Guanying as a propaganda tool, revealing that the faction affiliation of some historical figures was not as fixed as imagined. The intellectuals who devoted themselves to the revolution in the late Qing Dynasty have more or less experienced the &quot;reform&quot; stage. Sun Yat-sen&#39;s letter to Li Hongzhang is the best proof; Liang Qichao once tended to be full of revolution; Zheng Guanying may not have had &quot;revolutionary&quot; ideas, but it was not convenient to make them public. Huang Zongxi&#39;s famous articles &quot;Yuan Jun&quot; and &quot;Yuan Chen&quot; can be shared by progressive forces of all factions. It also shows that for a period of time after the outbreak of the Sino-Japanese War of 1898-1894, the progressive forces had not yet found a suitable weapon of public opinion. Huang Zongxi&#39;s heroic articles were the most &quot;easy&quot; ones. It is a propaganda tool used by revolutionaries to promote the revolution, and by radical reformists and reformers to promote the urgency of reform. Huang Zongxi&#39;s historical status suddenly increased in the late Qing Dynasty, which was conducive to the promotion of Paiman and the Republic of Xujun. However, it would be too flattering to say that &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot; had an ideological enlightenment effect on Zheng Guanying and Sun Yat-sen. After all, these two people could directly Reading English works, they are exposed to more powerful ideas than Huang Zongxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The original title is &quot;&quot;Yuan Jun·Yuan Chen&quot;: Shared Texts of Zheng Guanying, Liang Qichao, and Sun Yat-sen&quot;, now The title was prepared by the editor)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女足的跌宕与辉煌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261025]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the afternoon of November 20, the Chinese Football Association officially announced: Shui Qingxia will no longer serve as the head coach of the Chinese women’s football team because the women’s football team has not yet Can qualify for the Paris Olympics. In November 2021, Shui Qingxia was appointed at the critical moment and shared the ups and downs with the Chinese women&#39;s football team in two years. They brought victory and hope, winning the Asian Cup again after 16 years. They also brought defeat and even despair, missing the Asian Games finals and losing 1:6 to England in the World Cup. We have gone through wind and rain, seen wind and waves, and look forward to the sonorous roses blooming again.</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[青岛等大城市推行“租房入户”：实质上的迁徙自由意味着什么？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261018]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Qingdao City issued a notice to relax the residential settlement policy. The notice stipulates that those who live in rented houses in cities and apply for rental contract filing and residence registration. If they and their spouses do not have legal property rights in Qingdao, they can apply for collective household registration during the period of house rental. In a word, you can rent a house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to official data, as of the end of 2022, Qingdao has a permanent population of 10.3421 million, including an urban population of 7.4061 million; the city’s GDP in 2022 is 1.492075 billion yuan. Moving to Qingdao is attractive to many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao is not the first big city to implement rental housing. Previously, many big cities such as Jinan, Suzhou, and Zhengzhou have introduced similar policies, showing that the competition for people in big cities has entered a new stage. Compared with various methods such as points-based household registration, skills-based household registration, academic qualification household registration, and house purchase household registration, renting a house in big cities can be said to have the lowest cost and threshold, and there is almost no threshold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for some large cities (the so-called megacities and megacities), small and medium-sized cities have already relaxed household restrictions, but no small and medium-sized cities have seen a population explosion as a result. After all, the flow of population has never been based on hierarchical standards. It does not mean that people from the village go to the town, people from the town go to the county, people from the county go to the city, and people from the city go to the provincial capital. Whether in villages, towns, counties or cities, everyone is rushing to big cities and first-tier cities to find better opportunities and build a new life there. This is &quot;urbanization&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Big cities also need to constantly replenish fresh blood. To some extent, there is an inherent paradox in big cities: on the one hand, they have created miracles of commerce and civilization in a highly compressed space, with endless skyscrapers, busy streets, bustling crowds, The dazzling array of goods and colorful literature and art appear to be full of vitality; but on the other hand, large cities are often in the midst of ultra-low fertility rates and are unable to reproduce the scale of newborns and young people that the city needs. The foreign population continues to increase, making it difficult for any large city to survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, the various measures taken by large cities to attract net population inflow are related to their destiny and future. From a technical point of view, when people come, they can rent or buy a house, they can work and earn money, pay taxes and social security, they can consume, they can get married and raise children, they can spend money on their children’s education, and while supporting themselves and their families, they have also created a lot for the city. Value: It allows other people to earn money, the government has fiscal revenue, and retirees can receive pensions. From the perspective of Tao, a big city is a superorganism. Every new person is a new cell, consuming the self and continuing and maintaining the vitality of the big city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ideal situation is for the household registration to fade to the point where it has no sense of existence or even does not exist. When a person moves to a city, has a new residence, finds a new job, and lives stably for a period of time, he will naturally become a resident of the city. All he needs to do is confirm this fact through identity registration. A household is a family, and the home is registered wherever it is. Household registration is the registration of the family, which is the original meaning of household registration. After the citizen identity registration is established, the household registration is to some extent a superfluous and unnecessary step. It confirms the same fact as the identity registration. As for the tax time limit or the amount of tax before you can enjoy the benefits provided by the local area, it is another matter. Logically, it can be completely separated from the resident status or household registration of a certain city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many large cities have continued to relax household registration thresholds. In fact, they are moving in the direction of downplaying and weakening household registration. Qingdao and other big cities implement the &quot;rent-to-household&quot; policy, which does not require a stable job, education, skills or even property. You can come and live wherever you want. In essence, you have freedom of movement, and your household registration is equivalent to the city. The written proof of resident identity confirmation and household registration are equivalent to the routine procedures of urban resident identity registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another factor (especially in the past) that led to the strong household registration system in big cities is the control attached to household registration. Such as the real estate purchase restriction policy introduced during the housing market boom. However, as the housing market weakens, such controls are gradually being relaxed. Even in some first-tier cities, purchase restrictions have been reluctant to be relaxed in suburban counties. Another example is the car purchase control in first-tier cities in the name of congestion control and environmental protection. Beijing implements lottery, Shanghai implements license plate auction, and Guangzhou implements both. Taking Shanghai as an example, in addition to the city&#39;s household registration, those who currently hold a residence permit and have paid social security or personal income tax for a certain number of years can also participate in the auction. This in itself is a certain decoupling from the household registration. Therefore, from a trend perspective, it does not constitute a factor hindering the weakening of household registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, big cities are the last strongholds of the household registration system. In these places, if household registration is downplayed and weakened, the last obstacle to the free movement of the population will tend to disappear. Of course, conversely, theoretically anyone can come, which does not mean that everyone will come or that everyone can come. Whether you can survive in a city depends on your personal strength. Either you have a skill, or at least you are willing to endure hardships and hard work, or you have a strong family background, and there is no way to purely rely on welfare or parasitism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essentially free movement of the population will also lead to an inevitable result, which will make the efforts of &quot;locals&quot; in some places to oppose high school entrance examination immigration and college entrance examination immigration meaningless. Because there is no threshold for &quot;foreigners&quot; to become &quot;locals&quot;, and those who can settle down here are &quot;locals&quot;. There is no longer a way to establish strict divisions and barriers through household registration, so there are quotas for high school and university admissions. Where there are advantages, the so-called advantages will be smoothed out quickly, just like heat will flow from high-temperature parts to low-temperature parts, which is inevitable, leading to a natural balance or &quot;education equity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人口第一大县关停50所幼儿园 学前教育普及普惠考验保障能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261031]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Linquan County, Fuyang City, Anhui Province is the most populous county in China, with a registered population of 2.293 million in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August this year, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens would cease operations, accounting for 11.8% of the total number of kindergartens in the county in 2022 and 24.5% of the total number of private kindergartens in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, with the decrease in the number of births, the number of kindergartens and the number of kindergarten students in the country has decreased. In 2022, the total number of kindergartens nationwide will decrease by 5,610 compared with the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, news of large-scale closure of kindergartens has spread in many places. After the annual inspection of private kindergartens in Haikou ended recently, a total of 33 kindergartens were suspended, accounting for 6.4% of the total number of private kindergartens in the country; in September this year, 17 kindergartens in Longhai District, Zhangzhou City were terminated, accounting for 7.8% of the total number of kindergartens in the district in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts believe that the number and number of kindergartens may decrease at an accelerated pace in 2023. While the demographic dividend is declining, it has provided an opportunity to adjust the layout of preschool education and promote universal and inclusive development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National County Preschool Education Popularization Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference was held recently. The 21st Century Business Herald learned that the information at the meeting showed that the popularity rate of preschool education in some places has increased significantly. The next step for supervision and evaluation is to Adhere to problem orientation and accurately grasp key points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the school-age population has been significantly reduced, it will still be a medium- to long-term process for preschool education to reach universal standards. The crux of the problem is that kindergarten teachers have low incomes and large salary gaps, which urgently require local governments to increase financial security. intensity. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kindergarten closures continue&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Data from the Linquan County Government in February this year showed that there were 58,243 children in kindergarten in the county in 2023, a 9.2% decrease from the previous year. It decreased in the fourth year, and the decline suddenly increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from 2019 to 2022, the number of kindergartens in Linquan County was 377, 422, 425, and 425 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August this year, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens would cease operations. Among them, 12 private kindergartens applied to terminate their operations, 38 private kindergartens had no actual enrollment or school operation, and their school operating licenses had expired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that many of the 12 kindergartens that applied to terminate their operations have only been registered since 2021, and the latest of them was registered in June 2022. It was closed just one year after opening, which shows that the student supply situation of local kindergartens is tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The large-scale closure of kindergartens does not only occur in Linquan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, 17 private kindergartens in Longhai District, Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province applied to terminate their operations. In November, the results of the 2023 annual inspection of private primary and secondary schools and kindergartens in Haikou City were released, and 33 private kindergartens were suspended. Recently, six kindergartens in Ruian City under the jurisdiction of Wenzhou City have ceased operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts predict that the number and number of kindergartens will further decrease. On the one hand, it is due to the continued decrease in the number of births in recent years, and on the other hand, the gross enrollment rate in kindergartens has reached a high level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the national gross enrollment rate for preschool education will be 89.7%, but it is close to or reaching 100% in many places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Linquan County has reached 96.57% in 2022, and Anhui Province has reached 98.2% in 2022. Data released by the Henan Provincial Department of Education on November 14 show that the current gross enrollment rate of preschool education in the province is 91.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that preschool education degrees in various places will face overall saturation, with a surplus in rural areas and a shortage in urban areas. Taking Linquan County as an example, 37 of the 50 kindergartens closed were rural kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poses new challenges to kindergarten layout. Kindergarten children are too young to be suitable for boarding, so rural kindergartens cannot be blindly withdrawn and merged, but the retained kindergartens need to meet specified standards. Too few rural students will make it difficult to operate high-standard kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some places are cracking down on planning. Shandong Province issued a document in August this year to optimize the layout of rural primary and secondary kindergartens and clarify planning and layout requirements in terms of school-age population, enrollment radius, and regional coordination. On November 7, the Shandong Provincial Department of Education began soliciting opinions on the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Comprehensively Promoting the Integrated Management of Kindergarten Towns and Villages&quot;. This document proposed that when counties (cities, districts) prepare overall kindergarten layout plans, they should simultaneously clarify the kindergartens in each town and town. Layout, in accordance with the requirements for promoting integrated management of towns and villages, clarify the establishment and construction of the central park and branch parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total number of rural kindergartens has decreased. In fact, the decrease is greater than the increase. In October this year, Linquan County approved the construction of three more rural kindergartens to meet the kindergarten admission needs of different regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are great differences in the development of universal and inclusive education in various regions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reduction in the number of kindergartens and the number of children has provided an opportunity for the universal and inclusive development of preschool education. After all, limited resources can be more fully allocated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 10, the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference was held in Jinan City, Shandong Province. The meeting emphasized that we should steadily carry out supervision and evaluation work on universal preschool education in counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carrying out supervision and evaluation of universal preschool education in counties is a deployment made in the &quot;Several Opinions on Deepening Reform and Standardized Development of Preschool Education&quot; in November 2018. The Ministry of Education issued notices twice in 2020, clarifying Indicators and processes for supervision and evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is another important educational supervision work carried out in the field of basic education in addition to the supervision and evaluation of the high-quality and balanced development of compulsory education in our country. The establishment of counties (cities, districts) must achieve &quot;quantity standards and quality standards&quot;. After two rounds of evaluation at the provincial and national levels, it was finally recognized as a national county for the universalization of preschool education in five aspects: &quot;qualified, well-guaranteed, sound system, and satisfied with the masses&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the national to the local level, special attention is paid to this work. In December 2020, an on-site meeting to launch the national accreditation of national pre-school education universalization and inclusiveness supervision and evaluation in counties was held in Chengdu, Sichuan Province. The then deputy director of the Ministry of Education attended the meeting, and the expert group gave feedback to Qingbaijiang District and Shuangliu District of Chengdu City, which applied for national assessment at that time. In March 2021, these two districts were the first in the country to be recognized as national pre-school education universal HP counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, no public information has disclosed the progress of national recognition. Until the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Work Promotion Conference was held on November 10. Vice Minister of Education Wang Jiayi attended the meeting, and the expert group fed back the supervision and evaluation opinions to the Shandong Provincial Department of Education. 21st Century Business Herald learned that more than 20 counties (cities, districts) in Shandong Province have applied for national assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the differences between regions are too large, and the assessment work will not be completed overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Sichuan Province took the lead in breaking through the national assessment in 2021, it proposed to achieve the entire region to pass the national assessment by 2030. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The economically developed eastern region is moving relatively quickly. For example, Zhejiang Province has proposed to complete the assessment and identification of more than 90% of counties (cities, districts) by 2025, and strives to complete all of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even in Zhejiang, regional disparities are large. In terms of indicators, the &quot;quantity standards&quot; requirements such as the gross kindergarten enrollment rate in the three years of preschool, the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens, and the proportion of children in public kindergartens are easy to achieve, and the regional differences are not large; the teachers are qualified, the conditions for running kindergartens are qualified, It is difficult to achieve &quot;qualified quality&quot; indicators such as qualified nursing and education, and there are large regional differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A questionnaire survey of 100,000 kindergarten principals and full-time teachers across the country showed that only 85.04% of teachers hold teacher qualification certificates, of which only 77.95% hold kindergarten teacher qualification certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person from an educational and scientific research institution in an economically developed prefecture-level city in Zhejiang Province told the 21st Century Business Herald that the number of kindergartens in the city is similar to that in Hangzhou, but the total number of children in the kindergarten is about 100,000 less than that in Hangzhou. This is This means that the average number of children in the city&#39;s kindergartens is small, mainly because the local rural kindergartens are &quot;low, small and scattered&quot; and the degree of group education is not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he also pointed out that “the assessment of graded kindergartens mainly examines hardware indicators such as houses, venues, and toys. The more important factors affecting the quality of childcare are actually teachers and childcare workers. In addition, rural kindergartens pay too much attention to hardware facilities. There are also questions about whether it is wasteful and whether it can adapt to future population changes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Adhere to a problem-oriented approach to strengthen supervision&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Teachers are the most important factor affecting the quality of preschool education, and they are also the biggest obstacle to universal education. factors that benefit development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference on November 10 required that all localities should adhere to a problem orientation, strengthen the number of kindergarten teachers with qualified qualifications, &quot;equal pay for equal work&quot; for both staff and non-staff teachers in public kindergartens, and pay for teaching staff Supervision on issues such as &quot;five insurances and one housing fund&quot;, safe and hygienic food in kindergartens. Regarding teachers’ requirements, “four accounted for three.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A kindergarten teacher in Linquan County told the 21st Century Business Herald that local kindergartens still have large class sizes because there is a shortage of kindergarten teachers. The shortage of teachers is mainly due to low salary and limited attractiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My monthly salary is about 3,000 yuan.” The above-mentioned kindergarten teacher said, “Whether there is a staff establishment or not has a great impact on the income of kindergarten teachers. Teachers on staff are paid very well, and all the benefits combined can reach 3,000 yuan per year. 70,000 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coordinating the number of kindergarten teachers is the key to ensuring teachers&#39; remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shangyou County, Jiangxi Province, gave a speech at the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference on experience exchange. It was said that the county currently has 564 kindergarten teachers, including 350 teachers in public kindergartens and 214 teachers in private kindergartens. name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are currently only 134 teachers in public kindergartens in the county. This is the result of adding 86 public kindergarten teachers in the past five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Shangyou County has innovated a mechanism. Public kindergarten teachers are composed of two parts: the approved establishment number and the employment registration number. In response to the shortage of teachers in public kindergartens, the county editorial committee approved the total number of registered kindergarten teachers, and publicly recruited 216 registered kindergarten teachers within the total control, which better met the needs of teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Increasing local financial support is the basis for ensuring teachers’ remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yantai High-tech Zone has applied for national assessment. According to an article on the website of the Shandong Provincial Department of Education on November 15, from 2020 to 2022, the proportion of preschool education funding in the High-tech Zone has increased year by year, with a cumulative investment of 140 million yuan. Accounting for 23.17% of education funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu Zhaohui, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Educational Sciences, told the 21st Century Business Herald that in 2008, when he participated in the formulation and demonstration of the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot;, he calculated Preschool education funding should account for 9% of local education funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“But except for developed areas such as Beijing and Shanghai, many places have not yet achieved this.” Chu Zhaohui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problems of incomplete preschool education guarantee mechanism and insufficient universal resources, the Ministry of Education and other three departments’ &quot;Opinions on Implementing the Action Plan for Expanding and Improving Basic Education in the New Era&quot; clearly stated that students in public kindergartens in various regions In principle, the average public expenditure standard should reach 600 yuan per person per year in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The lack of funding guarantee will inevitably affect the recruitment of kindergarten teachers and the guarantee of wages and benefits. Therefore, to truly attach importance to preschool education, we need to improve funding guarantee, especially the financial subsidies for private inclusive kindergartens must be in place.” Zhaohui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访国际货币基金组织原秘书长林建海：中国在IMF的“份额”大幅提升只是时间问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261014]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the first year after the epidemic, my country’s economic recovery momentum has attracted the attention of all countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the International Monetary Fund (hereinafter referred to as the IMF in English) raised China&#39;s economic growth forecast for 2023 and 2024, saying that China is building a high-quality, sustainable and inclusive economy. Efforts are being made on multiple fronts to achieve sexual growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The IMF is the world&#39;s two largest financial institution alongside the World Bank. It has the important mission of promoting international monetary cooperation, supporting trade development and economic growth, and preventing policies that are detrimental to prosperity. Whenever there is an economic crisis or financial crisis globally or locally, the IMF will always appear in time. Therefore, the IMF is known as the &quot;fire brigade&quot; in financial crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reform and opening up, our country has gradually become an important member of the IMF. Since the restoration of its legal seat in the IMF in 1980, my country&#39;s &quot;quota&quot; share has jumped to the third place; since the RMB joined the Special Drawing Rights (SDR, also known as &quot;paper gold&quot;) in 2016, it is the IMF&#39;s currency based on the recognition of member states. A book asset that is allocated according to the share of contributions to the IMF and can be used to repay IMF debts and make up for the international balance of payments deficit among member governments.) Currency Basket So far, the weight of the RMB in the currency basket has been increased to 12.28%, becoming an international reserve currency. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did my country and the IMF go from acquaintance to becoming important partners? How can China gradually increase its “share”? Why does China’s “share” not match China’s proportion in the global economy? What far-reaching significance does the increase in the weight of &quot;inclusion&quot; have on the internationalization of the RMB? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Lin Jianhai, former Secretary-General of the IMF and Executive Vice Chairman of the International Financial Forum (IFF). Since joining the IMF in 1989, Lin Jianhai has served in the IMF for more than 30 years. He grew from an ordinary employee to an IMF executive. During this period, he took office as the Deputy Secretary-General of the IMF in March 2010 and was promoted to the Secretary-General of the IMF from 2012 to 2020. He is the first Chinese to hold this position. He has personally experienced and deeply participated in the entire decision-making process of many major events such as the IMF quota reform and the inclusion of the RMB into the basket. He is the main organizer of major meetings of the IMF and the World Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, Lin Jianhai said that it is imperative for the IMF to play its due role in the global economic system and reform its own governance structure and effectiveness without waiting for others. China&#39;s current share in the IMF is far lower than its share in the global economy. As the economy continues to develop, my country&#39;s share of IMF China will definitely increase significantly. This is not a matter of if, but a matter of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Vo2Gp2TlGRdvAffzQkKNZijggSkQ4rjNVODVgjRA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;475&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Vo2Gp2TlGRdvAffzQkKNZijggSkQ4rjNVODVgjRA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Jianhai, former Secretary-General of the International Monetary Fund and current Executive Vice Chairman of the International Financial Forum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;RMB&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Into the Basket&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;a milestone&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;international monetary history&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, how has the relationship between my country and the IMF changed? of? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;my country is a founding country of the IMF and participated in the Bretton Woods Conference held in New Hampshire, USA in 1944. This conference laid the foundation for the stable development of the global economy after World War II and established the IMF and World Bank. At that time, delegations from 44 countries participated in this historic meeting, and the Kuomintang government delegation was one of them. Therefore, the relationship between my country and the IMF can be said to have a long history. In 1980, my country restored its seat in the IMF and opened a new chapter in exchanges with the IMF. Over the past four decades, my country and the IMF have grown to know each other and become important partners. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you personally get involved with the IMF? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Interestingly, although my country did not have many contacts with the IMF at the beginning of its restoration of seats, it has been mentioned in some international financial publications. There is a brief description of the IMF. For example, in the spring of 1981, I co-wrote an article titled &quot;On the Multiple Exchange Rate System and the Internal Settlement Price of my country&#39;s Trade Foreign Exchange&quot; with a teacher who taught international finance at the Beijing Institute of Foreign Trade at the time, which was published in the school&#39;s &quot;Foreign Trade Research&quot; &quot;Phase one. In this article, we introduce the concept and types of multiple exchange rate systems, the IMF&#39;s regulations restricting member states from implementing multiple exchange rate systems, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than forty years have passed in the blink of an eye. In order to write this article, I still vividly remember the scene of browsing reference materials. To be honest, when I wrote this article, I knew nothing about the IMF. At that time, there were no systematic international finance textbooks in China. I only found a brief introduction to the IMF from the teaching materials printed by the school. However, what I didn&#39;t expect was that from then on, I would form a lifelong bond with the IMF. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your more than 30 years of service at the IMF, the relationship between China and the IMF has Which thing in the movie impressed you the most? Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the past few decades, there have been many memorable stories in my country’s cooperation with the IMF, one of which is very meaningful. The thing is that in 2016, the RMB was included in the IMF&#39;s Special Drawing Rights (SDR) currency basket, and together with the U.S. dollar, euro, Japanese yen and pound sterling, it constitutes an internationally freely usable currency officially recognized by the international community. This is a milestone in the history of the development of the international monetary and financial system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerning this matter, I quoted in a short article the then IMF President Christine Lagarde’s statement after the IMF Executive Board meeting: “The Executive Board has decided to include the RMB in the SDR currency basket. The decision is an important milestone in China&#39;s economic integration into the global financial system. It is a recognition of China&#39;s achievements in reforming its currency and financial system over the past many years. China&#39;s continued advancement and deepening in this area will promote Establish a more dynamic international monetary and financial system.&quot; In the book &quot;Turning Crisis into Opportunities - A Closer Look at the IMF&quot; recently published by Xinhua Publishing House, I gave a relatively detailed introduction to the inclusion of the RMB in the basket and its significance. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From learning to active participation and leadership&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just said that my country restored its seat in the IMF in 1980. Is the launch of reform and opening up the main reason for our country to regain its seat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. The reform and opening up launched in 1978 was a great initiative and a milestone in the history of world economic development. Since then, our country’s economy has continued to grow and develop, and it has become deeply integrated into global economic development and governance. Significant achievements include China&#39;s restoration of its seats in the IMF and World Bank in 1980; China&#39;s accession to the World Trade Organization in 2001; the launch and establishment of the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank in 2015; in 2016, the RMB was added to the SDR currency basket, and the RMB&#39;s status as an international reserve currency was confirmed; By actively participating in the G20, APEC and other summit agendas, my country has begun to play a leading role in some fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;my country is deeply integrated into global economic development and governance . What do you think it means? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;my country’s deep participation in global economic governance has not only created a good external environment for its own development, but also played its due role in global economic governance. role. Overall, three aspects stand out: first, from zero participation in 1980 to multi-faceted participation later; second, from one-way to multi-faceted cooperation; third, from learning to active participation and leadership. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you predict my country’s performance in international economic governance? participation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the long run, as our country’s economic strength increases, our country’s participation in international affairs will continue to deepen, and in many economies It has played a certain leading role in , trade and financial issues. Especially with the increase in China&#39;s economic size and the deepening of foreign economic, trade and financial ties, my country is having an increasingly extensive impact on the economic development of other countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How can our country play a more responsible role? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, our country has a relatively small number of staff in international organizations, and even fewer high-level officials. Therefore, it is necessary to increase efforts to broaden and improve the training of international civil servants, improve relevant international organization management regulations, and provide a supportive environment for international organizations to set up headquarters or branches in China and achieve good operation and development. Our country&#39;s think tanks and universities should also take the initiative to maintain dialogue and cooperation with international organizations and other institutions in this field. They must be able to express their opinions rationally and rationally based on data and facts in the dialogue; they must be good at empathizing with others. , tell the story of China well and make the other party understand the story of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Our country&#39;s share in the IMF is lower than its share in the global economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of the restoration of the IMF seat, my country&#39;s share in the organization accounted for about 2% of the total share. Do you think this share is in line with the national conditions at that time? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1980, my country’s GDP accounted for only about 2% of the global economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;share&quot; of the IMF is equivalent to a country&#39;s shares in the IMF, which constitutes the IMF&#39;s equity capital, that is, its own funds. When a country joins the IMF, it is assigned an initial quota that roughly reflects the member&#39;s global economic size and contribution. The IMF determines share allocation through a formula. The current share formula consists of the weighted average of four variables, namely GDP (weighting 50%), openness (30%), economic volatility (15%) and international reserves (5 %). Therefore, calculating a country&#39;s &quot;share&quot; in the IMF is more complicated. We can simply understand &quot;share&quot; as the relative proportion of a country in the global economy, but it is not exactly the same. This is the difficulty in understanding &quot;share&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Quota&quot; determines the limit of capital contribution of member states to the IMF, and is also related to the amount of loans that member states can obtain from the IMF. &quot;Quota&quot; also determines the voting rights of member states, as well as the allocation of SDRs. the quantity obtained. Therefore, the number of “shares” is very important to member states, especially regarding their right to speak on the international economic stage. This also explains why each &quot;share&quot; reform is so important, but also so difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;36 years after my country resumed its IMF seat, that is, in January 2016 On the 27th, the IMF announced that the 2010 quota and governance reform plan officially came into effect. my country has officially become the third largest shareholder of the IMF. my country&#39;s share increased to 6.394%, and its ranking jumped from sixth to third, second only to the United States and Japan. The share almost doubled. How do you evaluate this achievement? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, my country’s share in the IMF is 6.4%, which is far lower than the United States’ 17.4% and Japan’s 6.5% %, even lower than China’s share of about 18% in the global economy. At the same time, the share of many developed economies, especially European countries, is much higher than their share in the global economy. This is a challenge facing the IMF, which requires the IMF to keep pace with the times and intensify reforms to ensure its legitimacy, effectiveness and credibility. In this regard, the IMF still has a long and difficult road to go. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;IMF&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Reforming in Difficulties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is the IMF undergoing reform? When is it expected to be completed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The IMF is undergoing a new round of quota reform, which is scheduled to be completed in mid-December 2023. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of IMF quota reform is mainly two-fold: first, to increase the IMF’s quota funds to enhance the IMF’s “ammunition arsenal” to help member countries cope with financial crises; second, to adjust the quotas of member countries. share to reflect changes in their status in the global economy, that is, to increase the voice of emerging markets and developing countries. In the IMF&#39;s recent statement, the IMF Executive Board proposed to the Board of Governors to increase the IMF&#39;s share by 50% and distribute it according to the current share proportions of each member country, but without adjusting the share proportions of member countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this so-called &quot;capital increase&quot; is not a substantive increase in capital, but a replacement of part of the non-quota funds with newly increased quota funds, leaving the total amount of IMF loanable funds unchanged. About a trillion dollars. Although the quota reform has made progress, it is understandable that this quota reform is not ideal and does not meet the calls of emerging markets and developing countries to reform the existing international economic governance system and improve their voice. &amp;nbsp;In the current complex international situation, this may be a realistic and desirable reform option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In this way, the IMF has been reforming under difficulties. What efforts have you made in the process of increasing my country&#39;s share? Was it particularly difficult? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From 2012 to 2020, as the Secretary-General of the IMF, I was responsible for the Board of Governors and the International Monetary Fund composed of global finance ministers and central bank governors. Coordinates with the Financial Committee and is responsible for the daily administrative affairs of the IMF Executive Board, as well as the arrangement and convening of nearly 350 Executive Board meetings each year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this position, I have personally experienced and deeply participated in global macroeconomic policy supervision and financial crisis relief work. I have also participated in the reform of IMF quotas and voice rights and the addition of RMB to the IMF Special Drawing Rights currency. basket and other major decisions. During this period, I learned a lot and did a lot of work. I deeply realized the importance of the knowledge, experience, thinking methods and judgment accumulated in the past work process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as quota reform is concerned, I mainly do a good job in communication and coordination, assisting the IMF president to fully understand the views of member countries, eliminate doubts, and reach a consensus as much as possible. This is a long process. For example, the quota reform plan passed in 2010 did not take effect until 2016. It went through countless meetings and face-to-face discussions, but the reform finally achieved relatively ideal results. China rose from the sixth largest shareholder of the IMF to the third largest shareholder. Third, Russia, India and Brazil among the BRICS countries have also joined the ranks of the top ten shareholders of the IMF. Therefore, work is both hard, fun and rewarding, because all efforts are for the benefit of member states and the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Although it is difficult and slow, the IMF is still reforming. How do you anticipate my country&#39;s share in the IMF and its role? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;With the continuous development of the economy, my country’s share of the IMF will definitely increase significantly. This is not a question of whether. It&#39;s a matter of time. In order for the IMF (including the World Bank) to play its due role in the global economic system, it is imperative to reform its own governance structure and effectiveness. This requires IMF member countries to stand at the height of global economic development and changes, transcend narrow self-interests, and work together to promote the reform of voice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The internationalization of the RMB still has a long way to go&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2022, while maintaining the currency composition of the existing SDR basket unchanged, the IMF will increase the weight of the RMB in the SDR currency basket from 10.92% to 12.28%. This is the first review result since the RMB became an SDR basket currency in 2016. Is this the result of the two-way opening up of China’s financial market? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2022, the IMF will increase the weight of the RMB in the Special Drawing Rights (SDR) currency basket from 10.92% to 12.28%. This is the first review completed since the RMB was officially added to the Special Drawing Rights currency basket on October 1, 2016. It reflects the IMF&#39;s recognition of the progress made in China&#39;s financial market reform and will also promote the internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The RMB has become the fifth currency in the SDR basket since October 1, 2016. This is an important milestone for China’s economic integration into the global financial system. It is also a sign of the IMF’s reform and opening up to China, especially the It is a recognition of China’s achievements in monetary policy and financial system. The inclusion of RMB into the SDR basket makes the basket more diversified and representative, thereby helping to improve the stability of the SDR and its attractiveness as an international reserve asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently, what profound impact has it had on the IMF and China? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The currency composition in the IMF SDR basket reflects the importance of these currencies in the international trade and financial system, and its composition and interest rates The level directly determines the level of IMF credit interest rates. The importance of this to lending countries is self-evident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The IMF&#39;s review once again confirmed the rationality of the SDR basket currency combination and increased the weight of the RMB in the SDR basket, which also shows that the internationalization of the RMB is constantly advancing. For China, this is an important recognition and a responsibility, and it is also the driving force for the continued internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If the RMB is to achieve continued internationalization, how can my country’s financial industry achieve a high level? Reform and Opening? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking forward to the prospects of RMB internationalization, the following aspects deserve attention:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, economy Sustained growth is the basis for the further internationalization of the RMB. Over the past four decades, with rapid economic development, my country has become the world&#39;s second largest economy and largest trading nation, laying the foundation for the gradual internationalization of the RMB. Continuing to maintain stable economic growth, improving the macroeconomic and financial policy framework, and preventing violent fluctuations in the financial market are crucial to the further internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, reform and opening up is the guarantee for the further internationalization of the RMB. China&#39;s foreign economic activities continue to grow and develop, driving the overseas transactions and use of RMB. It is imperative to steadily advance the opening of capital accounts, continue to expand financial opening to the outside world, and promote the cross-border use of RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, improving the financial system and deepening the development of the financial market are the driving forces for the further internationalization of the RMB. The depth, breadth and openness of the domestic financial market are conducive to enhancing the confidence and use of the RMB in foreign markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, continuous improvement of the exchange rate system is a booster for the further internationalization of the RMB. Adhering to market supply and demand as the basis, enhancing the flexibility of the RMB exchange rate, and giving full play to the function of the exchange rate as an automatic stabilizer in regulating macroeconomics and the balance of payments, will help to give full play to its price signal role and improve the efficiency of resource allocation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, promoting cross-border trade pricing and settlement is a breakthrough for the further internationalization of the RMB. China&#39;s huge foreign trade scale is the biggest advantage in promoting the internationalization of the RMB. At present, the proportion of local currency settlement in China&#39;s trade still has considerable room for growth. Starting from cross-border trade pricing and settlement, improving cross-border RMB settlement services can achieve twice the result with half the effort in promoting the internationalization of RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the RMB’s inclusion in the SDR and the increase in its weight are important events for China, the IMF and its member countries, and will benefit the country in the long run. In the foreseeable future, the currencies in the SDR basket will continue to serve as the world&#39;s major reserve currencies. However, compared with the role of the US dollar in the international financial system, the internationalization of the RMB still has a long way to go, and it can be said that there is a long way to go. The further internationalization of the RMB is inseparable from the support of China&#39;s sustained economic growth, high-level opening up, and continuous improvement of the financial system and market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[湖南衡阳政务数据经营权出让被叫停：公共数据不应“资本化”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261010]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;nation&#39;s first&quot; public data franchise transfer transaction was halted. Well parked! Public data should be used with caution and should not be used as a &quot;franchise&quot; and become a tool for a few people to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Securities Daily&quot; report, on November 10, Hunan Hengyang City Public Resources Trading Center issued the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Resources and Smart City Franchise Transfer Project Transaction Announcement&quot; to transfer the city&#39;s political data Resources and smart city franchise rights are listed at a base price of 1.802 billion yuan, with a price increase of 10 million yuan. But a few days later, the transaction was requested to be suspended by the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the transferor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data is considered by some to be another &quot;factor of production&quot; in addition to land, labor, capital, and technology. Many organizations that own data want to get a piece of it. This &quot;first in the country&quot; government data auction announcement attracted great attention, and some people in the industry spoke highly of it, believing that it was the first of its kind to capitalize on government data elements. Some even believed that government data might replace land and become the basis for local government An important asset and source of income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the prerequisite for the transaction is clear ownership. Who does the data belong to? A piece of data contains information that usually involves different parties. For example, a person purchases a piece of clothing from an online store. This message involves consumers and online stores. So, who owns the rights to this information? If it belongs to consumers, theoretically, online stores cannot sell this information. If the ownership of the information belongs to the online store operator, do consumers have the right to withdraw and request the operator to delete this information? Even if only a subset of consumers ask for information to be deleted, the integrity of the entire data set is greatly weakened. How valuable is such data? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issue of data ownership is even more important when it comes to public data. The so-called public data refers to data generated by administrative agencies, public institutions, public institutions, state-owned enterprises and other public institutions in the process of performing their duties or providing public services. For example, case data from public hospitals, subway passenger flow data, census data from the Bureau of Statistics, marriage and divorce data from the Civil Affairs Bureau, etc. It is questionable whether these public authorities have the rights to this data. Under intellectual property law, official documents and other content produced by government agencies in performing their duties are not copyrightable. The reason is that using copyright to protect these official documents is not conducive to the disclosure of government information and is not conducive to social and public interests. In the field of public data, should this principle also be followed? Public agencies cannot own data obtained and formed in the course of performing their duties? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, data from public institutions usually contain sensitive information such as citizens’ names and ID numbers. In theory, public data should be desensitized before being made available to outsiders. However, hasty operations may result in incomplete desensitization and leave behind some personal information. Even if there is no problem with the desensitization process, if the granularity of the data provided is too fine, it is still possible to deduce already desensitized personal information through cross-analysis with other data. In a situation where data leakage is very serious and almost everyone has nowhere to hide in the face of big data, this possibility cannot but be considered. Once the data is desensitized, it may be used by telecommunications network fraud, causing heavy losses to the parties concerned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the &quot;20 Data Articles&quot; issued by the central government (&quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Building a Data Basic System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements&quot;) pointed out that the use of data must be in order to safeguard the national Data security, protection of personal information and business secrets are the premise. Especially for public data, it must be utilized on the premise of protecting personal privacy and ensuring public safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The information in public data is all information produced or obtained by relevant agencies in the process of performing administrative management or other public duties. According to relevant regulations on government information disclosure, information produced or obtained by administrative agencies in the course of performing their duties, except for information involving confidentiality or personal privacy, should be disclosed in a timely and accurate manner. According to the same principle, information generated by other public agencies in the course of providing public services should also be disclosed as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data is a collection of pieces of information. Every piece of information in the public data set should be made public, so naturally the entire data set should also be made public, and cannot be given or received privately, becoming an &quot;asset&quot; that the government can sell. From this perspective, even those public data that can be used should not be auctioned or &quot;franchised&quot; and become a tool for some people to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;20 Data Articles&quot; emphasize the need to protect the public interest in the supply and use of public data. To protect public interests, the best way is to make it public, not &quot;auction&quot;. Unlike land and other exclusive production factors, data is not exclusive. If a piece of land is given to A, B can no longer use it. Therefore, in order to maximize public interests, the land can be auctioned and awarded to the highest bidder, with the proceeds used by the government for public utilities. The data is different. If A is used, B can still be used. The reusable nature of data determines that only disclosure can achieve greater utilization, create greater value, and is more in line with the public interest. If the use of public data is handed over to a &quot;third party&quot; in the form of a &quot;franchise&quot;, it is actually giving this third party the power to monopolize public data with administrative power. This third party then charges other users, which increases the costs for other users and harms the interests of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, public data occupies a very large proportion and status in data. Currently, more than 80% of China’s data is in the hands of the government. As the pressure on government revenue and expenditure continues to increase, it is understandable that local governments are eager to find ways to generate income that can replace land finance. But if you want to monetize the public data you hold, you must be cautious. How to use public data must go through extensive discussions and reach social consensus. Until then, it’s better to rest on the “capitalization” of public data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[第三轮中央生态环境保护督察全面启动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261029]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 18:03:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the &quot;Central Ecological Environmental Protection Inspection Work Regulations&quot; and approved by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, the third round of central ecological Environmental protection inspection will be fully launched on November 21. The first batch of five central ecological and environmental protection inspection teams was formed to conduct inspections in five provinces: Fujian, Henan, Hainan, Gansu, and Qinghai for about one month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reporter learned from the Ministry of Ecology and Environment that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, the inspection team always adheres to the people-centered approach, adheres to serving the overall situation, adheres to the system concept, adheres to the problem-oriented and strict tone, and adheres to precise scientific and legal compliance. Focus on supervising the implementation of Xi Jinping’s Thoughts on Ecological Civilization by provincial party committees and governments and the major decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council on the construction of ecological civilization, the implementation and responsibilities of ecological and environmental protection responsibilities of relevant provincial departments, and the ecological and environmental protection of prefectural and municipal party committees and governments. Work progress and implementation status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the inspection, the inspection team will focus on the implementation of Xi Jinping Thought on Ecological Civilization and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions and instructions; the implementation of relevant major decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council; accelerating the green transformation of development methods and promoting high-tech development. Quality development, resolutely curb the blind launch of &quot;two high and one low&quot; projects and the elimination of backward production capacity; prominent ecological and environmental problems in the implementation of major regional strategies; major ecological damage, environmental pollution, ecological and environmental risks and their treatment; environmental infrastructure construction and operation status; the rectification of problems discovered by previous inspections; the prominent ecological and environmental problems reported by the people; the implementation of &quot;equal responsibilities of the party and government&quot; and &quot;double responsibilities for one post&quot; for ecological and environmental protection, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the period of stationing, each inspection team set up contact numbers and postal mailboxes respectively to accept letters, calls and reports on the ecological and environmental protection of the inspected objects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>