<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“吃货文人”梁实秋丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:31:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男性没有情绪价值需要”是偏见：互相取暖才能行稳致远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among the many values ​​that one person can provide to another person, emotional value is the most embodying &quot;interactivity&quot; &quot;A kind of. If two people interact and lose the &quot;reciprocity&quot; of emotional value, and the emotional value only becomes the supply of one party, it must mean that the power and status between the two people are not equal, and the person in the lower position needs to pay attention to the person in the upper position. Continuously provide emotional value, the so-called &quot;lower and smaller&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relationship between the sexes should generally be an equal relationship. Respecting each other and pleasing each other is a normal relationship. In this sense, men&#39;s need for emotional value is often ignored, which is an unavoidable issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger said that men actually need emotional value very much. He mentioned a typical example: an old man on the Internet complained on Weibo, talking about his mid-life crisis and his emotional breakdown. For a moment. This old man on the Internet usually appears as a &quot;friend of women&quot;, so he has accumulated a certain number of female fans. As a result, when he started to complain, he did not gain sympathy and comfort from his female fans, even though he usually provided emotional value to his female fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger lamented: Some women seem to truly believe that men must be very happy and should not complain. And they themselves complain all the time. Even if they look very happy to outsiders many times, they can always find something to complain about. These women seem to have a collective consciousness, &quot;You must never let men feel happiness, and you must never let men gain emotional value. As for why, I can&#39;t understand it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very close to my heart. Of course, there are always many examples of couples treating each other as guests or pleasing each other. However, according to my observation, men are always more likely to be frustrated in the process of obtaining emotional value from women. It is this kind of frustration that Fang Hongjian encounters in his wife in &quot;Fortress Besieged&quot;. Before getting married, the relationship between the two was okay, and Sun Roujia gave him a special kind of psychological satisfaction in the face of adversity. But after marriage, Sun Roujia seems to have changed into a different person, which makes readers feel a little incredible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger believes that men and women are not all interested in sex. If a woman talks about her emotional value every day and tries to squeeze her to the limit, any man with some self-respect will eventually leave - for example, Fang Hongjian had this intention. Of course, there are different ways to leave. Many men find that &quot;the emotional value that women cannot give, brothers can give, games can give, and even fishing can give.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very &quot;straight man&quot; statement. It not only explains why there are many &quot;fishing guys&quot; gathering at the nightclub by the river in front of my house all day long, but also explains why some middle-aged men The reason why they always play some games or wait quietly downstairs for a while before going home after work: they know that there are endless complaints and endless mental wear and tear inside the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is, as the blogger said: In the past many years, men’s demand for emotional value has been suppressed. So many women think that men only need to pay. The reason why this kind of abnormal relationship can barely be maintained is because a kind of ideological stamp called &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; restrains men - whether it is to society or to the family. Traditional thoughts and values ​​tell men that you must get married and have this baby. And should suffer for it to be sucked out of any value including happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These words must have hit the hearts of many men who cannot feel happy in their marriages. Many ladies often say that they need to find someone who is &quot;emotionally stable&quot; to get married. Why? The main reason for this choice is probably not only to eliminate those men who are emotionally unstable and like to get angry, but in a deeper and more practical situation, to allow &quot;emotionally stable&quot; men to work hard for the family and regard endurance as the highest pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, as a human being, who should be emotionally stable more than whom? This is clearly a false proposition. Emotional stability is always relative. No one is born with an &quot;emotionally stable&quot; person, and there is never any instability - if such a person exists, it must be made of plastic and steel. It is worth noting that when this requirement becomes a matter of course, it will inevitably lead to the emergence of unfair situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why get married? I&#39;m afraid everyone has their own ideas, but in general, it&#39;s nothing more than these points: continue to write about love, get stable sex, and raise children. When it comes to responsibilities after marriage, in most cases, men often become the main or even the only source of income for the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The twists and turns in the marriage of Fu Seoul and Lao Liu fully demonstrate that emotional value is affected by family economic relations. Once a man takes care of his children at home, the outcome is often not optimistic. Because society has different tolerances for stay-at-home wives and stay-at-home husbands, if a man wants to maintain his dignity and not be discriminated against or feel cowardly, he can only try his best to earn as much money as possible - preferably more than his wife. After all, a man who wanders around the world is more likely to be looked down upon by public opinion than a woman who only takes care of her children at home, and may even be regarded as a &quot;good-for-nothing waste.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It stands to reason that under the male-domestic model, men have great hope of gaining emotional value in the family. But interestingly, the theoretical connotations are often broken in reality. Some men work so hard outside that when they get home they are told that they only know how to play games but don&#39;t know how to do housework. It is sometimes labeled &quot;widowed parenting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, the so-called emotional value is &quot;coaxing&quot;. When a woman feels sad, a man will coax her, and vice versa. If men are always forcibly given a &quot;strong&quot; and &quot;rigid&quot; personality, and are made into a character insulated from emotional value, and blindly give in a wider range; in other words, men must take care of women&#39;s emotions, and in turn, men must take care of women&#39;s emotions. It won&#39;t work if you come over. Even if the man has troubles and can only solve them on his own, then the relationship will change and the emotional foundation of sharing weal and woe will be lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t men have emotional needs, or shouldn’t they seek emotional help? Of course not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the issue of emotional value, men and women should be equal. Acknowledging that men and women alike have emotional value needs and giving them respect and care is the normal way of getting along. Based on this, caring for each other and solving each other&#39;s problems is the way to balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A family must not become a quagmire where one party enjoys absolute power and the other party can only make concessions. No one would be willing to marry a slave or a &quot;slave owner&quot;, so both men and women hope that their rights and spirit will be respected by the other party, and refuse to kneel down and make endless unilateral contributions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current marriage rate is plummeting, the divorce rate is rising, and the number of unmarried people is increasing. To a certain extent, it shows that young people have a more rational and strict examination of the connotation of &quot;home&quot;, and thus take the initiative to make their own The body and mind escape from an invisible shackles. This cold fact tells us that marriage and family are &quot;non-material&quot; subjects that two people manage together with love and sincerity. If we want to make marriage and family last longer, and if we want everyone to have more confidence in marriage and family, we must treat the emotional needs of both parties fairly, create a loving and reciprocal relationship, and especially abandon the prejudice that &quot;men have no emotional value needs&quot; , so that each other can maintain the consciousness of understanding and tolerating each other to the greatest extent, and only by providing warmth to each other can we move forward steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戛纳金棕榈获奖影片，一场对亲密关系的审判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcO ZC4eqXITmA884bPF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie, after the husband fell to his death from a building, the court began a trial to determine whether it was murder or suicide. , while also unveiling an analysis of family relationships. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a cabin under the French Alps, an interview is taking place. The female writer seems to be good at avoiding questions, and once turned into the guest and became the questioner. The young reporter sitting opposite her seemed a little overwhelmed and had no choice but to follow her wishes and start chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly, the music played by the writer&#39;s husband came from upstairs, which was deafening, and his dissatisfaction was obvious. The interview was terminated and the female reporter left. Shortly after she left, the writer&#39;s husband was found dead in the snow outside the cabin by their son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, who is the murderer? According to previous suspense narrative strategies, the plot always has to go through multiple reversals before the truth comes to light. The film &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot;, which just won the Palme d&#39;Or at the Cannes Film Festival in 2023, provides another solution. Director Justine Trier does not seem to care whether the plot is reversed, and it does not even matter who the murderer is. unimportant. Putting aside the cloak of suspense, Trier is more interested in how people use their own narratives to complete the analysis of a death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film cleverly sets up the court trial, so that the intimate relationships that should be in the private realm are laid bare and presented to the public. One party wants to prove murder, and the other wants to prove her innocence by proving that her husband committed suicide. Both parties are trying to use their own narratives to get closer to the truth, and all clues may become evidence in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novelist, Sandler Voight&#39;s writing has become the object of scrutiny by the prosecution. &quot;Her life is in the book, especially her relationships.&quot; In the novel, the wife&#39;s disgust for her husband, the possibility of her husband&#39;s death, and the imagination of how to kill are all understood as reflections of the real motivations for killing. Under this kind of scrutiny, the narratives in the book are no longer complete. They are cut into fragments or even sentences, and then the narrative is reconstructed using human will to connect it with reality in the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the key pieces of evidence in the film is the recording of her husband Samuel before his death. Samuel is a former teacher who also enjoys writing. Out of guilt for being partially responsible for his son Daniel&#39;s permanent vision impairment, Samuel spent a great deal of his time on various family matters and on Daniel&#39;s company. He seemed unapologetic and willing, but the recording revealed another side of the family&#39;s close relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recording, Samuel asked his wife to reconsider the division of labor in the family, believing that he had sacrificed too much personal time on family affairs and that he wanted more time to write. After listening, Sandler mocked him coldly, saying that a writer would not stop writing just because he had children and housework. No one forced him, and he did not owe him anything. The director seemed to have intentionally reversed the genders. What Samuel experienced was actually the helpless and struggling situation of many women in married relationships in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the dispute between the two in the recording became more intense. Sandler&#39;s bisexual identity, cheating and other private information were revealed one by one from Samuel&#39;s mouth, and fell into the ears of everyone in the trial. In the view of the prosecution, these are the motives and reasons for the unbalanced relationship between husband and wife and the wife to murder her husband. Here, the recording, which originally only recorded a certain dimension of the relationship between people, is also used to refer to the whole picture, helping the prosecution complete the deduction and reconstruction of the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandler attempted to deny this ever-reconstructed narrative, telling Samuel&#39;s psychiatrist, who was one of the witnesses, &quot;You&#39;re only telling a small part of the whole situation. A pair of Husband and wife are like a mess...&quot; She believed that this did not prove that she was the murderer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradox is that Sandler himself is also consciously or unconsciously self-narrating the truth, including her husband&#39;s unusual behavior in taking medicine six months before his death, seeing a psychiatrist, and being depressed in writing, etc. , all became her reconstruction of the reasons for his suicide during the defense process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the evidence fragments presented by both the prosecution and the defense are real, perhaps no one dares to confirm that the suicide or homicide story reconstructed based on these fragments is the truth itself. As director Justine Trier said, &quot;This is very modern, this is how we live today. In the trial, various things change and are given extra weight, resulting in new fictions.&quot; &quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evidence was not only presented in front of the prosecution and defense, but also slowly unfolded in front of his son Daniel, who also began to look at his parents again. At first, he had no doubts about his mother, but as the two sides narrated at the trial, his attitude gradually became swaying, and he even had an image in his mind of his mother hitting his father hard and pushing him downstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, he also tried to give medicine to the dog to verify the fact that his mother said that his father had vomited after taking medicine. He also recalled the conversation his father had with him when he sent the dog to the doctor. He thought This revealed his father&#39;s suicidal tendencies. From various swings to his own selection of factual fragments after review, Daniel finally constructed his own narrative version of the truth in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A still from &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; (also translated as &quot;Judgment of a Fall&quot;). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier once mentioned in an interview, &quot;These trials have a profound impact on people.&quot; It&#39;s a nightmare to say because your own life is being taken away from you. Everyone is creating a fiction and not really trying to get to the truth. I&#39;m very fascinated by truth and trying to find it through stories and I find that very interesting .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the director also wants to draw the audience into the search for the truth and the construction of the narrative. Under the shell of suspense, we as the audience have naturally been thinking about who the murderer is since Samuel fell from the building. In the battle between the prosecution and the defense, every time they list new evidence, make new statements and excuses, we, like Daniel, can&#39;t help but turn our eyes to Samuel and Sandler, trying to learn from the evidence provided by both sides. Find your own narrative from factual evidence and their narratives to deduce the truth of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But outside the film, we are more passive. All narratives are always based on the characters&#39; interpretation of the truth in the film, which also means that our perception of the truth is more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film ends with Sandler being found not guilty. Since there are elements of fiction on both sides, why does one narrative prevail over the other? Perhaps it was the emotional power of it - Daniel&#39;s monologue about his father moved the judge and helped his mother win. After Sandler came home, Daniel hugged and kissed her. In the silence of the room, a rare warmth lingered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this the truth? Not really. In the previous narratives from all parties, the director has successfully planted the seeds of doubt in the hearts of the audience. Even if Sandler was found not guilty, people&#39;s hesitation and uncertainty about the truth have not disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandra Wheeler, who plays the heroine, once asked the director about the script, whether her character was guilty or innocent. Trier told her, &quot;I don&#39;t know, but I hope You act as if she is innocent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She could be responsible but not guilty, or she could be guilty but not responsible. She could be responsible for driving him to suicide but not guilty of killing him, or she could be guilty of killing him without wanting to. to kill him - either in an impulsive way or in a way that we can try to imagine. The truth is there, but it is too complex to grasp here.&quot; Director Justine Trier said in Said this in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But looking back, the truth may no longer be important. Fiction is a human talent. As long as you are willing, you can construct your own narrative with the help of a few keywords. However, if the relationships between people are like this death, being scrutinized and reconstructed, then in fact, no relationship can withstand such rigorous and detailed analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚太安全专家谈：中国发展红利被周边国家共享]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the end of the Cold War, despite some geopolitical tensions or regional hot issues, the Asia-Pacific region has still maintained peace Stablize. In Europe and the Middle East, wars broke out one after another. How to interpret such an international situation? Why has the Asia-Pacific region been able to maintain peace and stability for decades? How to continue to maintain a prosperous and stable Asia-Pacific? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 29, 2023, at the &quot;Dialogue of Chinese and Foreign Experts&quot; at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, former vice minister of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the People&#39;s Republic of China and founder of the Tsinghua Institute of International Security Strategy, said at the meeting that after the Cold War, the Asia-Pacific region seized the opportunity, quickly opened up to the outside world, and quickly entered regional integration. In the past few decades, there have been no major wars, political conflicts, or major social unrest in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Asia-Pacific region has enjoyed peaceful development for more than 40 years. In this process, China has played a central role. The dividends of China&#39;s rapid regional development have been shared by neighboring countries. China is also the largest international player in most Asia-Pacific countries. trading partner country,&quot; Fu Ying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 29, 2023, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 29, 2023 , many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining security in the Asia-Pacific.&quot; (Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Economic Development Miracle&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t know if you remember that in the 1980s (of the last century), when the Asia-Pacific region began multilateral cooperation, China also joined the regional integration At the time of globalization, many countries are still walking on the edge of development and poverty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying said in her speech that over the past long period of time, the Asia-Pacific region has achieved extremely rapid economic development, surpassing There are many countries and regions in the market. Citing data from the Bank of Asia, she said that in the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown sevenfold. This phenomenon is also called the &quot;economic development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying believes that peace and stability, regional focus on cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization are important reasons for the economic development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the unique driving force behind decades of stability and security in the Asia-Pacific region? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In order to maintain long-term stability and security in the Asia-Pacific, we need to discover a unique &#39;Asia-Pacific model.&#39;&quot; Chen Dongxiao, president of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, said that &quot;open regionalism&quot; is an important driving factor , and this concept contains many contents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;First of all, economic development cooperation is the focus. It transcends ideologies and government differences. Secondly, under regional openness, no matter big or small, all countries need to abide by relevant rules and regulations and should Follow social rules in an equal way. It is very important that we should not have double standards,&quot; said Chen Dongxiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast to the peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region, wars have been raging in Europe and the Middle East in recent years. During the forum discussion, two European and American scholars also expressed their thoughts on the &quot;differences between China and the West.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Why is the Asia-Pacific region different from Europe? There are many reasons behind it.” Michael Swain, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs in the United States, believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergei Karaganov, dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics, agreed with Shi Wen’s point of view, saying that “it is still in the early stages and we still have to remain cautious.” . At the same time, he also emphasized the &quot;cultural factors&quot; in Europe that were different from Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;European history is filled with many wars. European peace or war is always closely related to Europe&#39;s internal problems.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The risks of U.S. leadership are growing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As for the role of the United States in Asia-Pacific security, Huang Jae-ho, director of the Center for International Studies at Hankuk University of Foreign Studies, said, &quot;Although there is no perfect leadership in the world ( model), but the risks of U.S. leadership are growing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the U.S. policy toward China as an example, he said that from the Trump administration to the current Biden administration, the United States has undergone many changes in overall strategy and economic details. &quot;The United States has not seen the overall situation clearly, and its strategies and tactics are unclear. Therefore, the United States lacks a consistent vision and policy, which has caused instability in the current international order.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs, mentioned in his speech that &quot;China&#39;s ultimate security role in Asia is still uncertain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying directly refuted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t quite agree with this type of view. Mr. Michael Sven&#39;s logic is very confusing.&quot; Fu Ying said that China has actively promoted economic development in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited a lot from it. . This &quot;unconvincing&quot; logic probably originates from the theory of power change in the international community for hundreds of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, you know that China’s development background is completely different.” She said that there are big differences between China and the United States. But it does not affect China and the United States in pursuing their own development and supporting and benefiting from each other. If you think that China&#39;s strength has become a &quot;threat&quot; in the Asia-Pacific region, how should you view the rise of emerging countries such as India and Indonesia in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying also pointed out that the United States is currently anxious about its declining global influence, but this is not a problem caused by China, but the result of &quot;economic globalization and the United States itself making too many mistakes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The United States&#39; own problems make it difficult. Look at what benefits the United States has gained from the trade war? The trade war has caused the U.S.-China trade deficit to continue to increase, but has it reduced China&#39;s exports to the United States? In fact, it is not, on the contrary, the data is still increasing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She proposed that the United States should be an active contributor to the development of the region, rather than trying to use competition to prioritize and define the region&#39;s agenda and &quot;hijack&quot; A long-term agenda for successful cooperation, dialogue and economic development in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Finding balance and crisis management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In their speeches, many scholars unanimously stated that the old balance in the international order may be broken and new changes are about to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergey Karaganov said that as the United States and Western society began to exert influence to change globalization, the so-called era of globalization has ended. He said that we must have a new theory or a new global governance model, and this model must be decided by all partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For so many years, we have been saying that we want to achieve a win-win situation and that we want to benefit all parties involved. But unfortunately, we do not live in an ideal world. Sometimes we need to be shocked and we need to and reach a balance with different countries,” Sergey Karaganov said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Michael Swan said that any international system must balance the needs of different countries and cooperate after balancing. (Countries) need to seek common interests, have the same demands for economic development, and whether there are the same issues left over from history that need to be resolved, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He insisted that the current uncertainty still exists between countries and cannot be controlled. Countries large and small will be affected by changes in power, and there will undoubtedly be uncertainty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It cannot be said that China believes that all countries are unified and we can do this. It cannot solve many basic problems. Moreover, this is not caused by the United States, but due to structural changes. Yes, it will also trigger changes in the international order.&quot; Shi Wen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to maintain security and peace in the Asia-Pacific region before the new international order is formed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao proposed the &quot;three no&#39;s&quot; principle - that is, not to divide the group camp, not to initiate military war, especially nuclear war, and not to use double standards. &quot;In the past few years, the Chinese government has repeatedly reiterated on many occasions that war is not a good way to deal with differences between countries. On the contrary, it brings more crises.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao believes that Sino-US relations are an important factor in regional security. At the same time, the role of small countries in the Asia-Pacific region cannot be ignored, and they should not be divided into any faction. &quot;Some neutral countries, such as ASEAN countries, can play an important role in dealing with differences and achieving related cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Zaihao pointed out that compared with other regions, the Asia-Pacific region is relatively stable and China and the United States can maintain a relative balance. There are currently outside voices claiming that China and the United States have entered a &quot;new Cold War,&quot; but he believes this is more like a &quot;complex competition.&quot; Moreover, the two major countries have now begun crisis management and set up communication channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, there is no war now, only fighting, so it can still be controlled.” Huang Zaihao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九名市州长“进京检讨”：自然资源部组建以来首次高规格集中、公开约谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259895]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZylf9D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZ ylf9D. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, at the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, there were still flowers placed on the edge of the land with potted plants for sale. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Li Gui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the largest fresh cut flower trading market in Asia, Dounan Flower Market in Kunming City, Yunnan Province It is crowded all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the north side of Dounan Flower Market, across the road is another flower-related market - Yinlian Potted Flower Market. Unlike Dounan, which mainly sells fresh cut flowers, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, built in 2012, sells mostly green plants and potted plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, there was a potted flower market where various seedlings and succulents were grown in the greenhouses, and now some vegetables are also grown there. This has to do with natural resource inspectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 15, 2023, on Funei Street in Beijing, the Ministry of Natural Resources reported on the main violations of laws and regulations discovered during routine inspections in 2023. Among them, the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Yinlian Potted Flower Market was named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to reporting on typical issues, the Ministry of Natural Resources also held an interview meeting: Entrusted by the Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, Chen Chenzhao, the full-time Deputy Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, reviewed the violations of laws and regulations discovered by the inspectors in 2023. The main leaders of 9 municipal (state) governments held face-to-face interviews when the problem was highlighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nine cities (states) are Shijiazhuang City in Hebei Province, Harbin City in Heilongjiang Province, Wenzhou City in Zhejiang Province, Chuzhou City in Anhui Province, Linyi City in Shandong Province, Hechi City in Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, and Qianxinan Guizhou Province in Guizhou Province. Prefecture, Kunming City, Yunnan Province, and Lanzhou City, Gansu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the mayors of the cities (prefectures) who represented these cities (states) in the interviews, the deputy secretaries-general of the provincial (autonomous region) governments where these cities and states are located, and the &quot;top leaders of the natural resources departments at the provincial and municipal levels&quot; ” was also asked to attend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published by the Office of the General Inspector of Natural Resources stated that the interview was to “face-to-face point out the outstanding problems discovered by the inspector, urge the local government to increase rectification and investigation efforts, resolutely curb illegal activities on farmland, and firmly guard the Cultivated land protection red line”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first large-scale, high-level centralized and public interview held by the Ministry of Natural Resources since its establishment in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;Illegal occupation of cultivated land&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;77 acres&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Enter from Gate 1 of Yinlian Potted Flower Market , the first thing that comes into view are various shops with the words &quot;flowers&quot;, &quot;seedlings&quot; and &quot;horticulture&quot; printed on them. In October, osmanthus, bougainvillea and various camellias are still in bloom at the entrance of some shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of these shops exist in the form of greenhouses: the open air outside the house and the roof made of transparent film are covered with a black sunshade net; there are few cement and ceramic tiles on the floor inside the house, and most of them are smoothed. Yellow soil - the flower pots with plants are placed on the ground, and the roots come out from the bottom of the pot. The soil will provide them with moisture and nutrients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Go northwest along the main road for about 300 meters. The shops, greenhouses and sunshade nets have all disappeared, and both sides of the road have become empty and open spaces. There were many bulging white woven bags lying on the open ground. The word &quot;feed&quot; was printed on the outside of the bags. You could smell the stench of feces if you got close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers wearing sun hats tore open the bags and spread the black fertilizer on the yellow mud ground, and someone else opened it with a hoe. An excavator in the distance was working in another open space, and there was a rumbling sound. If it weren&#39;t for being in a city, the scene here would look no different from autumn sowing in the countryside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before it became a vacant lot, it was also a greenhouse selling green plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About a month ago, in September 2023, the greenhouse was demolished after an inspection by leaders of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City. On October 25, 2023, a greenhouse owner who once opened a shop here said that before the shed was demolished, he moved to the current greenhouse in August 2023. The two places are about 500 meters apart, and both are managed by Yinlian Community The established Kunming Qiding Economic and Trade Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Kunming Qiding) is responsible for leasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greenhouse owner said that although the lease contract between the two parties was signed once a year, he had been operating the original greenhouse for nearly ten years. Talking about the reason for moving the store, he thought it was &quot;policy adjustment&quot;: &quot;That piece of land was not approved for commercial use at the time, so it was demolished.&quot; When signing the contract, Kunming Geding &quot;wasn&#39;t sure&quot; about the nature of the land. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, in a notification from the Ministry of Natural Resources, the aforementioned open land was classified as cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that in February 2019, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Chenggong District, Kunming City was included in the scope of rectification of the &quot;big shed house&quot; problem and passed the rectification acceptance; in July 2022, the Yinlian Community will have been reclaimed The agricultural greenhouses were rented to 76 merchants for selling potted flowers, agricultural supplies, pesticides and other business activities, illegally occupying 77 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strictly speaking, the focus of the &quot;big shed house&quot; issue is not the form of building the house, but the nature of the land where the house is built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Agricultural Engineering Technology&quot; magazine, which is under the supervision of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, once explained in an article that the &quot;big shed&quot; problem refers to the illegal construction of agricultural facilities or agricultural parks by some industrial and commercial enterprises, individuals and organizations. The essence of illegally occupying cultivated land or even permanent basic farmland for non-agricultural construction is to change the nature and use of the land, change the agricultural production function, and touch the red line of cultivated land protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Information released by the WeChat public account of the &quot;Chenggong District Natural Resources Bureau&quot; shows that in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Supervision inspected the cleanup and rectification of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Kunming City in 2019. It was found that two cases involving the rebound of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Chenggong District were involved, one of which was the Yinlian Potted Flower Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, a staff member of the Chenggong Branch of the Kunming Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;responsibility for rectification of the &quot;greenhouse&quot; problem involved lies with the street, and he can report it to the Street to understand the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yinlian Potted Flower Market is located in Dounan Street. On October 25, 2023, a person in charge of the Dounan Street Office said: “(The contents in the shed) were vacated before, but last year due to the epidemic and villages were demolished, some green plants for sale were placed in the shed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the street said that during the inspection in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Inspection pointed out the existence of Question: &quot;According to the (inspector&#39;s) requirements, it is required to see loess inside the shed, but if there are things on the soil, it is considered a violation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Chenggong District Natural Resources The Planning Branch and the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau jointly issued notices ordering rectification of illegal acts and time-limited rectification notices to multiple land users. The person in charge of the aforementioned street stated that in accordance with the requirements of the rectification notice, they need to &quot;restore the problematic greenhouse to the state of 2019&quot; before the end of September 2023, that is, empty the contents of the shed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the specific implementation stage, the rectification requirements have been repeatedly refined. The person in charge of the street remembered that in June 2023, after the things in the shed were vacated, the soil was also loosened, but the relevant departments “will put forward different requirements for every different inspection.” “So we have repeatedly asked, and today we have to Remove the house number, and tomorrow I will tell you that there is still an advertisement on the door and I want to remove it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of August 2023, only the empty shell of the greenhouse remained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;昆明市呈贡区委书记陈净（左二）在斗南街道殷联盆花市场“大棚房”整改工作现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（“呈贡发布”微信公众号/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;多个共性问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大棚腾空近一个月后，2023年9月15日下午，包括昆明在内的9个市（州）被自然资源部约谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然资源部共有北京、沈阳、上海、南京、济南、广州、武汉、成都、西安等9个自然资源地方督察局。约谈会上，9个地方督察局的局长，分别通报了督察发现的违法违规问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然资源部官网公开的信息显示，此次督察发现部分地区耕地保护责任落实不到位，耕地“非农化”“非粮化”等冲击红线的突出问题依然存在，各类园区、开发区、城市市政道路未批先建等非农建设问题比较突出，违规占用永久基本农田和一般耕地种植草皮问题在部分省份不同程度存在，“大棚房”问题禁而未绝，违法侵占耕地挖湖造景问题在一些地方仍有发生，有些地方违反生态保护红线管控要求违规批矿、非法采矿严重破坏生态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;情况通报则披露了更多详细情况。综合来看，被约谈的9个市（州）出现违法违规用地问题的数量，在所在省份均排名靠前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，石家庄、哈尔滨、温州、滁州、兰州存在违法违规问题“全省排名第一”，临沂、贵州黔西南州，“全省排名靠前”，昆明“问题个数排名全省第一、耕地面积排名全省第二”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，此次督察亦发现多座城市存在多个共性问题。如耕地“非农化”“非粮化”等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通报显示，哈尔滨存在“非农化”问题51个，涉及耕地900.68亩；临沂存在“非农化”问题111个，涉及耕地1065.56亩；河池存在“非农化”问题150个，涉及耕地2629.55亩；黔西南州存在“非农化”问题207个，占用耕地1649.65亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耕地“非农化”更具体的表现则包括“大棚房”问题、农村乱占耕地建房、部分工程项目和基础设施未批先建等。不仅是昆明，哈尔滨、温州、河池也出现了“大棚房”问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，被通报的9个市（州）中，石家庄、哈尔滨、滁州、临沂、黔西南州、兰州等6地均存在非法采矿的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，哈尔滨代管的五常市对英泽砂石有限公司自2022年1月至2023年5月持续非法开采建筑用花岗石行为监管不力，未及时立案查处制止。将非法采矿行为上报为“伪变化”，不实上报，应付检查。哈尔滨市对五常市不如实上报行为监督不力，审核把关不严。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9个市（州）中，浙江温州是唯一被通报存在“自然资源领域信访持续多发”的城市。通报显示，2021年以来，温州市自然资源领域信访事项数量全省排位一直靠前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;会外整改&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在地方督察局局长通报9个市（州）的违法违规问题之后，市（州）长们分别发言，“逐个表态”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国之声报道，昆明市市长刘佳晨表示，昆明市耕地“非农化”“非粮化”问题十分突出，为此“深感自责与愧疚”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在表态环节，多位市长亦表示，部分问题已得到整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对滁州市来安县政府违法征地，用于建设金陵水乡小镇项目配套景观水系，侵占耕地400.4亩挖湖造景的问题，滁州市市长吴劲表示，来安县政府违法征地建设金陵水乡小镇项目配套景观水系的重点问题已于2023年6月30日全部整改复垦到位，并按照“人事并处”的要求提级办理，移交市纪委监委追责问责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约谈会结束后，多个市（州）长召开会议，部署了相关工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二天，2023年9月17日，河池市长王军主持召开政府常务会议，要求坚决守住耕地保护和粮食安全底线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月19日，温州市长张振丰在全市耕地保护和粮食安全工作会议上强调，要攻坚督察反馈问题整改，按照“一个问题一个方案，闭环推进一抓到底”要求，针对性制定整改方案，限期推动问题销号清零，同步开展已整改问题“回头看”和举一反三问题同标同质整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同日，昆明市召开全市违法用地和耕地流出问题整改工作会议。昆明市委书记刘洪建主持会议并讲话，市长刘佳晨传达自然资源部集中公开约谈会议精神。会上，昆明市自然资源规划局汇报全市违法用地和耕地流出问题整改情况并作检讨发言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5天后，2023年9月23日，昆明市呈贡区委书记陈净率队实地调研“大棚房”整治、耕地流出问题整改等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“呈贡发布”微信公众号发表的文章显示，在斗南街道殷联盆花市场“大棚房”整改工作现场，陈净详细了解了全区“大棚房”整治工作整体情况、工作推进情况及存在的困难问题等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“呈贡发布”公开的文章中，配有一张陈净站在大棚内的照片，他身后是拆到只剩框架的大棚。就在陈净调研后不久，大棚的框架也被拆了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述斗南街道负责人表示，此前，他们已经有了拆除大棚的计划，“主要是有些细节和标准（没确定），刚好赶在领导来了之后就制定了，我们就快速彻底地整治了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈及拆除大棚的原因，该负责人表示，是为了避免问题再次反弹。 “如果棚还在，下一次谁又把东西搬进去了，检查的时候又会说（有问题）。”他解释，“到最后，我们是做通了社区和群众的工作，就是为了一次性整治到位。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，盆花市场所处位置的土地都由殷联社区负责管理。 “大棚房”问题反弹后，由于“社区监管不到位”，目前这七十多亩土地已经收归街道。现在大棚拆除后的位置种地的，是街道委托的第三方公司。该负责人补充：“我们街道干部也不会种地，工作也很多，所以目前是委托给第三方先来完成种植任务，然后再谈以后。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该街道负责人还表示，2023年5月，发现“大棚房”问题反弹后，街道相关干部也被调离了原岗位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256896&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，殷联盆花市场内，工人们正在处理运来的肥料。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者李桂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;核心职能，仍和土地相关&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自然资源部约谈地市级政府负责人，与自然资源督察有关，这是上级政府对下级政府行政监察的形式之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家土地督察是国家自然资源督察的前身。为了遏制土地违法、落实耕地保护，2006年，国务院正式出台土地督察制度，主要督察对象为省、自治区、直辖市、计划单列市政府。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年3月，自然资源部成立，“随着自然资源管理职能的转变，为适应自然资源管理需要”，国家土地督察转型为国家自然资源督察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年6月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅发布《中央生态环境保护督察工作规定》，以党内法规形式明确了中央生态环境保护督察的制度构成、程序规范、权限责任等内容，同时确立了中央和省级两级督察体制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在武汉大学环境法研究所教授陈海嵩看来，即便自然资源部整合了多个部门的职能，但和土地相关的职能，仍是核心。 “自然资源的核心是土地资源”，陈海嵩说，因此，自然资源督察应该聚焦于最为成熟的土地督察业务，不断深入发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年9月1日起施行的《土地管理法实施条例》则首次明确了自然资源督察的范围和工作方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;条例规定，国家自然资源督察机构根据授权对省（自治区、直辖市）人民政府以及国务院确定的城市人民政府的耕地保护情况、土地节约集约利用情况、国土空间规划编制和实施情况、国家有关土地管理重大决策落实情况、土地管理法律、行政法规执行情况、其他土地利用和土地管理情况等进行督察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家自然资源督察机构还可以约谈被督察的地方人民政府有关负责人，并可以依法向监察机关、任免机关等有关机关提出追究相关责任人责任的建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和此次9个市（州）长被叫到北京约谈不同，此前，国家自然资源督察机构的约谈大都在地方进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月至11月，国家自然资源督察机构对31个省（自治区、直辖市）和新疆生产建设兵团开展了耕地保护和矿产资源实地督察，发现了一些违法违规问题。针对督察发现的突出问题，经国家自然资源总督察授权，派驻地方的国家自然资源督察机构对部分违法违规严重的地市政府进行约谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，成都局约谈云南大理，北京局约谈河北邢台、山西晋中，南京局约谈江西九江，广州局约谈广东清远、广西南宁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次在北京约谈地方政府主要负责人的深意，在陈海嵩看来，依然和粮食安全有关，“接下来很长一段时间内，耕地保护、粮食安全都是非常重要的问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在约谈会上，国家自然资源专职副总督察陈尘肇表示：“耕地保护任务没有减轻，而是更加艰巨了。要采取坚决有力的措施，持续加强耕地保护，牢牢守住18亿亩耕地红线。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部：中小学校要确保学生课间正常活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:11:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期，一些地方中小学生“课间10分钟被约束”问题受到社会广泛关注，新华社“新华视点”记者就此采访了教育部有关负责同志。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位负责同志表示，中小学校安排课间休息十分重要、十分必要，有利于学生调节情绪、放松身心、增强体质和防控近视。教育部高度重视学生课间休息，2021年9月1日起施行的《未成年人学校保护规定》（教育部令第50号）明确，不得对学生在课间及其他非教学时间的正当交流、游戏、出教室活动等言行自由设置不必要的约束。在实际工作中，要求中小学校每天统一安排30分钟的大课间体育活动，每节课间应安排学生走出教室适量活动和放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位负责同志指出，教育部将进一步督促地方和学校严格落实国家有关规定，遵循教育规律和学生身心发展规律，坚决纠正以“确保学生安全”为由而简单限制学生必要的课间休息和活动的做法；将指导地方和学校科学实施管理和安全防范措施，加强室外场所设施排查和人员值守，加强学生安全常识教育，把安全事故风险降到最低，让孩子们快乐放心活动。同时，将要求学校密切家校社协作，争取家长理解和社会支持，共同努力保障学生课间正常活动，促进学生健康成长和全面发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽武校投毒致7死案开庭：“26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;事发后，七家死者家属合照。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;事发后，七家死者家属合照。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我心里想，这个案子破不了了，没想到破掉了。”2023年10月31日下午，61岁的刁山云在电话里告诉南方周末记者。26年前，他的儿子钱敏在11岁的年纪被投毒致死。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平是在2023年6月得知凶手被抓获的，她的弟弟杨长伟死于同一起投毒案。“26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发于1997年6月30日7时许，安徽马鞍山和县南北少林武术学校约130名师生吃过早饭后出现呕吐、抽搐等症状，包括钱敏、杨长伟在内的7名学生因抢救无效死亡，经公安机关调查发现，均系毒鼠强424成分中毒死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;26年过去，2023年10月29日，马鞍山市公安局召开和县南北少林武术学校集体中毒案件通气会，宣告抓获该案的两名犯罪嫌疑人付某阶、朱某林。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月1日早晨9:00，该案在马鞍山市中级法院开庭审理。马鞍山市检察院提请以投毒罪追究朱某林、付某阶的刑事责任。被告人及被害人亲属四十余人旁听了庭审，未当庭宣判。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;投毒130余人报复馆长&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;午间休庭时，杨习平告诉南方周末记者，“上午审的是姓付的，他就说自己收了姓朱的500块钱投了毒，自己脑子稀里糊涂，还有话要说。”杨习平称，法庭下午将继续审朱某林。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据上游新闻报道，在法庭上，两名被告人否认预谋作案。公诉机关建议判处两人十年以上有期徒刑、无期徒刑或死刑，7名遇难者的家属提出近770万元民事赔偿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开庭前一天，杨习平把随身带的弟弟照片拿出来看，一个身穿红色运动服的小男孩，长相清瘦，永远定格在了11岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平姊妹四人，杨长伟是家中幼子，也是唯一的男孩。杨习平作为家中的老大，为了供弟弟上学，早早出去打工。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她疼爱这个弟弟，在家里干活时，走到哪儿带到哪儿。弟弟爱打闹，家里就让他去和县南北少林武术学校学习打拳，杨习平只记得学费不便宜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们一次性交七八千。”刁山云说，以前自己和丈夫钱发荣做生意，顾不上照顾小儿子钱敏，就安顿在武校，计划等儿子到18岁就去当兵，“上了不到两年，最后抱回来了个骨灰盒”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时那个打击太大了，承受不了。”62岁的钱发荣至今还在用钱敏的照片做微信头像，他记得，事发当天接到儿子中毒的消息后，自己急忙赶到医院，已经来不及了。1997年7月1日下午3点钟，钱敏浑身抽搐，离开了人世。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;钱敏在木桩上蹲马步。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钱敏在木桩上蹲马步。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但钱发荣夫妇没想到，凶手就是在武校任教的教练付某阶。“那个姓付的教练最喜欢我儿子了，他们住一个房间，我们每次去看儿子都要感谢他。”刁山云说，儿子时常念叨付某阶的好，“他不喜欢我儿子干嘛叫我儿子跟他住一个房间，我当时听儿子说这个付老师很好的，人品还是不错的，他咋能干这个事？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马鞍山市检察院的起诉书显示，这起投毒案发端于两家武术馆之间的竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994年左右，被告人朱某林和彭某伟在和县乌江镇卜集镇经营和县少林武术馆，朱某林任馆长、彭某伟任主教练。在经营过程中，二人发生矛盾。彭某伟离开了该武术馆，并在西埠镇重新开设和县南北少林武术学校，还带走了大部分师生，朱某林因此对彭某伟怀恨在心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1996年8月，被告人付某阶到彭某伟经营的和县南北少林武术学校任教，在任教期间，因琐事逐渐对彭某伟心生不满。朱某林和付某阶二人经他人介绍后认识，在相处过程中，两人都表达出对彭某伟的不满，遂决定一起报复彭某伟，把彭某伟的武校搞垮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年6月，付某阶、朱某林商议决定使用投毒的方式报复彭某伟，付某阶实施后由朱某林支付给付某阶5万元，朱某林当场支付付某阶500元。月底，付某阶从武校辞职，回到湖北监利老家购买了两包老鼠药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发前夜，6月29日晚，付某阶从和县南北少林武术学校南边窜至武校厨房内，将两包老鼠药投放在厨房南侧桌上红色塑料盆内的咸豇豆上，搅拌后从原路逃离，离开和县。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二天早晨7时许，武校130余名师生吃过早饭后发生呕吐、抽搐等症状，杨长伟、王俊、邢涛、刘文宝、田丹、汤玉叶、钱敏等7名学生死亡。现场勘查提取了咸豇豆、纱罩网罩纱等物品，均检出毒鼠强424成分。另对7名学生死因进行鉴定，经鉴定，7名学生均系424鼠药中毒死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而付某阶、朱某林已经不知所踪，警方一时难以破案。马鞍山市公安局在通气会上介绍，案件发生后，公安机关成立专案组，围绕案发现场周边开展走访排查，分析付某阶、朱某林有重大作案嫌疑。1997年7月14日，公安机关将付某阶、朱某林列为网上逃犯，悬赏通缉，持续追捕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;付某阶与学生游玩的合照。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;付某阶与学生游玩的合照。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“总算可以给个交代了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我们也不知道该找谁，下毒的人已经跑了，你说咋整？”杨习平接到邻居的消息已经是事发半个月之后，回到家就看到院里摆一口棺材，她记得很清楚，“我当时跪在地上那一刻，看我老爸头发全白了，瘦得都不像样子了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刁山云至今都想不通，儿子怎么就被自己最喜欢的教练毒死了。夫妻俩把儿子下葬后，买了一座墓碑，上面写：“爱子钱敏，九七年不幸发生6.30血案含冤致死。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直至2022年下半年，这起沉寂多年的投毒案有了突破，专案组在贵州发现了朱某林的踪迹，并于2023年年初基本锁定其藏匿地点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月初，福建晋江警方利用大数据分析，发现在一皮革厂打工的男子与嫌疑人付某阶存在相似体貌特征，经两地警方反复比对确认后，立即将其控制。专案组于5月6日晚赶赴福建晋江，经初步审讯，付某阶向公安机关交代了犯罪经过。5月9日，付某阶被押回和县。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;抓获付某阶同时，5月7日清晨，专案组前往贵州贵阳市，在当地警方协助下，将隐匿身份并在当地开办桶装水生产企业的朱某林在厂内成功抓获。见到前来抓捕的民警，朱某林僵在原地、惊讶不已，想不到过去这么久民警还会找上门。5月8日凌晨，朱某林被押回和县。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月，在武校投毒案新闻通气会上，马鞍山市公安局专案组介绍：经审讯，付某阶交代，作案后，他一直东躲西藏，居无定所，先后流窜到江西新余市、福建德化县、莆田市、晋江市等地，以打零工为生。因害怕身份暴露被公安机关查处，他不敢登记身份信息，在疫情期间不敢打疫苗、做核酸检测。在应聘工作时也从不挑岗位、谈工资待遇，只为有一处藏身之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据朱某林交代，为逃避公安机关打击，潜逃期间他隐匿真实身份，独自漂泊在外，先是在江西鄱阳县躲藏了2年，后又窜至浙江杭州市打工，先后在江西上饶市、贵州贵阳市开办桶装水生产企业，这么多年始终过着提心吊胆的生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“6月份，我老爸接到通知说凶手找到了，我立马回来了。”杨习平称，听说找到凶手时，自己和父亲都在电话里哭，“总算可以给弟弟一个交代了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平时常想，如果弟弟还在，这个家一定是另一番样子。她要求妹妹们不能远嫁，“因为没弟弟了，老妈身体也不好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平称，母亲因丧子大病一场，父亲受打击后神经衰弱，三妹也因此再无心念书。“我老爸经常夜里都找不到人，要么跑到弟弟坟上哭，要么跑到河里和砖坯子里，我们到处找。”杨父一直自责害了儿子，走不出来。因为当初是他不顾家人反对，将小儿子送到了学费昂贵的武术学校。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚，杨习平带着家人赶到和县，准备参加第二天的开庭。她希望付、朱二人受到应有的惩罚。“我弟弟要是不出事，今年就是37岁，该成家了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访俄专家安德烈·科尔图诺夫：俄乌冲突越早结束，对大家都越好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今秋的北方，为何又热又霾？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月1日早晨，石家庄市栾城区人民公园，市民戴着口罩在雾霾中晨练。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年华北的秋天，有点热，还有点霾。11月3日，随着冷空气到来，扩散条件逐步转好，污染自北向南逐渐清除。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夏季连续多日破40℃高温，10月底，北京、天津、山东等地气温再次罕见趋暖，河南省郑州市11月1日、2日最高气温甚至分别达30℃和29℃。11月初的北京，中午大街上仍然不乏穿着短袖、短裤的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，京津冀及周边城市又陷雾霾。据国家大气污染防治攻关联合中心统计，截至10月30日，该区域已有20个城市启动重污染天气预警。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这两天华北地区出现的污染过程再次提醒我们，中国要根本性改善空气污染，路还很长。”中国工程院院士、清华大学碳中和研究院院长贺克斌在11月1日于北京召开的中国清洁空气政策伙伴关系2023年度会议上称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅受气象条件影响，空气污染与全球气候变化也存在千丝万缕的关联。中国科学院院士、北京大学环境科学与工程学院教授朱彤在上述会议中表示，在人为源排放的污染物降低的情况下，气候变暖也会加剧空气污染，如森林野火带来烟尘、近地面臭氧污染加剧生成等，进一步影响人体健康，相关基础科学问题的解决是未来的挑战和重点。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;整体良好，重点区域表现一般&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月下旬开始，北方霾情开始扩散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我昨天很晚才从河北回来，有些城市启动了空气重污染橙色预警，有的地区比北京空气污染更重。”生态环境部大气环境司一级巡视员李培在会上说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据监测数据,11月2日17时,北京实时PM2.5浓度为73μg/m³，为“良”级别，而河北省邢台市、保定市、邯郸市、石家庄市突破200μg/m³，达“重度污染”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;256942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月22—29日全国PM2.5浓度逐日变化情况（来源：中国环境监测总站，河南省生态环境监测和安全中心）国家大气污染防治攻关联合中心/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013-2017年、2017-2020年，我国分别实行了《大气污染防治行动计划》（“大气十条”）、《打赢蓝天保卫战三年行动计划》。自2013年以来，PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;年均浓度整体一直保持下降趋势，达标城市数量也在增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月，据亚洲清洁空气中心发布的《大气中国2023：中国大气污染防治进程》，2022年，全国达标城市比例由70.2%增长至74.6%；全国重度及以上污染天数比率为0.9%，同比下降0.4个百分点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然全国整体表现良好，但是重点区域表现一般。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;浓度长三角地区同比持平；京津冀及周边“2+26”城市与汾渭平原均同比升高，增幅分别为2.3%和9.5%。168个重点城市中，PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;浓度不降反升的城市数量，由2021年的24个增至50个。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;冷空气活动偏弱&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;气象条件是此轮污染天气的外因。李培表示，我国大气污染治理虽然取得了一定成绩，但成效还不稳固，总体上来说，目前还未摆脱气象影响型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家大气污染防治攻关联合中心专家团队分析，10月22日以来，京津冀及周边区域冷空气活动偏弱，地面气温、低层大气相对湿度较常年均偏高，易形成区域性污染。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国气象局科普，秋冬季节更易发生雾、霾，与静稳天气有关。静稳天气中的“静”，指水平方向上的风速较小，“稳”指垂直方向上的大气层结比较稳定，低层大气和中层大气相互间垂直交换少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;静稳天气形成与地形、环流等因素有关。山地、丘陵、盆地等特殊地形会阻碍空气的流通，京津冀地区受西北高东南低的“簸箕形”地形影响，污染物容易在太行山和燕山前累积。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在环流因素下，大气层结若存在逆温（下层冷上层暖），导致较重的空气在下层，较轻的空气在上层，大气结构稳定，垂直扩散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空气质量不只是受短期的气象条件影响，也与长期气候变化相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中央气象台首席预报员方翀解读，一般来说，10月中下旬已进入冷空气活跃期，但2023年冷空气明显偏弱，气温显著偏高。目前，共有237个国家级气象站破10月下旬最高气温历史极值，情况罕见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“2023年，加拿大的森林大火对纽约的空气质量造成了严重影响。在纽约人可能已经忘记了空气污染为何物的时候，山火提醒他们，气候变化会带来非常严重的空气污染，并会对人体健康产生危害。”朱彤在会上表示，除野火的案例以外，未来气候变化还将带来更频繁的极端高温、干旱、沙尘天气等极端气候事件，所带来的危害也将成倍增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;256943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年6月，受加拿大山火扩散的烟尘影响，多伦多出现严重空气污染。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 新华社/路透&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家气象中心高级工程师迟茜元在会上介绍，首先，空气污染与气候变化均与人为源排放密切相关，从温室气体(如CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;、CH&lt;sub>;4&lt;/sub>;、N&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O 等)与大气污染物(如SO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;、NO&lt;sub>;x&lt;/sub>;、PM等)的产生原因看，两者具有高度同源性，大多是由矿物燃烧排放生成，所以当出现空气污染时，可能也代表温室气体排放的增加；其次，PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;的很多组分会影响大气辐射，进而影响能量收支平衡，造成气候变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟茜元称，气溶胶粒子可能也会参与云雨形成过程，进而影响天气系统与气候条件；另一方面，气候变化本身可能会导致空气污染加剧，比如升温可能会造成臭氧浓度的升高，再如大气环流形式的变化，可能会影响大气稳定度，影响扩散条件，导致PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;浓度的变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;减污降碳协同增效&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;贺克斌表示，2013年以来，“大气十条”“打赢蓝天保卫战”时期，大气污染物排放量下降，但年度减排幅度在逐渐收窄。这体现出大气污染防治的边际效应，“好干的、利润大的、减排潜力大的都干完了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本轮京津冀及周边地区的污染过程，内因仍然是人为排放。国家大气污染防治攻关联合中心专家团队解读，机动车、工业炉窑等排放是京津冀及周边地区PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;污染的主要来源，秸秆焚烧等对局地PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>;污染贡献突出。京津冀及周边区域内工业企业、重型货车活动水平和秸秆火点数量环比上升，污染排放呈增加趋势。在工业源方面，10月下旬以来，区域工业用电量较10月上中旬增长约5%；在移动源方面，京津冀及周边地区重型货车交通流量处于秋冬季以来的高位，较10月上中旬偏高约14%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大气污染治理需要找到新的动力，减污降碳协同增效是重要抓手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“到2030年碳达峰之后，末端治理的作用会越来越小，要逐渐转到四大结构（能源结构、产业结构、交通运输结构、用地结构）调整和减污降碳协同增效上去。”贺克斌认为，无论对经济发展还是对改善空气质量，减碳是近期的压力，亦是未来的动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年6月，生态环境部、国家发展改革委等多部委联合印发《减污降碳协同增效实施方案》，称“协同推进减污降碳，实现一体谋划、一体部署、一体推进、一体考核”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生态环境部环境规划院副院长严刚在会上介绍，从空气污染物和碳排放角度来看，2/3的城市在“十三五”期间都没有实现协同改善；从行业角度来看，目前虽然大部分行业污染物排放呈明显下降趋势，但碳排放仍然处于增长态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;严刚称，减污降碳协同治理，并不像以前其他污染治理工作那样，有很多国际经验可借鉴，目前我国减污降碳协同增效工作面临一些挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，在理论体系方面还缺乏支撑，应强化污染排放表征研究，识别排放同源性和异质性；在调控方面，目标分配、智慧调控、治理技术等方面仍需开展一系列研究；相关政策也需进一步协同等。挑战的另一面也意味着机遇，若积极应对，大气污染治理与碳排放控制可以取得双赢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清剿电诈还是军阀混战？缅北果敢到底怎么了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259885]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/aLb8TNP0traIg28E2TC5ktDQUzChTKWZqcnqnO5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/aLb8TNP0traIg28E2TC5ktDQUzChTKWZqcnqnO5f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月28日，缅甸掸邦北部，一枚导弹从一处军事基地发射&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月27日，缅北腊戌、贵慨等地的缅甸政府军军事据点遭武装袭击并爆发激烈交火。据缅甸“果敢资讯网”报道，果敢民族民主同盟军同日发表声明称对此次武装袭击负责，行动是为了“清剿电诈民团”。当地时间27日凌晨4时许，果敢民族民主同盟军在掸邦清水河、滚弄、腊戌等多个地方对军事部署区、警察哨所、收费站等据点发动攻击。5时许，包括清水河、滚弄等多个战略据点被果敢民族民主同盟军占领。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战事爆发的10月27日，在中国外交部例行新闻发布会上，发言人毛宁就缅甸军方与缅甸果敢民族民主同盟军（MNDAA）爆发的军事冲突表示：“中方高度关注有关冲突，呼吁有关方面尽快停火止战，坚持通过对话协商，以和平方式解决分歧，避免事态升级，并采取切实有效措施，确保中缅边境的安全稳定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了缅甸果敢民族民主同盟军（MNDAA），德昂民族解放军（TNLA）和若开军（AA）也一同参与了针对缅甸政府军的攻击。根据果敢同盟军方面的消息，三支反政府武装力量总参战兵力超过15000人，战斗地点主要集中在掸邦北部，这是自2015年果敢战事以来该地区爆发的最大规模战斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于战斗地点接近中缅边境，边境口岸已经出现了难民潮，我国政府相关部门已开始为躲避战火的入境难民提供庇护和帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这次战事到底是如何爆发的？对该地区未来的形势又会产生哪些影响？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/igdn0q9Q3pCnq5i7gjYGwF7ElsJnrCTscTGLsPLA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/igdn0q9Q3pCnq5i7gjYGwF7ElsJnrCTscTGLsPLA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月27日，缅甸掸邦，缅甸民族民主同盟军少将彭德奇（左四）指挥作战&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;政治战下的生存之战&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;尽管缅甸是中国的近邻，双方拥有2100多公里的绵长边境线，且缅甸为接壤的东南亚国家中国土面积和人口第一大国，然而对于大部分中国人而言，缅甸依然是个比较陌生的国家，存在感相当有限。去缅甸旅游的中国人，也远比去泰国、越南或柬埔寨等临近东南亚国家的少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最近两年，缅甸却因为电信诈骗和“噶腰子”（非法器官摘取买卖）在我国民间舆论中恶名鹊起。随着相关社交媒体信息和影视作品的传播，越来越多中国人了解到：与云南相邻的缅甸北部地区是电信诈骗和犯罪团伙活动猖獗的地区，且当地政府对此束手无策，甚至同流合污。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次缅北冲突爆发当日，果敢同盟军的社交媒体第一时间发布名为《缅甸民族民主同盟军、德昂民族解放军、若开军“10.27”行动声明》，声明中提到，“我们将根除包括中缅边境地区在内的全国范围内的电信诈骗、诈骗窝点及其保护伞，三家联军决定，联合采取此次军事行动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份声明发布后，这三支民族地方武装的文宣不断出现要打掉电信诈骗团伙、拯救被困被骗同胞的内容。其中果敢同盟军更在短视频社交平台发布了同盟军一分队的战前动员视频，发布动员令的旅长语气凝重，大声说道：我们的任务是铲除电诈集团、消除毒品、解救同胞，有没有信心！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后戎装在身的战士们齐声大喊：有！有！有！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们不只是一帮口号喊得响的人。在打仗这个问题上，果敢同盟军一直以进攻见长。早在2015年的果敢战争中，同盟军就在缅甸政府军的眼皮底下发动了进攻，不仅开战当天先头部队就进入果敢地区首府老街，其后更在敌后远程狙杀了一名缅军副旅长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年果敢之战最后时刻，果敢同盟军在老街北部海拔两千多米的南天门高地顶着缅军的炮火和飞机轰炸死守了两个月，最后缅军总攻时，坚守到最后的二十多名守军无一投降全部战死，其战斗意志令对手缅甸军队都颇为震惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在10月27日这次冲突中，果敢同盟军的表现更是相当迅猛，开战短短几天内就迅速占领了比邻老街且为对华重要口岸的清水河地区，攻陷了缅军六十多个据点，还成功依靠轻步兵摧毁6辆装甲车，全歼前来伞降支援的缅军空降兵特种部队。在同盟军的迅猛攻势下，有一个营的缅甸政府军官兵成建制投降。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与果敢同盟军配合的若开军和德昂民族解放军在外线作战，德昂军不仅进攻登尼镇，还成功摧毁了附近的南大河桥，以阻止缅军利用公路增援果敢地区。若开军和德昂军进攻腊戍地区，一度炮击缅甸北部最重要的腊戍机场，导致民航飞机停飞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从目前的态势来看，果敢首府老街外围的缅军据点基本上已经被扫清，老街攻防战恐怕很快会展开，一旦果敢同盟军成功夺回老街的控制权，那么这场战役基本可以宣告胜利。比起2015年的果敢战事，现在的果敢同盟军更为接近自己的目标，即夺回老街，重新成为果敢地区的控制者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在缅北民族地方武装的政治叙事里，自己是正面的英雄，相应地也会有邪恶的反派。这次的反派就是果敢四大家族。这四大家族分别为白所成代表的白家、魏超仁的魏家、明学昌的明家、刘阿宝的刘家。这四个家族的代表都是果敢地区的实权人物，也是果敢同盟军的死敌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就反电诈的叙事角度而言，把四大家族列为反派可以说是实至名归，这四个家族的企业多年来一直以创业园区为名开设电信诈骗业务，因此获得了大量的财富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在现实的国际政治或地区争端中，正义形象是力量运用的一部分，战争是政治的延续，而政治往往需要道德的加持。摧毁电诈拯救同胞，不一定是说说而已，对于果敢同盟军而言，只要成功光复果敢，彻底清除电信诈骗这个恶心的产业并不是什么问题，毕竟这不是他们的收入来源。然而如果说果敢同盟军一心为了铲除电信诈骗而开战，那也与事实并不相符，毕竟这不是果敢同盟军与果敢四大家族的第一次战争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在缅北成为电诈窝点前的2009年8月8日，后来的四大家族首领之一、当时还是果敢同盟军副司令的白所成，联合缅甸军队和其他三大家族发动政变，将果敢同盟军初代领导人彭家声赶出了果敢地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年，果敢同盟军蛰伏六年后，在春节期间发动了对果敢地区政府军势力的反攻。当时果敢同盟军是以回家过年为名发动攻击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此上一次战事不仅军事上并不成功，政治上也没有足够高的声浪，甚至很容易被旁观者认为是一场军阀利益集团之间的战斗。而这次果敢同盟军又经过了8年多的成长，无论军事、政治还是宣传能力都远胜从前，结果很可能也会大不一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实无论是否反电诈，对于果敢同盟军而言，能够打回老家果敢，重新掌控老街，才是其生存的根本。上一代领导人彭家声已于2022年2月病逝，现在的果敢同盟军在现任司令彭德仁（彭家声长子）的领导下，多年离开故土打游击。但这终非长久之计，没了故土依托、没有稳固的根据地，队伍很难发展壮大。因此2023年10月27日爆发的军事冲突对于果敢同盟军而言，相当于一场生存之战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/njM3JUYhKJyfESN1197AS2088mFAwDbyciHIGs5A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/njM3JUYhKJyfESN1197AS2088mFAwDbyciHIGs5A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年1月4日，缅甸内比都，缅甸国家管理委员会主席敏昂莱出席阅兵仪式&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;站在缅甸全国看果敢&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在熟悉缅北战争背景的人看来，果敢同盟军这次在战场上无往不利本来就是意料中事，因为早在2021年，缅甸就出现了一个远比缅北民族地方武装更为致命的敌人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年2月1日，缅甸政治领袖昂山素季在家中被缅甸军方逮捕，最终被判决33年的刑期。对于当时已经78岁的昂山素季而言，这无异于终身监禁。昂山素季被逮捕当天，缅甸各地就爆发了大规模的街头抗议示威，最终示威者与军警爆发大规模冲突，西方多国谴责缅甸军政府，并宣布对缅甸恢复全面制裁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，昂山素季所在的政党全国民主联盟（NLD）也被军政府取缔。这一系列作为，基本宣告了缅甸军政府与全国民主联盟的彻底决裂，因此导致NLD的核心政治精英以及他们的支持者彻底断绝了议会政治的可能，军政府针对示威的暴力镇压也导致昂山素季的支持者认定与军政府对抗只能依靠武力，于是宣布成立缅甸联邦共和国民族团结政府（缅甸语缩写NUG），其政治主张就是通过武力推翻军政府，并重新夺回政权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NUG可被视为NLD的流亡政府，其在2021年宣布建立军事组织：人民国防军（缅甸语简称PDF）。2021年9月7日，NUG宣布发动针对军政府的“人民保卫战”，并号召缅甸全国各地的公民反抗军政府。对于缅甸军政府而言，这无疑是比缅北民族地方武装更大的威胁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自二战后独立以来，缅甸的内战就从来没有停止过，但NUG的武装力量PDF和以前缅甸政府军面对的敌人不一样。在过去的内战中，缅军主要应对的敌人是边境地区，如缅北和金三角地区的少数民族武装。此类武装可能军力强大，如佤邦联合军拥有包括防空导弹和武装直升机这类重型装备，或者像克钦独立军，战术精良训练有素。但此类军队的特点是集中在其民族聚集区，并且政治诉求只是保持本民族的独立和领地，因此缅甸政府军与这些地方民族武装的交战主要集中在缅北地区，也就是所谓的上缅甸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;缅甸南部，也就是下缅甸地区，主要以缅族人为主，缅族人在缅甸人口中占比高达68%，是绝对的主体人口，缅北民族地方武装力量很难渗透进下缅甸作战。在政治上，民族地方武装也没有这方面的诉求。而NUG的核心成员本身就是缅族政治精英，其主要活动的区域恰好在下缅甸，尤其是NUG建立起武装力量PDF之后，就把核心成员送往克钦等民族地方武装政权学习如何作战，同时利用其在下缅甸社会中的地下网络不断进行宣传发动。大量有作战经验的士兵和军官被吸收进入PDF。而缅甸政府军军校最近几年不仅招生困难，甚至出现了毕业生带着装备投奔PDF的事件。迄今为止，至少有16000名缅甸军警叛逃并加入PDF。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了挖墙脚和搜集情报之外，PDF开始与缅军展开下缅甸地区的游击战，其成建制的作战单位甚至出现在缅甸首都内比都和最大城市仰光附近。2023年5月，NUG对外宣布建立约300个营和纵队，并在下缅甸250个乡镇取缔了军政府的政府机关，建立了自己的政权。2023年6月，NUG宣布组建第5101营，该营居然是建立在仰光地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管PDF自成立以来没有什么像样的战果，也并未成建制的歼灭任何缅军部队，然而由于其在下缅甸直接威胁缅甸的政治和经济中心，导致缅甸政府军不得不拨出大量资源防御PDF的偷袭。而NUG的情报和动员能力，也极大地削弱了缅甸军政府对下缅甸地区的控制能力。PDF之所以被认为比任何民族地方武装都更为致命，是因为他们的军事目标不是占领地盘或拥兵自重，而是彻底摧毁缅甸军政府，重新夺回政权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果回看2015年的果敢冲突我们会发现，缅甸政府军当时还能轻易从下缅甸调动几个旅的兵力驰援果敢，空军则可以直接从周边的机场起飞，集中力量攻击果敢同盟军的阵地。但这次冲突爆发后，政府军调动增援的力度和装备水平都远远低于上次，甚至连空中支援都相当有限。其根本原因在于，缅甸军政府手上的机动兵力已经捉襟见肘，如果大量抽调驰援果敢，那么仰光和内比都周边的PDF肯定会趁火打劫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4lWn6pGSgtdzDnCKmw06nWYn9rgCT1PcPrrxBIvb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4lWn6pGSgtdzDnCKmw06nWYn9rgCT1PcPrrxBIvb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年3月8日，缅甸掸邦，德昂民族解放军进行军事训练&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;果敢为什么那么重要？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对于果敢同盟军而言，果敢当然至关重要，因为那是这支军队目前唯一的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于果敢四大家族而言，果敢是他们的政治本钱和发财宝地，失去果敢等于失去了两代人奋斗几十年才得到的一切。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于军政府而言，果敢同样至关重要，军政府领袖敏昂莱大将之所以在诸多将领中脱颖而出，就是因为2009年成功占领果敢并驱逐彭家声的部队，使其在军中威望空前，成为新一代将领中的第一号人物。尽管果敢只是一个常驻人口14万、面积不过区区2000平方公里的掸邦第一特区，然而一旦失手，连锁效应却是致命的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此从政治上来看，缅甸政府军不会轻易放弃果敢，自然也会想尽办法支援果敢当地武装，避免果敢同盟军反攻得手。所以尽管果敢同盟军前期进展顺利，但真正发动进攻夺回老街，仍旧困难重重。愿意付出多大的代价驰援果敢，是缅甸军政府和四大家族能否守住果敢的关键，如果能保持上次果敢冲突中的军力投入水平，恐怕果敢同盟军仍难夺回老街。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“花西子事件”后，再谈美妆国货的初心与始终丨日化行业科创力榜单解读]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259879]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 12:45:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;花西子“79元眉笔”引发热议，美妆国货成为焦点。有人认为国货早已背离“物美价廉”，敬而远之，也有人继续支持“野性消费”，更多人感觉眼花缭乱、虚实难辨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;美妆国货发展和进化轨迹如何？科创能否赋能产品力、市场力？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;南方周末科创力研究中心近期发布2023年中国日化行业的企业科创力榜单，一探究竟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/118abecb6a445039e863364f0b716b02.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;1291&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/118abecb6a445039e863364f0b716b02.png&quot; data-key=&quot;256887&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;645&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南方周末企业科创力数据库中，2023年入库的日化行业上市公司共16家，涵盖了化妆品、洗涤用品、口腔用品等领域。其中有披露研发投入的15家，剔除1家ST公司，14家上市公司研发投入总额达11.54亿元，平均研发投入0.82亿元，其中5家公司研发投入过亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝泰妮&lt;span>;（300957.SZ）&lt;/span>;以77.13分的成绩排名第一，其代表品牌为薇诺娜，与第二名的分差达16分，是第十名的两倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;珀莱雅&lt;span>;（603605.SH）&lt;/span>;和上海家化&lt;span>;（600315.SH）&lt;/span>;，分别以60.93分和60.87分位列第二、三名，珀莱雅以微弱优势取胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海家化是老国货代表，旗下有佰草集、玉泽等品牌。同为老牌国货的名臣健康&lt;span>;（002919.SZ）&lt;/span>;排名第四，其产品主要是洗涤用品，代表品牌有蒂花之秀；与之业务类似的拉芳家化&lt;span>;（603630.SH）&lt;/span>;，排在第十。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;水羊股份&lt;span>;（300740.SZ）&lt;/span>;、逸仙电商&lt;span>;（YSG.N）&lt;/span>;、丸美股份&lt;span>;（603983.SH）&lt;/span>;等三家后起之秀，分别名列第五、第六和第七。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;卷研发，它是国货王者&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;光看营收，贝泰妮仅能排到行业第三，但它却牢牢占据行业科创力榜首。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末企业科创力评价系统，从研发投入、研发产出、公司发展三个维度，覆盖研发支出、研发人员、研发投入占比、知识产权、核心奖项、营业收入、营业利润、净利润、公司市值等近30个细分指标，每个指标项得分，以公司指标值与行业指标项最高指标值之比值而来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包括研发投入金额、人员和强度等在内的研发投入项，是榜单最为关键的指标项，也是贝泰妮的竞争优势所在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;2022年，贝泰妮的研发投入达2.78亿元，占到全行业的近1/4，在前十名中，除了上海家化、其余8家企业的研发投入金额都不到贝泰妮的一半。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;此外，它的研发投入强度超过5%，应用核心技术实现的销售收入占公司主营业务收入的比例超过95%。卷研发，不得不服它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4730fa2d8c9ef11b8664ea5dc8b5edc1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center; width: 100%; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;1070&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4730fa2d8c9ef11b8664ea5dc8b5edc1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256888&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;645&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1070&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝泰妮成立于2010年，其主品牌薇诺娜诞生于滇虹药业&lt;span>;（现已被德国拜耳集团收购）&lt;/span>;。背靠药企的出身背景和其所选择的“敏感肌”赛道决定了薇诺娜卷研发的道路，也奠定了贝泰妮高研发的基调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，中国敏感肌肤细分市场由欧美大牌占据，薇诺娜能够从欧美大牌中分一杯羹，与它坚持自主研发密不可分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贝泰妮研究院是承载贝泰妮研发创新的主要平台。2022年，贝泰妮研究院在原有功效性化妆品研发中心基础上，成立了创新原料研发中心，建立了系统的云南特色植物活性物筛选评估体系，以云南特色植物为基础，开展大量功效方向的自主研发。截至2022年底，公司累计成功自主研发了40项功效性化妆品植物原料，输出技术标准40 项，产业化上市了包含马齿苋、青刺果在内的11个云南特色植物活性物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自主研发，打造了其核心品牌薇诺娜的产品力，也为其讲好品牌故事，塑造适用于敏感肌的品牌形象奠定基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;排名第二的珀莱雅是近年来国货榜单中的“常胜将军”，但在科创力行业榜单中却与冠军失之交臂，主要因为研发投入不足。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，珀莱雅的营收达63.85亿元，仅次于上海家化和蓝月亮集团，行业排名第三，其研发投入金额为1.28亿元，也排在第三位，但其研发投入强度仅2%，排在了倒数第四。就连常常因“重营销轻研发”而饱受诟病的逸仙电商，研发投入强度也有3.51%呢。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;老国货，奋力转型&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;排名第三的上海家化，是中国最早发展起来的美妆个护集团，旗下有佰草集、美加净等创立于20世纪的老品牌，也有专注于敏感肌新赛道的新品牌玉泽。凭借着相对齐全的产品矩阵，上海家化以71亿元的营收力压群雄，居行业第一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为历史最悠久的老日化国货之一，上海家化的线上渠道铺设和营销玩法创新不敌新锐品牌。2022年，其线上渠道在总营收中的占比不到40%，同期贝泰妮、珀莱雅和水羊股份等化妆品企业已超过80%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重视线下渠道或许与上海家化中个护家清品牌的高市场份额密切相关，比起营销，老品牌似乎比多数新锐品牌更愿意在产品研发投入中花心思。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年上海家化的研发投入约1.8亿元，仅次于贝泰妮，行业排名第二。它的研发方向覆盖面广，包括医研共创、中医中草药、细胞生物、安全和功效评估设备、包装设计、AI定制化和美容仪器平台。在其他公司的年报中，AI涉及的内容通常与销售渠道相关联，但在上海家化，AI真正做到与产品服务相关联。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说上海家化的转型升级是数字智能和生物技术对主业的加持；排名第四的老国货名臣健康则是开启双业务模式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022财年，名臣健康的研发投入1.10亿元，同时投向日化产品和游戏业务。同期披露的23项研发投入项目中，近半为游戏研发；研发人员同比增长近八成至520人，主要为游戏业务板块新增。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;名臣健康在2020年通过收购发展游戏业务，2021年游戏业务和日化业务的营收占比三七开，2022年两者比例非常接近，游戏业务占比已达47%，2023年半年报显示，游戏业务收入占比已超过七成，下一年它大概率要被划入软件和信息服务业。不过，这也是传统日化企业转型的一种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;16家日化企业， 2022财年仅贝泰妮、珀莱雅、名臣健康、倍加洁、蓝月亮集团等5家实现营收同比增长。其实，名臣健康的日化用品的营收同比也在下滑，不过得益于游戏业务收入的倍增，拉升了整体营收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;名臣健康游戏业务在2022年的毛利率达73.55%，而日化业务的毛利率仅为33.75%。在行业内卷的时期，果断开拓新业务，是一条新路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛金王，2022年营收第一大来源也不再是化妆品，而是新材料蜡烛、香薰及工艺品等。多元化发展，又是另一种选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;高研发投入，值吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;抛开这些转型、转行，聚焦日化行业本身，高研发投入是否必须的选择？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从企业经营的角度，研发投入是企业的成本科目。相比软件服务、消费电子这些强科技属性的行业，研发能给日化企业带来的效益并非立竿见影。同时，研发投入不高，靠营销创下不菲营收的品牌不在少数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观日化上市公司的年报，其无一不是销售费用高于研发费用，比如珀莱雅的销售费用高达27亿元，是其研发投入的21倍。&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;我们无法否认品牌营销对日化产品的重要性，但追加高研发投入却在近年成为行业共识。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;16家日化企业，也用数字给出了答案。2022财年，共有11家营业收入同比下滑，占比近七成；但在15家披露了研发投入的企业里，仅6家压缩了研发投入，占比四成。为何如此？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，研发是品牌溢价的底气。“79元的花西子眉笔”事件中，有人计算其单克价格竟然比黄金还高。当然，价格高昂的不止花西子，许多国货近年都在悄悄上调价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管对比欧美大牌，国货美妆品的价格仍有上涨空间，但这次事件背后，是国货品牌营销的“苦功”无法支撑其涨价行为。消费者之所以不买账“79元的眉笔”，归根结底是对产品价值的质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消费品的价值通常包括品牌价值和功能价值，品牌价值的形成需要历经时间的积淀，而功能价值却是后发者可以通过研发获取的。对于品牌价值尚未形成的国货品牌，增强研发不仅是对产品功能价值的打造，也有利于其品牌形象的形成，薇诺娜就是一个以“专注研发”作为品牌发力方向的典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;其次，研发是打造新增长点的不二法门。&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;这在化妆品行业尤为明显。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，中国的美妆护肤行业一直是渠道为王。市场份额争夺的焦点，从线下店铺，到传统电商，再到社交电商。得益于社交媒体的发展，消费者与商家之间的信息不对称程度大幅降低，消费者开始更加关注产品的功效，看成分买护肤品成为潮流，美妆护肤行业进入了以产品功效为驱动的新时期。推出功效性护肤品、打造功效产品矩阵成为了化妆品企业争夺市场份额的新战场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美妆尤其是护肤产品的功效与产品原材料、配方密切相关，而原材料与配方的发现、发明无疑离不开研发投入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，随着功效护肤成为新的卖点，加之医美的流行，在配方研发、对症下“药”方面具有先天优势的生物医药企业也开始加入美妆行业“内卷”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;生物科技，跨界竞逐&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;或许已经有人注意到，持有米蓓尔、夸迪以及润百颜等化妆品牌的华熙生物&lt;span>;（688363.SH）&lt;/span>;未出现在榜单。华熙生物被划入了医药制造业下的生物技术行业，未参与日化行业排名，却是日化行业企业的重要竞争对手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立于2000年的华熙生物，从2016年开始进军护肤品行业，把玻尿酸生意做到行业第一。2022年，其功能性护肤品实现收入46.07亿元，同比增长38.80%，占公司主营业务收入的72.45%，这一营收甚至高于御泥坊的母公司水羊股份的总营收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a20f11734e761e45cf14adcd5b0c615d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 559px; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;559&quot; height=&quot;781&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a20f11734e761e45cf14adcd5b0c615d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256889&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;559&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此类似的，还有巨子生物&lt;span>;（02367.HK）&lt;/span>;，其主业之一就是功效性护肤品，旗下品牌包括可复美、可丽金等，2022财年营收达23.64亿元，其中功效性护肤品的占比超六成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，日化行业也正在积极往生物科技靠拢。丸美股份，在2022年提出基于重组胶原蛋白未来十年的研发规划，计划陆续推出重组胶原蛋白二类医疗器械证的产品、三类医疗器械证的重组胶原蛋白水光针产品、三类医疗器械证的填充类充足胶原蛋白产品、基于重组胶原蛋白的人工角膜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;实际上，生物科技和日化行业属于双向奔赴。医疗与美容的交叉融合越来越紧密，美妆护肤产品从配方和成分到技术再到包装，都在往生物科技的方向靠拢。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;发酵工程、分子生物学等技术使得新的活性成分得以提取与开发；纳米技术、微乳化技术等技术用于攻克皮肤难以吸收的难题；可降解包装材料在环保政策的推动下推向市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全方位将产品研发与生物科技交融，产学研一体，在精准护肤、功效护肤等领域，美妆护肤品牌们通过深耕生物技术塑造自身竞争力，新品牌也在抓住技术变革不断涌现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾欧莱雅、雅诗兰黛、资生堂等国际美妆巨头的发展史，其起家和护城河的建立也无一不与化学、生物医药密切相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在消费降级、国潮盛行的当下，一直以来主打“物美价廉”的国货美妆企业正在迎来拉近与欧美大牌差距的重要赛点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若要接住这“泼天的富贵”，美妆国货们需审视并学习欧美品牌的研发初心，切勿以高营销为底气随意涨价，毕竟公司所处的不是广告行业，让消费者感知到价值的不是华丽的包装与广告代言，而是产品给消费者带来货真价实的功效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>