<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[儿童是世界的主角]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260952]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Today (November 20) is World Children&#39;s Day, and it is also the day when the famous &quot;Convention on the Rights of the Child&quot; was born. The Lebanese poet Gibran once wrote in &quot;To the Children&quot;: They come through you, but not from you. Although they are with you, they do not belong to you. Children are the protagonists of the world and a beautiful reflection of the city. Be less malicious and more caring, so that the future masters can change the direction of the tide.</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“14岁当爹”不能只当八卦，保护未成年男性权利应尽快提上日程丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 19:06:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the news that &quot;in order to allow a 4-year-old boy to settle down, an 18-year-old father appeared for a paternity test&quot; has attracted public attention great concern. According to the Anhui Radio and Television Economic Life Channel, a 4-year-old boy in Hefei, Anhui, Wang Zien, had no one to take care of him and played alone on the street all day long. In order to settle Wang Zien&#39;s residence, the child&#39;s father, 18-year-old Wang, finally showed up. He said that he was only 14 years old when Wang Zien was born, and the child&#39;s mother was 20 years old at the time. The two parties broke up a few months after the child was born, and there has been no contact. He had to leave the child to his father to raise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident broke out, public opinion mainly focused on Wang giving birth to a child before the age of 14. He was still a child, which was too irresponsible, and the mother of the child was more likely to be suspected of abandoning the child. A lawyer interviewed by the media said that the mother should fulfill her parenting obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These angles cannot be said to be meaningless, but they obviously miss the point. The crux of the problem should be that boys&#39; sexual rights are not protected. According to Wang, he was only 14 years old when the child was born (I don’t know whether he was one year old or not, even if he was one year old, Wang was probably still under 14 years old when they had sex), and the child’s mother was 20 years old. It can be inferred that when having sexual relations, Wang was most likely under 14 years old, while the mother of the child was over 18 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What will happen if the genders are reversed and an 18-year-old man has sex with a girl under 14? I&#39;m afraid online public opinion has already exploded. According to the criminal law, sexual relations with a girl under the age of 14, regardless of whether the girl &quot;consented&quot;, will be severely punished as rape. If the circumstances are serious or cause serious consequences, the death penalty may also be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when the genders are reversed and adult women have sex with underage men, the situation becomes very embarrassing. The crime of rape cannot be applied because China&#39;s criminal law stipulates that the victim of rape can only be a female. Even if a man is forced to have sex, the other party does not commit the crime of rape. If the boy is under 14 when he is violated, he can be punished as child molestation. However, the penalty for this crime is only a fixed-term imprisonment of less than 5 years. Even if there are bad circumstances or serious consequences, the maximum sentence can only be 15 years in prison. This is not the same as the punishment for rape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the male victim is over 14 years old, he is no longer a child. Even if he is forcibly violated, criminal law cannot protect his rights. More importantly, in reality, if a minor male has sexual relations with a female, if the other party is an adult, judicial practice will not consider the male&#39;s sexual rights to have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is obviously abnormal. Minor males should receive the same protection as minor females. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quite coincidentally, a case of an adult female teacher sexually assaulting an underage male student recently broke out in Taiwan. Xu, a female teacher who works as a fifth- and sixth-grade primary school teacher, repeatedly sexually assaulted a boy under the age of 14 in her class. She eventually became pregnant and gave birth to a child. The crime was later reported. The judge recently ruled that Xu was guilty of sexual intercourse and forced intercourse with a man under the age of 14, and sentenced her to 17 years and six months in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analyzing this case, we can find the differences between Taiwan’s criminal laws and mainland criminal laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, having sex with a man against his will also constitutes the crime of rape (called &quot;forced intercourse&quot; in Taiwan). According to the criminal regulations revised in Taiwan in 1999, &quot;Men and women who have sexual intercourse by force, coercion, intimidation, hypnosis or other methods against their will shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than 3 years but not more than 10 years.&quot; In this case, The judge determined that the female teacher surnamed Xu had sex with a male student twice against the male student&#39;s will, so it constituted a crime of forced intercourse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, as long as you have sexual intercourse with a child under the age of 14, even if the child is voluntary, it still constitutes a crime (Article 227 of the Criminal Code of Taiwan, &quot;Any person who has sexual intercourse with a man or woman under the age of 14 shall be punished with 3 to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than 10 years but not more than 10 years”). In the above-mentioned case, the judge held that the female teacher named Xu had sexual intercourse with male students on seven other occasions. Although the boys were consenting, Xu&#39;s use of the girl still constituted the crime of sexual intercourse with men under the age of 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Taiwan’s criminal regulations also equally protect the sexual rights of minors of men and women over 14 years old but under 16 years old. “Anyone who has sexual intercourse with a man or woman over 14 years old but under 16 years old shall be sentenced to a fixed-term imprisonment of not more than 7 years.” &quot;. That is to say, having sexual relations with minors between the ages of 14 and 16 is also a crime, but the penalty is lighter than having sexual relations with children under 14 years old. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mainland criminal law, the protection of men’s sexual rights is much weaker. The sexual rights of minor males over 14 years old (let alone adult males) are not protected by criminal law, and the sexual rights of boys under 14 years old can only be protected by the much weaker crime of child molestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another point in Taiwan’s criminal laws that we can learn from, that is, multiple crimes can be punished based on the number of crimes committed, and they can be punished simultaneously. In the above-mentioned case, the judge found that Xu had sex with male students nine times. Although they were only divided into two categories, she was still convicted of nine crimes, and finally she was punished for several crimes. In the mainland legal system, only different crimes will be regarded as multiple crimes, the same crime will be classified as one crime, and the number of crimes will only be used as a reference for sentencing. This may result in a lighter sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at history, before Taiwan revised its criminal laws in 1999, the victims of rape could only be women. If a man was sexually assaulted, the perpetrator could only be held accountable for indecent assault. However, Taiwan revised the relevant regulations more than 20 years ago to provide equal protection for the sexual rights of men and women. This is something the mainland can learn from. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江大庆市肇州发生火灾，致7人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260964]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 19:09:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter learned from the People’s Government of Zhaozhou County, Daqing City, Heilongjiang Province that at 14:00 on November 20, 2023 At 04:00, the county fire brigade received an alarm that a fire broke out in a single-story steel structure simple board house of an individual industrial and commercial household in the south of Shizi Street, Fengle Town, Zhaozhou County. At 14:40, the open fire was extinguished at the scene, covering an area of ​​280 square meters. The fire caused 7 deaths. At present, the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“游客回家”，一些国际网红城市对过度旅游说不]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260941]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Stop the emergency brake now, otherwise we will be run over.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For Thinking about our children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two months ago, about 100 residents of Hallstatt, Austria, gathered in the tunnel leading to Hallstatt and shouted various slogans to protest against &quot;excessive travel&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Austrian town of Hallstatt has long been attracting tourists. The tree-lined mountains, the wooden houses towering over the villages, and the sparkling mountain lakes make you forget to leave. However, the town, which receives up to 10,000 visitors a day, is tiring for many of its approximately 800 residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/e8d6f4c91c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;737&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/e8d6f4c91c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;International internet celebrity tourist cities are overcrowded, and many places have enacted rules to restrict tourists. (Li Chunhua/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the recovery of global tourism, the term &quot;overtourism&quot; has reappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, 2023, at the World Travel Mart, the organizer and Oxford Economics jointly released a new 2023 global leisure tourism report, and pointed out that in 2023, global leisure tourism The total number of tourists only dropped by about 10% compared with 2019 before the epidemic, and the total number of leisure tourists accounted for 60% of the total number of tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerns about overtourism appear not only in popular cities such as Austria, Venice, and Bali, but also in other regions such as Hawaii and Greece, Spain, and Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/f6d22842ac.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;678&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/f6d22842ac.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258862&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Dozens of tourists are pouring into Europe&#39;s otherwise peaceful country The small town troubles many locals. (Yao Jiatong/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local residents are often dissatisfied that the influx of tourists has pushed up local consumption levels and put huge pressure on local infrastructure and urban management. In addition, the uncivilized behavior of some foreign tourists interferes with their daily lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many international celebrity tourist cities have formulated rules to restrict tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Venice charges a &quot;city entry tax&quot; for day-trippers; the ancient city of Croatia uses cameras to monitor the flow of people and closes its doors as soon as the number of people exceeds 6,000; Iceland restricts local residents from renting out properties for tourists to live in; Machu Picchu only Three fixed tour routes have been opened to foreign tourists...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations World Tourism Organization stated that from the release of the new crown epidemic to 2030, the number of international tourists is expected to increase by 50 million every year, and the growth will mainly come from Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Enough of the huge, noisy tourist groups”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;365 days a year, photographer Chen Chen Half the time is spent traveling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Austria, the &quot;artistic atmosphere&quot; hit him, which doubled his fondness for the city. When walking on the street, Chen Chen said he couldn&#39;t help but stop at what was playing on the big screen of the opera house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the small town of Hallstatt is a veritable &quot;Internet celebrity check-in place&quot;, located in the Salzkammergut region of Austria. In the past decade, its popularity has skyrocketed due to its use in movies and TV series. At the same time, it is also a world cultural heritage with picturesque scenery, ancient salt mines, ancient tombs and other attractions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/e25879925a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/e25879925a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258863&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Austrian town of Hallstatt is a World Cultural Heritage , picturesque scenery, and also has ancient salt mines, ancient tombs and other attractions. (Chen Chen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when he actually came to the small town of Hallstatt, Chen Chen’s feelings became different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are so many foreign tourists in that town.&quot; Chen Chen&#39;s tone unconsciously increased. &quot;Obviously the locals don&#39;t like so many tourists.&quot; He observed that on the doors of many houses in the town, there would be signs such as &quot;Please do not speak loudly&quot; written on them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many reports claim that in just a few years, this village with nearly 800 residents has become a world tourist attraction. It receives around 1 million tourists a year, many of them Asians, &quot;who turn Hallstatt into an important stopover&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Chen remembered that one time, when he was taking pictures of a house, a local suddenly rushed out the door angrily and shouted at Chen Chen, telling him to go away quickly, otherwise he would call the police. &quot;Locals have had enough of large, noisy, disruptive tour groups.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 27, 2023, residents took to the streets and blocked tunnels and main roads leading to the entrance to the town. Trying to draw attention to the problem of overtourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The roads in the Austrian town are very narrow and crowded with people. Even the restaurants where you eat have long queues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Chen felt that not only was the restaurant’s service speed slow, but its attitude towards tourists was not very good either. &quot;Indifferent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the mountain behind the small town of Hallstatt, there is a historic salt mine. Many foreign tourists come to this internet celebrity check-in place. But to take a small train up the mountain, Chen Chen couldn&#39;t wait in line, &quot;because there were too many people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to take pictures in the mountains. &quot;We take advantage of every crack, and the queue order is not particularly good.&quot; Chen Chen said that as a photographer, if there are too many passers-by in the shot, he can only change the perspective or rely on post-production to process the pictures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Too many tourists have also brought about some derivative problems, such as garbage visible everywhere.” Chen Chen believes that the uncivilized behavior of many foreign tourists will arouse the resentment of local people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After staying in the Austrian town for half a day, Chen Chen went to another town next door and found that the contrast was obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It was a very unknown town. It was very quiet, with few tourists. There was only one restaurant in the town.&quot; Chen Chen said that when I went there, the restaurant was full of locals dining. The elderly couple patted the empty seat next to them, indicating that Chen Chen could sit down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Chen found that the local people&#39;s lives were very leisurely. They got up late in the morning and everyone had a relaxed expression. The elderly couple said that they don&#39;t like too many tourists because they are too noisy, so they have been living in this quiet town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Austrian town, a travel blogger also uploaded some street graffiti in Barcelona, ​​Spain on his social media account. The alleys in the neighborhood were almost covered with the words &quot;Tourists go back to their own homes&quot; The slogan was accompanied by the text &quot;In August, the European tourist season, Barcelona is so crowded that you can&#39;t even walk in the alleys.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such posts quickly aroused a lot of discussion. Lining, a netizen from Spain, explained in the comment area that the slogans sprayed by people in Barcelona are mainly aimed at tourists from Northern Europe. &quot;They party wildly, drink heavily, and urinate everywhere. The streets are always dirty.&quot; Lining said that local Barcelona people had to move out because of this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports said that in protest, residents of the village of Hallstatt also erected a wooden barrier in the town, blocking the view of the Alps. However, the barrier was later removed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the mayor of Hallstatt had promised to reduce the number of tourist buses entering the town, but the problem of overtourism persists. Residents are demanding a limit on the number of visitors per day and a curfew on tour buses, which are also not allowed into the city after 5 p.m. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On online social media platforms, many netizens express their understanding of the anti-tourist behavior of international Internet celebrities. They believe that excessive tourists have indeed squeezed the living space of local residents and affected their living environment. It has also increased prices around the scenic area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a very normal reaction.” Zhou Zhao, head of the European Department of Shenzhen Vanzhong Cultural Tourism, said that international tourism is a “love-hate relationship” for local residents. Love is that tourists can drive the local economy, but hate is that too many tourists will affect the lives of local people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Ultimately make more money from tourists&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Fuzi is a freelance photographer, 2023 I started living in Bali in early September of this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bali is more than a thousand kilometers away from Jakarta, the capital of Indonesia, and is separated from Java Island by only a 3.2-kilometer-wide strait. It covers an area of ​​about more than 5,000 square kilometers. It is the most famous tourist and leisure area in Indonesia. Many travel magazines have voted it &quot;one of the most enchanting holiday destinations in the world&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The prices of accommodation and food in Bali have increased now,” Fuzi said. In the past, you could rent a large suite with a swimming pool for 2,000 to 3,000 yuan per month in Bali, with good decoration and beautiful scenery. . But after the epidemic is relaxed, you can only rent a single room at a similar price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even most restaurants have increased their prices. In the past, for 100 RMB per person, you could have a good Western meal in a restaurant with a nice environment, but now it costs at least 150 RMB. The starting price of a motorcycle has more than doubled from three to four yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Zhao told Southern Weekend reporters that for popular foreign tourist cities, it is generally necessary to book hotels about two months in advance, and prices have increased by about 30% on average compared to before the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Bali Province’s tourism statistics, from November 2022 to January 2023, Bali Province welcomed nearly 1 million foreign tourists. According to data released by the Chinese Consulate General in Denpasar, Indonesia, Bali Province receives about 40% of foreign tourists visiting Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the nature of her work, Fuzi often has to go out for filming. He bought a motorcycle, but there are often traffic jams on the road in Canggu, sometimes even for thirty or forty minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The road is very narrow, with a car in the middle and motorcycles jammed on both sides.” Fuzi told Southern Weekend reporters that tourists and locals overlapped, and some traffic jams also caused dust, causing the air to be dirty. good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/6ff705530e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/6ff705530e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258864&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A short and narrow road, sometimes even It will take thirty or forty minutes. (Fuzi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the car rental fees for foreign tourists in Bali have also increased. In the past, you could rent a motorcycle for 300 yuan, but now it costs 500 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Zhao said that this year, as the energy supply of most countries has been affected by the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, prices such as fuel, gas, and electricity are rising, and travel costs have increased. Therefore, some outbound tour group fees It is more expensive due to this reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, for Fuzi, the longer he stays in Bali, the more his favorability decreases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gap between the rich and the poor in Bali is large, and some people who rely on tourism have inspired others&#39; desire for money. After the epidemic was relaxed, many people who had houses at home opened B&amp;Bs or shops. In the past, Fuzi felt that most people in Bali were &quot;simple&quot;, but now they are more &quot;commercial&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May of this year, a piece of news about “you need to make a reservation one year in advance if you want to travel to Bali” attracted the attention of the international community. The source is a report from an Indonesian news website that the tourist resort island of Bali plans to impose restrictions on foreign tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Bali Governor Wayan explained to the media that the restrictive measures were implemented mainly to prevent some foreign tourists from staying in the local area on tourist visas and illegally doing business or looking for jobs after running out of money on vacation. In addition, with the recovery of tourism after the epidemic and the arrival of large-scale tourists, some illegal and disrespectful behaviors have also appeared, &quot;causing Bali residents to feel uneasy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this plan, Fuzi thinks it is &quot;difficult to implement.&quot; Because in Bali, &quot;money is king.&quot; He said that both the government and the people of Bali want to develop the economy. The so-called &quot;application restrictions&quot; are only a minor problem as long as the money is available. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuzi said that even if it is implemented, prices will not fall back to normal levels. &quot;Because these policies are essentially screening tourists and selecting tourists with better and more stable financial capabilities.&quot; Fuzi believes that in this way, tourists can make more money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the following month, Ayu Martini, Indonesia’s Deputy Minister of Tourism and Creative Economy, said that as of now, no reservation is required for Bali travel, and Indonesia’s visa policy has not changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant plans previously formulated by the Indonesian government, Indonesia strives to receive 3.5 million to 7.4 million international tourists in 2023, and the foreign exchange revenue from the tourism industry will reach at least 2.07 billion US dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“The key lies in passenger flow management”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When Taiwanese youth Chen Zhiwei went to Venice for the first time, In addition to admiring the cityscape, he was also surprised by the number of tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can see faces from different countries everywhere in the local area.” Chen Zhiwei said that the most common means of transportation on Venice Island is buses and boats, and each boat is always full of people. &quot;From morning to night.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Venice, this beautiful city known as the &quot;City on the Water&quot;, is located on the Adriatic Sea in northeastern Italy. It has always been a tourist attraction for tourists from all over the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/245f13e5c4.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/245f13e5c4.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Venice, the &quot;City on the Water&quot;, is a tourist attraction for tourists from all over the world. The picture shows tourists on a gondola ride in Venice. (Yao Jiatong/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, conflicts occur from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once, when Chen Zhiwei was visiting Pisa, he was told at the train station that the last train was temporarily cancelled. Since hundreds of locals and foreign tourists were stranded at the scene, the train station sent a return bus, but it could only accommodate 40 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, the staff allowed tourists with children to get on the bus first, but this quickly aroused the dissatisfaction of locals who could not get on the bus. They complained that it was all due to too many tourists, causing even the bus to run out of time. Can&#39;t sit down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many locals surrounded the bus and refused to let the driver drive away.” Chen Zhiwei said that who got on the bus and who stayed behind became the fuse of conflicts. After physical conflicts broke out between locals and tourists, many police officers were deployed to resolve the issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, many tourists, including Chen Zhiwei, could only stay overnight at the train station and wait for the train the next morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, 2023, Venice announced a policy that starting in the spring of 2024, tourists entering the city during peak periods will need to pay 5 euros (approximately 39 yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the Venetian government hoped that the money could be used to improve residents&#39; facilities and infrastructure. They &quot;had to deal with overflowing bins&quot; and rubbish thrown on the streets by tourists. At its peak, the number of foreign tourists outnumbered locals by about five times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Zhiwei is accustomed to things like &quot;taxation&quot;. For example, when staying in a hotel, many hotels charge a &quot;city tax&quot;, which is usually two or three euros a day, and it will be shown on the bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After the money is collected, it will actually be used to help maintain the city and deal with problems arising from tourism.&quot; Chen Zhiwei said that it is reasonable for foreign tourists to bear some maintenance costs while traveling. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;External public opinion believes that excessive tourism has caused many locals to leave their hometowns. The introduction of taxes and fees such as &quot;tourism tax&quot; can offset harmful effects such as waste resource pollution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/88eac1abe8.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/88eac1abe8.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many netizens complained on social platforms that the difficulty of parking at international celebrity tourist attractions is a thorny issue. (Yao Jiatong/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ivan Saprov, founder of the American travel technology company Voyagu, said that sustainability-related charges are not difficult for tourists to accept. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They conducted a survey and found that nearly 40% of tourists said that charging fees was okay and expressed support for this, saying that the income generated could be used to create pleasant experiences for tourists and locals. Facilities and Services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in order to restrict foreign tourists, homeless people and other people who spend the night outside, the Venice government has made efforts to install benches in public places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Zhiwei observed that there was a strange raised shape in the middle of some benches. Locals told him that the purpose of this was to prevent tourists and homeless people from sleeping on the benches and reduce their stay in public areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Venice, Croatia has introduced &quot;rules&quot; or instructions for tourists to prevent unruly behavior related to drinking. This includes requirements for appropriate attire in historic areas, prohibitions on alcohol consumption and gathering in public places where alcohol is prohibited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ina Rodin, director of North America at the Croatian National Tourist Board, said a code of conduct is a way of informing visitors of acceptable behavior at a destination. &quot;But compliance is often limited.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/043a1631e0.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/043a1631e0.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many places set &quot;rules&quot; or instructions to prevent unruly behavior. The picture shows a policeman issuing a ticket at the entrance of an Italian town. (Yao Jiatong/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as one of the most famous tourist destinations in the world, Venice’s current core area population is less than 50,000. During peak tourist seasons, the number of tourists sometimes exceeds twice the resident population. The huge foot traffic has caused serious problems over the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zurab Pololikashvili, Secretary-General of the United Nations World Tourism Organization, said in an interview that the key to solving overtourism lies in the management of passenger flow. He noted that new technologies can help solve this problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, towns in northern Germany use lidar sensors installed on self-driving cars to manage tourist flow. To combat crowding without sacrificing tourism revenue, some countries are attracting tourists to less crowded areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最高检挂牌督办山西永聚煤矿火灾事故案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 18:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 16, a major fire accident occurred in the joint building of Yongju Coal Mine, Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province. 26 people have died, 34 people have been hospitalized, and 4 people are under observation in outpatient clinics. At present, the Lishi District Branch of the Luliang City Public Security Bureau has opened a case for investigation against the relevant responsible persons, and the case is currently under investigation. The Shanxi Provincial Procuratorate was invited to participate in the accident investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to severely crack down on criminal crimes endangering production safety in accordance with the law and protect the safety of people&#39;s lives and property, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate has supervised the handling of the Shanxi Yongju Coal Mine fire accident case, requiring the Shanxi Provincial Procuratorate to give full play to its procuratorial functions and coordinate with the public security The agencies and relevant departments should accurately identify the responsibilities of all parties, consolidate the evidence base of the case, punish relevant crimes in accordance with the law, and safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the victims; at the same time, they should strengthen traceability management and promote the prevention and comprehensive management of production safety risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The procuratorial organs will continue to increase their efforts to crack down on criminal crimes that endanger production safety, starting from the implementation of the Supreme People’s Procuratorate’s “Procuratorial Recommendation No. 8”, urging relevant functional departments to strengthen and improve production safety supervision, and seize early Grasp small signs, grasp the implementation of systems and standards, and nip problems before they occur, so as to effectively protect the safety of people&#39;s lives and property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从民族问题到“赚快钱”，缅北冲突何时休？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260943]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the conflict in northern Myanmar has attracted attention at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, 2023, when answering a question from an AFP reporter, Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Wang Wenbin said that China is highly concerned about the conflict situation in northern Myanmar, urges all parties to immediately cease fire and end the war, and insist on dialogue and consultation to resolve the conflict. Resolve differences peacefully, avoid escalation of the situation, and take practical and effective measures to ensure security and stability on the China-Myanmar border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, the Myanmar National Governing Council (junta) held a meeting of the National Defense Committee. The Commander-in-Chief of the Myanmar Army, General Min Aung Hlaing, made it clear at the meeting that the attack launched by the Kokang Allied Forces was intended to retake the Kokang. control and regain the benefits of drug production and trafficking, while its allies, the Ta&#39;ang Army and the Kachin Independence Army, also have their own political goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Chaos in northern Myanmar, the impact of &quot;making quick money&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Northern Myanmar has been in a state of war for a long time, with a large number of ethnic minority local armed forces, Myanmar government forces and minorities recruited by the government forces. The militia groups transformed from ethnic local armed forces are fighting with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the main contradiction exists between the local armed forces of ethnic minorities and the government forces, under certain circumstances, some ethnic minority armed forces will cooperate with the government forces to a certain extent to target other ethnic minority armed forces. ; In some cases, the militia groups recruited by the government forces will turn against the government forces again, so that on the one hand, the government forces need to rely on the support of the militia groups as local people to deal with the local militias; on the other hand, they also maintain a high degree of vigilance against the militia groups, everywhere Limit it to prevent it from getting too big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The causes of Myanmar’s civil war are long-standing and complex. This involves the need to face the ethnic chieftain system left over from the feudal dynasty in the construction of the Myanmar nation-state, as well as the British colonists&#39; political tactics of strengthening support for ethnic chieftains and countering the majority Bamar ethnic group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What cannot be ignored is that in the 1960s, after launching a coup and seizing state power, Commander-in-Chief of the Myanmar Army Ne Win adopted an impatient attitude in building a nation-state and tried to divide the national identity into three Sixty-nine and so on, forcibly promoting the assimilation of ethnic minorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the area where ethnic minorities occupy nearly half of Myanmar’s territory, dozens of ethnic minorities who have lived here for generations suddenly became second- and third-class citizens overnight, and even their national identity cannot be guaranteed. What they lose is not only political rights, but also the most basic land property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, this attitude of &quot;the land is important but not the people&quot;, which has not been completely changed, is the most fundamental reason for the armed resistance of ethnic minorities in northern and southeastern Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myanmar is not a developed country, and areas inhabited by ethnic minorities such as northern Myanmar are even more remote and underdeveloped. The long-term consumption of war has completely complicated the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the Burmese Army recognizes the legitimacy of their political status, in reality, the Burmese Army’s military expenditures are not generous, and the supply of their weapons, equipment and personnel costs is basically better than nothing, which often leads them to “use drugs” &quot;Raise the Army&quot; route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Burmese army often adopts a indulgent attitude towards this. If controls are strengthened, it is easy for the vigilante groups to rebel again and become local militants. If the vigilante group collapses immediately, he will also lose a powerful arm. Therefore, this delicate balance is also an important reason for the rampant criminal activities in northern Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the shortage of military funds, the income of the military and police at the grassroots level of the Myanmar government is too low. At the beginning of 2021, a &quot;nest case&quot; occurred in Tachileik, a city in northern Myanmar, in which some military and police collaborated to shelter drug trafficking. For this reason, Myanmar The military government had to make major changes to the local military and police departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The huge profits of drugs are also the reason why the &quot;alternative cultivation&quot; model that the international community once seriously promoted has made occasional progress in northern Myanmar, but has always had little effect. If we can find another way to &quot;make quick money&quot; that is not so eye-catching to the world and is as profitable as the drug trade, this will be quite attractive to various ethnic groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in the past ten years, when &quot;online gambling&quot; was hit hard again, it quickly turned into widespread electronic fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, on the one hand, the Kokang Allied Forces will indeed deal a heavy blow to the electronic fraud problem in northern Myanmar; on the other hand, it may also make the future situation in Myanmar more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Each one has his or her own agenda&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although the Kokang area is only a tiny corner of the country compared to the whole of Myanmar, judging from the scope of this war, it is obviously beyond The scope of boldness. Not to mention that the direct goal of the Allied Forces is to regain control of the Kokang region. As allies of the Allied Forces, the Ta&#39;ang Army, Arakan Army, People&#39;s Protection Army (PDF) and Kachin Army, their demands are obviously not to combat electronic fraud. But for its own benefit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ta&#39;ang Army is fighting for a controlled area around Muse City in Myanmar, and may be able to achieve a status similar to today&#39;s Wa State in the future; the Arakan Army and the Kachin Army are pursuing in Rakhine State and Kachin State to establish an independent country; and the People&#39;s Protection Army (PDF)&#39;s primary goal is to overthrow the military regime throughout Myanmar...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the Allied Forces recapture Kokang, it may become a landmark event, prompting other civilian armed organizations to Political desires are rising again. In addition to the civilian armed organizations that have not signed the &quot;Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement&quot; with the Burmese army, other organizations that have signed the agreement and even those that have accepted the reorganization of the Burmese army into &quot;border defense battalions&quot; may again There is a change of situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is undeniable that the current relative strength gap between the Myanmar Army and the above-mentioned organizations is the biggest driving force for them to unite and cooperate in combat. There is no doubt that this has indeed caused considerable pressure on the Myanmar Army. It is worth noting that the political demands of various local armed forces and the People&#39;s Protection Army vary greatly. In the future, internal conflicts may escalate and become prolonged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a long-term and large-scale war breaks out in Myanmar, not only may traditional security issues such as the dispersion of weapons and the impact of refugee waves occur, but also if the De&#39;ang Army occupies the Muse Port, and considering that the Qingshui River Port has been captured by the Allied Forces, The land trade channel between China and Myanmar will be greatly affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the consumption of war will inevitably stimulate the recurrence of certain phenomena in the &quot;feeding the army with poison&quot;, &quot;feeding the army with gambling&quot; and the current &quot;feeding the army with fraud&quot; that civilian armed groups originally relied on. It may have reared its head, or it may have turned to other more novel models of &quot;black and gray industries&quot; again, causing more complex security issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some civilian martial arts organizations in northern Myanmar are likely to create some hidden concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First of all, the phenomenon of &quot;large mixed living and small settlements&quot; in northern Myanmar northern Myanmar is very common. There is no doubt that it will be caught in a series of problems in territorial and population jurisdiction, causing hidden dangers of future conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Secondly, the natural and humanistic conditions of northern Myanmar are quite limited. If these areas are independent, it is difficult to form a pillar industry in addition to minerals, and the lack of self -support in finance. There will be problems with social governance capabilities. In addition, the existence of a large number of cross -border ethnic groups in the region will eventually cause domestic contradictions and affect regional stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Finally, the consequences of the split Myanmar may seriously affect regional stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Can it &quot;crushed&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the past, the reason why the Burmese army was able to show the crushing trend of the civilian military organizations mainly depends on the advantages and resource advantages in the Burmese region. The only obstacle that is not easy to overcome is the geographical situation in the civil area. This advantage has been greatly weakened after the &quot;2 · 1 coup&quot; in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Democratic League government has a very powerful appeal within Myanmar, especially the Burmese. The coup of the Burmese army has caused severe division within the Burmese and seriously weakening the sustainable war of the Burmese army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of military forces, the Burmese Army can indeed increase troops on a large scale in theory to solve the danger of beyond the city. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Burmese -based area, the PICC has blossomed in the current place. Once the heavy soldiers go north to Myanmar&#39;s hinterland, how can they not seize this opportunity? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If the Burmese Army takes the means of mobilization reserve, first expand the army and then go north, there are also several obstacles: not only will it make it difficult to make the fiscal situation that is not wonderful, but it is also likely that the forces such as Baojun and other people&#39;s alliance forces will further infiltrate the influence Inside the Burmese army, more troubles are caused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If the Burmese Army is passively accepted by reality, first of all, it will severely crack down on the personal prestige of the Burmese army. If changes occur, it will inevitably bring a greater impact on the overall political situation of Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What choices will the high -level of the Burmese Army eventually make are obviously a question worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Myanmar, in the future, the Burmese army may be able to reach a certain compromise with the civilians of the civilians through political negotiations, and then turn around to focus on the Baojun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, things may in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Burmese Army and the NLD forces reached a compromise. This may cause Myanmar for a long time to be roughly stable, but various small conflicts will be one after another. This is also a tragedy for Myanmar itself, which means that the people of Myanmar must bear more pain, but it is better than the state of division and losing autonomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is also a result that is less likely but also exists. After the Burmese realizes internal reconciliation, the Burmese army finally relies on its own volume advantage to completely suppress civil land in a certain period of time, at least at least, at least In the form of form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the future, the autonomy of the northern Myanmar nation will be effectively guaranteed, especially the power between the central government of Myanmar and the local autonomous government of the ethnic minority is clearly divided, which can ensure the development and the development of northern Myanmar ethnic minorities regions and The development of the Burmese region is the fundamental move that truly eliminates the sources of trouble in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, this idea is still the air tower before today&#39;s Myanmar politics and social reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx. Best &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中华老字号”不是护身符：历史招牌只是其表，商业信誉才是其里丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260947]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Commerce and other five departments issued the &quot;Notice on Announcement of the Review Results of Chinese Time-honored Brands&quot;, which will lead to long-term poor management. , or even 55 brands that have gone bankrupt, canceled, closed down, or lost the ownership and use rights of time-honored registered trademarks, have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands; 73 brands with poor operations and declining performance are required to be rectified within 6 months; 1,000 brands will continue to be retained A brand with standardized operations and good development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chinese time-honored brand&quot; is not only a title/title, but also an officially certified identity/qualification. The &quot;remove, rectify, and retain&quot; measures taken by the five departments to &quot;remove, rectify, and retain&quot; &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot; just allow the outside world to rethink the true connotation of &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot; and analyze the right and wrong behind &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official definition of the so-called &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot; refers to &quot;long history, products, skills or services that have been passed down from generation to generation, with a distinctive traditional Chinese cultural background and profound cultural heritage, and have gained widespread social recognition.&quot; recognition and form a brand with good reputation.” From the literal meaning, &quot;inherited from generation to generation&quot; can be interpreted as &quot;historical and cultural traditional value&quot;, while &quot;products, skills or services are widely recognized by society&quot; can be reduced to &quot;commercial reputation and market status&quot;, which is also the construction of &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot;. &quot;Two pillars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connotation of &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot; is the &quot;traditional cultural background and profound cultural heritage&quot; behind it, or is it the market position and business reputation won in competition? The two cases in this notice can be said to be the answer to this question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the &quot;time-honored brands&quot; that have been removed from the list, Inner Mongolia Dashengkui and Anhui Beggar Chicken are two typical cases: Dashengkui lasted for hundreds of years from the Kangxi period of the Qing Dynasty to the Anti-Japanese War. &quot;Yin Yuan Bao Pu&quot; ruled two thousand miles of trade routes in Mongolia. When it resumed business more than ten years ago, it also placed many people&#39;s expectations on reviving the old brand; Anhui beggar&#39;s chicken is said to date back to the Hongwu period of the Ming Dynasty. Although this legend is false and true , but the reason why it was expelled from the &quot;time-honored brand&quot; is not its historical and cultural authenticity, but its poor management in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that the history of Dashengkui is more authentic, but this does not save it from the bad luck of being &quot;delisted&quot;; Anhui Beggar Chicken has doubts about its history and culture alone, but the last thing that crushed it The straw is probably not an academic verification of authenticity, but a defeat in the competition in the modern catering market. In fact, there is more than one &quot;Beggar&#39;s Chicken&quot;. The &quot;Daoxiang Village&quot; and &quot;Guanshengyuan&quot; that have been removed from the list this time also have brands with the same name. The reason why they failed to pass the review of &quot;Chinese Time-honored Brands&quot; is not because of &quot;historical and cultural traditional value&quot; &quot;Something went wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, for these &quot;Chinese time-honored brands&quot;, if they cannot embrace the latest changes in the market and cannot innovate themselves to meet the needs of consumers, they will inevitably die out; conversely, if a brand can Create brand new products and services, and even if they are not old, they will slowly occupy the minds of consumers and become a new tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Western academic circles have long noticed the phenomenon of &quot;invention of tradition&quot;: those &quot;traditions&quot; that appear or claim to be ancient often originate quite recently, and are sometimes even invented. . This is not uncommon in the Chinese context, which is the common phenomenon of &quot;replying family trees&quot; and &quot;recognizing ancestors&quot;. The &quot;traditional origins&quot; recognized by many &quot;time-honored brands&quot; are often suspected of being attached to others in academic circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts have proved that whether a tradition really has historical and cultural continuity value and whether it is really academically tenable is not determined by whether the tradition is widely accepted. The key factor is not even important. Regardless of these &quot;time-honored brands&quot;, even emerging companies that have not been established for a long time often have to make some &quot;inventions&quot; and even &quot;legends&quot; in the &quot;brand story&quot;, but no consumer will be like a professional historian. If we continue to delve deeper into how much of this is true and how false, we will be more inclined to spread these wonderful stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such cases abound in China, Europe and the United States. The history of &quot;A diamond is forever, a diamond will last forever&quot; is actually not that long ago, but this advertising slogan and the brand value behind it seem to have existed since ancient times. The untenable &quot;tradition&quot; can still win over consumers. The &quot;Eight Major Cuisines&quot; often claim to have thousands of years of history, but their true origins can often only be traced back to the mid-Qing Dynasty. However, this has not affected the reputation of the major cuisines. After all, food must be felt by the tip of the tongue, and consumers I don&#39;t care much about whether its history is true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this does not mean that the authenticity of &quot;time-honored brands&quot; is not important at all. &quot;Century-old stores&quot; that &quot;look fake at first glance&quot; will still make people see through their tricks, and then be suspected of false propaganda. In other words, only the quality of goods and services, consumer choices, and market judgment can enable a company and its brand to gain business credibility, consolidate the company&#39;s brand value, help companies spread their own brand stories, and let &quot;time-honored&quot; brands The brand stands. If a &quot;time-honored brand&quot; becomes a company&#39;s &quot;talisman&quot; and makes the company feel that it can &quot;win&quot; by relying on it, and even relies on the brand&#39;s long-standing mass base to not improve its business management and pay attention to the quality of its products and services, then the result will be in name only. I can&#39;t even keep my name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for a &quot;time-honored enterprise&quot;, the directory and trademark are only the surface, and long-lasting business reputation is the inside. A &quot;Chinese time-honored brand&quot; can maintain its business reputation not by a directory or a trademark, but by the sincere recognition of it as a traditional Chinese brand by consumers. The changes of the times will eliminate some &quot;time-honored brands&quot;, retain some time-honored brands, and also create a number of new &quot;time-honored brands&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奶茶按公斤炫！新疆人豪横起来连东北人都害怕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260575]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, milk tea in Xinjiang has become a hot topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some netizens posted pictures showing that when buying milk tea in Xinjiang, a cup starts at 1kg, triggering heated discussions among the public about the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The air in Xinjiang seems to be filled with baking powder, and food will &quot;expand&quot; several times once it arrives in Xinjiang. For example, 10 kinds of Xinjiang delicacies, including Xinjiang’s No. 1 Nang, Big Plate of Chicken, Noodle Soup for Ten Thousands of People, Largest Oil Cake Tower, and Rice Pilaf for Ten Thousand People, have all set Guinness World Records for their “bigness”. Compared with milk tea that starts at 2 pounds, It can be regarded as a &quot;baby meal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xinjiang&#39;s largest &quot;Aimai&quot; naan has a diameter of 40 to 50 centimeters. It requires 1 kilogram of flour to make. There are patterns stamped in the middle of the naan, and there are chopped onions or sesame seeds. . Nang with meat in a vat, pitted meat with naan, Xinjiang fried rice noodles with naan... Thousands of ways to eat naan, brewing the nostalgic memory of Xinjiang people when they were children waiting for their mother to break off a piece by the naan pit and feed it to their mouths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason why Xinjiang cuisine is so heavy is that Xinjiang people don’t have the concept of kilograms and liangs. What they call “one kilogram” is actually one kilogram. Because of the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang, they created their own weights and measures - there are 22 airports in one province of Xinjiang. In their eyes, distances within 1,000 kilometers are very close, and 1,000 kilometers is enough to travel from Beijing to Taiyuan and back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the large portions, the prices of Xinjiang dishes are also shocking in Northeast China, which is always known for its affordable prices. According to data from Dianping, the top ten restaurants in Urumqi, the capital of Xinjiang, only cost 74 yuan per person, which is lower than the average price in the capitals of the three eastern provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is large in area and heavy in weight, and the &quot;imagination&quot; of Xinjiang people is also very big. Many Xinjiang people&#39;s store names reveal a kind of simple humor. A series of store names such as &quot;Sexy Mommy&#39;s Postpartum Recovery Mother and Baby Center&quot; and &quot;Drag and Drive Over&quot; make people laugh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As an inland province, Xinjiang gives people the impression that it has nothing to do with water. Also because of its &quot;large&quot; territory, Xinjiang has almost all the country&#39;s specialties, such as Salmon production accounts for 15% of inland production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xinjiang also has great charm. In the first three quarters of this year, Xinjiang received 213.86 million tourists, a year-on-year increase of 77.73%. Tourists rushed to this western land, came with expectations, and left reluctantly as if they were heartbroken. Xinjiang’s specialty paper-skinned walnuts and Hotan jujubes are also on sale on Taobao. Even if they stay at home, they want to taste the taste of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;know&quot; will talk to you about the &quot;bigness&quot; of Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73461&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70268&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3fbf9d25ee.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3fbf9d25ee.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258185&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73462&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70269&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/14/5dc309c9d1.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5dc309c9d1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258186&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73463&quot; group-id= &quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70270&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/22777928eb.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/22777928eb.png&quot; data- key=&quot;258187&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73464&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70271&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b673748357.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom – 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b673748357.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258188&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img -id=&quot;73465&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70272&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3de07e6f6c.png&quot; img -title=&quot;custom – 5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/3de07e6f6c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258189&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73466&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70273&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f437541a92.png&quot; img-title=&quot;custom –6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f437541a92.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258190&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“永恒”的敌人：未了案横跨八十年，谁的“王洛宾”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260885]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng&#39;s &quot;In That Faraway Land&quot; &quot;Place&quot; manuscript. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng&#39;s manuscript of &quot;In That Distant Place&quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A stage play&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Only a few people realize that everything they enjoy at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A quarter of an hour before 7:30, outside the West Second Ring Road in Beijing, a group of children and parents gathered in front of the Erqi Theater. It was a cool evening in early September, and the new version of the red children&#39;s drama &quot;The Ballad of Soybean&quot; began its national tour here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some Chinese people are familiar with this story. In 1940, the Gansu Provincial Working Committee of the Communist Party of China was destroyed. Luo Lili, who was 8 months old, was arrested at the same time as his parents. After several twists and turns, he was imprisoned in Lanzhou Dashagou Prison, where he spent 6 years. Wang Luobin, who was also in prison, asked Luo Lili what the most delicious food in the world was. Luo Lili, who had never been exposed to the outside world, thought it was broad beans that he had eaten by chance. Wang Luobin composed the song &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; from this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A while after leaving the venue, the crowd suddenly surrounded an old man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The old man has appeared on CCTV 13 times. On TV, he is smart, wise, and tall. He is proud that he &quot;didn&#39;t make a single mistake&quot; when talking. &quot;, and sometimes, I even have to play and sing &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; on the stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the old man in front of him has droopy eye bags and a lot of white hair on his sparse head. He kept taking out performance tickets from the small shoulder bag on his chest, a total of 40 tickets, which belonged to &quot;old friends&quot; he had met through cooperation in the name of his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of these &quot;old friends&quot; reached the peak of their careers in the 1990s. They had their own programs in top media and were able to open solo concerts in the most central concert hall in Beijing. Concert, organize a commemorative concert for Wang Luobin in the most famous building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also officials from Zhuozhou, Hebei. This county-level city with a population of 650,000 has a 30-square-meter former residence of Wang Luobin and a Wang Luobin Chorus. The director of Zhuozhou Culture and Tourism Bureau and the director of the cultural center drove 60 kilometers to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is the youngest son of Wang Luobin, the &quot;King of Western Singers&quot;. Wang Luobin&#39;s ancestral home is in Zhuozhou, and a new Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is about to be renovated in an old factory in the north of the city as a local cultural landmark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin, who will appear on the stage in a quarter of an hour, is a &quot;prisoner&quot; who has to go through several political movements before he can be called the King of Singers in the future. , Prison Years, and Social Change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin&#39;s 83-year ups and downs often give playwrights a headache. He once participated in the Northwest Anti-Japanese War Theater Troupe with Xiao Jun, Seke and others. He was also highly appreciated by the warlord Ma Bufang and formed a children&#39;s theater troupe in Qinghai. During China&#39;s darkest period, he captured a hint of romanticism, and some of the songs he was most proud of in his life were born here, including &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At half past seven, &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; started. I got a chance to film Wang Haicheng, a documentary director who has been following him for more than ten years. The film is called &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the &quot;old friends&quot; in the audience, some people want to promote this drama to a bigger stage, and some people want to make a movie related to Wang Luobin. , two people respectively proposed to build a music school named after the king of singers in Hebei and Hainan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They all need to obtain authorization from Wang Haicheng. Only a few people realize that everything the son of the King of Songs enjoys at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng showed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio and video products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258760&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023 On the same day, in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng displayed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio-visual products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;SON OF THE SINGER&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Family has never been a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng has spent half his life defending his father&#39;s honor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin has two marriages, three sons and several loves. Among the three sons, the eldest went to Australia in the 1980s. The second child was a truck driver and died of illness. After surviving a period of history, the four fathers and sons now only have the third child left. Therefore, interviews, authorizations, rights protection, concerts, commemorations, and publications all fell on Wang Haicheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, for a long time, the identity of &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s son&quot; made Wang Haicheng breathless. When he was 8 months old, Wang Luobin was arrested, followed by a search of his home. A month later, his mother passed away in the hospital bed. Relatives in Beijing did not dare to have contact with the Wang family. After hearing about it, the fifth uncle in Zhuozhou drove a carriage all day and night from Beijing in the early winter in the north to bring the body back from Beijing and bury it in a wheat field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few years ago, Wang Haicheng tried to find his mother&#39;s tomb, but he could no longer find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Studying stopped in the second grade of junior high school. When it was time to go to the mountains and countryside, Wang Haicheng stayed on the farm for nine years because of Wang Luobin. When groups of educated young people returned to the city one after another, he also got a nickname: &quot;Cushionzi&quot;. This dialect refers to the last puppy out of a litter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Family is never a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention. Wang Haicheng wrote that the union between his father and his mother was due to the breakup of his father&#39;s previous relationship, so he wanted to take revenge on his life. Wang Luobin was born free. He went to the grassland, to the market, and even in prison, collecting folk songs. A producer who visited the singer&#39;s deeds mentioned a detail. In his later years, Wang Luobin rode a bicycle everywhere. When it got dark, he would lie on the road and fall asleep, and then go home the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin passed away in 1996. Wang Haicheng immediately joined the China Music Copyright Association and registered 207 musical works recorded, organized and created by Wang Luobin with the association. He became increasingly aware that his father had left a shining legacy. Since 2000, Wang Haicheng has successively published two biographies of Wang Luobin, a song sheet of Wang Luobin, invested in TV films, and a long narrative poem. Four exhibition halls have been created in Turpan, Xinjiang, Haibei, Qinghai, Baishui Ancient Town, Dabancheng, Xinjiang, and Liupan Mountain, Ningxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is difficult to say how father&#39;s love plays a subtle role in Wang Haicheng&#39;s life. In order to guard this heritage, he was like an ascetic, stationed in the Grape Valley of the Flame Mountain for 16 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first few years of the 21st century, the Turpan Wang Luobin Music and Art Museum in Grape Valley was the only temple to commemorate the king of singers. This building has an Ottoman-style white circular dome and 80 panels displaying the singer&#39;s life. Visitors came in the 40℃ high temperature. When they opened the door, they saw the sweaty son of the singer wearing a shirt with Wang Luobin&#39;s logo in front of him. There were biographies, song collections, tapes and records on the counter. When the operation of the art museum was most difficult, Wang Haicheng went to bring in strange stones from the Gobi Desert that looked like pork belly and English letters. This is the most popular commodity in Xinjiang’s tourism market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also set up an incense burner in front of his father&#39;s portrait - Wang Luobin converted to Buddhism in his later years. There was once a man who claimed to be a physicist and kowtowed three times directly to the portrait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng honed his speaking skills, pondered the details of his father&#39;s life, paid attention to his image, and never refused any opportunity to appear in the national media. The comment that moved him most came from an old man from Shandong: &quot;Wang Haicheng, you are the biggest filial son in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music was located in Putaogou, Turpan, Xinjiang Art Museum. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music Art Museum is located in Grape Valley, Turpan, Xinjiang. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salvage and Debate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changing one note, two notes, or a chorus counts as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 1990s, a modern storm swept through Urumqi: the most cutting-edge local popular music came from further west. Ethnic minorities hold weekly house music gatherings. Seven days and nights after the song &quot;Forgetting Love Water&quot; reached Urumqi, the shops in the Grand Bazaar would use rough-sounding speakers to play versions in other languages. The bars all over the street are full of singing bands. On the radio, the male host can talk endlessly about the Beatles, Tchaikovsky and Rachmaninoff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yibo, the director of &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;, was the popular host of the Urumqi Economic Radio program &quot;Music Leisure Island&quot; at the time. After more than 20 years, she believes that Urumqi at that time showed tolerance for all kinds of music and was the &quot;center of Asian music.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But there is no local singer&#39;s name in popular music. His limelight comes from outside Urumqi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin was rediscovered in the context of an era where order was brought to order. In May 1981, on an afternoon when the temperature suddenly soared to 33°C and the snow suddenly melted, in a five- to six-square-meter concierge at the Qianjin Theater, Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhao Quanzhang met Wang Luobin, who had just been released from prison. In Zhao Quanzhang&#39;s reminiscence article, this person who looked like Quasimodo in &quot;The Hunchback of Notre Dame&quot; was unemployed, had no household registration, and did not even have &quot;food and oil connections.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Quanzhang wrote the internal reference for Wang Luobin, and soon received instructions from Song Renqiong, then head of the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. Zhao Quanzhang once recalled that the work of bringing order to the country was not completely smooth at that time. The resolution of Wang Luobin&#39;s problem had an impact on Xinjiang and the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Openness was the theme of the 1980s. And for a musician who has experienced the war of resistance, prison, and rehabilitation, is there any symbol more suitable to glimpse a country&#39;s path of exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 1988, &quot;Eight Thousand Miles to the Clouds and the Moon&quot; hosted by Taiwanese artist Ling Feng went to Xinjiang to interview Wang Luobin. This was the first program from the other side to introduce China. TV programs about mainland China’s customs and customs. Then, Xia Jie, a female writer from Hong Kong, China, also came to visit and wrote three articles. Soon, Singapore, Australia, North America, and overseas Chinese had someone to pay attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The media calls him the King of Western Singers and enjoys special government subsidies. China Record Corporation awarded him the Golden Record Special Creation Award, and UNESCO awarded him the &quot;Promote &quot;Special Contribution Award for Cultural Exchange between East and West&quot;. But all medals are inferior to the gifts given by the people. In the era when the word &quot;fan&quot; only refers to fans, Wang Luobin&#39;s most proud example is, &quot;Chinese friends said that at least half of the two million Chinese in the United States can sing. &quot;In that distant place&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A more well-known story is that Sanmao, a female writer from Taiwan, China, moved directly into the home of the singer, and scandals abounded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Trouble is coming quietly. One day in 1993, Luo Dayou&#39;s agent called. Not long ago, Rolling Stone Records released the tape &quot;Love Song Anniversary - Luo Dayou and Wang Luobin&#39;s Great Collaboration of the Century&quot; without Wang Luobin&#39;s consent. The King of Songs was very angry and took Luo Dayou to court for infringement of his copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Greater controversy ensued. Someone revealed that Ling Feng paid 20,000 yuan to buy out ten of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs, including &quot;In That Faraway Place&quot;, &quot;The Girl from Dabancheng&quot;, &quot;Mayila&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The music issue soon turned into a political issue. Someone asked, can Wang Luobin sell folk songs that belong to the people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A major discussion that lasted for more than a year began. In June 1994, &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine began to discuss the copyright issue of Wang Luobin&#39;s folk songs. Dai Penghai, an associate researcher at the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, published two articles criticizing the news media for hyping up Wang Luobin, and also accused Wang Luobin of &quot;selling out the people&#39;s sovereignty and interests in national music culture.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also people who support Wang Luobin. Liu Zaisheng, a professor at the Music Department of Shandong Normal University, pointed out that “collecting brotherly ethnic songs in different languages ​​is a more complex and difficult task, and the translation and dubbing of lyrics often plays a key role in success or failure.” And “if we combine the When the lyrics are analyzed together, it is not difficult to find that they have formed Wang Luobin&#39;s unique creative style that is lyrical, colloquial, and popular.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another background to the great discussion is that during China&#39;s &quot;resumption of customs&quot; negotiations, the Copyright Law was promulgated in 1991, which stipulates that &quot;adaptation, translation, The copyright of works resulting from the annotation and arrangement of existing works shall be enjoyed by the person who adapted, translated, annotated and arranged them.&quot; In other words, if Wang Luobin &quot;adapts, translates, annotates, and organizes&quot; folk songs, the copyright of the new songs belongs to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But, does changing one note, two notes, or a chorus count as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 5 of that year, a symposium attended by more than thirty people was held in Beijing, including musicologists, composers, and legal professionals. people and journalists. The person presiding over the meeting was Qiao Jianzhong, then director of the Music Research Institute of the China Academy of Arts. He later recalled in an article that this symposium was actually an &quot;absent criticism&quot; against Wang Luobin, which was very explosive. However, the meeting finally reached a consensus that Wang Luobin had worked hard in recording, translating, editing, and adapting folk songs, but the rights he enjoyed needed to be quantitatively analyzed before the rights could be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The eighty-year-old singer was very hurt and left the stage to participate in the debate in person several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the death of Wang Luobin in 1996, the big discussion did not continue. But this discussion could have clarified some fundamental issues, such as the quantitative standards for adaptation and the copyright of folk songs. In that era, Wang Luobin was not the only one who encountered similar problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Shanghai, a young man who was writing &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was also troubled by this problem. In the process of sorting out Xian Xinghai&#39;s works, Wu Yuebei, a top student in the composition department of the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, checked and filled in the original scores. Some melodies that he thought were not harmonious even needed to be changed. When Xian Xinghai&#39;s descendants heard about Wang Luobin&#39;s dispute, they worriedly asked, if the original score was adjusted, would the copyright belong to him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After consulting the leaders of the Ministry of Culture at the time, &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was finally processed as follows: the works with major changes were also included in the revised original works. version, as well as a more substantial adapted version. For revised or revised editions, the name of the reviser will be marked as a footnote at the end of the work, but no copyright will be generated. The edited version will have a copyright page marked with the name of the organizer, who owns the rights to the content compiled by him in the new version, but not the rights to the original work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This young man majoring in composition has no way of knowing that after more than 20 years, he may end the discussion about the copyright of the singer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Carpet rights protection&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;His opponents include video city vendors, publishing houses, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new century is coming, and the law has become a modern weapon to protect rights and interests. Wang Haicheng suddenly discovered that everything his father left behind could be easily taken away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, China was in the midst of a heat wave to achieve modernization through a market economy. The &quot;resumption of customs&quot; turned into &quot;joining the WTO&quot;, a stable and international The integrated legal system is gradually improving. Intellectual property rights are a focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2002, Wang Luobin&#39;s adaptation of &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was sued by the family of a deceased musician for copyright infringement. The family members believe that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; is not a folk song, but a song composed by the late musician, originally titled &quot;How Beautiful My Garden is.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The family did not sue Wang Haicheng directly, but first sued an audio-visual company in Guangzhou. The CD published by the company labeled &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; as a folk song. The court found that the song was composed by the late musician. Afterwards, the family took this judgment and sued Wang Haicheng, claiming 230,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng said that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was written by his father in 1969 while serving a sentence. At that time, a young man was unjustly imprisoned, and his new wife died. The young man stopped cutting his hair and shaving. Wang Luobin felt inspired and adapted &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; based on an Ili folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A friend in Yili told Wang Haicheng that the original version of this ancient folk song can be found in the local archives. But before he was about to leave, the friend said that the information was missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2004, the court of first instance sentenced Wang Haicheng to pay compensation of 237,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the appeal, Wang Haicheng and his lawyer began to think about how to collect evidence. In October 2005, he and his lawyer pretended to be collectors from Beijing and spent 4,600 yuan to buy a small video camera. After arriving in Yili, they arranged to grab mutton and invited local music teachers and old people who could sing folk songs for interviews. At first, they did not reveal their interest in &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and started talking about Ili folk songs. The cameras are always working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the conversation was almost over, Wang Haicheng turned to &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and asked if there was an original folk song version of this song. Everyone said yes, and everyone hummed a line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when they reveal their identities, very few people are willing to testify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After hitting a wall one after another, they finally found three old people willing to testify. I also met an &quot;Avanti&quot; (meaning &quot;teacher&quot;) named Ishamuddin, who said that the original song had probably been circulated for two hundred years, and he also knew that a lawsuit was ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, Wang Haicheng thought that if he lost the lawsuit, &quot;things would develop like dominoes.&quot; Dozens of publishers had published this song Society will also be in crisis. Even if he travels to Hainan, he will pray with Mazu, hoping that Mazu can help him, the son of the king of singers, who is in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On May 8, 2006, the Xinjiang High Court made a judgment that the two songs each enjoyed property rights in copyright. In Wang Haicheng&#39;s words, &quot;Both songs come from folk songs, and they are in a parallel relationship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At almost the same time, Wang Haicheng launched a blanket rights protection campaign that lasted for several years. For the sake of copyright, he fought against pirated CDs, KTV bosses, and singers who randomly covered his father&#39;s works. His opponents include audio-visual city vendors, publishers, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was in 2004 when he was ordered to pay 237,000 yuan in compensation that Wang Haicheng received an unfamiliar phone call. The other party introduced himself like this: Ju Yonghe, a native of Jiangsu, a lawyer in Beijing, and a loyal fan of Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When they finally met a year later, Wang Haicheng was deeply impressed by his &quot;uprightness and non-joking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He said that he was concerned that there were many publications infringing Wang Luobin&#39;s rights on the market, and he especially wanted to help protect his rights.&quot; Wang Haicheng was &quot;a little nervous financially at the time, and he was also weighing Should I file a lawsuit?&quot; Lawyer Ju dispelled his concerns: He would bear the cost of the lawsuit. If he lost the lawsuit, he would not ask Wang Haicheng for money. If he won, he would pay half of it after deducting travel expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This may be a more subtle way, and it also uses legal weapons to confirm again and again that Wang Luobin owns the copyright to a certain song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2005, Lawyer Ju has continued to make efforts. He went to the audio and video market and Xinhua Bookstore, walked around, saw the allegedly infringing publications, bought them, issued invoices, and sued. &quot;All those audio and video publishers came to me to ask for authorization. They can also use high-definition pictures of Wang Luobin on the covers of their publications. I also provided the introduction of Wang Luobin on the inside pages. It is more accurate and the text is smoother.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin became an invasive iconic icon. Around 2010, lawyers turned to KTV, and in the words of the time, it was &quot;sweeping&quot;. KTV&#39;s infringement made Wang Haicheng even more intolerable. The picture with &quot;in that distant place&quot; is Hainan beach and bikini beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Based on the Yangtze River Delta, the lawyer has stepped up step by step. In his eyes, &quot;the judicial environment of the Yangtze River Delta was relatively good at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The victory is as big as the snowball. To some people in the music industry, even if they did not belong to him before, they now belong to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to Wang Haicheng, this round of economic income is not as much as people imagine. &quot;. But he was very happy, and felt that the battle was broken, &quot;hitting those pirated KTV quietly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He gave himself an indestructible significance: maintaining his father&#39;s eternal and immortal status in the history of Chinese music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But this blanket-type rights defended abruptly in 2013, and Wang Haicheng was put on a hug. After mediation of the Supreme Law, Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants reached an agreement: Some previous lawsuits were withdrawn, &quot;those who could not withdraw the lawsuit should take the initiative to notify the acceptance authority to add Wang Haiyan (big brother) and Wang Haixing (second brother) as the joint litigant. The lawsuit shall be made by the three people (Wang Haiyan, Wang Haixing, Wang Haicheng). &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lawyer appeared again, waiting for 6 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 10, 2023, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Lazhou, Hebei, where the Wang Luobin Music Memorial is planning. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture)&quot; SRC = &quot;HTTP: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7F942B41F0.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot;//images.infzm. COM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/19/7F942B41F0.JPG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 258763 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; 2023 On September 10, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Luzhou, Hebei, where Wang Luobin Music Memorial is planning. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Singing Song &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai , Stkaiti; &quot;>; On this night of the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked the silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song that is also yours? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin left a world of water grass, there are youthful birds, Yijiang water, long braid Daban City girl, and the most the most It is important, no matter when, you must praise the courage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The world left by the father, Wang Haicheng spent more than 20 years, marking the birth and origin of each symbol, youthful birds and long braids. The girl of Sakura City was born in 1938, and Alamu Khan did not appear until May 1944. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One reason is that Wang Luobin does not sign much. He edited a &quot;Northwest Singing&quot; related to the Anti -Japanese War, and the background was printed with &quot;the Gansu people&#39;s anti -enemy aid will be compiled.&quot; Wang Luobin said in his own manuscript, &quot;I think this job is the obligation of a citizen.&quot; In special years, many of his songs were not signed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Hai has become a father&#39;s creation of three biography. Among them, it is the creative story of pursuing his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But for the first time he heard his father about his creative motivation, it was 1974. One day, the father and son came to the friend&#39;s house to celebrate the full moon for the children. With the wine blended by alcohol, everyone coaxed and let Wang Haicheng sing. He took the guitar, sang a &quot;Man Li&quot;, and talked about the source of the song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There was a pair of lovers on the Mongolian grassland. During the Anti-Japanese War, the man signed up for the army to fight. The woman heard that the man was sacrificed in the rear. I came back after the man&#39;s fight. When I heard that the fiancee died, she ran to the cemetery and sang the song in front of her tomb. Suddenly, the woman stood out from behind the grave again. &quot;Wang Haicheng recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin, who is no longer loves speaking, sulk a bite: &quot;It&#39;s interesting today, my son sang Lao Tzu&#39;s song, but I don’t know that this song is Lao Tzu. Write. &quot;It was a yellow song, criticizing it in the 1950s, reaching its peak in the 1950s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; More stories are collected during the period when they temporarily live in the second brother&#39;s family. Father and son slept with a small room with two beds on the left and right, and a window in the middle. During the day, Wang Luobin lifted the bed and copied the bedboard as a table. In the evening, the mosquito couldn&#39;t sleep. On such a night of the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked the silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song for you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But this experience will not be helpful until 30 years later, Wang Haicheng&#39;s biography of his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the death of the father, the difficulty of finding songs became more difficult. Sometimes song problems were legal issues, and sometimes even political issues. Only the origin of a song does not require Wang Haicheng to find, that is, &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, the &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; of the Western Song King. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1939, Wang Luobin followed the director Zheng Junli to the Qinghai to shoot the movie &quot;Long Live Nation&quot;. Do a helper. When catching the sheep, Wang Luobin accidentally pumped a whip on the horse&#39;s buttocks, Zhuima on the horse shook the whip and gently hit Wang Luobin&#39;s body. So, there was the plot in the lyrics: &quot;I would like to make a lamb/I followed her/I would like to hit me with a leather whip every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The king himself told the media too many times. But maybe it is too much, so that one day in the future, some people who are interested start to compare the time, place and characters of each story, and find that it is difficult to fulfill the flaws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin also told the actor Ma Yue. In his early years, the actor won the second prize of the Blogo Singing Fa in the Qing Ge Charity. After holding a personal concert at the Beijing Opera House, after singing &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, a goat Hu Hu found him and said, &quot;Ma Yue, you look like when you are young.&quot; Second The saying is, &quot;You sing my singing accurately.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; That was a big discussion in 1994. The King of Song pointed out his two errors, one of which was the wrong tune. &quot;I am in prison, you sing my song outside. Now I sing back the song back, everyone said that I sang the wrong, I I can&#39;t change it anymore. &quot;Many people don&#39;t know, the&quot; In the Far Far &quot;, which is widely sung, is indeed not a version of Wang Luobin. His version, the score is now engraved on his tombstone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the two met twice, the song king added the process of spreading this song. He said, &quot;There are a lot of people who sung in the front of the front line. Why? Because each Anti -Japanese soldiers have a good girl.&quot; The young man who was rising in his career realized that Wang Luobin &quot;all the works grew from the soil of the nation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /19/32F0379936.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1516 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/32F0379936.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258764 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Okay, let&#39;s play to the end&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; The courier in the community to send the court courier every day, very wondering. What did this family commit? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The second day after the performance of &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot;, a student of Wang Luobin invited Wang Haicheng. The dishes were overwhelmed, and she asked carefully whether she needed help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The worry of the old friend is not without any reason. Wang Haicheng&#39;s second round of rights launched in 2019 has just encountered a defeat. In June 2023, the final judgment of the Beijing Intellectual Property Court determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants no longer enjoyed the copyright of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons&quot; and &quot;Under Silver Moonlight&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 9 months ago, the Yangzhou Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jiangsu Province had identified Wang Luobin as the copyright owner of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unlike the abnormual rights protection ten years ago, most of the defendants are professional musicians and publishers. In the list, the national first -class composer Gong Yaonian, Hu Tingjiang, deputy director of the composition department of the Chinese Conservatory of Music, and the People&#39;s Music Publishing House were listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The issues of arguments are mainly concentrated. Is the song presented in the publications of these composers copy or adapted from Wang Luobin&#39;s version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For example, the reason why Gong Yaonian was sued was that he had previously compiled a batch of folk song piano songs from circulating folk songs, named &quot;Somson&#39;s folk songs&quot; &quot;Gong Yaonian &quot;Arrangement&quot;. This has aroused the dissatisfaction of Wang Haicheng. In his opinion, the nine capitals including &quot;The Far Far&quot; belong to Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;A inappropriate metaphor proposed by the other party is the relationship between grandpa and grandson. &quot;Li Yan, deputy director of the editor -in -chief of the People&#39;s Music Publishing House, said,&quot; But in the words of the other party in court, &#39;Wang Luobin is grandfather, all of you are grandson&#39;. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text -rign: left; &quot;>; The defendants also questioned accordingly, thinking that some of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs did not go through&quot; adaptation &quot;at all, or even&quot; copied &quot;the creation of others directly. The family of one of the defendants also found that the authenticity of the creative stories written by Wang Haicheng and the creative story of the King of Songs is yet to be questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The defendant&#39;s family is Wu Yuebei, who participated in the &quot;Complete Works of Xinghai&quot; more than 20 years ago. He is now a professor at the School of Music and a doctoral tutor in the composition direction. The defendant Gong Yaonian was his father -in -law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The second round of rights are turbulent. At the beginning, the defendants each fought. Hu Tingjiang, the earliest prosecution, adapted a &quot;Marrayam&quot;. In just this song, the lawyer of the residence sued him nearly a hundred times in many courts across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Hu Tingjiang recalled that he had been prosecuted, and there were still many puzzles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Around 2017, Wang Haicheng suddenly added Hu Tingjiang WeChat to inform him of the adaptation of &quot;May&quot; from Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;May&quot;, and he needs to get his own. Authorization. Hu Tingjiang replied to respect Mr. Wang Luobin, but &quot;Marra&quot; was not created by Wang Luobin, but a well -known Kazakh folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Once, Wang Haicheng sent a message and praised Hu Tingjiang&#39;s adaptation very successful. He hoped that he would continue to work hard and adapt a few more Wang Luobin&#39;s works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In June 2017, Wang Haicheng sent another solo concert list of Changji College, which was printed with the words &quot;Young Dance&quot; Hu Tingjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It didn&#39;t take long for him to be prosecuted. The subpoena was sent from all over the country, and Hu Tingjiang remembered that the courier in the community was sent to the court courier every day, and he was very puzzled, &quot;What did this family commit?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until a trial live broadcast, Hu Tingjiang, who was fighting alone, learned that Gong Yaonian was also prosecuted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Soon, these prosecution professors, musicians, and publishers formed an alliance of interoperability information. There are 43 people in the &quot;Wang Luobin Copywriter Case, and there are more than a dozen publishing houses in the&quot; Music Publishing Unite &quot;. Different from those KTV and audiovisual companies that have been sued by the son of the king of the song, the people in the &quot;alliance&quot; uphold such beliefs: even if they are only claimed with 10,000 yuan, they must make the reason clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the afternoon of April 20, 2023, 29 years after the discussion was launched, another symposium was held at the People&#39;s Music Publishing House called &quot;National Folk Music Work Protection -Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants of the Western Folk Song Copyright Dispute Case &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On this day, Li Yan once doubted that some publishers far away from Shanghai and Hunan would send representatives to this meeting with only half a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On that day, she was surprised to find that more than thirty publishing houses, many of them were present in person. At the meeting, some people admitted that they did hesitate to the court&#39;s subpoena before: (Wang Haicheng) It costs 10,000 yuan a song to bargain with him, and 5,000 can be reconciled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Someone later proposed that it was not money. Finally, everyone formed a consistent opinion, okay, let&#39;s go to the end.&quot; Li Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another consensus reached by the conference is that &quot;the legislative level should be introduced as soon as possible&quot; to &quot;realize the law can be rely on, avoid the same case in the judicial practice, &quot;Different judgment&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, the original provisions of the copyright law introduced in 1991 that &quot;the copyright protection measures of folk literature and art works are separately stipulated by the State Council.&quot; But there is no following. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The most active Hu Tingjiang, northern Wu Yue, etc., turned the libraries of the Central Conservatory of Music, the Chinese Academy of Music and the China Institute of Music, and even Also find original information from the Moscow Library of Kazakhstan and the Moscow Library in Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After more than three years of searching and research, Wu Yue north now believes that he can complete the tasks that the teachers have not completed many years ago and put Wang Luobin down the altar . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At the end of September 2023, I met Wu Yue in a community near Wanshou Park, Beijing. He has a majestic national face, and he has a tired elegance when he walks. Beside a piano, he prepared a chair and a laptop for me, which contained evidence he collected. Earlier, he had to bring two things, a Bluetooth speaker, and a luggage full of physical evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This composer made me stare at the computer screen carefully. Then, he closed his eyes and repeated everything he had investigated in the past 4 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 15, 2023, Beijing, Wu Yue north shows the evidence he collected in the computer. Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/c8081ce523.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com// CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/19/C8081ce523.jpg &quot;Data-key =&quot; 258765 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; September 2023 On the 15th, Beijing, Wu Yue north showed the evidence he collected in the computer. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body style _GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Speaking of&quot; In the Far Place &quot;, the person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On March 31, 1946, a student society named Shan Ge Club was announced at the National Music Institute of Qingmuguan in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Shange is the product of the student movement. Earlier, the authorities planned to cancel the subsidies of the student&#39;s consumption of coal and were opposed by the students. After the &quot;Coal Incident&quot;, students began to seek autonomy in a school in the subtropical canyon. At the same time, they couldn&#39;t wait to find some deeper things from the soil of folk songs from the soil of folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, the situation was unknown, but this group of music students began to worry more eternal issues. In the first series of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot; they printed, there is such a wish: &quot;After analyzing these folk songs, the problems that have not been paid attention to in Western composition can be produced. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; There was no way to pick the style at the time. According to a memories article by Xie Gongcheng, the first series of&quot; Chinese Folk Song &quot;was from&quot; New Music &quot; Magazine, Yan&#39;an&#39;s small singing book, Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; and private relationships, more than a hundred national songs collected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; was published in Chongqing in 1942. At the end of 1939, Wang Luobin gave the manuscript to the reporter Zhang Xiluo, a reporter from Chongqing in Xining to publish it, and Zhang Xiluo found the opportunity until he opened the Dagong Bookstore. The collection of the Capital Library shows that the song collection contains 17 songs, and there is no &quot;in the distant place&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; During the collection of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot;, the students of the piano group were responsible for the accompaniment, and the vocal group was responsible for the singing. There are two teachers joining, namely the professor of the composer and the director of the teaching affairs, Chen Tianhe, and the professor and director of the composition department, Jiang Dingxian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History has a bifurcation here. Although Volkswagen regards Wang Luobin as the benchmark of the western folk songs, the college faction has also paid attention to Wang Luobin, but in the music education of professional colleges, the history of the folk song system has begun to start with the &quot;folk song movement&quot; of the Shan Song Club. When it comes to &quot;Alamu Khan&quot;, they will think of Xie Gongcheng&#39;s four chorus adapted in 1945; when it comes to &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, he will think of Jiang Dingxian; and when it comes to the &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; of the Song King, The person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There is only one reason. The accompaniment of this song popular version is equipped with Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei looks for clues from Wang Luobin&#39;s own words. &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine published an article &quot;History is fair&quot; written by Wang Luobin in 1994, which mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; can allow his colleagues, a lady named Ug Huiying to testify as a testimony. &quot;It can not only prove that this song was written by me, but also proved that this song should have copyright.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Ugly Huiying at the time was the chairman of the Taipei Music Copyright Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei found the &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; compiled by Ugly Huiying in 1967. A total of 88 songs, 84 of which are edited by Ugly Huiying, and &quot;in the distant place&quot; is marked as Chen Tianhe arranged. Interestingly, the version of Chen Tianhe is currently a small version, and it is engraved with the tombstone of Wang Luobin, which is a big version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1994, Ugly Huiying presented a &quot;Selection of the Chinese National Ballad&quot; by her in 1982 by her in 1982. Nothing was marked with her name. As for &quot;In the Far&quot;, only &quot;Qinghai Folk Songs&quot; are written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These two versions seem to contradict each other. From the north of Wu Yue, two key issues are explained. First of all, there is no version of Wang Luobin published by Ug Huiying. Secondly, according to the analysis of Wu Yuebei, the reason why the second version has the names of ugly Huiying and Chen Tianhe, it is that the version of the &quot;removed &#39;part&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This is actually an old topic in the 1990s discussion. What exactly is the difference between &quot;adaptation, sorting&quot; and &quot;notes&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the north of Wu Yue, the arrangement is on the basis of the original work. It simplifies the complicated works by increasing or decreased and deleted. The work, plus his own play, becomes a readable vernacular work. The adaptation must be incremental, for example, a folk song is changed to a symphony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; And, folk songs have its particularity. The folk song is a song created by the public. The words and songs have been continuously polished and deformed by countless people. According to different times and place, different versions will be generated. Wu Yuebei also gives an example, &quot;You change the&quot; In front of the bed, the moonlight &quot;to the&quot; In front of the window, the moonlight &quot;, are you going to replace Li Bai?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He found a &quot;Selection of Chinese People&#39;s Songs&quot; published by Shan Ge Society in 1946, which selected a small version of &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, which stated that &quot;Chen Tianhe is accompanied by accompaniment&quot;. According to the survey of Wu Yue, a female student in Qinghai sang to Chen Tianhe in 1945, and the latter spent the piano song for this. Wang Luobin&#39;s version was officially published in 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. Wang Luobin knew that the existence of a small version was also attached to the book, but he explained that this was the result of the female student who went to school in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In some circulating statements, the female student was Ugly Huiying, who graduated from Chongqing National Music Institute in 1947. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The memoir called &quot;Walking through the Memory Star&quot; also inadvertently mentioned Ugly Huiying and Wang Luobin. This book was written by Luo Wenzhi, the vice president of the former Ningxia Huangpu Military Academy Association, and wrote his son Luo Jiyuan in 2010. It is mentioned that in August 1993, Luo Wenzhi met with Tang Ying Ugly Huiying in Beijing. During the chat, Ug Huiying said that in 1993, Wang Luobin reunited with her in Taipei, and learned that she had spread her &quot;The Far Far&quot;, &quot;Youth Dance&quot; and &quot;Daban City Girl in Dazya City&quot; in Qinghai for many years. Folk songs are very emotional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Pearl on the crown&quot;. According to Liang Maochun, a professor at the Central Conservatory of Music, in 1940, a musical named &quot;Flower of the Desert&quot; was staged in Xining. The &quot;New Music&quot; magazine published in November 1942 reported the matter. The &quot;Songlin&quot; magazine published in December of the following year records the complete script and music of the play. In the preface of &quot;The Song of Desert&quot;, Wang Luobin mentioned that the episodes used in the play are all Kazakh people&#39;s songs, with new words. &quot;I Want to Be a Shepherd&quot;, which is the predecessor of &quot;The Far Far&quot;, appeared in the first act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History meets the narrow road here, but as the parties leave the world one by one, some statements have been difficult to verify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2023, the opinion of the lawyer is that the signature on any or several &quot;earliest publications&quot; cannot prove that the signature is 80 80 Author of a certain song a year ago. He also made an example: &quot;A watch on a person&#39;s wrist, and life experience tells us that the person wearing a watch is the owner of the watch, and the person who does not need to wear a watch provides any other evidence to prove it. And their descendants have claimed their rights, exercise their rights, and defend their rights for songs such as &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons&quot;, &quot;Mayera&quot;. No one else has proposed rights proposal in the past 40 years. Anti-evidence. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; north of Wu Yue, why did the students of the music department that year become the main force of the altar of the king of La Ge more than 20 years later? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The reason is that his understanding of Wang Luobin has begun since the 1980s. In the 1990s, many friends and teachers, including Dai Penghai and Xie Gong, had participated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One more important reason may be that Wu Yuebei is responsible for a national folk song inheritance project. Wang Haicheng&#39;s prosecution will make him unusual difficult. Do you want to include folk songs related to Wang Luobin? Will there be legal risks after inclusion? What should I do if similar people come out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Not long ago, some editors asked Li Yan and wanted to use western folk songs to deal with it? &quot;I suggest him that the case has not been finalized yet, so you don&#39;t need it.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;The 1947&quot; Chinese Song Selected &quot;by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;(Jiang Dingxian&quot;. Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 258766 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The 1947 version of&quot; Selected Chinese Songs &quot;found by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Smoke disappear &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Initially, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At least one thing, Wu Yuebei and Wang Haicheng have a rare consensus. They all found that society pays attention to new series of lawsuits. Not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until today, there are still Wang Luobin&#39;s memorials in Pakistan, Hubei, Baishui Ancient Town, and Urumqi. Member of the CPPCC also hopes that all children in Puzhou will sing Wang Luobin&#39;s song. In early September 2023, at a lecture at the Three Gorges University, Wu Yuebei mentioned this protracted copyright dispute, but the audience at the scene did not know who Wang Luobin was except the teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Today, the person who knows the western song king most lives in a 26-storey commercial house in the north of Lazhou. This is a residence purchased after Wang Haicheng was moved by the enthusiasm of Lizhou officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Most of the time, Wang Haicheng is a long-awaited and strictly restricted old man. Once, he took me to the old factory in Puzhou to check the construction progress of the Wang Luobin Music Art Museum. He indirectly reached a call, and the other party wanted to buy Wang Luobin&#39;s manuscript. He was full of &quot;good&quot;, hung up the phone, and made a look at me. &quot;I asked others to know that Wang Luobin&#39;s son sells manuscripts, which is incredible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is easy to be excited, especially when it comes to these difficult and from the academic opponent, he will doubt the motivation of the opponent and admire their cunning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is difficult to confirm whether Wang Haicheng understands these complaints from the professional music circle. In this commercial house, he continued to move out of his published Wang Luobin&#39;s work and several thick Xinjiang folk songs, and repeatedly emphasized that the change of a note and a word is the result of his father&#39;s exhaustion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Uyghur is a multi-syllable, Chinese is a single syllable, and the Han people say that good is &#39;good&#39;, Uyghur said that a good one is&quot; To sing the Chinese folk songs in Chinese, it must be a big surgery for it. &quot;Wang Haicheng can also give more examples. For example,&quot; Alamu Khan &quot;is adapted to the Children&#39;s Troupe of Qinghai, so it has been added for half a rest, which is convenient for convenience Children breathe when singing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The 72-year-old man still needs to answer the &quot;love&quot; between his father and Sanmao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;I have seen it, eating at my house, my wife gave Sanmao noodles, eaten two meals, and told me to talk to me when I have come, I have been here for several days. Today this day is the most comfortable &#39;. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; I understand her, there is a kind of &quot; Feeling, she wants to integrate into her home, and she wants to live with my father. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Once valid. His &quot;My Father Wang Luobin&quot; Douban score is 7.9, and many people have burst into tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the Library of Laizhou, the photos of Sanmao were placed on a desk that was used by Wang Luobin, which was moved from Xinjiang. Wrapped wrapped, Wang Haicheng said that all of this was arranged according to Wang Luobin&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But in the photos of Wang Luobin and desk he showed afterwards, there were no three-hairy photo on the table. He also explained that the photo was actually placed on the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now, some stories are invalid. The Tianjin High Court determined that the &quot;Mayera&quot; adapted from Hu Tingjiang was not infringed; during the trial of Hu Tingjiang&#39;s version of &quot;Youth Dance&quot; case, the Hubei High Court directly stated in a 34 -page judgment: If Wang Haicheng and others have the demands of rights, then then It is tantamount to &quot;belonging to the right of primitive folk songs.&quot; The Hubei High Court also ordered a series of &quot;risks&quot; after litigation: Once supported rights protection, Wang Haicheng and others can be based on Wang Luobin&#39;s first work, and arbitrarily initiate lawsuits in other homologous works in the subsequent subsequent. This is undoubtedly &quot;harmful to the right to the original folk song.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another reason is that the world left by his father, Wang Haicheng spent half a lifetime and continued to construct. Those who accused Wang Luobin of no copyright may disappear all this smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is the child who has won Wang Luobin from the three brothers. So far, he will play the piano every day and play with the guitar. If anyone says he and Wang Luobin are very Like, he will show a sincere smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin did have a dream to let his songs sing for 500 years. So far, the longest Chinese songs are said to be &quot;Jasmine&quot;, which has been circulating for nearly 400 years. In 1794, I finally met the Macanloni Mission of the Emperor Qianlong, ready to return to Britain from Guangzhou. Here, the group secretary John Baro heard the Guangzhou dialect version of &quot;Jasmine&quot;. He was in &quot;China Travel&quot; The song was recorded with Roman Pinyin and translated lyrics, becoming the earliest record in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, who is pushing the eternal universe of the western song king and let it slide into the abyss of forgotten? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Perhaps, all this has nothing to do with the law. All cultural idols will disappear in time. At first, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. Idols may be mentioned briefly at a certain moment and a certain period -but this is only accidental. In the end, they will sink into the long fog again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; How many people remember, this year is the 80th anniversary of the birthday of Sanmao? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/ Figure) &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258767&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style: #999999; text- Align: Center; &quot;>; September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; What is it if it is not a folk song? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; After many inquiries, he finally found &quot;Dada and He The author of Maria and &quot;Marray&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A sunny and kind Beijing autumn afternoon in the afternoon, I saw Du Yaxiong, who edited 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. He is now Chinese music. Professor of the Department of Music of the College. He just discharged from the hospital, his face was rosy, his hair was silver, and he often made a strong laughter. In the afternoon of the same day, a male tweeter came to visit and heard about Wang Luobin. He talked: &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s songs dare not touch, and we (units) have also defended.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left ; &quot;>; In the summer of 1982, Du Yaxiong was still a young man. He lived in Wang Luobin&#39;s house to help him organize the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recalling the summer of forty years ago, Du Yaxiong has a feeling of vagueness. Wang Luobin did not understand the origin of his song. &quot;After all, he is not engaged in us. This major (ethnic music), we know whether a song belongs to a folk song or a song, which is very clear. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; National music began in 1959. Dutch musicians, who have been dispatched by Java for 15 years, renamed the 3rd edition of his book &quot;Music&quot; to &quot;National Music Science&quot;, which created this discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong that the song &quot;Dadal and Maria&quot; was sang by a Kazakh old lady in Xining, Qinghai around 1940. Including &quot;Maura&quot;, Wang Luobin believes that these are folk songs, but Du Yaxiong does not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;People who have studied Kazakhson folk songs can be seen that these are not folk songs. Why? Kazakh folk songs have specific rhythm, a song divides the main song and chorus song In the two parts, the lyrics of the main song must be 11 syllables, their combinations can be 344, 443, 434. Each combination is a sound step. &quot;Du Yaxiong said,&quot; There is still a rule, that is, the combination The lyrics and songs are consistent, and a phrase of the Kazakh folk song has ended, but the word has not been sang, and the last voice of the first sentence should be placed in the second music. The first sound of the last lyrics in the last music festival. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Du Yaxiong speculates that this way of presenting this music is likely to come from the daily life of the Kazakh people. Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There is a swap mechanism for nomadic peoples. Young people will not stay in the tent and go sheep. , Riding the horse, 200 meters away from the tent, first &#39;ah 呺 —&#39; shouting, someone in the tent, he will come out to tie the dog, and use &quot;Ah 呺 —&quot; to respond to you. &quot;This Scholars who studied the history of music have added a naughty supplement, &quot;but I am not necessarily right.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; What if it is not a folk song? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong understands Kazakh. After inquiring from many parties, he finally found the author of &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot; and &quot;May&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the first song is Mary Jagel (1887-1950), born in Acko Mora, Kazakhstan, is Kazakhstan. Stan people artist. Du Yaxiong inferred that she created the song around 1903. This song has been widely circulated in Kazakhstan, once the theme of many music works. Judging from Wang Luobin&#39;s record, at the latest in the early 1930s, this song was introduced to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the second song is Marrara Shammustinovova (1890-1927), Professor Ah Hedi, Aramutu Conservatory of Music McDIS Jubanov introduced this person in the book &quot;The Nightingale of the Times&quot; and said that the song was the author&#39;s &quot;self -portrait&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong also verified &quot;Girl in Daban City&quot;. Cut the rhythm. He was curious why Wang Luobin&#39;s version was not like this. Wang Luobin&#39;s saying was that the driver he heard was singing -not Wang Haicheng said, but the active version of the version suitable for the Han people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Regarding &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong: &quot;It was recorded in Jiuquan Dongguan in 1939. The lyrics were original, not me. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; As for the&quot; pearl on the crown &quot;, Du Yaxiong does not think that the popular version is the result of&quot; tuning &quot;, but a version of the male cavity, using&quot; Anti -tuning &quot;method creates a female cavity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Therefore, in the 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;, Du Yaxiong divided the songs into two parts, the first part was the folk song, the second part was Wang Luobin&#39;s of Creation, and these songs are in the first part. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, Du Yaxiong also affirmed the contribution of Wang Luobin&#39;s translation of ethnic minorities. Translated into Chinese, it is too difficult, translation is to see Yada. Of course, some things are not right with the original, he is a half -compiled and half translation. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, Wang Haicheng still won part of the victory in the final judgment of the Beijing Intellectual Property Court. The court determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants continued to enjoy the copyright of &quot;Daban City Girl&quot;, &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot;, &quot;Mayra&quot;, and &quot;in that distant place&quot;; for &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, he enjoys lyrics copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But Wang Haicheng still determined that someone is accelerating the disappearance. Not long ago, when Beijing Normal University produced the musical &quot;The Ballad of the Past&quot;, some people proposed that &quot;in the distant place&quot; may be controversial. The school conveyed was reported by a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The lawyer&#39;s name is Dong Xiaoyue, the granddaughter of Chen Tianhe. She also has a persistent life. When holding a chorus competition in high school, some students mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; belongs to Wang Luobin, and she will scratch others. Chen Tianhe died in 1955. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Dong Xiaoyue after the 80s became a reporter and book editor, but from time to time, she held her. Around 2010, she began to find the &quot;Selection of Chinese Songs&quot; from the major libraries in Beijing. The earliest version of this book has only two volumes in China. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is like the result of a period of life, Dong Xiaoyue became a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Someone once asked her to charge the copyright fee. She replied in a letter: &quot;It should not be entangled in the copyright dispute, let everything follow the wind. The problem of music does not need to be given to the law. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; The young Wang Luobin more than 80 years ago would not expect that the copyright and origin of a song will be far away. It will become so important in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1935, at the age of 22, he worked as a music teacher at a middle school outside Beijing&#39;s Xizhimen. There is a river nearby. At noon in the summer, he ran to the river to swim, and there were many college students who moved after the fall of the Northeast. One day, the naked and mud people listened to their classmates to read &quot;August Village&quot;. This novel describes the story of the Northeast military and civilians fighting with the Japanese invaders after the &quot;September 18th&quot; incident. When I read a poem called &quot;I want to fall in love, I also want the freedom of the motherland&quot;, Wang Luobin, full of passion, wore clothes, copied the poem down, and went home to compose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Later, a young man found it and said that his songs were well written or sang well, but do you know who the novel author is. Wang Luobin was embarrassed and did not know. The young man laughed and said, &quot;The author is Xiao Jun, I am Xiao Jun.&quot; Wang Luobin recalled: &quot;I was shocked, so the two of us hugged, laughed, and became friends.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaita, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (Southern Weekend Intern Huang Xiaoying also contributed to this article) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt =&quot; September 10, 2023, Lizhou, Hebei, Hebei, Hebei, Wang Luobin&#39;s former residence memorial. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 258768 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; September 10, 2023, Hebei, Hebei, Wang Luobin&#39;s former residence Memorial Hall. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h5>; Wang Luobin Chronicle &lt;/h5>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti &quot;>; 1913, born in Beijing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1931, entered the National Peiping Normal University Music Department to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In 1937, the Anti-Japanese War broke out and went to Shanxi to participate in the Eighth Route Army&#39;s Northwest Warfield Service Troupe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1940, served as music education in Xining, Qinghai, and was responsible for the establishment of Qinghai Children&#39;s Anti-Japanese War Theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1949, participated in the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1952-1976, he was imprisoned many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In 1981, he recovered his reputation and military status and served as art consultant of the Xinjiang Military Region Cultural and Art Troupe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1991, enjoy special government allowances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;FonT-FAMILY: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1994, a special contribution award for Eastern and Western cultural exchanges by UNESCO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1996, died at the age of 83 due to the invalidation of gallbladder adenocarcinoma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4个月挣250元”，去横店当“童漂”值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260937]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-20 12:25:46 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/20/26999ccfccca7220487e539964EB758DE.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 427 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/ 11/20/26999ccfccca7220487E539964EB758DE. JPEG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 258849 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to media reports, many parents now take their children to be&quot; children&#39;s drift &quot;in Hengdian to find the opportunity to appear in film and television dramas. The life of &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is also very bitter. &quot;100 people grab a seat&quot;, &quot;Earn 250 yuan in 4 months&quot; and &quot;paying a lot of money with the capital&quot; are the norm of many &quot;children&#39;s drifts&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are media statistics, in 2022, in the film, online dramas, TV dramas and other film and television cultural works filmed in Hengdian, 230 minors participated in the performance of minor entertainers, with more than 6,000 people. This number is not small, and it is the reason why &quot;Tong Diao&quot; exists -Hengdian does provide an opportunity to act in acting and famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, with the influx of children and their families, &quot;Children&#39;s Drifting&quot; quickly became inside. It is difficult for the &quot;Tongfu&quot; industry to say that it is a pure dream chasing story, but has evolved into a strange capital game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In 2,000 years, at least 3 plays can be guaranteed in one year, and you can appear in special actors. In 53 years, at least 8 dramas in 3 years, you can be able to play special actors and characters.&quot; This is the charging model of several children&#39;s brokerage companies in the media report. According to the &quot;members&quot; of various levels, it is equipped with corresponding resources according to the amount paid. Obviously, for families who lack an economic foundation, &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is very cruel and the return rate is extremely low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another problem of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot; is that the main body of dreaming is children. If they are in a kind of irregular situation, what should I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The compulsory education law stipulates that children, parents of adolescents, or other legal guardians shall ensure that they are accepted on time and complete compulsory education in accordance with the law. If the parents let the child leave the school early for a child star dream, they are suspected of illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Even if the child completes compulsory education, the basic education is too weak. This impact may be lifelong. The cost of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot; is too huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, for the risk of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot;, parents should have more rational and comprehensive assessment. &quot;Being a wrist and becoming a horns&quot;, after all, has huge uncertainties. Family gambling everything to fight a very low probability of probability. Is this wise? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; And children do not have full capacity for civil behavior. They have not yet fully aware of their nature of their behavior. Many children really like acting, but they lack cognition about &quot;sinking costs&quot; -once the acting path is blocked, how can children return to conventional growth paths? Children are ignorant about this, and if parents lack prudence, it is undoubtedly an irresponsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, there is no need to criticize the &quot;children&#39;s drifting&quot; and his family to make too high criticism. Some common criticisms on the Internet, such as &quot;taking children as a tool for making money&quot; and &quot;Parents have a dream of getting rich&quot;, are not accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It can be seen from the interview that many parents are just because their children want to act and want to help their children dream. They may not be a parent who wants to smoke, which is essentially no different from asking children to &quot;read famous schools&quot;. They all chose a road with a very internal curler and unclear prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; While persuading parents to maintain prudential, society should also intervene. For example, whether the acting brokerage company is formal should actually attract the attention of relevant departments. Some parents reported that the &quot;bringing capital into the group&quot; was suspected of suffering from fraud. After paying money, he was not only played without play, but also was &quot;black&quot; by the parties. For these, the market regulatory authorities should follow the relevant clues to investigate whether there are any violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A red line that cannot be blurred is: No matter what growth path of the family chooses for children, but educated must be mandatory to implement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In any case, the bitterness of Hengdian&#39;s &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is an unpleasant inner volume after all. The journey of dreaming is of course full of hardships, but this road does not seem to be in line with a simple childhood narrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In view of this, whether the &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot; is suitable for its own family condition, it still needs to consider it carefully; and society should obviously work hard to eliminate the hidden risks of the existence to protect the rights of minors, at least given to at least given &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is a little less pit. &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[假如我变成了“熊孩子”丨世界儿童日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260935]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-20 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>