<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[​张又侠：中国军队绝不答应、绝不手软]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:25:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器丨视频]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259590]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[500万人次求助，800亿元捐赠：慈善法修正可否终结个人求助争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, this type of personal help donations has exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256024&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, such individual donations for help have exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 25, 2023, the draft amendment to the Charity Law after deliberation at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress will be officially released for public comment. The revised draft adds new content to regulate personal help-seeking behavior and the management of personal help-seeking online service platforms, which is considered to fill the legislative gaps and has attracted much attention. On the National People&#39;s Congress website, this is called one of the four highlights of this draft amendment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recent incident of a 2-year-old girl being bitten by a Rottweiler dog in Chengdu, public opinion questioned the individual&#39;s request for help. After the girl was bitten, her family started to raise 2 million yuan on the Easy Raising Platform. Within 5 hours and 18 minutes, more than 87,000 people donated, and the donation goal was achieved. But the girl&#39;s family quickly fell into disputes over the amount of the aid and the use of the funds. On October 25, EasyCho released refund instructions and refunded all unused donations in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, Xu Anbiao, deputy director of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, said that the original intention of this revision of the law is to improve the charity, fundraising, funding, service and other systems during emergencies, and to address some new issues that have emerged in the charity field. New situations and new problems, summarizing practical experience, such as &quot;fingertip public welfare&quot; and &quot;public welfare for everyone&quot; and other new situations and new problems that have emerged in the Internet era, it is necessary to reasonably regulate these phenomena and improve relevant systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are endless problems with personal help-seeking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Charity Law was reviewed and passed by the National People&#39;s Congress in March 2016 and has been in effect for 7 years. However, personal help-seeking has not been included in the regulation before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin, a professor at the School of Public Administration at Tsinghua University and deputy director of the Philanthropy Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that the legislative purpose of the Charity Law is to promote charity and regulate charity behaviors and charitable organizations. Charitable organizations can raise funds publicly for public welfare purposes and enjoy tax-free treatment, which is equivalent to the use of public resources, so its beneficiaries must be a non-specific public rather than a specific individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Personal help-seeking does not meet the purpose of public welfare, so the Charity Law did not regulate personal help-seeking at the beginning of the legislation. However, in recent years, with the help of online fundraising platforms such as LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, personal help-seeking has become more active and prominent than charity activities, and problems in the field of personal help-seeking have also emerged one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Luo Yixiao, a 6-year-old girl from Shenzhen, Guangdong, unfortunately suffered from leukemia. Her father Luo Er wrote an article online to raise about 2.7 million yuan for treatment expenses. Later, it was revealed that Luo Er had three houses and three companies in his home. He also said in an interview that &quot;the house in Shenzhen is reserved for his son,&quot; which caused him to be questioned. Amid the whirlpool of public opinion, Luo Yixiao died of illness, and Luo Er also returned all donations to the donors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Wang Fengya, a 3-year-old girl from Taikang County, Henan Province, suffered from retinoblastoma. Her mother requested help on multiple online platforms. In April 2018, it was revealed that his mother had donated 150,000 yuan through fraudulent donations to treat her son&#39;s cleft lip. Although the police investigation found that the donation fraud claim was untrue, Wang Fengya died of illness in May of that year, and her family was also subjected to online abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amid repeated controversies, calls for strengthening supervision of online fundraising platforms are getting louder and louder. In 2018, under the guidance of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, the three major online fundraising platforms, LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, issued a self-discipline convention. This was upgraded again in 2020, proposing that platforms should abide by seven &quot;bottom-line rules&quot; to strengthen platform self-discipline management and improve Risk prevention level and improve social supervision mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2019, the country’s first online dispute over personal critical illness help was pronounced. In this case, Mr. Mo launched a personal fundraising campaign on Shuidichou for his seriously ill son. However, because he concealed his property and other social assistance, the fundraising platform took him to court and demanded the return of the donation. After trial, the Beijing Chaoyang District Court found that Mr. Mo misappropriated the funds raised for other purposes in violation of the agreed purpose, constituting a breach of contract. The first instance order ordered the full return of more than 150,000 yuan raised and the payment of corresponding interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference after the verdict was announced in the case, Wang Min, the president of the Wangjing Tribunal of the Chaoyang District Court, pointed out that there are problems in the field of personal help for serious illnesses on the Internet, such as unclear legal definitions and overly principled provisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment of the case also mentioned: &quot;At present, only departmental regulations stipulate that personal seeking help does not belong to charitable fundraising and charitable public fundraising information. Regarding the rights between the network platform and the donor in personal seeking help for serious illness on the Internet, The obligations have not yet been clearly defined.” In addition, many unclear boundaries emerged during the trial, such as whether Mr. Mo provided comprehensive information, whether the fundraising platform should provide separate items to fill in the family property item by item, whether there were insufficient verifications, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, the Chaoyang District Court sent judicial suggestions to the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Shuidichou platform respectively, recommending that the Ministry of Civil Affairs coordinate and promote the legislation on personal help-seeking behavior for serious illnesses, establish and improve departmental regulations, and promote orderly personal help-seeking for serious illnesses on the Internet. carry out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke, a lawyer at Beijing Zhicheng Law Firm, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that as an individual right, individual seeking help is not subject to legal restrictions or prohibitions. For example, going to the streets to beg, as long as it does not violate city management regulations; seeking help from classmates or relatives after falling ill is a small-scale personal request for help. Whether the information for help is true or not only involves both the donor and the recipient. issues of rights and obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the factors of the Internet, the scope of communication and influence of personal help-raising on the Internet have changed dramatically. At this time, the authenticity of the help-seeking information has a certain degree of publicity. Netizens who make donations on an online fundraising platform are both donors and users of the platform. From the perspective of providing services to users, the platform also needs to verify the authenticity of the information of the help seekers, &quot;for our vast number of donors.&quot; Very good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the volume of personal requests for help on the Internet is huge. The first domestic &quot;Research Report on the Personal Serious Illness Help-Seeking Internet Platform (2022)&quot; shows that according to incomplete statistics, from September 2014 to the end of 2021, a total of more than 5 million serious illness patients posted help information through the personal serious illness help-seeking Internet service platform, and more than 20 100 million people donated funds through critical illness help platforms including Shuidichou, with a fundraising scale of more than 80 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Individual seeking help is a relatively active and large-scale phenomenon in society at present, and it is necessary for the Charity Law to respond in principle to this.” Jia Xijin said, but the current amendment to the Charity Law includes the addition of individuals The content of asking for help does not mean that individual asking for help is regarded as a charitable activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Information inspection” rather than “information review”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a member of the Expert Advisory Committee of the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, He Guoke participated in the meeting discussion of the revised draft of the Charity Law. According to him, due to the essential difference between personal help-seeking and charitable public welfare activities, the personal help-seeking section did not include chapters on charitable donations and charitable fundraising. Instead, it was placed in the supplementary provisions, and in the form of authorized legislation, the Civil Affairs Department of the State Council, in conjunction with Relevant departments will formulate specific management measures separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This draft amendment to the Charity Law clarifies: If an individual causes financial difficulties for his family due to illness or other reasons, and releases information for help to the society, the person seeking help and the information publisher shall be responsible for the authenticity of the information, and the personal assistance network service The platform shall bear the obligation to inspect information, and specific management measures shall be formulated separately by the civil affairs department of the State Council in conjunction with relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke believes that compared with the first revised draft, the latest revised draft has three main adjustments to the content of personal help-seeking: first, the definition of personal help-seeking puts more emphasis on the reasons of &quot;personal illness&quot;; In addition, the &quot;network service provider&quot; in the amendment is clearly defined as &quot;personal assistance network service platform&quot; in the amendment, which means that when the Ministry of Civil Affairs formulates specific management measures in the future, it is likely to re-qualify the platform party to do so. Stricter management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last adjustment is that the &quot;information review obligation&quot; that the platform should bear is changed to &quot;information inspection obligation.&quot; &quot;&#39;Review&#39; is more important than &#39;inspection&#39;.&quot; He Guoke said that the platform has not been granted the power and responsibility like government departments and judicial agencies, and cannot review the property in the name of the requester. &quot;For example, the requester said that he only has one house. &quot;The platform can only see that the real estate certificate of this house is basically true, but it cannot go to the Housing Authority to check how many properties he owns in total.&quot; This adjustment was made after considering the opinions of multiple platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin believes that in the draft amendment to the Charity Law, it is necessary to add the principle content that &quot;the person asking for help and the person publishing the information should be responsible for the authenticity of the information&quot; because the basis for personal seeking help is still civil. In the &quot;gift&quot; relationship, the primary responsible parties are both the donor and the recipient. &quot;Whoever publishes false information is responsible&quot;; as a third party that promotes cooperation, the platform needs to conduct necessary formal reviews, such as requiring family financial information. Certificates, medical certificates, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above-mentioned Shuidichiou case, the Chaoyang District Court held that the Shuidichiou platform has strict formal review obligations and strict supervision obligations. In this case, the court found that Shuidichiou had review flaws, but this did not affect Mr. Mo’s responsibility to return the donation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information provided by Shuidichou to Southern Weekend reporters, Shuidichou has currently strengthened measures to ensure the authenticity of fundraising cases, using technology and manual methods to pass preliminary review, reexamination, third-party review, etc. The platform will continuously review user information. Only after the platform reviews the information is correct and meets the qualifications, can online fundraising be initiated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the materials provided by Shuidichou, the platform intercepted an average of 12 fundraising applications that did not meet the requirements every day. In the first half of the year, it intercepted and rejected a total of 2,096 fundraising applications that did not meet the launch conditions, including There are 544 illegal users who have been permanently blacklisted from the platform and are prohibited from launching fundraising again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in Jia Xijin&#39;s view, individual case assistance and personal help are like &quot;after-care medicine&quot; for the plight of seriously ill families. They can exist but do not need to become bigger and stronger. She believes that it is more important to establish multiple response mechanisms, such as inclusive medical insurance and medical assistance systems, commercial insurance, public welfare advocacy and beneficiary services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明星发声缘何遭遇舆论反弹：公共空间不应是少数人表演的舞台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the discussion surrounding the incident of vicious dogs injuring people in Chongzhou, Sichuan has gradually extended to the management and disposal of stray animals in the city. On many public affairs, it has become a vent for social emotions for a period of time, including relatively rational thinking and suggestions, as well as more radical remarks and propositions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon of &quot;using topics to vent emotions&quot; is common in itself, but one of the phenomena is very interesting. After several well-known actors made remarks on personal social media calling for kindness to stray animals, their comment areas were blocked. Netizens were &quot;outraged&quot; and a large number of fans left messages to &quot;unsubscribe&quot; and &quot;drop followers&quot;. Many actors have closed the comment area to passively fight against the storm of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of traditional communication studies, it is generally believed that film and television stars rely on their personal charm, the persona they have created in public affairs for a long time, as well as the fans and traffic they bring, and they have great influence in the field of public opinion. With huge appeal and influence, the joint &quot;voice&quot; of several celebrities can often change the direction of public opinion. However, in this incident, the celebrities without exception failed in the field of public opinion. This is thought-provoking The changes actually include a series of quite profound social changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“A stage for the few” and “a society for the majority”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the era of television media and the early era of online media, “unitary subjectivity” and “central focus” are reflected Incisively and vividly, young people in frontiers and villages gaze at the love affairs and joys and sorrows of middle-class people in the reinforced concrete forests of Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou from fashion magazines, movies, TV and computer screens, and have not yet realized the need for self-subject expression. Most cultural products are produced in megacities and only depict life there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the society of the majority revolves around the stage of the minority, and regards the lifestyle of the super urban middle-class citizens performed on the stage as an advanced, civilized, and universal And one-size-fits-all paradigms and templates. The imitation of this lifestyle is considered a fashionable, progressive, and civilized pursuit, while the opposite is considered an archaic, backward, and barbaric conservatism. This “progressivist life template” is not original to urban middle-class citizens, but an imitation of the lifestyles of European and American middle-class citizens who achieved modernization and urbanization earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cultural industry born in super cities produces cultural products through imitation and interpretation of this &quot;progressive life template&quot;, and then promotes it to the whole society through cultural products. As one of the producers of cultural products, actors must naturally accept this &quot;progressive life template&quot; and the ideas behind it. Otherwise, not only will they not be able to work smoothly, they will even find it difficult to gain a foothold and live in the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is not difficult to see that although the acting styles of the actors are different, a considerable number of actors have a highly consistent personality in life: they love nature, sports and travel, and have certain ideas. Depth and artistic taste, emphasis on material enjoyment and emotional value, and a &quot;personality&quot; that is passionate about environmental protection and public welfare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in a series of public discussions derived from the &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident&quot;, some celebrities&#39; actions to speak out for &quot;kindness to stray animals&quot; are not only a commercial act to create and maintain their personalities, but also their A true reflection of values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some celebrities have ignored two issues. Their standards of civilization are based on their living environment and lifestyle. The probability of them being bitten and injured by off-leash dogs and stray dogs in their lives is extremely small. . But this is not the case for ordinary people. Data from a public health study show that taking Zhengzhou City, Henan Province as an example, there are more than 90,000 rabies exposure risk cases in Zhengzhou City every year, and dog bites account for 77.68%. More than 80% of bite cases occur in urban areas. This The data also does not include bites that did not seek medical attention. Judging from Zhengzhou’s population base of nearly 13 million people, the probability of being bitten by a dog in the city is not low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a natural and instinctive reaction for people to become anxious about their own safety due to the incident of vicious dogs in Chongzhou and their own living environment. While some celebrities make empty calls to &quot;be kind to animals&quot;, they lack in-depth rational thinking about the incident itself, let alone put forward any meaningful suggestions and feasible solutions. Instead, they deliberately pretend to be &quot;civilized&quot;. Inadvertently pushing those netizens who are worried about their own safety to the opposite side of &quot;barbarism&quot; will naturally encounter fierce backlash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the trend of flattening of social public opinion in the Internet era has become more and more obvious, and &quot;mono-subjectivity&quot; has been eliminated. The routine of eliminating freedom and pluralism under the banner of freedom and pluralism has increasingly aroused public concern. In the past, it was difficult for a few celebrities to appeal to fans and reverse the trend of public opinion. On the contrary, this can easily make &quot;vocal&quot; stars become the target of public criticism and the vent of collective emotions, leading to a situation where the comment section has collapsed and fans have collectively lost their fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let the screen return to the screen, let the reality return to reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with developed countries, our country’s modernization process is too rapid. In the process of modernization, the film and television industry has developed particularly As a result, a considerable part of the public lacks an accurate understanding of the profession of actors, and a considerable number of actors also lack an accurate positioning of their profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confusing the image of an actor in reality with the image he plays in opera is a common psychology among people in pre-modern society. Our overly rapid modernization process has more or less extended this psychology to modern society. Actors play politicians, scientists, business tycoons and other social elites on the screen, as well as the profound lines of these elite images. , making it easy for the audience to ignore one of the most basic facts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how professional and outstanding the doctors, scientists, and soldiers the actors play on stage and screen, their most professional and outstanding field is still acting. Only in the field of performance are they truly outstanding experts. They may shine in other areas outside their majors, but in the final analysis they are still ordinary people. Once their opinions exceed their professional fields, they can easily make the same mistakes as ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because of the ultra-high income level and ultra-high social status that this profession achieved during the economic boom period, which far exceeds that of general industries in society, the above basic facts are easier to ignore. Not only do a considerable number of ordinary people generally follow celebrities as &quot;opinion leaders&quot; who are morally and intellectually superior to others, there are also a considerable number of actors who increasingly express opinions outside of their own profession on public affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the &quot;disenchantment&quot; effect brought about by the flattening of the Internet, more and more people&#39;s perception of celebrities is becoming increasingly mature, and they can objectively realize that acting is just one of many professions, and celebrities are among other professions. Apart from the halo of his acting career, he is just an ordinary person who specializes in art. When faced with some public opinions expressed by celebrities that are not constructive, lack in-depth thinking, and are purely emotional expressions, we dare to express different opinions instead of blindly following them. This is also an important reason why the comment sections of many celebrities have overturned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thoughts derived from this &quot;rollover&quot; incident are actually more than the above two points, but one thing is absolutely certain: in a social environment where the pre-modern state lasts too long, the post-modern state comes too early. , the standards of &quot;civilization&quot; are set by a few people and required to be accepted by the majority, which is definitely not a civilized plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香山论坛 外国代表怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:57:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023软科世界一流学科排名：中国内地收获17个世界第一学科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 27, Ruanke, a professional institution for higher education evaluation, officially released the 2023 &quot;Ranking of World-Class Subjects of Ruanke&quot; (ShanghaiRanking&#39;s Global Ranking of Academic Subjects). The 2023 ranking covers 55 disciplines, involving five major fields: science, engineering, life sciences, medicine and social sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This ranking targets more than 5,000 universities around the world. A total of more than 1,900 universities from 104 countries and regions finally appeared on the lists of various subjects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/40c9bfc857c252c4575a006558b08b7b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/40c9bfc857c252c4575a006558b08b7b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256014&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;U.S. universities have an advantage in the total number of universities on the list, and universities in mainland China have increased significantly&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;American universities still have an absolute advantage in the rankings of various subjects, winning the championship in 30 subjects, with 303 universities on the list. The total number of times on the list reached 4318 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 333 universities in mainland China are on the list, with a total of 3,390 times on the list, ranking second in the world after the United States. Compared with last year, the number of universities in mainland China and the total number of universities on the list increased by 13.7% and 26.2% respectively, both of which were significant improvements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2023 Ranking of World-Class Subjects in China, Harvard University won the championship in 11 subjects, ranking first among universities in the world. Other universities with more than one champion subject are the Massachusetts Institute of Technology ( 5), University of Michigan-Ann Arbor (2), Hong Kong Polytechnic University (2), University of Chicago (2). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three universities with the largest number of disciplines in the world&#39;s top ten are Harvard University (26), Stanford University (22), and Massachusetts Institute of Technology (18). The others have more than 10 in the world. The universities with the top ten disciplines include Tsinghua University (16), Oxford University (11), Columbia University (11), Shanghai Jiao Tong University (11), and University of Pennsylvania (11). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Mainland China has reached a new high, ranking first in the world in 17 disciplines&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the 2023 Ranking of World-Class Subjects in China, mainland China’s universities have added three new disciplines to rank first in the world. Hua University won the first place in the textile science and engineering discipline released for the first time, Northwest A&amp;F University ranked first in the world in the agricultural discipline for the first time, and Nanjing Agricultural University ranked first in the world in the veterinary science discipline for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, universities in mainland China have become global champions in 17 disciplines, namely Tsinghua University (Energy Science and Engineering), Xi&#39;an Jiaotong University (Mechanical Engineering), Harbin Institute of Technology (Instrument Science), Tongji University ( Civil Engineering), Hohai University (Water Resources Engineering), Jiangnan University (Food Science and Engineering), Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics (Aerospace Engineering), Shanghai Jiaotong University (Shipbuilding and Ocean Engineering), Beijing Jiaotong University (Transportation Engineering) , Wuhan University (Remote Sensing Technology), Central South University (Mining Engineering), University of Science and Technology Beijing (Metallurgical Engineering), Xi&#39;an University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (Communication Engineering), University of Science and Technology of China (Nano Science and Technology), Donghua University (Textile Science and Technology Engineering), Northwest A&amp;F University (Agriculture), Nanjing Agricultural University (Veterinary Medicine). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/2e69a42f1f13ce0a02a202202d846223.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1286&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/2e69a42f1f13ce0a02a202202d846223.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256013&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the number of listed subjects among universities in mainland China, Zhejiang University ranks first in mainland China with 53 listed subjects, and has also become the school with the largest number of listed subjects in the world. Sun Yat-sen University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Peking University, Tsinghua University, Wuhan University, Fudan University, Sichuan University, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, and Central South University also all have more than 40 disciplines on the list. Tsinghua University has 16 subjects among the top ten in the world and 33 among the top 50 in the world. It has also become the university with the largest number of top ten and top 50 subjects among universities in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The newly selected universities in the second round of &quot;double first-class&quot; construction have performed well in the ranking of world-class disciplines in China. Southern University of Science and Technology has 31 disciplines on the list, 15 of which are among the top 100 in the world, and 6 of which are among the top 50. South China Agricultural University has 13 disciplines on the list, and 4 disciplines are among the top 100 in the world and ranked among the top 50 in the world. ShanghaiTech University and Nanjing Medical University each have three disciplines ranked among the top 100 in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among non-&quot;Double First-Class&quot; universities, Shenzhen University has 39 subjects on the list, leading non-&quot;Double First-Class&quot; universities in the number of subjects on the list. Qingdao University and Jiangsu University ranked second and third with 25 and 24 appearances respectively. Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou University and Zhejiang University of Technology tied for fourth place among non-&quot;double first-class&quot; universities with 20 appearances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Ruanke World-Class Subject Ranking&quot; uses a series of internationally comparable objective academic indicators to measure the performance of global universities in relevant disciplines. The ranking indicators include international authoritative academic awards, top academic achievements, and high-level scientific research. Output, scientific research quality, international cooperation, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马修·派瑞：说一声再见，就是死去一点点丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259601]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:00:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/zCyareI9Bnps0Wz6kcjlUKCcLzYtj8SDLrIqeHMZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/zCyareI9Bnps0Wz6kcjlUKCcLzYtj8 SDLrIqeHMZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matthew Perry (1969-2023), American, actor&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Friends&quot; has been so popular that many people think that there is always a parallel time and space where youth remains forever. It wasn&#39;t until the news of Matthew Perry&#39;s sudden death came from across the ocean that people discovered that there are no fairy tales in the real world. Time passes through everyone&#39;s body and soul equally, growing up, aging, and finally accepting impermanence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media have sorted out Matthew Perry’s life: his parents divorced when he was less than 1 year old, and he lived with his mother in Canada; he once wanted to be a professional tennis player, but acting was the next best thing. However, he was lucky. At the age of 25, he encountered &quot;Friends&quot;, a hit drama that is rare in the world. He played Chandler Bing for ten years, a sensitive, gentle man who can always rely on cold jokes. Masters of dry humor to relieve embarrassment - they are so well-suited that they are indistinguishable. If it weren&#39;t for the clothes that were loose and tight, the audience wouldn&#39;t even realize that they are two people - Chandler lives in In Matthew&#39;s out-of-control body, Matthew hides the pain in Chandler&#39;s face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/oqfWuMLOKGt8hH5H11laGV4V4tgOo6IaWC1dEzYG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/oqfWuMLOKGt8hH5H11laGV4V4tgOo6IaWC1dEzYG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256079&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Friends&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alcoholism and drug dependence made Chandler lose his temper in the series Matthew&#39;s sudden fits of weight and weight caused him to go back and forth between nursing homes and rehabilitation. &quot;I can stay awake for a while, but not completely.&quot; In 2000, Matthew, who was in his thirties, underwent pancreatic surgery. His pancreas became inflamed and swollen due to alcoholism. However, the body&#39;s alarm failed to stop Matthew from seeking peace in alcohol and drugs. He made up his mind to say goodbye to the chaotic life again and again, and searched for inner order in the chaos again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Matthew&#39;s colon exploded inside his body. After seven hours of surgery and two full weeks of coma, he woke up from a 2% hope of survival. After that, he lived with a colostomy bag for 9 months, and it was not until 2020 that the situation improved. In April 2021, Matthew recorded a reunion show with the other five leading actors of &quot;Friends&quot;. Everyone recalled the scene of filming twenty years ago. Matthew used a black suit and black tie to hide his departure from Chandler. The storm that followed. He and they all said to let the story stop there and not to make another comeback series just to imagine &quot;what are they doing now&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last episode of Season 10 of &quot;Friends&quot;, the six people were about to start a new life. Chandler hugged his adopted child and said: &quot;Little guys, look around, here are you The first home, a happy place, full of love and laughter.&quot; Everyone left their keys, and Phoebe said, &quot;I think that&#39;s the end of it.&quot; Joey nodded, and Monica began Crying: &quot;It&#39;s harder than imagined.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sPYxVGOlW9oSgmfmOAbLLtbmNQkoqxbtnoGJb7OL.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sPYxVGOlW9oSgmfmOAbLLtbmNQkoqxbtnoGJb7OL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256080&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Friends&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On October 28, 2023, Matthew Perry passed away at his home in Los Angeles. According to local police reports, the cause of death was drowning caused by cardiac arrest. There were no drugs and no signs of homicide. Of course, there was no goodbye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the play, the crying Monica fell into Chandler&#39;s arms, and he said: &quot;It&#39;s okay, it will be fine.&quot; Rachel suggested going for coffee again, and Chandler once again They used cold jokes to relieve their sadness: &quot;Where to go?&quot; They pushed the stroller outside. In the barrage, an audience member said that every time at this time, he would immediately go back and watch the first episode. The audience naturally did not explain the reason. Perhaps a long time ago, he understood what another Chandler - the famous American writer Raymond Chandler - said in the novel: &quot;To say goodbye is to die a little. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广西官宣“试管婴儿”纳入医保，你怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259594]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the implementation of the three-child policy, many places have intensively released fertility support policies, among which medical insurance provides for assisted reproductive medical services. support is an important measure. For example, in July 2023, Beijing officially included 16 assisted reproductive technologies such as ovulation induction examinations and embryo transfers into medical insurance. Recently, Guangxi has officially announced: &lt;strong>;From November 1, medical services such as &quot;test tube baby&quot; will be included in medical insurance, and up to 70% can be reimbursed&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice mentioned that some therapeutic assisted reproductive medical services such as &quot;ovum retrieval&quot; will be included in the payment scope of basic medical insurance and work-related injury insurance funds; when insured persons enjoy basic medical insurance benefits, there will be no The minimum payment standard for the fund, the reimbursement ratios of basic medical insurance for employees and basic medical insurance for urban and rural residents are 70% and 50% respectively, which are included in the maximum annual fund payment limit for insured persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the authoritative medical journal &quot;The Lancet&quot;: from 2007 to 2020, the incidence of infertility in China has increased from 12% to 18%. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, there will be 9.56 million births in the country in 2022, with one child accounting for less than 50%, and the natural population growth rate is -0.60‰—&lt;strong>;This is the first time that New China has experienced negative population growth since 1961&lt;/strong>; strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some experts said that the inclusion of &quot;test tube babies&quot; in medical insurance will be a good boost to reduce the burden on patients and increase the national fertility rate. At present, there are first-, second- and third-generation IVF technologies, with an average cost of 30,000 to 100,000 yuan. This price will also vary depending on the age and physical quality of the individual. Some experts are cautious. The &quot;reservoir&quot; of medical insurance is limited. If it is included in the scope, it may increase financial pressure. Young people should be encouraged to marry early and have more children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this? Welcome to share your opinions in the message area and I will send you hot comments! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[志向和焦虑并存，留学还是好选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259576]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;International students have lofty dreams, but in the process of pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles, and also have negative feelings about I feel confused about my future. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. All these anxieties force them to think about the ultimate question: Is studying abroad really worth it? &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[东北亚新安全态势初现，如何推动局势缓和？| 智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the post-epidemic era, leaders of various countries have reunited, but they have not yet achieved significant results on political, economic and climate issues. Results. It is difficult for countries to unite collectively and instead prefer small-scale alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, even in Northeast Asia, a similar new security situation has emerged, and the roles of South Korea and China in dealing with the new situation have also attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New security issues emerge in Northeast Asia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 13, the summit held at Camp David, Maryland, brought together the leaders of South Korea, the United States, and Japan to jointly respond to pressing international security issues situation. During the summit, the leaders announced the opening of a &quot;new era of trilateral partnership&quot; and emphasized the three countries&#39; commitment to security cooperation. They held a joint press conference to outline plans and cooperation strategies involving tripartite cooperation, the Camp David Principles and the Camp David Spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the meeting, in order to ensure the stable development of trilateral cooperation between the United States, South Korea and Japan, a cross-level and cross-field systematic cooperation foundation was established. In addition to standardizing the U.S.-South Korea-Japan summit, officials from each country, including the ministers of foreign affairs, defense, and national security advisers, also agreed to hold annual meetings in their respective fields to closely coordinate cooperation plans among the three countries. In addition, the three leaders decided to establish communication channels to facilitate rapid consultation and rapid response when urgent regional issues that threaten the common interests of the three countries arise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to strengthen strategic cooperation among the three countries in the region, the three countries agreed to establish a ministerial-level dialogue called the &quot;U.S.-South Korea-Japan Indo-Pacific Dialogue&quot; and explore new areas of cooperation within the Indo-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the leaders discussed practical cooperation measures to enhance joint operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，美国、韩国和日本重申，将致力于维护基于主权、领土完整和和平解决冲突等准则的国际秩序。同样的，三国还同意在实施印太战略时，支持在东盟和太平洋岛国地区强化海上安全能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，9月13日，金正恩和普京在俄罗斯阿穆尔州的东方航天发射场举行了首脑会谈。这次是他们自2019年4月以来，时隔约四年零五个月再次会晤。紧急会晤的背景，是朝鲜面临主要由美国和西方国家实施的强力制裁。朝鲜受到了联合国安理会（UNSC）的制裁，并遭受严重粮食短缺和技术缺陷。而俄罗斯也面临着欧盟和其他国家的经济制裁，正在竭力解决长期存在的“武器短缺”问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在当前的国际形势下，俄罗斯和朝鲜被认为是能够满足彼此需求的独特伙伴，两国还打算在联合国安理会的活动中合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果东北亚地区出现了新的安全问题，韩国、中国和相关国家在安全和更广泛的经济方面将出现不稳定性的恶性循环。要解决朝鲜核问题也将变得更为复杂，区域经济发展定会停滞不前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;韩中推动合作&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在此背景下，韩国和中国是有潜力驾驭这一局面的主要国家之一。美俄之间仍属敌对关系，美朝之间和韩朝之间的双边对话长期停滞。韩国和中国可以通过合作，在缓解和应对东北亚新的安全问题上发挥关键作用。因此，为了实现这一目标，韩国和中国可以通过各种方式进行合作，为缓和东北亚的紧张局势做出贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，韩国、中国和日本之间的三边峰会是合作的直接机会。三国首脑会议自1999年开始，已举办八次。然而自2019年12月以来，三边峰会一直没有召开，目前由韩国担任主席国。三方峰会已经暂停三年，可能会冲散笼罩在东北亚上空的阴云。韩国外交部旨在年内举办三国首脑会议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，韩中可能举行首脑峰会。峰会由韩国国务总理韩德洙提议。最近，韩国报纸《每日联合新闻》与民意研究公司Opinion and Public合作进行的一项调查显示，82.3%的受访者认为韩中峰会“有必要”举行，只有11.3%的受访者认为“没有必要”，6.3%的受访者表示不确定。不论地区、年龄或政治派别的差异如何，大多数受访者认为有必要举行两国峰会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，在重建韩中信任的同时，有必要激活各种安全合作机制。自1992年建立外交关系以来，韩国和中国在各领域都取得了重大进展。两国关系从1992年的睦邻友好合作关系，发展到1998年的面向21世纪的中韩合作伙伴关系，并进一步发展到2003年的全面合作伙伴关系，2008年升级为战略合作伙伴关系。然而，2016年萨德导弹防御系统部署在韩国后，两国关系紧张，导致交流与合作受到限制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，美中战略竞争和国际秩序影响了韩国和中国之间的安全交流。朝中关系和韩美同盟的独特性，也会限制韩中的交流。此外，政治氛围可能会影响韩国和中国之间的交流，导致缺乏实质性议程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是从追求朝鲜半岛稳定、和平与繁荣的共同国家利益的角度出发，韩国和中国有必要恢复交流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，两国很有必要保持沟通渠道，以解决敏感的安全和军事问题，防止意外冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩中近邻，互为伙伴，不可分割。时至今日，韩中之间的合作可共同驱散阴影，携手开辟实现地区稳定、和平与繁荣的道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（作者：李昌衡，韩国国防分析研究所韩国大陆战略研究所所长；翻译：郑为豪）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[枪械教官“大开杀戒”，“全美最安全州”响起无差别扫射枪声]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259575]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;月&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;日&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;罗伯特·卡德的尸体，在缅因州里斯本附近的树林里被发现，头部有明显的自伤枪伤。这两天，他所居住的美国东北部缅因州刘易斯顿几乎成了“鬼城”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他是该地大规模枪击案的“嫌疑人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此前，当地警方在社交媒体上说，刘易斯顿发现一名“机动枪手”，要求民众“就地避难”，“待在家中并锁好门”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自2023年10月25日晚枪击案发生以来，美国警方一直在搜捕卡德。他在一家保龄球馆和酒吧先后进行了无差别杀人，造成至少18人死亡，数十人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随后，缅因州刘易斯顿警方确认，40岁的卡德是一名持证枪械教官，也是美国陆军预备役成员。但今年夏天，他在美国军事学院训练期间表现异常，被送进了一家精神健康治疗机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;此次大规模枪击事件被认为是缅因州有记录以来最严重的枪击事件。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;缅因州&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;曾被誉为“全美最安全州”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;作为美国人口最少的州之一，该州的枪支拥有率很高，但枪支暴力水平相对较低。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;此次枪击案&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;受害者人数几乎达到该州2022 年全年凶杀案受害人数水平。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;为何此次枪手会在这里“大开杀戒”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;为何美国枪支暴力问题又大规模爆发&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;成了国际社会关注的焦点&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;月&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;29&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;日&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;正在北京参加香山论坛的复旦大学中国研究院院长张维为就在会上&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;谈到美国枪支管制问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;他曾在一档电视节目中表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;中国人的“政道”观就是人民整体和长远的利益，用“道”来管“术”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;如果没有“政道”这个理念，只有法律条文，美国的&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;控枪&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;改革将很难推动。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;727&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/RSZkCUtwxkJRDLsS361ZrDduMf14vWknOe5nRcpk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是10月25日在美国缅因州路易斯顿拍摄的该持枪男子（视频截图）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社美联/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;无差别扫射”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月25日&lt;span>;夜晚&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;如果不出意外&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;聚集在刘易斯顿保龄球馆内的一群年轻人&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;将在这里度过属于他们的“保龄球之夜”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;保龄球馆位于贝茨学院校园以北约3.2 公里处，地处市中心郊区。不远处还有一间小酒吧，是当地保龄球联赛和年轻派对的热门场所。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;但很快，一声枪响打断了这场狂欢&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“我听到了大约10 声枪响，我以为第一声枪声是气球破裂的声音。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;一名投球手在接受媒体采访时说到&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;当他转身后，看到的并不是一个气球，而是一个拿着武器的男人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;手持半自动步枪的罗伯特·卡德出现在了门口。保龄球馆里挤满了家长和青少年，惊慌失措的小保龄球手们&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;争先恐后地试图躲在球瓶后面。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;枪声并没有因为人群的恐慌和现场的哭声而停止，反而变得更加激烈了起来。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;随后&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德对着人群开始了无差别扫射。紧接着&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;他选择换一个地方&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;酒吧延续制造悲剧&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;不到&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;分钟，警方接到大量来自酒吧的报警电话&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;人们表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德在酒吧内继续扫射&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;但刘易斯顿警察还是慢了一步，卡德连续疯狂扫射后&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;驾车潜逃&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;并没有被当场抓获&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;当地首席医疗官约翰·亚历山大博士称&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;此次袭击对于这座小城市来说是“前所未有的”。他说，大约50 名医疗服务提供者、护士、呼吸治疗师和外科医生响应号召，帮助治疗受害者。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;事发后&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;刘易斯顿街道上空无一人，巨大的标志牌提醒人们一定要锁好房门，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;待&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在室内。整座城市都因&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;这起疯狂枪击案&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;陷入了静止状态。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;而&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;距枪击现场50 英里（80 公里）远的城市，学校、医生办公室和杂货店&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;都关闭了&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;与此同时&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州最大的城市波特兰关闭了其公共&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;设施&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，加拿大边境服务局向驻扎在美国边境的官员发出“武装和危险”警报。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;人们惴惴不安，默默祈祷着警方能够再快一些抓到凶手&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;隔天&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;上午的新闻发布会上，缅因州公共安全部专员&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;一百多名警方调查人员&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;包括&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;联邦特工&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;参与其中，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;正&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在全城紧锣密鼓&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;地&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;搜寻凶手，不放过任何一个便于隐藏的角落。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;缅因州警方表示，嫌疑人最近&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;出现了&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;精神健康问题，包括“听到声音和威胁要射击缅因州南部的一个军事设施”。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;其&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;嫂子凯蒂·卡德&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;则&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在接受&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;媒体&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;采访时表示，其家人已向警方和军队报告，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;正在经历严重的心理健康危机&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;卡德家人的邻居里克·戈达德&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在接受媒体采访&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;时&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;表示，几周前&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;看起来“完全正常”。戈达德住在&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;事发地点附近&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，他认识卡德一家&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;并透露&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;是卡德从小长大的地方&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;每一个隐藏在后面的壁架、每一&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;处&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;灌木丛，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德都非常熟悉&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;卡德受过枪械教练培训，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;也是&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;一名&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国陆军预备役成员&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;警方表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德“听到了声音”并威胁要炸毁一个&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;军事&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;基地。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;于是&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;他被送往精神病院，但只在那里&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;待&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;了两周就&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;离开&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;据悉&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪手使用的是带有加长弹匣和瞄准镜的半自动突击步枪。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪手所持枪械威力很大。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;上海政法学院东北亚研究中心副主任&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;杨震向南方周末记者分析&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;此次枪手所用的枪械是AR-15型步枪，该型号比棒球棒短，比保龄球轻，价格低廉，射击简单，后坐力轻微，易于瞄准，并且保有量极大，便于获得零件。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;目前还不清楚&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;卡德&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;如何或何时获得枪击事件中使用的枪支。枪击事件的动机&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;尚不清楚&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨震表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;从作案手法以及过往经历看，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪手&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;有可能是受过心理创伤，人格扭曲，并且长期得不到有效治疗&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;因此可能&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在外部因素刺激下导致反社会反人类倾向&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;此前&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在枪手还没被抓到之前&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;阴影笼罩着&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;直到&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;当地时间&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;月&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;27&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;日晚上&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;该&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;州&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;召开紧急新闻发布会&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;公共安全专员迈克尔·索查克表示，在里斯本瀑布地区的安德罗斯科金河附近&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;发现了卡德的尸体&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;距离枪击事件的地方大约10公里左右的路程。卡德死于明显的自伤枪伤&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;当“最安全”变得不安全&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;具有军事背景的枪手进行大规模射杀&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在美国并非特例&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;例如2018年，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;就有&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在千橡市酒吧枪杀&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;名无辜&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;民众的&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;前海军陆战&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;队&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;队员，以及在&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;得&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;克萨斯州萨瑟兰泉一座教堂&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;里&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪杀&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;26&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;人的空军退伍军人。 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;美国酒精、烟草、火器和爆炸物管理局（ATF）特工弗格森称，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;此次&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪击事件中使用的武器是合法购买的，并称找到了“不止三把”枪支。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;在《美国新闻与世界报道》评选的“美国十大最安全的州”排行榜上&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;名列前茅&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;虽然美国&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;民主党控制着州长职位和州议会两院&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;但缅因州长期以来一直抵制枪支管制措施&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;因为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;狩猎是那里文化的组成部分。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;今年&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州众议院于&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;6&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;月批准了一项加强对私人枪支销售背景调查的措施，但该提案在州参议院未能通过。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;另外&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;州众议院还通过了&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;一项法案，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;禁止&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;持有、销售或制造&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;撞火枪托和其他速射改装装置&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，但该法案也被缅因州参议院否决。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;值得关注的是&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州允许购买某些攻击型武器和大容量弹匣，并且没有&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;类似&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;书面的极端风险保护法令。这些措施也被称为“红旗法”，如果认为某人对自己或他人构成威胁，执法人员或家庭成员可以向法官寻求命令，暂时限制某人使用枪支。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;根据兰德公司2020 年的一项研究，2006 年至2017 年间，45% 的缅因州家庭至少拥有一把枪，而全国平均水平为32%。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;该州的枪支拥有率很高，但枪支暴力水平相对较低。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;此次枪击案&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;受害者人数几乎与该州2022 年全年的凶杀案总数相匹配。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;不少美媒披露&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;这起枪击事件标志着&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;其&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国今年发生的第36 起大规模&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪杀&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;事件。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;根据&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/&quot;>;&lt;span>;枪支&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;暴力档案馆数据&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span>;，截至&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;10 月&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;26 日，今年美国至少有35,275 人死于枪支暴力，平均每天有近118 人死亡。自杀死亡占今年枪支暴力死亡的绝大&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;多数。今年有19,734 人死于枪支自杀&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023年预计将成为美国大规模枪击事件有记录以来死亡人数最多的一年&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;值得关注的是&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;缅因州州长珍妮特·米尔斯是总检察长出身的民主党人&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;年10月25日&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;拜登与其进行通话，表示白宫将为缅因州提供支持&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨震认为，当前正值美国处于内忧外患之际，特别是美国总统大选实际上已经开始了暗流涌动的政治斗争。拜登此举，一方面有向公众作秀的意思，另一方面也是试图拉珍妮特一把，帮其在接下来的抨击和问责中过关。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“对抗性思维”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;美国的枪支问题是一个老问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;每当有美国总统雄心勃勃地想要对枪支贸易进行改革&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;之时&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，国会议员们都会表现出非常激烈的反对态度。最终总统往往也会向国会议员们做出妥协，这个问题也就不了了之。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;中国人民大学国际事务研究所所长王义桅&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;向南方周末记者表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国没办法彻底清除&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;枪支暴力&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;就像把每次的总统选举当作是“发泄筒”类似&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;暴力枪击&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;被视为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;更加极端的&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;发泄”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;枪支贸易在美国经过数百年的发展，已经形成了一个庞大的既得利益群体。这些既得利益者们成立了一个所谓的“美国步枪协会”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;在美国的反枪控活动中，该协会提供了近90%的经费。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;杨震表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;协会还通过金钱捐赠，拉拢国会议员，从而影响立法。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;从这一点来看，美国控枪是死局。不断发生的枪击案使这种死局陷入了死循环中&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;王义桅&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国枪击案件频发&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;是个“&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;老顽疾&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。美国从建国时就造就了持枪的传统，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;再到&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;后来变成了宪法修正案，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;现在&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;加上步枪协会绑架了这种暴力文化&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;此次大规模枪杀事件发生后&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;寻求连任的拜登在白宫声明中，提到了他为减少枪支暴力而颁布的立法。拜登表示，“虽然我们通过《两党更安全社区法案》、成立首个白宫枪支暴力预防办公室在枪支安全方面取得了进展，但这还不够。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;他&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;敦促，共和党议员&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;应&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;尽早&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;通过禁止攻击性武器的法案、对枪支制造商进行普遍背景调查并终止&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;责任豁免，“履行保护美国人民的责任”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨震认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;目前拜登政府内外交困，焦头烂额。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“这种背景下，禁枪只是芥藓之疾&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;他补充道&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;摆个架势应付一下，不太可能有后续&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，他们&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;既无能力也无意愿彻底解决该问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;不过人们还关注&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;为何近几年美国枪击案不仅无“降温”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;反而愈演愈烈&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年10月16日，美国联邦调查局公布了一份最新的调查报告。这份报告详尽地阐述了2022年美&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;国社会的犯罪情况。根据报告中的内容显示，2022年，全美各地的仇恨犯罪案件已经达到了11634起。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;可见&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;美国社会中仇恨犯罪的现象正以肉眼可见的速度在迅速蔓延。白人群体与有色人种群体之间的矛盾、本地居民与外来移民之间的矛盾、不同政治派别之间的矛盾在美&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;国社会里集中爆发。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;王义桅&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;目前美国国内存在着不少矛盾问题&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;如个人主义的崇尚&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;暴力的文化&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;对立的思维&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;社会的撕裂&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;种族的冲突等&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;目前整个美国社会都呈现出一种分裂的状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“现在美国不断&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;地&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;好战&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;不管是对以色列的支持&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;还是到处输出暴力的战争文化&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;肯定是影响了国内的民众&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”王义桅&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;分析&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;包括所谓的捍卫个人自由&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;永久持枪的自由等，动不动用枪支来解决对社会的不满，尤其是军队里面训练有素的&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;军人&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨震认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，近年来美国对外采取攻击性行为增多，不仅激化了社会矛盾，而且恶化了财政状况。一旦财政状况不佳，必然导致社会治理投入减少。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;他分析&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，美国是个移民国家，对外攻击性行为增加将会导致社会矛盾增加，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;且&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;程度远比其它国家高。而糟糕的社会治理导致枪支泛滥，警力不足，自然就会使得枪击案频发。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;值得注意的是&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，自2020年以来，美国联邦调查局对涉国内恐怖主义和极端主义的案件调查数量增加了一倍多。司法部建立了一个新的国内反恐部门，以应对不断变化的安全形势。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;“美国社会的撕裂仍在加剧&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;杨震判断&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;明年美国的大选将会进一步撕裂美国社会，激化阶级矛盾。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:25:09 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>