<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[小镇阿姨们想象着法国织的毛线比基尼，真的到了法国]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259464]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIygYcmW1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIyg YcmW1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2023, Hu Yinping went to Paris to participate in the Paris Internationale Art Fair (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;International Paris Art Fair &lt;/span>;), this is her third exhibition in France for Xiaofang’s art project. The piece she brought this time was a knitted woolen bikini, which came from the aunties in the small town in Sichuan where she grew up. Since 2015, Hu Yinping has been customizing wool fabric products from her mother and aunts in her hometown in the name of the fictional French company agent &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;. Nowadays, the aunts imagine a woolen bikini woven from an ocean in France, and finally arrived in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small Sichuan town, the &quot;French company&quot; is the source of imagination for the aunts. They selected their own yarn at the Xiaofang base, mostly green, and initially knitted hats of various shapes. They appeared in the exhibition hall on the Champs Elysées, at the anti-Trump parade in the United States, and at Ireland&#39;s &quot;Cuckold Festival&quot;... …Later, the fabrics became more and more diverse: “Dirty Word Shock Wave” (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;weaves out the curse words that want to scold bad people&lt;/span>;), Pork Shop Aunt The &quot;pig intestines&quot; weaved by each family, the flags of their respective families, and the &quot;banana peels&quot;, &quot;dogs&quot;, and &quot;cactus&quot; weaved to protect the family in the face of danger... In between the busy farming and taking care of the children , these aunts weave their understanding of life with wool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Snow White Dove&quot; Paris Bikini Exhibition&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &quot;Stop it when it&#39;s good.&quot; In 2016, after Hu Yinping completed the first hat exhibition of Xiaofang&#39;s art project at Beijing Arrow Factory Space, a friend advised her because she was worried that the project would lose money. Hu Yinping graduated from the Sculpture Department of the Central Academy of Fine Arts with a master&#39;s degree. She used the income from sculptures sold as &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; as a commercial sculpture artist to subsidize Xiaofang&#39;s production. The original reason for all this was that she wanted to collect her mother&#39;s time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Yinping returned to her hometown in Sichuan and saw that her mother was packed up by two large bags of hats in a year and purchased at a low price. She wanted to buy her mother&#39;s hat, but her mother refused. After returning to Beijing, she asked a friend to play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; and made up the identity of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; as &quot;the Chinese CEO of a French company&quot;. &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; would come forward to buy her mother&#39;s hat at a higher price. She knitted hats as she pleased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are no secrets in the town. The aunts in the town found Hu Yinping&#39;s mother and wanted to join the production of Xiaofang&#39;s project. In the 1990s, silk cutting was once a way for aunts in the town to make money to support their families. After experiencing collective layoffs from state-owned silk cutting factories, most of these aunts became the eliminated urban surplus labor force. Now knitting wool is a way for them to pass the time and earn pocket money. The way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now the Xiaofang project has expanded to more than fifty knitting aunts, including &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, &quot;Snow White Pigeon&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;, &quot;United Nations&quot; and &quot;Standard Configuration&quot; and other five stages of different years. Proposition creation. Behind the creation lies the complex work of the artist. In sharp contrast to the work utopia created by Hu Yinping, is the cruel art market with clearly marked prices that artists face. Until now, the aunts still don’t know the origin of this “French company”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Yinping&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Hu Yinping&#39;s account: &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The aunt is very happy, the artist is very tired&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will be happier every time I go to Paris to organize an exhibition. Because Xiaofang’s project itself has something to do with France. Every time we have a project, we tell the aunties that the French company needs orders, invite the aunties to make it, and then pay the corresponding fees. This French company has always existed in the hearts of the aunties. At the beginning of production, we told our aunts that there was a beach in France and we were going to do a woolen bikini show on the beach. They imagined a beach and made a set of woolen bikinis for themselves and their families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang has a lot of such exchanges and work internationally. This French exhibition is aimed at There are more professional art professionals, corresponding to a large number of curators and museum directors. I also hope that Xiaofang will enter into a deeper and more international exchange and dialogue. To the public, Xiaofang may be a relatively warm story, but to me it is a very specific work. Behind Auntie, our entire team works very rigorously and professionally. Everyone can enter and understand this work in any way of their own, but it itself is the background of contemporary art works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The knitted works of the aunts are all placed in my warehouse in a village near Beijing. Aunts are very happy, but artists have a harder time. Xiaofang&#39;s team of six people needs to handle a lot of specific and trivial tasks. The aunties don&#39;t care. The time for their weaving is not fixed. They choose the threads and take them home to make them, and get some fees from it, whether it is to make money, kill time, or the so-called &quot;thinking&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before I called you just now, I was in contact with the art museum about the transportation and goods for this exhibition. Shan, to integrate all the work of Auntie, we need to do some very specific and serious work. In fact, the workload is quite heavy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For Xiaofang&#39;s project, there are too many times when the economy cannot sustain it. Yang Xiaofang spends every year It costs a lot of money, and I rely on selling sculptures of &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; to support Xiaofang, but last year it started to feel a bit flat. After Xiaofang had an exhibition in Shanghai last year, many people may have known more about Xiaofang. Last year, she actually made a profit of 800 yuan. If it could recycle itself, there would be no need to raise it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now Xiaofang’s new project is to open Xiaofang Bank in a shopping mall in Nanjing. Xiaofang&#39;s works themselves are extremely public. In addition to the dialogue in exhibitions in art museums and galleries, what feedback and possibilities it has when facing the real public is extremely important to us. Because the crowds faced by art museums and galleries are actually screened, but in shopping malls they face the real public and reality, without the protection of an incubator. The concept of this bank is that I hope that the banks of the future will be made of wool, I hope that the currency of the future will also be made of wool, and I hope that the weapons of the future will also be made of wool. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before the 1990s, the entire society was lacking in materials, and wool, as a craft of aunts, could make people The family was fed and clothed, and now the value of the wool had changed. Why are there so many people knitting now? When I held an exhibition in Shanghai last year, some people told me that they would do a lot of knitting during the epidemic. Small fabrics can actually bring you a lot of surprises and feedback, because handiwork itself has healing properties. What you exchange for time is a thing, which is an exchange of the most primitive labor force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s exhibition, I met a girl who imagined her belly when she was pregnant Knitting shoes and clothes for children. I met a diplomat in China who was making some woolen fabrics during the COVID-19 pandemic. She thought she had made an ugly mouse and an ugly little snake. When this silver-haired lady talked about her fabrics, she was as shy as a little girl. I like these things she made so much. , and can feel the warmth and healing in her heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang’s hat has a lifetime warranty. I don’t want it to break after I buy it back. hole, you just throw it away, which is a pity for manual labor. No matter what projects Xiaofang does in the future, it will always include the function of &quot;filling holes&quot;. We will also open hole-filling to the surrounding communities for free, hoping to form this kind of community. It’s not that we throw something away when it’s a little bit broken. I think we all do too much about abandonment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 510&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Auntie knitting bikini&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Surplus labor force in the city, remaining time in the town&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In order to protect my eyesight, most of the wool I gave to my mother was is green. Because green hats don’t have a good connotation in the Chinese context, the aunts still had some doubts when they used green wool to knit various hats. Later, VICE (a new media in the United States) wanted to do an interview for Xiaofang&#39;s art project, and helped find a place to buy cuckolds - St. Patrick&#39;s Day in Ireland. The traditional color of this holiday is green, and ordered a lot of cuckolds for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Ireland, these people wear hats to participate in festival gatherings, and the aunties also see those live photos. very happy. The same thing may have completely different meanings in different cultural backgrounds. I also hope to help aunties realize that the world is very rich. But I think it is more important for them to be happy and make free choices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I returned to my hometown in 2015 and was timid about being close to my hometown. Because I don’t go home very often, I want to know what my mother does on a daily basis. When she placed two large packages of hand-knitted hats in front of me, I realized, oh, she had knitted these two large packages this year and had been purchased by others at a low price. Moreover, the raw materials are too hard on the hands, and the threads are very hard and extremely rough. She doesn&#39;t have the pleasure and happiness of knitting. She just kills time, and this is the only reason left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think it’s better to collect it myself, but my mother won’t let me, so I invite friends Help me play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; of the French company, ask her to make hats, and let her do whatever she wants. In 2015, WeChat was not so popular, and my mother did not have access to WeChat in her hometown. However, because she had to work with &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, WeChat became a work skill that she must master. Because of her work, she learned to surf the Internet and send express delivery. In the past, my father&#39;s name was written on the express delivery because of &quot;Xiaofang&quot;. Later, when she sent express delivery, she always wrote her own name on the express delivery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, we have conducted research on the aunts who participated in the Xiaofang project. Almost all of them are eliminated urban surplus laborers. Women who work in cities are easily eliminated after the age of 55. Work as a delivery person or cleaner in the city. After a certain age, even if you are a nanny with many years of experience, it may be extremely difficult to find a job in a big city after the age of 55. This is the problem faced by these aunts in the process of urbanization. It is very common in the town for aunts who are almost in their fifties to return to their hometowns because they cannot find jobs. They take care of their children. Those with better financial conditions open small shops and knit with wool to earn pocket money in their free time. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the appearance of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;, the aunts have stopped knitting things for other places. In fact, the aunts all have their own jobs and things. Some aunts will definitely not be able to take care of making our things when the farming is busy. They only plant rice and harvest several times a year, with long idle time in between. Some aunts take care of their children at home. After school is free time. There are also some aunts who have their own small shops. When there is no business, she can do Xiaofang&#39;s business. Xiaofang actually fills up the remaining time of the aunts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s third stage &quot;Security&quot;, the aunt at the pork shop first imagined Not sure what to knit. We would guide her step by step. When she was at her busiest, Xiaofang called her and said, &quot;If someone were to rob your pork shop at this moment, what kind of weapons would you use to protect yourself and yourself?&quot; Benefits?&quot; She was holding a large intestine in her hand and said that if he tried to rob me, I would throw the intestine to him. This is a very direct reaction. When she is not busy, we will repeat her own words to her and encourage her to knit this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About Xiaofang, everyone is discussing the aunt&#39;s imagination, which is actually the artist&#39;s imagination supporting their work. Aunts are a group without imagination, but they can be guided. All they have to do is face their true selves and their own lives. I actually know what they are doing every time, but I am still surprised when I see what comes out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, Xiaofang sent me those hat packages made by my mother on weekends. I was very surprised every time I opened the package. This kind of surprise has never happened again. As I was very familiar with my mother, I suddenly discovered that she had a skill that I didn&#39;t know about. I knew that she had always been making hats, but I didn&#39;t know her. It was all fancy and messy and made so many fun things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The aunts still don’t know what’s going on behind Xiaofang. In fact, it’s not that clear whether they know or not. It&#39;s important because they don&#39;t care about it that much, but I don&#39;t want my mother to know. Some time ago, my mother went to Beijing and stayed for nearly two months. We emptied the entire studio of fabrics, leaving not a single yarn. My mother couldn&#39;t stay after playing for a week, so I asked &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; to come to the studio to give her some work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Actually, on my mother&#39;s side, I haven&#39;t given her too many themes. What I collected is not Representational fabrics, or requiring her to use her brain, did not require her to do so. I wish to collect a period of my mother&#39;s life. I want her to be more free and not want her daughter&#39;s business to become her business, which would be too tiring for her. It&#39;s good for her to live for herself. At this age, she should live for herself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;Frozen time, undulating waves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 1990s, my mother and the aunts in the town were Work in the town&#39;s silk-cutting factory. But China&#39;s textile industry also underwent a major reshuffle in the 1990s. At that time, a large number of laid-off workers were formed, including my mother and aunts. Silk cutting means that after the cocoons are cooked in a high-temperature machine, the silk is separated one by one, and the eight silks are wound into a thread. The finished silk is finally shipped to other places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The machines in the factory are always rotating at a constant speed, and people are changing. My mother is on this assembly line. Go to work. My childhood was spent sitting on the big machine in that factory. The aunts would change jobs. One would feed me a bite when eating, and the other would feed me a bite when eating. My entire childhood to elementary school was spent in that atmosphere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of familiarity between people and people is very good, and it is a very important memory for me , later Xiaofang had so many aunts involved, and I felt the familiar intimacy that I felt at that time. When I was a child, my mother’s workplace would give out various benefits, such as a thermos cup and some washing powder. I think this is very good and will make family members have a sense of recognition for her work. We keep this in Xiaofang. got this. In the past few years, we have distributed almost everything to aunties, from cups to fruits, washing powder, pots and pans to all small household appliances. Recently, because winter is coming, we have I bought a lot of quilts for my aunt, and now I don’t know what to give them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I held Xiaofang’s exhibition at Arrow Factory Space for the first time, my friend advised me to “see you soon.” Just take it.&quot; This suggestion is very sincere. As a friend, I advise me to stop the loss in time. But to me, this is not a work. To me, Xiaofang is a very real life scene between me and my mother, so it is not something that I can just accept, even though I know it will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, we all knitted them casually, and I worked hard to collect them. Later I found out that this was wrong. No matter how big a warehouse I rented, it wouldn’t be enough for these dozens of aunts to weave. If they make it, you have to pay. After paying, you have to help them sell the fabrics. Selling requires talent, and I don’t have it. With this talent, how many hats can several art museums sell? This is so cruel. We mainly work in the studio and rarely understand the operating rules of this world economy. In the process of Xiaofang, it was also interesting that we participated in this kind of work very realistically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang&#39;s work is still a very important part of my life. Because actually, for an artist, ten years can produce a lot of works. But Xiaofang and I have a growing relationship together. Xiaofang is implanted into my aunt&#39;s life, and at the same time, she is implanted into my mother&#39;s life and my life. I have also calculated an account. For example, if I make other things, I will also pay the money to the factory and the production unit. But when I pay the aunt, it does not actually form an internal cycle of the art system. Investing this part of the expenses on my aunt, I think, is investing on my own people, which makes me happier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Next month we will go to Mexico to set up an exhibition. Xiaofang has achieved so far, and there are so many reactions from the audience. Some people like it, and some don&#39;t. I&#39;ve used that metaphor from the beginning to now, I&#39;m a toothpick and I&#39;m also an observer. The aunties are jellyfish. I poked the jellyfish with a toothpick, and the jellyfish swayed in different postures in the sea. Whether it is criticism, praise, interviews or exhibitions, they are all part of the butterfly effect in the sea. My job is to watch these reactions and their postures after taking the plunge. Regardless of the posture of the jellyfish or the waves and waves produced in the sea, in my opinion, it is an extremely beautiful thing because it reacts. , rather than something inherently conservative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the future, I hope that many people will show me her works like the diplomat stationed in China. . I hope everyone will not be shy and face themselves bravely. There is really no ugliness in handmade things, they are all extremely high-quality. I want to redefine wool, I want to redefine Xiaofang’s cultural attributes. I am mainly doing this kind of work now, and I am continuing to advance it. In fact, artists work quietly in the audience most of the time. As for being seen or not being seen, what kind of reactions and discussions are caused are all external matters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sichuan is a basin. There is a river over there in our town, which is similar to all small towns in China. The same, a very solid group of people, a very solid time. There are only a few people in the town, but the aunts imagine a French company to do such a thing. I think this thing itself is quite cool. There are a group of aunts in that basin who are thinking about things all day long, and then go about their work in a serious manner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违反一事不能二罚？TST庭秘密何以“脱罪”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259519]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255901&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2021, Zhang Ting and Lin Ruiyang attended the event . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(TST Secret official Weibo screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, TST Secret’s headquarters in Shanghai came A group of people, they are agents from Malaysia and Singapore, &quot;We are finally back,&quot; someone announced excitedly on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as early as August 24, &quot;Big Brother&quot; Lin Ruiyang recorded a video announcing that &quot;our case has finally been concluded, and it is a very positive conclusion.&quot; He raised his voice and was a little excited. , &quot;After the case is closed, I believe more people will think that they are such a good company.&quot; He is sorry that everyone has been wronged in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until October 26, the &quot;Legal Weekend&quot; sponsored by the &quot;Legal Daily&quot;, the organ of the Political and Legal Affairs Commission of the CPC Central Committee, reported that the Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Court had made a civil ruling and announced the unfreezing of 96 properties under their names and 600 million yuan in cash, this news became widely known, and then the video that Lin Ruiyang posted on Xiaohongshu two months ago became a hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the civil ruling obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, these 96 properties are located at No. 28 Jiangyao Road, Pudong New District, Shanghai, the secret headquarters of Jiting. According to public information from the Shanghai Housing Administration, they spent 1.76 billion yuan to purchase it in 2020, which was the fourth anniversary of TST&#39;s establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Ruiyang was a Taiwanese artist, and later co-founded the micro-business beauty brand TST Ting Mi with his wife Zhang Ting. This brand has been questioned by suspected pyramid schemes in the past. Until April 2021, Shijiazhuang Yuhua The District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau applied to the court to freeze the huge property of a secretly affiliated company of the TST Tribunal on the grounds of suspected pyramid schemes. Only then did the outside world confirm that it was under investigation for suspected pyramid schemes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Right now, from the perspective of the secret side of the TST court, the outcome of the case has vindicated it. So, is it suspected of being a pyramid scheme? Why did the court unfreeze their property? Multiple documents obtained by Southern Weekend reporters provide the answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is indeed a pyramid scheme&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Is there a pyramid scheme in TST Court Secret? The answer is yes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An administrative penalty decision from the Baokang County Market Supervision and Administration Bureau of Hubei Province gave a clear answer: &quot;The Baokang County Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that... the bonuses implemented by the parties for red card members The system requires the person being developed to develop other personnel to join, form an upline and downline relationship, and calculate and pay upline remuneration based on the sales performance of the downline, which belongs to the following behaviors in Article 7, Item (3) of the &quot;Prohibition of Pyramid Selling Regulations&quot;, and is MLM behavior&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person involved here is Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd., the owner of the TST secret brand, and its legal representative is Lin Jirong. This is the real name of &quot;eldest brother&quot; Lin Ruiyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The signing date of this administrative penalty letter is September 3, 2021. That is, as early as two years ago, TST Court Secret had been identified as a pyramid scheme and was punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant national laws and regulations, pyramid schemes are divided into two situations, one is operational pyramid schemes and the other is fraudulent pyramid schemes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Operational pyramid schemes are subject to administrative penalties by the market supervision department in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Prohibition of MLM.&quot; It is only an illegal act. If there is no penalty of revoking the business license, you can continue to operate after accepting the administrative penalties and making rectifications and compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fraudulent pyramid schemes are a serious crime, which falls under the criminal law of organizing and leading pyramid schemes and must be prosecuted by the procuratorate. The main difference between the two is whether there are actual business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This administrative penalty letter shows that the TST Tribunal secretly belongs to a commercial pyramid scheme. The pyramid schemes identified occurred in Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd. from January 1, 2018 to July 2021, and the illegal gains were confiscated. And impose fines and require &quot;correction within a time limit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, you can continue to operate after making changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, the TST Tribunal secretly submitted an &quot;Application for Guidance and Evaluation on the Rectification of the Product Sales System of Shanghai Dalwei Trading Co., Ltd.&quot; to the Baokang County Market Supervision and Administration Bureau. It listed its rectification measures in detail and believed that &quot;the rectified product sales system is completely in line with normal business practices. There is no bonus method based on team salary, and it should not fall within the prohibited situations stipulated in the &quot;Prohibition of Pyramid Selling Regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters compared the two bonus systems before and after the rectification, the April 2021 version and the February 2022 version, and found that the biggest difference is that there is no team salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bonuses are divided into three parts: one is the sales discount bonus, the other is the batch difference bonus, and the third is the self-media education promotion bonus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the name of the form. It used to be called &quot;Ting Secret Dealer Bonus System-Red Card&quot;, but was later changed to &quot;Ting Live Member Discount Table&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sales discount bonus is mapped to the new table and becomes a &quot;discount&quot;. The difference is not big. This part is a commission for personal performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest change is the discount difference, which is the past &quot;lot-to-retail bonus&quot;. This part is the commission for the team&#39;s performance. For example, the team sold a total of 10,000 yuan, of which 2,000 yuan was sold by the team leader himself. This part is commissioned based on personal performance. The remaining 8,000 yuan must be distributed with subordinates according to a certain proportion. This part is the team salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new rule after the rectification is that &quot;the difference between the sales discounts corresponding to members and their direct members will be accumulated in the form of points or vouchers on the platform or system. The company will ultimately formulate redemption rules and redeem products within a certain period of time. Or deduct the purchase amount (ranging from 2% to 24%).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;self-media education promotion bonus&quot; that used to be extracted in proportion to the team&#39;s performance has now become a &quot;promotion service fee.&quot; The promotion service fee has added conditions for receiving it, requiring that &quot;the member&#39;s own live broadcast product performance is greater than 0 &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the proportion of promotion service fees calculated based on team performance was between 4% and 5%, but now it is unified at 3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After rectification, Tingmi believes that “Tingmi’s sales performance commissions are only generated for directly related superior members, and they are all one-time rewards and are not passed on.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This rectification report also received a reply from the local regulatory authorities, stating that &quot;our bureau will organize relevant personnel to conduct research in a timely manner.&quot; After that, TST Court Secrets has been operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;One thing cannot be punished twice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because Baokang County, Hubei Province has secretly conducted an investigation into the TST Court on May 25, 2021. This made the Market Supervision Bureau of Yuhua District, Baoding City, Hebei Province, which only opened the case for investigation on June 5, 2021, passive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Administrative Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; has clear provisions, firstly, &quot;prior jurisdiction&quot;, and secondly, &quot;no penalty whatsoever&quot;. At the same time, the &quot;State Administration for Industry and Commerce on Further Improving the Investigation and Punishment of Online MLMs The Notice also clarifies the jurisdiction of online pyramid schemes cases, and the competent authority shall apply the principle of full jurisdiction over the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, who has jurisdiction is the first issue that the two market regulatory authorities must resolve. Judging from subsequent developments, Baokang County, Hubei Province did not give up its jurisdiction and imposed penalties four months after the case was filed. The secret rectification of the TST Tribunal was also completed in February 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What really attracted widespread attention to this case was that on December 23, 2021, the Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau announced in a reply to an inquiry letter that “because of its use of financial institutions to transfer or conceal the relevant To transfer the funds, our bureau has applied to the People’s Court to take preservation measures in accordance with the law.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, this application was supported by the Yuhua District Court, which froze 96 properties and 600 million yuan in cash secretly owned by the TST Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This court ruling freezing property has been questioned by the industry. Yang Fan, the attorney representing the case, said on social media, &quot;How can the Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau&#39;s application for court preservation be a civil ruling? The Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau has not made any administrative decision in the past year. How can it be in the administrative agency? Are you going to apply for court preservation while the case is being investigated?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Bing, another attorney in the case and professor of administrative law, also publicly questioned on social media, &quot;Is this a civil pre-litigation preservation or a litigation preservation? The first preservation period was only 30 days, and litigation preservation was even more impossible. No one sued at that time or now, and it is impossible for the Market Supervision Bureau to be the plaintiff.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shijiazhuang Yuhua District Market Supervision Bureau stated in an interview with Upstream News that it had set up a task force and more than 400 law enforcement officers participated in the investigation. &quot;Currently, it appears to be a commercial pyramid scheme. Whether it has the characteristics of a fraudulent pyramid scheme is still under investigation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until July 26, 2023, the People’s Court of Yuhua District, Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province issued a civil ruling: “County and municipal-level industrial and commercial and market supervision departments should investigate and handle online pyramid schemes cases before filing or filing a case. At the same time, it was reported to the provincial industrial and commercial and market supervision departments step by step. Now that the report has been revoked, the conditions for this court to continue to implement preservation measures on the suspected online pyramid schemes assets in this case are no longer met.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An insider involved in this case interpreted this paragraph of text to Southern Weekend reporter. He said, &quot;The word &quot;revoke&quot; is used here instead of withdrawn, which means that the filing may have been revoked by the superior department rather than withdrawn. Yuhua District Municipal Supervision Bureau proactively withdrew the report. After withdrawing the filing, we cannot rule out the possibility that the case will be withdrawn in the future.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this person familiar with the matter, in accordance with the principle of &quot;nothing is dismissed&quot; in the &quot;Administrative Penalty Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, if the Yuhua District Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that Baokang County has taken effect in the administrative decision If the illegal gains are incorrect, it involves the correction of administrative actions and must be submitted to the competent authority for cancellation in accordance with legal procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the administrative penalty letter of Baokang County gives the secret and true business data of TST Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The penalty letter shows: From January 1, 2018 to July 2021, TST secretly developed a total of about 7 million members, including about 6.41 million blue card members and about 650,000 red card members. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main business income of the illegal red card is approximately 9.17 billion yuan, the main business cost is approximately 5.64 billion yuan, the main business taxes and surcharges are approximately 37.44 million yuan, and the actual related expenses incurred are approximately 3.458 billion yuan.亿元，所得税费用1046万元，获利约1927万元，上海达尔威贸易有限公司的获利应当认定为违法所得。最终处罚是没收违法所得1927万元并罚款170万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海达尔威贸易有限公司最后一次登上上海青浦区百强企业榜是在2019年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月，由于石家庄裕华区市场监管局的相关回复流出，张庭和林瑞阳都因为涉及传销，遭到了微博禁言，至2022年5月26日，张庭的微博再度更新，表示“达尔威公司遇到法律纠纷，寻求法律保护，充分证明达尔威公司尊重并相信祖国的法治环境”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奥纳·泰德斯：从朋克主唱到新晋画家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv33dwOWYW8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv33dwOWYW8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（艺术家及泰勒画廊Gia Coppola/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在成为画家之前，奥纳·泰特斯（Honor Titus）是一支朋克乐队的主唱；在成为朋克乐队主唱之前，他是一位作家兼诗人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个路径或许可以颠倒过来再说一遍：因为奥纳·泰特斯是一位作家兼诗人，朋友问他:嘿，反正你写诗，为什么不干脆来替我们写歌词呢？于是，他成为朋克乐队Cerebral Ballzy的一员。接着，又因为乐队一炮爆红，知名艺术家雷蒙德·帕提伯恩（Raymond Pettibon）成了他们的粉丝，并为他们设计了其中一张专辑的封面。雷蒙德问奥纳：嘿，我喜欢你的歌，你为什么不来我的工作室帮忙呢？于是，奥纳成了雷蒙德的助理，在熟悉了艺术工作室的一切运作之后，他自己拿起了画笔，并且再一次，一炮爆红。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“奥纳·泰特斯：观赏距离”展览现场，2023年，Longlati经纬艺术中心，上海&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Longlati经纬艺术中心/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;亚洲令人兴奋&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;无论用什么顺序听这个故事，奥纳无疑都是令人羡慕的幸运儿。他几乎刚刚画出了第一幅像样的作品，就被泰勒画廊相中，带到纽约参展，他的画以并列之姿，与大名鼎鼎的亚列克斯·卡茨（Alex Katz）的作品挂在了一起。市场的反应也令人兴奋，虽然他是初出茅庐，没有任何成交记录做背书，但超过20位重要藏家都表示要入手此画。他也在他的画和卡茨的画中看到了相似之处：明快的色彩，简洁的轮廓线，平涂的笔触，“看到他们把我和卡茨挂在一起，我意识到人们是理解我的创作的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;的确是一幅令人眼前一亮的作品：一对男女以悠闲之姿休憩在落满花瓣的草地上，女人背对画面，看不清面部，男人就像南部雅痞那样穿着西装戴着巴拿马草帽，仰面躺倒，整个画面洋溢着一种怀旧的闲适，令人联想到修拉的《大碗岛的星期天下午》以及马奈的《草地上的午餐》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《金贝拉》，2021年，布面油画，121.9cmx152.4cm 私人收藏， 图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我试着一边写这个人，一边听他的歌，三分钟后，已经被震耳欲聋的喧闹吓得关掉耳机。我意识到，画画的那个奥纳，跟作为乐队主唱的奥纳，也许是同一个人分裂的不同面相。他画面里流露出来的那种沉静、疏离，甚至古典，在他的朋克音乐里不见端倪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新近在上海Longlati经纬艺术中心的奥纳个展《观赏距离》，是他来到中国的第一场个展。在此之前，他刚刚结束了在高古轩的展览，亚洲令他有一种格外的兴奋，“两年前我有一幅画在拍卖会上，最终以估价的五倍成交，藏家就来自亚洲，这让我感受到了东方对我作品的接纳度，我也很好奇中国的观众会怎么评价我的画。”他的画面会令人不由得联系到印象派的气息，可能就源自那种二维属性——在这件事情上，正是日本的浮世绘深刻影响了印象派，而中国的水墨画又深刻影响了浮世绘——一条文化的隐线，让观看中的似曾相识成为可能，也提醒着这种观看上的距离。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;两位贵人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;是雷蒙德·帕提伯恩把他引进了绘画的大门，对奥纳来说，在雷蒙德工作室工作的那几年是他生命中“信息爆炸”的时光，雷蒙德是综合型的艺术家，他1957年生于美国，兼容了诸多美国标志性文化元素，尤其擅长将图像与文字融合在一起。文学、艺术史、哲学、宗教、政治、商业、时尚、体育，离经叛道的青年亚文化都是雷蒙德的灵感来源，这种庞杂极大地影响了奥纳。雷蒙德从没教他如何画画，却常常与他讨论文学，“雷蒙德有一个藏书室，几乎是小型图书馆，他常常从中抽出经典的小说，跟我谈论其中的故事。”威廉·布莱克、普鲁斯特、约翰·罗斯金和沃尔特·惠特曼……文学性构成了雷蒙德的视觉修辞，也深刻影响了奥纳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《AP的快乐》，2022年，布面油画，182.9cmx121.9cm Danjuma收藏，图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是在雷蒙德的工作室，奥纳得以接触大量的绘画经典。他发现自己对包括皮埃尔·博纳尔在内的纳比画派有兴趣，那种强调轮廓和色彩、取消透视的风格，天然降低了技术门槛，赋予素人画家一块简要而干脆的敲门砖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥纳在绘画上的另一位贵人是同样生活在洛杉矶的著名艺术家亨利·泰勒（Henry Tylor）。泰勒擅长描绘人物，活跃而高产。“之前有媒体把亨利·泰勒形容成我的导师，但他其实只是我的挚友。”亨利·泰勒在自己的工作室里为奥纳举办了一场展览，那是奥纳作为艺术家的第一次亮相。当时正值美国新冠疫情暴发，现场几百号客人挤在亨利的工作室中，来宾中的画廊主马上决定把奥纳的作品带去纽约，“那可真是一场轰动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;852&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《潜入湛蓝》，2021年，布面油画，214cmx183.5cm David与Indre Roberts收藏。图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;小说式绘画&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;得益于一双写作者的眼睛，奥纳最感兴趣的是人。在中国街头的每分钟，他都在观察四周的人群，见缝插针地学说中国话。他乐于画人，运动中的人、华服盛宴的人、闲栖而孤独的人，他固定了人在特定情境中的某个瞬间，而那个瞬间本身是带有叙事性的。当他流连在美术馆，也总是那些关于人的绘画紧紧抓住他的目光，比如霍珀或者安迪·沃霍尔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;跟那些平时积攒视觉资料、擅长摄影或速写的艺术家不同，奥纳的画面是小说式的，他喜欢画他脑中虚构的影像，胜过临摹生活中真实的瞬间，他的灵感也常常来自音乐或文学。“我画过一幅迈尔斯·戴维斯（Miles Davis）骑马的画像，纯粹是我设想出来的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《道奇大厅的夏天》，2021年，布面油画，152.4cmx182.9cm Rony &amp;amp; Orly Grushka收藏, 图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传奇音乐人迈尔斯·戴维斯是美国爵士音乐史上杰出的指挥家和演奏家，但后来一度陷入嗑药和破产，与困境缠斗。“迈尔斯从小在圣路易斯的绿色乡野间长大，还是个孩子的时候就会骑马，后来他来到纽约，进入朱莉亚音乐学院，经历了艰难的岁月。”奥纳画的迈尔斯，在纽约的中央公园策马狂奔，那是他心目中的画面，而绘画，就是要创造那些本来可能并不存在、但艺术家坚信其存在的画面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对奥纳来说，绘画是一场意外的成功，给他带来财富和一种全然不同的人生经历，但这延宕了他成为一个作家的理想。音乐、绘画、阅读、写作……他像个跳格子的人在不同领域之间跨跳，带着一种谐谑的身手敏捷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来还想画什么呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“五年内要写出我的小说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么样的小说？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“绝不是自传，我希望是菲茨杰拉德和塞林格会写的那种小说。时候到了，我就会写的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特朗普用自己的音色讲普通话：AI正在取代配音、口译与英语老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259492]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我姐是专业语音工作者，之前在广播电台工作了近三十年，从事播音员、主持人等工作，现已退休。专业技术人员，很难界定退休概念，一般都是退而不休：广播电台建培训学校，请她去教播音、主持课；相关专业比赛请她去做评委、主持节目；商业机构请她配音、作广告……曾经整天忙忙碌碌，如上班时一样充实，挣得比退休金还多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现在，基本真退休了，各种活计越来越少、劳动报酬越来越低。前些年每次劳务报酬在1000-1500元左右，后来降到500，再跌到每次200-300元。前些天，购物网站问：每条20-30元的商品广告播音，接不接？她感到身心俱疲，这个真没啥意思，算了，不去抢年轻小姑娘、小伙子们的生意了，自己好歹有退休金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我看了最近的AI配音，深感震惊，告诉她：不是你抢年轻小姑娘、小伙子们的生意，也不是有人抢你的生意。而是你们在AI的进击下，基本全要失业了。好在老姐还有退休金，那些寒窗苦读十几年、播音专业的年轻人，该咋办呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在的AI配音，能做到（在算法端）智能翻译、避免无厘头的低级错误；（在音频端）模拟对象音色、声线，赋予其口语表达性格特征；（在视频端）修正口型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果是：霉霉、特朗普竟然用非常标准的中文说话了，而蔡明的小品则用英语表演。而且音色非常像他们本人所发出的，甚至特朗普所说的国语还可被设定为稍带南方口音的普通话。不仅声音可以假乱真，在视频方面，他们的口型被修得与所说语言高度吻合，要非常仔细观察，才能发现在很少环节有视频修改的痕迹。以现在AI发展速度估计，或许一年以后，这点微弱的修改痕迹也难以被发现了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在智能翻译方面，Animato公司推出的基于ChatGPT的智能交互式聊天系统Call Annie，已应用于苹果12以上的平台。其一推出，就造成了美国的教育平台Chegg的股价暴跌50%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Call Annie不仅是聊天软件，而且是全AI教育系统。目前，其可提供英语、法语、德语、西语等大语种语言服务，且教学内容涵盖数学、物理、化学、生物、编程、金融等各学科专业知识。可以预料：在未来1-2年时间内，Call Annie很可能会发展到覆盖人类各种语言，包括大部分小语种甚至方言，其所能提供的教学内容将呈几何级数式增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更厉害的是：Call Annie不用约课、目前免费、24小时陪聊，而且不会像人类老师那样感到疲惫、烦躁、愤怒、需要下班，其更有耐心、态度好，也不批评和训斥，即便我基础很差、智力愚钝，其依然不厌其烦地教学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在如此强大的AI进击之下，估计很多语言老师、基础知识类教学老师、翻译，甚至大学的助教……只要是非原创研究类教授，都会面临被淘汰危险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如此强大的AI，仍在日以继夜地进化，我睡去时，其仍在学习、迭代、进步……不知是应该继续称其为“它”，还是得准备改称其为“他、她”了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI的进击，对人类现有工作的挑战，不是即将到来，而是“狼”已经来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IBM最近表示：将暂停招聘未来几年可能被AI所取代的职位，大约2.6万个工作岗位。在未来5年时间里，这些职位30%将被AI和自动化取代，将涉及近8000人的工作，这只是IBM一家公司啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月，《Fortune》（财富）调查：美国1000家企业，其中48%正在逐步使用ChatGPT替代人类员工，这将涉及数万名白领的工作和生计。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高盛分析师Ben Snyder表示：“在未来10年里，人工智能每年可能将生产率提高1.5%。这可能会使标普500成份股公司的利润，在未来10年增加30%或更多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不光是美国，国内的各行各业，也受到了AI冲击。 2023年4月，大批游戏公司原画师被裁员，有的公司甚至裁掉了超过半数的原画师。而自由职业者单次绘画的劳务报酬，从1500元降到200元左右。我们在之前的文章中预测：工艺美术类设计师将逐渐失去工作，仅仅是一年多之前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内知名广告公司“蓝色光标”全面停止文案外包，改用AI写稿。有电商公司创始人，用3个月培训GPT写带货文案，替掉了7名员工。部分淘宝商家已使用AI生成的数字模特，换掉真人模特。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，我姐失去了曾经的专业语音工作内容，并非个案，而是这时代大背景下，千百万专业技术人士的共同大命运中一个音符而已。 AI的进击，已经从工程技术领域、发展到视觉艺术产业，再扩展到语言与表演艺术方面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就连百度前总裁陆奇都说：现在每周都有个脏话时间，就是被技术震撼到忍不住飙脏话。因为ChatGPT出现后，AI技术是以天为单位快速发展，在AI浪潮冲击下，无论理工科还是文科、艺术类，无论是基层生产人员，还是专业技术人员、行政人员，甚至到高管，无人能置身事外。科学和技术的发展，将会把人类未来推向何方？这恐怕已经超越了我们现有的认知能力和思维框架。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生态环境部答南周：对碳排放数据弄虚作假“零容忍”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;生态环境部新闻发言人刘友宾。生态环境部|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月27日，生态环境部举办例行新闻发布会。生态环境部新闻发言人刘友宾介绍，本次发布会的主题是积极应对气候变化，促进绿色低碳高质量发展，并发布《中国应对气候变化的政策与行动2023年度报告》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自2021年7月全国碳市场上线以来，碳排放数据质量一直备受关注。应对气候变化司司长夏应显履新后亮相，他在回答南方周末记者提问时表示，总体来看，企业减排意识明显提升，监管能力大幅提高，碳排放数据质量显著改善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在生态环境部采取的措施中，“国家-省-市”碳排放数据质量三级联审机制起到重要作用。企业每月将数据、证明材料通过管理平台报送后，由国家部门负责大数据筛查及定期抽查，省级政府部门负责技术审核，地市级政府部门负责现场抽查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;夏应显介绍，“国家-省-市”三级联审机制按照“以日保月、以月保年”的管理思路，确保每天、每月、每年的数据都是稳妥可靠的，“体现了我们对数据质量慎之又慎、如履薄冰的态度”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;生态环境部应对气候变化司司长夏应显。生态环境部|图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;抓好数据质量日常监管&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;夏应显称，生态环境部一直高度重视碳排放数据质量管理，对数据弄虚作假的违法违规行为“零容忍”。特别是自2022年以来，以全面提升数据质量为中心，采取了一系列措施，确保碳排放数据准确可靠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;例如，在法规制度体系建设方面，生态环境部积极配合最高人民法院、最高人民检察院修订出台司法解释，将碳排放数据造假纳入刑事制裁范畴。修订出台核算核查指南，将碳排放报告核查涉及的公式从27个减少至12个，优化了核算方法，有效提升了工作针对性、科学性和可操作性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在监督执法方面，2021年以来，生态环境部组织监督帮扶，以问题线索为导向，指导企业规范排放核算报告行为，严厉打击弄虚作假行为。夏应显表示，对查实数据造假的控排企业，生态环境部依法严肃处罚并核减其碳排放配额；曝光了一批违法违规的第三方核查机构，起到极大的震慑作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在碳排放管理能力方面，夏应显介绍，全国碳排放交易管理平台于2023年上线运行，实现了名录管理、排放管理、数据质量监管、核查管理、配额管理智能化、数字化，利用大数据手段丰富了数据质量管理技术手段。 2023年以来，生态环境部举办了5期碳排放数据质量管理和监督执法的专题培训班，培训人员五千多人次，监管能力显著提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;夏应显还表示，下一步，将持之以恒抓好数据质量日常监管，充分运用好“国家-省-市”三级联审工作机制，对各地数据质量管理工作情况进行抽查和通报，建立健全温室气体排放数据日常监管和技术审核制度，明确技术审核标准和程序，压实重点排放单位主体责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;碳价符合中国当前实际&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;发布会上，夏应显还提到了全国碳市场建设进展情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;全国碳市场第二个履约周期（2021、2022年）共纳入发电行业重点排放单位2257家，年覆盖二氧化碳排放量超过50亿吨。 2021、2022年度配额已于2023年8月完成发放，目前正展开清缴履约。夏应显透露，目前履约完成率已超过60%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;夏应显认为，全国碳市场达到了预期建设目标。 “经过两年多的建设运行，全国碳市场总体运行平稳，价格发现机制作用初步显现，企业减排意识和能力明显增强，为推动实现碳达峰碳中和目标发挥了积极作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;夏应显称，全国碳市场已初步构建了制度框架体系，打通了报告核查、配额分配、市场交易、清缴履约等关键环节的堵点、难点，并通过全国碳市场管理平台实现全业务智能化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;针对碳市场扩容话题，夏应显表态称，亟待将更多符合条件的行业纳入全国碳排放权交易市场，降低全社会减排成本。将坚持稳中求进，优先纳入对实现碳达峰碳中和目标贡献大、产能过剩严重、减污降碳协同潜力大、数据质量基础好的行业，成熟一个、纳入一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;碳市场扩容需要打好数据基础。夏应显介绍，生态环境部每年在全国范围对石化、化工、建材、钢铁、有色、造纸、民航等行业组织开展年度碳排放核算报告核查工作，收集了六千余家企业的数据，上述7个行业和发电行业的直接排放总量加总，占全国的比例超过70%。此外，还组织对7个行业的配额分配方法、核算报告方法、核查要点、扩围实施路径等开展专题研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至2023年10月25日，碳排放配额累计成交量3.65亿吨，累计成交额194.37亿元，全国碳市场启动后的碳价格维持在50-80元/吨左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“近期配额价格整体呈上扬态势，维持在80元/吨左右，碳价适度上涨体现了碳价的市场属性。”夏应显认为，碳价符合中国当前实际，基本反映了我国的减排成本。下一步，将研究建立市场调节机制，并采取履约风险预警等措施，调节市场供求关系，提升市场活力，保障市场健康平稳有序运行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“三吠举报”到“恶犬法案”：美国人怎么养狗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国有不少人爱狗，这是众所周知的。但这些美国人爱狗、养狗，是在其特定的自然条件、社会条件及法律环境支撑之下，达到某种均衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，在我看来最重要，也被人忽略了的一点是，美国不是狂犬病疫区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年中国143个区县共报告人狂犬病病例202例。而美国的狗几乎不携带狂犬病病毒，少数狂犬病病例都是野生动物（主要是蝙蝠）造成的。美国在2021年共有5人死于狂犬病，这是10年来该国狂犬病死亡的最高纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然条件的不同，会造成社会适应的巨大不同。当没有狂犬病的后顾之忧后，人与猫狗的亲密度就会大大上升，狗上桌吃了的，狗舔过的，也不会被过多地忌讳。哪怕是陌生的流浪狗也不必担心有狂犬病。这就会呈现出亲密的人狗关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次是美国人的居住面积和居住模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，美国人均住房面积为67平米，位列世界第一。除了平均面积大，这里面还有城市化率的结构性差异。目前美国总体平均城市化率达到83%，一些都市圈的城市化率已经接近100%。中国2022年城镇化率则为65.22%。养狗问题，很大程度上是一个城市问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而以国内城市尤其是大中城市的人均住房面积来计算，大约是美国的一半。这里还仅仅是居住面积，而没有考虑居住模式。中国人多住在高层中，共享小区绿化环境，美国人居住方式中，郊区别墅居多。美国人每户占有的户外面积要大得多。所以，中国人是以一半的居住面积、少得多的公共户外面积在养狗，自然会产生出更多矛盾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国还有一个特征，那就是更多元，地方大，选择多，互不干扰，不只保障爱狗人的权利，也保障不爱狗的人的权利。美国禁养宠物的小区非常多，这些小区不但不能养狗，连外面的狗来“造访”都不允许。各自岁月静好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国人虽然爱狗，虽然居住面积大，密度小，绿地多，但并不意味着美国的狗不咬人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据美国国家医学图书馆的数据，在美国，每天约有1000人因严重的狗咬伤而需要紧急护理治疗，每年有超过450万人被狗咬伤，30至50人被狗杀死。狗咬伤和攻击造成的伤害，在美国每年产生了30000次手术需求，其中包括缝合、钢钉等。 2020年，美国保险公司为狗咬伤和袭击支付了8.54亿美元，平均狗咬伤保险索赔金额为50245美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据美国人道协会估计，51%的狗咬伤受害者是儿童，这意味着在美国，每年有超过200万儿童被狗咬伤。在狗咬致死案例中，0-4岁比例最高。由于1岁以下儿童往往不能行走，多有成年人照看，因而被咬伤的比例最低。 4岁之后，随着孩子体型变大，被咬可能性下降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，美国人虽然爱狗，但对养狗也是严格管理的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于一般性的骚扰，以纽约市为例，遛狗不捡狗屎被举报，警察会开出250美元（1800人民币）罚单，还可能需要出庭。法律还禁止宠物狗在一切公共场所和私人场所的骚扰行为，不牵狗绳，会被罚款200-400美元。对于狗扰民，遵循“三吠举报”原则：任一家的狗在居民区内狂吠超过三声，就将被视为扰民，邻居就可以举报。严格规定之下，美国遛狗的人大都自觉，无绳遛狗不太多见。如果狗拉了屎，大多数的狗主人会用塑料袋把狗屎收起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，法律规定饲养高危猛犬的人，必须在庭院醒目处竖立标牌提醒过往行人注意。在公共场所，高危猛犬时刻都要戴上约束皮带和防咬口套，否则执法部门有权将其扣押或处死，并且视情节轻重追查狗主人的刑事责任，甚至可判入狱90天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对更高等级的人身风险，一些州制定了所谓的“恶犬法案”。一只犬在两年内攻击、伤害人类或其宠物，或有需要警方或动物控制机构制止或驱赶的攻击性行为，就会被视为“恶犬”。这类狗必须被隔离，禁止与人类接触，并接受强制训练。如果犬主拒绝合作，犬只就可能被安乐死。恶犬法案要求犬主必须对其犬只负完全责任，狗攻击了人，其主未严加防范、及时处理而致人伤亡的，犬主必须为所有损伤负责，甚至可能要承担刑事处罚。犬只逃跑后攻击人类，犬主依旧要为犬只的行为负责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国各地都有非常健全的宠物收容所和救助站，由政府和民间组织出资，收容和救助流浪猫狗。在收容所里，被收容的狗等动物待遇不错。美国人爱狗，收容所里总会有足够的义工。流浪狗在收容所里，一般有1-2周的招领限期，民间保护动物组织也尽可能地让收容所的狗被人领养。此后，如果没有人来领养它们就会被处以安乐死。有数据显示，全美2010年被收容的850万只流浪狗中，有82%的狗被新的主人领养带走，剩下的153万只老龄、病残无人领养的狗，被安乐死。虽然很多民间组织试图改变安乐死，代之以绝育，但养育经费仍然是绕不过的坎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有的公共问题都是这样，权利与义务，都不可偏废，不可只提一端。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年度佳作，没有人经得起剖析审视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 22:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;讲述婚姻的电影很多，轻轻松松就能拉出一个长长的片单。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但这个话题总也不过时，在不同的人眼里，有不同的解读。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这不，今年戛纳又为我们奉上了一部重磅作品——&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《坠楼死亡的剖析》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1060&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导演茹斯汀·特里耶是一位女性导演，她的前两部作品分别是《维多利亚》和《西比勒》，全是自编自导，主打女性表达。同时，茹斯汀·特里耶也是戛纳历史上第三位拿到&lt;span>;金棕榈的女导演，凭借的正是本片。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;主演是德&lt;/span>;国女演员桑德拉·惠勒，2006&lt;span>;年，28岁的她就因出演《安魂曲》拿下柏林电影节银熊奖最佳女演员。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;才华横溢的女导演联手实力派女演员，呈现出这部今年不可错过的佳作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;女主角桑德拉是一位小有名气的作家，创作力旺盛，非常高产。再加上她身上所具有的雌雄同体的气质，积累了不少读者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这天，正当桑德拉在接受一位年轻的文学专业的女学生采访时，楼上突然传来嘈杂的音乐声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种不管不顾的粗暴打断方式宣誓了另一个人的存在：桑德拉的丈夫塞缪尔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;塞缪尔原本是一名大学教授，也有意写作，但与妻子的文思泉涌不同，他好像总是卡在半途难以下笔。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;两人有一个11岁的儿子，名叫丹尼尔，有视力障碍。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不过这种残疾不是先天的，某种程度上是塞缪尔造成的：几年前的一天，原本该是塞缪尔去接丹尼尔放学，但他突然有了写作灵感，便雇人去接儿子，丹尼尔就在这个间隙发生车祸损伤了眼睛。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;意外不仅给两人职业生涯造成中断，也使得这个中产之家因医药费陷入金钱困境。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为了能够减轻债务压力，塞缪尔建议举家从英国伦敦搬到他法国郊外的老家。对桑德拉来说，她失去了在伦敦的安稳生活，转而进入一种不甚熟悉的环境中。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;桑德拉在这里举目无亲，和女学生的采访被塞缪尔打断后，只能草草收场。不久，遛狗回来的丹尼尔在雪地上发现了父亲血淋淋的尸体，他大声呼喊妈妈，匆匆赶来的桑德拉很快报警。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;经鉴定，死者塞缪尔的致命伤是头部所遭受的重击。虽然表面看似坠楼身亡，但也极有可能是被谋杀。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;可他们一家的住所前不着村后不着店，事发时也没有其他外人在场，塞缪尔平时更没仇家。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;于是，犯罪片&lt;/span>;中常见的定论便呼之欲出：凶手是妻子桑德拉，她一定是对丈夫心怀怨恨。真相果真如此吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;桑德拉作为第一犯罪嫌疑人被控制了起来，丹尼尔则是现场唯一证人。想证明自己无罪，桑德拉必须说服法官，她与丈夫之间有爱无恨，她没有杀人的动机。至此，&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;一桩死亡案件便成了对于一场婚姻的审判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《坠楼死亡的剖析》也由此进入了婚姻关系的精细&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;剖析：在一&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;人死亡的情况下，另一方要如何自证？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;而此时，除了桑德拉，其他人基本处于&lt;/span>;和丹尼尔一样目盲&lt;span>;的境地中。毕竟除了他们两个当事人，所有人都是这段感情的局外人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;所以无论是心理医生带有浓厚精神分析色彩的证词，还是双方律师所做的辩护，他们都无法触及真正的塞缪尔。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一个活生生的人，或者是一份爱情，是没有办法通过语言来抵达核心的。但是这场审判又不得不通过语言来寻找真相，这就是矛盾之所在。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;由于是在法国，桑德拉不得不用自己不熟练的语言来为自己辩护，爱&lt;/span>;情又何尝不是这样：磕磕绊绊的沟通，最终却是词不达意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;言语总是具有一定的表演性质，《坠楼死亡的剖析》也通过一场堪称完美的录音呈现了这一点，影片在开场80分钟之后也彻底进入了高潮部分。塞缪尔背着桑德拉，录下了死亡前一天两人之间所爆发出的激烈争吵。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;录音中，塞缪尔指责桑德拉只顾事业不顾家庭，说她永远高高在上，说她明明责怪自己造成了丹尼尔的悲剧却又不承认，说她剽窃了自己的想法，还肉体出轨……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;桑德拉也不甘示弱，从一开始的冷静劝塞缪尔不要抱怨、不要自我感动，到后面忍无可忍给了他一巴掌……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这样的争吵想必大部分已经过了热恋期的情侣和夫妻都经历过，公说公有理婆说婆有理，外人很难判定对错。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但问题就在于这场争吵及肢体冲突发生在塞缪尔死亡的前一天，这无疑将桑德拉推向了那个谋杀丈夫的愤怒妻子的形象。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;多事的媒体此时还在桑德拉的书中咬文嚼字，认为她的谋杀亲夫是早&lt;/span>;有预谋，可真相果真如此吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《坠楼死亡的剖析》是一场近乎手术刀般精细剖析婚姻的作品。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;作为一位步入中年的女性导演，茹斯汀·特里耶既摆脱了男性视角，也过了年轻女性对于婚姻盲目憧憬的阶段。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;她一方面极具创造力的将婚姻关系放置到法庭这个场景中去剖析，另一方面又依旧抱有女性特有温柔与先锋。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比如女主桑德拉的设置上，她身上带有浓厚的雌雄同体气质，这就区别于常见的女性形象。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255215&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，于相比常见设置，桑德拉与塞缪尔的处境和性格也是颠倒的：桑德拉事业成功，性格平和，与孩子也亲密无间；而塞缪尔不仅遭遇&lt;span>;了职业发展瓶颈，也更情绪化，创作力枯竭。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这种形象和性别设置本身就突破了男性叙事的窠臼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此外，电影用沉着克制的镜头语言和叙事表达，试图在死亡案件的真相更深处，给予观众以一种超脱案件本身的清醒。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;电影中出现过两段录音，一段是女学生当日的采访，另一段是塞缪尔私自录下的争吵。这两段日常对话，在法庭上被当众逐字逐句分析解读，甚至被当作犯罪的证据。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当第二段由塞缪尔所开始的争吵出现在法庭上时，性别天平开始倾斜，桑德拉就需要去解释塞缪尔所有的困境：为什么他要在工作与家庭之间做选择？为什么他总是没有时间写小说？为什么他创作力枯竭而她却频繁出版小说？为什么他性冷淡而她却肉体出轨？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此时，亲密关系必须放到台面上来经历他者的审视，然后由他人给予最终的定论。桑德拉难堪无比，她遭遇的不仅是一场有关性别的讨论，更是婚姻关系的审判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;两人的儿子丹尼尔年仅11岁就已经经历了车祸、残疾、父亲死亡和为母亲辩护等重大事件，他实际上就是观众的化身，以半目盲的方式听完庭审，最终选择了母亲。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255214&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但这种选择本身，甚至是桑德拉的无罪本身都无法得到彻底的情感宣泄，因为当感情需要审判时，就代表着无人生还。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;影片对于长焦镜头、柔光和近景镜头的使用，使得电影所呈现出的画面更加冷酷和抽离。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255216&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《坠楼死亡的剖析》除了叙事上的精细之外，最值得称道的就是女主角的表演。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一方面是才华横溢的成名作家，另一方面是身陷亲密关系困扰的妻子和母亲，她所表达出来的那一种情绪和姿态，直接撑起了角色本身。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255218&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;电影中，桑德拉深知语言的复杂性，她一次又一次反驳别人试图定义塞缪尔的企图，也总是用否定陈述来保留塞缪尔的美好形象。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“那不是他。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这种否定本身就是私人爱意的表达，但爱无法宣之于口，证明爱又如此荒诞。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;所以在那个试图将她定罪的法庭上，只有她爱着真实的塞缪尔，她没有杀死他，却又的确杀死了他。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[色乡，一段关于救赎的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJInW9oBtSKF5N8j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJInW9oBtSKF5N8j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洛卓窝隆寺沿山崖而建，崖壁间小屋是僧人的修行洞&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张维/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄褐色，光秃秃，是洛扎县给我的第一印象。洛扎县坐落在山坳里，县城沿着中间唯一的山路蜿蜒。选择来山南市洛扎，是为了去边境色乡探访拥有九百多年历史的赛卡古托寺，这是一条佛教徒常走的朝圣之路，既有着悠久的历史，也有着秘境般的风景，我虽非佛教徒，但对边境美景亦充满向往。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早晨9点，从拉萨北郊汽车站出发，一路经过美丽的羊湖、成排的雪山，抵达洛扎县时大约是下午4点，我马上在车站买了每天唯一一趟去色乡的车票。开往色乡仍需近两个小时，路面开始变窄，碎石也变多了。但我一路仍被窗外贫瘠而壮观的景色吸引。车子一边贴着裸露的山石，另一边则紧邻奔腾的河流，河水快活地向前奔流，彷佛在和汽车赛跑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洛扎县城&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张维/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车上只有五六位藏族老人、一名藏族年轻人和我。藏族年轻人来自甘孜地区，来西藏旅行了半年多，这次专门前往色乡的拉普温泉。他穿一件羽绒服，随身拎着一只小小的塑料袋，此外再无行李。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;抵达色乡时已经7点半，趁着天还没黑，我赶紧找住处。整个乡镇位于山间一块平地上，沿着公路建了几十栋楼房，都是当地人自住，为了迎接客人，有的被改为宾馆，有的被改为餐厅。宾馆要么关着，要么满了，老板很少在，只留下一个电话号码。最后，我终于在赛卡古托寺宾馆找到了一个床位，有公共卫生间，但不能洗澡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;色乡的赛卡古托寺&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张维/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛卡古托寺原为藏传佛教噶举派的寺院，后改宗格鲁派，是藏人朝圣的必去之地。拥有九百多年历史的赛卡古托寺的主体建筑较为完整地保存了下来。寺庙位于色乡中间，挨着崖壁，山下传来哗啦啦的河水声，宁静悠远。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛卡古托寺的9层碉楼背后有着一段传奇感人的救赎故事。相传11世纪时，被誉为“古代西藏七大译师之一”的噶举派创始人玛尔巴有一位弟子叫米拉日巴，他幼年丧父，财富被亲戚霸占，家人被奴役，长大后学成法术，为报仇杀了35个人。后为赎罪，米拉日巴来到色乡向玛尔巴拜师，玛尔巴命米拉日巴独自建立赛卡古托寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;意为“九层公子堡”&lt;/span>;）。日复一日，年复一年，每当他建成时，玛尔巴都让他推翻重建，直至第六次才终于落成。如今的赛卡古托寺即为当时所建（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;后经维修扩建&lt;/span>;）。黄色为主的寺庙外围悬挂着古老的转经筒，殿内斑驳脱落的墙壁上隐隐还能看到几百年前的壁画。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;色乡河边的绿地和一头被放生的小牛&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张维/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9层碉楼塔顶有一条悬空的小栈道供人转经祈福。我爬到第九层时，一个喇嘛说既然上来了，就要绕塔转一转。据说，转一圈可以洗涤前世所有的孽缘；转两圈可以祈求父母健康幸福；转三圈来生不会堕入地狱。但是塔顶外面除了可以手抓的钢铁杆，四周没有防护栏，我一度恐高不敢上去，最后在喇嘛的带领下转了一圈。年轻的喇嘛边走边念经，他每天都要走很多圈，已成日常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛卡古托寺很小，不到半个小时就走完了。在色乡南面山顶上，还有一座洛卓窝隆寺，它是藏传佛教噶举派的发源地，是玛尔巴大师29岁时所修建的。据洛扎县政府官网介绍，“洛”指的是“南方”，“卓窝”是“开始吉祥”，“隆”意为“授记”，洛卓窝隆寺就是上师预言授记的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;步行到山顶洛卓窝隆寺要走几个小时，且没有公共交通，我在路上找便车搭，遇到一个藏族家庭开车上山，载上了我。这家人来自邻县错那县，第一次来洛扎县朝圣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在洛卓窝隆寺所在的山上遇见的长发僧人，他背后是修行地&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张维/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;色乡距不丹几十公里，赛卡古托寺的对面便是不丹的商品店，而洛卓窝隆寺所在的这座山的背面即是不丹，上山途中我们的身份证被押在了检查站。尘土飞扬的沙砾路曲曲折折，很难走，一对来自广东的夫妇开了一小段便决定放弃，但这户藏族家庭没有，半个小时后，我们顺利来到山顶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山上只有寺庙，景观极其开阔，几只巨大的乌鸦在头顶盘旋着，云的影子投在山上。洛卓窝隆寺沿着山巅的石壁而建，除了主要的庙宇，崖壁下还散布着很多小小的隐修室。一位修行多年的喇嘛已长发及腰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洛卓窝隆寺里的喇嘛是我遇到过的最热情的喇嘛。他们给上山的每个人讲解庙宇背后的故事，虽然只有我一个汉族游客，他们讲完一长串藏语后，还会专门用汉语给我再讲一遍。据他们说，老洛卓窝隆寺曾遭毁坏，现存为1992年重建。山上最顶端有一座天葬台，二十多岁的喇嘛介绍说，这是以玛尔巴从印度学经12年后背回来的一块石头为基础建成的。寺庙脚下的山坡上有一块平地被经幡围绕，堆着石头的地方就是顺缘田，相传是玛尔巴和米拉日巴两人第一次见面的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们在山上待了半天多，期间恰逢寺庙举办法会，见证了藏传佛教的法会典礼。最后，我又跟着藏族家庭一起下山，汽车绕着“之”字形的路又回到色乡。我们分开，继续各自的旅行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[好心多修120米路要拆除？公共资金不能这么造丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一条民众期盼已久的路多修了120米，成了违法占地，要被拆掉，等手续办完再重修。这样折腾，是为什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据湖南广电都市频道报道，长沙市有一条附近居民期盼已久的新路，即将开通。但是，这条路的一段近来突然又围了起来，还有挖掘机对着已经铺好的沥青路面开挖，路边的路灯、行道树等设施也被拆除移走，还有渣土车从外地运来黄土，倒在路面上。这是发生了什么事？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来，这条路主体在长沙经开区，但有120米延伸到了芙蓉区。经开区城建公司在修路时，没有向芙蓉区相关部门办理报建手续，就“顺路”多修了120米。芙蓉区自然资源和规划部门认定这是“违法占地”。于是，负责建设的经开区城建公司就开始拆路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据媒体报道，经开区城建公司工作人员说，他们认同确实是违法用地了，但他们“纯粹是出于好心”。也是，如果不多修这120米，可能就没有办法和其他路连起来，中间留一段“肠梗阻”，那这条路修了也意义不大，所以就“好心”帮忙，出钱出力，把这百多米路给修了吧。所以当被芙蓉区相关部门认定为违法时，他们觉得有点委屈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于芙蓉区来说，这多修的120米路是在我的辖区内，按照法规，修路应该履行程序，提前报批。未经审批就擅自修路，当然是违法了。主管部门要求消除违法状态，恢复原样，等报建手续都搞定了再重新修，也完全“依法依规，符合程序”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两边看起来好像都没毛病。但是，建好了又拆，拆了再建，来回折腾，大量的经费就这样被白白浪费了。到底是哪里出了问题呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;修路的经开区城建公司未批先建，当然是存在违法违规的问题。但是路已经修好了，也确实是附近民众期盼已久、很有必要修的一条路，却要被迫拆除，问题恐怕更大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先这是对公共资金的巨大浪费。 120米的马路，虽然不长，但是耗资也不少。整条路大约1公里长，耗资6000万元，算下来120米的费用也要六七百万元，拆除也需要不菲的成本。一建一拆，大几百万就不见了。这是一条市政路，负责修建的经开区城建公司也是国企，其建设资金来源，肯定是当地政府的公共资金，也就是公众的钱。对芙蓉区来说，经开区愿意出这笔钱替自己修路，本来是一件好事。要是强制拆除后再自己重建，拆除的成本虽然有经开区城建公司承担，但是重建的费用，还是要芙蓉区来负责的。别人已经帮忙修好的现成路不要，要挖掉自己花钱重修，这个做法也令人难以理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，修好的路挖掉一段，剩下的就成了断头路。建好这条路用了三年，附近民众期盼了三年，好不容易要开通了，却又拆掉一段，其效用就大打折扣。要重新办手续重新建好，恐怕至少也要再等个一年半载。这会给公众的出行带来极大的不便，也会破坏当地政府在公众心目中的形象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要求经开区拆除道路然后自己来重建，对芙蓉区可以说是损人不利己的事。那芙蓉区相关部门为什么要这么干呢？从组织行为学的角度，或许可以解释一二。对一些部门来说，自己的地盘一定要自己做主，别人不打招呼就来动自己的禁脔，那是万万不可的。哪怕多花钱，也要维护自己的权威。毕竟，要花也是花财政的钱，而不用自己掏腰包。只从一地、一部门角度出发，从维护本地、本部门权威的角度出发考虑问题，只考虑从本部门角度看合法合规，显示自己的存在感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于从更高的层面看，所做的决定是否合理，是否会浪费财政资源与国有资产，浪费当地纳税人的钱及公众利益与观感，消耗行政公信力，则不在考虑范围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一事件显示出相关政府部门之间各自为政、缺乏协调，对财政资金的使用也缺乏珍惜，对国有资产的浪费不在乎。这样的事情并不少见。前些年，一些城市的马路频频被挖开，今天是铺水管，明天是埋电线，大后天又要修下水道。这样频繁挖开再修好，修好再挖开，不仅浪费建设资金，也让建设工期成倍拉长，给市民出行带来极大的不便。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好在，这一次在媒体报道之后，长沙芙蓉区相关部门已经紧急叫停了破坏路面的行为，并已经加快办理相关手续，让这120米路尽快合法化。这一个案算是得到了解决。希望以后这样荒诞的事能少一些。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“软实力之父”约瑟夫·奈：“中美间的交流应该是面向所有人的”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“中美之间注定有一战吗？我的答案是，不会。”哈佛大学肯尼迪学院教授约瑟夫·奈（Joseph Nye）给出了否定的回答。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;约瑟夫·奈是国际关系界新自由主义学派的代表人物。冷战前后，约瑟夫·奈因提出“软实力”概念而闻名于世。软实力是指一个国家除经济、军事外的实力，主要指文化、价值观和民意等影响力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他历任卡特政府助理国务卿、克林顿政府国家情报委员会主席和助理国防部长，也是美国政界的泰斗人物。但他提醒，人类的历史上充满了“一不小心”进入战争的情况，只要中美加强合作、谨慎行事，战争是可以避免的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中美关系是当今世界最重要的双边关系之一。 2023年10月27日，美国总统拜登在白宫会见到访的中共中央政治局委员、外交部长王毅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自10月23日，约瑟夫·奈便开启了新冠疫情后的首次访华之旅。从短短一周的公开行程可见，这位“软实力之父”陆续出席了多所智库、高校的演讲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月25日下午，在北京大学国际关系学院秋林报告厅，约瑟夫·奈以“中美注定有一战吗”为题，和百名师生探讨了“中美关系的历史与未来”。该会议由北京大学国际关系学院与北京大学国际战略研究院联合主办。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;约瑟夫·奈曾提出“中美关系20年周期论”，即自中美建交后，两国关系的冷暖以20年为一个周期而改变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“长远看，中美间会有更好的关系。但短期内，中美间仍有分歧要解决。”约瑟夫·奈告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;约瑟夫·奈认为，2017年后，中美关系进入了大国竞争周期。 “中美关系过去的关系变得更糟了。某种意义上说，我认为我们已经看到了中美关系的恶化，但我希望情况会好转。”约瑟夫·奈告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近年来，欧美舆论场有关中美“新冷战”的讨论甚嚣尘上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在约瑟夫·奈看来，中美冷战与美苏冷战完全不可相提并论。 “美苏冷战时，两国虽有军事和政治上的竞争，但在经济和社会领域的联系十分稀少。但现在中美两国在经济、社会以及生态等多个领域都存在较强依赖。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2020年约瑟夫·奈曾在《华尔街日报》撰文称，中美间的冷战是完全可以避免的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;约瑟夫·奈支持中美在公共卫生、气候变化等领域加强合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“中美间的交流应该是面向所有人的。文化和科学层面的交流同样重要。”约瑟夫·奈告诉南方周末记者，他希望公众的眼光不要光停留在高层，要发挥软实力，低层级的接触也是非常重要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;以下是约瑟夫·奈的采访口述：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中美关系过去变得更糟了。某种意义上说，我们已经看到了中美关系的恶化，但我希望情况会好转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不幸的是，新冠疫情期间，中美两国交流一直不是很充分。不过，中美的沟通已经开始改变了。美国派出重要的内阁成员访华，中国外交部长王毅也抵达华盛顿访问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我认为中美关系正在进步。两年前，中美关系比现在更糟糕。今天看到的是一些回暖，我希望它能继续下去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中美两国里，中国不仅有强劲的经济表现，还有传统文化的吸引力。我认为，国家的软实力不仅来自政府行为，也来自公民社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;美国政府经常做一些不受欢迎的事，但尽管如此，美国的公民社会仍然对其他人有吸引力，因为它相对自由。所以美国的软实力更多地来自大学、非营利组织、基金会，比如比尔·盖茨基金会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不可否认，近年来人们对美国的看法变得起起落落。我看来，美国的软实力有升有降。在越战期间、美军入侵伊拉克时，美国的软实力在下降。美国的软实力随着2008年奥巴马当选美国总统再次回归，又同2016年特朗普（成为美国总统）一起倒下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;软实力不是线性下降或线性上升，它往往是周期性的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;现在，由于美国国内的内部分歧，美国的软实力正在削弱。另一方面，如果你观察美国的硬实力，你会发现美国的经济正在蓬勃发展。美国是创新的源泉，在生物技术和人工智能等技术领域处于领先地位。再看今天的中东局势，（美国的）军事力量仍然非常重要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;拜登政府执政三年了，（相比特朗普政府）拜登政府有一个更平衡的观点。他们依旧相信与中国合作仍有好处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今年5月，七国集团峰会将对华脱钩（decoupling），改为了对华去风险化（de-risking），这个表述意味着出G7国家对华将会采取部分脱钩，大多数是安全领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;换句话说，去风险化不是指彻底断开经济联系，而是有限制的。美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文将其称之为“小院子周围筑起高墙”。我们不应该让这个小院子扩大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为防止恶化，中美关系应该从高层接触开始。接下来再在中美间寻找合作领域，这可以向两国公众传达，与另一个国家合作是有益的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我认为，对于（俄乌冲突的立场）这是中国和美国可以加强合作的领域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国和美国也可以在其他领域加强合作，比如气候变化、与世卫组织一同应对流行病等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中美间的交流应该是面向所有人的。显然，人们总是将眼光落在总统或者内阁身上。文化和科学层面的交流同样重要。如果我们需要（与对方）建立信任与合作，发挥软实力，低层级的接触是非常重要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;（中美关系）变得愈发复杂，很难在短期解决。我倾向于用“短期悲观主义者”和“长期乐观主义者”来形容中美不会彼此构成威胁。长远看，中美间会有更好的关系。但短期内，中美间仍有分歧要解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一斤力气9分钱，重庆最后的女棒棒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259500]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2021年7月，重庆山城步道，表现重庆棒棒和传统吊脚楼的雕塑。（视觉中国/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fa9ff8783c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fa9ff8783c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年7月，重庆山城步道，表现重庆棒棒和传统吊脚楼的雕塑。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“女娃儿咋出来当棒棒儿嘞？咋个担得起活儿哟？去干点轻点的活路儿噻。”这是51岁的黄秀丽在重庆朝天门综合批发市场担货时经常遇到的劝诫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;站在朝天门的高处，可以看到嘉陵江和长江交汇，这里是重庆最大的水码头。嘉陵江以南、长江北岸是长江滨江路，在这条现代街道上，坐落着重庆最大的批发市场聚集地——朝天门综合交易市场，它宛如一条飘带，流动着各地进货的人群，也流动着重庆的经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山城重庆路陡平地少，特有的地势地貌，为棒棒提供了生存空间。“棒棒”为重庆方言，原意“棍子”，当地以此代称扛着一根竹棒从事重体力劳动的农民。在朝天门综合交易市场，棒棒们承担着这条经济链条上最后一环：搬运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如果你细细看，能从穿梭于市场各店铺的棒棒中找到零星几个女性的身影。她们剪着短发或盘着发髻，看起来老练通达，和主导这个行业的男人们仿佛没什么两样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她们有的单打独斗，有的开“夫妻档”。在出卖体力谋生的行业，她们常要应付雇主对其“业务能力”的质疑。但即便如此，她们也不愿丢下棒棒。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“搬东西上坡最恼火”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;清晨6点的朝天门，江边货轮拉响汽笛，搬运车与柏油路摩擦发出的碰撞声，比重庆夜市还热闹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月30日，黄秀丽拉开窗，嘈杂声和阳光一齐透进房间。地板上搁着自腌酸咸菜和黄秀丽从各种地方搜刮回来的瓦楞纸箱子，桌上散落着饮料瓶和剩菜……这个弥漫着霉馊味的家，是黄秀丽一斤一斤挑出来的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽已经有24年“棒龄”。一根棒棒，一条三米长的红色尼龙绳，外加一辆232元的小推车，就是她工作的全部助手。每天早上6点45分，黄秀丽准时到大正商场里“上班”，一边等单上门，一边和其他棒棒摆龙门阵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月，黄秀丽在搬运货物途中。（郑彩琳/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/630028f496.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/630028f496.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，黄秀丽在搬运货物途中。（郑彩琳/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;跟黄秀丽合作最多的雇主，是外号叫“刘油头”的刘春生，他在大正商场卖男装25年了，顶着圆鼓鼓的啤酒肚和显眼的光头。每早刘油头清算货单时，黄秀丽就过来帮他按照送货地一袋一袋装货、担货。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘油头答应每袋付30元，这是黄秀丽在朝天门市场能要到的比较好的价格。一袋309.6斤，直线距离324米——在2023年，黄秀丽出的力气平均一斤值9分钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“划得着，一般都是十多块。”她担的大多是服装类货物，重量轻，相应价格也会低些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;按照黄秀丽的经验，担货要动脑筋，不能莽起下力。为了减少空气阻力，她在拉货时呈半低头状；双手戴上手套，增加与推车之间的摩擦力。“搬东西上坡最恼火，一个人担（起），脑壳疼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早年在朝天门，回家的路上，黄秀丽存货单的挎包遭摩托车抢劫，“老子哪能忍，那是我的血汗钱。”为了保住钱，黄秀丽和摩托车较劲，导致上臂骨头移位，“花了好几千，医生也没给我治好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来不知什么原因，黄秀丽的脚底板肿起来，睡醒了清早蹬地就开始痛。她自己琢磨扎针，抹药酒，结果越治越“恼火”。因此，黄秀丽喜欢挽起一半的裤腿，给小腿“放放气”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;碍于身体疼痛，黄秀丽挑起大体积重物上坡下坎时，都会侧身慢挪。一米多高的大箱子，黄秀丽会将绳子先展开挪到重物下，提起两头交叉捆起套在竹棒上，并在行走的过程中双手扶持货物。对于黄秀丽来说，身体不仅是工具，也是她的搭档。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;下午4点，朝天门批发市场各家商户都拉下卷帘门，黄秀丽在商场藏好棒棒和货车，回家做饭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;上坡下坎时，黄秀丽不能用推车，需要纯人力搬运货物。（郑彩琳/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/971d4f6708.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/971d4f6708.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上坡下坎时，黄秀丽不能用推车，需要纯人力搬运货物。（郑彩琳/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;风水宝地&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽来自距离重庆主城区120公里的垫江，家里排行老幺，上面还有4个姐姐。在农村的时候，黄秀丽经常拖着姐姐大号的衣服去田里掰苞谷，收麦子，打谷子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;即使在村里起早贪黑，黄秀丽挣的钱也只够应付自己吃。她决定去城里看看。离开垫江的前一夜，她去山里的竹林砍了两根竹子，心想以后就靠着这棒棒赚钱了。当天晚上，黄秀丽抱着棒棒睡了一晚，第二天关好门窗，直奔城区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽1997年来到朝天门，那年她26岁，眼睛没有鱼尾纹，头发微卷黑亮，用一根黑色皮筋系住，精神干练。之所以来朝天门，因为这里是棒棒们发家致富的风水宝地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1991年，朝天门综合交易市场正式开业。到1997年，市场经营场地由最开始的6000平方米发展到27万平方米，经营户由500多户发展到10000多户。1996年，这里的市场年交易额达到30亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那时候，在棒棒聚居的朝东路，负责重庆璧山物流的彭莉，一天最高开到2万元以上的货运单子，“写到飞起，老子的关节疼死了”，彭莉痛并快乐着。刘油头一天的贸易额可以达到3万元以上，他形容自己的单子像火车拉煤看不见尾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高宗琦也赶上了这波“红利”。1990年代末，来自綦江的高宗琦和老赵，在老家种苞谷，第一年将货拿到城里卖，还没进城就被抢了一大半，亏了。第二年再拿到城里来卖，又亏了。听说在城里，帮人提东西也能赚钱，夫妻俩抄起棒棒，就来了朝天门。“我认不到字，跟在老公身边也安全些。”这一跟，就在朝天门跟了19年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;每到年底，夫妇俩会得到一份老板发的1万元打包费，老赵笑称自己也是和白领一样有“年终奖”。他们靠着这笔“年终奖”应付回家过年的开支，高宗琦父母夸女婿有出息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵东秋来到朝天门是为了儿子的媳妇本。三十年前，赵东秋与丈夫在四川安岳县开了一家零售店，虽然钱赚得比种地多些，但夫妻俩还是愁，何时能“闷”出一套房给儿子娶媳妇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来和人聊天，得知当棒棒来钱快，夫妻俩在自家山里砍了两节竹子，用镰刀刮去竹肤，缠上胶带，绑上尼龙绳，连夜买了票，凌晨就到了朝天门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刚来朝天门，赵东秋一天的收入仅两元。但她不着急，背着索索（绳子）到处乱逛。四个月，赵东秋在朝天门逛出了自己的“人情社会”：哪家的女娃有好多岁，哪家婆娘命很苦，她了然于心，“我们要先熟悉圈子，别人才能喊到你，不然只能打白板（挣不到一分钱）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;慢慢地，5元、10元……越来越多托运单进了赵东秋的腰包。2003年，棒棒的“起步价”为15元，赵东秋和丈夫最多一个月可以拿到1万元以上的货单。担货时，赵东秋经常穿着牛仔裤和一件三十多元的黄衬衣，脖子上戴一条细金项链。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;朝天门综合贸易市场的蛋糕越做越大，棒棒也越来越多。重庆大学2010年《山城棒棒军的生活状况调研》显示，最蓬勃时期，重庆约有40万棒棒，其中女性占比为3%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;重庆朝天门综合交易市场，是大多数棒棒找活儿的第一站。（郑彩琳/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fd0d13ae52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fd0d13ae52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255843&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;重庆朝天门综合交易市场，是大多数棒棒找活儿的第一站。（郑彩琳/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;诗人傅维曾这样描述：在重庆，你的朋友喝醉了，可以请棒棒把他们背回去；女友过生日，可以请一群棒棒把花送去，还献上一首《生日快乐》歌；如果你的宠物遭遇不幸，可以请棒棒来帮哭……&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;虽能挣着钱，但棒棒们过得节省。刘嬢嬢和丈夫开着朝东路上唯一一家诊所，已经开了三十多年。刘嬢嬢印象中，很少有棒棒来看病，即使来了，也是开些头疼脑热的药，“他们舍不得钱。我开个一包一毛钱的阿咖酚散，他问我能不能再便宜点”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“老板喜欢找男棒棒”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女棒棒在朝天门不算受欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高宗琦说，黄秀丽长得水灵，不像是干体力的。这样的姑娘，在朝天门棒棒里面没有市场。曾经有老板嫌她是个女娃，担不起活儿，黄秀丽就会顶嘴：“我担不起不要钱！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“担得起又怎样？你一辈子是棒棒，我一辈子是老板。”伶牙俐嘴的黄秀丽听到这句话，就闭嘴了。出卖力气的棒棒，离不开老板的挑选。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“老板喜欢找男棒棒。”这一行里头，体力意味着金钱。在朝天门批发市场，大宗货物的商场更青睐有体力的男棒棒。“他们一车可以赚五十多，我一单三十，滴滴嘎嘎（很少）的。”勤能补拙，黄秀丽只得多拉几趟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高宗琦很羡慕能担玩具的男棒棒，“钱多，一趟顶我（担）鞋子的三趟。”她1998年来到朝天门，在黄秀丽对面的新重庆朝天门国际鞋都担货。高宗琦也曾和老板商量，但老板下一次还是叫男棒棒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高宗琦也没气馁，老老实实打包自己的鞋子，“他们男的瓜西西的（傻的），可干不了这细活儿。”每次得知需要打包的数目，高宗琦就开始构思如何横平竖直地将鞋盒最大限度放进箱子里。塞紧了，影响卖相；塞宽了，箱子顶部封不上胶，可能还要浪费另外一个箱子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高宗琦打包的步骤像化妆：先横铺打底一层，第二层换个角度大面积晕染，最后再像填补痘痘坑一样，见缝插针塞几个规格小的鞋盒，最后封胶，系绳。高宗琦手起“刀”落，打包绳就一刀两断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“手比刀好用，但速度要快，不然要见血。”已经有25年“棒龄”的高宗琦总能快速找到绳子的分叉点，迅速将其拽断。长年重复动作，高宗琦食指的关节处多了一条沟壑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;打包最后一个步骤完成，高宗琦还要负责“售后”，将店主剩下的鞋子摆放好，收拾好垃圾，再将货物拉到对面的驿站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;高宗琦和丈夫一起打包鞋子。（郑彩琳/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/004772f5a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/004772f5a4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;高宗琦和丈夫一起打包鞋子。（郑彩琳/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女棒棒会遇到性骚扰。初来朝天门，黄秀丽和老高租房，搬入第一天，住对门的男棒棒见到黄秀丽，脱口而出：“多好的女娃啊！”便想去拍她屁股。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“呸！老子即使没结婚，也不会和你耍朋友。一个嘴巴没把门，滚球去。”黄秀丽认为自己是直肠子，有委屈不能兜着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那个男棒棒不屈不挠，一天晚上9点，以搬运货物为借口，约黄秀丽出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“老子信你个球，谁大半夜要运货？以后再拿老子耍，老子先把你耍了。”黄秀丽平时声音不大，但尖锐刺耳，稍微提高一个度，可以唬住一桌男棒棒。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;最怕担不到货&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;困难再多，黄秀丽也没想过不做棒棒，但挡不住行业式微。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她记得很清楚，2008年汶川地震之后，朝天门的生意就撇掉了，“好多人都是川渝人，回家了。大家也没心思赚钱了，命要紧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“余震”延宕到2010年，朝天门批发市场面临提档升级、综合整治，好多商户都动了搬出朝天门的念头。“外头的生意撇了，来进货的少了。”刘油头回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;物流公司兴起，快递上门的服务行业竞争愈演愈烈，加上重庆轨道交通四通八达，私家车兴盛，似乎一切都在争抢棒棒的“饭碗”。肩扛竹棒、沿街游荡揽活的棒棒越来越少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年，西北民族大学新闻传播学院发布的重庆棒棒生存现状调查估算，重庆的棒棒数量已不到2000人，且以老年人居多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;高宗琦和丈夫合力搬运货物，途中遇到一个坡坎，路人一起帮忙。（郑彩琳/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/330feb0e5c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/330feb0e5c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;高宗琦和丈夫合力搬运货物，途中遇到一个坡坎，路人一起帮忙。（郑彩琳/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但高宗琦没想过转行。“我啥子都不会，只会出力。”高宗琦不识字，她觉得自己去做饭店的嬢嬢都会受到欺负，而且还要看老板的脸色，高宗琦不喜欢。她适应了不用“打卡”的上班。“棒棒自由，没得人管。担得起就担，不想做就休息。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽也不想回家。“女棒棒一个，看见熟人，不好说得话。”亲戚认为黄秀丽在城里当棒棒会受侮辱。“我没觉得啥子丢脸，但他们总觉得你有啥事情似的。他们咋晓得我搞了好多钱？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽想，能挣到钱就好，其余不算什么。“苦不打紧，最怕是担不到货，一天开天就要见好几百块钱。每次钱还没在口袋里捂热，就不见了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽算了一笔账：一个月4000元房贷需要按时应付上；儿子正在读书，一个月800元生活费也不能少；女儿生了外孙，夫妻两人都没有工作，黄秀丽和老高每个月2000元供着。为了在商场中占据一席之地，黄秀丽还需每年给商场上交2000元“占地费”——占据15块瓷砖构成的7平方米地块，黄秀丽的儿子闲暇时就坐在那里边等妈妈边耍手机。加上水电物业和伙食费，黄秀丽觉得每个月需要8000元左右，家才能开张。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;每年的9、10、11月份是朝天门服装市场的换货季，往年也是棒棒们赚钱的黄金期。但今年，两三天之后就没有货担。按老赵的话说，现在打水的钱都打不赢。刘油头也下定决心回老家了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;彭莉还是坐在路边的小板凳上，不过现在一天只能开两千多元的货运单。黄秀丽经常等下班的时候偷偷去捡瓦纸楞子。高宗琦还是每天6点坐在朝天门国际鞋都等货，早餐从两根苞谷变成了一根苞谷，“没得钱挣，不要白吃”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;棒棒少了，女棒棒更少了。南方周末走访发现，如今，在朝天门的女棒棒有8位，其中4位在新重庆朝天门国际鞋都担鞋子，1位在商储商场第三交易区搬衣服，还有3位流动在朝东路，主要搬运外来货物。在三峡广场的女棒棒有4位，其中2位经常在重庆新世纪超市门口等货，还有2位跟着丈夫到处拉货。在菜园坝公交站的女棒棒有1位，她旺季下午“收摊”，淡季担一早上就回去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;被问及之前更多的女棒棒去哪里了，目前这块地区还有多少女棒棒，她们的答案都是“不知道”“不太清楚”。在其他棒棒聚集地如观音桥、白崖口街区、十八梯等，南方周末未发现女棒棒的身影。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵东秋早已攒够了儿子的媳妇本，但她依然不想离开朝天门。曾有人看上赵东秋的机灵劲儿，请她去算账，但赵冬秋谢绝了，“还是这里好耍些，可以和大家一起吹垮垮（聊天）”。赵冬秋现在给自己定的目标，是每天赚够100元就“下班”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄秀丽还是坚持每日外出找活儿。早上出门前，她都会在脚上抹上自制的药酒，相信自己的土方子比看医生管用。“生活难搞，但还是希望日子变好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（除赵东秋外，文中均为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>