<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[布克奖得主弗兰纳根：活下去，比时代活得更久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3sGId82ZeAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3 sGId82ZeAd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Joel Saget/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The world is becoming more and more uncertain and disorderly. Since no one knows what will happen tomorrow, this story may remind them that in an uncertain world In this world, we still have each other&#39;s love, which is probably the only thing we can be sure of in this life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, the Australian writer Richard Flanagan (Richard Flanagan) wrote the novel The novel &quot;The Way North&quot; won the Booker Prize. The novel is based on his father&#39;s experience of being captured by the Japanese during World War II and building the &quot;Death Railway&quot; in Thailand and Burma. It tells the life of Australian military doctor Dorigo Evans in two lines: he tried his best to save lives in a prisoner of war camp and was on the verge of death. companion, when he is lonely and hopeless, he will continue to recall the only unforgettable love in his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Flanagan&#39;s writing, &quot;Dorigo Evans will live a long time and witness all the changes&quot; - he feels that something is withering, but he will live on and be better than himself Live longer...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a masterpiece about love and war,&quot; the Booker Prize citation stated. &quot;Flanagan&#39;s elegant narrative tells a story of the coexistence of sin and heroism.&quot; The story connects the East and the West, the past and the present.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flanagan was born in Tasmania, southeastern Australia, in 1961. For generations, people have lived in this &quot;end of the world&quot; &quot;The logging life on a desert island. Both his grandparents were illiterate, and his father was the only one in the family who received a basic education. &quot;My father had a strong feeling for the beauty and magic of words. He lamented until his death that people can use these 26 letters to glimpse the universe. Reading can enjoy freedom and transcendent power. The magic carpet of literature has lifted me from this world. Take a small island far away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, Flanagan published his debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;. He tells the story of the river guide Aliyah in a language that is freehand, dreamy, and full of original tension. Even through his experience of capsizing a boat and drowning in Tasmania&#39;s Franklin River, through the torrent-like confessions of the dead, Flanagan closely tied his personal experience to the mythical history of Tasmania&#39;s ancestors. &quot;I could write about the mud, the smell, the heat and the blood, but it was the readers who brought the emotion, the sympathy, the sorrow and the pity. The book didn&#39;t get many reviews at the time, but it gained readers, which is enough to give a book life .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late summer and early autumn of 2023, the new translation of Flanagan&#39;s &quot;The Road to the North&quot; and the Chinese translation of his new work &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot; were published in China. Hobart, the capital of Nigeria, accepted an online interview with Southern People Weekly. “Literature opened my eyes to the depth and breadth of each person, and the possibilities that are within each of us, both evil and good. When you realize that people can be everything, they can be murderers and When you are a saint, you can learn to look at the world with humility and understand that anything that happens has nothing to do with you, but is a way of our existence as human beings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The lower world is more real, The universe of literature points directly to human nature&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I heard that before becoming a professional writer, you worked as a construction worker and gardener, and you also considered going to northern Australia for mining. How have your past work experiences inspired you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed, I have done a lot of work, and these experiences have made me realize that most people&#39;s lives are so difficult. In order to have food to eat and a house to live in, people struggle to survive. They don&#39;t like their bosses, and their jobs are very menial and extremely hard. This is actually the daily life situation of most people in the world. I always tell myself that if I’m lucky enough to be a full-time writer, I’ll never forget those hard times and I’ll never complain about the difficulties of writing, because you’ve been given the extraordinary privilege of having the opportunity to do what you love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various experiences in the past have also made me discover that when you are close to those powerful and famous people, their world is not real, but when you are at the bottom, people are often very honest, and they are Tell the truth to each other, so you&#39;ll find plenty of truth. My grandparents were both illiterate, and I was lucky enough to become a writer. When I was with them and their friends, I could see a real world, but when I was with people who had achieved great things, I found that understanding The truth is much more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, the protagonist Aliash fell in love with a girl of Chinese descent, Kota He. You also wrote about the history of the He family. What original material was there? You also visited China in 2018, can you share your impressions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, I have some Chinese cousins. In the 19th century, many Chinese came to Australia and they intermarried with the locals, so many Australians Everyone has Chinese relatives. I wrote about China in my novel because I grew up in such an environment and I am no stranger to the Chinese. There was a period in Australia&#39;s history when racism was high and many Chinese were forced to leave, but thankfully that has changed again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I visited China last time, I talked with the Chinese writer Yu Hua. His experience was very different from mine, but we shared our thoughts on reading and writing. His literature The hero is also William Faulkner like me, and I find that our creative philosophies are also very similar. When you become a writer, you may enter forbidden areas, but you also belong to a literary universe, and that universe speaks directly to human nature. I was deeply moved by the fact that you meet a friend from far away, who writes a book from another far away country, but you share similar sources of inspiration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned your hero Faulkner. Faulkner believed that experience, observation and imagination are three necessary conditions for a writer. Which one is the most important in your writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Faulkner is not completely telling the truth here, because his experience is not rich, and mine is not. not much. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Laugh)&lt;/span>; I visited Faulkner&#39;s former home in Oxford, Mississippi, and he created that world out of his imagination, a kind of To a certain extent, this is also his observation of that world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing is a craft that requires long-term polishing, just like making furniture. Many times it is just the continuous improvement of ordinary labor, which is what Maupassant said: writing black words on white paper. But there is also a mysterious part to writing. The great jazz musician Duke Ellington once talked about his composition. People said that the piano music was so great. He said, no, it was a dream. I completely agree that all great creations are like a dream. When you dream, you will find that, for example, you are in Shanghai and I am in Tasmania, but we are connected, talking about the absent Yu Hua and the late Faulkner. You find that you are not just one person and one person. You are connected to everyone, even beyond time, space and life and death. All of this is you and not you. It is important to find this in imagination. This points to the highest realm of creation. When we reach there, we know that we are not you. No longer alone. Writing reminds me to share with others, and just as people can relate to a work of art, I think creators must bravely break into that place. Observation and description alone are not enough. We need to rely on imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;We are constantly corrupting as we move forward, and we are lost in the theater of emotions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Why is there always light at the beginning of all things?&quot; &quot;The Path to the North&quot; opens with this philosophical question. How did this beginning come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Parts of this novel touch on the dark side of the world. I think that if your creation involves darkness, it must be balanced with light. If all readers see is the dark side, they will not believe it, and they have reason to choose not to believe it, because it is not in line with our knowledge and understanding of ourselves as human beings. . If there is only darkness in the end, then it does not truly tell the whole story of human nature. The core of the human spirit lies in having hope. Without hope, we are just zombies. So, I chose to balance the whole story with light and hope. Therefore, this work is about war, but it also depicts love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, my first memory of light is actually in that church, my grandmother and mother hugged me, and I saw a beam of light coming over me, and it was the woman who loved me. running in their arms. As we age, we lose our sight, our hair... but I think the saddest thing is that we lose that sense of wonder. As a child, you retained this extraordinary and wonderful feeling that as long as you could see the light, you were content. I wanted to commemorate this flash of memory by placing it at the beginning of the novel, because it tells a truth that we have long forgotten. As we grow up, we lose this sense of wonder, awe and joy, but this was once It’s a great truth that we learn as children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;697&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The novel opens with a description of a little boy’s fear after his finger was injured and being bullied by his peers while playing ball. Have these details about a boy’s growth also happened in your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, these are more based on stories my father told me. Tasmania is not like other places. It is the poorest region in Australia. People here not only live in poor areas, but also live in older eras. I tried to write that feeling in the story. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the football story, once again, he ran into the light and felt the light. This moment embodies the profound feelings we had when we were young, and we can never go back to them. There&#39;s this misconception in the West that we&#39;re constantly moving forward and shedding innocence, and I don&#39;t buy that. We are constantly corrupting as we move forward. In fact, innocence is a treasure we once had, but we are too forgetful and have discarded many of the most basic things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Later, crying became a simple confirmation of emotion... Emotions have become fashionable, emotions have become theater, and as actors, people have no way of knowing who they are after getting off the stage.&quot; Can you give some interpretation to this passage in the book? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The world is undergoing tremendous changes. People now express their emotions more, but sometimes, the emotions they express are not Not sincere. It&#39;s not good to suppress emotions, but I think sometimes expressions in public spaces have gone too far. Whether people agree with it or not, this is one of the biggest changes in the past 100 years. I think a novel could reflect these kinds of changes that we talk less about. I wanted a character who understood these strange changes and documented them. For the protagonist Dorigo, this change is shocking because he has been playing a certain role his whole life. He is not a hero but has to pretend to be one because this is what the other prisoners of war demand of him. After the war, he had to continue playing this role, he had to wear this mask, and he knew it was a lie, but it had become a necessity in life for other people, so he agreed, partly because he avoided it. own emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What interests me is that when a person becomes a leader or a celebrity, we often think that they created this identity themselves, but in fact we &quot;created&quot; them, we decided to let them Becoming a celebrity or a hero, sometimes these roles are a kind of imprisonment for people. Celebrity and fame are some manifestations of misunderstanding and trouble. Behind this is loneliness. The fact is that the more famous you are, the lonelier you are. This is not a paradox. But the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life is alive, walking on the roof of hell, gazing at flowers&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The title and the first part of the quotation of &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot; are all quoted from haiku by Matsuo Basho. The last four parts of the novel are opened with haiku by Kobayashi Icha. Please tell me your considerations in choosing these haiku. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This book was difficult for me to write. At first I didn’t think I could do it. I didn’t want to offend my father by writing something that he felt was incompatible with his experience and seemed like a betrayal. It took me 12 years to write this work, and it also took me that long to find the most suitable way of expression. Finally, I finished this writing with love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t want to judge anyone, I just want to show what humans do to each other. I wanted to organize the book in a form that I learned from Japanese literature. I could use the most beautiful things in Japanese culture to present the worst atrocities in the same society. Writing it like this might be a way for me to liberate myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The structure of this book is a bit like &quot;Rashomon&quot;, looking at crimes from multiple perspectives, presenting different perspectives on the same crime, interspersed with Japanese poetry. I long to strip away all the trappings, and in fact, the more you strip away, the more you allow readers to discover the true meaning. When I write, I try to keep taking things away, cutting and cutting, so that what is left is something that the reader can find meaning and purpose in, rather than me telling him what it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Two of the haiku of Kobayashi Icha you quoted involve &quot; &quot;The World of Dew&quot;, how do you understand &quot;The World of Dew&quot;? What do you think of Eastern Zen thought? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Japanese militarism was deeply influenced by Zen thought&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(Note: The theory of Zen is one of the ideological weapons used in Japanese militarism&#39;s war mobilization. For relevant discussions, see &quot;Japanese Zen and Militarism&quot;, &quot;Misunderstandings of Modern Japanese Zen and Its Beyond&quot; and other papers)&lt;/span>;, There is a strange ecstasy in the latter, but the same ideas can also manifest themselves as evil when they advocate Japanese militarism. At the end of the book, I quoted a haiku: &quot;While I&#39;m alive/Walking on the rooftops of hell/Looking at the flowers,&quot; for me, that&#39;s the haiku that sums up the book. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2014, Australian writer Richard Flanagan (right) won the Booker Prize for his novel &quot;The Passage to the North&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;In the novel, you inserted the &quot;circle&quot; made with one stroke of the brush into the text. Could you tell us about your understanding and conception of this pattern? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a famous death poem by the 18th-century haiku poet Zomizu. Death poems are one of the traditions of Japanese literature. Before, Zhishui grabbed a brush and &quot;drawed&quot; the poem. People found that he just used the brush to draw a circle on the paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To me, the void, mystery, and reincarnation contained in this circle fit the theme of the story, and also fit the novel’s repetitive structure, echoing from beginning to end, “the magnificent wheel, the eternal return.” &quot;: The Opposite of a Circle and a Thin Line.&quot; At the end of the book, we don&#39;t know whether Dorigo is dead or alive. In fact, he never left the prisoner of war camp. Some ghosts trapped him in a special place forever: there is love and hell. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tasmania, we have a different concept of time: it often feels like time goes back and forth and never moves forward. I think this is a broader concept of time. We often move from this year to next year, and then to the year after that. What happened 10 years ago is in the past, but the aboriginal people here believe that what happened a thousand years ago It is happening today and it will happen again tomorrow. I think this more truly reflects our self-perception. The idea that what happened in the past is the past is actually an illusion. Nothing has ever passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people suffer from dementia, we say they have lost consciousness, but they have only lost their memory. Once you lose your memory, you cannot control your current life because people rely on their memory to understand everything. So this Australian Aboriginal concept of time plays a role in my work, and my novels are often presented in a cyclical structure, rather than being linear in a one-dimensional space like most English novels. Narrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The past can be forgiven, but cannot be forgotten&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;From &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; to &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot;, your writings have all explored the secrets of memory. You once mentioned, &quot;I have witnessed how people who have lost their memory fall into panic. .&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I&#39;m fascinated by the way people remember the past. We usually think of memory as a kind of witness. I tell you what happened 50 years ago, just like I have a camera. But in fact, memory is more likely to be an act of creation, capable of spinning lies as well as truth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father gradually lost the memory of the violence and pain he suffered, but in the end, he left behind the idea of ​​love. Although what he experienced was not love, what he finally had Memory was something he himself discovered to be valuable. I thought a lot about this, trying to capture the way people think through memory. Memory is thought to represent some kind of statement of justice, which it may or may not be. There is a paradox here: when people experience major trauma and you and your compatriots suffer great pain, the first thing people want to do is forget. I think the reason why humans survive is the ability to forget; but with At the same time, in order to free yourself, you must retreat into your memory and face the shadows in order to understand what happened and free your soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to war, we are fed a lot of lies about villains and heroes. When something terrible happens, it doesn&#39;t just affect the individual, a terrible war or social unrest, the trauma affects my family as well. and friends, will eventually slowly poison the surrounding community, and even the entire society. Because war is a black hole of horror, and those huge traumas are difficult to describe and spread. Those who have experienced it sometimes erase part of their memories. The responsibility falls on novelists, who try to piece together the past to better understand what happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your father once said: &quot;You can forgive the past. , but you can’t forget.” You just mentioned releasing your soul. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just said that people survive by forgetting, but they have to remember something, and people will hate it. You want to live because hate is a strong emotion, but ultimately, you can&#39;t move forward in your hate and you have to put it aside and find another way out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father experienced a very touching thing during his lifetime. About twenty years ago, three middle-aged Japanese women showed up at my house. They were incredibly brave and dedicated their lives to documenting Japan’s war crimes. One of them wrote a book about Unit 731, a horrific crime committed by the Japanese in your country. She suffered a lot in Japan for writing this book. She herself is actually a survivor of the Tokyo bombing, a horrific crime committed by the Allies against Japan that killed more than 100,000 innocent civilians. But she came to my house with two other ladies. They wanted to apologize to my father. They did not represent the government or the Japanese people. I was very surprised. I never thought that someone from another country would come to my house and apologize to us. It meant a lot to our family to apologize and it was such a release for all of us. The feats of these three women taught me that there is a way out, and that it is not about dividing people into opposing sides, but that we can rise above it all and live a better outcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salute to the open and free world&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You often mention your father, can you tell us about your mother and siblings? I know you are the fifth of six children, have they all read your work? Any feedback? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You did your homework! We were all very close as brothers and sisters, and everyone was surprised that I became a writer. No one expected a writer from Tasmania. They read my books and liked my novels. Being a writer and winning the Booker Prize are honors, but in any family, you are ultimately a son or a daughter, a brother or a sister, and what your family means to each other is the most important thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother was a lovely woman, full of stories. Tasmania was once the golden bag of the British Empire and a huge prison. Over the centuries, the British exiled felons here. Political prisoners, slave owners and slaves... all kinds of people came here. here. My ancestors are Irish, and there are many Catholics in Ireland. They gathered, intermarried, and settled here, forming a unique culture. Ireland is rich in stories and has produced many writers. I talk about my father because of &quot;The Road to the North&quot;, but I am very close to my mother. I have listened to her telling stories passed down from generation to generation since I was a child. Many of my writings come from my mother. Like women of her time, life was restricted and unlike Women today have all kinds of opportunities, but she was an amazing woman and I loved her so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How has Irish literature influenced you? Are there any Irish writers that you particularly admire? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I admire many Irish writers, but the ones who really influence me are Borges, Neruda, and Marquez , Cortázar and other South American writers, because their world is more like the world of Tasmania. We have people here who do comedy, trying to find their own experience, their own reality and escape the colonial influence of the British, while they were trying to escape the colonial influence of Spain in South America. The beauty of Faulkner is that he was both an American writer and not, he was from the South but was never really accepted into the United States, but he had an important influence on French and South American literature, and in my opinion he really was the 20th century The central figure who achieved breakthroughs in novel writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; Aliash was not born in Tasmania, but in Trieste. Why did he choose this small European city as his birthplace? Joyce lived in Trieste, does this have anything to do with where he wrote &quot;Ulysses&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s right! As you can imagine, Death of the River Guide was my debut novel, and I wanted my first &quot;child&quot; to be born in Trieste. Trieste is different from many places in the world. It is a mixture. It is freer and more open. It is not really Italy, it is not really Slovenia, and it is not really Germany, but it is all, all kinds of ideas. and culture meet there. What interests me is that Joyce wrote his great novel not in Paris, not in Dublin, but in this dilapidated, disintegrating old port. His writing was influenced by all these peoples, and he was deeply inspired by &quot;The Consciousness of Zeno&quot;, but the author Italo Svevo only used a pseudonym. He was an Italian Jew, and his real name was Ettore Schmitz. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another reason why Aliash was born in Trieste. My wife is from Slovenia. When I wrote &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, Yugoslavia had just disintegrated and Slovenia had just Birth. I am very interested in multi-ethnic countries where different ethnic groups live together and often have frictions and conflicts, but sometimes they are full of creativity. You just asked me which writers I am influenced by. I mentioned South American writers, but I am also influenced by Central European writers. Before World War II, especially before the 1940s, those great &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Central European)&lt;/span>; writers did not represent their own countries; Greater ideas at the time, but after ethnic cleansing many places became small enclaves. Australia, which was a very racist country for most of the 20th century, now opens its doors and welcomes everyone in and is a richer place because of its cultural and spiritual tolerance. Central Europe at the beginning of the 20th century allowed me to see a world full of hope. I made the protagonist in my novel live in Trieste to pay tribute to that open and free world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Hometown pain&quot;: I have never left home, but I feel vaguely separated from my hometown and feel deeply lost&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About your new work &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot; published in 2020, you once mentioned that this work is related to &quot;Hometown Pain&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（solastalgia）&lt;/span>;The artistic conception of this new word is related. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a new word proposed by an Australian philosopher: When a person&#39;s environment is destroyed and his heart is lost, I vaguely feel that I am separated from my homeland. I have never left home, but I feel the painful feeling of being a stranger in a foreign land. The term began to be used heavily after Australia experienced its horrific bushfires. That&#39;s the feeling one gets after a hometown has gone through some hard times and realizes that the good old days are gone forever. I think the trauma of so many precious things being taken away from us in the name of development and progress, which benefits only a few and deprives everyone else, affects us in very real ways. causing a devastating blow to the body and mind. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 17, 2018, one-way space in Beijing, Chinese writer Yu Hua (right) talks with Australian writer Richard Flanagan&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot;, facing a disaster, the heroine Anna keeps checking the news updates on her mobile phone, but her fear and anxiety only increase. Starting from the loss of a ring finger, various parts of her body gradually disappeared, but she felt no pain or consciousness. How did this idea come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We live in a strange time, with a lot of things happening to us, but we choose not to look at them. At the beginning of the novel, I quoted the English Romantic poet John Clare&#39;s &quot;Memorial&quot;: &quot;The ax of destroyers and selfish desires has cut down its prey; / I will never see the water lily path and the narrow round oak street here again / There are also large hollow trees like church pulpits: / The enclosure movement was like Napoleon, eradicating everything...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The enclosure movement in the 19th century was a very tragic and terrible event in European history. thing, but I think there&#39;s a new enclosure movement in the world now that&#39;s taking away from us those things that anchor us spiritually. People started losing limbs, eyes, knees...no one noticed, and at the same time we were checking our phones more and more every day instead of paying attention to what was going on in the real world. With the rise of social software, many people’s souls have been occupied. Everyone has a public life and a private life and a secret life, and great literature creates characters in conflict who do one thing and think the opposite, and there is a third side that they don&#39;t understand either. Why are we so contradictory? This is what we humans are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, these technologies allow us to display our private lives publicly, interpret our lives, and turn them into benefits to please others. This is a threat to us no matter where we are, and for most people, I think, ultimately, their presence is not to help us, but to exploit us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think you are a pessimist or an optimist? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Neither. In &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot;, Anna&#39;s mother said before her death that the world is so beautiful, but few people see it. I think the world is beautiful when I find those lovely people, but we often choose to turn a blind eye. The more we allow ourselves to see, the greater our hope becomes. So I am not pessimistic. I try to discover the simple beauty in people every day. I believe that this little bit of joy will nourish you and keep you alive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“助农”靠假货，走红靠演技？野生MCN怎么成了“凉山制造”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258014]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访《人世间》导演李路：“任何时代都是以小人物为分母构成的”丨影视大咖谈③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257479]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE6 3. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the TV series &quot;Human World&quot;, the head of the Zhou family, Zhou Zhigang, returned from the junior college after his retirement. &quot;Photographic films&quot; to my hometown and the urban-rural fringe area. Even so, it is difficult for the family to reunite and make dumplings during the New Year. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the crew)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV series &quot;The World&quot; shows the &quot;silent generation&quot; and also brings to life the &quot;silent generation&quot; generation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, it was China in 1969. In Jichun City, a provincial capital city in Northeast China, a young man named Zhou Bingkun experienced two major events: one was witnessing death row prisoners being paraded and shot, and the other was working together in a factory workshop My son&#39;s good friend was deeply shocked; secondly, his father Zhou Zhigang wanted to work as a bricklayer in the &quot;third front&quot; to support the construction of the third front. His brother Zhou Bingyi and sister Zhou Rong also responded to the call to &quot;go to the mountains and countryside&quot; and became educated youths. Zhou Bingkun and his mother depended on each other. The family&#39;s life trajectory has changed dramatically since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story unfolds from here, spanning fifty years. The five members of the Zhou family, who are from the working class and are the permanent residents of &quot;Light Word Film&quot;, are the center of the story, from which branches and branches radiate. In addition to the Zhou family, there are as many as hundreds of characters appearing in &quot;The World&quot;, outlining the &quot;big rivers&quot; of a generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play is adapted from the novel &quot;Human World&quot; by writer Liang Xiaosheng and Mao Dun Literary Award-winning novel of the same name. When director Li Lu got the novel, &quot;Human World&quot; had not yet won the award. Li Lu was so moved after reading it that he decided to adapt it into a TV series. His two previous masterpieces were the anti-corruption drama &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and the legal drama &quot;Itinerant Prosecution Team&quot;. Earlier, he was the deputy director of production at Nanjing Film Studio and the director of the TV Drama Production Center of Jiangsu TV Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Lu is ambitious in making TV series. If he wants to make a film, he must make a great work. The little characters in &quot;Human World&quot; meet his inner definition of &quot;greatness&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the project was finalized, Li Lu asked Liang Xiaosheng to meet. The first thing he asked Liang Xiaosheng during the meeting was: Why do you want to write this novel? Liang Xiaosheng told him that it was just some personal feelings at first. Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s father was a construction worker in the &quot;Grand Third Front&quot;. He left home in the mid-1950s and only returned every few years. After finally returning home to visit relatives, the &quot;educated youth&quot; Liang Xiaosheng went to the countryside again. He always missed his father and saw him very rarely. One of the reasons why Liang Xiaosheng wrote &quot;Human World&quot; was to make up for the lack of emotion. Especially after the death of his father, he felt that he should use words to pay tribute to that generation of workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation of Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s family is very similar to that of the Zhou family in &quot;The Human World&quot;. During the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, his father went to the third line, and Liang Xiaosheng and his eldest brother went to the countryside. The mother, brother, sister and one child were left in the family. Little brother. The elder brother suffers from mental illness, and the younger brother bears the burden of taking care of the whole family. Zhou Bingkun in the play has the shadow of his little brother. &quot;These young people who stay in ordinary working families in the city are almost missing in our literature, drama, film and television dramas. They are rarely shown and they are a silent generation. So I will write a book for them.&quot; Liang Xiaosheng said in the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Xiaosheng also had questions about Li Lu. He asked Li Lu: Why should such a novel be made into a TV series? Li Lu replied: &quot;I have feelings for the theme of workers.&quot; Seven years ago, Li Lu spent his own money to acquire an industrial-themed novel, but could not find a screenwriter. Like Liang Xiaosheng, Li Lu is also from the Northeast. When he was growing up, he witnessed the prosperity and decline of Northeast heavy industry, and also witnessed the pain and perseverance of workers in the face of being laid off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since &quot;Human World&quot; was launched on January 28, 2022, it has become a hot topic on the Internet. The angle of discussion covers all aspects and overflows the play itself - there are discussions about success and filial piety: Part 1 Who is more successful or more filial, the elder brother and sister from Peking University, who returned from school to become the deputy governor, and the younger brother who never went to college and devoted himself to taking care of the family? Someone discussed love: The old couple of the Zhou family have not seen each other for several years. Is there any love between them? My sister Zhou Rong risked everything for love and went to a mountain ravine to accompany the poet to live a hard life and become an educated youth. Years later, she had to face her lover&#39;s cheating and betrayal. Was her efforts worth it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the broadcast of &quot;Human World&quot;, Li Lu often received WeChat messages from friends. A doctor friend sent a WeChat message and repeatedly confirmed to him, &quot;Bingkun and Bingyi, are they okay in the future?&quot; ? No problem, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe this type of drama has become less popular over the years, so it really touches everyone&#39;s hearts.&quot; Li Lu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Lu remembers that when &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; was broadcast in 2017, &quot;There was feedback from all walks of life, including many provincial leaders who watched &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; during lunch and sat there with their lunch boxes. , as well as the people in the army and the grassroots of society, it is really a broken circle. This time we are also paying close attention to whether the circle is really broken in the true sense. Is it you who are shouting, or more people like it after dinner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;It must be warmth as the background color&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Original work by Liang Xiaosheng &quot;The Human World&quot; is called &quot;the epic of the common people.&quot; When you decided to shoot &quot;The Human World&quot;, how did you understand and sort out this work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was June 2018 when I got &quot;Human World&quot;. At that time, it had not won the Mao Dun Literature Award, and it had not yet won the Mao Dun Literature Award. It’s not called a “popular epic,” just a set of novels that have just been published. After &quot;In the Name of the People&quot;, I took on some projects, but I felt that none of them surpassed &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and &quot;Inspection Team&quot;, which made the cooperation team very difficult. They asked what kind of theme you should choose, and I said, great, just three words. Later, a literary editor told me that Liang Xiaosheng had just published a novel that you should read, but it was longer, with 1.15 million words. I read this novel and was very interested. But there is still a huge difference between text and visuals, and the reading level and viewership are completely different. Therefore, there needs to be an improvement from the novel text to the script, and there is another way to go from the script to the visualization. The 58-episode TV series now presented to the audience is an extremely compact version that we have made, because we rough cut it to 88 episodes, fine cut it to 72 episodes, submit it for review to 66 episodes, and finally compress it to 58 episodes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You hope to make a great work, &quot; &quot;Human World&quot; tells the story of a group of small people. Is there a connection between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To clearly see the huge power behind the words of the novel &quot;The World&quot;, this may not be seen by many people. How can writing the youth history of such a small family, an alley, and an area reflect the tremendous changes in China over the past fifty years? How can it have huge appeal and influence? Speaking of conscience requires discernment. Some people even questioned the Internet sense, and some questioned the age level of the audience, whether anyone would watch such a story about suffering, etc. I am the overall person in charge and the actual operator of this drama. From the selection of materials to the gestation and layout of this drama, I have always been like &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; (I signed the contract with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate Film and Television Center with my personal ID card). I know how to make this kind of play, who should be cast, and on what platform it will be broadcast. It is very clear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the filming of &quot;The Human World&quot; was finalized, I met with teacher Liang Xiaosheng. After meeting me, I wanted to hear Teacher Liang’s original intention of creating it. Just like when I approached Zhou Meisen, Zhou Meisen impressed me with just one sentence. He told me what kind of &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; he wanted to make and how to make it. This time too, after Teacher Liang came, I think everyone has the same point of view. They have a sense of mission. They want to serve the people, want to serve the common people, and want to serve the people and things of this era, which have undergone drastic changes in Chinese history over the past 50 years. Given visual and written proof, everyone still has feelings for family and country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years ago, I personally paid for a novel about factory industry, but I couldn’t find a screenwriter and no one would write it. I think this is also inevitable, because seven years ago we were still walking around in absolute entertainment, and no one would sit down and watch it when it was filmed. Therefore, the most important thing is that many things happen at the right time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The opening of &quot;Human World&quot; is about the years of educated youth during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; , what are your thoughts on the presentation of this special historical period? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Xiaosheng’s “scar literature” is “good human literature”, which has left a deep mark on the literary world. But this time in the TV series, we did not add more words to the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and the issue of educated youth, and used only a few words to represent a community. For example, the female educated youth who plays the piano is a southern educated youth from Shanghai. When she came to Northeast China, it was so cold. In her words, my hands were reserved for playing the piano and could not do menial work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there were many stories about educated youth like this, but we didn’t exaggerate or expand it, we just filmed the plot truthfully. She sacrificed a lot to return to the city, but even for such a small character, we didn&#39;t write her off without writing a single word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Scar literature&quot; was very popular during a historical period. Gradually faded out of public view. What do you think of scar literature, especially adapting it into film and television works that can be accepted today? What is the biggest challenge you face? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Scar literature&quot; is a term used in a specific historical period after the reform and opening up. Nowadays, it is no longer necessary to mention &quot;scar literature&quot;. It fits. &quot;Human World&quot; is not about scars, but about the fireworks of the world. It does not mock anything with a critical eye, but every little bit of life reflects the changes of the times. If you like this work, you must agree with the values. You can only do it if you have passion. If you don’t have passion, you can’t do it, so just shoot something else. I agree with the theme and values ​​of the novel &quot;Human World&quot;. What I did was make some convergences from the visualization aspect. When I was doing the overall planning, I determined that warmth was the background, and the adaptation would be centered around this. When filming &quot;In the Name of the People&quot;, the evaluation of the TV Drama Department of the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television at that time was that light holds darkness, justice holds evil, and this ratio must be used correctly. The proportions of our play use warmth as the base color. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Lu believes that &quot;Human World&quot; is not about scars, but about fireworks in the world, in which every little bit of life reflects the changes of the times. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the crew)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;There is a blue sky in any era, and the sun rises every day&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What changes did you make from the novel to the TV series? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We change words and scenes. There are many examples like this. Sometimes we change the line of action. The screenwriter condensed the original novel in the second creation, because you can&#39;t tell it too eloquently like the novel, after all, the episodes are here and the characters are here. Shooting is another conceptual matter. The on-site actors have some improvisations, the director has some improvisations, and there are even some desk adjustments that need to be made. Our cast of actors this time is of a relatively high standard, and they basically all have the same background in acting. In this case, the director&#39;s responsibility is to identify and identify, this is okay, that is not okay, and there is no need to ask them to act exactly as I want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Teacher Ding Yongdai plays Zhou Bingkun’s father. When he joined the crew, he had just finished filming &quot;Across the Yalu River&quot; and played Peng Dehuai. After he came, he kept his hands in his hands every day, like a general, so I became anxious, &quot;Old Ding, Brother Ding, take your hands off. You are an old worker now. Hunch your waist a little bit, be a little bit silly.&quot; Come on, we don&#39;t have thousands of troops here!&quot; He was really a good actor. He came back after a few days and lowered his body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These require the skills of actors, but also require the crew to create a creative atmosphere. Many people who came to visit the class were shocked. We had an RV lounge. Basically, no one ran outside when we were changing lights and lenses. We all sat there chatting and watching each other&#39;s performances. It was very quiet. No one was posing or running around. They were all quietly preparing for the next scene and the next shot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The protagonist in &quot;Human World&quot; is a &quot;light type film&quot; The Zhou family, as well as the various characters associated with them, total more than a hundred people. How did you arrange these characters? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I found the screenwriter Wang Hailu and invited her to come. Not long after, the new crown epidemic broke out and I returned to Beijing from other places. After reading more than a dozen episodes of the script, I watched it from night to daybreak. Tears filled my eyes. I was very excited and sent a long WeChat message to Wang Haiyu, saying that this direction was the right one and it was done. Teacher Hailu&#39;s refining and description of the topic is similar to the novel, but there are also differences. For example, the character Luo Shibin was my proposition. I said there should be such a person. He is a businessman, a generation of businessmen who came up after the reform and opening up. There is no one in the original novel, and Luo Shibin provided a color comparison board. Like Zhou Bingkun, he is a small person. He has no success in the worldly sense, but you can see the ferment on the Internet now that &quot;a stupid son will benefit his parents&quot; and &quot;the old trouble in the family is actually the warm baby of his parents.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We did not expect that the social discussion would extend to so many places, but the benevolence, justice, propriety, wisdom, trust, filial piety, and the warmth between people reflected in the light-type film are what we value more. , or in other words, there is still a corner of people’s hearts that has been missing over the years. You see the scene that often appears in Korean dramas, that of a family having a delicious meal. It is true that over the years, the population of our family has become more and more sparse, the flavor of the year has become less and less, the human touch has become less and less, the neighbors do not interact with each other, and the only child has no family community. However, although it is rare, you cannot say that everyone does not have it in their heart. They all have it, but they are not awakened. This play has an awakening function, which is to weave here the warm connection between human relationships, family, country, small and big things that the Chinese people have had for thousands of years. Following this direction, we removed some peripheral things and made warmth one of the main themes of the play, so that everyone can feel more about the great changes in China in the past fifty years, composed of officials, workers, and people from all walks of life. The product of hard work, dedication, and forbearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The appearance of Zheng Juan (Zhou Bingkun&#39;s wife) played by Yin Tao is surprising deep impression. It was obviously a shabby thatched house, a down-and-out woman without cotton pants, but the scene of her sitting on the kang skewering candied haws and making a living was eye-catching. What considerations did you take when shooting a scene like this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We spent a long time filming the scene where Yin Tao appears. If we go by the pace of a TV series, it would be very expensive. We spent a lot of time filming it. A lot of time is spent on lighting and scenery. If we follow the pace of some dramas, one episode in three days or one episode in four days, it would be impossible to shoot this scene. From our perspective, there is a blue sky in any era, the sun rises every day, and there are beautiful people in even the darkest corners, it just depends on which perspective you look at. Although Zheng Juan&#39;s home was bare with only a few broken cabinets and rotten cotton quilts, her beauty could not be blocked, otherwise Zhou Bingkun wouldn&#39;t have been so moved as soon as he saw Zheng Juan. So any age has its own unstoppable beauty, especially for our show. Disney bought the copyright a month after the filming started, and it wants to be broadcast around the world. So we have this awareness all the time, not only for ourselves. Every family, this play will travel across the ocean. You can be broken, but you can&#39;t be dirty. Your window grilles may be very poor, but they still need to be clean. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The protagonists in the play, the Zhou family and his son, especially Do you think the relationship between Bingkun and his father is a typical Chinese father-son relationship? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, Zhou Bingkun and his father are the kind of father-son relationship we are calling for or have had. Zhou&#39;s father worked as a bricklayer in the &quot;Grand Third Line&quot;. He was an eighth-level bricklayer. His income was not low at that time, equivalent to the income of a senior cadre. The lines are also mentioned. Since he got married, he has not met Li Suhua, his wife, many times. He took three years of family leave, and sometimes he saved it when he couldn&#39;t come back. One year, the Spring Festival was even eight years away. Come back, think about it, how many eight years does a person have in his life? Zhou Bingkun is undoubtedly the biggest male protagonist in this drama. The character who tells the most about the destiny of the whole drama is Bingkun. The novel uses a low-down perspective, a person who has not succeeded in the worldly sense, and the ups and downs of his life&#39;s destiny as the narrative point. I think this is the main reason why Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s novel won the Mao Dun Literature Award - little people, big heroes. Any era is composed of these people as the denominator. It is impossible for everyone to succeed and become a big shot. Life is the accumulation of countless Zhou Bingkun. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;In the Name of the People&quot; is your other It was a masterpiece that was not favored by everyone at the time. Unexpectedly, a theme film later became a hit. The same is true for &quot;In the World&quot; this time. What is your secret? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If there was a formula for making a hit, then everyone could make a hit. &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and &quot;In the World&quot; are two completely different genres and plots. &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; has a strong plot and a sense of time against the background of the anti-corruption craze at that time. But &quot;Human World&quot; does not have these two items. It has neither a strong plot nor a strong timeliness of anti-corruption. Instead, it is narrated. (They) are completely hits with two techniques and two styles. Hot hits are the result. Without the passion and thinking in this area, it would be impossible to make this kind of thing. It must be inspired by feelings, passion, and responsibility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[玉树光影澜湄源丨指尖华夏③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257583]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Yushu Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Qinghai Province, the birthplace of the Lancang-Mekong River has a pleasant scenery, with landscapes in the morning light and sea of ​​clouds The light and shadow change against the background, and the scenery is picturesque. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;499&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon in Yushu Zaduo County, Qinghai Province, a sea of ​​clouds appears over the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;511&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taken at Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai golden peaks surrounded by the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chadan Wetland, the source of the Lancang River, photographed in Yushu, Qinghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Chunjin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai, Lancang River A sea of ​​clouds appears in the sky. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[红河梯田上，那些逆流的追乡者丨月是故乡明③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257354]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Hani Village, the spring of the cattle herding class&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Yuanyang Hani Rice Terraces Airport Connection Line Construction has made the road conditions in the already extremely isolated mountain villages of Honghe County even worse. Most of the short 8-kilometer mountain road has turned into mud. It took more than half an hour to reach the destination of Qielongzhong Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Farmers resting among the terraces of Qielong Zhongzhai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;39 The 20-year-old Che Zhixiong picked me up at the door of my house and helped me carry my luggage up to the Datongbu room on the third floor of my old house. This is for investigators from all over the world doing ethnoanthropological research. Different from the village youths, he went to Gejiu, a major town in southern Yunnan, to work for two years before he was 20 years old. He then returned to the village and worked as a team leader and veterinarian. Six years ago, he began to organize nearby left-behind children and teach them to sing and dance traditional Hani. Song and dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun, the administrative village to which Qielong Zhongzhai belongs, is the birthplace of Hani multi-part folk songs, a national intangible cultural heritage, and Che Zhixiong’s father, Che Kesan, is the provincial inheritor. . In 2018, after attending the one-week village imaging training class of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; in the county seat, Che Zhixiong excitedly set up a Canon DV distributed by a charity organization, shot and recorded the life and festivals of Qielongzhong Village, and then recorded his The edited materials are saved to the hard drive for researchers from Kunming to take away when they come over. &quot;In the past three years, two 4T hard drives have been filled up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another house opposite the residence is Che Zhixiong&#39;s new home. . Last summer, with the help of 40,000 yuan in project start-up funds donated by a caring fan of Wang Yibo, Brother Che emptied the first floor and repainted it, turning it into a &quot;local imaging and cultural transmission hall.&quot; On the wall between the load-bearing columns, two LCD TVs are hung. The station at the door was broadcasting a CCTV set of the rice-planting gate opening ceremony filmed and produced in the village. When the rice-planting girl marries the young man from the field in early spring, the villagers who plant the rice-planting are all the bridesmaids and best men. Planting the rice-planting in a good field means marrying into a good family. Che Kesan frequently appears in the camera. As the ditch leader, he has to strictly measure the proportion of each ditch dug to ensure that the water from the forest reservoir flows fairly and accurately into the field ridges of each household. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV inside is Che Zhixiong&#39;s own &quot;Personal Film Exhibition&quot;. The sudden heavy hailstorm, the city children who came here for study tours, and the slaughter of cattle to worship the gods during the &quot;June Year&quot;, each section is an anthropological documentary with a complete narrative and clear rhythm. &quot;Most of my peers don&#39;t understand so many Hani rituals, let alone children. I only have a third-grade elementary school education, and all I can do is film and edit all the festivals here,&quot; Village Eyes &#39;People then use it to add subtitles. As for Kuaishou Douyin, it may occasionally attract attention, but it is not complete and even the surface is not captured.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New documentary director Che Zhixiong, Talk about your creative passion. He then pointed to the &quot;One Year&#39;s Festival Ritual&quot; display board on the wall between the two LCD TVs. For example, in the first month of the lunar calendar, the Hani people hold Lazuozuo and Angmatu successively, both of which are sacrificial ceremonies for the dead. &quot;Our ancestors will turn into little gods after they die, and they may come back to harass us. After death, the little gods will turn into great gods, and only then will they bless us. We kill cows for sacrifice to ensure that they can turn into great gods. . When the great god dies, it turns into dew, which drips down at night to irrigate the terraced fields and breed new life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It happened that an old man in the village was about to leave, so the driver took me to where the villagers kept watch. room. All the middle-aged and elderly people who stayed behind gathered here. The woman was in the back room, and the man was on the terrace, drinking pot-stewing wine just scooped out of a sealed earthen vat, chewing green chili peppers dipped in chili oil, and chatting in Hani dialect. The old man who smoked hookah encouraged me to be more generous, &quot;Go inside with your phone and take pictures.&quot; The daughter of the deceased man came back and told me, &quot;She is 80 years old, there is no need to stay in the hospital and suffer, let everyone have fun It&#39;s our tradition to stay with you.&quot; Later, most people would go home and sleep, but there would always be someone staying with them to wait for the final moments. Che Zhixiong carried the old man on his back, and while watching him the documentary he shot on TV, he told me, &quot;The bema (shaman) in the village will calculate the exact day to leave, and the funeral will begin three days before.&quot; . The posthumous affairs are more grand, and one or twenty cows may have to be killed and raised in the underworld for the deceased. This is not an exaggeration. Each of the children will have one, and if the spouse and family members have others, the beef will be taken back to their respective villages to be divided. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Longzhong Village keeps vigil at night. Che Zhixiong carries the departing old man on his back and watches the documentary he shot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun Village, where the village primary school is located, is only a 20-minute walk from the village. Less than ten children would go to the village every night to learn Hani dance from Che Zhixiong. The popular song &quot;Honey Baby&quot; with a hip-hop style has become a &quot;county dance&quot; vigorously promoted by Honghe primary and secondary schools, and children never tire of dancing it. The &quot;Music and Dance&quot; that has been passed down from our ancestors in production and life is more popular among energetic children because of its rich routines of squatting, jumping, lining up and circling. Accompanied by the cheerful beats and high-fives, I also followed the Hani cattle herding class and entered a selfless state of joy with nature and heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Zhixiong teaches children music and dance in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The young people of Yisa Town dedicated their entire youth to musical instruments&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Honghe County Government The town of Yisa is located at the top of a hill where two winding asphalt roads meet. At the highest edge of the ancient city, starting from the east gate with three floors and three rooms, a large and majestic ancient castle that combines Chinese and Western styles spreads out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a masonry town brought on horseback by local business gangs 90 years ago, and the primitive tribes who practiced slash-and-burn farming, carved wood and knotted ropes were upgraded into &quot;Little Shanghai outside the Yangtze River&quot;. Jiang refers to the Red River that flows to Vietnam and divides Red River Prefecture into two. Places such as Jianshui and Mengzi, which have many Han immigrants and are economically developed, are in the north and are called inside the river; while counties such as Yuanyang, Honghe and Luchun, which have developed world heritage terraced landscapes, are outside the river, which is backward. Yisa means &quot;drought and water shortage&quot; in the dialect of the Yi people who first came here to open up wasteland. During the Qianlong period, copper mines were discovered in the mountains, and immigrants followed the mining industry. These ancestors also experienced a history of prosperity and decline with the Qing Dynasty. At the end of the Qing Dynasty, the copper mines dried up and the new mountain people had no land to cultivate. They had to drag horses and go deep into the mountains and forests of Southeast Asia to do trade. They gradually developed from traditional caravans to tobacco gangs. In the early years of the Republic of China, the government&#39;s vigorous crackdown on opium led to a sharp increase in black market profits. Cigarette gangs organized and strengthened private militia to safeguard their vested interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; The French designers I knew drew drawings and hired Jiangnan craftsmen to build various stone mansions with European-style exteriors and Chinese-style interiors, row upon row on the hills. Since then, more men have dispersed overseas and reorganized their families, making Honghe County the second largest hometown of overseas Chinese in Yunnan, with more than 10,000 overseas Chinese distributed in 18 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wave of overseas immigrants on horseback has long been replaced by the wave of designated labor exports. But there are always people who insist on staying behind, such as Awen, the traditional musical instrument maker and inheritor I met at the east gate. &quot;Do you understand Honghe dialect? I can&#39;t speak Mandarin.&quot; Awen confessed in advance on WeChat. The craftsman who doesn&#39;t speak Mandarin must be an old man with a white beard smoking a hookah, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the bluestone road, the roaring Aprilia 150 motorcycle turned off its engine. The &quot;white vest&quot; on the car took off the helmet with the three colors of the Italian flag. The cool guy with a ponytail stepped forward and said, &quot;I That’s Ah Wen.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I went from the village to the county cultural center to work when I was sixteen or seventeen years old. Now I am 35 years old, and I have dedicated all my youth to musical instruments.” In the restaurant next to Daguangtang in the center of the ancient town, Ah Wen Wen continued to introduce himself. &quot;I quit my job last year. I know nothing but making musical instruments. I&#39;m so hurt by music!&quot; Although he was a little sad, when he was flipping through the various beautiful instruments on his phone, Awen became excited again, &quot;I ride a motorcycle. When I visited various villages in Hani, I couldn&#39;t put it down when I saw these treasures. Every sanxian and every straw have different materials, appearance and sound quality. They can&#39;t be made in factories. They will be gone when the older generation leaves. I can only Take photos and videos, listen to the sounds, and restore them all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dinner, we walked through the lush Xishan Park and walked to the musical instrument workshop next to the County Cultural Center. Master Wu Zhiming was lying on a bamboo chair. When he heard me say that he had just come from Qielong Zhongzhai, memories of his life came back to him, &quot;It can be said that it was them who started my career, and I played a role as a link between past and future.&quot; 1986 In May, when Wu Zhiming, who was employed by the County Culture and Sports Bureau, went to Puchun to collect folk music, he heard the eight-part chorus of rice-planting girls coming from a distance, and followed the sound to find it... Later, he changed from a county actor to a song and dance creator. and music theory researchers, and brought Hani singing and dancing to the world. Ah Wen and Che Zhixiong have traveled as far as Shandong and Beijing respectively, but their master and father have already traveled to Taiwan, Singapore, Japan and the Netherlands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Awen from Yisa Town Musical Instrument Making Workshop&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like those young and middle-aged people in the city who are separated from their work units and pursue personal values, Awen also worries about how to monetize his hobbies. &quot;Many scholars and teachers can only provide spiritual support, but &#39;Village Eyes&#39; has raised 10,000 to 20,000 yuan for me.&quot; . But there are many others, but even a small business loan of 50,000 yuan cannot be approved.&quot; With the capital, Awen can build his own studio and improve the efficiency of working all night and three days to make two sanxian. One piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still have to be realistic and start with a wind instrument that saves time and materials. Although it is not as good as the cucurbit flutes in the pedestrian streets of ancient cities, you should try to reduce the production cost first, and then put it into Go to the Samaba Visitor Center to try out the sales.&quot; Xu Tianming, an old colleague who still works at the County Cultural Center, reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming is from the Yi ethnic group. In June 2021, under the guidance of the state song and dance troupe, he and other colleagues rehearsed the first courtyard drama &quot;Caravan Women&quot; in Honghe Prefecture. The Wanxing Courtyard was staged by relying on money. As the name of the play suggests, it tells the stories of chaste women displayed in this mansion.舞者们，从开始灰头土脸的马夫形象，跳到后面成了喜庆归乡的洋装男团，望穿秋水的少女，最终熬成了提着走马灯、盼不到归夫的老妈妈。一个多小时的剧，虽是非常完整的音乐剧格式，但也因不是原生态演出，而单一化成了汉族风格的流行作曲串联，且因为费用没给够，配乐里时常传出尴尬的版权信息。万事开头难，票务告诉我，由他们这剧开头，接下来整个红河州各县市，都要打造出自家的庭院剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;空心化村落，城里人的度假乐园&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;许天明建议阿文去售卖竹笛的撒玛坝，位于山坡起伏缓慢的一头，是红河县最著名景区，有着1.4万余亩、4300多级的全球集中连片规模最大梯田。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;撒玛坝梯田&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张海律/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;景观梯田另一边的甲寅乡，虽是600年历史哈尼长街宴的发源地，但其间本该最好看的历史文化村落“作夫”，却没能保留下几间民族特色的蘑菇房，取而代之的是钢筋水泥房。追求一劳永逸的居所，当然无可厚非，不过，“很多村里老的东西别去动，收拾清爽就挺好，就像县城东门，姚、钱两家大宅，成为博物馆前，分别是公检法和拘留所，一直保留地用着，”在甲寅乡深处管理康藤·红河谷帐篷营地的柳志刚，作为外来经营者，对乡村保护和发展议题有着较为客观中立的发言权，“而距离甲寅不远有个土司府，就弄得很浮夸，以前哪可能那么宏伟。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打造高端度假产品的康藤公司，之所以将项目选择在景区之外，是因为得找方便改造的空心化村落。 “石头寨空了十多年，就只有一两户早在新村有房的人家，把老宅用来存放农具，我们拿过来做营地难度不大。”柳志刚如今忙碌着开发另一片空心化村寨，撒玛坝梯田核心区的苏红村。为此已经和县政府成立了旅投公司，聘请著名建筑师张永和担任总规划师，以“低介入”理念，打造分时度假地产，让城里人来过农村生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大雨过后，营地到苏红村的县道，竟被冲下来的泥石流彻底隔断，只得从有着上百道弯的狭窄村路翻下爬上。道边景观，从高海拔处被雨水浇灌过的木连、红椿，渐变到热气腾腾、阔叶遮天的茂密芭蕉林。过去的走烟帮，大抵也是经常这般，来回穿梭于高寒山区和热带密林间吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;苏红村一隅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张海律/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哈尼人的锄头抵不过敌人的铁枪。七千个女人变成寡妇，七千个小孩望不见爹娘，高高的秋千推倒了，三层的蘑菇房烧光了。”一曲哈尼古歌，曾哀叹先祖们一路战败、颠沛南迁的命运。好不容易安居在由哀牢山、无量山、澜沧江、元江、红河组成的“两山三江”区域后，在好伙伴老水牛帮助下，一锄头一锄头地挖出壮阔的梯田。而今，除了少数因原生态服务需求，而在营地工作的当地人外，对更多像阿文这样留在故乡的红河青年来说，城里人过来体验插秧、秋收、扎帐篷的梯田生活，他们再熟悉不过，也就不会稀罕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;追故乡的人&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“乡村之眼”昆明办公室电脑的NAS系统里，存储着车志雄拍摄的大量纪录片。这是一家帮助西部乡村农牧民通过自己的民族视角、以摄影机为工具、记录家乡生态和文化变迁的公益机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;介绍车志雄给我的，是他的同乡、刚毕业一年多的年轻小伙李旭东。 “我在一家民办高校学酒店管理，毕业后先在大理的高端民宿做过两个月管家，去年8月，看到有人在我最活跃的群里，发了&#39;乡村之眼&#39;公号一篇关于哈尼放牛班的文章，就被吸引来这家公益机构。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比村寨里那些外出打工的男同学和早早嫁人的女同学，96年生的阿东，是极少较早就有了自觉民族身份意识的青年。 “从大二开始，每年一到4月，我就请假，从昆明搭顺风车回家，参与组织隆重的矻扎扎节，写活动策划书、做主持人、做财务会计，穿上民族服装，跟着牛角号队，带着那些不再跟秧苗接触的小孩，到梯田里玩耍。这个节日，是哈尼人春苗插完之后的休憩娱乐时间，也期待几个月后丰盛的秋收。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿东还和4个好友，合作运营着一个公众号——追故乡的人。随时分享以红河县为主的哈尼族支系、服饰、仪式、音乐、诗歌等内容，发表老乡们的散文，并向家乡的中小学生发起征文活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;路遇哈尼村民&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张海律/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;红河哈尼梯田申遗成功已经8年了，让当地百姓有了文化自信。 “现在的情况，应该说是&#39;有进有出&#39;。回流增加了，年轻人是出去打工，但到了40岁以上，回来的就多了。同时半农半工的兼职身份，也让村民的务农积极性回来了。”红河学院哈尼梯田保护与发展研究中心主任张红榛，讲述了自己的观察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我所理解的五千年中华文明之精华]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257944]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China is a giant country in terms of population, land area, and history and culture. The late well-known archaeologist Su Bingqi, who proposed the &quot;starry sky&quot; theory about the origin of Chinese civilization, once said that what we want to build is a modernization with Chinese characteristics commensurate with the ancient country of five thousand years of civilization. This naturally puts forward the idea of ​​five thousand years of civilization. What is the essence, what is the national soul, and what is the spiritual pillar? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of &quot;Chinese nation&quot; was proposed by Liang Qichao a hundred years ago, but even starting from the Liangzhu Culture characterized by jade culture, the civilization creation of our ancestors on the land of China has exceeded 5000 years. The Liangzhu ancestors’ divine and animal facial patterns, head-up and head-down dragons, and tomb forms with obvious ritual connotations, all clearly show that they are an important source of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese civilization naturally has more than one origin. In addition to the Liangzhu Culture in the Taihu Lake area, there are also the Hongshan Culture in western Liaoning, the Yangshao Culture in the Central Plains, the Pengtoushan-Chengbeixi Culture in the Yangtze River Basin, the Longshan Culture that is a fusion of various cultures in China, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The basic spirit of Chinese civilization has gradually formed in the historical development, including the invention of square characters, the &quot;work&quot; of the &quot;system&quot; of the previous kings in the actual social development form, and the &quot;narration&quot; of the previous teachers, as well as The &quot;interpretation&quot; of scholars and intellectuals of all dynasties. Whether it is the &quot;new underground materials&quot; that are advancing rapidly in the modern era or the rich ancient documents dating back to Oracle Bone Inscriptions and Bronze Inscriptions, they can all help us today understand more deeply what the &quot;Chinese national spirit&quot; is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this understanding cannot only be directed towards the past. Although Zhou is an old state, its destiny is renewed. It is facing the future and participating in the present. Here, I try to summarize what I understand about Chinese civilization from five aspects: society, politics, faith, economy, and culture and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Society: Family Orientation and Individuality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a social perspective, we attach great importance to the value of a small community such as &quot;family&quot;, which leads to the spirit of benevolence and individual personality. growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benevolent people are the most important to people who are close to each other. To be close means to be filial to one&#39;s parents, to be kind to one&#39;s children, and to be friendly to one&#39;s brothers and sisters based on human blood and nature. And &quot;Old people are like the old people, young people are like the young people&quot;, and this kind of love is extended to everyone. Different from Mohism’s proposition of universal love, as the mainstream of Han culture, Confucianism admits that “there are differences in love”, but it still has a feeling of universal love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern people tend to value individualism first. Does this kind of &quot;familism&quot; conflict with respect for individual personality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a motivational point of view, parents raising their children comes from their own nature and is the best natural mechanism to help individuals grow. Family love provides relatively pure love and good emotions between parents and children. In terms of children&#39;s growth, the family structure can provide more support. From the perspective of ethnic continuity, this culture is obviously beneficial to increasing fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dear love does not advocate unconditional submission. If parents are at fault, the &quot;Book of Filial Piety&quot; advocates that &quot;there are faults in the family&quot;, but it only advises parents to pay attention to their attitude and methods. Mencius encouraged everyone to &quot;nurture my awe-inspiring spirit&quot; and &quot;even if there are thousands of people, I will go there&quot;. It is a kind of personalism with abundant independent consciousness and free spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in reality there are overbearing and irresponsible parents and rebellious children, this is precisely because they have betrayed the love of their relatives and cannot be blamed on this kind of balancing of family structure and individual personality. The social structure and value form of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family, a small community, constitutes a social unit, and the independent individuals with community and public care bred in it have become the foundation of the country. The laws promulgated by the governor should encourage this kind of love, but not destroy it. If conditions are created to make it easier for parents to raise their children and for children to get closer to their parents, it is care that nourishes this spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Political ideal: The world is for the common good&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the mainstream of our culture, individuals not only live within the family structure, but also naturally extend to the country and the world. To cultivate oneself, manage one&#39;s family, govern the country, and bring peace to the world, in &quot;The Great Learning&quot;, individuals need to constantly study things to gain knowledge, be sincere and righteous, and expand their areas of concern and efforts to the vast areas of the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When someone asked Confucius why he did not engage in politics, Confucius quoted &quot;Shangshu&quot; and replied: &quot;Filial piety is only filial piety, and friendship is with brothers.&quot; Politics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a social structure and cultural spirit, &quot;keeping the family together&quot; is already a part of public affairs. Expanding this spirit to a wider social space is also &quot;for government&quot; rather than for government. You must &quot;serve as an official in the government&quot; to enter politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern families are families of three or four, but in Chinese history, unless official laws deliberately required &quot;family separation&quot; to weaken the organizational strength of small communities, our culture often praised &quot;multi-generational families&quot;. &quot;Together under the same roof&quot; encourages large families to live together and help each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of large family living together combines the principles of &quot;kinship&quot;, &quot;respect for respect&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; to form the social autonomy of a small community. From this, the tradition of gentry autonomy was derived. This made it possible to create a &quot;small government, big society&quot; where the imperial power did not extend to the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhou system of feudalism and founding of the country directly used family as a link to establish the basic political order of the entire Chinese world: on the one hand, the eldest son inheritance system was implemented to ensure the institutionalization and stability of the inheritance of power; On the one hand, talented people are selected to govern. Of course, the Zhou system still embodies moral governance in the family and the world, and the degree of openness of power is still limited. In the political field, the value that best embodies the spirit of the Chinese nation is the spirit of &quot;the world is for the common good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original text of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; is: In the journey of the great road, the world is for the common good, selecting talents and talents, adhering to trust and cultivating harmony, old friends do not only kiss their relatives, do not only give birth to their children, so that the old will die well. The strong have their uses, the young have their talents, and those who are modest, widowed, lonely, and lonely are all supported... Another example is &quot;The king and his ministers are united by righteousness.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s not all about the same surname&quot;... These political thoughts, which exude eternal brilliance, have broken through the &quot;kinship&quot; principle of the family and become a concrete manifestation of the commonwealth of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since selfish desires are difficult to eliminate, it is extremely difficult to achieve the goal of serving the world for the common good. Needless to say, the Qin system, from the Han and Tang dynasties to the Song, Ming and Qing dynasties, the separation of imperial power and prime ministerial power, the system of admonishing officials and historians, the feudal system throughout the Han, Tang, and Song dynasties, the education of princes, and the system of co-governance of scholar-bureaucrats, etc., are only partial and It plays a certain role in the short term. Royal power is never truly under the law. The Chinese nation’s political spirit of “the world is for the common good” is so premature and yet so immature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the famous &quot;Debate between Righteousness, Benefit and Overlord&quot; with Chen Liang, Zhu Xi lamented decisively: For fifteen hundred years, he was just sitting on this, so it was just a matter of time to make up for it. Although there may have been some moderate prosperity during this period, the Tao taught by the three kings Yao and Shun, Zhou Gong and Confucius, has not yet been practiced in heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the political standard of the world for the common good continues to exist. Whether to put the interests and happiness of the people first in governance, and whether to keep the economic, social and spiritual life vigorous and prosperous? These political requirements for governors are also an important dimension of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Economy: People have permanent property&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the economy, how does &quot;the world is for the common good&quot; be reflected? For the government, it is &quot;the king, why should he call it profit&quot;. From the emperor, princes to officials, managers at all levels should not compete with the people for profit; for the common people, it is &quot;those who have permanent property have perseverance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to do this specifically? What the government wants to do is to &quot;benefit the people according to their interests&quot; and naturally carry out production, trade and consumption activities based on the needs of the people in the world. Therefore, in the choice between cannon and butter, butter obviously takes precedence. This only requires the establishment of a service-oriented government that provides &quot;benefits at no cost&quot; and cannot compete with the people for profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Benevolent government must start from the borders.” The basis for the interests of the people is to ensure that citizens have their own three-acre land, and they can use their own land according to their personal and family interests. Judgment, to produce and trade. Although Mencius&#39;s proposition mainly focused on delimiting the boundaries of mine fields, its essence pointed to the determination of property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, Mencius also advocated encouraging commerce and protecting travelers by providing warehouses for merchants and requisitioning them in accordance with the law to avoid stagnant goods, only registering and inspecting but not collecting taxes, only doing labor service but not collecting land rent, etc. Let it be beneficial to farmers, so that all merchants in the world will be happy and willing to hide in their markets, all travelers in the world will be happy and willing to go out on their own roads, and all farmers in the world will be happy and willing to plow their fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the current economic reform is concerned, the confirmation and long-term stability of agricultural land rights, as well as deepening the reform of state-owned enterprises, protecting the investment and property rights of the private economy in various fields, tax laws, etc., all fall into this category. economic issues. This also determines whether entrepreneurs have long-term confidence in the Chinese economy and whether they dare to make large investments. In short, the essence of the economic spirit of an ideal Chinese community is to achieve economic prosperity, prosperity and prosperity for the people, and ensure the material life of the people through the property rights, production and trade system of &quot;big public ownership and private ownership&quot; and the fiscal and taxation system that is light on corvee and light on taxes. of plenty. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Belief: The unity of nature and man&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For families, why should fathers be kind and sons should be filial? For rulers, why should the world be for the common good? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do ordinary people have perseverance only if they have perseverance? For a person like Yan Hui, why can he achieve &quot;a basket of food and a ladle of drink, and he cannot bear the worries, but his joy will not change even after he returns&quot;? How can he have perseverance without permanent income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This involves the fourth dimension of Chinese civilization, faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businessmen believed in the personified &quot;Emperor&quot; and were biased toward the dominating heaven; Zhou people believed in &quot;the destiny of heaven is constant, only virtue is the supplementary one&quot;, and in the dominating heaven there was a profound meaning of the heaven of righteousness; although Confucius &quot;revered &quot;Keep the ghosts and gods at a distance&quot;, but still &quot;offer sacrifices to the gods as if they were present&quot;, reminding the disciples to realize the sincere spirit of life from the great popularity of &quot;Heaven can say nothing&quot;, and firmly believe that they carry &quot;Heaven will not lose the grace&quot;, which deepened the Zhou people&#39;s The concept of destiny; in the Han Dynasty, Dong Zhongshu believed that humans are copies of heaven, that heaven and humans can sense each other, and can warn the king of his misconduct and mismanagement with &quot;disasters&quot;; by the Song and Ming dynasties, heaven mainly became the heaven of justice, tending to one an inner transcendence and infinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For heaven, most of the most outstanding kings and sages of the Chinese nation had a strong and heartfelt awe, and regarded the unity of heaven and man as their ultimate pursuit, thus giving integrity to daily life and political life. sense of meaning, certainty and direction. Mencius has a very vivid description of this realm of belief that is both ordinary and holy: what is desirable is called good, what is called self-belief is called faith, what is full is called beauty, what is full and glorious is called great, what is great is called transformation. Holy, what is holy but unknowable is called God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Father&#39;s kindness and son&#39;s filial piety originate from the &quot;nature of destiny&quot; and from &quot;the child is free from the arms of his parents for three years&quot;. If this kind of human nature is brought into full play like Shun in &quot;Yao Canon&quot;, we can A saint who acquires a set of abilities including avoiding disasters, harmonizing the family, and governing the country is a saint who unites nature and man;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Emperor&quot; regards himself as the eldest son of Heaven to gain legitimacy and even sanctity, and must serve Heaven To carry on, we must nourish all people, and the world is for the common good;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ordinary people don’t understand this enough, and they don’t have the time to cultivate themselves. They need a constant income to have perseverance. This is normal, but it has a family “kissing” mechanism. With nourishment, there is still benevolence and righteousness in the heart. As long as you don&#39;t cut it off, you can also see the virtuous and considerate people; The obsession with external objects returns to the state of life where meaning flows. March is not contrary to benevolence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is extremely difficult to truly practice faith. For ordinary people, if they have permanent property and perseverance, maintain a comfortable life and common sense rooted in the meaning of family, they can become qualified members of the Chinese community; for people in high positions, if they cannot &quot;devour their heart and soul to understand heaven, &quot;If you cultivate your mind and cultivate your nature to serve Heaven&quot;, you will begin to pollute a large area from the source of law, politics, culture and education, and spread evil to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Mencius affirmed that all people have the four ideals, he also clearly realized that &quot;human beings are somewhat different from beasts.&quot; He quoted from &quot;Shang Shu·Tai Oath&quot; that &quot;Heaven sees me and the people see me, and God listens to me and the people listen&quot;, and gave a principled explanation of the relationship between heaven and the people. God’s will is unpredictable and manifests itself through public opinion. A holy king who unites nature and man is rare to find in five hundred or even a thousand years, but secular kings who are holy because of their kings are everywhere. The reverence for heaven and the people is not empty talk, so it is necessary to establish a technical system to restrict the royal power, so that public opinion can be fully reflected, and governance can fully reflect public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public opinion may be divided and antagonistic, what should we do? Will it bring about the disadvantages of &quot;welfarism&quot;? Will the &quot;public opinion&quot; of this generation harm the &quot;public opinion&quot; of future generations? These challenges have entered the field of building a modern republic and legal system. In addition to drawing on the more mature modern governance system, we also need to give full play to the spirit of &quot;Spring of the First Year, King Zhengyue&quot; in &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot;. In the era of great changes, we should constantly return to the origin of politics and beliefs, consider profits and losses, and &quot;make&quot; new systems. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Literature and education: Respecting teachers, respecting morality, and vigorous spirit&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Liangzhu, Hongshan, Yangshao to Longshan, from Xia, Shang and Zhou to Qin, Han, Tang, Song, Ming and Qing, the Chinese community gradually formed and split frequently And it can be continuously unified, and the culture whose roots were formed over five thousand years will never be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have a unified square character that has basically not changed since ancient times. Even though &quot;the winds are different in hundreds of miles, and the customs are different in thousands of miles&quot;, a county may have several dialects, but we can still recognize and identify with each other. There is also the ideological system from Zhou Confucius, Mencius, Xun, Lao and Zhuang. They have governed themselves and made history, and they have also learned from history and classics, providing rich resources for spiritual inspiration and institutional reconstruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no insurmountable rivers or mountains in the land of China. Whether it is divided into feudal states or prefectures and counties, the gradually formed Zhou Wen and Han systems, Tang style and Song style are diverse but capable of unification, and have strong agglomeration effect. For thousands of years, no matter what force entered China, it would be transformed by Chinese culture to a large extent. They inherited Chinese culture and therefore gained basic recognition from the scholars in this tradition. This is the attraction and centripetal force of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this cultural spirit faces not only the debate between China and the West, but also the changes in ancient and modern times. How to inherit and update our cultural spirit has been a major issue that several generations of intellectuals in modern times have struggled with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Han Dynasty to the Tang and Song Dynasties, we spent thousands of years absorbing Buddhist culture, which not only gave birth to Chinese Zen Buddhism, but also gave birth to Taoism in the Song and Ming Dynasties. Since the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China, in the face of the strong Western learning and Western politics, scholars from both sides of the Taiwan Strait and three places have translated a large number of translations, digested them quickly, practiced them politically, and compared and absorbed them academically, which has initially opened up a new situation for Chinese culture. The process is far from over. To return to the roots and create new things requires a free and powerful cultural and educational system that represents the fifth dimension of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher is someone who teaches, teaches and resolves doubts. China has a tradition of scholarship. The Jixia Academy, which flourished 2,400 years ago, was once an international academic center in China, even though it was officially run by the Qi State. Scholars from Taoism, Confucianism, Legalism, Ming Dynasty, Ming Dynasty, Agriculture, Yin and Yang, Mencius, Xunzi, Shen Buhai, Lu Zhonglian, Shen Dao and other scholars whose names were important for a time and even influenced thousands of years are here to &quot;discuss without ruling&quot;, &quot; &quot;Discussing state affairs without holding office&quot;, the ideological power derived from this has surged forward with the source of living water, and its influence continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Confucius broke away from &quot;learning in the government&quot; and gave private lectures, to the &quot;Jingshe&quot; in the Han Dynasty, from the &quot;academy&quot; where individuals studied and lectured in the Tang Dynasty, to the Yuelu Academy in the Southern Song Dynasty, where Zhang Shi lectured , the Bailudong Academy restored by Zhu Xi... The folk academy system is well-established, with independent subject-based teaching systems, autonomous methods for students to participate in management, and relatively independent funding sources, finally forming a mature private school system. By the Ming Dynasty, academies such as Longgang, Guiyang, and Kuaiji, which were founded or presided over by Wang Yangming and promoted the purpose of Xinxue, changed to Donglin Academy, which criticized the shortcomings of Xinxue and advocated practical learning. This has never ceased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These academies have the character of pursuing the Tao rather than seeking official positions, the style of study of free debate, the aura of making friends to help others, and the worldly sentiments of &quot;the sound of wind and rain, the sound of reading, family affairs, state affairs, and world affairs.&quot; In &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;, Huang Zongxi even put forward the view that &quot;what the emperor is right may not necessarily be right, and what the emperor is wrong may not be wrong, so the emperor will not dare to be wrong for himself and publicize his right and wrong to the school.&quot; Right and wrong and truth were elevated to a higher status than the emperor, restoring the traditional essence of discussing politics based on Tao, and inspiring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern intellectuals need to inherit the spirit of scholars, not only to interpret and continue the great ancient Chinese civilization, but also to &quot;work&quot; according to the times and explore new philosophical, institutional and scientific principles. In short, the foundation of this cultural and educational system is the guarantee of the institutionalization and legalization of &quot;teachers&quot; and &quot;scholars&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The final conclusion: This article believes that heaven (the belief system in which heaven and man are unified), earth (the economic system in which people have permanent property), and the country (the political system in which the world is for the common good) System), relatives (kinship is the most important, a personality development system nurtured in the family structure), and teachers (a cultural and educational system full of dynamic research, preaching and civilized dialogue), the above five constitute the main content of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国跳水队包揽亚运会跳水项目首个比赛日的两枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:38:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese group Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yu Xi in the competition. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;252916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 30, 2023, the diving competition of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou officially began. The first competition day was the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final and the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final. In the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving competition, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan/Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with a huge advantage. The Chinese team achieved six consecutive titles in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving at the Asian Games. In the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final, although the Chinese team Yan Siyu/He Chao made varying degrees of errors in the fourth and sixth jumps, it did not affect their overall success in winning the gold medal with a 29.55-point lead over the runner-up South Korea. The Chinese diving team won two gold medals on the first competition day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese group will be all red Chan (right)/Chen Yuxi during the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao competed. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 30, the Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform is the first completed event in the Hangzhou Asian Games diving competition. As Olympic champions, this is the first time for the gold medal team of Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan to participate in the Asian Games. The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition does not have preliminaries and will go directly to the finals. In this project, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan are the only ones in the world in terms of strength, while the strong players in the second tier are mainly from Europe and the United States. During the competition, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan led the way from the first jump, with a total score of 375.30 points in 5 jumps, leading the runner-up Japanese team by 85.26 points, and won the first gold medal in diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, Chinese group Yan Siyu (Part 2)/ He Chao is in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard also has no preliminary schedule and goes directly to the finals. The Chinese combination Yan Siyu/He Chao ranked fifth in the order of appearance. During the competition, He Chao and Yan Siyu demonstrated their extremely high technical level and tacit cooperation ability. Taking off, turning, and entering the water, the entire set of movements of the two people is very smooth. Although he successfully won the men&#39;s synchronized three-meter springboard championship, He Chao was not very satisfied with himself because of his mistake in the last jump. &quot;The result was good, but all the movements were not perfect in the process. This is the first time for Yan Siyu to participate in an international competition. I am also participating in an international competition again after six years, which is a test for both of us. But winning this gold medal is our best gift for National Day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On September 30, 2019, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79 .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed the gold medal in their hands to the audience . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao shows the audience the gold medal in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games diving event will be held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium from September 30 to October 4, 2023. A total of 10 gold medals will be produced. gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), and the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Jili (first from the left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Linong Anak Pamg (first from the right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;785&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Matsuri (first left), the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Rinon Anak Pamg (first from right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Yan Siyu (third from left)/He Chao (third from right), the runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae-kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan ( Second from left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/01/53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;793&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/ 53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, champion Chinese group Yan Siyu (third from left)/ He Chao (third from right), runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae Kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan (second from left) and third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik Bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[易水悲风：追寻燕国往事丨古国多少事③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257352]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The wind is coming again. The imaginary group of people gradually disappeared on the other side of the misty water, but the imaginary wine and food still exuded steam, as if chasing the sound of construction and singing that had just disappeared... More than two thousand years passed by in a blink of an eye, and this road from North China The rivers flowing across the plains brought me closer to those people and things that were far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The river is named Yishui, and it is famous in history because of that famous farewell. ——That year, they sang softly by the river:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wind rustles and the water becomes cold,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strong man will never return once he is gone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yishuihan, Yixian County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yandu&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;The North China Great Plain extends to Yixian County, Hebei Province, and has reached its western edge. In the county town, looking to the west from a high altitude, a line of dark mountains stretches across the end of the plain, which is the Taihang Mountains that separate the North China Plain and the Shanxi Plateau. The Yishui that gives Yixian County its name originates from the eastern foothills of Taihang Mountain. In fact, the Yishui is not one river, but divided into three: North Yishui, Zhongyishui and Nanyishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various signs that that famous farewell should be on the shore of Zhongyi River. The man named Jing Ke, when he finished singing generously amidst the sound of Gao Jianli&#39;s construction, and everyone&#39;s eyes were splitting with anger, he had already jumped on the carriage and headed to Xianyang, the capital of Qin, two thousand miles away. In order to repay Prince Dan for his kindness, he is going to perform an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the traffic conditions at that time, there were two roads for him to choose. One was to go south, along the Great Plains to today&#39;s Kaifeng, Henan, and then turn west; the other was to follow the Yishui River, Passing through Puyinxing and Feihuxing among the eight hidden tunnels in the Taihang Mountains, they entered today&#39;s Shanxi, then traveled southwest, crossed the Yellow River from Pujin, and entered Guanzhong. For no reason, I think Jing Ke would probably choose the latter. Although the latter journey is more difficult, the mileage is shorter. What is particularly important is that perhaps, only when he slowly climbed from the flat plain to the majestic mountain - at that time, the wind was also blowing, blowing Jing Ke&#39;s white robe - he stood at the mountain pass, and then turned back to take one last look at the sad scene under the sunset. The windy home is more in line with Jing Ke’s character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Jing Ke appeared on the scene, the life of Yan State had entered a countdown. And Jing Ke, a native of Wei, is undoubtedly a colorful part of the historical drama of Yan. The 800-year history of the Yan Kingdom came to a desolate and tragic end with Jing Ke&#39;s stubbornness and despair in attacking Qin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The history of Yan State must start from three hundred miles north of Yishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is also a river, a river that is shallower and thinner than Yi Shui: Liuli River. The Liuli River is an insignificant tributary of the Haihe River Basin. When it flows into Fangshan District, Beijing, a small town surrounded by the Liuli River is named after the Liuli River. To the east of the town, a number of Shang and Zhou cultural relics and sites have been excavated since the 1940s. Now, relying on the ruins, the Western Zhou Yandu Ruins Museum has been built. There are eight big characters on one wall of the museum: Ding Tian Ge Di, appointed to the Northern Territory. These eight characters illustrate that the purpose of establishing the Yan State was to ensure the security of the northern frontier of the Zhou Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1449&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Territory tiles with Taotie patterns from the Yan State, collected by the Yandu Museum of the Western Zhou Dynasty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Shang Dynasty in the Zhou Dynasty, the princes were granted great titles. The first person to be ennobled in the Yan Kingdom was the eldest concubine of King Wen of Zhou, who was also the half-brother of King Wu of Zhou, Ji Shi. Since Ji Shi wanted to stay in the royal city to assist the emperor, he did not go to the fief to govern, but sent his son Ji Ke there. He himself was called Zhao Gong because of his fiefdom, so he was called Zhao Gong in history. This means that the nominal first monarch of the Yan Kingdom was Zhao Gong, but the actual first monarch was Zhao Gong&#39;s son Ji Ke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The territory of Yan State is roughly equivalent to today&#39;s northern part of Hebei plus Beijing. Among all the princes, Yan State is located in the north, and bordering it is the ethnic tribe called Rong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first capital of the Yan Kingdom - for the sake of narrative convenience, let&#39;s call it the first capital of Yan - is near the museum. Of course, the capital city of a feudal state more than two thousand years ago was just a larger market town. When the Yan Kingdom was first established, it was adjacent to another smaller country: Ji. Soon, Yan State annexed Ji State and moved its capital to Ji. The location of thistle is located in the Guang&#39;anmen area of ​​today&#39;s Beijing city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside Guang&#39;an Gate in Beijing, there is a Liao Dynasty Buddhist temple - Tianning Temple. The Tianning Temple Tower is the oldest above-ground building in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yan Kingdom lasted for more than 800 years, and it can be said that it had little sense of existence for the first 700 years. In other words, the only time it had a sense of existence was when this small country in the north encountered big trouble - Shanrong invaded and almost destroyed the country. Fortunately, the Central Plains region was in the era of Duke Huan of Qi, the leader of the Five Hegemons in the Spring and Autumn Period. Under the banner of Zun Wang and Expelling the Barbarians, Duke Huan of Qi contacted the princes to form a coalition. He personally led his troops deep into the hinterland of the Shanrong and fought several battles with the Shanrong until the Shanrong came far away. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, the Yan Kingdom was just like ordinary passers-by A and B, living and multiplying in the northern country in obscurity. By the time the princes turned their attention to it again, it was already three hundred years later. At this time, a major event occurred in the Yan Kingdom that shocked the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the important difference between the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period is that although the Spring and Autumn Period also had frequent wars, they generally only beat their opponents until they surrendered and admitted their mistakes, while the Warring States Period focused on occupying the opponent&#39;s territory or even annexing the opponent. Purpose. During the bloody Warring States Period, with wars and wars raging, ancient countries perished one after another, and the remote Yan State also felt great pressure to survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 321 BC, the first king of the Yan Kingdom, King Yan Yi, died. His son Ji Kuai ascended the throne and was known as King Kuai of Yan in history. Faced with the great powers surrounding the country and the weak state of Yan, King Kuai of Yan was worried. He wanted to work hard to make the backward Yan state invincible. He sincerely believes that as long as it can make the Yan country strong, he will not hesitate even if he and his family are not in power. Various signs show that King Yan is a simple and open-minded person. Only in this way can his dream be used with ulterior motives. The traitor took advantage of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The treacherous minister was his son, who was the Prime Minister of Yan State at that time and was highly regarded by King Kuai of Yan State. Zi Zhi was indeed quite talented, so much so that King Kuai of Yan mistakenly believed that Yan must rely on him in order to revitalize the country. Zizhi fully grasped the eagerness of King Kuai of Yan to seek governance. His two confidants Su Dai and Lu Maoshou often gave advice to King Kuai of Yan, praising Zizhi&#39;s ability to govern the country, and urging King Kuai of Yan to follow the example of Yao and Shun and cede the world to the throne. Son of. In this way, Zi Zhi can not only govern the Yan Kingdom well and realize the rise of the Yan Kingdom, but at the same time, King Kuai of Yan will also become a saint like Yao and Shun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kuai of Yan deeply believed in these deceptions, &quot;because the whole country belongs to the son, and the son is of great importance&quot; - King Kuai of Yan handed over all the important affairs of the country to the son, so the power of the son was extremely popular. ——Of course, I also want to sit on the throne. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, under the continued instigation of Zi Zhi and his associates, King Kuai of Yan &quot;received the seals from his son who was an official of three hundred stone&quot;, that is, he took all the seals of middle and high-level officials with more than three hundred stone in the country. Leave it to Zi, and let Zi control it. So, &quot;the son went to the south to do the king&#39;s business.&quot; The throne of the King of Yan passed from King Kuai to his son, who became the King of Yan. King Kuai instead became a minister. He no longer interfered with political affairs on the grounds of old age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucianism has always beautified the three generations and believed that the abdication of Yao, Shun and Yu was a symbol of the great unity of the world. Later, there were many abdication events, including Emperor Xian of the Han Dynasty, whose throne was Cao Pi, Emperor Gong of the Jin Dynasty, Liu Yu, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty, Li Yuan, Emperor Ai of the Tang Dynasty, Zhu Wen, and Emperor Gong of the Zhou Dynasty, Zhao Kuangyin. However, the concessions between these foreign surnames were backed by force by the recipients, and the monarch had no choice but to give in. In contrast, King Kuai of Yan&#39;s true and heartfelt surrender was unprecedented, if not unprecedented, in thousands of years of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the sage-like abdication of King Yan brought a catastrophe to the Yan country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;子之在位三年，燕国没有像燕王哙希望的那样振兴，反而更糟，“燕国大乱，百姓恫怨”。燕王哙的儿子太子平，原本应该他继承王位，但父亲的禅让，却让他成了臣子，他当然想夺回本属于他的王位。于是，在将军市被支持下，太子平及其拥护者密谋推翻子之。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与燕国毗邻的齐国看到了染指燕国的绝佳时机。齐宣王派使者与太子平联络，表示愿意帮助太子平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了齐国承诺，太子平自感大事将成，遂与市被攻打王宫。但是，齐国并没有按承诺及时出兵。太子平及市被战败身死，燕国一片混乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;趁此良机，齐宣王发兵攻燕。燕军人心涣散，纷纷逃跑，燕王哙和子之均被齐军杀死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;齐军侵燕，燕国损失惨重，大量重器被运走，宗庙被焚毁，死于非命的燕人达数万之多。齐军对燕人屠杀的直接证据，事发两千多年后重见天日：1966年，在河北易县燕下都发现了战国人头骨丛葬墓十四座，考古工作者对其中的5号墓作了抢救发掘。黄土下，大量白花花的人头骨被随意掩埋在一起，没有任何陪葬品。发掘报告说，“这批人骨几乎全是男性成丁个体”；“头骨中最多的属于18—35岁的青壮年，约占观察数的80%”；并且，考古工作者还发现，其中一些头骨要么被砍去一部分，要么还残留着箭头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵国与燕国毗邻，在赵武灵王帮助下，燕王哙的另一个儿子公子职被护送回国继承王位，这就是燕昭王。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕昭王接手的是一个烂摊子，蓟被齐军洗劫破坏，无法再做都城。于是，他在更南方的易水河畔兴建了一座新城，这就是燕下都；相应的，蓟就是燕上都。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕初都遗址地处北京郊区，一条铁路紧贴着遗址，偶有火车驶过，发出惊天动地的声响，稍远处，是人烟稠密的琉璃河镇。至于燕上都遗址，则处于车水马龙的繁华大都市，车来车往，昼夜喧嚣。与燕初都和燕上都形成鲜明对比的是燕下都——在已经发掘的春秋战国诸侯都城里，燕下都是占地面积最大的一座，极盛时，估计约有三十万人口——而整个燕国的人口，大概率不超过三百万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京房山区琉璃河镇的琉璃河古桥，古桥建于明朝嘉靖年间。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而今，我看到的燕下都，是一片片翠绿的玉米地。玉米地里，偶有一座座突兀而起的土堆。特立独行的土堆隐约表明：这不是普通的庄稼地。这是两千年前，中国最重要的大都市之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玉米地尽头，黑杨挺拔，掩映着一条小河，小河流向易水。那一年，白衣飘飘，衣冠似雪，太子丹和一群燕人簇拥着荆轲，坐上马车，缓缓驶出燕下都，来到了城外不远的易水河畔。那里，有一座亭子；亭里，酒菜已经摆好。他们，即将最后一次共同举杯……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1507&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;易县燕下都古城遗址&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;死间&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;燕下都兴建之际的燕国，无疑是七雄中实力最弱的一个。如何整治这个烂摊子，如何使暮气沉沉的燕国变魔法似的振兴，这是燕昭王即位之初面临的迫切问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕昭王意识到了人才的重要性，只有吸纳最优秀的人才为燕国服务，燕国才可能在短时间内富国强兵。燕昭王求贤若渴的消息迅速传遍天下，不少身怀利器的士人纷纷前往燕国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寻访燕下都遗址前，我先去了河南洛阳。洛阳郊外公路一侧的田野里，有一座气度不凡的坟墓。墓侧，是河南省重点文物保护碑：苏秦墓。墓首广场上，立着几块高大的石碑，其中一块碑文为《战国合纵家苏秦墓碑记》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;投奔燕国的士人中，最知名、影响也最大的就是周天子直属的洛邑人苏秦。苏秦的事迹，主要记载于《史记》和《战国策》，但两书自相矛盾的地方非常多。这是因为，无论司马迁还是刘向，都苦于缺少真实可靠的一手材料。直到1973年底，长沙马王堆三号汉墓出土了一批帛书，苏秦的真实面目才渐渐清晰。这批帛书被专家整理为《战国纵横家书》。二十七章中，有十六章是司马迁和刘向未曾见过的久已失传的佚书。佚书的内容，正好与苏秦有关——于是，两千多年后，通过这些文字，我们终于得以还原一个以生命作代价的潜伏者：间谍苏秦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;投奔燕昭王前，苏秦周游列国，寻找机会，但他磨破嘴皮，花光盘缠，却没有任何一个君主重视他。他回到家里，家人也对他爱理不理。因此，当燕昭王尊重他、礼遇他，把他视作国士时，苏秦决意士为知己者死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏秦认为，七国中，燕最弱。秦、齐是强国，赵是次强国。燕国无法与它们任何一国抗衡。要想打败齐国复仇，必须削弱齐国，而削弱齐国的最好途径，就是怂勇、支持齐国去吞并宋国，这样齐国势必成为众矢之的。为了让齐国执行错误路线并达到削弱它的目的，苏秦愿意前往齐国作内应。他与燕昭王约定：“内寇不与，外敌不可距。王自治其外，臣自报其内，此乃亡之之势也。”——内乱不生，外边不能轻易行动。大王在外策划对付齐国，我打入齐国制造混乱。这样，灭亡齐国的形势就造成了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏秦以燕国使者的身份来到齐国，及后，他以卓越的才华和口才，赢得了齐湣王的信任，被任命为相国——其地位，甚至超过了在燕国。随着苏秦受到齐湣王重用，燕昭王的身边人开始怀疑，苏秦或许不会信守曾经的承诺，燕昭王一度也动摇了。为此，苏秦写信告诉燕昭王，发誓他将“信如尾生、廉如伯夷、孝如曾参”——这些当时属于绝密的通信，正是通过汉初帛书的传抄，在两千多年后重见天日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在齐国十余年间，尽管国际局势不断变化，苏秦始终如一地执行他与燕昭王的约定，即在为齐国制定对外政策时，总是想方设法削弱齐国。其间，他既曾劝阻了秦王约齐王共同称帝，还成功地离间了秦、齐关系，组成五国联军伐秦，并使赵、楚等国均与齐国关系紧张。尤其重要的是，他促使齐王三次入侵并最后吞并了宋国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了麻痹齐国君臣，对齐国恨之入骨的燕昭王唯齐王马首是瞻。齐国伐宋时，燕国派兵相助。甚至，齐湣王因小事处死了燕军将领，燕昭王虽悲愤下泪，却又派使者向齐湣王承认错误……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前286年，齐灭宋。位于中原膏腴之地的宋国，系周初分封殷商遗民而建，级别很高：公爵。这个高贵而富庶的国家被齐国吞并，引发了其他诸侯强烈不满。此时，燕国在燕昭王呕心沥血治理下，已然兵强马壮。此消彼长，齐国早已外强中干。于是，一年多后，燕昭王倾全国之兵，由大将乐毅率领，潮水般地越过齐燕边境，杀入齐国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当燕军进攻齐国，苏秦名为齐国相国，实为燕国间谍的身份暴露了，他被狂怒的齐湣王处以车裂的酷刑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;齐王的狂怒却无法抵挡志在复仇的燕军，燕军攻破齐都临淄，齐湣王逃跑，后来被楚军将领淖齿所杀——他的死非常悲惨：“射王股，擢王筋，悬之于庙梁，宿昔而死。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕军连下齐国七十余城，仅余下即墨和莒还在困兽犹斗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，即墨之围期间，燕昭王去世了。时局，也一下子发生了峰回路转的巨变：即位的燕惠王做太子时就与乐毅有隙，在齐国挑拨下，他将乐毅撤职，乐毅只好投奔赵国——春秋战国时代，这种用脚投票的行为屡见不鲜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原本处于绝对弱势的齐国，在名将田单的运筹帷幄下咸鱼翻生——燕军被赶出国境，齐国失去的城池一一收复。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;燕国昙花一现的强盛也就到此为止，它像一颗划过天空的流星，当人们还在仰望它并惊讶于它的灿烂时，它已熄灭并坠落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;后来&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;有意思的是，享国八百余年的燕国，它最精彩的两大历史事件，即苏秦间齐和荆轲刺秦，其主角都是外国人；而不论是作为间谍还是作为刺客，以这种非同寻常的手段试图打败一个国家或是拯救一个国家，都充满了天马行空的想象力和步步惊心的传奇色彩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从辈分上说，太子丹是燕昭王六世孙，两人之间相距五十多年。从燕昭王去世到太子丹的父亲燕王喜在位的半个世纪里，燕国国运每况愈下，四代燕王昏招叠出，九次对外战争，仅小胜一次。其中，燕王喜在位时，赵国在长平之战中惨败，作为赵国邻居，燕国不仅没有唇亡齿寒，反而趁火打劫，却被惨败之余的赵国暴击，以致燕都被困，不得不纳重金求和。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鹬蚌相争，渔翁得利。奋六世之余烈而进行统一战争的秦国乃是诸侯火拼的最终受益者。秦灭韩后，再灭赵，秦国势力进抵南易水。此前，燕国已沿着南易水修筑了长城。然而，太子丹知道，简陋的长城，根本无法抵挡秦国的虎狼之师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他希望有一个办法，能够快速且一劳永逸地解除秦国威胁，拯救风雨飘摇的燕国。于是，便有了众所周知的荆轲刺秦；便有了两千多年前，易水河边那场风萧萧兮的饯别宴……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1850&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;荆轲拜别&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末资料/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;昔时人已没，今日水犹寒。夏秋之交的易水，有风，却不寒冷，大多数河段水流平缓，沙洲上生长着诸多水草，鸟儿轻飞，看上去更像湿地。距燕下都遗址数公里的河畔，平原上隆起一座土堆，土堆上矗着一座塔，建于辽代，名为荆轲塔。据说，土堆附近有荆轲衣冠冢。那个衣冠似雪的男儿，掷下手中的酒樽，头也不回地朝着夕阳沉落的方向远去。从此，再也没有回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从远处看，荆轲塔的形状像一柄短剑，直刺蓝得空洞的苍穹。它让我想起了荆轲藏在地图中的匕首。图穷匕现，如果那把淬过剧毒的匕首刺死了嬴政；又或者，燕昭王的寿命再延续十年；历史，一定不是我们后来看到的那样。只是，世界上有苹果有芒果有开心果，却没有如果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1445&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;易县荆轲塔&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辽阔的燕下都遗址，大部分是庄稼地，小部分是林子，更小部分是村落。玉米长势良好，野花漫不经心。沟渠里，蹲伏着青蛙，向天空睁大了警惕的双眼。风来，杨树发出夸张的声响。高树多悲风，萧萧愁杀人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夕阳西下时，如血的残阳斜射在一座座隆起的土堆上，它们，要么是从前的宫殿台基，要么是埋葬死者的封土。厚重潮湿的黄土下面，杨树扎根的大地深处，还残留着一个逝去时代，渐行渐远的血泪，呼喊和挣扎……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈冠锋：苏炳添接班人？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258020]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxKabk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;715&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxKabk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252911&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月30日，杭州亚运会田径项目男子100米决赛，中国选手陈冠锋在比赛后&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月30日21：55，杭州亚运会田径男子100米决赛，中国选手、30岁老将谢震业以9.97秒获得冠军，追平个人最好成绩。 23岁的小将陈冠锋跑出10秒34位列第七。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，谢震业主攻男子200米，曾先后获得2010年青奥会男子200米冠军、2014年仁川亚运会田径男子4×100米接力赛冠军、2017年天津全运会男子100米和200米冠军、2018年英国伦敦田径世界杯男子200米冠军、2019年国际田联钻石联赛伦敦站男子200米冠军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252912&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月30日，杭州亚运会田径项目男子100米决赛，中国选手陈冠锋（中）在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年多哈田径世锦赛，谢震业以20秒03的成绩闯进男子200米决赛，创造了中国短跑历史，成为中国首位进入该项目世锦赛决赛的运动员。 2021年8月6日，在东京奥运会男子4×100米接力决赛中，汤星强、谢震业、苏炳添、吴智强代表中国队出战，获得铜牌，创造历史最好成绩。同年9月，在第14届全运会中，谢震业夺得男子100米和200米亚军、男子4×100米接力冠军。他是男子200米亚洲纪录保持者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，男子100米的亚洲纪录是中国选手苏炳添在2021年东京奥运会上创造的9.83秒；亚运会纪录同样属于苏炳添，他在2018年雅加达亚运会中跑出了9.92秒。决赛时，他现身直播间进行解说，表示他们这批老运动员已经完成任务，接下来就要看年轻运动员了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月6日，在成都举行的第31届世界大学生夏季运动会田径项目男子4x100米接力决赛中，中国队以38秒80的成绩获得冠军。中国队选手陈冠锋（左一）与严海滨（右二）在比赛中交接棒&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈冠锋便是苏炳添看好的年轻运动员之一，他曾多次在公开场合称赞陈冠锋为国内00后选手中的佼佼者。在一次采访中，他提到：“按照我当年的进度来算的话，三年时间他应该能接上班。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月2日晚，陈冠锋站在成都世界大学生夏季运动会男子100米决赛第二道上，他俯下身，等待发令枪响。 12年前，同样是23岁的苏炳添也站在深圳大运会男子100米决赛第二条跑道上，那次，他获得了铜牌，媒体称他是“中国短跑的希望”。后来，苏炳添在百米赛道上一路扬名，将众多纪录收归名下，在世界田坛闯出一席之地，成为无可争议的中国短跑领军人物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23岁的陈冠锋几乎复刻了苏炳添的夺牌之路，这是他职业生涯第一次出现在真正意义上的世界大赛中，也是第一次踏上世界级比赛男子百米决赛的跑道。他在半决赛跑出10秒16的个人赛季最好成绩，两小时后的决赛中，他以10秒17的成绩第三个冲过终点线。比赛结束后，陈冠锋身披国旗，绕着田径场跑了一圈向观众表示感谢。 4天后，他与队友获得4×100米接力金牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;578&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252914&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月30日，杭州亚运会田径项目男子100米决赛，中国选手陈冠锋（前）、谢震业（右一）在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;100米决赛夺牌的相似性让媒体和观众将他与苏炳添联系在一起。陈冠锋身高1.80米，比苏炳添高出8厘米。 2020年，他在百米项目上的成绩约为10.40秒，2021年个人最好成绩达到10 秒19。同年的全国锦标赛，陈冠锋在接近零风速下以10 秒06战胜国家队两位名将吴智强、许周政夺冠，距离奥运标准仅差0.01秒，一举超越何宇鸿的10.19秒，成为中国“00后”百米第一人。他也成为中国队史上继苏炳添、谢震业和张培萌之后成绩第四好之人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈冠锋说：“我会尽我最大的可能，向奥运会的领奖台发起冲击。虽然不知道自己能不能成功，但我也会像苏炳添大哥一样，帮助后面的年轻人，给他们做好榜样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管在全国田径赛场上，陈冠锋还是一张新鲜的面孔，但在广州他早就有了“西关飞人”的称号。在17岁之前，陈冠锋一直是一名校园选手，没有进入体校接受系统的专业训练。他曾多次代表广州第一中学参加校际比赛，跑步速度远远强于一般同学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我就是从小比较好动，喜欢跑跑跳跳，好像小学时体育成绩就一直比较好，体育老师们就推荐我在学校田径队练习。也没有牺牲很多学习时间去练田径，跟其他同学一样，也是要写功课参加考试的。”陈冠锋说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他多次在荔湾区的比赛中名列前茅，被西村青少年业余体校原教练顾燕强发现。 2015年，顾燕强履新广州体育职业技术学院，他跟陈冠锋父母及其本人做了长期思想工作，将中考后的陈冠锋招入学校。 “父母对我很支持，一直和我说的是做你喜欢做的事，自己开心最重要。”陈冠锋回忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾燕强评价他：“接受专业训练的时间有点晚，但他练短跑有天赋，身材不错，弹跳力好，是不可多得的人才。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月2日，在成都第31届世界大学生夏季运动会田径项目男子100米决赛中，中国选手陈冠锋以10秒17的成绩获得季军&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初入体校时，陈冠锋基础比较薄弱，百米成绩最高11秒03。随着年龄增长和教练慢慢引导，陈冠锋的训练逐步走上正轨。在顾燕强的计划中，他要花两年时间打基础，训练爆发力、协调性、平衡力、灵敏度，循序渐进提升力量和频率。 2017年末，陈冠锋加入了广东省省队。 2018年，他从省队转正并入选中国国家田径队，成为男子4×100米接力项目的主力队员，开始向更大型的比赛发起冲击。他不断刷新自己原有的速度，在田径赛场上崭露头角。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年12月，陈冠锋加入苏炳添的团队接受训练。苏炳添在东京奥运会创造9秒83的“神话”后，由暨南大学、广东省体育局、中国田径协会三方共建的苏炳添速度研究与训练中心成立，以探索田径训练的前沿技术、学科建设和科技创新，支撑田径后备人才的培养和选拔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;技术团队对陈冠锋的日常训练进行拍摄，针对他的技术动作进行分析。他因此改进了起跑和途中跑。 “我在起跑上的优势还算行，但途中跑非常糟糕。经常前面六七十米是领先的，但是最后二三十米被反超了。”陈冠锋分析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾在杭州亚运会百米跑道上的表现，陈冠锋表示自己的前半程发挥正常，但调整技术后，后半程严重掉速的老问题依然存在。他坦承决赛跑到后半程时腿部略有不适，所以选择了相对保守的完赛策略，毕竟后面还有接力任务。 “目前还处于新技术的适应和磨合中，但已完成挺进决赛的目标，以我目前的硬实力，在亚洲并不算特别突出，所以决赛就是学习、享受的过程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看着前辈谢震业在杭州打破10秒大关，陈冠锋兴奋地表示这是属于中国短跑的历史性时刻。对于是否有机会成为第四个打破百米10秒大关的中国选手的提问，陈冠锋表示会全力以赴，时刻做好接棒的准备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我觉得有天赋的人太多了，你必须通过刻苦训练，每天保持最佳状态，才能在竞技场上不落下风。”陈键锋说，“这是我第一次参加亚运会，以目前亚洲各国的短跑水平，我不能说肯定能拿名次，但给自己设定的目标是挺进决赛。”就这次亚运会表现来看，他实现了自己的目标，我们有理由相信这位00后运动员会带给我们更多的惊喜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中小学流行“萝卜刀”惹争议：让孩子没有害人之心，比严防死守害人之物重要得多丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一款儿童玩具引发舆论热议。据媒体报道，小学生几乎人手一把“萝卜刀”，这是一款彩色塑料仿刀玩具，借助自身重力实现刀体滑动。“萝卜刀”可选不同颜色尺寸，价格从5元到25元不等，还有“印花闪光萝卜刀”“夜光重力萝卜刀”等不同款式，网上已经“热销40万”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;媒体报道说，有家长向重庆网络问政平台反映，中小学生把“萝卜刀”带进学校聚在一起玩有安全隐患。还有家长担忧，孩子们模仿刺、捅等动作，会不会对其心理造成负面影响。有专家学者受访时表示“萝卜刀”存在安全隐患，以及“潜意识里激发孩子暴力倾向，拿着真刀做出同样举动”的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乍一看来，似乎萝卜刀是一种名如其物的“刀具”，存在割伤划伤捅伤儿童的危险。如果萝卜刀真的是一种刀刃锋利、容易伤人的道具的话，别说未成年人不应持有，在成人世界里也应该列为管制刀具。但从这款玩具的实际情况看，恐怕其危险性并没有报道中家长与专家渲染得那么严重，“危险”“警惕”“提醒”等字眼，也未免存在夸大其词的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，从萝卜刀的外观与材质看，其“刀口”是个钝角，本身也是塑料制品，其对人类能有多大的伤害能力，仅凭几张捅破白纸与苹果的照片是不具备说服力的，拿铅笔、圆珠笔同样可以捅破，是不是也以危险而一禁了之？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;把玩手里的物体，这是人类与生俱来的天性。哪怕是尺子、圆珠笔这些常见文具，孩子都发展出了转笔、摆尺的娱乐用途。硬要说危险程度，30度的三角板、薄薄的钢尺、尖锐的圆珠笔尖，这几样常用文具中的任何一种拿出来恐怕都比萝卜刀厉害许多。甚至于，长长的手指甲都能划破皮肤。一纸书页也可以划破手指。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，如果仅仅是为了防止这种“塑料钝刀”的可能伤害，就要祭出“家长监护下玩耍”“不让孩子将其带到学校”的举措，这显然是夸大了一个塑料钝刀玩具的威力，并向其投入了不成比例的注意力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，专家学者受访时“激发孩子暴力倾向”的说辞，也值得辨析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在萝卜刀出现之前的漫长岁月里，世世代代的未成年人同样会模拟“刺、捅、戳等动作”，因为这是写在人类基因里的东西。人类祖先是从狩猎活动中一跃成为万物灵长进而统治地球的，模仿与使用武器是每一个小孩的天性。简陋的木剑木刀，或者精致的玩具刀剑，几乎是所有人的童年记忆。谁小时候不曾幻想过自己是超级英雄，或者多少是个将军侠客？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玩乐本来就是孩子认知世界的一种方式，角色扮演与模仿武打动作更是他们不可压抑的天性，“亮出我的萝卜刀，一击制敌”这样的广告语其实也没有什么大问题。如果将孩子模仿使用武器的行为一律贬低为“暴力倾向”，这肯定是不符合形式逻辑也有违常情常理的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小小的塑料玩具与真正锐利的管制刀具之间的差别，模拟游戏与持刀伤人的不同，乃至合法暴力与非法暴力之间的分野，稍有辨识能力的孩子在接受教育之后都可以轻易分得清清楚楚。“激发暴力倾向”的说法未免有些跨越度过大，也是在否认孩子的认知与辨别能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后从未成年人健康成长的角度而言，对他们进行过度保护其实并不现实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未成年人的成长历程里总会遇到种种风险，这既是人生的必经之路，也是躲不开的代价。交通规则尚且无法消除所有交通事故，体育竞赛也做不到消灭一切伤病，即便成人社会也无法消除所有风险。校园之内，文具、树枝、桌椅、板凳都可伤人，是否应将校园像监狱一样杜绝尖锐物品与坚硬墙壁，管得水泄不通？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，“不要小看孩子”早就是教育学的共识。家长与学校都不应过度保护未成年人，或是完全否定他们自我管理的能力。未成年人总有一天会长大，不可能一直将他们严防死守在无菌环境里，为每一丝可能的安全风险担惊受怕。正确的做法应是引导他们正确地评估风险，教会他们独立对抗风险的能力。否则，中文世界里就不会有“文明其精神，野蛮其体魄”这样的名言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，面对“萝卜刀”玩具的爆火，成年人正确的做法是进行合理的导引，传授给孩子正确的价值观。让孩子没有害人之心，比严防死守害人之物要重要得多。毕竟不正之心一起，徒手亦可害人害己；心怀正见正知，利器恰可自卫护人。一个小小的塑料钝刀不但没有多少安全风险，反而可以成为孩子正确看待暴力、学习面对风险的“经验包”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不在景区“人挤人”，批发市场成假期新选宝地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257768]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>