<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[她年少成名，十四年后拍出新片再得大奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260408]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, for the promotion of the movie &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot;, director Liu Jiayin registered for the first time Weibo. In order to learn how to use it skillfully, she specially asked a friend to teach her online, wrote her first tweet, and left an anxious message to the producer&#39;s account: &quot;I seem to have #(marked) the wrong content, why is it different from yours?&quot; ?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; is Liu Jiayin&#39;s third feature film, but she said, &quot;To a certain extent, this is my debut film.&quot; This film is her first time working with professional actors and a filming team, which requires a lot of communication work. The introverted Liu Jiayin needs to take a brand new step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, director Liu Jiayin released her new feature film &quot;Worth It&quot; after a lapse of fourteen years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiayin is a teacher in the Literature Department of Beijing Film Academy. In her 17 years of teaching, she has often been criticized by her colleagues. Ask the same question as the students: &quot;When will you make a movie again?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, Liu Jiayin can be regarded as famous at a young age. In her first year of graduate school, at just 24 years old, she made her debut with the feature film &quot;Cowhide&quot; shot on DV. &quot;Won an important award in the Youth Forum section of the Berlin Film Festival. At the age of 28, she was shortlisted for the Cannes Film Festival Directors&#39; Fortnight for &quot;Cowhide 2&quot; and became a young director of great concern to the international film community. But for the next fourteen years, due to various reasons, she had no new films released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People around me are asking why I stopped filming? The motivation brought by pressure is huge.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first two movies, Liu Jiayin took care of almost all the affairs of the crew by herself. She was the director, screenwriter and photographer, as well as the producer and starring role. &quot;It was the era of DV, and I am particularly grateful to this period. I was definitely a beneficiary of it. This equipment was very suitable for my personality of &#39;working alone&#39;.&quot; Liu Jiayin recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Liu Jiayin began to officially write the script of &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot;. The final version was more than 60,000 words long, which is more than twice the length of ordinary scripts. Liu Jiayin also wrote a novel of more than 100,000 words for the characters in the script, describing the life of the novel&#39;s protagonist Wen Shan in more detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original title of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; was &quot;Listening&quot;, not only because Wen Shan&#39;s work in the film requires listening to complete, but also because of Liu Jiayin&#39;s insights in life, &quot;Listening is not hearing. It’s about understanding the other person and learning to think from the other person’s perspective.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan, the protagonist of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;, is a frustrated screenwriter. He gave up his original profession because he couldn&#39;t write the stories that Party A needed, and accidentally became a eulogy writer. . This new career requires him to learn to listen to other people&#39;s stories and restore the emotions of the deceased to the deceased, and his own life has also turned around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time he receives an order, Wenshan will visit the relatives and friends of the deceased and take a lot of notes to learn as much as possible about the deceased. He interviewed his sister who felt sorry for her brother who always acted as a &quot;good guy&quot; and could not let go of him until his death; he met a son who was busy with work and neglected to communicate with his old father when he was still alive, so he could only regret it for the rest of his life; he also got to know the man who had traveled thousands of miles from Gansu to A persistent girl in Beijing who explores the true state of deceased netizens... Among Wenshan&#39;s many clients, there is also Aunt Fang, a cancer patient who booked a eulogy for herself early. After learning that she had cancer, she chose to actively &quot;fight towards death&quot; born&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this job, Wenshan healed his clients and himself. Starring Hu Ge told Southern Weekend reporters that Wen Shan&#39;s work is to influence others, &quot;nourishing the living with the dead&quot; and allowing the living to feel the meaning of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the film, Wenshan finally had the courage to face his past failures, and he could face the script that he could not finish no matter what, and write characters he believed in. &quot;The most important thing is that life recognizes Wen Shan.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the 25th Shanghai International Film Festival awarded the Best Director Award to Liu Jiayin, and she was once again recognized by the Class A film festival. In September, &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; was officially released, which was Liu Jiayin&#39;s first movie to be released in public. After the movie was released, her Weibo really played a &quot;listening&quot; role. She received hundreds of private messages from viewers. People shared their feelings about watching the movie with the director in text, pouring out their deepest feelings to their relatives and friends. emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the process of directing a new film, listening and cooperation have taken on a new meaning for Liu Jiayin (second from right). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A pair of elderly sisters in their seventies, suffering from lung cancer and breast cancer respectively, They actively treated each other and encouraged each other, while accompanying their 95-year-old mother until her old age. After watching &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; four times, my sister wrote in a private message: &quot;We wrote eulogies for our mother, but we were shy to express our love in front of her; just like Wen Shan, when he was down and out, he was confused and inferior, and he struggled to give up... Your story allows us to see ourselves.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young girl shared the story of her mother who died after eight years of suffering from cancer. &quot;It would be great if my mother could leave the traces of her short life on paper. I am also a filmmaker. I hope that one day I can have my mother&#39;s story well recorded...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Some of the people who shared regretted being too rebellious when their grandma was alive, some did not catch up with their relatives for the last time, and some opened up their hearts with their families because of this movie... These stories flew into Liu Jiayin&#39;s mailbox one after another, and she would Try to reply one by one during work breaks. &quot;These strangers gave me a lot of encouragement. This is the most meaningful part of the movie.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Very specific fears” bring huge creative motivation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;When you first made a movie, you chose one person to do everything. Isn’t this a very common approach? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it were the kind of movie machine that I used to have, I might not be able to afford it, nor would I know how to cooperate with others. I was using a DV player. At that time, there were still many doubts about using such a special method to shoot movies. So I chose not to listen, thinking that I could just make it myself. I grew up slowly after the age of 30 and began to learn how to communicate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The earliest name of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; is &quot;Listen&quot;, how do you understand this name? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After working, I gradually discovered that in life we ​​really need to listen. Listening is not about hearing, but about truly understanding the other person. Not only have I been misunderstood by others in my life, but I have also misunderstood others. After something like this happens again and again, you need to constantly correct your views on others, and you need to listen to them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people may be concerned about the aftermath of &quot;Niuhide&quot; , why did it take fourteen years to make a movie, and why is this &quot;A Journey Well Worth It&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am not a person who does things very quickly. I have my own rhythm, and I may not have waited for the story I particularly wanted to tell. The things I encounter every day in my daily life are very specific, and there are also some rewards and fun, so I have a lot of &quot;excuses&quot; not to create. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, the prototype of the character Wen Shan came into being, and it took several years. The character didn&#39;t have a name at the time, but I felt that he often appeared in my life, even in my room, and I would always think of him, so I gave him a name and determined to write his story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your previous two movies are very close to your own life Yes, you and your family are directly on the scene. &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot; is a completely fictional film. What is its relationship with your own life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The previous creations were quite experimental, and &quot;Worthless Journey&quot; is different in every aspect. To a certain extent, it is My debut novel. But this movie still has a lot to do with my personal experience. It is a summary of my life over the past ten years, and everything I want to say is in it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back over the past ten years, do you think you What are the changes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was filming &quot;Cowhide&quot;, I was young, so I just gritted my teeth and made the film. Now my mentality is more complicated and requires greater drive. will be more rational. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t made a movie for a long time, and there is a high probability that I will never make another one, but I almost never stopped thinking about it. As I get older, I realize that time is limited, and I am afraid of it. If I don’t do something, I can predict what will happen in the future. This is a very specific fear, and it brings great motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2006 to the present, you have been a university teacher for seventeen years. What impact has your teaching experience had on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If I want to teach my class well, I must understand my students. This process is not particularly easy for me, especially since I am very bad at interacting with people. Every time I open the door to meet new students in the new semester, I need to do some mental construction. But what I teach is how to write stories. You must know why students write such things. You can&#39;t just say whether it is good or not. You need to understand them through stories. After slowly adjusting, I roughly knew how to express myself and take care of every student as much as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;You can find the answer by living seriously&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Wenshan needs to come into contact with all kinds of people in his work. Several of his customers appear in the movie, and they all have their own stories. Do these characters have life prototypes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no prototype. It mainly comes from daily observation of life and the screenwriter’s skills. A screenwriter should write in a way that makes people believe. In fact, I don’t have any creative skills, I just live seriously. The client&#39;s story is different in age, relationship with deceased relatives and friends, and understanding of emotions. It is similar to the situations we encounter in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wen Shan can’t be a good screenwriter, what do you think? Where is the problem stuck? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Human beings have a natural part, coupled with their experiences from childhood to adulthood, they have shaped us together and made us what we are today. look. I think Wen Shan encountered too many rejections in his previous work as a screenwriter. He was thought that the things he wrote were too ordinary, not enough for this, not enough for that. In short, the characters he wrote were &quot;not worthy&quot; of being the protagonists. After Wen Shan was denied again and again, he gradually began to doubt himself. Especially when you still can&#39;t pay the rent a few years after graduation and have to ask your parents for rent, it&#39;s a very difficult feeling. This sense of failure not only denies work, but also denies values. Do you think, &quot;Is the way I look at life wrong?&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Wenshan has not tried to defend himself, but his voice is too soft. In this case, a person&#39;s personality will also change. But to a certain extent, a screenwriter who fails to defend his story is failing to defend himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think life finally recognized Wen Shan? What does it look like specifically? Recognition? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After writing the eulogy, he found that what he had been denied before found answers in life. We can be affected by some small things, and we can also establish real connections with other people. These people are either very dramatic people in the script, or ordinary people who are inconspicuous, but they are very important to the people around them and are important to them. They themselves are also important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this, Wen Shan will continue to write stories without any obstacles in his heart. We are often like this, always troubled by some invisible and intangible things, but I am convinced that we can find the answer as long as we live seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you hope the audience will see through this movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For most people, it is much easier to deny themselves than to affirm themselves. This may be the life of adults. But people still have to care about themselves in the end. &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; tells the story of Wen Shan&#39;s process of starting to care about himself. He realized that his feelings and things he did were important. This may also be the reason why many viewers left me messages saying they saw themselves in the movie. Those who are completely indifferent after watching this movie are the lucky ones, because no one in this movie really succeeds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The appearance of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; can Does it solve some of your previous life confusions to a certain extent? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it was because I solved these confusions that I came up with this movie. In other words, after knowing yourself, you must accept yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[担心被称“普信”，不敢接触异性：一位大学老师对男生女生的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent Friday, at 2:30 in the afternoon, I parked my car in the parking lot of Guangzhou University and found that the playground There were two boys playing basketball, and they came to play so early. My curiosity drove me to get closer. I pitched and chatted with them. They are freshmen from the School of Foreign Languages. They are not only classmates, but also fellow Zhanjiang fellows. It happened that there were no classes or homework on Friday afternoon, so we were bored, so we met to play basketball. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Men and women are clearly differentiated&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As I walked, I asked how many people were in their class. They told me that there were 34 girls and 5 boys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why didn&#39;t you think about asking the female classmates in the class to go out for fun?&quot; I asked casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were quite surprised by my suggestion: &quot;Teacher, I don&#39;t know any of the girls in the class.&quot; &quot;Teacher, I know two girls in our class, but they asked me to date them. This is absolutely impossible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are 34 girls, how many people have you added to WeChat?&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I added 5 people, but I don’t have much contact with them.” Classmate A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three, and they are all cadres in the class, but I only contact them when something happens.&quot; Classmate B replied to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You are a freshman now. You should have a lot of courses, and there should be many opportunities to take classes together.&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes, we have classes together almost every day. The problem is that although we are in the same classroom, boys sit with boys and girls sit with girls. In class, they mainly listen to the teacher&#39;s lectures; after class, they disperse separately. , there is little communication and interaction with each other.&quot; Student A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Both boys and girls, everyone deliberately keeps their distance. Everyone agrees that as soon as they enter the classroom, boys and girls will sit separately.&quot; Classmate B added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, college students should have relatively free control of their time. Their physical and mental development has matured, and their need for interaction with the opposite sex is relatively strong. It is normal for them to date and become friends with the opposite sex, but the reality is not in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although classmates in the same class can meet every day and have many contact opportunities, having contact opportunities does not necessarily mean that substantial familiarity, understanding and understanding will occur in real life. Where is &quot;Geng&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing the confusion on my face, classmate B told me the whole story, &quot;Teacher, have you heard of some hot words on the Internet, such as &#39;licking the dog&#39;, &#39;lowering the head&#39; and &#39;Pu Xin&#39;?&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After his explanation, I realized that among boys and girls, the one who takes the initiative to add the other party’s WeChat account or asks for the other party’s contact information will be considered by a small number of members of the opposite sex to be a “dog licker” and a “lower” person. This situation is relatively common for boys who take the initiative. In other words, when a boy takes the initiative to add a friend to a girl he is interested in or finds interesting, some girls will think this is a strange thing and ask, &quot;What do you want to do?&quot; &quot;What are your intentions?&quot; &quot;Do you want to pursue her?&quot; Me?&quot; If the boy is not the right person for the girl, the girl will think that the boy is &quot;general trustworthy&quot;, which means &quot;ordinary but confident&quot;. The problem is that some girls may not think this way, but in order to avoid girls thinking this way, boys do not want to be misunderstood and bear the stigmatized label of &quot;normal men&quot;, so they would rather or simply not be active or take the initiative to avoid embarrassment, even in the face of The girl you are most attracted to or the girl you like the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Does the teacher know about the &#39;campus wall&#39;?&quot; Classmate A asked me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I don’t know. He explained to me this way: &quot;It is a public platform for students to publish information. It seems that every university has it. For example, once I join someone else and I am rejected, they will remove me. If I post screenshots of others on the &#39;campus wall&#39;, then all the students in the school will know about me, and I will be polite and sweep the floor in school, unable to hold my head up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t control the other person&#39;s thinking, thoughts and actions. , I am even more unable to face and avoid this kind of risk, so I will not take the initiative to get close to the opposite sex.&quot; Classmate B said helplessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Invisible Wall&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This reminds me of: A year ago, I played ball with several boys from my senior graduating class. They told me that after four years, they could not recognize any of them. Students in the same class may not be able to name their classmates. In their eyes, students of the opposite sex in the same class or major are just &quot;classmates&quot; rather than &quot;friends&quot;, &quot;close friends&quot; or &quot;besties&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to my observation, a basic feeling is that the current friendship or friendship between college students in the same major or class, especially between people of the opposite sex, is very weak. They are either busy or idle, and they are busy. Even if they may have a crush on a classmate of the opposite sex, they will never take the initiative or actively express their needs or wishes to make friends or interact with each other. In other words, after entering college, an &quot;invisible heart wall&quot; suddenly appears between boys and girls. This wall imprisons boys and girls, and no one wants to take the initiative to tear down this wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it was high school before entering college. The relationship between classmates in high school was generally very good. They got along with each other day and night, discussed and solved problems together, had fun and decompressed together. The boys handed ambiguous notes to the girls they liked, and the girls Look at the boy you like a few more times, meet at a corner of the school gate next night during self-study, and arrange to go home together. When you are excited, hold each other&#39;s hand and give him warmth, strength or encouragement. How normal is this? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My college years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;I can’t help but think of my college career, which was from 1997 to 2001. In the first class in the first week after the military training, the head teacher spent two whole classes asking each student to come up to the podium and introduce themselves. Then everyone went to a restaurant at the school gate to have lunch together, and they quickly became familiar with each other. . Boys and girls meet together for morning reading, breakfast, and class; after dinner, everyone has evening self-study together. After self-study, they play badminton for an hour on a wide road in the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public displays of love were also extremely common at that time. When it comes to the person of the opposite sex they like, a generous and cheerful person will express their feelings directly, &quot;Can I ask you to watch a movie?&quot;; a shy and reserved person will use an intermediary to act as a matchmaker and express their intention to date through a small note or letter. If two people have dinner together, watch a movie (usually an all-night movie), and then hold hands, it basically declares that the &quot;intimate male-female relationship&quot; has been basically established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, it is normal to express this emotion or affection to someone you like or like. I remember clearly that there were 42 people in our class, 22 boys and 20 girls. When I graduated as a senior, there were as many as 5 couples. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Concerned about the values ​​​​and true psychology of contemporary college students&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Boys today are generally not interested in love, don’t they want to know and understand girls? Or on the contrary, are girls today generally not interested in falling in love and not wanting to get to know and understand boys? I feel neither. Faced with the overall environment of high employment pressure, some people have been nervous since their freshman year and are busy with postgraduate entrance examinations, public entrance examinations, College English Level 4 and 6, driver&#39;s licenses, teacher qualification certificates, etc. However, in addition to &quot;many things to do&quot;, they When people still feel lonely or lonely in their hearts, they also long to meet or have a beautiful love. The problem is that no one wants to be considered a &quot;dog-licking tribe&quot;, &quot;Xiatou tribe&quot; or &quot;Puxin tribe&quot;, and no one wants to take the initiative Go out and get to know the opposite sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary college students are relatively unfamiliar with their classmates, so who are they relatively familiar with? It is understood that compared to students taking public courses or professional courses, it is easier for them to get acquainted with people who have the same or similar interests or hobbies. For example, the relationship between classmates within hip-hop clubs, literary clubs, basketball clubs, opera clubs, etc. should be close to classmates who have taken the same professional course. The reason is that various clubs are more in line with the interests or hobbies of students. This is what they like or like to do in their hearts. Everyone communicates and learns skills together, and closely cooperates and collaborates together, which can often brew the seeds of emotion. And in In professional courses, the course itself may be relatively difficult, and most students are not very interested in discussing or communicating together, so the establishment of close relationships naturally takes a long time. From a spatial perspective, professional classrooms are formal, formal and serious spaces, while various clubs are informal, informal and leisure spaces. The latter make people relatively relaxed, relaxed and natural. This is the informal space. effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let college students feel more relaxed and light, make them feel physically and mentally happy, let them dare and have the courage to do the &quot;duty things&quot; that suit their age group, let the friendship between classmates return to innocence and depth, and let the conversation Talking about love has become a matter of course, which is what the new atmosphere of contemporary college students should mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve the above goals, I believe that relevant parties should pay more attention to the values ​​​​and true psychology and mentality of contemporary college students. Each university has set up public required courses on the psychology of college students to encourage and advocate the construction of an open An inclusive and harmonious relationship between men and women breaks down all kinds of conceptual barriers and obstacles that create gender opposition and hostility. In terms of course learning, teachers may wish to encourage students to conduct group discussions, and suggest that men and women be paired into groups to create a good atmosphere for heterosexual discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, relevant parties should find breakthroughs in extracurricular time, fill students&#39; extracurricular time with as many public activities as possible, and create opportunities for male and female students to contact, understand and understand each other, such as organizing students to carry out Campus tours, city tours, outings, autumn outings, weekend hikes or dinner parties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[辛柏青：适度的，饱满的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK 2zBnv225d7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, director Zhang Lu returned to Beijing from South Korea and was quarantined in a hotel in Guangzhou for two weeks in accordance with the COVID-19 prevention and control policy at the time. He wrote a script and sent it to Xin Baiqing, saying that the protagonist Gu Wentong was written for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong is from Beijing. He is divorced. His daughter is fostered at his sister’s house. He lives in the old house left by his mother. He has an affair with a young girl and then separates. His best friend as a boy is in a foreign country. suicide. This person who once wrote poetry now makes a living by writing articles about food. He wanders the streets and alleys of Beijing, lonely, and has a sense of drifting that cannot be stabilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actor Xin Baiqing previously collaborated with Zhang Lu in &quot;The Long Confession&quot; (2021) - the brothers Lichun and Lidong went to Japan from Beijing to find Yanagawa, a girl with whom they had a bond when they were young. Having something on your mind. Xin Baiqing plays Li Chun, who already has a family. He goes to a foreign country and hides his loneliness and discomfort in a nonchalant way. He said, &quot;Director Zhang Lu prefers to write about people who have a sense of wandering and loneliness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin Baiqing let Zhang Lu see this feeling at a certain moment when Xin Baiqing was resting or lost in thought on the set. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong lives next to the White Tower, and Xin Baiqing also grew up in Beijing. Zhang Lu once said that Xin Baiqing has the &quot;not anxiousness&quot; of an old Beijinger. People who are not in a hurry seem to be taking things too slowly, have heavier traces of time on their bodies, and have a closer relationship with the past than those who keep running forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong in &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; looks like a man trapped in time. He wears lazy cloth shoes, only a ginger corduroy jacket and a floppy backpack. Most of the time Walking, occasionally taking the bus, and eating braised food that &quot;only people over fifty years old miss&quot; are separated from everything that is happening at the moment, and I am used to saying sorry to everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do I look at such a person more often?&quot; Zhang Lu said in an interview with &quot;Watching Movies&quot;, &quot;Because for this kind of person, the past time is still there, and the present time is still there. Subtle changes have occurred, and two things from time are squeezing on him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Gu Wentong, the past time and the present state are both related to the missing father: the five-year-old In 2006, my father was accused of molesting a woman on the bus and my mother kicked him out of the house. When he reached middle age, he suddenly received news that his father&#39;s &quot;hooligan crime&quot; was an unjust case. For so many years, his father had been watching him from a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of reconciliation between father and son was brief. The two danced a ballroom dance in a simple room accompanied by DVD footage from the last century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two grown men dancing together is not a Chinese way of expressing emotions, let alone Xin Baiqing&#39;s. He asked Zhang Lu, how to dance? Zhang Lu said that he can dance when the time comes. He asked Tian Zhuangzhuang, who played the father, that he could understand all the scenes in the script and could imagine the final appearance, but the dancing scene was weird. Tian Zhuangzhuang also said that there will be a solution on that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When that day came, Xin Baiqing said one line first: Dad, stand up. The two of them jumped stiffly a few times. Xin Baiqing said to Tian Zhuangzhuang, Dad, the blood vessels in your hands are like earthworms - this is what his daughter said to Gu Wentong before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Zhuangzhuang glanced at his hand, and then put his hand on Xin Baiqing&#39;s shoulder. Dancing comes naturally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That’s right, Xin Baiqing sighed. &quot;With this one action, my father&#39;s emotions for so many years fell into his hands and onto my shoulders. This action is small, but it contains too much content.&quot; He thought, &quot;When you go straight to the result and the goal, When you are doing this, you will wonder why it is so difficult? But forget about the result and purpose, and when you enjoy the process and express it, the results will appear naturally.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Movie &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; Stills &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;People&#39;s Insurance Drama&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; will be released. The film was shortlisted for the main competition of the 73rd Berlin Film Festival at the beginning of the year. In April, director Zhang Lu attended the &quot;Light of the White Tower&quot; post-screening event at the Beijing Film Festival and commented, &quot;Xin Baiqing&#39;s performance is self-evident. It&#39;s easy to win awards for hard-working performances. Xin Baiqing deserves the award.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In terms of fame, Xin Baiqing may not be a first-line star actor. In some years, he did not have many film and television works. But in the movie &quot;Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; (2017), in just a few scenes, the audience was completely attracted by his performance as Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He only has one scene in the script: Gao Lishi carries Li Bai to the Banquet of Bliss. Li Bai was drunk and composed a poem, &quot;The clouds want the clothes and the flowers want the face.&quot; Drunkness is the keynote. Xin Baiqing thought, does he really want to act drunk? &quot;My understanding of Li Bai is that it was a period when Li Bai was particularly sober, because all his illusions about his official career had been shattered. Everyone was praising him for being a high official. He knew very well that it was over.&quot; To have Drunk state, but you must be sober and cannot act drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the set, director Chen Kaige said that there would be no need to walk in the scene later, and he would just shoot it directly. Great, Xin Baiqing later said, &quot;I am willing to collide with the most vivid things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first shot was passed in one go. When he got to the monitor, Chen Kaige first said something off-topic, &quot;We have to cooperate in the future&quot;; then he showed Xin Baiqing the monitor: Xin Baiqing sat up, stretched out, and rubbed against the golden tortoise, and then asked Concubine Yang Youyou ,who are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Kaige said, this is Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TV drama viewers may have known Xin Baiqing through &quot;Happiness is Like a Flower&quot; (2005) in the early years or &quot;Da Qin Fu&quot; (2020) in recent years. The role that really makes him remembered is Zhou Bingyi in the period drama &quot;Human World&quot; (2022) - the eldest brother in an ordinary family in Northeast China: sent to the countryside as an educated youth, admitted to Peking University, and later became an official with outstanding contributions during the reform and opening up period. The shadow of many people in special times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenwriter Wang Haiyu received an invitation to adapt and read Liang Xiaosheng’s original novel. He felt that the description of Zhou Bingyi was relatively thin, such as the process of demolishing the &quot;Guangzi Film&quot; in the shantytown where he grew up after he took over the government. Passed a few pens. In Wang Hailu’s story, his younger brother Zhou Bingkun represents the family (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;the grassroots people&lt;/span>;), and his older brother Zhou Bingyi represents the country (&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Government officials&lt;/span>;) are the backbone. So she put a lot of effort into writing the scene after Zhou Bingyi became a leading cadre. &quot;If I have to say it, the first half of this play is Zhou Bingkun&#39;s home court, and the second half is Zhou Bingyi&#39;s home court,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About halfway through the broadcast of &quot;Human World&quot;, Wang Hailu and Xin Baiqing met at an event. Zhou Bingyi&#39;s highlight hasn&#39;t been aired yet. Wang Haiyuan doesn&#39;t know what Xin Baiqing can do. The two parties only exchanged a few polite words. She seemed to have heard Xin Baiqing say, &quot;This script is very literary.&quot; She thought this was just a polite comment. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the complete drama, Wang Hailu regretted not chatting more with Xin Baiqing, &quot;This is such a good actor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A brief example: watching the demolition of shantytowns in the drama Before that scene, I was a little nervous. I gave Zhou Bingyi a few thousand words of lines for that scene. When the plot came to that point, I could only write it like this. I thought the director might have a way to reduce the difficulty of performing this scene during filming. ——I didn’t dare to expect the actor to fulfill his wish. At that time, I had the impression that Xin Baiqing was a niche actor in literary films. ——Unexpectedly, the ten-minute scene was filmed in one shot. Xin Baiqing used his His understanding of the characters, his talent in temperament, and his line skills have successfully endowed him with the real nobility that a ruler should have.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a year has passed since the premiere of &quot;Human World&quot;, and Zhou Bingyi was demolished in a shanty town. Clips of handling disputes on the spot and explaining policies to neighborhood friends whom he has known since childhood are still circulated on self-media and have become classic examples of both performance and speech. Wang Haiyuan started her career as a novelist, and was later transferred to the General Political Repertory Theater to do drama. She said, &quot;At that time, I often heard senior teachers say that the theater protects the people, and the people protect the opera. The success of Zhou Bingyi&#39;s character must be the people protect the opera.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一个人&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;《人世间》之后，辛柏青接到大量官员类角色。但他不想被类型化，新鲜的角色才能激起他的好奇心。他拍了纪录片导演徐童的首部剧情片《三个十年》，演反角闫永刚，和演警察贾国志的段奕宏搭戏。在春风得意的年代，闫永刚于一次追捕行动中打伤警察贾国志，贾没死，闫也没被捕，结了血仇，但是生出了棋逢敌手的惺惺相惜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童在自己的原著小说《珍宝岛》里是这样写官员子弟闫永刚的：出手黑，人白净，带着一股阴气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童和辛柏青一起去作家阿城家讨论《珍宝岛》的改编，那是他第一次见辛柏青，刚停车下来，看到后面辛柏青开着一辆SUV也到了，一个人，没有团队，没有助理。 “当时我就觉得很舒服，他是很自然的、一个人的状态。没有演艺圈的习气，或者说演员的做派。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿城家见过面之后，阿城跟徐童说，你注意看，柏青含胸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童后来仔细观察，辛柏青一点儿也不含胸，一米八几，挺直溜个人。徐童问辛柏青，一直就是这个形体？辛柏青说是，几十年一直这样，一点儿没胖，也一点儿没瘦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童明白了，阿城指的并不是形体，而是辛柏青给人一种含胸的印象。 “因为他的消瘦气质，他身上的含蓄。”类似的，徐童发现辛柏青有一种特殊的眼神，“他看事物看东西，不是那种眼睛放光，直接看，而是感觉好像隔着一层东西，光往回收，含在里面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意识到这两点，再看辛柏青塑造的角色，徐童觉得，“他的表达是适度的，同时也是饱满的，饱满是说他背后的东西是饱满的。”陈凯歌对辛柏青有类似的评价，他说辛柏青“吃得很深，吐得很少”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年春天，《三个十年》在陕西开机。辛柏青答应徐童提前进组，推掉了别的安排。 “他说过完春节之后，我就溜达过去了。”徐童回忆，“至今回想起来我们那一段时间的工作，我都觉得他不是一个演员，他没有把我们这个合作当成一个项目，他就是创作一个人物。熟悉环境，进入空间，然后进到这个人物当中去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开机前有剧本围读，大家谈得不多，徐童说，辛柏青和段奕宏已经把人物翻来覆去吃透，再谈多，反而影响现场的即兴感。他用“非常刺激，又非常惊喜”形容两位演员的表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然合作愉快，但徐童和辛柏青在那部戏之后的交往并不多。部分原因是徐童有意为之，“我需要跟演员保持一个距离，是为了产生一种陌生感，私交多了会影响未来对人物的想象力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他觉得辛柏青更懂这个道理，所以在角色之外很少露面，“如果观众对你这张脸太熟悉了，当你再去塑造一个人物的时候，那个人物的可信度就会降低，或者说冲击感就会降低。”好演员需要保持相当程度的孤独状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“三板斧”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们找到的辛柏青的合作伙伴都很愿意谈论他的表演，但是要和他本人聊表演并不容易，像张律说的，他是含着的；或者像徐童说的，他是往回收的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比起细致地讲述心路历程，他更愿意这样总结：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我的工作方法就是尽量把文学描述变为可视化的形象。第一步，我的形象从哪而来？他是什么样子的，大概什么发型，穿什么衣服，戴不戴眼镜，他走路的姿势，他说话的方式，他有没有习惯动作，这其实都是上学的时候学的最基础的。然后，剧本的一些背景，剧本没有写的，但是我要给他丰富的一些情感关系，或者是一些经历，自己去更多地为这个人物想象更深的一个维度。这样演出来以后这个人物就没有那么片面和单一化，观众就会觉得他可能有更多的侧面和立体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这演员的基本功是观察生活，没别的技巧，没有什么新的内容，全是三板斧，但是这三板斧你要扎扎实实地做好，那就是演员武装到自己的牙齿。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就是靠着这三板斧，他一次次离开自己的舒适区，迎接新角色的挑战。 “我接戏只考虑我感不感兴趣，而不会考虑我能不能掌控。我看到一个新角色，我掌控不了，就不演了，永远没有进步。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乍一看，《漫长的告白》中的立春和辛柏青一点都不像。制片人徐佳含回忆，剧组最早定下的演员是张鲁一，演弟弟立冬，一个有点执拗的罹患癌症的文艺中年。他们问张鲁一，你给自己找个哥哥，看谁合适？哥哥立春有点像立冬的反面，世俗、外放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张鲁一回答：辛柏青。他觉得辛柏青有点“闷骚的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有了辛柏青和导演张律的第一次合作。一场戏，在日本的民宿，立春和年少的恋人柳川相对而坐，说话，辛柏青眼泪唰地流下来，“那是在诉说，在悔悟。那种表现我觉得特别清晰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张律喊咔，再来一条，让辛柏青冲着墙说台词。 “我当时就想，刚刚那个不好吗？当然我没跟导演探讨，既然已经有表达强烈一点的了，我就来一遍导演说的。”下一条，辛柏青背对镜头，喃喃自语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成片里，张律用了后一条。辛柏青想，也对，立春也许是对柳川有感情，也许只是为了寻找自我来到此地，“而我那种表演把所有的可能性局限在了一种，反而让路子更窄了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青迅速理解了张律的风格，他说，看张律的电影像读诗，没有标准答案。 2020年底，我采访张律时，他确实说，电影应当像诗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凭借立春这个角色，辛柏青获得了中国电影金鸡奖最佳男配角奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到《白塔之光》，两人已经非常默契，没有过多的讨论。张律会问他，演得舒服吗？挺舒服的。那就行了，拍下一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所谓的舒服（就是），我觉得都对了。这场戏没有&#39;个个楞楞&#39;的，没有那种很难受的、过不去的动作、行为、语气。是波澜不惊的、静水深流的表达方式，而不是哪个音符蹦出来了，变得强烈了；哪个音符又变得低沉了。可能用在这个电影里，舒服的感觉是这个样子的。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;背负着时代和家庭的不如意，在暧昧的两性关系和戏剧化的父子关系里，谷文通这个角色可演的地方很多。但辛柏青知道张律要的是不外化的表演，甚至是不演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他就经常说，生活当中人是多面化的，你也许上一秒还在挺高兴地说一件事，下一秒可能就陷入到一种很自我的情绪里边了，不知道为什么。人也会经常跑神，也会说一些不着边际的话，这都是真实的生活状态。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这就对表演者提了更高的要求，不演，需要特别强大的内心定力，要不然会觉得，我没演，是不是不对？但恰恰是我不怀疑自己、内心特别笃定的时候，可能生出来另外一种无法言说的状态。观众会捕捉到。不演反而可能内心需要更充实，这种充实不是说目的性更充实，而是你的过往人生、阅历，你的气质、思想内涵在那一瞬间，都会让人能够感受得到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月29日，北影节闭幕式暨颁奖典礼举行，如张律所说，辛柏青果真拿了奖。他凭借《白塔之光》获得“天坛奖”最佳男主角。这是他拿到的第一个影帝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;话剧《狂飙》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;游戏感&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;影视角色之外，辛柏青一直是国家话剧院的演员。第一部大剧场戏是导演田沁鑫的《狂飙》（2001），他演主角田汉，戏里有打破第四堵墙的自述，有和表妹、和妻子、和红颜的情感，还有若干戏中戏，比如田汉翻译的《莎乐美》中的叙利亚少年、写的剧本里的关汉卿，都由辛柏青演。后来在《红玫瑰与白玫瑰》（2007）中，他演个全上海都知道的“柳下惠”。 《四世同堂》（2010）里，他演胡同里汲汲于名利、向日本人求官的冠晓荷——拿了话剧金狮奖表演奖。到《青蛇》（2013），他演法海，有人性，有神性。 2023年他还在排田沁鑫的新戏《苏堤春晓》，演苏轼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青记得多次合作的导演田沁鑫的一句话：戏剧和影视最大的不同，或说戏剧最大的魅力在于，可装扮性更强。影视剧不会找辛柏青的，田沁鑫会找。 “去装扮这个角色，就特别有游戏感，这一下让我豁然开朗。这件事变成了一件好玩的事儿，不是说我要苦大仇深地去塑造一个什么，戏比天大，这么大一个枷锁给你套上，不是的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在舞台上二十多年，辛柏青的角色不算多，两只手数得过来，现在回看，每一个角色的故事他都还能想得起来。与影视相比，戏剧离名利远，辛柏青自己有时候也想为什么一直没有离开戏剧呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“名利可能就是某一瞬间，我这戏播火了真好，被这么多人认可了，很享受，但很快就会过去。但是演话剧，在排练场里天天连滚带爬地排练，这种简单的快乐太难得了。岁数越大，面临的事、社会环境、关系也越来越复杂，（演话剧）这事儿就是不复杂。我能回到简单的地方，找到小的时候的状态就会特别快乐。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他身上有一种非常干净的气质。这份干净是很难得的。”田沁鑫说过，在排练场，她有时会突然被辛柏青感动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，新版《狂飙》上演，辛柏青作为观众去看，觉得年轻一代演员比自己当年演得好。 “我年轻的时候有点没心没肺，每天就是乐呵、傻玩，并不过脑子，事儿不往心里装。因为装多了以后挺痛苦的，你知道吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但是没办法，生活就硬往怀里塞，这么多年也塞了不少了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活给他塞了什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“柴米油盐，都往里装。具体你真的说不出来。这就是活着，过日子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青演的那版《狂飙》，有一段，田汉在东京看戏，一段自白，大意是，找到了自己热爱的志业，像是行星找到了轨道一般：“小时候我就有些迷障，我大概是无法悟道了。我只热爱我要的颜色，我会听凭它牵引出一条轨道，引我自由公转。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说出这段台词，问辛柏青在年轻时是否很有共鸣，他否认了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小的时候真的不知道这是什么意思，只是把这词念出来了，为赋新词强说愁的一种状态。什么人生，什么牵引，什么我的颜色，到底我要什么，我不知道。现在到了这个岁数了全都知道了，反而也可以不用说这样的话了，一切感悟都在，却道天凉好个秋了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过作品，很难寻觅到他在表演上爬坡的轨迹。他也没有给出所谓的“开窍时刻”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我明白你的问题，但是没有一个具体节点。因为生活本身没有节点，我的生活四平八稳的，但是四平八稳的生活，愿不愿意去用心体会？用心体会了，年龄、岁月带给人的就会潜移默化、一点点积淀。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他只说，如果现在再演田汉，应该是不一样了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;钝&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2008年，导演姜伟拍《潜伏》，最先考虑的是请辛柏青和朱媛媛两口子出演余则成和翠平，他觉得辛柏青身上有文人气。不巧赶上朱媛媛怀孕，姜伟说辛柏青一个人去也可以，辛柏青为了陪产也没去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《潜伏》播出之后，成了现象级电视剧，全国各地拿奖。辛柏青有遗憾，但不后悔。与喜爱的角色擦肩而过，这不是唯一一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾经辛柏青最想演的角色是浮士德。在歌德的戏剧《浮士德》里，这位博闻的学者与魔鬼梅菲斯特做交易，出卖自己的灵魂以换取无尽的学识和智慧，甘愿在死后投身地狱。后来真的有人来找他演《浮士德》的时候，他拒绝了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么这个机会到我手边的时候，我又不去演了呢，我纠结了好长时间，后来发现我想演的不是歌德的浮士德。”他无法用只言片语解释自己想演的浮士德是什么，但是他清楚自己不要什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我给人感觉挺钝的，生活当中给人感觉反正也不大灵光不大聪明的。”辛柏青这样说自己。但他有自己的小世界。特别累的时候，或者坐车赶路，他在网上看别人下四国军棋，有时候看到棋出得太臭，他也说，这看不下去，给关了，过会儿再点进去看看。 “就诸如此类，我自己心里边玩得特别高兴，但是跟别人一沟通起来，又变成了一个特别无聊的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青喜欢潜水。把生命搁在水底，杂念被迫压缩到最少，氧气含量、潜水深度、方向，都没问题了，终于可以放下心来看一眼海底的时候，他觉得，可能跟到了太空的感觉差不多，心情一下就变得开阔了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做演员的人都敏感，但是敏感有时候会伤害自己，作为“内向的、不善于表达的人”，辛柏青用这种方式让自己放空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐佳含是《漫长的告白》和《白塔之光》的制片人，她说，“柏青老师在现实生活中，跟剧组人员都特别客气，特别融洽。”《漫长的告白》到日本拍摄，辛柏青不懂日语，但是“会尽量适应，不愿意给别人添麻烦”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但你总觉得他有点小秘密，恰好在剧本里找到了一个出口。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1997年，中央戏剧学院表演系1993级本科生临近毕业，排练的间隙，十来个同学跟着老师去蹭饭。走在学校门口的东棉花胡同里，老师问了一句，你们毕了业谁还能坚持演话剧？本来欢快的气氛一下子安静了。那个时候演话剧意味着清贫，谁也没吱声。辛柏青接了一句，“要让我一辈子演话剧我都乐意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，辛柏青50岁了，当年的老师有的已经离世。每当排话剧、同学聚会、给老师扫墓，他都会回想起那一幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微短剧的“危险”狂飙]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260414]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 14:33:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;微短剧从各种层面都在狂飙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从市场规模看，据中文在线援引第三方研究报告数据，2022年短剧全年市场规模在100多亿元，2023年微短剧规模预计突破300亿元。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从市场供给来看，据广电总局数据，2021年微短剧全年备案数398部，而2022年备案数接近2800部，同比增长600%；2023年3月-8月，全国重点网络微短剧规划备案通过剧目部数，基本在260部以上，且7/8月分别为361部/401部，供给显著增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从公司看，中文在线、华策影视、芒果超媒、华谊兄弟、柠萌影视、掌阅科技、长信传媒均在此块加大投入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但另一头，基于题材“媚俗化”，微短剧市场监管不确定犹存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月10日，中文在线报收25.40元/股，跌幅9.19%。此前11月2日到9日，该公司股价短短6个交易日翻倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨蓉主演的微短剧《二十九》在抖音短视频平台正片总播放量超8亿次。图片来源：剧方海报&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“爽点密集”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;微短剧最大特点是，回收效率高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当红微短剧概念股中文在线在投资者交流纪要中表示，短剧特点在于，内容短、集数多，一般是80-100集，每集两分钟以内，剧情带有较强戏剧性，创作内容更加贴合群众需求，故事快反转，剧情爽点密集。更多依托平台广告推流，实现C端客户触达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此基础上，微短剧商业验证周期短，回收效率高，主要靠广告投流，投流方只要能够实现首日回收目标，就可以继续优化投流的策略，然后实现高额的ROI回收。一部作品从剧本打磨到拍摄、制作、投流验证， 短时间内就可以完成验证和闭环，资产中转率高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，微短剧制作周期短， 制作成本低，拍摄周期一般在一周以内。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不行就换题材，成本太低了。就是打一枪换一炮。”有微短剧创业者对21世纪经济报道记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这让影视基础薄弱的中文在线迅速切入核心赛道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“公司拥有海量IP优势。目前短剧剧本主要来源于网络小说改编，公司拥有550万种IP，可源源不断提供优质短剧IP改编剧本，长时间赛跑能力突出。”中文在线称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老牌内容巨头华策影视也在迅速进军这一市场。该公司对外披露，从去年下半年开始研究短剧赛道，今年6月开始建团队， 目前已有6 支队伍，也在引进编剧、制片人，和投流公司合作。 “ 未来的定位是进入微短剧的前五。”华策称。其自认为的优势，显然是制作能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客观上，影视巨头布局这一赛道还是有优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据柠萌影视披露，2023年初，其打造的微短剧《二十九》在抖音短视频平台的正片总播放量超8亿次，集均播放量超4000万次，相关话题全站总播放量14.5亿次，为抖音短视频微短剧的最高水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当下，微短剧最大特点是“爽感”，对精品制作需求似乎不多。从微短剧创业者到头部影视公司中层，均向21世纪经济报道记者坦承，目前头部影视公司在这一市场优势相对有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;譬如，《二十九》第二季播出即登上微短剧最热榜TOP1 ，连续5周占据抖音微短剧榜TOP1。可是，热度相对第一季有着明显下滑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;平台变迁&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大火微短剧背后是，落寞的长视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位影视公司项目负责人均向21世纪经济报道记者感慨，随着平台“降本增效”，挣钱越来越难了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财报显示，爱奇艺在2022年内容成本为165亿元，同比下降20%。此外，该公司还在力推自制剧。当下，爱奇艺自制内容资产占比持续上升，从2018年的32%升至2022年的63%。爱奇艺还披露，每年上新的重点剧集中，原创内容占比从2018年的20%提升至2022 年的50%以上。以上种种，都挤压了影视项目的利润空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此种变化诱因为，长视频脆弱的盈利模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年二季度，爱奇艺营收78.02亿元，同比增长17.2%；归母净利润3.65亿元，去年同期净亏损2.14亿元。但从环比来看，爱奇艺营收处在下滑区间。受《狂飙》推动，一季度，其营收达到83.49亿元，同比增长15%；归母净利润6.181亿元，而上年同期净利润为1.691亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长视频业绩如此波动在于，用户需求走向碎片化以及相对低的变现效率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据易观千帆数据，2023年9月，爱奇艺月活用户减少至5.6867亿人，腾讯视频月活用户减至4.5017亿人。同期，抖音月活用户减至7.9767亿人，快手月活用户减至5.2236亿人。长短视频差距明显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另从广告来看，基于更高的变现效率，广告主们纷纷奔向短视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香飘飘就对外披露，上半年其冻柠茶销量同比增长547.09%，线上渠道同比增长235%，抖音渠道占比约30%且累计复购率维持高位。劲仔食品也对外表示，线上渠道方面，该公司抖音等新媒体渠道表现亮眼，同比增长约600%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有头部饮品市场部负责人告诉21世纪经济报道记者，相对爱奇艺等长视频平台，短视频推销效果更直接，变现效率要强得多。 “对长视频变现基本没报太大预期。”他说。另有头部户外运动产品创始人也表达了类似观点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流量与营收双重夹击下，长视频生态走向存量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，内容公司们也不得不奔向微短剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“不确定性”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;然而，微短剧市场也面临着种种问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大量影视公司乃至平台，目前并不愿意在这块业务上过于高调，核心在于微短剧在政策上依旧存在不稳定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;短剧的规范化监管可追溯至2020年8月，广电总局在重点网络影视剧信息备案系统增设了网络微短剧快速登记备案模块，标志着微短剧正式纳入监管体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年4月，广电总局发文明确将包括短剧在内的国产网络剧片审查纳入行政许可事项管理，需要取得相关广播电视行政管理部门的发行许可才能播放上映; 当年11 月，针对小程序微短剧，发文开展专项整治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在引导规范化发展的同时，广电总局也给予短剧必要的支持，2022年12月，《关于推动短剧创作繁荣发展的意见》提出要培育壮大短剧创作主体，在资源、人才、营销、排播、宣传等方面对短剧进行倾斜性支持。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须注意的是，目前，爽剧仍是该市场主流。据巨量引擎，当前短剧以“爽”为内核，90%的题材都以“爽”为主，爽的方式多样，包括战神、穿越、逆袭、重生等题材。由此，呈现“媚俗化”倾向。据21世纪经济报道记者了解，对于大量“擦边”内容，监管层正在关注中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“市场走向充满着不确定性。”多位行业上下游参与者如此表态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另从市场规模来看，微短剧相对长视频还是有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2022年，单爱奇艺一家营收就达到290亿元，同比下滑5%。这一数据，远超同年微短剧总体市场规模，且接近2023年微短剧预计规模。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下，短剧终端盈利主要分为三种。分别为会员付费、广告变现和电商带货。会员付费包括定期的会员费和单部剧集购买，主流长视频平台单月会员价格在22-25元，短剧专属平台会员费更高，在30元左右；单剧付费收费标准为1-3元/集，爆款剧单集收费可达10 元。广告收入也是短剧收入的重要组成部分，包括贴片广告、广告植入、IP 授权营销；其中，贴片广告是长视频平台的专属，软广植入是短视频平台的常用方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体来看，此种盈利模式依旧趋向短平快，离真正的成熟商业模式还有距离。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[此情可待成追忆：本师吴金华先生逝世十年祭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzzlOu07pkyhn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzz lOu07pkyhn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Wu Jinhua, Distinguished Professor of Fudan University and Researcher of the Institute of Ancient Books (1943-2013) 2007 Photos taken during his visit to the United States in December. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, nine years had passed since I graduated from Nanjing Normal University with an undergraduate degree in ancient literature. One spring afternoon, I went up to the fourth floor with my four-year-old daughter in my arms. When I took out the key and opened the door, I woke up from my own heavy breathing. Because I was unwilling to let my life go down, I decided to go back to college to start another kind of growth. At that moment, I thought of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after graduating from college, I stopped thinking about you for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I saw you in college, you had a bald head like a European monk, energetic eyes behind big glasses, and thick lips that were always smiling. Except in summer, he seems to always wear a blue or black tunic suit with one or two pens in the top pocket. A classmate from the previous class said that they saw you wiping the blackboard with the sleeves of your Mao suit while you were engaged in class. We didn’t take your class very often, so we never saw you do this in class, but I did see you darken your face after class. The corners, cuffs, pockets, etc. of the tunic suit looked like they were stained with chalk dust. I was admitted to Nanjing Normal University in 1984. The various inexplicable and severe restrictions I had suffered before led to strong rebellion in the tolerant university. During those four years, I couldn’t see anything, including you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As graduation approaches, my view of you has changed a lot. I went to your home to receive guidance on my graduation thesis. That was the only individual communication in the past four years. The house was very crowded and there was no desk, so you invited me to sit down at a small round dining table filled with books and started talking about my thesis. During this period, I have been attracted by a copy of &quot;The Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; spread out in the middle of the table. The blank space on the opened page is filled with long and short school slogans written in different pens. When you talk about it later, you forget why, as if you are looking for an example to illustrate, you start to flip through the book. Then I saw clearly that every page of the book was filled with colorful words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; annotated by Mr. Wu Jinhua. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very ashamed. What you talked to me about academics that day was quickly forgotten. Only the appearance of this book still comes to mind from time to time. After graduating from Nanjing Normal University, I returned to my hometown of Changshu. After only a year or two, my arrogance naturally turned into decadence. In the next few years, I rarely read. When the weather is bad, I wander aimlessly by Shang Lake at the foot of Yushan Mountain, letting the rain and snow fall from my head. Try to persuade yourself and try to play cards day and night with all kinds of people from all walks of life. Smoking more and more aggressively, especially when alone. I often drank, got drunk late at night, and sat alone in the darkness on the side of the road, crying silently. It wasn&#39;t until this spring afternoon that everything came to an abrupt end. I decided to start over and do something seriously for a long time. What came to mind again at that time was the &quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; filled with words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I wrote to you. I didn’t even know that you left Suiyuan two years ago (Editor’s note: the former site of Yuan Mei Suiyuan, the old campus of Nanjing Normal University). Your reply from Shanghai said that it was a pleasure to know that you wanted to come to study. Professionally, as long as we don&#39;t completely abandon what we have learned and review it, not many people can compete. What you have to do is to concentrate on preparing foreign languages. In the winter of that year, in the last two months before the postgraduate entrance examination, it seemed to be raining all the time. I locked myself in a room, lowered the curtains, put away the clock, and read, recited, and dictated, day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I came to your home after being admitted to Fudan University, you came out of the study. Because you still retained the memories from ten years ago, you looked much older and had less hair, but your eyes Still energetic. I said, I came too late, I should have come ten years ago. You immediately said with a smile on your face, it&#39;s not too late, I just started at your age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year, you asked me to translate the papers of Japanese scholars in conjunction with foreign language learning. Before submitting the completed translation, you asked me to write a translator&#39;s note. For those few hundred words of notes, you revised it four or five times. Through repeated frustrations, I began to slowly understand what &quot;negative rhetoric&quot; is. When you finally changed the schedule, you smiled and said gently that it seemed that you had been away from school for too long and you were no longer in the mood. But it doesn’t matter, just start slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the first school year, you asked me to go to the library to borrow different versions of &quot;Jiankang Records&quot; and use my summer vacation time to do the revision. After school started, I reported the findings of the review to you, and you seemed very happy. I remember when my wife came over to pour us water, you turned around and said to your wife seriously, &quot;Ji Zhongping is very attentive. I have read this book so many times, but I didn&#39;t see many of the problems he found.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; height= &quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qing Yi Xun Tang published &quot;Jiankang Record&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I came to Fudan again to study for a Ph.D., it was the first time I talked about choosing a doctoral thesis topic. You introduced what you discovered. A category of words created using classic sentences. I blurted out that the use of such words should be to make the rhetoric more elegant. After hearing this, you patted your thigh with an exaggerated movement that was completely beyond my expectation and said, Great, this understanding is great, this is your invention. Well, let&#39;s call this type of words Yayan words, and you can do this topic. The next day, I went to class in the liberal arts building and saw my senior who had just finished class and said to me, the teacher said in class that you have an important invention. A few days later, I met a friend from East China Normal University and told me that Teacher Wu went to their school for a meeting and said at the meeting that I had an amazing invention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those years when I was studying at Fudan, after having long conversations with you, on the way back to school late at night, I would always stand up and pedal my bike hard, eager to sit down at my desk the next second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a teenager, I read books such as &quot;The Detectives of Sherlock Holmes&quot; and &quot;Three Heroes and Five Righteousnesses&quot;. I imagined that when I grew up, I could become a detective who pursues the truth and an impartial judge. However, I realized that this was unrealistic when I became an adult. . You taught me how to do collation and exegesis, and how to make reliable inferences through thorough investigation and meticulous analysis. I will pursue the truth relentlessly and base myself on the facts without any compromise. Everything depends on me. Discovering a typo is like exposing a villain; restoring an original word is like clearing up an unjust case. Sitting at my desk late at night, I felt like Sherlock Holmes sitting in a carriage on his way to investigate a case, or like Bao Zheng sitting in the lobby of the Kaifeng government office. I don’t have any great talents to gain wealth in the world, nor do I have any ambition to achieve greatness in the world. When I come to this world, I have to live in a certain way. If I can live my life with this feeling besides being harmless to humans and animals. I have been content for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remember one time, when I said goodbye to you and said I was leaving because a friend had an appointment to play football, you asked me, does football really fascinate you so much? At the time I just said yes. I didn&#39;t tell you that day why I never tire of football, because it was the only relatively fair game I could participate in. On our court, there are only simple and clear rules, relying only on one&#39;s own skills and efforts, everything is under the sun, and all power and influence are meaningless. I don&#39;t know any skills other than poetry, I just like to participate in this kind of game with my own ability and enthusiasm. Only this kind of game can allow me to truly feel the joy of life, even though no one cheers, there is no income, and there is even the risk of breaking my muscles and bones at any time. I am very superficial, and my understanding of knowledge is no different from playing football. Although I still play football twice a week to this day, I know very well that in my lifetime, my strength and speed will gradually fade away. One day, I will no longer be able to run as much as I want on the court. However, even then, , I can still continue to experience the same fun on my desk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met you, I brought you some tea. You told me seriously that this would never happen again. We don’t need this when we get along. If you can write an article and show it to me, that would be better than giving me anything. From then on, all I can think of in return is to write something to you. In the days I spent with you, I don’t remember saying any words of gratitude in front of you in a serious manner. You passed away suddenly in June 2013. I rushed back to Shanghai from Kyoto. I came down from your house alone late that night and sat in the small garden next to the building. I regretted that I had not had time to say many things to you in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know if we can meet again in another world in the future. If not, then we will never have the chance to say those words in person, so I have no choice but to write the above words. Although It&#39;s just a very small part of it. If you have a soul, you will surely understand what I mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua and Mr. Jao Tsung-I (left), taken in 1993. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to gratitude, there is also an apology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my lifestyle has changed completely since I came to Fudan to study, some of the beliefs I formed since I was a student at Nanjing Normal University have not changed. Those beliefs may just be a joke in the eyes of others today, but I am willing to stick to them for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for a master&#39;s degree at Fudan University, the Institute of Ancient Books Collation held a meeting for students to evaluate scholarships. The meeting had a section that was equivalent to self-declaration. The students who spoke in front talked about what they had done and what they had published, and they talked very enthusiastically. Although I have done some research and published papers in journals, I cannot speak like they did. Seeing that it was almost my turn, I stood up quickly, picked up the blank form that was given to me, handed it to the teacher who was hosting the meeting, and said that I was ashamed and felt that I could not compare with them, so I quit first. The next day, you called my dormitory and told me seriously that as long as you applied, you would have won at least the second prize. This is very important, don’t do this next time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, I still don’t think this is important. My idea is very simple, because I didn’t win this award, I got through with it. What kind of honor can there be for an award that requires application only? After the doctoral thesis was written, you told me twice that after the defense, we would go to the Academy of Social Sciences to apply for the Lu Shuxiang Award, or go to Peking University to apply for the Wang Li Award. The first time I pretended not to hear, but the second time I told you clearly that I would not apply. When I was studying for a PhD at Fudan University, I won the highest award in liberal arts, but I never thought about applying. You applied privately on my behalf. You suddenly called me after 11 o&#39;clock the next night and told me that you had applied for me, and now you only need me to go to the award meeting the next day to make an introduction. I hesitated for a while and reluctantly agreed. Of course I know this is all your hard work, and I really can&#39;t bear to disobey you late at night. The next day I only used half of the allotted time and ended my uncomfortable self-cutting hastily. When I left the venue, I felt relaxed all over. I didn&#39;t care whether I won an award or not. I just felt that I had gone through this process, which was more or less an explanation to you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I like football very much, I rarely take the initiative to ask people to play football. Because I don&#39;t like others to accompany me reluctantly because of my invitation. I don’t like the state of being in my heart but not in my heart, and I certainly don’t want my friends to be like this. The games we play are just a bunch of ragtag games, but everyone is united physically and mentally. It is a game without any dirty things other than football. Although my technical level is limited, I thought I was enjoying the real joy of gaming. Any association with anything other than football would probably make me feel uncomfortable. It makes me feel a little sad to think that one day we all in this world will inevitably end in clouds and rain. However, I am not depressed at all when I think that all the hard work I have done will eventually be wiped out. Every run, every pass, every shot, while doing your best, the fun is in it. The moment I came off the field, I had finished enjoying football. In the days to come, if you tell me how I was in that game, I actually feel nothing. I rarely remember what kind of goals I have scored, even if they were just played yesterday. What I never forget every day is just where to start the next game. I have little knowledge and cannot give any lofty meaning to my profession. I just hope that the research I engage in can be as pure as football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height= &quot;742&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua graduated from the Chinese Department of Nanjing Normal University in 1966. In 1968, he was assigned to teach in a middle school in Ganyu County, Xuzhou area. In 1978, he returned to his alma mater and studied the history of Chinese under the tutelage of Mr. Xu Fu. After graduating in 1981, he stayed at the school to teach. In 1986, he won the second prize of the Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. In 1991, he was promoted to professor. In 1995, he was transferred to Fudan University. Institute of Collation of Ancient Books, author of &quot;Exegesis of the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;Research and Interpretation of Shishuoxinyu&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on Ancient Documents&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I quit my original job when I came to study for a Ph.D. During the holiday in early October of the first semester, you asked me to go to your house for dinner. During this period, you asked me if I have any requirements for my workplace after graduation. I said it didn&#39;t matter to me, as long as I had a bite to eat. You said, then see if you are willing to stay. I said of course that&#39;s good, so I can always be by your side. Then you said that you believed that I would have no problems with my business, but you hoped that I could do some things outside of business to ensure that I could stay. I told you on the spot that I didn&#39;t want to. I just wanted to make a living based on my own ability. You mentioned it twice after that, and I explicitly rejected it both times. The last time, I even said that if I had to do that to stay, then I would go somewhere else. If I have to do academic work that way, then I would rather live on the streets pulling a cart and carrying bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I know that&#39;s arrogant and rude to say. In fact, I have never seen and can&#39;t imagine anyone talking to you like that. Of course I fully understand that you have my life in mind, but if I do what you say, I will have trouble sleeping at night. These beliefs have been rooted in my heart since I was a teacher in Nanjing. They are the promises I made to myself. Even when I was dissolute, I never violated them at all. Perhaps, for others, there shouldn&#39;t be any doubts about doing something like that, because everyone does it, but I am me, and in my opinion, no matter how many people do it, it is impossible to change this kind of thing. nature, I cannot deceive myself, so I am willing to accept the life I choose. I think if the research we did is credible, it must be the only judgment made based on real materials and strict logic. The beliefs I adhere to are the same kind of non-dual judgment. It is impossible for me to change because of the intervention of anyone other than facts and logic, not even you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are very strict with students. My wife once told me privately that even several older doctoral students were scolded by you until they cried in front of them. I don’t know why you are so tolerant to me. You have never spoken harshly, so that I have the confidence to speak freely in front of you again and again, especially for those beliefs that are ridiculous in the eyes of others, but you always smile gently and make some remarks. Advice, and ultimately make it clear that you respect my choice. I admit that if you were still alive, I still would not apologize to you for things like the above. Because although I am stubborn, during the time when I was studying with you, I regarded you as the judge of this world to a certain extent. I need to state the facts clearly to you, and then get a fair ruling from you. . It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t respect you, but I&#39;m afraid that my apology will change your original decision. In my opinion, such a change of judgment, even if it is beneficial to me, no longer has the meaning of a ruling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been ten years since you went to another world, and I no longer need you to make any judgments. Therefore, please accept my apology now. I apologize to you for all my past arrogance. Apologize. Forgive me, more than 20 years ago, I just wanted to go back to the peach blossom land I once had. I didn’t know it at that time. Things have changed, and the place I yearned for has already kept pace with the times. But I have always been like that warrior who is searching for a sword, stubbornly guarding that place. mark. Forgive me, I don’t want to live just for food, that’s no different than a dolphin or a dog. I want a life with wine. The gentle smile you show in the face of those unbridled smiles is a great comfort to an inappropriately lonely student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People often say that once you are a teacher, you will always be a father. This is just a matter of etiquette, because how much emotion can be created in a day&#39;s interaction. Deep feelings are the accumulation of emotions generated after long-term mutual understanding. I know there are teachers who are different from you, but for more than ten years, you are the only one to me. To this day, I still feel lucky that on that spring afternoon twenty-six years ago, when I said goodbye to comfort and wanted to start another kind of growth, you adopted me, just like a father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品集采12小时：“割肉”也不想丢标]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;This collective purchase 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased, and the prices of the selected drugs were reduced by an average of 58%, the second largest price reduction in history. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;If the company&#39;s market share in the next four years was determined within 12 hours, how would you choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of Monday, November 6, 2023, the temperature in Shanghai dropped sharply, but there were crowds of people outside the Fengxian District Conference Center and the discussion was lively. The ninth batch of centralized bulk procurement of state-organized drugs is underway here, and representatives of various pharmaceutical companies carrying sealed quotation information materials are waiting anxiously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;We have ten manufacturers bidding together for our drug varieties, and the competition is fierce, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;Long procurement cycle&lt;/span>;) is both a temptation and a challenge. I personally think it will prompt companies to further lower their quotations.&quot; A representative of a pharmaceutical company from Shangqiu, Henan told a reporter from Southern Weekend that the company is It was my first time to participate in the national centralized drug procurement, and I started preparing for this round of application since passing the consistency evaluation half a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Starting at eight o&#39;clock, business representatives poured into the first floor of the conference center. Within 12 hours, a total of 382 products from 262 companies participated in the bidding. The staff of the notary office will unseal, announce and read out the product specifications and quotations of each pharmaceutical company one by one, and then release the list of proposed winners; the proposed pharmaceutical companies will then Transfer to another hotel conference center to wait - enter into groups according to the order of drugs, and select and confirm the supply area in the next four-year procurement cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that there were pharmaceutical distribution, local state-owned enterprises and other related enterprises inside and outside the site eagerly waiting for the event. Although these companies themselves are not participating in this collective purchase, they are also looking forward to the results of the ninth batch of collective purchases, especially if they can collide with some cooperation opportunities with the selected pharmaceutical companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At about 19:00 on November 6, the National Medical Insurance Administration announced that 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase, and the average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%. It can save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year - the second largest price reduction in history, second only to the previous record high of the first national procurement after the 4+7 pilot (59%). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Once the bid is lost, it will be &quot;sidelined&quot; for the next four years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The ninth batch of centralized procurement It covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. At present, during the period of high incidence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, the much-anticipated azithromycin oral suspension is also on the list of this centralized purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is different from the first eight batches of centralized procurement is that once selected, the procurement cycle will be extended from two years to four years, that is, from the implementation date to December 2027 March 31st. This is more attractive to pharmaceutical companies than in previous years. On the morning of November 6, many business representatives kept discussing the topic of extending the procurement cycle while waiting for declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;While waiting, a representative of a Jiangxi pharmaceutical company looked embarrassed while holding a thick stack of written documents. &quot;During the eighth batch of collective purchases, we did not win the selection for an exclusive product with a high market share, and most of the volume on the market was &#39;divided up&#39; by several successful bidders. Therefore, we participated in this collective purchase, even if we &#39;cut the meat&#39; We don’t want to lose the bid, we have to keep the production line.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Hengwei, deputy general manager of the marketing center of Zhonghuan Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd., introduced to Southern Weekend reporters that the three projects they applied for Two products are planned to be selected. “Both are new products that have just been introduced into the Chinese market, and are also recommended drugs in the diagnosis and treatment guidelines. Although the current market sales are not large, it is expected to have a large growth in the next four years. Taking into account the patient Drug accessibility and hospitals will give priority to the centralized procurement of drugs from the winning bidders, and we have shown the greatest sincerity for this centralized procurement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Jiang Changsong, assistant to the dean of the National Medical Insurance Research Institute of Capital Medical University and director of the price procurement office, said that the procurement cycle of centralized procurement has been extended to four years for the first time, further ensuring The stability of drug use in medical institutions also means that if pharmaceutical companies &quot;lose their bids&quot;, they will have to watch their huge market share &quot;sideline&quot; in the next four years. &quot;National centralized drug procurement means large and stable quantities, and the supply cycle To ensure long-term growth, companies must exchange prices for volume and ensure supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to a report from the National Medical Insurance Administration, among the pharmaceutical companies participating in this centralized procurement, 266 products from 205 companies have been qualified for selection, including 200 domestic companies. 260 products from pharmaceutical companies and 6 products from 5 international pharmaceutical companies (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Including 1 original research drug and 5 imported generic drugs&lt;/span>;), the proportion of bidding companies planning to be selected is about 78%, with an average of 6.5 companies planning to be selected for each variety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Amiodarone injection to treat arrhythmia, dopamine injection to rescue shock, oxytocin injection to induce labor, etc. 5 kinds of shortage medicines and emergency rescue For pharmaceuticals, we use the &quot;volume-driven&quot; procurement method to stabilize corporate expectations and achieve a balance between multiple goals of ensuring supply and reasonably reducing prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of November 6, 2023, representatives of pharmaceutical companies submitted application materials on the first floor of the Fengxian District Conference Center in Shanghai. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Fierce battle: The battle for pharmaceutical companies’ supply areas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;November On the morning of the 6th, after the acceptance of application materials and the disclosure of application information ended, the companies to be selected could not relax their nerves because they would face another &quot;fierce battle&quot; that afternoon - the selection and confirmation of supply areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to the &quot;National Drug Centralized Procurement Document&quot; released by the National Drug Joint Procurement Office on October 13, 2023, the companies to be selected must first determine their main suppliers. Region, the first-ranked company will give priority to selecting one region among the supply regions. All companies to be selected will confirm the remaining regions in order. Each company will select one region at a time. Repeat the above process until all region selections are confirmed. The selection process for the reserve area is similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the purchase quantities of all drugs in different specifications in various provinces and regions are also announced, which can be used by applying companies to formulate constituency strategies accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 6, two large conference rooms were prepared at the constituency site, one for business representatives to wait, and the other for confirming supply area information . The organizer calls the numbers one by one according to the drug types, and after checking the ID cards and authorization letters, the companies enter the selection areas in groups. This process starts around 14:00 that day and continues until the evening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Tian Yong, executive deputy general manager of Qilu Pharmaceutical Group Sales Corporation, told Southern Weekend reporters that there are multiple considerations for corporate constituencies. “First look at the donor district hospital report. How big the volume is? Secondly, it depends on the market capacity of the province. Thirdly, it depends on the importance that enterprises attach to different regions. For example, enterprises tend to choose Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou to enhance brand awareness. For example, our Shandong enterprises certainly want to choose the area at their doorstep, but they also Maybe he wasn’t selected and was picked by a company with a higher ranking.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Some business representatives also mentioned that some western provinces may not be popular in the electoral process due to low reporting volume and high distribution costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed at the scene that after the first round of companies entered the conference hall to select areas, it took more than an hour for people to come out one after another. Representatives of pharmaceutical companies should adjust their constituency plans in a timely manner based on the conditions of their competitors. Someone not only recorded his own district selection, but also made notes on the district selection of other companies. The filled-in notes attracted onlookers. People competed to take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Determining the main drug supply and supply areas is largely to avoid situations where the centralized procurement of drugs cannot be supplied in sufficient quantity in time or the selected company is disqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Starting from this year (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Collection of medicines to ensure supply&lt;/span >;) Judging from the situation, it is much better than before.&quot; Gao Xiaoyan, deputy director of Shanghai No. 7 People&#39;s Hospital, told Southern Weekend reporters. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital of Capital Medical University (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as Xuanwu Hospital&lt;/span>;), also said that hospitals all hope to collect drugs collectively Achieving quality and quantity supply requires the guarantee of a long-term mechanism, including the supervision and evaluation of winning bidders by relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the afternoon to the evening of November 6, 2023, the companies to be selected will enter the venue in groups according to drug types and select supply areas. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Scientific and rational use of drugs attract attention&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;National Drugs From the beginning, centralized purchasing focused on large varieties, and now it has progressed to include all varieties that are clinically deemed necessary. In the implementation of each batch, Ruijin Hospital covers a relatively large number of varieties. So far, it has The procurement cycle of the first five batches of centralized medicines has been completed, and the sixth batch is in progress.&quot; Ruijin Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;The following Bian Xiaolan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Ruijin Hospital, said that medical institutions are now very concerned about how to use drugs more scientifically and rationally in the next step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Since 2018, the National Medical Insurance Administration has organized nine batches of national drug procurement, including a total of 374 kinds of drugs, with an average reduction of more than 50%. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital, said that centralized purchasing has been carried out on a regular basis, and clinicians have been observing the efficacy of centralized purchasing of generic drugs for some time. On the basis of respecting the patient&#39;s wishes, doctors will combine the diagnosis and treatment guidelines and the patient&#39;s condition to provide patients with Choose the right medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In response to some voices saying that generic drugs selected through centralized purchasing may not be as effective as original drugs, Xuanwu Hospital has led a number of hospitals with strong research capabilities to conduct centralized purchasing and selection in batches. Real-world research on generic drugs. A recently published study covering 29 medical institutions in 16 provinces across the country and about 140,000 real cases showed that the clinical efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected through centralized procurement are equivalent to those of the original drugs (see Southern Weekend’s October 22 report for details&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/259061&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;140,000 cases, 2-year PK, centralized purchasing of generic drugs What is the efficacy and safety?》&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;generic drugs and Original drugs&lt;/span>;) differences are within controllable range. Moreover, the drug configuration of different hospitals will be slightly different according to the actual situation. Our hospital tends to be equipped with both centralized drugs and original drugs, with the patient as the center and combining their needs. The medication plan will be comprehensively considered based on disease progression, past medication, etc.,&quot; Bian Xiaolan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Ruijin Hospital selected endocrine metabolism-related drugs and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular drugs based on clinical characteristics, and participated in the second and third batches of national centralized procurement led by Xuanwu Hospital. Real-world studies of generic pharmaceuticals. Bian Xiaolan said that there are now more and more evaluation systems and tools. For example, Shanghai is developing a comprehensive drug clinical evaluation management system, and relevant research will be announced in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Zhang Lan introduced that real-world research on the fourth and fifth batches of generic drugs selected by the national centralized procurement has been launched, and the original data collection and reporting process will be more perfect in the future. Provide evidence-based support for clinical medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[危险的快递驿站：一场不该发生的意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;589&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh2 0BlLq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At noon on August 25, 2023, Zhang Xiang, who was on a business trip, received When I got the call that my wife was injured and rushed back to Taiyuan, Shanxi Province, it was already past two o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The son was sitting on an iron chair in the waiting area, keeping his mother&#39;s mobile phone, myopia glasses, and the pair of white sandals that he had thrown off when he fell from the second floor. Lin Mei was lying on the hospital bed with her eyes open and her face pale. She was soon sent to the intensive care unit (ICU). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon that day, Lin Mei had cut the vegetables. The message pushed by the Tmall APP on her mobile phone showed that the plasticine purchased online for her son had arrived at the Cainiao Station near the community. She put down the kitchen knife, casually wore a pair of jeans and a pair of white sandals, and took her son out to pick up the express delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If everything goes well, she will pick up the express delivery and return home in 10 minutes and prepare lunch. They had just moved into this new house. The developer called them and asked them to apply for the real estate certificate together. Unfortunately, the housing management center was off work at that time, so they agreed to do it as soon as they got back from a business trip.她和丈夫是高中同学，相识20年，结婚十几年，一起打拼到现在终于有了车、房和一个10岁的儿子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;该驿站一楼为便利店，二楼为菜鸟驿站&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从后来的监控视频可以看到，取件时，林梅一边看着手机上的取件码，一边在货架上找快递，根本没有注意到，脚下还有一个敞开的洞，她侧身寻找快递时不幸掉入脚下的洞中。洞口是老板平时用来上下货的，从二楼洞口到一楼地面高度为2.8米，洞口通常应该关闭，但事发时没有及时关上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这家菜鸟驿站用钢架和钢板结构把一个商铺的空间隔为两层，一楼是便利店卖水果蔬菜，二楼取快递，通常需要自己到二楼找件，自助扫码取件。快递驿站和便利店是同一个老板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据驿站老板描述，他也曾从洞口掉下去过，当时不小心闪了一下摔下去，只是腿受伤休养了一段时间。 “他是有心理防备的，但是我老婆没有任何心理防备，她掉下去的时候完全懵了，根本不知道发生了什么。”张象说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在病床上的林梅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在ICU门外，张象写了几行关于“勿念”的纸条让护士送进去，又在纸上空白处补充“每天下午五点可以探视”，画上两个笑脸，附带一支笔让林梅可以写点什么。后来纸条送出来的时候，纸是湿的，没有字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生命体征稳定以后，陆续做了三场手术，出现各种并发症，肺炎、泌尿系统感染、压疮、血栓，“四大并发症占全了，每天都有新的挑战。”张象在一个多月的时间里瘦了十多斤，“太痛苦了！”他描述，治疗血栓的过滤器，做的时候从大腿植入到血管，取的时候从脖子上取出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次大手术，是颈椎手术，张象印象深刻。他记得林梅从手术室出来的时候，她躺着，但表情放松，面带笑容，“因为觉得手术终于做完了，觉得可能很有希望，可能很快就能好了。”后来，这样的笑容越来越少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西医科大学第二医院康复医学科主治医生张昱告诉《南方人物周刊》，林梅在摔落的过程中，头撞到侧边的墙壁上，颈椎骨折造成的颈部脊髓损伤，导致四肢瘫痪。下肢完全不能活动，上肢活动很差。双腿的感觉和运动都处于丧失状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林梅在ICU时，张象写的纸条&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，颈脊髓是大脑脑干往躯体椎管内延续的一部分脑组织，受到损伤之后，不受大脑脑干支配，所以会出现瘫痪症状。脊髓损伤造成向大脑传输感觉的功能缺失，导致下级神经元会产生异常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“医生让我们做好最坏的打算。”张象说，“太痛苦了，如果癌症是判了死刑，脊髓损伤就相当于凌迟。”林梅无法自主翻身，甚至不能动动脚趾，只有病理性的抽搐，神经无法自主控制，没有出汗功能，感知不到冷和热。她会突然之间颤抖，但不觉得冷。有时候又觉得特别冷，像在冰天雪地里一样，实际上被子盖得好好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上肢力量小，拿不住碗筷，只能喂饭吃。张象在医院附近租了一个房子，给爱人做饭，平时家属和护工轮换照顾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱表示，完全性脊髓损伤恢复希望非常小，几乎是没有希望恢复。 “林梅目前来看是完全性损伤的状态，双腿恢复的难度非常大，但是在时间上还不能下定论。我们医院一般是3个月左右，如果3个月后还是这样的体征症状的话，就可以下定论了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，林梅累计治疗费用已超18万元，未来还将有很多开支。而在多次沟通下，截至目前菜鸟方面仅支付了2万元，菜鸟驿站店主支付了3.5万元。事发之后一个多月内，这家菜鸟驿站还在正常营业，甚至那个洞还在使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场不该发生的意外，彻底改变了一个家庭的命运和一位37岁女性的人生，儿子刚上小学五年级，而她的下半生都有可能将在病床上度过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意外背后暴露出快递驿站模式存在的诸多隐患。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;危险的发生：菜鸟驿站是如何运营的？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;某县城菜鸟驿站老板告诉《南方人物周刊》，自己的这家店于两年前开设，店内另有两位亲属帮忙，“正常驿站两三个人就够了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他描述，菜鸟不收取加盟费，开一家菜鸟驿站的前期投入并不算高：需要到菜鸟官方购置扫描枪、工作台、云监控、货架等设备，成本约为1万元左右；再加上保证金3000元、门面租金、水电费，基本上开一家菜鸟驿站的成本在3万元左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在店铺审核上，“需要在看好地方和房子之后，在网上提交申请，店铺的要求不严格，申请好了之后他们会过来看。之后直接去跟快递员或者快递公司片区负责人谈好价格就可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站的收入来源，主要是跟快递公司合作，由快递公司支付给驿站老板派送费及寄件收入。菜鸟驿站官方网站显示，每件快递的派送费为0.5-1元，寄件收入为3-5元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站模式之所以覆盖迅速，也与快递行业愈演愈烈的价格战相关。快递公司用价格换规模，必然影响利润，导致网点派送费降低，利润空间进一步被压缩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为节约“最后一公里”的末端配送成本，快递驿站可谓应运而生。中国物流协会调查数据显示，末端配送成本占物流行业总成本的30%以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈君曾是某电商平台旗下自营快递的网点经营者，负责“最后一公里”的末端配送，“公司确实下了不少本。”她提到，快递公司负责租房费用和电费水费，并免费配备电脑设备、安装摄像头，需要发该网点3个人的基本工资，之外还需要付每个快件的派送费，经营者只需要交一笔保证金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和亲戚经营该网点约6年时间，派送费从最早的4元，逐渐减少到1.5元、1元。在该店内，两个人负责送快递，一个人守店，负责分件、寄快递、处理退货等工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个客户他们都会送货上门，挨个打电话。凌晨4点多，需要起床去高速路口接快递，然后回来卸货、扫码分件。每天的件必须当天派送完，直接面对消费者，会碰到各种不同的情况，想做好这份工作，必须要有很强的服务意识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，这家电商平台因物流成本高而关停了旗下的自营快递公司，陈君便也不再经营。 “相比我们以前做的那些，现在这种快递驿站模式确实给快递公司省了不少成本，节省了快递员的精力，但对用户来说没以前方便了。”末端配送从快递公司全盘负责，变成了驿站老板自负盈亏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;行业竞争激烈，快递驿站的品牌越来越多，极兔速递驿站、圆通妈妈驿站、中通兔喜生活……甚至一个社区会出现多个快递驿站，有网友以自身经历吐槽：“因为小区比较大，取6个快递，竟然在6个不同的驿站。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;派送费也在持续下跌，《南方人物周刊》采访的两位菜鸟驿站的老板表示，在他们所在区域，派送费分别只有每单0.3元、0.5元，均比几年前的价格有所下跌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我家小区菜鸟驿站两年都换了七八个老板了。”一位网友表示，这种驿站的转让费一般并不低，亦出现驿站老板靠转让费“割一波韭菜”的情况——靠经营驿站赚的钱还没有转让费赚得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，经营副业便成了一个能够增加收入来源的选择。根据菜鸟驿站官网，其在介绍“菜鸟驿站是怎么赚钱的？”中提到：除了稳定的派费收入之外，依靠驿站带来的固定人流量，可以经营副业、售卖生活用品快销品等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但问题也在于，作为高频的生活场景，快递服务关键的“最后一公里”，店主若不能投入足够的精力，便难以保证服务质量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梅出事的菜鸟驿站便是如此。在这家店里，驿站成了副业，主业是蔬果超市。 “大家既然都要来，这是一个天然的引流渠道，所以他们把蔬菜水果放到一层，取快递在二层，且是自助的。”张象提到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在钢架结构私自开“洞”，存在安全隐患。事发时“洞”为敞开状态，林梅从中掉落&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被诟病的加盟模式以及法律风险&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国家邮政局的数据显示，2010年至2022年，我国快递业务量规模增长了47.3倍，电商的快速发展给快递业带来了巨量的需求增长，快递驿站模式应运而生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京东从2007年开始自建物流，凭借自有物流的优质服务赢得了客户的口碑。阿里深知自建物流所要耗费的成本高昂，为了提升平台的快递服务质量，它于2013年联合零售、地产、物流等企业打造菜鸟网络，其模式较轻，定位是物流体系中的“数据中枢”，即物流平台，采用加盟模式，菜鸟公司不承担驿站具体的运营成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，马云还曾表态“绝对不做物流”，这对于发展淘宝、天猫和拉拢物流公司起到了作用，得以进一步掌握物流环节的话语权。菜鸟既有阿里电商提供的流量，又具备稳定的物流配送网络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据阿里2023财年年报，菜鸟集团成为阿里巴巴集团内增长速度最高的业务，收入为556.81亿元，同比增长21%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月26日，菜鸟智慧物流网络有限公司正式向港交所提交上市申请，成为阿里“1+6+N”组织变革以来首个正式开启IPO进程的业务集团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8年前，菜鸟在安徽芜湖推出首个提供快递代收服务的“菜鸟驿站”。招股书显示，菜鸟如今在全球已有380多个物流分拨中心和17万个驿站，运营着全球最大的菜鸟驿站网络，日均处理包裹超8000万个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种加盟模式也引来争议，其本意是为消费者提供多元化的最后一公里服务，提高配送效率，但也极易出现相互推卸责任的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕竟，快递公司只负责到驿站这一环，而驿站直接赚的是快递公司的钱，而不是赚消费者的钱，菜鸟和消费者之间不存在直接的交易关系。菜鸟具有品牌影响力，但难以对每家加盟驿站严格监管，因此就难以让客户获得较好的服务体验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快递驿站模式本身也存在一定的法律风险。国务院2018年发布的《快递暂行条例》第二十五条规定，从事快递业务的企业应当将快递投递到约定的地址、收件人或者收件人指定的收件人，并告知收件人或者收件人当面验收。收件人或代理人有权当面验收。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在驿站模式下，很难做到送货上门。上述县城菜鸟驿站老板表示，的确有不少送货上门的诉求，“都可以送，现在如果说驿站不送的话，可能就落到快递公司上面了。快递公司让快递员给他派送，后续投诉驿站的话会有罚款。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在社交平台，有用户表示“投诉也没用，会被驿站拉黑名单，以后就不给你入库了，每次都从驿站返到快递网点，你的快递总会比别人的慢，目前来说没有什么有效的方法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京衡律师事务所合伙人钱颖刚告诉《南方人物周刊》，未经消费者同意，快递公司无权将消费者购买的商品放入快递驿站。消费者通过网络签订的电子商务合同，约定以包邮或支付邮费的方式将购买的商品运送至指定的地址，“快递公司如果未经消费者同意擅自更改送达地点或送达方式构成违约，应当承担继续履行合同或其他补救方式，并承担违约责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对驿站监管不力带来的安全隐患，后果则更为严重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在菜鸟驿站官网，提到驿站店铺的具体要求为：位于一楼（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;与马路平行&lt;/span>;），写字楼、商业体不限楼层。但林梅出事的驿站并未遵守此要求，私自搭建钢架结构，且在经营时间内未受到菜鸟公司的监管和整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“消费者完全不知道，总公司跟网点之间是什么关系，只知道菜鸟是个大公司，去取件，完全是天猫后台给我们推送的信息，这里是公共经营场所，但完全没有安全保障可言，导致了悲剧的发生。”张象说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱颖刚表示，在林梅事件中，“在加盟情况下，从保护消费者角度考虑，按特许经营来理解，特许人和加盟店应当对外承担连带责任。驿站老板因为自身的疏忽、过失，在服务过程中导致损害他人后果的，赔偿责任一般来说不能免除。在未经消费者同意的情况下，快递公司也应当承担共同侵权责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;坠落之后&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;每天一觉醒来是张象最痛苦的时刻，会觉得这是真的吗？如果是一个梦该多好。可现实如此残酷且真实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但他需要振作精神，在爱人抑郁、崩溃大哭的时候给她安慰。他在床边给林梅读苏东坡的诗词，读史铁生的文章，告诉她一个人的命运不可能是完美的，总会有一些坎坷曲折。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个多月以来，林梅大部分时间都在病房躺着，偶尔可以看到窗户外面的云，“你看外面的云越来越多。”她望着云，对张象说。这让他想起过去的某个普通的日子，两个人一起散步时，林梅会说：“你看天上的云，其实我们一起在外面走一走，看看天上的云，吹吹大自然的风就很幸福了。”张象说，“现在想来那个时候是最幸福的，但那时候我还不以为然。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张象眼里，林梅是一个特别简单、很会操持家务的人，只有她知道家里所有物品的摆放位置。出事之后刚开始一段时间，张象回家住过一晚，但“完全睡不着，每天晚上都很难受，看到家里所有的地方都是她的痕迹，都是她的影子，我完全没办法睡觉。在出租屋里，陌生的地方反而好一些”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从在一起以来，每年过生日的时候，林梅都会亲自给张象包饺子吃。不久前，张象生日，林梅对他说，“今天不能给你包饺子了。”“后来我妈包饺子，我回家取来，她也没吃多少，只吃了五六个。”张象回忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出差之前，张象去超市买了条鲫鱼，做了一道林梅最喜欢吃的鲫鱼豆腐汤。他记得那天林梅特别开心地吃完了，把他的皮鞋拿出来擦，黑皮鞋的白边擦得雪白，“像新买的一样。”张象叹口气，“等我赶回来以后，看到这双鞋边还是白的，但是人已不是以前了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱提到，在医院，黄金康复期是3-6个月。如果长期瘫痪，难以避免的并发症是心肺功能的降低，如果没有经济上的压力，可以做一些康复训练，用可动肢体去代偿失控肢体在生活工作上的一些训练，使身体的其他机能维持在一定的水平。后续护理、家庭康复阶段对照顾者的要求较高，家人和陪护人员需要付出很大的辛苦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我曾经承诺带她去一些地方，本来计划今年要去的，不管以后恢复成什么样，哪怕是坐轮椅也要带她去，当然坐轮椅会很不方便，所以就想一定要把她尽量治好，要实现我对她的承诺。”张象说他会继续“讨个公道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身为青年作家的张象，8月份有一本新书出版，林梅出事后出版社给他快递样书，他发现自己还只能去菜鸟驿站取，“感觉我一辈子都不想再去那个地方，但是没有办法，必须去拿我的书，因为没有选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中林梅、陈君化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最近，在社交媒体上火了一款运动裙裤，让人意外的是，这条“神仙裙子”既不是中产必备的Lululemon，也不是耐克安德玛等知名品牌，而是广大直男的老朋友——迪卡侬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一直以平价天堂和直男最爱著称的迪卡侬，这次为什么靠女性出圈了呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;数据显示，2022年至今，小红书上有关迪卡侬的笔记就已高达10w+，随着流量的激增，也带动了旗下女士产品的销量，据其淘宝官方旗舰店销量top5显示，排名最低的女性瑜伽裤都有高达3w+的销售量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，迪卡侬年销售额达到140亿欧元，中国成为最大的海外市场之一，其中女性需求最为耀眼，在迪卡侬官方店中，女士产品数量约占半数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这跟中国户外经济的发展有着密切的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2020年中国户外用品市场规模达3150亿元，2025年预计达到5990亿元，与欧美国家相比，我国户外经济市场规模仍有较大发展空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有调查显示，国内参与户外运动的群体主要为一线及新一线的青年女性，花得多、买得多、省得多成为当代女性旅游消费的三大特点，逐渐掀起小众运动之风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，迪卡侬看到了“女性消费者+小众运动”的发展潜力，今天，“知道”带你探索迪卡侬的转型秘诀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;封面.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省卫健委党组书记、主任朱宏接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260404]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:55:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision: Zhu Hong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law. He voluntarily surrendered and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Hong’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Hong, male, Han nationality, born in September 1966, with an on-the-job postgraduate degree, started working in September 1982, and started working in March 1986. Joined the Chinese Communist Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as member of the Party Committee and Vice President of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, director of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Academic Exchange Center, secretary of the Party Committee of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, and secretary and director of the Party Leadership Group of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探索宇宙中相互竞争的隐秘力量：欧几里得望远镜发布首批照片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 09:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 7, 2023, Beijing time, the European Space Agency released the Euclid Telescope (Euclid) The first 5 full-color pictures taken. These images are the result of scientists&#39; preliminary processing of the first batch of data obtained by the Euclid Telescope, but they have already demonstrated the powerful observation capabilities of the telescope - no telescope has ever obtained such clear images across such a large area of ​​the sky before. image. They believe that this telescope is ready to create the largest three-dimensional map of the universe in history, helping us gain insights into the nature of dark matter and dark energy in the &quot;dark&quot; universe, thereby revealing the hidden secrets of the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclid is a famous ancient Greek mathematician and is known as the &quot;Father of Geometry&quot;. His &quot;Elements of Geometry&quot; has been passed down to the world and laid the foundation for the development of geometry for more than two thousand years. Foundation. Scientists now realize that the density of matter and energy is closely related to the geometry of the universe and determines its future. Therefore, the European Space Agency (ESA) decided to name the telescope that explores the structure and evolution of the universe after Euclid to commemorate the pioneer of geometry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Key Questions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the current mainstream cosmological theory, only 5% of the visible ordinary matter in the universe is , the remaining 95% includes 25% dark matter and 70% dark energy. Therefore, understanding the nature of dark matter and dark energy has become one of the most important issues in science today. The Euclid telescope is expected to play an important role in research in this area over the next decade and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a range of up to 10 billion light-years, Euclid will observe billions of galaxies in more than 1/3 of the sky, creating a picture of the large-scale structure of the universe. picture. Scientists hope to study five key issues in cosmology by exploring the composition and evolution of the &quot;dark&quot; universe: the structure and evolutionary history of the cosmic web (matter in the universe is arranged in a huge network), what dark matter is, and the nature of the universe. How expansion changes over time, what the nature of dark energy is, and whether we really fully understand gravity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2007, researchers proposed two research plans in response to the European Space Agency&#39;s space exploration plan from 2015 to 2025, namely the &quot;Dark Universe Explorer&quot; (Dark Universe Explorer). DUNE) and the Spectroscopic All Sky Cosmic Explorer (SPACE). Both proposals propose complementary techniques to detect dark energy. After a period of evaluation and demonstration, the two plans were merged, and this became the later Euclid Telescope. In October 2011, the European Space Agency&#39;s Science Mission Committee selected the Euclid Telescope; in June 2012, the telescope project was officially established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than ten years of demonstration, design, construction and testing, the Euclid Telescope is finally ready for use. On July 1, 2023, the Euclid Telescope was successfully launched from the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Site in Florida, USA, on board the Falcon 9 rocket of the US Space Exploration Company (SpaceX). At the end of July, the telescope flew near the Sun-Earth&#39;s second Lagrange point, about 1.5 million kilometers away from the Earth, and successfully entered its working orbit. The European Space Agency&#39;s Gaia telescope and NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope are also in orbit around this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic illustration of the workings of the Euclidean telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope is about 4.7 meters high and 3.7 meters in diameter. It consists of a service module and a load module composition. Among them, the payload module that performs the detection function includes a 1.2-meter-diameter telescope and two scientific instruments: the visible light band camera (VIS) and the near-infrared band camera (NISP); the service module mainly includes power generation and distribution, attitude control, data Devices for handling, propulsion, thermal control, remote control and telemetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Space Agency has high hopes for the Euclid telescope. &quot;Dark matter pulls galaxies together, causing them to spin faster than visible matter itself can explain; dark energy is driving the accelerating expansion of the universe. For the first time, the Euclid Telescope will allow cosmologists to study these competing forces simultaneously Dark mysteries,&quot; European Space Agency science director Carole Mundell said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website. &quot;The Euclid Telescope will help us make leaps in understanding the entire universe, and these beautiful images show that , the mission is poised to help answer one of the biggest mysteries of modern physics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Amazing Images&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The first five images released by the Euclid Telescope are the Perseus Cluster of galaxies, the spiral galaxy IC 342, the irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822, the globular star cluster NGC 6397 and the Horsehead Nebula. Picture of (The Horsehead Nebula). The field of view of the telescope for observation is very large, reaching 0.5 square degrees, which exceeds the sky area occupied by the full moon. It took less than a day to shoot the five images released this time. From bright stars to faint galaxies, the Euclid Telescope relies on its powerful observation capabilities to create exceptionally clear visible and infrared images. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perseus is one of the largest known structures in the universe, located 240 million light-years from Earth. This image of the Perseus Galaxy Cluster shows the 1,000 galaxies that are part of the cluster, along with more than 100,000 more distant galaxies in the background. This is the first time astronomers have been able to capture so many of the Perseus Galaxy at such a high level of detail in such a large image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Perseus Galaxy Cluster photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of these faint galaxies have not been observed by astronomers before because some of them are very They are so far away that it took 10 billion years for their light to reach us. Astronomers have shown that galaxy clusters like Perseus could only form if dark matter was present in the universe. They will observe many galaxy clusters like Perseus through the Euclid telescope and map the distribution and shape of the galaxies in them to learn more about how dark matter binds these galaxies together to form galaxy clusters and shapes us The universe as seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in orbit, the Euclid Telescope will image billions of galaxies, revealing the invisible effects of dark matter and dark energy on them. Among the first galaxies observed by Euclid, one was nicknamed the &quot;Hidden Galaxy&quot;. This spiral galaxy similar in shape to the Milky Way was officially numbered IC 342 and was also known as Caldway. Er number 5. Thanks to the infrared capabilities of the Euclid Telescope, astronomers have discovered key information about the stars in this galaxy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The spiral galaxy IC 342 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early universe, most galaxies did not look like the typical spiral shape of the Milky Way. Not only are they irregular in appearance, they are also small and form the building blocks of larger galaxies like the Milky Way. We can still find some such galaxies in the relatively nearby universe. Among the images released by the Euclid Telescope, there is an irregular dwarf galaxy numbered NGC 6822, 1.6 million light-years away from the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope also photographed the globular star cluster NGC 6397, which is the second closest to Earth globular star cluster, about 7,800 light-years from Earth. Globular star clusters are collections of hundreds of thousands of stars held together by gravity. Currently, no other telescope other than Euclid can see an entire globular cluster in a single observation and identify so many stars in the cluster at the same time. These faint stars can tell us about the history of the Milky Way and the location of dark matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Globular star cluster NGC 6397 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the celestial objects for which the Euclid Telescope released images this time, the Horsehead Nebula is the closest One, also known as Barnard 33, is part of the constellation Orion and is about 1,500 light-years away from Earth. In this image of the Horsehead Nebula, we can see not only the spectacular panorama, but also the fine details. In new Euclid observations of the stellar cradle, scientists expect to find many faint, never-before-seen Jupiter-mass planets in their early stages of formation, as well as young brown dwarfs and baby stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Horsehead Nebula taken with the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Six years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;continuous observation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although only 5 pictures were released in the first batch, these pictures already reflect the tremendous efforts of the scientists and engineers behind the development of the telescope to create these masterpieces. Euclid project manager Giuseppe Racca said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website: &quot;Our high standards for this telescope have paid off. There is so much detail in these images, thanks to Special optical design, perfect manufacturing and assembly of the telescope and instruments and extremely precise pointing and temperature control.&quot; said René Laureijs, Euclid project scientist Comment: &quot;We have never seen astronomical images like this before, with so much detail. They are more beautiful and clearer than we could have hoped for, showing us much that has never been seen before in the known regions of the nearby universe. Characteristics. Now we are ready to observe billions of galaxies and study their evolution throughout the history of the universe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The debut of the Euclid Telescope has inspired the astronomical community, and many people insist that Have the same opinion as Rene Laures. The images demonstrate the extraordinary capabilities of the Euclid Telescope&#39;s various instruments, which allow astronomers to study the distribution of matter in the universe and its evolution on the largest scales. Based on a large number of high-quality observations covering large areas of the sky, they will show us dark and hidden parts of the universe. And beyond the realms of dark matter and dark energy, these images show how Euclid can help astronomers create a treasure trove of information about the physics of individual stars and galaxies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclidean Union director Yannick Mellier said: &quot;Over the next few months, Euclid Union scientists will analyze these images and develop A series of scientific papers are published in the journal &lt;em>;Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics&lt;/em>;, as well as papers on the scientific objectives and instrument performance of the Euclid mission.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the months since the Euclid Telescope was launched, scientists and engineers have been testing and calibrating the telescope&#39;s science equipment. The team is currently making final fine-tuning in order to begin regular observations in early 2024. As the mission progresses, data obtained by the telescope will be released annually and open to researchers around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, the Euclid telescope will carry out observations for six years, after which the possibility of extending the mission will be evaluated based on the remaining amount of cryogenic gas used for propulsion. In the next six years, we can expect that the Euclid Telescope will continue to bring us new surprises and use more wonderful pictures to show us the hidden charm of the universe. The analysis of observational data will last longer, and astronomers will carefully search for clues to unravel the mysteries of dark matter and dark energy in these data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[万亿特殊再融资债券：云南、内蒙古、辽宁超千亿，北上广未发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260402]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73412&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70221&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG211250367208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan , ranking first in the country. Visual China/Picture&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257853&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan, Ranked first in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All creditors have been notified to settle their arrears.&quot; A grassroots official from a western province told a Southern Weekend reporter that the funds for the special refinancing bonds issued this time have been received and are being paid. Complete government debt. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, various regions began to issue special refinancing bonds on a large scale. According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, as of November 5, 25 provinces (municipalities and autonomous regions) have issued a total of 1.13 trillion yuan, equivalent to Gansu&#39;s GDP in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special refinancing bonds are issued by provincial governments. For municipal and county governments, they are equivalent to an extra amount of low-interest debt repayment funds, which can replace high-interest debts and lengthen the repayment cycle. Compared with refinancing bonds issued in ordinary times, special refinancing bonds do not list specific bond information for repayment. According to past issuance history, it is mainly used to repay implicit debts in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A number of local financial system officials revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that this special refinancing bond has two main investment purposes, one is to replace high-interest non-standard debt, and the other is to repay the debt owed by government departments to enterprises. accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of this round of special refinancing bonds, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on July 24, emphasizing the need to effectively prevent and resolve local debt risks and formulate and implement a package of debt reduction plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Zhang Qingsong, deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, said at the International Financial Leaders Investment Summit that &quot;a few provinces may face debt repayment pressure, and most of the debts of the relevant provinces are backed by real assets. Add A package of market-oriented plans has been formulated, and I believe that with the implementation of targeted policies, some local government debt risks will gradually be reduced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, and Liaoning issued over 100 billion yuan&lt;/p>; h4>; &lt;p>;According to the issuance information of this special refinancing bond, as of November 5, the top three provinces by issuance amount are: Yunnan (107.6 billion yuan), Inner Mongolia (106.7 billion yuan), Liaoning (100.6 billion yuan) . The region with the least issuance is Shanxi, with only 2.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt/GDP)*100%, in 2022, the debt ratios of the above three places will rank first among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions (excluding Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). Nine, tenth, twelfth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, only six regions including Beijing, Guangdong, Shanghai, Zhejiang, Hainan and Tibet did not issue special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Guangdong, Zhejiang, Shanghai, and Beijing have low debt ratios and developed economies. The government debt of Hainan and Tibet is not large. In 2022, Tibet&#39;s government debt balance is only 56.8 billion yuan, ranking last among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions. Hainan’s debt balance is 348.7 billion yuan, ranking fourth from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of issuance structure, as of November 5, among the special refinancing bonds issued, the scale of general bonds was 759.4 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%; the scale of special bonds was 368.6 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%. 32.7%. General bonds have a wide range of uses for funds, while special bonds have limited investment options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this round of special refinancing bond issuance, no department has yet explained the quotas for each region. However, judging from the issuance situation, funds still flow more to the central and western provinces with relatively low fiscal self-sufficiency rates, as well as regions with larger debt scales and higher debt ratios. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The province requires us to deal with high-interest non-standard debt first.” A financial system official in a northern province told Southern Weekend reporters that after issuing special refinancing bonds, his prefecture-level city obtained With more than 10 billion yuan in funds, arrangements are currently being made to redeem non-standard products. Since the beginning of this year, there have been many non-standard defaults in the local area, which has put great pressure on repaying principal and interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to debt replacement, another important purpose is to pay off the government&#39;s debts to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the bond issuance information disclosed by Inner Mongolia showed that it plans to issue 66.32 billion yuan of refinancing general bonds, and the funds raised will be used to repay the arrears of corporate accounts that the government is responsible for repaying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, the above-mentioned bond issuance materials were updated, and the purpose of the funds was adjusted to repay existing debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Audit Work Report on the Budget Implementation and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures of the Autonomous Region in 2022&quot; previously released by Inner Mongolia showed that the policy of clearing up the accounts of small and medium-sized enterprises owed to private enterprises has not been implemented, and 62 companies are owed 111 million yuan. . In addition, at the end of 2021, Inner Mongolia&#39;s temporary payment balance was as high as 47.055 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, Premier Li Qiang chaired an executive meeting of the State Council. The meeting pointed out that the provincial government should take overall responsibility for the settlement of arrears in the region, promptly solve the problem of government arrears on corporate accounts, and untie the &quot;chain&quot; of mutual arrears between enterprises, and central and state-owned enterprises should take the lead in repayment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Every creditor is now required to complete the procedures first.” The grassroots official in the western province mentioned above said that for example, in the past when building a road, the company had to complete a complete set of procedures for completion acceptance and submit it to the province for review and approval before releasing the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some regions have begun to offer discounts to repay accounts owed to companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Wuxi Delinhai Environmental Protection Technology Co., Ltd. (688069.SH) issued an announcement stating that the company, Yuxi Water Conservancy Bureau and Dali Erhai Protection Investment and Construction Co., Ltd. had receivables for some projects. The accounts receivable reached a debt restructuring plan, and the above-mentioned accounts receivable totaled 160 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement, Delinhai agreed to give the debtor a certain discount and is expected to recover 120 million yuan through this debt restructuring. Industrial and commercial information shows that Erhai Investment Company is a state-owned enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement explains that there are two backgrounds for this debt restructuring. First, the above-mentioned National Standing Committee requires that the problem of corporate account arrears be solved; second, the Yunnan Provincial Government strives to resolve the existing hidden debts and implement hidden debts. The policy of clearing sexual debts was implemented and the implementation of a number of debt reduction measures was implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issuance of special refinancing bonds is undoubtedly an important part of the debt reduction measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73413&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70222&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG1515.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2266&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257854&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Faster and higher than the previous two rounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, there have been two peak issuance periods of special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that from December 2020 to September 2021, a total of 627.8 billion yuan of special refinancing bonds were issued, mainly used for the pilot program of implicit debt resolution in incorporated counties. Immediately afterwards, from October 2021 to June 2022, a total of 504.18 billion yuan was issued, mainly for the pilot program without hidden debt in the entire region, concentrated in Beijing, Shanghai, and Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Luo Zhiheng, president of the Guangdong Securities Research Institute, the proportion of local government bond renewals from 2018 to 2022 were 81.3%, 87.3%, 87.2%, 86.3% and 86.1% respectively, all at the The higher level is mainly to repay bonds issued in 2015-2017. From January to August 2023, the renewal ratio will increase to 90.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maturity renewal ratio = (refinancing bonds - special refinancing bonds) / maturity size. Generally speaking, after local government bonds mature, in addition to issuing refinancing bonds, fiscal funds, etc. will also be arranged for repayment. In other words, as the tight financial balance of local governments intensifies, they rely more on issuing bonds to renew maturing debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the previous two rounds of special refinancing bonds issued, this issuance is faster. In just over a month, the issuance amount exceeded one trillion yuan. The amount of this issuance is also close to the sum of the previous two rounds, and it has not yet ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after refinancing bonds replace implicit debt, it will increase the government debt balance. According to current regulations, local government debt (general debt and special debt) is subject to limit control. The difference between the debt limit and the debt balance is the maximum issuance amount of local special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the main issuance of general bonds as an example. As of November 5, seven regions including Inner Mongolia, Tianjin, and Guizhou have exceeded the local maximum issuance quota, that is, the debt ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Laicheng, a professor at the Central University of Finance and Economics, told Southern Weekend reporters that the issuance of special refinancing bonds in some places may exceed local debt limits. To this end, the Ministry of Finance will make overall adjustments and increase the debt limits of some regions on the basis of the local debt limits approved by the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the &quot;Report on the 2022 Municipal Budget Adjustment Plan (Draft)&quot; released by Chongqing City in September 2022 mentioned that the Ministry of Finance requires that the balance limit of special debt should be approximately 70%. It is retained by each province (autonomous region and municipality) and recovered by the central government at a proportion of approximately 30% for overall deployment among provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as a special means, special refinancing bonds can only relieve local government debt pressure in the short term, and the issuance amount is limited, which cannot completely solve the hidden debts of various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An executive of a county-level urban investment company in the north told Southern Weekend reporters that his province issued tens of billions of special refinancing bonds this time because the company had successively experienced non-standard overdue incidents this year. Due to heavy debt pressure, he reported to higher-level government departments to apply for bond funding support, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, after the issuance of trillions of special refinancing bonds, the financing demand of local urban investment platforms remains strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of a financial leasing platform in Shanghai told Southern Weekend reporters that several provinces he is responsible for have issued special refinancing bonds, but it has not affected business development. Several urban investment platforms he has recently contacted, Liquidity is still urgently needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>