<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[69个案例，多个政府部门被立案调查背后：反垄断的硬骨头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260196]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Starting in March 2022, the State Administration for Market Regulation will launch a nationwide campaign to curb administrative abuses Powers, special actions to eliminate law enforcement that restricts competition. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/b7302f0170.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/b7302f0170.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257560&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beginning in March 2022, the State Administration for Market Regulation will launch a nationwide special campaign to curb the abuse of administrative power and exclude and restrict competition from law enforcement. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On April 7, 2023, the Urban Management Bureau of Dingnan County, Jiangxi Province was placed under investigation for reasons related to the operating rights of shared bicycles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of 2022, the Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau will conduct a public bidding for the shared electric bicycle operating rights project in the main urban area of ​​the county. In the end, two companies obtained the operating rights, and the Urban Management Bureau signed contracts with these two companies, limiting a total of 1,500 vehicles to be put into operation for a period of three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After investigation by the Jiangxi Provincial Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, it is believed that the Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau limited the number of shared electric vehicles in the main urban area through public bidding without any legal and regulatory basis. Operating enterprises excludes or restricts other business entities with qualified qualifications and service capabilities from entering this market, hindering fair market competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau was found to have abused administrative power to exclude and restrict competition. This behavior is also called administrative monopoly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Bing, director of the Competition Law Research Center of Nankai University, explained that administrative monopoly is an administrative monopoly that directly or indirectly interferes with market competition to protect or support certain entities by abusing administrative power. specific operators or commodities to maximize the interests of themselves or others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 is the 15th anniversary of the implementation of the Anti-Monopoly Law. The &quot;Regulations on Preventing the Abuse of Administrative Power to Eliminate or Restrict Competition&quot; have also been revised. Starting from April 15, 2023 Effective from today. Since March 2022, the State Administration for Market Regulation has launched a nationwide special campaign to stop the abuse of administrative power and exclude and restrict competition from law enforcement. From June 2022 to January 2023, a total of 5 batches and 63 administrative monopoly cases were announced. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, the State Administration for Market Regulation will launch a special anti-monopoly law enforcement action in the field of people&#39;s livelihood. The two batches of typical cases currently announced include 6 administrative monopoly cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, the behavior of the Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau was reported as a typical case of anti-administrative monopoly. At present, the Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau has made rectifications, canceled the contract, and issued an announcement to fully open the shared electric vehicle market in the main urban area of ​​the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;With &quot;good intentions&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 18th, relevant staff from the Dingnan County Urban Management Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that they had canceled the bidding. The Harbin Urban Management Bureau, which was put under investigation for the same reason, stated that the shared bicycle bidding business has been handed over to the Municipal Transportation Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that in 69 cases, a total of 69 administrative agencies were punished. Generally speaking, the cases involved are mainly concentrated in the fields of people&#39;s livelihood such as urban management, medical care, education, and construction. Chen Bing explained that industry supervision in these fields has obvious characteristics, and administrative agencies can directly allocate resources during the management process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the typical cases published, the motivations of the units involved are different, and some administrative monopoly behaviors even occur out of &quot;good intentions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2022, the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau of Xiangshan County, Ningbo City issued a recommended list of housing safety appraisal institutions, requiring those who carry out housing safety appraisal business in Xiangshan County to obtain the municipal certification After filing the certificate with the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, you should register with the County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau. In October 2022, the Zhejiang Provincial Market Supervision Bureau determined that this behavior constituted the abuse of administrative power to exclude and restrict competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A staff member of the Xiangshan County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that their original intention was to facilitate the masses, “They always ask questions like this when they come to do business. ——We don’t know which housing safety agencies to look for for appraisal, so we put the list of nearly 20 registered agencies on the official account of the County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above-mentioned staff emphasized that house safety appraisal is a bottom-line issue. They need to comprehensively analyze the qualifications, capabilities, and creditworthiness of all appraisal agencies before making it public. Therefore, they A directory of housing safety appraisal agencies registered in Ningbo City will be formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the investigation, the Xiangshan County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau has withdrawn the recommended list. However, this staff member believes that if there are only one or two houses, it may be a monopoly. However, their recommended list includes more than a dozen housing safety appraisal agencies from Ningbo and Hangzhou, and &quot;there is none in Xiangshan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, some administrative agencies are not aware that the documents issued constitute an administrative monopoly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2017, the Finance Bureau of Pingluo County, Ningxia designated an insurance company as the underwriting unit for traffic accident insurance for various administrative institutions in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The person in charge of the relevant departments of the Pingluo County Finance Bureau said that because the document was released for so long, the drafter of the document and the person responsible for its preparation and issuance are no longer in the bureau. They had not noticed this document before. It was not until March 2023, when the Market Supervision Bureau came to investigate, that they found the document and invalidated the relevant provisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When it comes to the implementation of the document, the person in charge said that it also depends on the budget of each unit. Some units are implementing it, while others have not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Jin, director of the Competition Law and Policy Research Center of Wuhan University, believes that administrative agencies lack the concept of fair competition in the policy formulation process and often only think about bidding and investment. Introducing investment to stimulate the economy while ignoring the need to maintain the bottom line of fair competition in the market can easily lead to the emergence of administrative monopolies. &lt;strong>; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; sp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp ;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Antitrust and Anti-Corruption&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Among the reported administrative monopoly cases, the common handling methods are to abrogate the execution of the original documents, terminate the bidding work or cancel the contract, and submit a rectification report. There are also cases where the market supervision and administration administration issues administrative proposals to the local people&#39;s government, and a few supervisors Personnel and those directly responsible were punished, often involving corruption such as power-for-money transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In April 2021, the Chenzhou City Education Bureau of Hunan Province identified 4 school uniform production and supply manufacturers through bidding, and divided the urban area into 4 areas, limiting each area. Regional schools can only purchase uniforms from designated manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Hunan Provincial Market Supervision Bureau believed during its investigation in August 2021 that the above-mentioned behavior deprived the school and the parent committee of the right to make independent choices. As a result, the bidding process was terminated in September 2021. (The special action in 2022 announced 5 batches of 63 typical cases, 23 of which were filed for investigation in 2021.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, A staff member of the Chenzhou City Education Bureau office said that the technical equipment department, a secondary organization under the Education Bureau, is responsible for the primary and secondary school uniform business. Due to disciplinary violations in the public bidding process for the qualification of primary and secondary school uniform manufacturers, this organization was suspended midway. The Administration for Market Regulation called a halt, and the Commission for Discipline Inspection subsequently intervened in the investigation, and the person in charge of the agency was also punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Chenzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection pointed out that from 2013 to 2022, Li Junhong took advantage of his position as deputy director and director of the Technical Equipment Department of the Chenzhou Municipal Education Bureau to facilitate others. Undertaken primary and secondary schools uniform business, school laboratories, facilities and equipment and installation service procurement projects to provide assistance, illegally receiving other people&#39;s property totaling 2.448 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2022, Li Junhong was expelled from the party and dismissed from public office. Suspected criminal issues were transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being punished, the Chenzhou Municipal Education Bureau took rectification measures. The above-mentioned staff stated that the Education Bureau, together with the Municipal Development and Reform Commission and the Municipal Supervision Bureau, issued a notice on further standardizing the management of primary and secondary school uniforms on September 15, 2021, emphasizing that all documents and materials for the selection and purchase of school uniforms should be archived by the school. School uniforms Procurement contracts must be filed with the competent education department, and transactions shall not be interfered with by violating market principles or by fixing trademarks or other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, a monopoly case involving the Health Bureau of Shuangfeng County, Hunan Province is also worthy of attention. At the end of October 2021, relevant companies in the county jointly reported that the Shuangfeng County Health Bureau signed an agreement with a company to issue mandatory target tasks for drug procurement by county-affiliated public medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;An investigation by the Hunan Market Supervision Bureau found that Shuangfeng County Health Bureau signed a cooperation agreement with Sinopharm Holding Changsha Co., Ltd., requiring all public medical institutions in Shuangfeng County to A certain proportion of the purchase volume of medicines, consumables, equipment, etc. is provided to Sinopharm Holding Changsha Co., Ltd., and the Shuangfeng County Health Bureau also issues quotas in the form of documents to public medical institutions in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The agreement also stipulates that from July 2021 to the end of 2022, the total purchase quota from public medical institutions in Shuangfeng County to Sinopharm Holding Changsha Co., Ltd. is 1.2 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 19, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted the person in charge of the Essential Drugs Unit of Shuangfeng County Health Bureau who is responsible for drug procurement and asked about the whole story. The other party said, &quot;I don&#39;t know and I don&#39;t want to talk about it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Sun Jin’s view, antitrust is often closely related to anti-corruption. Some companies rack their brains to maintain relationships with officials with decision-making power, waiting for the time to mature. , they will require the other party to formulate rules to protect their interests, such as granting exclusive business rights, or giving opportunities in policy preferences, incentives and subsidies, and bidding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This also means that some market entities will also push administrative agencies to abuse administrative power.&quot; Sun Jin added. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The harm of administrative monopoly&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared to the economy Sexual monopoly and administrative monopoly rarely come into public view. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Bing believes that on the one hand, there are indeed fewer cases of administrative monopoly than economic monopoly cases; on the other hand, administrative monopoly is mainly ordered to correct and punished by superior authorities. The focus is on punishing supervisors or other responsible personnel in accordance with the law, and the punishment information does not belong to the content that must be disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;But administrative monopoly is more harmful than economic monopoly.&quot; Chen Bing explained that administrative monopoly sets unreasonable entry barriers, causing market Fragmentation and misallocation of resources prevent other operators from making full use of their own advantages to participate in competition. In the long run, this will reduce the competitiveness and innovation capabilities of all enterprises in the market, and at the same time reduce the total social welfare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Jin believes that for anti-monopoly law enforcement agencies, anti-economic monopoly is mainly a technical issue, and it is not difficult to judge whether it has substantially hindered fair market competition. Not big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He emphasized that the hard nut of anti-monopoly is actually administrative monopoly. At present, abuse of power still occurs from time to time, and it is still very serious in some areas. In addition, in administrative monopolies, there is a large amount of interest transfer, and some companies gain unfair competitive advantages, suppress small and medium-sized enterprises, and compete for their profit opportunities. This is contrary to common prosperity, high-quality development, and the construction of a unified national market. Anti-administrative monopoly has always been the top priority of anti-monopoly work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that on August 1, 2022, the first day the new Anti-Monopoly Law came into effect, Gan Lin, Director of the State Anti-Monopoly Bureau, published an article in the &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; The signed article mentioned that &quot;we must insist on equal emphasis on preventing market monopoly and breaking administrative monopoly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the 2023 National Market Supervision System Anti-Monopoly Work Conference, anti-administrative monopoly is also the focus of the 2023 work goals, including strengthening the supply of fair competition review systems , studying and drafting the &quot;Fair Competition Review Regulations (Draft)&quot;, etc. At present, the &quot;Fair Competition Review Regulations&quot; have been publicly solicited for opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 15 years since the Anti-Monopoly Law was implemented, the fair competition review mechanism has been an important part of the anti-administrative monopoly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Establishing a Fair Competition Review System in the Construction of the Market System&quot;, emphasizing standardizing government behavior and establishing a fair competition review system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A landmark node is that the State Administration for Market Regulation was officially listed in April 2018 and began to assume unified anti-monopoly law enforcement responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2022, the Anti-Monopoly Law was revised for the first time after its promulgation. The chapter involving anti-administrative monopoly added a fair competition review system. &quot;This is equivalent to controlling the situation from the source and reducing the impact of policies formulated by administrative agencies on market competition,&quot; Chen Bing analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Breaking down regional barriers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Relevant regulations and policies are constantly evolving While improving, anti-administrative monopoly law enforcement has also been continuously strengthened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The special anti-administrative monopoly action in 2022 is not the first time. From September 2019 to January 2020, the State Administration for Market Regulation carried out special actions nationwide to stop the abuse of administrative power and exclude and restrict competition from law enforcement, focusing on transportation, construction, medicine, official seal engraving, bidding and government procurement5 an area where there are many illegal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the special operation, the market supervision department investigated more than 50 cases in the above five fields and verified more than 80 case clues. However, no typical cases were announced to the public at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, the State Administration for Market Regulation has published an annual report on antitrust enforcement every year since its establishment. The report shows that from 2019 to 2022, law enforcement agencies investigated a total of 354 cases of abuse of administrative power to eliminate or restrict competition, and concluded 198 cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the numbers of such cases investigated from 2019 to 2021 were 84, 98, and 80 respectively, and the numbers settled were 12, 67, and 46 respectively. The State Administration for Market Regulation launched a special law enforcement action on the abuse of administrative power to exclude and restrict competition in 2022, investigating a total of 92 cases and settling 73 cases. The number of settlements increased by 59% compared with 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In contrast, in the eleven years from 2008 to 2018, antitrust law enforcement agencies investigated and dealt with a total of 223 such cases, with an average of approximately 20 cases; and in the four years from 2019 to 2022, the average was 88 cases per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fair competition review system is also constantly being implemented and promoted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the fair competition review system achieved full coverage of the national, provincial, municipal, and county governments. As of the end of 2020, a total of 857,000 newly issued policies had been reviewed across the country, and more than 4,100 policy measures that violated review standards were discovered and corrected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022 alone, various regions and departments will review 163,700 newly issued policies and measures, clean up 452,000 existing policies and measures of various types, and abolish, revise, and correct There are more than 20,000 policies and measures to eliminate or restrict competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In other words, these policy documents that may affect fair competition in the market have not been issued because they have not passed the fair competition review, or previously issued documents have been abolished because they have not passed the review. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, the anti-administrative monopoly work has a long way to go, and there are still some problems that need to be solved urgently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Bing pointed out that on the one hand, it is necessary to break down local protection and regional barriers, thoroughly clean up policies and practices that hinder market access and the free circulation of commodity factors, and reduce institutional Transaction costs are the key to breaking down barriers that restrict economic circulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, it is necessary to continuously regulate the interference of administrative power in market competition, &quot;especially in the fields of bidding, government procurement, public utilities and other fields, to prevent designated transactions , discriminatory conditions and other unfair behaviors, allowing local governments to effectively form an integrated competition protection mechanism of &#39;pre-examination + in-process and post-event supervision&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Sun Jin’s view, consciousness and concepts are the core issues. He believes that antitrust laws need to be popularized among government officials so that they can make scientific, reasonable and legal decisions based on the provisions of antitrust laws and fair competition review systems. “Consumers and small and medium-sized enterprises also need to be mobilized to supervise the government, and all parties can work together to promote An ecology of fair competition.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[跨国药企扎堆进博会，多款创新药首秀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被传收购碧桂园？中国平安回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 09:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 8, foreign media reported the news of Ping An’s acquisition of Country Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4b28e3afa0ab6ee807d2c994e8a6fd08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4b28e3afa0ab6ee807d2c994e8a6fd08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257517&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Ping An issued a statement saying that the company has noticed a news report published by Reuters about the company being required by relevant government departments/institutions to acquire Country Garden Holdings Co., Ltd. and inherit its debts. The company solemnly declares that the report This is completely untrue and the company has never received any relevant request from any government department/agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statement pointed out that the company had previously provided clarification in writing to Reuters when receiving relevant inquiries, but Reuters still insisted on publishing relevant false reports, and the company deeply regretted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern+ reporters noticed that as of press time, the latest share price of Country Garden (02007.HK) was HK$0.82, up 10.81%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[少林寺在非洲设分支：黑人武僧是切实的文化输出]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260162]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Shaolin Temple Abbot Shi Yongxin and his party visited Bolivia, Argentina and other South American countries to carry out a series of cultural exchanges Activity. On the morning of October 21, 2023, local time in Bolivia, the Shaolin cultural delegation watched the Shaolin Kungfu report performance of Bolivian Shaolin disciples and interacted on the spot. While in Bolivia, the Shaolin cultural delegation also visited the South American Shaolin Cultural Center, Bolivia Baoen Temple and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, a video on Weibo of a young black monk practicing Shaolin Kung Fu also sparked heated discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the young monk boxing in the video black, but the master is also black. This is a branch of the Shaolin Temple in Africa. Some people say that this is the flowering of Chinese culture within the wall and the loss of culture; the Shaolin Temple is becoming more and more international, making people feel that it has lost its original flavor. This view is of course wrong, and someone has refuted it very well: once it is exported, it will be lost, and if it is not exported, it will be criticized as cultural weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shaolin Temple has been engaged in systematic cultural dissemination, forming many practice platforms that influence and disseminate Shaolin Kungfu and its culture, and building a global dissemination mechanism centered on Shaolin culture at home and abroad. It has had a huge social impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2001, Shaolin layman &quot;foreign disciple&quot; Deller opened the Shaolin Cultural Center in Berlin, Germany. This was the first overseas branch directly authorized to cooperate with the Shaolin Temple. Currently, there are nearly 200 overseas Shaolin cultural centers distributed around the world. According to data from relevant institutions, there are no less than 60 million people practicing Shaolin Kung Fu around the world; there are hundreds of Shaolin cultural institutions in more than 100 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, the &quot;Shaolin European Federation&quot; was established in Vienna; in 2004, the California House of Representatives unanimously passed a resolution and established in law March 21 of each year as &quot;Songshan Shaolin Temple Day&quot;. In 2010, the &quot;Shaolin European Federation&quot; was announced in Vienna, Austria; in 2011, the &quot;Shaolin North American Federation&quot; was established in Los Angeles, the United States. In 2014, the 10th anniversary of the establishment of &quot;Songshan Shaolin Temple Day&quot; in California, the then US President Obama said in his congratulatory message: &quot;Shaolin culture can provide us with spiritual space and help us cultivate a strong sense of social responsibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shaolin Temple recruits foreign disciples and even goes out to build temples and Kung Fu training classes, which can not only promote Buddhism, but also Shaolin Kung Fu and spread Chinese culture. Shaolin Temple is the place where Patriarch Bodhidharma stayed the longest after he came to China. It is known as the ancestral palace of Zen Buddhism. Zen Buddhism absorbs a large amount of ideological content from Confucianism and Taoism, turning foreign Buddhism into a Chinese Buddhism that corresponds to China&#39;s specific social and historical conditions and ideological and cultural background. Therefore, Zen Buddhism has realized the transformation from the Sinicization of Buddhism to Sinicized Buddhism and is rich in profound Chinese cultural elements. Shaolin Kung Fu and Shaolin Temple have gone global, and Chinese culture has also expanded its influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although black young monks and black abbots seem to be inconsistent, it is just because they are not used to it. It should be pointed out that the process of cultural export, success and acceptance cannot remain unchanged. It will also change and alienate according to local social, cultural, technological, economic, moral, conceptual and other factors, forming new ones to some extent. culture. We must maintain a tolerant attitude toward such changes and mutations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the influence of the Chinese New Year (Spring Festival) is growing, and many countries and regions have designated the Chinese New Year as a legal holiday. There will be a holiday on this day, and national and regional leaders will extend holiday greetings to those celebrating the Spring Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the international context, the Chinese New Year is often written as: Chinese new year. &quot;Happy Chinese New Year&quot; is translated as &quot;Happy Chinese New Year&quot;, indicating that this New Year comes from the Chinese calendar. However, with the growing influence of the Spring Festival, there is now a trend to translate the Spring Festival into &quot;Lunar New Year&quot;. Lunar means &quot;moon&quot; and can be understood as &quot;lunar calendar&quot;. Nowadays, many people use it this way. US officials use &quot;Lunar New Year&quot; when issuing New Year greetings. United Nations Secretary-General Guterres also used &quot;Lunar New Year&quot; in his New Year greeting video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that this is an attempt to de-Sinicize the Spring Festival and steal a Chinese festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You don’t have to look at it this way. This is the normal state of cultural export. The Romans originally used the Egyptian lunar calendar. In 46 BC, Roman commander Julius Caesar decided to recompile the Julian Calendar based on the Egyptian solar calendar. In 325 AD, the Roman Emperor Constantine established the Julian calendar as the Christian calendar. By the 6th century AD, Christians regarded the day when Jesus, the founder of Christian legends, was born more than 500 years ago as the first year of AD. Before the 16th century, most Western countries adopted the Julian calendar. In 1582, Pope Gregory XIII, with the assistance of the Neapolitan astronomer and physicist Giraldi and the German mathematician and Jesuit Clavius, corrected the Julian calendar promulgated in 46 BC. Errors formed the Gregorian calendar commonly used in our modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Revolution of 1911, the Provisional Government of the Republic of China legislated to use the Gregorian calendar from January 1, 1912, and stipulated that January 1 of the Gregorian calendar would be the &quot;New Year&quot;. This is now recognized around the world as the starting point of the new year. However, now everyone in the world can only say &quot;Happy New Year&quot; but not &quot;Happy Roman New Year&quot;. This is not stealing a holiday from the Romans or Christians, but a normal process of cultural export. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many countries in Asia also celebrate the Lunar New Year, such as South Korea, Vietnam, Singapore, Malaysia, etc. From their perspective, they may not want to use an obviously regional name like &quot;Chinese&quot;, so they will use &quot;Happy Lunar New Year&quot; to express &quot;Happy Spring Festival&quot;, which is just like the Chinese people don&#39;t know how to express &quot;Happy Lunar New Year&quot;. It&#39;s the same as saying &quot;Happy New Year Roman&quot;, but what does it matter? This calendar was passed down from China. Under the tributary system in the traditional era, the Chinese dynasty would issue calendars and allow surrounding vassal states to &quot;honor Shuo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, whether it is African black Shaolin Temple disciples or it is called &quot;Lunar New Year&quot;, it is a real cultural export. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[争论“开门杀”责任与赔偿：为何司机负主责，为何保险要代赔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260160]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Taxi parked on the roadside in Beijing. &quot;Opening the door to kill&quot; has become a hot topic in recent years . Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Yi Haifei China News Service Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f1e419dff4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f1e419dff4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A taxi parked on the roadside in Beijing. &quot;Opening the door to kill&quot; has become a hot topic in recent years. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Yi Haifei China News Service Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October 2023, the incident of a child in Tianjin being &quot;killed by opening the door&quot; and then being run over by a bus attracted attention. While riding an electric bicycle to carry her daughter, a woman hit the newly opened door of a passenger bus on the side of the road. The child fell to the ground and was crushed to death by the wheels of a passing bus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is another &quot;open door killing&quot; case. Southern Weekend reporters searched the relevant judicial documents website and found that in recent years, &quot;open door killing&quot; accidents have occurred frequently. Dai Xianfeng, secretary-general of the Legal Affairs Committee of the China Communications and Transportation Association, believes that with the substantial growth of private cars and non-motor vehicles, the public generally lacks awareness of the dangers of &quot;opening the door to kill&quot;, resulting in the frequent occurrence of such accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters that door-opening killings are mainly divided into two types: one is when the driver opens the door himself and collides with a non-motorized vehicle, in which case the driver bears full responsibility; If a passenger opens the door and collides with a non-motor vehicle, the passenger will generally constitute a joint tort with the driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latter situation can be subdivided into different accident types, and the final liability for compensation will also be different. Two common situations are: the driver and the passenger have an operational relationship, such as taxis, online ride-hailing and other passenger-carrying activities; the driver and the passenger are friends or relatives, and there is no operational relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;&#39;Opening the door to kill&#39; is a hot topic in traffic accidents. It is very lethal and its liability determination has always been controversial.&quot; Zhou Bo, a senior lawyer who has been representing traffic accident cases for many years, added that at present, all over China The traffic control department in China still lacks unified identification standards when determining responsibility for &quot;opening the door to kill&quot; accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What responsibilities does the online ride-hailing platform bear?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 18:00 on November 3, 2020, just after work, 39-year-old Zhang He was riding an electric bicycle on the non-motorized lane on his way home. He collided with an online ride-hailing car that had just opened the door, causing Zhang He to be seriously injured and unconscious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident occurred on Zhongshan 2nd Road, Songjiang District, Shanghai. Relevant judgments show that after completing a trip, the online ride-hailing driver Xia Moulin temporarily stopped the vehicle and did not keep the vehicle close to the right side of the road. He also did not remind passenger Fang Mouxin to observe the traffic coming from behind. Fang Mouxin opened the right door. , resulting in Zhang He’s injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My husband now can’t even remember the names of his father, mother and son, nor his own name.” Zhang He’s wife told Southern Weekend reporters that Zhang He was originally the backbone of the family because The car accident resulted in a craniocerebral injury that constituted a tenth-level disability, and the treatment has not healed yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The traffic police detachment of the Songjiang Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau determined that the driver Xia Moulin bore the primary responsibility for the accident, the passenger Fang Mouxin bore the secondary responsibility, and Zhang He was not responsible. The court later ruled that the driver and passenger constituted joint infringement. Among them, the driver&#39;s compensation ratio is 70%, and the compensation is 820,000 yuan; the passenger&#39;s compensation ratio is 30%, and the compensation is 350,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The transportation department will first issue an accident liability determination document to determine the primary and secondary responsibilities of the driver and passengers. Later, the court will make a judgment based on the liability determination document during the trial.&quot; Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters , the responsibility determination letter issued by the transportation department will not clarify the responsibilities of the driver and passengers into specific proportions. As for how the final court divides the proportion of primary and secondary responsibilities, it is within the scope of the people&#39;s court to exercise discretion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the judgment of the above-mentioned case shows that Xia Moulin did not actually have insurance related to operating vehicles when using a private car, and his online ride-hailing platform Didi Chuxing Company failed to perform its due review duties. ; And as a platform, Didi and Xia Moulin share profits, bear risks, and ensure operational safety, and they are both considered as the carrier of passengers. Therefore, Didi shall bear joint and several liability with the driver Xia Moulin for the losses suffered by the injured in accordance with the law, and jointly compensate 820,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Regardless of whether the online ride-hailing car has the relevant qualifications to operate a vehicle or not, the driver taking the order is regarded as performing his duties. The driver may not be an employee of Didi, but legally, as long as he performs his work tasks , the platform has the responsibility.&quot; Dai Xianfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 16 of the &quot;Interim Measures for the Administration of Online Reservation Taxi Operations and Services&quot; stipulates: &quot;Online taxi-hailing platform companies assume the responsibility of the carrier and should ensure operational safety and protect the legitimate rights and interests of passengers.&quot; The Chinese Civil Code also states Relevant regulations require online ride-hailing platforms to assume the responsibilities of the carrier under the transportation contract between the driver and the passenger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that when facing consumers, the carrier’s responsibilities and compensation obligations originally belonging to the driver under the transportation contract may be borne by the online ride-hailing platform to a large extent. The same goes for taxi drivers and taxi companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a passenger pushes the door and causes a &quot;door kill&quot;, but the driver has fulfilled his obligation to remind him, does he still need to bear responsibility? Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Unless the passenger was intentional, the driver still needs to bear certain liability for the accident. There is a platform or insurance company behind the driver, which has a stronger compensation ability. It is the substantive fairness of the law to allow the victim to receive compensation according to the law. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But not all situations require the owner of a motor vehicle to be held responsible. Zhou Bo added to Southern Weekend reporters that if a vehicle parked on the roadside and opened its door in compliance with regulations, and a non-motor vehicle drove in the wrong direction or caused an &quot;open door kill&quot; casualty accident due to other reasons, the traffic control department may also determine that the non-motor vehicle bears major or even full responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Should insurance recognize the car or the person?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhou Bo told Southern Weekend reporters that in the case of &quot;open door killing&quot; caused by passengers, there are two main controversial links: one One is how the front-end traffic control department determines the primary and secondary responsibilities of the driver and passengers; the other is the insurance company that insures the vehicle. Should it compensate on behalf of the passengers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The most critical link is the identification of front-end responsibilities, under what circumstances passengers should bear responsibility, how to divide primary and secondary responsibilities, and under what circumstances passengers are not required to bear responsibility.” Zhou Bo told Southern Weekend reporters that the traffic control department The methods and standards for determining responsibility are currently not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, in the &quot;open door killing&quot; cases represented by Zhou Bo, the identification standards of traffic police in various places have been different, which also directly affected the final court judgment. For example, when they both open the door for a passenger, some traffic police believe that the passenger and the driver are one and the same tortfeasor; some traffic police believe that the driver should bear full responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a judgment made public in 2020 showed that after a &quot;door-opening killing&quot; accident occurred in Luocheng County, Guangxi, the &quot;Road Traffic Accident Determination&quot; issued by the local traffic police department on the accident involved determined that the passenger If you obstruct the passage of other vehicles when opening and closing the door, you will bear all the responsibility for the traffic accident. The driver is not responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Xianfeng said that under normal circumstances, the court&#39;s judgment will be consistent with the accident liability determination issued by the transportation department, unless there is other direct evidence to the contrary that is sufficient to overturn the liability determination. &quot;On the one hand, from a professional perspective, judges are no better at handling traffic accidents than traffic police; on the other hand, the probative power of evidence issued by state agencies is higher than other general evidence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the driver is responsible If the passenger is fully responsible, there will not be much controversy, because the insurance company will pay in the end. But if the passenger is held responsible, there will be controversy.&quot; Zhou Bo said that when the passenger is found responsible, the main point of dispute will become : Should the insurance company that insures the vehicle bear the liability of the passengers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked multiple judicial documents and found that when the driver and the passenger who took the initiative to open the door did not have an operating relationship, but were relatives or friends, many drivers would claim that they were fully responsible. The reason is that drivers, as car owners, have purchased compulsory traffic insurance or commercial third party insurance, and the insurance company can compensate them on their behalf. It is precisely because of this that in such &quot;open door killing&quot; cases, there are endless lawsuits between insurance companies and the infringers of the cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2019, a &quot;door-opening killing&quot; accident occurred in Fengtai District, Beijing. The car driver Zhang Mouyan was friends with the passenger Ma Mou who pushed the door open. After handling by the Fengbei Brigade of Fengtai Traffic Detachment, the car owner and passengers in this case were equally responsible for the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In court, the car advocate Mouyan argued that he failed to fulfill his obligation to remind and should bear full responsibility. Passenger Ma Moushuang also pointed out that if there is no vehicle, there is no act of getting out of the vehicle. Insurance companies should identify the insured vehicle rather than the person who caused the vehicle accident. The insurance company argued that the company was only responsible for the insured car claimant&#39;s compensation amount, that is, compensation at a rate of 50%, and did not recognize that Zhang Mouyan bore full responsibility. It said: &quot;According to the insurance law, Zhang Mouyan violated the principle of good faith and took the initiative to increase her own responsibilities, which may have resulted in excessive compensation for our company. Our company reserves the right to pursue the two of them for insurance fraud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the court ruled that the insurance company should be liable for the injured person&#39;s various losses within the scope of insurance based on the joint and several liability of the car owner and passengers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that in such &quot;open door killing&quot; cases, there were many verdicts in which insurance companies were ultimately responsible for compensation on behalf of passengers. In the aforementioned &quot;open door killing&quot; case in Luocheng County, although the court ruled that the passengers were fully responsible, the final compensation for the injured was paid by the insurance company that insured the vehicle involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Insurance companies generally defend themselves. They believe that insurance compensation is for the insured car owner. Once the driver is not the car owner, no compensation should be paid. However, this defense opinion can only be said to have a certain degree of truth, and the court often does not Adopted.&quot; Zhou Bo said that at present, the exemption clause in this aspect of the insurance contract itself is not clear, and different people will have different understandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, some online ride-hailing platforms and taxi companies require passengers to open the right door to get in and out of the car as a measure to prevent &quot;open door killing&quot;. Dai Xianfeng believes that it is necessary to strengthen the education and publicity related to &quot;opening the door to kill&quot; for students: &quot;I think that &#39;opening the door to kill&#39; should also be a key part of the training when taking the driver&#39;s license test. We will ask to look at the reflector before starting and after stopping the car. , but there is no direct training for &#39;opening the door to kill&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(Zhou Bo and Zhang He are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改革开放45周年—建言者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;45 years ago, under the guidance of Deng Xiaoping’s requirement to “turn banks into real banks”, China began a planned and Step-by-step financial system reform. Finance, the core of the modern economy, has been given an extraordinary mission in China&#39;s reform process. 45 years ago, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance separated, and China&#39;s &quot;unified&quot; financial system reform began. Although it was once trapped in the reform detour of the &quot;Five Major Contracts&quot;, it entered a &quot;big step&quot; process since 1993. 45 years later, &quot;deepening the reform of the financial system&quot; has become the action plan, and the reform and opening up of the financial market has also entered the deep water zone. Taking history as a mirror can help us understand gains and losses. To this end, we conducted in-depth interviews with the promoters, experiencers and witnesses of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up to provide suggestions for the stable and long-term development of China&#39;s financial industry.</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中华白海豚“迷路”，广州正在追踪施救]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260218]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清华国家金融研究院张伟：房贷证券化是双刃剑，目前更不宜推出丨首席访谈⑬]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260180]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The much-watched Central Financial Work Conference proposed “&lt;span>;Aiming to accelerate the construction of a financial power&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;This is the first time that the central government has proposed the goal of “financial power”. Among my country&#39;s major financial fields, the banking industry is the largest and is the main transmission system for macroeconomic control policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the banking industry is facing multiple challenges: under the counter-cyclical trend, the net interest margin of the banking industry has dropped to a historical low; at the same time, as the real estate industry enters a new stage, banks regard it as high-quality assets. The mortgage business is facing difficulties; after testing the waters of equity investment, the investment research capabilities of bank wealth management subsidiaries have also been questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China’s A-share “profit king”—can the banking industry achieve breakthroughs by leveraging financial technology? Has it reached a critical point in transformation? How do banks shape their core competitiveness? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A researcher from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center interviewed Zhang Wei, deputy director of the National Institute of Financial Research at Tsinghua University. Zhang Wei focuses on researching monetary policy and financial crisis early warning mechanisms. He also took the lead in compiling the &quot;2023 China Banking Industry Ranking Top 200 Research Report&quot; and taught more than 300 training courses for the five major state-owned banks and some joint-stock banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/zslPwg6O7gV7qMYCXPkV9k3e0LDmM0nIxuTB425I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;307&quot; height= &quot;410&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/zslPwg6O7gV7qMYCXPkV9k3e0LDmM0nIxuTB425I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Wei, deputy director of the National Institute of Financial Research at Tsinghua University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mortgage securitization&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;High risk&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our research found that housing mortgage loans in my country basically have floating interest rates. Most foreign bank mortgage loans have fixed interest rates. Why is it different? What is its background? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Most foreign mortgage interest rates are fixed interest rates, while our country’s mortgage loans have quasi-floating interest rates, that is, they are not completely floating. There is an essential difference between the two. In the past, after the central bank adjusted interest rates, existing mortgage interest rates were not adjusted immediately, and were often adjusted accordingly the following year. In other words, the central bank can adjust the interest rate multiple times within a year, but the borrower&#39;s mortgage interest rate remains basically unchanged within a year and can only start to adjust on January 1 of the following year. Therefore, it is not a fully floating interest rate but a quasi-floating interest rate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the development of the banking system, the primary purpose of various policies was to make banks grow and grow, and to reduce bank capital operation risks. The choice of a floating rate form stems from banking tradition. Fixed-rate mortgages are lower risk for the borrower but higher risk for the bank. In the past two years, some reforms have been made to mortgage interest rates. Borrowers can choose fixed interest rates or floating interest rates. However, existing housing loans still account for the majority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We also found through research that the balance of domestic housing mortgage loans is huge, but Mortgage asset securitization (MBS) has developed slowly since its inception in 2006. In the first half of 2023, there will be zero issuance of RMBS. This is also very different from the mortgage business in developed countries. Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four reasons for the slow progress of domestic mortgage asset securitization. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, mortgage asset securitization is an imported product. Mortgage securitization tools such as MBS in the United States have been developed since the 1970s. China&#39;s housing loan market developed relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, domestic mortgage asset securitization started in 2006, just as the U.S. real estate bubble began to burst. The following year, the U.S. subprime mortgage crisis triggered a chain reaction of MBS defaults and credit derivatives such as CDO and CDS, which eventually led to the 2008 global financial crisis. The external crisis requires us to re-understand the pros and cons of mortgage securitization. For regulatory agencies, a more cautious approach has been chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, mortgage asset securitization is a financial derivative. China has always been cautious about the development of financial derivatives because derivatives are highly leveraged and risky. Domestic laws on futures and derivatives were promulgated many years after the subprime mortgage crisis broke out, and did not include credit derivatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, over the past 20 years, my country’s commercial housing market has experienced a process of development and regulation of relaxation-tightening-relaxation-retightening-relaxation again. Maintain strict control over the financing of the real estate market through asset management products such as credit and trust to prevent the real estate market from overheating. Mortgage asset securitization is an important means of real estate financing and will also be strictly controlled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think it is possible to accelerate the implementation of asset securitization to activate the market? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Activating the real estate market through MBS is an option. my country&#39;s real estate credit market is an issue and hold model. If mortgage assets are securitized, banks can package the mortgages and sell them through securitization, and brokers can then distribute them to institutional investors including funds. The final investor may be an individual or a business. Mortgage risk is thus dispersed. Banks also receive more liquidity as a result. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But mortgage asset securitization is a double-edged sword. Because it has high leverage, if there is any disturbance or unfavorable situation, the impact it will have will be huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, mortgage securitization is indeed a direction. However, I believe that the risks are relatively high, the supporting systems and regulatory measures are still weak, and it should not develop too fast. Especially in the current situation where risk prevention is the keynote, it is even more unsuitable to launch. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Need to shift to intensive&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;development&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Under the counter-cyclical situation, the profits of the banking industry generally increased slightly and even the profits of individual banks dropped sharply, and the provision coverage ratio and capital adequacy ratio both declined. The 2023 interim reports of various banks revealed this group signal. However, under the current capital market conditions, refinancing on the stock market is difficult to achieve. How do you think banks can replenish core capital at this stage? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Commercial banks can replenish their first-tier core capital by issuing common shares, increasing capital from existing shareholders, or issuing additional shares. In addition, endogenous funds are also important channels. Such as retained profits, other comprehensive income and risk reserves, etc. This is to make &quot;blood&quot; by oneself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listed banks are the &quot;outstanding elements&quot; among banks. There are more than 4,000 small and medium-sized banks that cannot replenish capital through the stock market and can only increase capital through targeted capital increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks mainly issue subordinated bonds, preferred stocks and perpetual bonds to supplement secondary capital. However, the threshold for issuance of perpetual bonds and subordinated bonds is relatively high, and not all thousands of small and medium-sized banks are eligible. In addition, the issuance of special bonds by local governments is also an important means to supplement the capital of small and medium-sized banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that endogenous funds are also very important. How do most banks get rid of the predicament of becoming increasingly dependent on external financing as they develop? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the past few decades, the scale of the banking industry has expanded rapidly and interest rates have been earned. In recent years, both the return on assets and the return on capital have been declining, and companies can only &quot;win&quot; by relying on scale. Large scale, low efficiency, and rapid capital consumption. If you cannot support the rapid expansion of asset scale by relying on your own &quot;blood production&quot;, you must rely on more external financing to replenish capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To completely get rid of this predicament, banks need to conduct refined operations on existing assets and earn more profits with the same asset scale, rather than simply increasing absolute profits by increasing scale. Extensive way. The core is to shift from the current extensive development model that emphasizes scale to an intensive development model that emphasizes efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, interest rate spreads have fallen to historic lows, and the financial sustainability of bank operations is in doubt. When the current scale remains unchanged or even continues to decline, banks must find ways to be more refined and detailed, increase revenue and reduce expenditure, especially to reduce management fees and other costs. At the same time, it is necessary to improve the efficiency of fund utilization. For example, adjust the direction of loan investment, make more efforts in the financial market, and do more financial market business. In addition, efforts need to be made to improve risk control levels and reduce bad debt costs and risk losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Core competitiveness cannot be shaped through outsourcing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now digital finance has become the transformation path for banks, and it is also the only way to achieve inclusive finance. You also had similar views in the &quot;2023 China Banking Industry Ranking Top 200 Research Report&quot; published by &quot;Tsinghua Financial Review&quot;. You also believe that when financial institutions build underlying business logic in accordance with the genetic requirements of the Internet, they need to break the internal data barriers of the institution and make comprehensive adjustments to the working mechanism. In this process, banks are bound to be exposed to many risks. What do you think is the underlying business logic of banks’ Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core of bank digital transformation lies in data connectivity. At the same time, the organizational structure and top-level design must be reconstructed according to Internet thinking. There will be many challenges and risks involved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there are many obstacles in data connection. A bank is a behemoth that involves many businesses, institutions, personnel, and outlets, and the phenomenon of data islands is serious. The problem is particularly serious for large banks, where it is difficult to integrate data between head offices and branches, between various departments of the head office, and even between departments within the same department. In addition to breaking through internal data barriers and breaking down information islands, it is also necessary to achieve safe and standardized connections with external data such as government data, corporate data, alternative Internet data, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always held the view that the banks of the future will be technology companies with banking licenses. It requires data, scenarios, and technology, that is, &quot;no data, no finance&quot;, &quot;no scenario, no finance&quot;, &quot;no technology, no finance&quot;. This is a trinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, in order to open up external data, banks need to build some scenarios themselves and have the ability to continuously generate new data. Therefore, establishing the scene is particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks need to pay attention to this matter from the top-level design and reconstruct the business logic structure and organizational structure that are different from traditional banks in the past. The difficulty is that traditional genes may eat away at Internet genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the traditional business of banks is still strong - the Internet business is still &quot;Sesame&quot;, and the traditional business is still &quot;Watermelon&quot;. However, in the future, the Internet business will grow into a &quot;watermelon&quot; and the traditional business will gradually shrink into a &quot;sesame&quot;. Due to operating pressure, traditional businesses still have to pay attention. &quot;Sesame&quot; cannot become &quot;watermelon&quot; overnight. It requires a process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform must not only prevent some new businesses from being cannibalized by traditional businesses, but also prevent traditional businesses from simply being moved online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Judging from the recruitment situation this autumn, most bank IT R&amp;D positions Hiring is down. This may be related to the rise of large model technology. Some banks’ fintech strategies are shifting from building their own intelligent customer service systems to cooperating with external technology platforms. What do you think of this phenomenon? Will outsourcing financial technology business bring greater risks to banks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Outsourcing has advantages and risks, and different organizations should have different choices. Large and medium-sized banks should maintain their core technologies and avoid relying on outsourcing institutions; while small and medium-sized banks can consider outsourcing part of their business or cooperate with other platform companies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on external institutions can quickly solve the bank&#39;s current problems. In the long run, over-reliance on outsourcing institutions and platforms and loss of opportunities to develop internal skills is the biggest risk, followed by the risk of data security. The reason is that relying on outsourcing makes it difficult for banks to establish solid core technical capabilities over time. This is particularly important for large banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long run, banks, especially large banks, will still have to build their own systems. Core competitiveness cannot be shaped through outsourcing. It is a long-term solution for large banks to improve their internal capabilities. For some small banks, they can choose to outsource most of their businesses to build their core competitiveness in other aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Test the equity market&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Establish a high-level &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;investment research team&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yes Important matters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bank’s financial management subsidiary is testing the waters of equity financial management The product is 3 years old, but generally performs poorly. As of October 16, 2023, among all 34 bank equity products, 29 have broken the net. What do you think of this phenomenon? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the new regulations on asset management, the development model of bank financial management has undergone fundamental changes. The development of equity financial management products is one direction. . Compared with public funds, wealth management subsidiaries or the asset management departments of many banks are too young. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of equity products of bank wealth management subsidiaries being depleted is, on the one hand, the downward environment of the entire market, which is also the main reason. On the other hand, it is caused by the lack of management capabilities of the financial management subsidiaries themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novice, the wealth management subsidiary is inferior to the market in equity investments, but it is still tolerable at the moment. But in five to ten years, if there is no improvement, the road for equity bank financial products will only become narrower and narrower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Should financial management subsidiaries cooperate with fellow fund companies and share the latter investment research results? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the long run, building a strong investment research team is a top priority for financial management subsidiaries. It is difficult for wealth management subsidiaries to cooperate with fund companies under the parent bank because competition between the two outweighs cooperation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the incentive mechanism and salary levels of financial management subsidiaries are a major shortcoming. Subject to salary distribution constraints, the salary levels of wealth management subsidiaries of major state-owned banks are significantly lower than those of public funds. This is a great constraint on building a high-level investment research team. A breakthrough is needed in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[串标围标在工程建设等领域多发；招标方设租寻租不容忽视丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate released a number of typical cases on the official website of punishing the crime of collusive bidding in accordance with the law. The relevant person in charge of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate said that in recent years, problems in the bidding process have become prominent. In many fields such as engineering construction and equipment procurement, illegal and criminal cases such as collusion in bidding, bribery, and bribery have occurred frequently, causing hidden dangers to project quality and safety management and seriously disrupting Market Order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tendering is a procurement method used in some large-scale projects. In theory, tendering is a means to promote competition, especially public tendering. From the perspective of a tenderer, let your procurement needs reach more potential suppliers and promote competition among them as much as possible so that you can buy the best goods, services, etc. with the least money. For bidders, through public bidding channels, they can learn more about business opportunities, participate in competition, and win business through strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, national regulations stipulate that some specific projects must identify suppliers through public bidding. For example, the Government Procurement Law stipulates that government procurement projects of goods and services above a certain amount (the specific amount is uniformly stipulated by the provincial level, and many provinces set it as more than 2 million yuan) must be publicly tendered. Relevant construction law rules stipulate that if the estimated price of a single construction contract for housing construction and municipal infrastructure projects is more than 2 million yuan, or the total project investment is more than 30 million yuan, bidding must be conducted, all of which use state-owned funds or state-owned funds. Those holding a controlling or dominant position must invite public bidding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if multiple bidders or even tenderers collude with each other and collude in bidding, the bidding will become a cover to hide the public and fail to achieve the purpose of bidding. For example, in a typical case released by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate this time, there was an information technology project of a certain unit that was openly tendered to the public. Two companies colluded in the bidding. As a result, the winning bid price of the project was more than 35 million yuan, which was far higher than the actual cost. Such a result has caused serious losses to the bidding unit. In addition, collusive bidding by multiple suppliers will also affect market competition. Some bidders even bribe bid evaluation committee members to give their bids high marks in order to win the bid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some cases of bid-rigging, the tenderer may not know about it, but the bidders collude with each other to raise the price and obtain more benefits. However, there are also many cases of bid-rigging. The staff of the bidding unit are not only informed, but they may even actively collude with the bidders to raise the price, or give the project to a designated bidder to benefit themselves. As for other companies participating in the bidding, they only &quot;accompany the bidding&quot; to meet the requirement of multiple suppliers participating in the bidding. In fact, the contents of their bid documents are worse than those of the designated bidders, and it is impossible to win the bid. They appear just to cooperate in acting and get a little &quot;accompanying the bid fee.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is undoubtedly rent-seeking, bribery and bribery. If the bidding unit is a state-owned enterprise or even a government agency or public institution, it will be suspected of bribery by public officials. Even if the bidding unit is a private enterprise, collusion in bidding will also constitute crimes such as job embezzlement and bribery of non-state personnel. The bidder paid bribes. The corruption behind this rent-seeking is quite astonishing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Zhejiang Daily&quot; once reported that Zhu Zhixiang, the former chairman of Shaoxing Urban Investment Group, as the main person in charge of the bidding unit, colluded with others and the bidders during the bidding process of relevant projects. , the total winning bid amount of the bidders reached more than 4.42 billion yuan. In April 2023, Zhu Zhixiang was sentenced to eleven years and six months in the first instance for bribery and bid collusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in some fields, bid-rigging and collusion have formed a complete industrial chain. Some practitioners do not have relevant qualifications themselves, so they &quot;affiliate&quot; with qualified units. The affiliated units charge a &quot;management fee&quot; that is a certain percentage of the winning bid amount and share the profits from the winning bid. There are also professional scalpers and engineering brokers who specialize in bid-rigging. They have great powers, and some may be related to the tendering party, and some can even obtain the contact information of bid evaluation experts in time and bribe them. There are also &quot;hackers&quot; who can invade the bid evaluation expert database and provide them with expert lists and contact information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang police once uncovered a company with only nine employees and no construction team, but it repeatedly won bids for large engineering projects. In just two years, it participated in a total of 338 bids for engineering projects. The investigation found that this is a professional bid-rigging gang. After winning the bid, they illegally sell the project and profit from it. These engineering projects are stripped down and subcontracted at many levels. Not only will the project cost increase, but the quality of the project will also be difficult to guarantee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, according to the latest criminal prosecution standards formulated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security in 2022, collusion in bidding, the winning amount of the bid is more than 4 million yuan, the illegal income is more than 200,000 yuan, or threats, deception, bribery By using other means, colluding in bidding multiple times, etc., they are all suspected of committing the crime of colluding in bidding, and a case should be filed and prosecuted. In particular, we must severely crack down on rent-seeking and corruption involving insiders of the tendering party to maintain a fair market order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[允许博士生分流转为硕士，你支持吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260095]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[平均降价58%！南周记者直击第九批国家药品集采现场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>