<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“制造业当家关键在于人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259951]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2008, Hu Xiaoyan was elected as the first batch of migrant workers to the National People&#39;s Congress. (Interviewee/ Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1051&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In 2008, Hu Xiaoyan was elected as the first batch of migrant workers to the National People&#39;s Congress. (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It took me three days and three nights to get to Foshan, changing trains and buses all the way. So, I My first impression of Guangdong was probably the feeling of motion sickness.&quot; It was the late autumn of 1998. Hu Xiaoyan was 24 years old. In order to pay off the foreign debt of more than 20,000 yuan owed by her family, she decided to leave her hometown of Guang&#39;an, Sichuan and embark on the furthest journey in her life. A trip - to work in Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;35 years later, Hu Xiaoyan is already the full-time vice chairman of Foshan Sanshui District Federation of Industry and Commerce. On October 25, 2023, at the third &quot;Storytelling Meeting on the 45th Anniversary of Reform and Opening Up&quot;, she recalled the years when she first arrived in Guangdong to work hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In ten years, Hu Xiaoyan rose from a female assembly line worker in an electronics factory to the management of a ceramic production workshop, and was selected as one of the &quot;Top Ten Migrant Workers in Foshan&quot;. In 2008, for the first time, three representatives of the migrant workers group participated in the National Two Sessions, including Hu Xiaoyan from Guangdong, a major labor import province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the reform and opening up, the &quot;tide of migrant workers&quot; has promoted China&#39;s industrialization and urbanization process. Guangdong is a major labor importer. In 1988 alone, the number of laborers from other provinces who came to work reached about 3 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The event was hosted by the Information Office of the Guangdong Provincial Government. In addition to Hu Xiaoyan, Shang Xiaodong, a second-level researcher at the South China Sea Institute of Oceanography, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and a mechanical technician from Guangdong Province were also invited College teacher Yang Denghui tells his story. The three people are from different generations and backgrounds, but what they have in common is that they are all foreign talents from Guangdong. Shang Xiaodong was admitted to Taiyuan Institute of Technology (now Taiyuan University of Technology) after the resumption of the college entrance examination. He entered graduate school at the age of 32. In 2005, he came to Guangdong to research physical ocean research. Yang Denghui, who was born in 1997, is the champion of the CNC milling project of the World Skills Competition. He studied at the Guangdong Mechanical Technician College and was elected as a representative of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 26, 2023, workers at an agricultural science and technology enterprise in Yunfu City were cultivating flower seedlings. With the help of the local rural revitalization talent station, the company solved the problem of industrial talents, Technology shortage problem. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256983&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 26, 2023, workers at an agricultural technology enterprise in Yunfu City were cultivating flower seedlings. With the help of the local rural revitalization talent station, the company solved the problem of shortage of industrial talents and technology. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The first batch of migrant workers&#39; representatives&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As the spokesperson of more than 200 million migrant workers, I participated in the 5 During the National Two Sessions, a total of 20 suggestions were put forward, and each suggestion was ultimately implemented for migrant workers.&quot; Hu Xiaoyan mentioned that since the reform and opening up, the system for protecting the rights and interests of migrant workers has been changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Migrant workers are a group born with the reform and opening up. &quot;Household production quota&quot; liberated rural surplus labor from the land, and a large number of rural people poured into cities in search of opportunities. This trend continues today. According to the National Bureau of Statistics, the number of migrant workers was 78.49 million at the beginning of the century, and the total number in 2022 exceeded 295 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangdong occupies three of the four major special economic zones identified in 1979, which has created a huge demand for labor. Hu Xiaoyan thus joined the ranks heading south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The emergence of migrant workers has also highlighted the problem of migrant workers. In 2006, relevant documents from the State Council mentioned that there were problems such as low wages and arrears for migrant workers, and many occupational diseases and work-related injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2008, Yang Chengyong, deputy director of the Election Committee of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress, revealed to the media that Guangdong, as the province with the largest influx of migrant population, planned to elect After six migrant workers were elected as representatives to the Provincial People&#39;s Congress, one migrant worker was elected as a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before that, Guangdong had been at the forefront in protecting the political rights of migrant workers. In 2000, four outsiders were elected during the general election of the Shenzhen Municipal People’s Congress. Representatives of migrant workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, Hu Xiaoyan became the first batch of migrant workers to be a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress, but before that, she had never served as a deputy to any people&#39;s congress at the township, county, city, or province levels. Hu Xiaoyan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;I don&#39;t find it difficult because I already live among them (migrant workers).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Xiaoyan mentioned To: &quot;The first batch of migrant workers to represent the National People&#39;s Congress became the most eye-catching label on me. From then on, I began to learn how to conduct research, write suggestions, speak, and learn how to perform my duties.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After becoming a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress, she used her vacation time to visit workers and put forward suggestions including criminalizing unpaid wages, connecting with medical insurance, off-site college entrance examinations, and housing benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At almost the same time, national policies also shifted to consider the new needs generated by migrant workers entering cities. Hu Xiaoyan once suggested “allowing the children of migrant workers to take the college entrance examination in the workplace.” At the end of 2013, Guangdong Province officially announced the implementation measures for the college entrance examination for migrant children in other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, more &quot;Hu Xiaoyans&quot; have become deputies to the National People&#39;s Congress. Among the deputies to the 14th National People&#39;s Congress, there are 56 migrant workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 26, 2023, students are practicing industrial robot operation at the Technician College in Zhaoqing, Guangdong. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;October 2023 On the 26th, students were practicing the operation of industrial robots at the Technician College in Zhaoqing, Guangdong. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Scientists and Craftsmen&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shang Xiaodong, a 32-year-old graduate student, said that he and Hu Xiaoyan &quot; “Have the same starting point” as shop workers. It&#39;s just that it&#39;s much older. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The turning point occurred in 1978. Shang Xiaodong heard that his high school classmates were admitted to college, and he began to prepare for the exam. In the second year, he relied on self-study and was admitted to the physics teaching class of the Department of Physics Basics of Taiyuan Institute of Technology. After graduation, he was assigned to serve as a teacher at the Command College of the Chinese People&#39;s Armed Police Force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than ten years later, he keenly discovered that there were more masters around him, and he felt that &quot;if you don&#39;t study, you will fall behind.&quot; After completing his postgraduate studies in the Department of Mechanics of Tianjin University, he went to Hong Kong, China and the United States for further studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2005, Shang Xiaodong came to Guangdong and entered the South China Sea Institute of Oceanography, Chinese Academy of Sciences. Previously, Guangdong had just issued the “Decision on Accelerating the Construction of a Strong Science and Technology Province.” &quot;There is a good scientific research atmosphere here, and there is a passion for pioneering and bold attempts. This is why our family chose to take root in Guangdong.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Just returned to China At that time, ocean observation instruments had long been monopolized by foreign countries, so Shang Xiaodong decided to lead his team to independently develop ocean observation instruments. In the end, the team developed the &quot;fast temperature sensor for ocean detection&quot; with the fastest response in the world, with a response time of 7 milliseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the policy of &quot;strengthening the province through science and technology&quot;, Guangdong also hopes to solve the problem of &quot;two skins&quot; between technology and economy. Empowering new manufacturing industries with new technologies focuses on the integration of technological innovation and industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Denghui said that after enrolling in a technician college in 2014, he &quot;competed with things thinner than a hair every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Denghui, who was born as a technician, saw the new demand for talents behind the &quot;manufacturing industry&quot;. “The key to success in the manufacturing industry lies in people.” He believes that in addition to scientific research talents like Shang Xiaodong, it also needs a large number of highly skilled talents to support it. This is an important reason why he chose to stay in Guangdong Mechanical Technician College to teach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After entering the school, Yang Denghui was selected into the training team preparing for the 43rd World Skills Competition. The training project was CNC milling, which is an automatic processing technology that uses computers. Drawing and programming realize part machining. At that time, China had not won a gold medal in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you want to achieve success in CNC milling projects, you must practice &quot;knife skills&quot;: choose appropriate tools according to different materials and production requirements of the parts, and strictly control them The accuracy of parts and components is controlled within 0.02 mm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2017, Yang Denghui, who started his career again, won the CNC milling championship at the 44th World Skills Competition. He was only 20 years old that year. After graduation, he joined the technical education team, and the students he guided won the world championship gold medal in this project again in 2019 and 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data from the Guangdong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security show that currently, the total number of skilled talents in Guangdong is 18.5 million, including 6.31 million highly skilled talents. Talents account for 34.1%. In 2023, Yang Denghui will also become a representative of the National People&#39;s Congress, and naturally he will focus on the cultivation of skilled talents in performing his duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;(Hope) to help skilled employees break through the &#39;ceiling&#39; for promotion, so that more talents can make a difference in Guangdong.&quot; Yang Denghui expressed at the event His vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违法转运火化遗体，蓄意瞒报4死4伤事故，36人被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:36:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 13:29 on April 2, 2023, Jikun, Jiangyuan District, Baishan City, Jilin Province Mining Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jikun Coal Mine&lt;/span>;) +290m east of Shimen South Wing, a large gas explosion accident occurred on the second floor of the fourth uphill coal mining face, causing 4 deaths and 4 injuries (another 4 people Physical discomfort, recovered after receiving oxygen), direct economic loss of 10.16 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, Jikun Coal Mine failed to report the accident as required, illegally transshipping and cremating the remains of the victims, and sealing off the accident site to conceal the accident. After receiving reports from the masses, when the Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau and the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau went to the coal mine to verify the reported cases from April 3 to 12, 2023, the mine still failed to report truthfully. On April 13th and 14th, four people including the mine investor and mine manager surrendered under pressure. The accident was verified to be true by the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Jilin Bureau of the National Mine Safety Supervision Bureau released the accident investigation report. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How the accident occurred&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the day shift on April 2, 2023, mine manager Li Yonghai organized a pre-shift work meeting. Li Yanping, deputy director of production, Lu Wanping, chief engineer, and Li Shichen, technical consultant, assigned production tasks to each team. After the meeting, Yang Licheng, captain of the third mining team, assigned production tasks for the shift to Wang Hongchang, the squad leader of the accident squad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hongchang’s team has 13 people on duty and 1 tile inspector. Wang Hongchang arranged for Leng Jun, Ji Yaomin, Zhang Chengxue and Zhang Qinglong to set off cannons and produce coal at Sanshang Mountain. He, Wang Junfu and Sun Cheng set off cannons and produce coal at Sishang Mountain, Li Junsheng and Guo Wensheng built wood stacks for reinforcement at Wushang Mountain, and Yang Lianpeng and Gao Cai installed equipment in the main alley. Cars, Huang Fujun and Zhang Yongsheng are responsible for pulling coal. Lu Xiang is responsible for checking the gas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers entered the well from the abandoned heating tunnel at about 8:00, and picked up their own miner&#39;s lamps from the &quot;Miner&#39;s Lamp Supermarket&quot; there. They did not carry personnel identification cards and self-rescuers, and arrived at their respective operations at about 8:15. Place. At around 10 o&#39;clock, in order to solve the ventilation problem at the Wushangshan working face, the ventilation team leader Guan Yanlin led three workers to move the local ventilator between Sishangshan and Wushangshan at +290m East Shimen back 20 meters and move it away from the wind The bifurcation of the cylinder connects the air duct to Wushangshan. This local ventilator supplies air to the three working surfaces of Sanshangshan, Sishangshan and Wushangshan at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 13:30, Ji Yaomin and others who were working on Sanshang Mountain suddenly saw a puff of black smoke and the wind stopped. They felt difficulty breathing and could not see anything. Zhang Qinglong and Zhang Chengxue took the lead to escape. Ji Yaomin and Leng Jun took the tools and then ran outside. When they ran to Sanshang Pass, they found that there was wind in the alleyway. At this time, Zhang Qinglong and Zhang Chengxue were lying on the ground and lost consciousness. They immediately performed cardiopulmonary resuscitation and rescued them. About 5 minutes later, The two woke up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, Liu Tiezhu, the project manager who was walking to the entrance of the central water pump room at +290m, felt a large fluctuation in the wind flow, and saw a lot of dust in the wind flow in the direction of Dongyi Shimen, so he went After checking, they saw the injured Lu Xiang, Gao Cai and Guo Wensheng respectively (Gao Cai and Guo Wensheng were seriously burned), and heard Leng Jun&#39;s voice at Mikami Pass, and then returned and took Lu Xiang to the +290m water pump room, and Call the dispatch office to report the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Accident rescue process&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After receiving the accident report, dispatcher Meng Fanjun reported the accident to mine director Li Yonghai. Yonghai immediately reported the situation to mine investor Wang Haoming and legal representative Cong Peifu, and arranged for Li Tao and Huo Jianguo to organize personnel to go down the mine to carry out rescue. Rescuers met survivors such as Lu Xiang, Zhang Chengxue, Ji Yaomin, Guo Wensheng, Huang Fujun and Zhang Yong, and sent people to escort them to the well. At the same time, a person (Yang Lianpeng) was found buried in coal at the fan switch, with only one leg exposed. He was confirmed dead at the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rescuers found a fall at the Sishang Pass. They checked that the carbon monoxide concentration on the inside of the Sishang Pass was 999ppm (portable multi-function detector range 0~999ppm), the gas concentration was 0.1%, and the oxygen concentration was 5%. All people on the mountain were believed to have died, and the search for rescuers continued. When we reached the Sanshang Pass, coal fell and blocked the roadway. We found 4 people calling for help in Sanshang Mountain. We immediately cleared the coal and entered Sanshang Mountain to rescue the seriously injured Gao Cai and Li Junsheng. Then we lifted out Zhang Qinglong, who could not stand on his right leg, and finally Rescue Leng Jun and escort him to the surface. At 18:10, all survivors had reached the ground and were sent to hospitals for treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 18:40, rescue workers began to clear the pile of coal where Yang Lianpeng died, and pulled out the body and transported it to the ground. Then the carbon monoxide was discharged section by section up the mountain. When the discharge reached 13 meters from the mountain pass, the deceased Wang Hongchang was found. The gas continued to be discharged, and the victims Wang Junfu and Sun Cheng were found about 1 meter below the shelter. So far, all the bodies of the victims have been found and transported to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Direct reasons&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;+290m East Shimensi Mountain is connected to the +355m goaf area, and gas surges in the goaf area out; a local ventilator was used to supply air to three working locations at the same time. The air volume was insufficient, causing gas accumulation, and the workers fired cannons in violation of regulations, leading to accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;The accident concealment process&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the accident, Wang Haoming, the investor and actual controller of Jikun Coal Mine, arranged for the mine manager Li Yonghai organized the rescue on his own without reporting to the emergency department; arranged for Wang Zhenshan and Wang Weidong to treat the injured and the aftermath of the deceased; arranged for Cong Peifu to assist the mine manager in handling the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Weidong sent four seriously injured people to the Hunjiang District Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital, and then transferred them to the First Affiliated Hospital of Jilin University in Changchun City. Four workers who felt unwell were sent to Tonghua City Hospital for inhalation. Oxygen therapy. Wang Zhenshan sent the four victims to the Jiangyuan District Cemetery Funeral Home, Jiangyuan District Ni Tai Hospital, Sanchazi Forestry Bureau Hospital Morgue, and Textile Factory Funeral Home, and reached a compensation agreement with the families of the victims. Subsequently, he purchased two &quot;Resident Death Medical Certificates (Inference)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Death Certificates&quot;) from Wang Yonghai, director of the textile factory funeral home, for 50,000 yuan each, resulting in the illegal disposal of the remains of the two deceased persons. At the same time, Wang Zhenshan arranged for personnel to delete video surveillance data related to the accident on the afternoon of April 5, deliberately concealing the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 2:00 on April 3, after the on-site rescue work was completed, Li Yonghai arranged for Guan Yanlin to lead the ventilation team members into the well, and at the original sealed position of +290m East Shimen and +355m return air alley. Construct a &quot;quick seal&quot; to seal the accident scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concealing the verification process&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 23:00 on April 2, Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau, Jilin Provincial Emergency Management Department, and Provincial Party Committee Inspection Team have successively received reports about the Jikun Coal Mine accident. report. On April 3, the Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau took the lead in setting up a joint verification team with the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau to verify the reported cases, inspected the safety monitoring system, personnel location monitoring system and video surveillance system, and conducted a review of the April 2 incident. During the day shift, 52 people working in the well were questioned and collected evidence. As of April 13, the inspection team found no signs of a gas accident in Jikun Coal Mine, and evidence collection from those who entered the mine on duty showed that no accident occurred in Jikun Coal Mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of April 13, in accordance with the spirit of the Baishan Municipal Party Committee meeting on April 12, the relevant leaders of the Baishan City and Jiangyuan District governments took the lead and organized the Public Security Bureau, Emergency Management Bureau and other departments to establish a joint verification team. , conduct in-depth verification of reported matters. At 18:00 on April 13, Jikun Coal Mine Director Li Yonghai, legal representative Cong Peifu, and Deputy Mine Safety Manager Li Tao surrendered to the Jiangyuan District Public Security Bureau with the consent of investor Wang Haoming under pressure from the investigation, admitting that gas occurred underground in Jikun Coal Mine. The accident resulted in 4 deaths and 4 injuries. On April 14, investor Wang Haoming surrendered to the Jiangyuan District Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation and verification, the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government Office&#39;s &quot;Explanation on the &quot;4·2&quot; Gas Accident of Jikun Mining Co., Ltd., Jiangyuan District, Baishan City&quot; confirmed: at about 14:00 on April 2, 2023 , a gas accident occurred in Jikun Coal Mine, resulting in 4 deaths and 4 injuries. After on-site inspection by the mine rescue team of Tonghua Mining Group Company, the hidden area was sealed and comprehensively searched, and no other casualties were found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;36 people were held accountable: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident investigation report put forward accountability and handling suggestions for 36 relevant responsible personnel. . Among them, 12 people were recommended to be transferred to judicial authorities for processing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 people including the manager of Jikun Coal Mine, legal representative, investor (actual controller), chief engineer, and the outpatient department of Jiangyuan District Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital A total of 12 suspected criminals, including the director and the director of the Jiangyuan District Textile Factory Funeral Home, were transferred to the judicial authorities for investigation and investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Eight people were recommended to be given administrative penalties: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jikun Coal Mine Project Department Manager, Deputy Manager, and Deputy Safety General Manager Eight people including the engineer, deputy chief engineer of mechanical and electrical engineering and director of the dispatching office were respectively imposed administrative penalties and had their professional qualifications revoked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;15 people were recommended to be held accountable for party and government discipline: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment contracts of three mine safety supervisors were terminated and Ordered not to engage in coal mine safety production work within the administrative area of ​​Jilin Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director of the Wangou Town Safety Supervision Branch of the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau was given a one-year party probation and was removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the second office of the Coal Supervision Section of the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau was given a serious demerit penalty and removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Criticize and educate the executive deputy director of Jiangyuan District People’s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the deputy director in charge and captain of the law enforcement detachment of Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau, the former party secretary and director and deputy director in charge of Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau, the party committee secretary, town mayor and deputy town mayor of Wangou Town and Nine public officials, including the president and vice president of Jiangyuan District Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, were given party disciplinary and government sanctions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Jikun Coal Mine was fined and closed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 5 million was fined for concealing the occurrence of a major accident in Jikun Coal Mine and concealing the report. A fine of RMB 10,000 was included in the joint punishment targets;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jikun Coal Mine did not obtain a safety production license and illegally produced coal outside the scope of technical transformation design. It was an illegal coal mine and its illegal gains and mined coal and mining were confiscated. equipment, and be fined and requested to the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government to close it down in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海，他们进行了一场现实主义“万梗节”狂欢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259893]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 31, 2023, on Julu Road, Shanghai, cosplaying with White Snake and Fa Hai young people. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, on Julu Road in Shanghai, a young man cosplayed White Snake and Fa Hai. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Halloween has passed, but the &quot;Ten Thousand Stem Festival&quot; has not. This large-scale carnival still has lingering warmth in the metropolis of Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 1st every year is the traditional Western festival of Halloween. The most lively moment is on Halloween, when children dress up as various cute ghosts, knock on doors and do trick-or-treating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Halloween in Shanghai in 2023 comes earlier. Starting from October 28, the city switches to the magical side. Major theme parks and some Internet celebrity bars will hold Halloween activities, as well as spontaneous street parties. Monsters and monsters of different shapes appeared on the street. What is unexpected is that Internet memes with a strong Chinese style have suddenly emerged and become popular all over the Internet. They are dubbed as a new trend of &quot;Renaissance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the lanterns come on, an ordinary old street can turn into a movable feast. It will be a fairy tale world where you can cosplay various characters and experience another identity; it can be a channel to release stress and express yourself; it can also be a traffic pool full of temptations. The cosplayers in the pool are eye-catching enough, and there are precedents for Xiti’s hot search lists on major platforms, which means that traffic and money will have the opportunity to be included in the bag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters interviewed more than a dozen &quot;crazy citizens&quot;. According to them, Shanghai has not been this lively for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, the Julu Road area was crowded with people. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /03/66c8c013f9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/66c8c013f9.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, the Julu Road area was crowded with people. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Pure happiness&quot; on Julu Road&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After leaving the subway station, the flow of people under the bright yellow lights was surging in one direction. Even without navigation, you can determine the general direction of Julu Road. The closer you get there, the denser the crowds will be. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The location with the strongest Halloween atmosphere is Julu Road in Huangpu District, Shanghai. This is a commercial street named after the giant cruise ship &quot;Julu&quot; of the French Post Line. There are many exotic and Western-style shops. Historical buildings spread across this prosperous area. The most iconic one is the Sunken Plaza at No. 158 Julu Road, which has always been the most popular place to visit on Halloween. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31st, the night in Shanghai was getting darker and the carnival began. There is Tathagata Buddha riding a shared bicycle inadvertently passing by, exuding golden light; there is a zombie bride and the fire ghost king who are all dressed in red; there is also Lu Xun in a long robe, lamenting that studying medicine cannot save the Chinese people ; Pretending to be a potted plant, acting out a famous painting, or even raising a middle finger in a headband can create a bizarre landscape... The journey from Julu Road to Fuxing Park, less than 1 kilometer away, is packed with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of crowding made police nervous. The entrance to Julu Road has been blocked by police with iron railings, and blue and red police lights are flashing everywhere. While maintaining order, the traffic police repeatedly emphasized: &quot;I am not a cosplayer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the fence could not stop the enthusiastic flow of people. They took a shortcut from the nearby green slope about ten meters and sneaked into Julu road. Southern Weekend reporters followed the flow of people up the slope. Looking from above, Julu Road looked like a colorful light strip. The crowds of people almost filled the entire space on the road and flowed slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The adjacent Chengdu South Road disperses some of the flow of people overflowing from Julu Road. Relatively speaking, this place is a lot ordinary. There are two or three-story private houses on both sides of the road, full of clothing stores, leather bag stalls, taverns and fly restaurants. A restaurant owner sitting on the street is surrounded by a crowd of people. &quot;Normally there are not many people here.&quot; Here, from last Saturday until now, there are many people in the store.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you take a few steps, you will see large and small black and white impermanences. They hold long red tongues. On their black and white high hats are written &quot;Peace in the world&quot; and &quot;Wealth at first sight&quot;. , including many children wearing thick black eye shadow and looking cute. At the corner, I met the White Snake and Fahai living in harmony. The masked men from the popular Korean drama &quot;Squid Game&quot; stood in a row against the wall and obediently cooperated with tourists to take photos. It had nothing to do with horror. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching people at the scene were the boys cosplaying Batman. They were tall and tall, with black masks covering their eyes, clear mandibles and indifferent expressions. From time to time, girls around him would scream, &quot;So handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Batmans have been touring twice, always causing commotion at the scene. Their trump card is to take off their tight tops and expose their porcelain chest muscles if they disagree. Circle after circle of people gathered around to cheer. The tourists on the outside couldn&#39;t see it. They just stood on tiptoe and pointed their raised mobile phones towards the center to take pictures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within only three seconds, the Batmans were pushed out of the crowd by the police, and there was a burst of laughter from the crowd. This is a routine operation to maintain order on Halloween. People and &quot;ghosts&quot; causing congestion will be taken away by the police and moved to another place to ease the flow of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Batman Strong Man. Photographed by Li Zixuan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256938 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Batman hunk. Photo by Li Zixuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A God of Wealth holding a gold ingot was undoubtedly respected. There was a long queue of tourists taking photos. Some people clasped their hands and bowed their heads in worship to the God of Wealth, begging her to bless them with good fortune. For about half an hour, the God of Wealth was blocked and did not move a step. The gold ingot was touched here and there. Every time he wanted to leave, he was pulled back by the person who took the photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faces of the elderly also appeared in the crowd, and they were also very busy. Maybe it’s because “I can’t understand it, but I’m very shocked.” An elderly man sighed, “We also get to know the things of young people. It’s lively, fun, and fresh.”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &quot;Don&#39;t you think this is a release? A release of stress.&quot; Another Shanghai uncle talked to a Southern Weekend reporter. He had been standing on the roadside for two hours, observing and feeling the carnival atmosphere. My uncle is from Shanghai, but he has never seen such an atmosphere. &quot;I am very happy to see such an atmosphere. I think everyone is also happy from the bottom of their hearts. This is not a festival. Everyone is just using the festival as an excuse to be happy.&quot; , pure joy.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Go crazy together and release stress”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A novel scene appeared at the subway entrance near Julu Road. Many people gathered together to exchange professional opinions. So much so that the subway entrance was blocked again. Some said they were studying law, some were studying civil engineering, and some were studying architecture. Everyone complained that it was difficult to get along in the corresponding industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What resonated strongly was the boy Xiao Xie who was surrounded. He looked haggard and had pale lips. The card hanging on his chest had four big words written on it: Studying Architecture. He was also carrying a bag with two wads of toilet paper. take-out box, looking impoverished. &quot;It is true that this industry is not very prosperous, and my work is not going well, so I take this opportunity to go crazy together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone is going crazy, and I want to go crazy too. It feels so good, and I put all my inner thoughts into it.&quot; Release the pressure.&quot; Xiao Xie just did a bold thing and resigned naked in October 2023. It was a period of work where &quot;I couldn&#39;t move even if I wanted to curl up, but I didn&#39;t dare to lie down&quot;. Everyone didn&#39;t dare to leave their seats after get off work, and they were chased by their leaders to make work demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The migrant worker who is even more out of the circle is Li Qiubai, the actor of Party B who wanders the same street. His makeup was rough and exaggerated. The dark eyeshadow and highlighter applied on his face made it look like his cheekbones were protruding and his cheeks were sunken. He had an A4 paper with &quot;Party B&quot; written on it in the collar of his checkered shirt, clearly showing a person who had been squeezed by Party A for a long time. haggard beat worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Party B coser. Photo provided by interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1194&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256939 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Party B cosplayer. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I cosplayed a character who had just finished his shift, and I didn’t expect the effect to be so good.” Li Qiubai had indeed just finished his shift, and it was already late at night when he arrived at Julu Road, so he decided to perform a Party B, who was tired, was constantly surrounded by people taking photos. The number of views on his social account has &quot;exploded&quot;, and many netizens have left messages expressing sympathy. &quot;Some people read the jokes, and some people look in the mirror. There are many comments like this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe it&#39;s because after the epidemic, there is no such activity that everyone can enjoy. Although the previous festivals were holidays, various tickets were not available.&quot; Li Qiubai said that now it has reached a In a festival where everyone can go crazy, I have an outlet to vent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, Li Qiubai also encountered many poor people who did not need to dress up, as well as the resentful Party A. Some people held up signs: &quot;People who usually have a hard time pretending to be themselves don&#39;t need to dress up for Halloween.&quot; It&#39;s OK.&quot; Li Qiubai summed up this type of cosplay as: using realistic expression techniques to present the things that workers fear most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31st, many cosplayers said they came over right after get off work. A King Zhou finished putting on a solemn dramatic face in his company, and walked around the streets to find two strangers, Daji, to form a CP; a 28-year-old young man drove here from Jiaxing City, Zhejiang Province, and she cosplayed Hayao Miyazaki&#39;s classic animated character, the Faceless Man, stood hunched silently on the roadside, with more than a hundred people gathered around to take a group photo. Because she had to go to work the next day, she returned to Jiaxing overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Gongzi chose to release herself in another way. She played the role of SpongeBob SquarePants, who is also 37 years old. On weekdays, she is engaged in the company&#39;s business work, talking about cost-effectiveness and the company&#39;s maximum benefits. But before Halloween comes, the homemade yellow felt board square shell makes her purely the embodiment of happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Mr. Wang cosplayed Spongebob Squarepants into Happy Valley, he immediately became the center of attention and was even mistaken by tourists for being a professional staff member of the park. A crowd of chirping children followed her, stuffing her with candies and throwing out a hundred thousand whys: Did Mr. Krabs give you a day off? Why don&#39;t you bring Xiaowei to play with you? What’s the secret ingredient to the Krusty Krab? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, Mr. Wang said, the whole group went crazy. Di Dixi, a colleague cosplaying as a Haidilao waiter, was originally a typical i person (referring to an introvert). In this atmosphere, she was directly reshaped into an e person (referring to an extrovert). She would take the initiative to get in front of some tourists. There is no real thing to do in the crazy performance, just twisting the hands in the air, but it is self-intoxicating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, Di Dixi also interviewed &quot;Li Jiaqi&quot; who sells eyebrow pencils for 79 yuan in cos. The other person replied in a long voice, &quot;Why is it so expensive? It&#39;s always the same price. It&#39;s really annoying.&quot; Dixi burst into laughter on the spot. Later, this video unexpectedly went viral. Prince Wang and his friends were all shocked. Is the Sheniu girl in front of them the same Didixi who dared not speak in front of others and pretended to be immersed in looking at her mobile phone? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She became more aggressive after she woke up the next day. Looking back, she felt so embarrassed and a little bit ashamed.&quot; Didisi&#39;s friend recalled to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within a few days, Didixi led her two friends who were smarter than herself and headed towards Julu Road. She put on heavy makeup and went back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;There are people on the street who cosplay and learn computers. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are people on the street who are cosplaying and learning computers. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Take advantage of the popularity to become a fan”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Yanzhi is on the hot search again. In 2022, he was dressed like An Lingrong and danced on roller skates, which made him a hot search. After all, &quot;The Legend of Zhen Huan&quot; is the &quot;electronic mustard&quot; for all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sea of ​​folk joy, Halloween has also become a traffic carnival, with many video teams wandering around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“She is so hot.” ​​A Ying, who cosplayed An Lingrong’s Maid, was a little proud. She told Southern Weekend reporters that after deciding to perform the scene of “An Lingrong singing on the bow”, several commercials A team of people made careful planning and posted a &quot;thaw&quot; trailer on the short video platform, implying An Lingrong&#39;s return. They also made a video invitation with a route plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们找的是货拉拉把道具船拖过去，刚从货拉拉下来，就有好多人喊安陵容。”10月28日晚，安陵容坐着船一出场，就被人流包围，直接分走了附近其他coser的流量。他们戴上廉价的假发，穿着与剧中一模一样的服装，船头的安陵容手持莲花，蓝牙音响里播放音乐《江南可采莲》，众人跟着合唱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时团队拍摄的短视频，点赞量飙升到数万。到了第二次在复兴公园出场时，现场直播有上千人观看。 “蛮好玩的，大家不约而同有非常多的创意，终于看到上海人民的松弛感了。”阿莹说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前安陵容妆造的出圈，也启发到了杭州男孩醒醒。在这次万圣节中，他以cos向太的形象火出了圈。在其传播最广的一段视频中，醒醒穿着团队临时花了400元买来的粉红色大衣，一脸富贵相。有人问他怎么看待向太儿媳郭碧婷，他微微一笑：模仿道：“挺好操控的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，向太本人隔空回应：“衣服太low了，他应该模仿得更漂亮点。”这让醒醒团队受了惊，原本大家调侃，万圣节cos明星的阵仗，足以收到全网明星律师函，但火到这种程度，还是让人猝不及防。 “我们其实是有点害怕的，怕万一向佐团队找过来说我们有什么问题，但他们最后只说互动一下，那就去互动了。”醒醒团队工作人员阿眯对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿眯介绍，醒醒本职是一名自媒体美妆博主，向太妆造火后，有不少合作商家找上门，“非常多人私信我们谈合作，要醒醒去扮向太互动，我们拒绝了，挺怕被骂的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人忐忑，有人欢喜。当看到向太和安陵容在网上爆火后，那英的扮演者这英也动了心。 “那我必须去呀。”11月1日，她在南方周末记者采访的电话那头模仿那英的口吻。此前，她买来《妻子的秘密》剧中黎明朗的衣服，最低配版的墨镜、发夹和话筒，连去巨鹿路三晚，模仿那英不断输出“那言那语”，“我一张嘴，他们就嗷嗷叫唤”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;效果立竿见影。这英版的那英，走到哪里都自带流量，即使是戴上口罩，摘掉眼镜，换上朋友的衣服，还是会被人认出来，狠狠体验了一把明星被追的待遇。 “他们以为我是真的那英，所有人尖叫，说太像了，喊&#39;那姐，别跑&#39;，&#39;那姐，给我拍照&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我去之前我就知道会出圈，只是不确定会出圈到什么程度。”三天下来，这英的抖音粉丝涨了近十万，她紧紧抓住流量密码，“万圣节当晚回到家后，我还开了一场直播，希望可以趁着热度涨点粉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在10月31日现场狂欢中，一声嘶吼突然让噪杂的人群顿了一下。 “还让不让人过了？”一个陷在人流里的外卖小哥发了火，他的车轮此刻寸步难行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但很快气氛就恢复了，这样的场景并不陌生，时不时就有外卖员在沸腾的人群里嚷嚷：“让一让，超时了，超时了。”在这场分不清楚真真假假的狂欢活动中，很难不让人怀疑，他们是在cos外卖小哥。在采访期间，也有人向南方周末记者投来疑惑的眼神，问“你是在cos记者吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到临近午夜时分，巨鹿路的人流逐渐淡了下来。跨过这个夜晚，上海又将回归大都市节奏紧张的一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（文中受访者姓名均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[划着轮椅，出门去]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259854]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvVquGUPdTNq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvVquGUPdTNq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;田野在他的串串店图/网商银行公益小店联盟提供&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海是蓝蓝的，一眼望不到边。向外是沙滩，长满了度假的人。再向外是主路，平坦宽阔，一台轮椅从远方驶来，正从沥青路向海边移动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是海南三亚，松软细腻的沙粒尽显优质，然而却是对轮椅的挑战。轮椅的轮子容易下陷，田野坐在上面，得有人倒着向前拉，他才能缓缓移动，一点点，再一点点，沙滩和大海以更缓慢的速度，来到这个小伙身前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门最艰难的处境在于，经常要等，“等一个帮助你的人出现”。田野几次跟我回忆旅途，比如从主路到沙滩，半米高的铁栏杆挡在眼前，别人能一下跨过去，他却不能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;溜冰、散打、开车，17岁之前的西安小伙田野好动，眼中的未来“无所不能”。 2004年，一场意外车祸导致他高位截瘫，此后只能坐在轮椅上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在被动等待之外，他和其他坐在轮椅上的“伤友”们互相鼓励着，走出门去，绘制出西安主城区三环内各处无障碍设施的地图，标记出存在的问题，打通出门的路。 3个月、4辆轮椅，每天15小时，成就一张597平方公里的无障碍地图，三种颜色分类做出了上千个标记，布满西安三环内所有主干道，相关部门据此清理障碍，更多出门的路出现在身障人士眼中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一路走来，他们遭受过不少非议，“绕一下不就得了吗，为什么非走这条路？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“没有想抄近路，我只是想走本来的那条路。”田野坐在轮椅上，重复这个回答。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“伤友”们一起推着轮椅行走在无障碍通道图/微电影《嘿，出来》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被精确的身体需求&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;一辆轮椅遇见另一辆轮椅，越来越多，五六个开轮椅的人聚在空旷的场地上，“嘿，出来！”简单的招呼过后，他们开始了比赛——轮椅竞速。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛道很长，需要穿过一些无障碍通道，道路细微的不规范可能导致轮椅的减速甚至暂停，这是坐在轮椅上的他们驶过无数次的路，曾经的不规范被一一标注、反馈、打通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竞速结束，他们会相约去吃上一顿，聚餐地点在田野的串串店。在那里，身障人士就餐打五折，是“伤友”们的固定聚餐点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但一连数日，我始终没等到这样的画面。 9月中旬，正逢西安雨季，持续十几天的阴雨，分隔开此前的夏与之后的冬。 “西安没秋，”当地人这么说。一转眼，天气由热转冷，不给人准备的时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便在西安生活了数十年，即便是天气的细微变化，“伤友”们也感觉不适，雨来了，他们更加出不去了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凑在一起，不容易。他们正在慢慢习惯，就像生活中很多的细节，都需要重新适应，在时间中寻找新的秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们需要精确控制自己的身体需求。比如最简单的喝水，要定时、定量，做好精确管理，否则无法控制大小便的时间规律，给出门增加困难；不喝水是不行的，有人试过，膀胱系统感染、尿路感染的问题会随之而来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;微电影拍摄杀青后，田野和剧组人员合照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喝水的速度也要控制，喝得太快、太猛，水过快从喉咙到了膀胱，误差随之出现，五分钟的时间差，对于出门的轮椅来说，就可能意味着超过两小时的意外。这两小时的行程是紧凑的：找到合适的地点、清理自己的身体，再推开门走上街，假装一切不曾发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与身体培养默契，需要应对季节的变化。比如夏天和冬天，人的出汗量不同，对应的喝水规律自然不同。探索每一细小规律的方寸之差，源自“伤友们”心底深处难以抗拒出门的诱惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野开的打五折的串串店也是“伤友”们出门的诱惑之一。 17岁那年他遭遇意外车祸，高位截瘫，依靠轮椅出行，成为“伤友”圈的一员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次见到田野，是在他的家中。尿路感染是伤友们的常见病之一，田野刚从医院输液回来，坐在轮椅上，身体歪向一侧，讲话的尾音垂在地上，带着强撑精神的疲惫。脚上是运动鞋，不时需要人帮他搬动一下，确保踩在轮椅的踏板上，聊天时间一长，就需要移动一下。重力的作用会让他的脚越来越不舒服，直到向身边的人开口求助。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数时候，这个人是他的爸爸。 “爸，喝水。”“爸，可乐。”不需要道谢，不需要解释，或者其他任何理由，漫长的时间会把这样的对话简化为最直接的表达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野住在西安市曲江新区，这里平均每隔几百米建有一个公共卫生间，配备有无障碍卫生间。田野坐在电动轮椅上，熟练地开往家附近的一个公共卫生间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打开无障碍卫生间的门，里面设施完备，有能把婴童放在横板上躺着换尿布的设施，有能把婴童固定坐在一侧方便家长如厕的设施，也有带着扶手方便残障人士如厕的设施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而完备的另一面，只有真正使用的人才能感受到其中细微的差异。田野推着轮椅，走到镜子前，在平整洁净的半身镜中，他看不到自己。田野解释，镜子需要有一定的倾斜度，才能在低处看到自己的面貌。我试着弯腰低头，让自己的视线与坐在轮椅上的他的头部高度持平，不再敢说这是“细微”之差。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从主路通往卫生间的无障碍通道的两边并不平整，而站在一旁却看不出异常。 “两边不平，”田野的爸爸用手比量了一下。相关道路规范是误差不能超过2厘米，“1厘米以内（误差）对于轮椅上下来说不影响，但这条路至少有5厘米的误差。”直到田野的轮椅缓缓上行，几次用力都推不上去，猛然加速可能侧翻，我才意识到视线内的毫厘之差对于轮椅意味着什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野接着解释刚刚走过的盲道分类：盲道砖是分两类，条形状的是引导砖，引导盲人安全放心前行的，这种称为行进盲道砖；另外一种就是圆点状的提示砖，用于提示盲人前面有障碍，应该进行转弯了，这种称为提示盲道砖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我以前什么都不懂，”田野笑了笑，开始回忆“懂”的节点，那是一场意外车祸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;田野的串串店成了“伤友”的相聚之地&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;给所有人看的戏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;灰白色的桑塔纳穿过，车牌号留在田野心底，直到多年后他依然能脱口而出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车子尚未驶过之前，田野的人生是“动”的。他出生于1987年，祖祖辈辈在西安大雁塔附近生活。田野从小调皮好动，喜欢看武侠片。李连杰主演的《黄飞鸿》里“狮王争霸”的名场面给他留下深刻印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，他去了武校，从13岁到15岁，整整两年，练习武术。年少时喜欢滑旱冰，他总是滑得最好最快的那一个。当时流行一种叫“开火车”的游戏，一群人前后拽着向前滑，时而直，时而斜，变换着队形，开在第一个的人被称作“火车头”，“火车快不快，全靠头来带”，田野总是扮演火车头的角色。有武校的底子在身，他的速度与平衡感、力量感都很出挑，“像秋天的叶子在空中飘落”，侧空翻、劈叉不在话下，拉火车能拉一百多人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再后来，不念书、不学武了，田野开过推土机，修过车。在工地，除了塔吊，别的能见到的“车”，他都开过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的速度停在17岁那年。 2004年，田野遭遇车祸。捡回一条命后，他住了21天ICU（重症监护治疗病房），不知道花了多少钱，接着又在床上躺了8个月，瘦成皮包骨，那是人生中最痛苦的一段时间。田野回忆，当时他1米7多的身高，体重只有七八十斤，身上肋骨根根分明，看得真切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来的10年里，父母带着他四处求医问药，去过专科医院，也找过江湖郎中。偏方、秘方不知试了多少，钱花了，苦吃了，人却没能站起来。 “凯子（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当地方言，意为&#39;傻子&#39;&lt;/span>;）上当，当当不一样，”田野感慨当时一家人的状态，不愿意接受事实，总觉得还能站起来，应该能站起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实中寻不到出口，田野把一个梦记在心里。梦里他进了一座庙，很多和尚正在打坐敲木鱼，他跪在佛像面前。大雄宝殿突然门开了，伴随一道金光，一个老和尚进来，他对着田野说，“你本应该下地狱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野不解，哭着问，“我这么善良，没做过什么天大的坏事，为什么我要下地狱，为什么我要坐轮椅？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和尚回，“坐轮椅已经很不错了，你本来要下地狱的。”和尚在空中画了一个圈，像是个电视，田野在里面看到自己是一个王子，在战乱厮杀中跑进一座寺庙，拿木棍把一尊菩萨像的头打了下来。看完后，田野在梦里嚎啕大哭，醒来继续哭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哭过之后，尽管梦境虚幻，田野却好像从现实之外找到了某种安慰的理由。他不再困惑，不再觉得被命运针对。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聊到转变的节点，田野沉吟了一会，说到“使命”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的使命是什么？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在演一场戏，观众是所有人。过去我是个特别调皮的孩子，意外出了车祸，周围的一些人说那就是报应，或者说是因果，因为我以前太调皮了，别人会用我来教育自家孩子。一开始我觉得反感，后来我是开心的，我的遭遇成了家长教育孩子的反面教材——&#39;不要学田野&#39;。就从这里，我慢慢找到了自己人生的方向，便不再寂寞。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野决定开一家串串店。最早开在小区里，2013年5月，从8个蜂窝煤炉、一把伞、几条板凳，到六七十个炉子、搭了棚子，再到活动板房，“变得有模有样”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年夏，田野和“伤友”们在西安曲江南湖体验无障碍设施&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年6月，小店搬到离家1公里左右的铺面，“那是生意最好的时候”。 120平方米的店面，每天能开百来桌，人多到坐不下。半年后，店面再次扩大，田野换租到隔壁300平米的店铺。刚搬完的当月中旬，西安出现新冠肺炎病例，2021年11月，田野的串串店刚开张就迎来闭店。 2022年整一年，小店关门180天，亏损几十万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了2023年，田野以为疫情没了、政策放开了，一切会变好，但生意却变淡了。我们见面的9月中旬，店面正在装修，田野想用新的面貌来迎回曾经的红火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“新店要不要装无障碍卫生间？”在田野的另一家米线店，我看着他问。这家米线店可能开不下去了，田野想缓解一点财务压力，以后有余力再做。米线店的房租支出一年在9万元左右，生意并不好，他分析是因为地段不好。我们在店门口聊天的时候，小雨时不时落下，这家店夹在写字楼的背面，附近还有几家快餐店，生意都不算好，雨天的街上行人稀少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，考虑过装无障碍卫生间，但还是不现实。好在方便的是，串串店附近一百米左右就有公共卫生间，那里有无障碍设施，方便“伤友”解决如厕问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开店以来，身障人士来田野的串串店消费，一律打八五折。 2021年5月，网商银行公益小店联盟成立，田野的串串店加入，在网商银行的支持下，推出残障人士半价吃串的套餐活动。王烨是这个公益小店项目的发起人，她介绍平台的主要用户是小店主。在做这个公益项目的时候，她想知道“店主们”都是什么人。当时正处在疫情期间，王烨最先接触到一家西安饺子馆的店主，一些人来西安找工作没找到、钱花完了，老板在门口贴了张纸，大意是“有困难没什么大不了，进来吃碗饺子，不要钱”。公益小店项目给了饺子店主1万元扶持金。 “怎么会有这么真诚的人，他明明就很难。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来王烨发现了田野的串串店，同样给了1万元扶持金，“伤友五折吃串”的活动上线。王烨的工作任务是在全国找到1000家这样的店，“1000是我们的上限。我们不找一开始就下决心做公益的，那样很难坚持下去的，我们就找那种本来就在正常经营的。”接触过很多家这样的公益小店后，王烨感慨公益不是靠感性的冲动，需要有目标感，需要有价值观在心里，不能是一时的热血，一定是一直的信念，“我知道我在干嘛。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;微电影拍摄期间，导演王烨（左一）和伤友一起体验轮椅出行&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;交给时间去呈现&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除串串店外，田野和伤友们的公益“版图”还在于绘制一张无障碍地图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年8月，田野与结识的6名残障人士自筹资金共同成立“SCI无翼飞翔”公益中心。 “没有翅膀，也想飞行”是他们成立“无翼飞翔”的初衷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无翼飞翔”成立后，田野与伤友们用3个月的时间开展西安市三环内的道路无障碍环境调查，想法最初是“伤友”黄远提出来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄远，今年52岁，2011年7月遭遇车祸，胸部第9根到第12根肋骨受伤，此后需要借助轮椅出行。在轮椅上，他跑过半程马拉松。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到和“伤友”一起出门，他觉得更加没有压力。最困难的可能是临时上厕所的问题，比如大小便没控制好，尤其是大便，要回到家中或者在无障碍厕所一点点清理自己，动辄一两个小时。 “伤友”之间一个眼神、一句话就完全懂，不需要解释，也能给予全部的理解，因为他们有“平等的身体”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身体最严重的问题在于没有知觉，他的大腿在一次出门后肿成了原先的3倍，直到那时才发现受伤。右腿伤疤，是2022年5月份留下的，至今还没好。他挽起裤管，凹凸不平的小腿上有深深浅浅的疤痕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;讲到出门，黄远总是笑意满满。 “伤友们”开着轮椅在路上观察，发现哪里的无障碍设施有问题就拍照传给黄远，汇集了上万张照片。黄远最终选择可用的5000张照片，制作成电子地图。这需要大量的幕后工作，比如GPS反向读出坐标，然后把照片对应到相应位置，用不同颜色的记号标注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份电子地图有不同图层加以区别：一是按照行政区域划分，二是按照原因分类，包括设计不规范、建设不到位和后期破坏与损耗三类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以黄远的经验来看，设计方案大部分是到位的，因为有标准图，但在施工建设和监督验收的环节，有时会出问题，出现“样子货”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过3个月的调研，黄远编写了《西安市无障碍设施状况调查报告》，制作出一份特殊的西安无障碍问题分布的电子地图，清晰标注了每一个存在无障碍问题的地点、图片展示、原因类别等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查结果以电子邮件方式递送到相关路政部门，其中一些问题得到了整改。这份地图和报告依然在黄远的电脑中保留着，尽管“公益中心”目前已经因为资金不足无力维系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;完整的调查并不是一开始就有的，最初是零星的“爱心贴”。刘思芳顺手从茶几下拿出一沓，粉红色的便利贴上印有“我是残障人士，您的车辆挡住了无障碍通道”的话语，他的轮椅背包里也有一摞，出门随身带。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘思芳今年60岁，50岁那年血管发病，颈动脉漏了，医生告诉他，患这种罕见病的人，世界范围内的记录不超过50例。 2014年，他在西安医学院做了手术，此后的生活离不开拐杖和轮椅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘思芳家里养了几只鹦鹉，在房间里飞来飞去，一会儿落在肩上、一会儿落在头上，平添几分生气。他给这些鸟都起了名字，在家也算多个了乐趣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到制作爱心贴和做无障碍通道地图，刘思芳提到，“是给出门找一个理由。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原先是零零星星的爱心贴，后来伤友们想，“算了，自己跑吧，做个整体的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“验收的人也不是残疾人，”谈到使用无障碍设施遇到的问题，刘思芳更多选择了理解：会碰到不合规的“斜坡问题”，还有一些把无障碍通道做成石子路的，也许是为了美观，但小轮轮椅走不成，得是大轮轮椅，限制了一部分轮椅的出行……这样的细节只有坐在轮椅上才能有真正的认知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加速度会上瘾，为了让更多“伤友”出门，也为了鼓舞自我，3个月、4辆轮椅、每天15小时，小店“伤友”们在西安走出了一张597平方公里的无障碍地图，3种颜色、上千个标记，布满西安三环内所有主干道。 “伤友”们被称为“轮椅竞速小王子”，他们经常约在西安城郊，坐在轮椅上开展竞速赛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门是困境，也是诱惑。田野去过最远的地方是三亚，那是在五六年前。面对大海，头上是阳光，脚下是沙滩，喝着冰镇西瓜汁，戴着墨镜，他仿佛置身于一个新世界。那是春节时分，远在千里之外的家乡西安正是隆冬，风照刮、雪照下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他并不擅长表达，海浪的声音怎么形容呢？谈到那种遥远，田野的目光拉长，变得越来越远，穿过面前的墙壁，淡淡的笑容浮现在脸上，他好像又听见了，那“像西安的春天”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“等一个帮助你的人出现”是出门可能需要的好运气。就在我们访谈的前几天，西安下了一场大雨。店里有事必须去对接一下，田野开着电动轮椅出门，一不小心栽倒在路边水坑，因为雨太大把坑盖住了没留意到。妈妈看他半天没过去，沿路回来找，才发现儿子人跪在地上，半个身子泡在水里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雨天行人不多，有位女士想帮忙扶，但力气不够，后来又来了一位男士，几人合力才把田野救出。等待足足花了半小时，“也有经过但没帮忙的人”，田野在最后淡淡补了一句。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门会听到反对的声音，“残疾人啥都干不了，就在家里别出来了。出门干嘛，尽给社会添乱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野对这样的话感到愤怒，“一个正常的社会应该是一个包容的社会，不但包容人，连马路上的小动物、花花草草也应该包容。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接触中，王烨感受到田野的乐观是带有悲凉底色的，“他不是没心没肺的、没有痛苦的，他会有很多沉思的时候，他遇到的困难都是经营上的，身体上的他已经习惯了。”在王烨眼中，田野是用心经营的一个店主，“我更愿意介绍他是一个用心努力的人，是一个店主，而不是先用残障人士去介绍他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10年前，有了想写一本书的念头，田野坐在轮椅上，断断续续述说过往，他想写自己这一生。窗户在他背面，屋外是淅淅沥沥的雨声，屋内有些凉意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我没有想过开头和结尾，”田野回答我对于“一辈子”这本书的疑问，“也许人生毫无意义，但并不代表应该随便度过。我知道自己的剧本是什么样子，但还是会把它演完。”这本书，他想一步一步讲，用时间去呈现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黄仕忠：怀念郭在贻老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDVbVt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDV bVt. png&quot; data-key=&quot;256610&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi (1939-1989). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi is fundamentally a very proud person. More than thirty years after his death, I read a long letter he wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi on November 21, 1977. He talked freely about calligraphy schools and famous calligraphers at that time, and criticized Fang Qiu. in this way. The depth of calligraphy attainments seen in the handwriting astonished me. Because he knew what he said, it flowed out naturally from his mind. To him, it was just a normal conversation with his brother. Since it was a private letter, there was no need to be restrained, so he spoke frankly and heartily, rather than pretending to make shocking remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256609&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1988, Teacher Guo worked with students to complete the first draft of &quot;Review of the Dunhuang Bian Anthology&quot;. A friend wrote in a letter: &quot;This manuscript is devoted to our own opinions. We are confident and not without inventions. There are many unique secrets in the research and interpretation of common words and proverbs.&quot; It is also full of confidence rather than boasting. This tone can be seen or heard in his letters and conversations with friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo and I only exchanged words occasionally. He is not tall and his eyes are not big, but they are bright and bright. When he glances past with slightly squinted eyes, he seems to be condescending, which makes me feel uncomfortable. Health shrinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, he had just passed his forties, and his body seemed to be condensed with infinite energy, shining so brightly that it was impossible to look directly at it. Especially in the field of Chinese history, he is the person who carries the banner after Jiang Liangfu and Jiang Lihong. In July 1986, with the approval of the Discipline Review Group of the State Council, the Chinese Department of Hangzhou University welcomed a new group of doctoral supervisors after Mr. Jiang Liangfu. They are: Shen Wenzhuo, Jiang Lihong, Xu Shuofang, and Guo Zaiyi. The first three are all over 60 years old, and Mr. Guo is only 47 years old. He was the youngest doctoral supervisor in the field of humanities and social sciences at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was an undergraduate (1978-1982), he offered elective courses for the 1978 and 1979 students. I didn’t choose them at the time, but I have looked up to him for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, several students in Grade 77, influenced by Teacher Guo’s ancient Chinese class, spontaneously formed an interest group to carry out research on word exegesis. One of them is named Bian Xincan, who is from my hometown, and we are the same age, so we have a lot of exchanges. He said: &quot;Teacher Guo is knowledgeable and humorous in class. One of the sentences touched me very much: &#39;Discovering a new meaning is like discovering a planet.&#39; It can be said to illuminate my soul.&quot; So he dived into ancient books. In the pile, I made cards and copied words. By the fourth grade (1981), I published papers in &quot;Hangzhou University Journal&quot; and &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. He was only 21 years old that year. His graduation thesis was also supervised by Teacher Guo. I have read his paper published in &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;. The words he explained are well-documented and convincing. They are exactly the same as Mr. Jiang Lihong&#39;s &quot;Explanation of the Meanings of Dunhuang Bianwenwen&quot;. He said that after the article was written, he cautiously submitted it to Mr. Jiang Lihong, and received enthusiastic guidance and recommendation to &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;; the article in &quot;Chinese Language&quot; was accepted by his own submission. At that time, many teachers were struggling to write papers and therefore could not be promoted, so this incident left a deep impression on me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yimin, Zhang Yongquan, and Ji Weiqiang in the interest group also published papers in influential professional journals when they were in college or early after graduation. Yimin said that he was slightly excited when he saw his name listed with Mr. Ni Baoyuan, a teacher from Hangzhou University, in the catalog of &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. Yongquan re-entered Hangzhou University two years after graduation and studied for graduate school with Professor Guo, opening up a new world in the field of Dunhuang colloquial word research. Behind this, you can see the figure of Teacher Guo Zaiyi. They were just undergraduates, but under Teacher Guo&#39;s guidance, they achieved such outstanding results. As a student at the time, I admired him very much and could not imagine how great he was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was in the autumn of 1982 that I was admitted to the graduate school of ancient literature at our university after graduating from my undergraduate degree. Teachers Guo Zaiyi, Zhu Hongxi and others recruited six graduate students in ancient Chinese, including Fang Yixin, Chen Baiye, Jin Xiaochun, Guo Xiaowu, Wang Yunlu and Ye Qing. The boys&#39; dormitory is next to each other. Yixin, Baiye and I are undergraduate classmates, so I often visit them and listen to their discussions. Teacher Guo asked me to read through the paragraph notes of &quot;Shuowen&quot; first with punctuation. At that time, there was a photocopy of the notes, with a purple cover and a large format. Each of them had it open on the table. It was very solemn and quite showing off, because &quot;our Teacher Guo&quot; believed that this was the right way to get started, and Teacher Guo himself ordered Read it three or four times. This made me very envious, and I bought a copy. However, I hesitated repeatedly on whether to read it through, and finally gave up, because at that time I was working on &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Han Dynasty&quot; under the guidance of Master Xu Shuo. There is not enough time for comparison of books. In the second academic year, I returned to opera from &quot;History&quot; and &quot;Han&quot; and systematically read through the basic literature on Yuan and Ming opera. In fact, I was indirectly influenced by Teacher Guo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave his graduate students a course on &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, and I also took the course. This was the first time I walked into his class. It was an eye-opener and I was hooked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256607&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;When Teacher Guo was young, he was full of sunshine. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo is from Zouping, Shandong, and has a strong accent. For me, a Zhejiang native, it sounds a bit strange. The pronunciation of the characters is quite difficult to distinguish. Even so, his lectures were engaging. He first put forward examples and listed different theories, and then laid out his evidence, one, two, three, four, as if he were doing vertical arithmetic problems for primary school students, with clear layers and a clear view. In fact, it is extremely difficult to select examples for exegesis. Unless you are very familiar with the semantics of words and their origins, you will not be able to find accurate examples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, I only thought that it was enough to understand some &quot;methods&quot; of exegesis. I only had a superficial taste of Mr. Guo&#39;s thesis, and my understanding was not deep enough. Teacher Guo is based on his own years of research and combines the results of his predecessors to provide supplementary extensions and demonstrations in class. The core content has been published. One article is &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, published in &quot;Literary History&quot; (6th and 14th series, 1979, 1982); the other is &quot;Explanation of Vernacular Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, published in &quot; Chinese Language, Issue 6, 1983. In 1984, with these two papers, he won the second prize of the first Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (a total of three people won the award, the other two being Li Jiahao and Jiang Shaoyu from the Chinese Department of Peking University). This award was established after the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; by Mr. Lu Shuxiang with a donation to commend young scholars (limited to those under 45 years old). There was no first prize in the &quot;first edition&quot;, so this is the highest award. Two years later, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor. It is said that Mr. Xu Fu greatly appreciated his research and strongly recommended him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have mostly forgotten many of Mr. Guo’s incisive explanations, but some of the “methods” he taught played a real role in my subsequent academic research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Teacher Guo introduced the concept of continuous words, which are mostly double-sounding rhymes, and the sound must be emphasized. There are different writing methods with similar sounds, and they cannot be broken into individual words for explanation. He also said that some of them were discovered by Mr. Jiang Liangfu. Mr. Jiang&#39;s famous work &quot;Collation and Annotation of Qu Yuan&#39;s Fu&quot; was completed when he was only 29 years old (originally written in 1929 and completed in 1931). I looked through the &quot;Chu Ci&quot; and found that dozens of words are continuous words. However, most of the annotated versions of contemporary scholars still use split words for explanation. In other words, just relying on &quot;continuous words&quot; as a trace gave the young Jiang Liangfu many new insights. His graduation thesis at Tsinghua University, &quot;An Examination of Shi Sao Lian Mian Zi&quot;, was supervised by Wang Guowei. Wang Guowei keenly listed the discussion of Qing Confucianism as a special topic. He only pointed out the problem in one article and gave the topic to the students. The students followed this and expanded it to open up their own fields. This allowed me to see the necessity of mastering &quot;academic principles&quot; and &quot;criteria&quot;, and at the same time I also learned the importance of &quot;family law&quot; and &quot;teacher-to-teacher inheritance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave a wonderful explanation in class on the difficult words in Chu Ci, as well as the words that scholars in the past considered &quot;unexplainable&quot;. From Wang Yi, Zhu Xi, Hong Xingzu, to Guo Moruo and other contemporary famous Chu Ci scholars, they all revealed certain weaknesses in the face of his exquisite &quot;exegesis&quot;. He stands on a high platform in this field and gives guidance to the country. In addition to explaining the exegesis, he also told us some tidbits, with a proud tone. He said that he would buy any new annotated version of the Songs of Chu that came out, look through it, and then throw it away because he didn&#39;t see anything new. At the same time, he would write to some annotators to express his congratulations, indicating that I have read your book, and also giving a hint: &quot;If you use Guo Moruo and Wen Huaisha, you will specify it; in my explanation, I will use Even if you don’t tell me, I actually know it!” After saying this, he tightened his lips, tilted his head slightly, and raised his chin, leaving a freeze in my mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——I then knew that for a scholar to be recognized, it requires a process of accumulation of qualifications. This gives me the peace of mind to face the same thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi was one of the most dazzling young scholars at that time. This also makes us very curious, how does he stand out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that he was a &quot;Xiaoyao sect&quot; during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. He brought books about &quot;Chu Ci&quot; from the reference room and read them one by one. His &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot; was written after reading hundreds of relevant materials. The obsession and fascination during this period can be evidenced by a story told by himself: Once when he went to buy meat, there was a long queue. He was holding a book and was fascinated. When he woke up, he found that it was dark and the market had already dispersed. , he was the only one, standing there reading for a long time. But at that time, &quot;the more knowledge, the more reactionary&quot;. Reading these things only had negative effects, so many people laughed at him. An old classmate of his, who may or may not be inferior to him in terms of talent, but far surpasses him in terms of &quot;shrewdness&quot;, actively participated in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and once dominated the world. After the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, he became one of the &quot;three types of people&quot; under inspection. When he returned to teaching, Guo Zaiyi had already shone in the academic world. Only then did he realize his past mistakes and start over. This led to a consensus that scholars should stay away from the “movement.” At the same time, there are also vague rumors that Teacher Guo is not in good health because he studies too hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1985, after I graduated as a graduate student, I stayed at the school to teach. I was assigned a faculty dormitory and shared a room with my classmate Jin Xiaochun. Xiaochun’s graduation thesis was supervised by Teacher Guo. In the following year, I heard many stories from him about &quot;our teacher Guo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, I have a story related to Teacher Guo. In the autumn and winter of this year, Teacher He Chunhui and I went to Shanghai to deliver review materials for the promotion of teachers in our department, involving teachers such as Wu Xionghe, Cai Yijiang, Guo Zaiyi, and Ni Baoyuan. I am responsible for serving the experts in literature, and Chunhui is responsible for serving the experts in language and philology. She said that she was very enthusiastic when she met Mr. Shi Cunzhi from East China Normal University, and spoke highly of these teachers at Hangzhou University, especially Teacher Guo. I have participated in the promotion of several of my respected teachers to professional titles, and I feel quite &quot;honored&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaochun got married before the Chinese New Year. His wife was from Hangzhou and her family was very well off. He moved to a new house and seldom came back. But when I come back, I always share the story of &quot;our Teacher Guo&quot; with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring and summer of 1986, because of his professional title promotion, Teacher Guo improved his salary and purchased some new furniture. He was in a very happy mood, playing with his newly purchased items for Xiaochun. Xiaochun and the teacher are both teachers and friends, and sometimes they deliberately quarrel with the teacher. I remember that Teacher Guo was proud of his newly bought double sofa, so Xiaochun said jokingly: My sofa is a three-person sofa! Teacher Guo was speechless for a moment and said, &quot;Hey, I&#39;m not going to compare with you.&quot; He looked left and right, appreciating it for himself, unable to contain his inner joy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listening to Xiao Chundao telling such short stories, the common feeling in our hearts is one of indescribable bitterness. However, fortunately, all this will be a thing of the past, and the teacher’s vision has been filled with sunshine! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fall of this year, I was admitted to Sun Yat-sen University to study for a Ph.D. Soon after, Xiaochun also went to the United States for academic exchange, and I rarely heard from Teacher Guo. More than two years later, in mid-January 1989, the news suddenly came that Teacher Guo Zaiyi had passed away. I was simply shocked! Is it fate? I have no words to say, I can only pray silently, may he be well in heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, I learned about Teacher Guo’s final condition from Zhang Yongquan’s article. On the afternoon when the B-ultrasound examination showed that he had liver cancer, Teacher Guo endured great mental pain and wrote a suicide note to his students:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic script, italic script_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yongquan, Huang Zheng:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Farewell in a hurry, extremely melancholy. You must work hard to complete our scientific research plan and strive to publish all three books to comfort my soul in heaven. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have a favor for you:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Please collect my articles that have not been included in the &quot;Exegetical Series&quot;, compile a sequel, and try to publish it in a few years (of course it is impossible now), for I just want to earn some royalties to support my family, but I personally have nothing to ask for. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;zaiyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;November 5, 1988&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a proud man, at that moment, he did not forget his &quot; &quot;Scientific research plan&quot;; and for the sake of my family, I can only say humbly that I hope to &quot;earn some royalties to support my family&quot;, but still declare: &quot;I personally have nothing to ask for.&quot; After reading this &quot;will&quot;, How can it not make people cry! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo endured the pain and entered 1989, but in the end he was unable to save himself and passed away on January 10th. There is still one day left before his fiftieth birthday! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I later read the memories written by Fu Jie: &quot;In the last days of his life, Master Zai Yi spoke less and less - both because of lack of energy and because of depression. More than once, he was silent or even He was lying numbly, his eyes not looking at us around him, only looking at the ceiling, and suddenly he started sobbing loudly, which made us who were still young at the time panic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day when the illness was confirmed, He said to Yongquan: &quot;The situation is not good. I have been mentally prepared. I only pity their orphans and widowers...&quot; But even two days before his death, he also said to Yongquan: &quot;Fang Yizhi&#39;s &quot;Tongya&quot; is a good book. If you come here, buy me a copy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How nostalgic he is for this world! Because he has too many things to do, he has recently planned the &quot;Three Books of Dunhuang&quot;, which is being implemented with his disciples. He also has a pair of young children who are still in middle school. However, his frail body is no longer able to support him. Even though he is extremely Unwilling to do so, but helpless, and with no one to talk to, I would &quot;just stare at the ceiling with my absent-minded eyes&quot;, and &quot;suddenly sob&quot; &quot;more than once&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;This photo was probably taken on the last summer day. The brows are slightly furrowed, which is not without melancholy. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi passed away more than thirty years ago. He is only eighty-four years old this year, but what a world that will open up for the study of Chinese history! His classmate later made great achievements in academic studies and is now in good health. If people could choose again in life, how would they choose? Xia Chengtao said to his friend Wang Jisi: &quot;Ji Si, knowledge depends on longevity, not hard work.&quot; However, in life, it has nothing to do with the times and society. How can you really have your own choice? Moreover, &quot;Articles hate destiny.&quot; No matter how proud you are, you can&#39;t resist the tricks of fate! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“无级别”5年后，国家消防救援指挥机构明确为副部级丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259954]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 23:06:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3HQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1126&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3 HQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the morning of August 29, 2023, the Zhejiang Mobile Team of the National Fire Rescue Bureau was established The move-in ceremony was held in Tonglu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten months after the listing, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; were finally announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 31, 2023, the establishment regulations released by the China Institutional Establishment Network clearly stated that the National Fire and Rescue Bureau is a national bureau managed by the Ministry of Emergency Management and is at the deputy ministerial level; the leadership pattern is &quot;one director and four deputies&quot; , with a political commissar; a total of 275 administrative staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Ministry of Emergency Management, since October 2023, the Central Organization Office has intensively announced information on the adjustment of the responsibilities of multiple other ministries and commissions, involving the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, and the National Health Commission , People&#39;s Bank of China, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An important reason why the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; have attracted attention is that after integrating the former Fire and Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management and the Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, since their establishment in October 2018, There has been no clear administrative level. The two agencies merged in January 2023 to form the National Fire and Rescue Service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this calculation, the leadership and command organization of China&#39;s fire rescue team has been in a &quot;levelless&quot; state for the past five years, until this time it was clearly defined as deputy ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management system and organizational structure of the fire brigade have changed several times. In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and became part of the Ministry of Emergency Management to establish a national comprehensive fire rescue team. Among them, the management organization of the Public Security Fire Force was changed to the Fire Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and the management organization of the Armed Police Forest Force was changed to the Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year later, in November 2019, the Central Organization Office issued a notice clarifying that the Fire Rescue Bureau and Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management are the leading and commanding agencies of the fire rescue team and forest firefighting team respectively, but &quot;temporarily The administrative level of the team is unclear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice also shows that starting from August 22, 2018, there will be a three-year &quot;trial running-in period&quot;; during the running-in period, issues such as the number and allocation of leadership positions will be standardized in a timely manner based on the running-in situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the running-in period has expired, the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan National Emergency System Plan&quot; issued in February 2022 further clarified that it is necessary to &quot;integrate the fire rescue team and the forest firefighting team into a formalized, A professional and professional national comprehensive fire rescue team.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another year has passed since then. On January 6, 2023, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, which was formed by integrating the Fire and Rescue Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management and the Forest Fire Bureau, was officially launched. Another 10 months have passed since the National Fire and Rescue Bureau was listed and the administrative level was clarified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot; of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau clearly state that the National Fire and Rescue Bureau will have a first political commissar who will concurrently be the main responsible comrade of the Emergency Management Department, and the director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau will be concurrently served by the Deputy Minister of the Emergency Management Department. The political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau is concurrently served by the director of the political department of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, news on the website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security showed that Wang Xiangxi, secretary of the Party Committee and Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, has concurrently served as the first political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, and Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management, has served as the director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau. Xu Ping, a member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Management, serves as the political commissar of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Three Certain Plans&quot;, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau Command Center will also be hung on the Emergency Command Center of the Ministry of Emergency Management. The director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau Command Center will be the deputy director of the Emergency Command Center of the Ministry of Emergency Management. concurrently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time as the National Fire and Rescue Bureau&#39;s &quot;Three Fixed Plans&quot; were announced,&amp;nbsp;the functions of the Emergency Management Department were also adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsibilities of the Fire Rescue Bureau and Forest Fire Bureau of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and the responsibilities related to the education and training of the national comprehensive fire rescue team undertaken by the Education and Training Department are transferred to the National Fire Rescue Bureau; the Ministry of Emergency Management manages the national fire rescue Bureau, and added the responsibilities of formulating firefighter exit and resettlement plans, organizing their implementation, and guiding local governments to establish and improve a comprehensive emergency joint command platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Emergency Management Department will continue to perform related tasks such as appointment and dismissal, deployment, commendation, rewards, punishment, and martyr assessment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in accordance with the principle of decentralization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ The Ministry of Civil Affairs has changed its leadership. Lu Zhi was originally appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and Tang Dengjie was transferred to Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Before taking up his new post, Tang Dengjie served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. The post of Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee was previously held by Lan Fo&#39;an, who has succeeded Liu Kun as Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Tang Dengjie took over, Lu Zhiyuan has been appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. Lu Zhiyuan has worked in Shaanxi Province for many years, serving as deputy secretary of the Yulin Municipal Party Committee and mayor, and secretary of the Weinan Municipal Party Committee. In January 2018, he was promoted to deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. In September 2018, he was transferred across provinces to serve as member of the Standing Committee of the Liaoning Provincial Party Committee and Organization Minister. In September 2021, Lu Zhiyuan was transferred to the Standing Committee of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee, and later served as Deputy Secretary of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Director of the National Development and Reform Commission Zheng Shajie takes on a new position]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November According to news from Qiushi.com on the 1st, the 21st issue of &quot;Qiushi&quot; in 2023 published an article signed by Zheng Shajie - &quot;Through hard work over a long period of time, we will solidly promote the high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;&quot;. The author&#39;s introduction at the end of the article shows, Zheng Shanjie, director of the National Development and Reform Commission, has been appointed as the director of the office of the leading group for promoting the “Belt and Road” construction. &lt;p>; >;Recently, the Personnel Department of the State Sports General Administration issued an announcement stating that based on work needs, Chen Ruolin plans to be deployed from outside Beijing to work at the Swimming Sports Management Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ruolin, female, born in December 1992, has a bachelor&#39;s degree and is currently a coach at the Swimming Academy of Nanjing Institute of Physical Education. Chen Ruolin joined the Jiangsu Provincial Diving Team in 2000 and was selected for the National Diving Team in 2005. She won the women&#39;s single and synchronized 10-meter platform championships at the 2008 Beijing Olympics, the women&#39;s single and synchronized 10-meter platform championships at the 2012 London Olympics, and the 2016 Rio Olympic Games. Olympic women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform champion. She is also Quan Hongchan’s coach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Law: Liu Shaoyun is a first-level justice of the People&#39;s Republic of China]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On October 28, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Court issued an announcement indicating that in accordance with the &quot;Judges Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and other relevant regulations, Liu Shaoyun is a first-level justice of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ From January to September 2023, a total of 405,000 people were punished nationwide]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission on October 29, from January to September 2023, the national discipline inspection and supervision agencies received a total of There were 2.617 million petitions and reports, including 819,000 reports and accusations. 1.283 million clues were handled, including 266,000 interviews and correspondence. 470,000 cases were filed, including 54 cadres at the central management level, 2,480 cadres at the department and bureau level, 20,000 cadres at the county and division level, and 65,000 cadres at the township and section level; the current or former village party branch secretary and village committee director were registered. 46,000 people. 405,000 people were punished, including 331,000 party disciplinary sanctions and 108,000 government affairs sanctions; 34 provincial and ministerial level cadres, 2,244 department and bureau level cadres, 16,000 county and division level cadres, 54,000 township and section level cadres, and general There are 56,000 cadres and 277,000 other personnel in rural areas and enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[He Zehua, the former deputy director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was prosecuted after retirement]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the WeChat public account of &quot;Procuratorial Daily Justice Network&quot;, the former deputy director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, He Zehua, was suspected of accepting bribes and using his influence to accept bribes. The investigation was concluded by the National Supervisory Commission and was designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Dalian City, Liaoning Province reviewed and prosecuted. Recently, the Dalian People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Dalian Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zehua was once Ling Chengxing&#39;s deputy. In May 2013, when Ling Chengxing was appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, He Zehua had been a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration for nearly 10 years. On October 23, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission issued a notice that Ling Chengxing, the former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was suspected of serious violations of disciplines and laws and was undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Children of leading cadres in Hunan’s rectification ask each other to do things]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Hunan The Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision held a meeting to promote the special rectification work of leading cadres in the province who used their power or influence to make profits for relatives and friends. The meeting emphasized that it is necessary to further expand the focus of supervision, not only focusing on the 21 key contents in three categories such as illegal business operations, &quot;branding&quot; and &quot;carrying baskets&quot;, but also paying close attention to the tasks that the children of leading cadres ask each other to do 6 This is a typical performance, strengthen education management supervision, and resolutely put an end to unhealthy tendencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hunan information shows that the cases of Yi Pengfei, former vice chairman of the Hunan Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, and other cases have exposed the problems of children of leading cadres asking each other to do things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[For accepting bribes of nearly 50 million yuan, Wang Xinghua, former secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee, was sentenced to 13 years in prison]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 31, 2023, the Rizhao Intermediate People&#39;s Court publicly pronounced the first instance verdict on Wang Xinghua, former member of the Standing Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee and former secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee, for accepting bribes. The defendant Wang Xinghua was sentenced to 13 years in prison for accepting bribes. A fine of RMB 4 million was also imposed; Wang Xinghua&#39;s property obtained from bribery was confiscated in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Ministry information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ National Health Commission: Promote the establishment of infant care service majors in secondary vocational schools, higher vocational colleges, etc.]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2023, Wang Bin, Director of the General Office of the National Health Commission, It was introduced at the press conference that it will promote the addition of infant care service majors in secondary vocational schools, higher vocational colleges, and higher vocational undergraduates, promote medical institutions to support the development of childcare services, and gradually improve the policies, regulations, standards and service supply of childcare services. , to further promote the continuous optimization of population policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Culture and Tourism: Suspension and cancellation of the qualifications of some national-level intangible cultural heritage protection units]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News, recently, 2,981 conservation units have passed the assessment through self-inspection of conservation units, local inspections and evaluations, soliciting opinions from project inheritance groups, and review by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism; 1 conservation unit has passed the assessment If the evaluation fails, the qualification to apply for national intangible cultural heritage protection funds will be suspended, and rectification will be carried out within a time limit; 3 protection units failed to perform their duties well, and their protection unit qualifications will be revoked and the protection units will be re-identified; 619 protection units have problems with the nature of the unit, organization, etc. In case of major changes, such as failure to meet the basic conditions of a protected unit, the protected unit will be re-identified; 3 previously vacant protected units will be recognized; 12 declared areas or units will not be recognized as protected units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ Since 2017, more than 4,200 cases of illegal cultural relics have been handled]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2023, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the State Administration of Cultural Heritage stated at a joint press conference that since 2017, A total of more than 4,200 cases of cultural relic violations were handled across the country, and more than 650 people were administratively held accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The standards for land acquisition compensation and resettlement for &quot;married girls&quot; are not uniform, and the procuratorial organs issued procuratorial recommendations]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problems such as inconsistent resettlement standards in the land acquisition and compensation process for &quot;married women&quot;, the procuratorial organs issued procuratorial recommendations and promoted the administrative agencies to formulate unified compensation standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate stated that whether &quot;married women&quot; should be compensated and resettled, and whether the compensation and resettlement standards are consistent, is related to the vital interests of women. In land expropriation compensation and resettlement, &quot;married girls&quot; who are registered separately by rural collective organizations shall have equal rights to resettlement and compensation, and shall be compensated and resettled as a single household according to unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After being detained for 902 days and found not guilty, the former richest man in Hubei, Lan Shili, received a compensation of 590,000 yuan from the state]&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, 2023, Lan Shili received the &quot;Criminal Compensation Decision&quot; from the Guangzhou Municipal Procuratorate. &amp;nbsp;On December 17, 2021, the Guangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the charges against Lan Shili could not be established and ruled that Lan Shili was not guilty. Three days later, Lan Shili was released. The &quot;Criminal Compensation Decision&quot; determined that Lan Shili was detained and restricted his personal freedom for a total of 902 days and should receive more than 590,000 yuan in state compensation. &lt;br>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Public reports show that Lan Shili, born in 1960 in Wuhan, Hubei Province, was on the Forbes list of richest people in 2005 with a net worth of more than 2 billion yuan, becoming the &quot;richest man in Hubei&quot;. He is also a member of Dongxing Group and founder of Eastern Star Airlines. In 2008, the global financial crisis broke out, East Star Airlines was also affected and eventually went bankrupt, and Lan Shili was involved in litigation. In 2010, Lan Shili was sentenced to four years in prison for evading the collection of owed taxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ Hangzhou Municipal Education Bureau: Will carry out risk-taking research on on-campus cultural and sports activities]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to news from the Hangzhou Municipal Party Committee and Hangzhou Municipal Government websites on November 1, the Hangzhou Municipal Education Bureau recently responded to the Hangzhou Municipal Recommendation No. 146 of the Second Session of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference on &quot;Ensuring that schools have the courage to implement physical education from court rulings&quot; and &quot;multiple guarantees to prevent parents from excessive accountability&quot; and other contents stated that it will conduct research on self-restraint in school cultural and sports activities, and at the same time adhere to The voluntary principle encourages parents to purchase comprehensive student (child) insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Guangdong Provincial Department of Education: Harmful toys such as &quot;carrot knives&quot; are strictly prohibited from entering campus]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Recently, a new toy called &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; has become popular among primary and secondary school students (young children). Recently, the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Education and Management of Hazardous Toys&quot; (referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), requiring all primary and secondary schools and kindergartens to strictly prohibit such dangerous and harmful toys from entering the campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[It is rumored on the Internet that Wei Dongyi was fired, Peking University refutes the rumor]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently , information about the dismissal of Wei Dongyi, assistant professor at Peking University, circulated online. On November 1, China News Network sought verification from the School of Mathematical Sciences of Peking University, where Wei Dongyi works, for the above information. A staff member of the General Affairs Office of the school said that Wei Dongyi is still employed. A staff member of the Publicity Office of the college said, &quot;We have not received any news of any changes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, on the official website of the Department of Mathematics, School of Mathematical Sciences, Peking University, the name Wei Dong is still listed in the column of &quot;All Faculty&quot; Yi&#39;s resume information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ The Xinjiang Pilot Free Trade Zone was established]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2023, China’s 22nd pilot free trade zone, the Xinjiang Pilot Free Trade Zone, was established, becoming China’s first free trade zone in the northwest The first free trade pilot zone established in border areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Kunming: Cancel sales and purchase restrictions on commercial housing]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&quot;Kunming &quot;Release&quot; news shows that on November 2, the official website of the Kunming Municipal Government issued the &quot;Notice of the Office of the Kunming Municipal People&#39;s Government on the Abolition of a Group of Real Estate Policy Documents&quot;, deciding to abolish the relevant real estate policies issued in 2017 and 2018, which means that the relevant real estate policies issued in the past All sales and purchase restrictions on commercial housing have been cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Changchun three-child child care subsidy plan launched: local household registration required, one-time subsidy of 10,000 yuan]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to news recently announced on the Changchun Municipal Government website, families where couples legally have three or more children will receive a one-time subsidy of 10,000 yuan per child. The conditions are: both husband and wife have permanent residence in Changchun City (including one spouse has a permanent residence in Changchun City and the other is an active military member, or both spouses are active military personnel). From the date of issuance of this plan (i.e. October 25), it is legal. Families that have three or more children and have settled in this city must have completed birth registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&amp;nbsp ; Lou Yangsheng: Today’s Henan attaches more importance to innovation than ever before and is more hungry for talents than ever before]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, at the 6th China·Henan At the opening ceremony of the Talent Recruitment, Innovation and Development Conference and the Third China·Henan Open Innovation and Transnational Technology Transfer Conference, Lou Yangsheng, Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, delivered a speech: &quot;Henan is an important birthplace of the Chinese nation and Chinese civilization, with outstanding people since ancient times. , Talents are emerging in large numbers, inventions and creations are gleaming, and respecting talents and loving them has become a common practice.&quot; &quot;Today&#39;s Henan attaches more importance to innovation than ever before and is hungry for talents more than ever before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from Xinhua News Agency, CCTV News, Shangguan News, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, the &quot;Kunming Release&quot; WeChat public account, CCTV, China News Service, Guangzhou Daily client, The Paper, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃货文人”梁实秋丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:31:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男性没有情绪价值需要”是偏见：互相取暖才能行稳致远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among the many values ​​that one person can provide to another person, emotional value is the most embodying &quot;interactivity&quot; &quot;A kind of. If two people interact and lose the &quot;reciprocity&quot; of emotional value, and the emotional value only becomes the supply of one party, it must mean that the power and status between the two people are not equal, and the person in the lower position needs to pay attention to the person in the upper position. Continuously provide emotional value, the so-called &quot;lower and smaller&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relationship between the sexes should generally be an equal relationship. Respecting each other and pleasing each other is a normal relationship. In this sense, men&#39;s need for emotional value is often ignored, which is an unavoidable issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger said that men actually need emotional value very much. He mentioned a typical example: an old man on the Internet complained on Weibo, talking about his mid-life crisis and his emotional breakdown. For a moment. This old man on the Internet usually appears as a &quot;friend of women&quot;, so he has accumulated a certain number of female fans. As a result, when he started to complain, he did not gain sympathy and comfort from his female fans, even though he usually provided emotional value to his female fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger lamented: Some women seem to truly believe that men must be very happy and should not complain. And they themselves complain all the time. Even if they look very happy to outsiders many times, they can always find something to complain about. These women seem to have a collective consciousness, &quot;You must never let men feel happiness, and you must never let men gain emotional value. As for why, I can&#39;t understand it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very close to my heart. Of course, there are always many examples of couples treating each other as guests or pleasing each other. However, according to my observation, men are always more likely to be frustrated in the process of obtaining emotional value from women. It is this kind of frustration that Fang Hongjian encounters in his wife in &quot;Fortress Besieged&quot;. Before getting married, the relationship between the two was okay, and Sun Roujia gave him a special kind of psychological satisfaction in the face of adversity. But after marriage, Sun Roujia seems to have changed into a different person, which makes readers feel a little incredible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blogger believes that men and women are not all interested in sex. If a woman talks about her emotional value every day and tries to squeeze her to the limit, any man with some self-respect will eventually leave - for example, Fang Hongjian had this intention. Of course, there are different ways to leave. Many men find that &quot;the emotional value that women cannot give, brothers can give, games can give, and even fishing can give.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very &quot;straight man&quot; statement. It not only explains why there are many &quot;fishing guys&quot; gathering at the nightclub by the river in front of my house all day long, but also explains why some middle-aged men The reason why they always play some games or wait quietly downstairs for a while before going home after work: they know that there are endless complaints and endless mental wear and tear inside the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is, as the blogger said: In the past many years, men’s demand for emotional value has been suppressed. So many women think that men only need to pay. The reason why this kind of abnormal relationship can barely be maintained is because a kind of ideological stamp called &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; restrains men - whether it is to society or to the family. Traditional thoughts and values ​​tell men that you must get married and have this baby. And should suffer for it to be sucked out of any value including happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These words must have hit the hearts of many men who cannot feel happy in their marriages. Many ladies often say that they need to find someone who is &quot;emotionally stable&quot; to get married. Why? The main reason for this choice is probably not only to eliminate those men who are emotionally unstable and like to get angry, but in a deeper and more practical situation, to allow &quot;emotionally stable&quot; men to work hard for the family and regard endurance as the highest pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, as a human being, who should be emotionally stable more than whom? This is clearly a false proposition. Emotional stability is always relative. No one is born with an &quot;emotionally stable&quot; person, and there is never any instability - if such a person exists, it must be made of plastic and steel. It is worth noting that when this requirement becomes a matter of course, it will inevitably lead to the emergence of unfair situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why get married? I&#39;m afraid everyone has their own ideas, but in general, it&#39;s nothing more than these points: continue to write about love, get stable sex, and raise children. When it comes to responsibilities after marriage, in most cases, men often become the main or even the only source of income for the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The twists and turns in the marriage of Fu Seoul and Lao Liu fully demonstrate that emotional value is affected by family economic relations. Once a man takes care of his children at home, the outcome is often not optimistic. Because society has different tolerances for stay-at-home wives and stay-at-home husbands, if a man wants to maintain his dignity and not be discriminated against or feel cowardly, he can only try his best to earn as much money as possible - preferably more than his wife. After all, a man who wanders around the world is more likely to be looked down upon by public opinion than a woman who only takes care of her children at home, and may even be regarded as a &quot;good-for-nothing waste.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It stands to reason that under the male-domestic model, men have great hope of gaining emotional value in the family. But interestingly, the theoretical connotations are often broken in reality. Some men work so hard outside that when they get home they are told that they only know how to play games but don&#39;t know how to do housework. It is sometimes labeled &quot;widowed parenting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, the so-called emotional value is &quot;coaxing&quot;. When a woman feels sad, a man will coax her, and vice versa. If men are always forcibly given a &quot;strong&quot; and &quot;rigid&quot; persona, and are made into a character insulated from emotional value, and they blindly give in a wider range; or in other words, men must take care of women&#39;s emotions, in contrast, It won&#39;t work if you come over. Even if the man has troubles that he can only solve on his own, then the relationship will change and the emotional foundation of sharing weal and woe will be lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t men have emotional needs, or shouldn’t they seek emotional help? Of course not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the issue of emotional value, men and women should be equal. Acknowledging that men and women alike have emotional value needs and giving them respect and care is the normal way of getting along. Based on this, caring for each other and solving each other&#39;s problems is the way to balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A family must not become a quagmire where one party enjoys absolute power and the other party can only make concessions. No one would be willing to marry a slave or a &quot;slave owner&quot;, so both men and women hope that their rights and spirit will be respected by the other party, and refuse to kneel down and make endless unilateral contributions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current marriage rate is plummeting, the divorce rate is rising, and the number of unmarried people is increasing. To a certain extent, it shows that young people have a more rational and strict examination of the connotation of &quot;home&quot;, and thus take the initiative to make their own The body and mind escape from an invisible shackles. This cold fact tells us that marriage and family are &quot;non-material&quot; subjects that two people manage together with love and sincerity. If we want to make marriage and family last longer, and if we want everyone to have more confidence in marriage and family, we must treat the emotional needs of both parties fairly, create a loving and reciprocal relationship, and especially abandon the prejudice that &quot;men have no emotional value needs&quot; , so that each other can maintain the consciousness of understanding and tolerating each other to the greatest extent, and only by providing warmth to each other can we move forward steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戛纳金棕榈获奖影片，一场对亲密关系的审判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcO ZC4eqXITmA884bPF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie, after the husband fell to his death from a building, the court began a trial to determine whether it was murder or suicide. , while also unveiling an analysis of family relationships. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a cabin under the French Alps, an interview is taking place. The female writer seems to be good at avoiding questions, and once turned into the guest and became the questioner. The young reporter sitting opposite her seemed a little overwhelmed and had no choice but to follow her wishes and start chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly, the music played by the writer&#39;s husband came from upstairs, which was deafening, and his dissatisfaction was obvious. The interview was terminated and the female reporter left. Shortly after she left, the writer&#39;s husband was found dead in the snow outside the cabin by their son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, who is the murderer? According to previous suspense narrative strategies, the plot always has to go through multiple reversals before the truth comes to light. The film &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot;, which just won the Palme d&#39;Or at the Cannes Film Festival in 2023, provides another solution. Director Justine Trier does not seem to care whether the plot is reversed, and it does not even matter who the murderer is. unimportant. Putting aside the cloak of suspense, Trier is more interested in how people use their own narratives to complete the analysis of a death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film cleverly sets up the court trial, so that the intimate relationships that should be in the private realm are laid bare and presented to the public. One party wants to prove murder, and the other wants to prove her innocence by proving that her husband committed suicide. Both parties are trying to use their own narratives to get closer to the truth, and all clues may become evidence in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novelist, Sandler Voight&#39;s writing has become the object of scrutiny by the prosecution. &quot;Her life is in the book, especially her relationships.&quot; In the novel, the wife&#39;s disgust for her husband, the possibility of her husband&#39;s death, and the imagination of how to kill are all understood as reflections of the real motivations for killing. Under this kind of scrutiny, the narratives in the book are no longer complete. They are cut into fragments or even sentences, and then the narrative is reconstructed using human will to connect it with reality in the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the key pieces of evidence in the film is the recording of her husband Samuel before his death. Samuel is a former teacher who also enjoys writing. Out of guilt for being partially responsible for his son Daniel&#39;s permanent vision impairment, Samuel spent a great deal of his time on various family matters and on Daniel&#39;s company. He seemed unapologetic and willing, but the recording revealed another side of the family&#39;s close relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recording, Samuel asked his wife to reconsider the division of labor in the family, believing that he had sacrificed too much personal time on family affairs and that he wanted more time to write. After listening, Sandler mocked him coldly, saying that a writer would not stop writing just because he had children and housework. No one forced him, and he did not owe him anything. The director seemed to have intentionally reversed the genders. What Samuel experienced was actually the helpless and struggling situation of many women in married relationships in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the dispute between the two in the recording became more intense. Sandler&#39;s bisexual identity, cheating and other private information were revealed one by one from Samuel&#39;s mouth, and fell into the ears of everyone in the trial. In the view of the prosecution, these are the motives and reasons for the unbalanced relationship between husband and wife and the wife to murder her husband. Here, the recording, which originally only recorded a certain dimension of the relationship between people, is also used to refer to the whole picture, helping the prosecution complete the deduction and reconstruction of the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandler attempted to deny this ever-reconstructed narrative, telling Samuel&#39;s psychiatrist, who was one of the witnesses, &quot;You&#39;re only telling a small part of the whole situation. A pair of Husband and wife are like a mess...&quot; She believed that this did not prove that she was the murderer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradox is that Sandler himself is also consciously or unconsciously self-narrating the truth, including her husband&#39;s unusual behavior in taking medicine six months before his death, seeing a psychiatrist, and being depressed in writing, etc. , all became her reconstruction of the reasons for his suicide during the defense process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the evidence fragments presented by both the prosecution and the defense are real, perhaps no one dares to confirm that the suicide or homicide story reconstructed based on these fragments is the truth itself. As director Justine Trier said, &quot;This is very modern, this is how we live today. In the trial, various things change and are given extra weight, resulting in new fictions.&quot; &quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evidence was not only presented in front of the prosecution and defense, but also slowly unfolded in front of his son Daniel, who also began to look at his parents again. At first, he had no doubts about his mother, but as the two sides narrated at the trial, his attitude gradually became swaying, and he even had an image in his mind of his mother hitting his father hard and pushing him downstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, he also tried to give medicine to the dog to verify the fact that his mother said that his father had vomited after taking medicine. He also recalled the conversation his father had with him when he sent the dog to the doctor. He thought This revealed his father&#39;s suicidal tendencies. From various swings to his own selection of factual fragments after review, Daniel finally constructed his own narrative version of the truth in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A still from &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; (also translated as &quot;Judgment of a Fall&quot;). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier once mentioned in an interview, &quot;These trials have a profound impact on people.&quot; It&#39;s a nightmare to say because your own life is being taken away from you. Everyone is creating a fiction and not really trying to get to the truth. I&#39;m very fascinated by truth and trying to find it through stories and I find that very interesting .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the director also wants to draw the audience into the search for the truth and the construction of the narrative. Under the shell of suspense, we as the audience have naturally been thinking about who the murderer is since Samuel fell from the building. In the battle between the prosecution and the defense, every time they list new evidence, make new statements and excuses, we, like Daniel, can&#39;t help but turn our eyes to Samuel and Sandler, trying to learn from the evidence provided by both sides. Find your own narrative from factual evidence and their narratives to deduce the truth of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But outside the film, we are more passive. All narratives are always based on the characters&#39; interpretation of the truth in the film, which also means that our perception of the truth is more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film ends with Sandler being found not guilty. Since there are elements of fiction on both sides, why does one narrative prevail over the other? Perhaps it was the emotional power of it - Daniel&#39;s monologue about his father moved the judge and helped his mother win. After Sandler came home, Daniel hugged and kissed her. In the silence of the room, a rare warmth lingered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this the truth? Not really. In the previous narratives from all parties, the director has successfully planted the seeds of doubt in the hearts of the audience. Even if Sandler was found not guilty, people&#39;s hesitation and uncertainty about the truth have not disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandra Wheeler, who plays the heroine, once asked the director about the script, whether her character was guilty or innocent. Trier told her, &quot;I don&#39;t know, but I hope You act as if she is innocent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She could be responsible but not guilty, or she could be guilty but not responsible. She could be responsible for driving him to suicide but not guilty of killing him, or she could be guilty of killing him without wanting to. to kill him - either in an impulsive way or in a way that we can try to imagine. The truth is there, but it is too complex to grasp here.&quot; Director Justine Trier said in Said this in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But looking back, the truth may no longer be important. Fiction is a human talent. As long as you are willing, you can construct your own narrative with the help of a few keywords. However, if the relationships between people are like this death, being scrutinized and reconstructed, then in fact, no relationship can withstand such rigorous and detailed analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚太安全专家谈：中国发展红利被周边国家共享]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the end of the Cold War, despite some geopolitical tensions or regional hot issues, the Asia-Pacific region has still maintained peace Stablize. In Europe and the Middle East, wars broke out one after another. How to interpret such an international situation? Why has the Asia-Pacific region been able to maintain peace and stability for decades? How to continue to maintain a prosperous and stable Asia-Pacific? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 29, 2023, at the &quot;Dialogue of Chinese and Foreign Experts&quot; at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, former vice minister of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the People&#39;s Republic of China and founder of the Tsinghua Institute for International Security Strategy, said at the meeting that after the Cold War, the Asia-Pacific region seized the opportunity, quickly opened up to the outside world, and quickly entered regional integration. In the past few decades, there have been no major wars, political conflicts, or major social unrest in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Asia-Pacific region has enjoyed peaceful development for more than 40 years. In this process, China has played a central role. The dividends of China&#39;s rapid regional development have been shared by neighboring countries. China is also the largest international player in most Asia-Pacific countries. trading partner country,&quot; Fu Ying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 29, 2023, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining Asia-Pacific security.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 29, 2023 , many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on topics such as &quot;China&#39;s role in maintaining security in the Asia-Pacific.&quot; (Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Economic Development Miracle&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t know if you remember that in the 1980s (of the last century), when the Asia-Pacific region began multilateral cooperation, China also joined the regional integration At the time of globalization, many countries are still walking on the edge of development and poverty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying said in her speech that over the past long period of time, the Asia-Pacific region has achieved extremely rapid economic development, surpassing There are many countries and regions in the market. Citing data from the Bank of Asia, she said that in the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown sevenfold. This phenomenon is also called the &quot;economic development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying believes that peace and stability, regional focus on cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization are important reasons for the economic development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the unique driving forces behind decades of stability and security in the Asia-Pacific region? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In order to maintain long-term stability and security in the Asia-Pacific, we need to discover a unique &#39;Asia-Pacific model.&#39;&quot; Chen Dongxiao, president of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, said that &quot;open regionalism&quot; is an important driving factor , and this concept contains many contents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;First of all, economic development cooperation is the focus. It transcends ideologies and government differences. Secondly, under regional openness, no matter big or small, all countries need to abide by relevant rules and regulations and should Follow social rules in an equal way. It is very important that we should not have double standards,&quot; said Chen Dongxiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast to the peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region, wars have been raging in Europe and the Middle East in recent years. During the forum discussion, two European and American scholars also expressed their thoughts on the &quot;differences between China and the West.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Why is the Asia-Pacific region different from Europe? There are many reasons behind it.” Michael Swain, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs in the United States, believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergei Karaganov, dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics, agreed with Shi Wen’s point of view, saying that “it is still in the early stages and we still have to remain cautious.” . At the same time, he also emphasized the &quot;cultural factors&quot; in Europe that were different from Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;European history is filled with many wars. European peace or war is always closely related to Europe&#39;s internal problems.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The risks of U.S. leadership are growing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As for the role of the United States in Asia-Pacific security, Huang Jae-ho, director of the Center for International Studies at Hankuk University of Foreign Studies, said, &quot;Although there is no perfect leadership in the world ( model), but the risks of U.S. leadership are growing.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the U.S. policy toward China as an example, he said that from the Trump administration to the current Biden administration, the United States has undergone many changes in overall strategy and economic details. &quot;The United States has not seen the overall situation clearly, and its strategies and tactics are unclear. Therefore, the United States lacks a consistent vision and policy, which has caused instability in the current international order.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs, mentioned in his speech that &quot;China&#39;s ultimate security role in Asia is still uncertain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying directly refuted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t quite agree with this type of view. Mr. Michael Sven&#39;s logic is very confusing.&quot; Fu Ying said that China has actively promoted economic development in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited a lot from it. . This &quot;unconvincing&quot; logic probably originates from the theory of power change in the international community for hundreds of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, you know that China’s development background is completely different.” She said that there are big differences between China and the United States. But it does not affect China and the United States in pursuing their own development and supporting and benefiting from each other. If you think that China&#39;s strength has become a &quot;threat&quot; in the Asia-Pacific region, how should you view the rise of emerging countries such as India and Indonesia in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying also pointed out that the United States is currently anxious about its declining global influence, but this is not a problem caused by China, but the result of &quot;economic globalization and the United States itself making too many mistakes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The United States&#39; own problems make it difficult. Look at what benefits the United States has gained from the trade war? The trade war has caused the U.S.-China trade deficit to continue to increase, but has it reduced China&#39;s exports to the United States? In fact, it is not, on the contrary, the data is still increasing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She proposed that the United States should be an active contributor to the development of the region, rather than trying to use competition to prioritize and define the region&#39;s agenda and &quot;hijack&quot; A long-term agenda for successful cooperation, dialogue and economic development in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Finding balance and crisis management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In their speeches, many scholars unanimously stated that the old balance in the international order may be broken and new changes are about to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sergey Karaganov said that as the United States and Western society began to exert influence to change globalization, the so-called era of globalization has ended. He said that we must have a new theory or a new global governance model, and this model must be decided by all partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For so many years, we have been saying that we want to achieve a win-win situation and that we want to benefit all parties involved. But unfortunately, we do not live in an ideal world. Sometimes we need to be shocked and we need to and reach a balance with different countries,” Sergey Karaganov said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Michael Swan said that any international system must balance the needs of different countries and cooperate after balancing. (Countries) need to seek common interests, have the same demands for economic development, and whether there are the same issues left over from history that need to be resolved, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He insisted that the current uncertainty still exists between countries and cannot be controlled. Countries large and small will be affected by changes in power, and there will undoubtedly be uncertainty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It cannot be said that China believes that all countries are unified and we can do this. It cannot solve many basic problems. Moreover, this is not caused by the United States, but due to structural changes. Yes, it will also trigger changes in the international order.&quot; Shi Wen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to maintain security and peace in the Asia-Pacific region before the new international order is formed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao proposed the &quot;three no&#39;s&quot; principle - that is, not to divide the group camp, not to initiate military war, especially nuclear war, and not to use double standards. &quot;In the past few years, the Chinese government has repeatedly reiterated on many occasions that war is not a good way to deal with differences between countries. On the contrary, it brings more crises.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Dongxiao believes that Sino-US relations are an important factor in regional security. At the same time, the role of small countries in the Asia-Pacific region cannot be ignored, and they should not be divided into any faction. &quot;Some neutral countries, such as ASEAN countries, can play an important role in dealing with differences and achieving related cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Zaihao pointed out that compared with other regions, the Asia-Pacific region is relatively stable and China and the United States can maintain a relative balance. There are currently outside voices claiming that China and the United States have entered a &quot;new Cold War,&quot; but he believes this is more like a &quot;complex competition.&quot; Moreover, the two major countries have now begun crisis management and set up communication channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“However, there is no war now, only fighting, so it can still be controlled.” Huang Zaihao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九名市州长“进京检讨”：自然资源部组建以来首次高规格集中、公开约谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259895]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZylf9D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZ ylf9D. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, at the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, there were still flowers placed on the edge of the land Potted plants for sale. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Li Gui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the largest fresh cut flower trading market in Asia, Dounan Flower Market in Kunming City, Yunnan Province It is crowded all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the north side of Dounan Flower Market, across the road is another flower-related market - Yinlian Potted Flower Market. Unlike Dounan, which mainly sells fresh cut flowers, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market, built in 2012, sells mostly green plants and potted plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, there was a potted flower market where various seedlings and succulents were grown in the greenhouses, and now some vegetables are also grown there. This has to do with natural resource inspectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 15, 2023, on Funei Street in Beijing, the Ministry of Natural Resources reported on the main violations of laws and regulations discovered during routine inspections in 2023. Among them, the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Yinlian Potted Flower Market was named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to reporting on typical issues, the Ministry of Natural Resources also held an interview meeting: Entrusted by the Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, Chen Chenzhao, the full-time Deputy Chief Inspector of National Natural Resources, reviewed the violations of laws and regulations discovered by the inspectors in 2023. The main leaders of 9 municipal (state) governments held face-to-face interviews when the problem was highlighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nine cities (states) are Shijiazhuang City in Hebei Province, Harbin City in Heilongjiang Province, Wenzhou City in Zhejiang Province, Chuzhou City in Anhui Province, Linyi City in Shandong Province, Hechi City in Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, and Qianxinan Guizhou Province in Guizhou Province. Prefecture, Kunming City, Yunnan Province, and Lanzhou City, Gansu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the mayors of the cities (prefectures) who represented these cities (states) in the interviews, the deputy secretaries-general of the provincial (autonomous region) governments where these cities and states are located, and the &quot;top leaders of the natural resources departments at the provincial and municipal levels&quot; ” was also asked to attend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published by the Office of the General Inspector of Natural Resources stated that the interview was to “face-to-face point out the outstanding problems discovered by the inspector, urge the local government to increase rectification and investigation efforts, resolutely curb illegal activities on farmland, and firmly guard the Cultivated land protection red line”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first large-scale, high-level centralized and public interview held by the Ministry of Natural Resources since its establishment in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;Illegal occupation of cultivated land&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;77 acres&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Enter from Gate 1 of Yinlian Potted Flower Market , the first thing that comes into view are various shops with the words &quot;flowers&quot;, &quot;seedlings&quot; and &quot;horticulture&quot; printed on them. In October, osmanthus, bougainvillea and various camellias are still in bloom at the entrance of some shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of these shops exist in the form of greenhouses: the open air outside the house and the roof made of transparent film are covered with a black sunshade net; there are few cement and ceramic tiles on the floor inside the house, and most of them are smoothed. Yellow soil - the flower pots with plants are placed on the ground, and the roots come out from the bottom of the pot. The soil will provide them with moisture and nutrients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Go northwest along the main road for about 300 meters. The shops, greenhouses and sunshade nets have all disappeared, and both sides of the road have become empty and open spaces. There were many bulging white woven bags lying on the open ground. The word &quot;feed&quot; was printed on the outside of the bags. You could smell the stench of feces if you got close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers wearing sun hats tore open the bags and spread the black fertilizer on the yellow mud ground, and someone else opened it with a hoe. An excavator in the distance was working in another open space, and there was a rumbling sound. If it weren&#39;t for being in a city, the scene here would look no different from autumn sowing in the countryside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before it became a vacant lot, it was also a greenhouse selling green plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About a month ago, in September 2023, the greenhouse was demolished after an inspection by leaders of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City. On October 25, 2023, a greenhouse owner who once opened a shop here said that before the shed was demolished, he moved to the current greenhouse in August 2023. The two places are about 500 meters apart, and both are managed by Yinlian Community The established Kunming Qiding Economic and Trade Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Kunming Qiding) is responsible for leasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greenhouse owner said that although the lease contract between the two parties was signed once a year, he had been operating the original greenhouse for nearly ten years. Talking about the reason for moving the store, he thought it was &quot;policy adjustment&quot;: &quot;That piece of land was not approved for commercial use at the time, so it was demolished.&quot; When signing the contract, Kunming Geding &quot;wasn&#39;t sure&quot; about the nature of the land. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, in a notification from the Ministry of Natural Resources, the aforementioned open land was classified as cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that in February 2019, the Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Chenggong District, Kunming City was included in the scope of rectification of the &quot;big shed house&quot; problem and passed the rectification acceptance; in July 2022, the Yinlian Community will have been reclaimed The agricultural greenhouses were rented to 76 merchants for selling potted flowers, agricultural supplies, pesticides and other business activities, illegally occupying 77 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strictly speaking, the focus of the &quot;big shed house&quot; issue is not the form of building the house, but the nature of the land where the house is built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Agricultural Engineering Technology&quot; magazine, which is under the supervision of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, once explained in an article that the &quot;big shed&quot; problem refers to the illegal construction of agricultural facilities or agricultural parks by some industrial and commercial enterprises, individuals and organizations. The essence of illegally occupying cultivated land or even permanent basic farmland for non-agricultural construction is to change the nature and use of the land, change the agricultural production function, and touch the red line of cultivated land protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Information released by the WeChat public account of the &quot;Chenggong District Natural Resources Bureau&quot; shows that in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Supervision inspected the cleanup and rectification of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Kunming City in 2019. It was found that two cases involving the rebound of &quot;greenhouses&quot; in Chenggong District were involved, one of which was the Yinlian Potted Flower Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, a staff member of the Chenggong Branch of the Kunming Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;responsibility for rectification of the &quot;greenhouse&quot; problem involved lies with the street, and he can report it to the Street to understand the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yinlian Potted Flower Market is located in Dounan Street. On October 25, 2023, a person in charge of the Dounan Street Office said: “(The contents in the shed) were vacated before, but last year due to the epidemic and villages were demolished, some green plants for sale were placed in the shed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the street said that during the inspection in May 2023, the Chengdu Bureau of National Natural Resources Inspection pointed out the existence of Question: &quot;According to the (inspector&#39;s) requirements, it is required to see loess inside the shed, but if there are things on the soil, it is considered a violation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Chenggong District Natural Resources The Planning Branch and the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau jointly issued notices ordering rectification of illegal acts and time-limited rectification notices to multiple land users. The person in charge of the aforementioned street stated that in accordance with the requirements of the rectification notice, they need to &quot;restore the problematic greenhouse to the state of 2019&quot; before the end of September 2023, that is, empty the contents of the shed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the specific implementation stage, the rectification requirements have been repeatedly refined. The person in charge of the street remembered that in June 2023, after the things in the shed were vacated, the soil was also loosened, but the relevant departments “will put forward different requirements for every different inspection.” “So we have repeatedly asked, and today we have to Remove the house number, and tomorrow I will tell you that there is still an advertisement on the door and I want to remove it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of August 2023, only the empty shell of the greenhouse remained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Jing (second from left), Secretary of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City, is at the rectification work site of the &quot;greenhouse&quot; at Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Dounan Street. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(&quot;Chenggong Release&quot; WeChat public account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Multiple common issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nearly a month after the greenhouse was vacated, on the afternoon of September 15, 2023, 9 cities (states) including Kunming were interviewed by the Ministry of Natural Resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Natural Resources has 9 local natural resource inspection bureaus in Beijing, Shenyang, Shanghai, Nanjing, Jinan, Guangzhou, Wuhan, Chengdu, and Xi&#39;an. At the interview meeting, the directors of the nine local inspection bureaus reported the violations of laws and regulations discovered by the inspectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The information disclosed on the official website of the Ministry of Natural Resources shows that the inspection found that the responsibilities for protecting cultivated land in some areas have not been implemented in place, and prominent problems that hit the red line such as &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grain conversion&quot; of cultivated land still exist. Non-agricultural construction problems such as parks, development zones, and urban municipal roads without approval are more prominent. The problem of illegal occupation of permanent basic farmland and general farmland for turf planting exists in some provinces to varying degrees. The problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; continues to be prohibited and illegal. The problem of occupying farmland, digging lakes and landscaping still occurs in some places. In some places, minerals are illegally approved and illegal mining violates the ecological protection red line control requirements and seriously damages the ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The briefing disclosed more details. Taken together, the number of illegal land use problems in the nine cities (states) interviewed ranked high in the provinces where they are located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Shijiazhuang, Harbin, Wenzhou, Chuzhou and Lanzhou &quot;ranked first in the province&quot; for problems with laws and regulations, Linyi and Guizhou Qianxinan Prefecture &quot;ranked first in the province&quot;, and Kunming &quot;ranked first in terms of the number of problems&quot; Ranking first in the province and second in the province in terms of cultivated land area.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, this inspection also found a number of common problems in many cities. Such as the &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grainization&quot; of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that there are 51 &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Harbin, involving 900.68 acres of cultivated land; there are 111 &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Linyi, involving 1,065.56 acres of cultivated land; and there are &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; problems in Hechi. 150, involving 2,629.55 acres of cultivated land; 207 &quot;non-agricultural&quot; problems exist in Qianxinan Prefecture, occupying 1,649.65 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specific manifestations of the &quot;de-agriculturalization&quot; of cultivated land include the problem of &quot;greenhouse houses&quot;, the indiscriminate occupation of cultivated land to build houses in rural areas, and the construction of some engineering projects and infrastructure without approval. Not only in Kunming, but also in Harbin, Wenzhou, and Hechi, the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; has appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, among the 9 cities (states) notified, 6 places including Shijiazhuang, Harbin, Chuzhou, Linyi, Qianxinan Prefecture, and Lanzhou all have illegal mining problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wuchang City, which is managed by Harbin, failed to supervise the illegal mining of granite for construction by Yingze Sand and Stone Co., Ltd. from January 2022 to May 2023, and failed to promptly file a case to investigate and stop it. Reporting illegal mining activities as &quot;false changes&quot; and reporting false information should be subject to inspection. Harbin City has failed to supervise Wuchang City’s untruthful reporting practices, and the audit control is not strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 9 cities (states), Wenzhou, Zhejiang is the only city that has been notified of &quot;continuous frequent petitions in the field of natural resources.&quot; The report shows that since 2021, Wenzhou has been ranking high in the province in terms of the number of petitions in the field of natural resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rectification outside the meeting&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the director of the local inspection bureau reported the violations of laws and regulations in 9 cities (states), the city (state) chiefs spoke separately , &quot;State your position one by one.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Voice of China report, Kunming Mayor Liu Jiachen said that the problem of &quot;non-agriculturalization&quot; and &quot;non-grainification&quot; of cultivated land in Kunming is very prominent, and he &quot;feels deeply self-blame and guilt&quot; for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the speech session, many mayors also said that some problems have been rectified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the problem that the Lai’an County Government in Chuzhou City illegally acquired land for the construction of the supporting landscape water system for the Jinling Water Town Project and occupied 400.4 acres of cultivated land to dig out lakes and landscape, Wu Jin, mayor of Chuzhou City, said that the Lai’an County Government The key issues of the illegal land acquisition to build the supporting landscape water system of the Jinling Water Town Project have been rectified and reclaimed in place on June 30, 2023. They have been upgraded in accordance with the requirements of &quot;concurrent personnel management&quot; and handed over to the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision for accountability. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, several city (state) mayors held meetings to deploy relevant work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, September 17, 2023, Hechi Mayor Wang Jun presided over a government executive meeting, demanding that the bottom line of farmland protection and food security be resolutely maintained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, Wenzhou Mayor Zhang Zhenfeng emphasized at the city&#39;s farmland protection and food security work conference that we must tackle the rectification of problems reported by inspections and follow &quot;one problem, one plan, and closed-loop promotion to the end.&quot; According to the requirements, we will formulate targeted rectification plans, promote the elimination of problem accounts within a time limit, and simultaneously carry out &quot;look back&quot; on rectified problems and draw inferences from one example to make rectifications of the same standard and quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Kunming held a city-wide rectification meeting on illegal land use and farmland outflow. Kunming Municipal Party Committee Secretary Liu Hongjian presided over the meeting and delivered a speech. Mayor Liu Jiachen conveyed the spirit of the Ministry of Natural Resources’ centralized open interview meeting. At the meeting, the Kunming Municipal Natural Resources Planning Bureau reported on the city’s rectification of illegal land use and farmland outflow issues and made a review speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five days later, on September 23, 2023, Chen Jing, secretary of the Chenggong District Committee of Kunming City, led a team to conduct an on-site investigation on the rectification of &quot;greenhouses&quot; and the rectification of farmland outflow problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published on the WeChat public account of &quot;Chenggong Release&quot; shows that at the rectification work site of the &quot;greenhouses&quot; in the Yinlian Potted Flower Market in Dounan Street, Chen Jing learned in detail about the overall rectification work of the &quot;greenhouses&quot; in the district situation, work progress and existing difficulties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the article published by &quot;Chenggong Release&quot;, there is a photo of Chen Jing standing in a greenhouse. Behind him is the greenhouse that has been demolished to only its frame. Shortly after Chen Jing&#39;s investigation, the frame of the greenhouse was also demolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of Dounan Street mentioned above said that they had already made plans to dismantle the greenhouses before, “mainly some details and standards (not yet determined), which were formulated just after the leaders arrived. We It was rectified quickly and thoroughly.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about the reason for demolishing the greenhouse, the person in charge said that it was to avoid the problem from recurring again. &quot;If the shed is still there, whoever moves the things in next time will say (there is a problem) during the inspection.&quot; He explained, &quot;In the end, we have done the work of the community and the masses, just to make it one-time The renovation is in place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the land where the potted flower market was located was managed by Yinlian Community. After the problem of &quot;big sheds&quot; rebounded, due to &quot;inadequate community supervision&quot;, more than 70 acres of land have now been returned to the streets. Now, the land planted in the place where the greenhouse was demolished is a third-party company commissioned by the street. The person in charge added: &quot;Our street cadres don&#39;t know how to farm and have a lot of work, so we currently entrust a third party to complete the planting task first, and then discuss the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The street person in charge also It said that in May 2023, after it was discovered that the problem of &quot;greenhouses&quot; had rebounded, relevant street officials were also transferred from their original posts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height= &quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256896&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, workers were handling the fertilizer shipped in the Yinlian Potted Flower Market. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Li Gui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Core functions are still related to land&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Natural Resources interviews the person in charge of the prefectural and municipal governments, which is related to the inspection of natural resources. This is one of the forms of administrative supervision of lower-level governments by higher-level governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Land Inspectorate is the predecessor of the National Natural Resources Inspectorate. In order to curb land violations and implement farmland protection, the State Council formally introduced a land inspection system in 2006. The main inspection targets are provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government, and municipal governments under separate state planning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2018, the Ministry of Natural Resources was established. &quot;With the transformation of natural resource management functions and in order to adapt to the needs of natural resource management,&quot; the National Land Inspectorate was transformed into the National Natural Resources Inspectorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2019, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Regulations on the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Supervision&quot;, which clarified the institutional composition, procedural specifications, and procedures of the central ecological and environmental protection supervision in the form of intra-party regulations. In terms of authority and responsibilities, a two-level inspection system at the central and provincial levels has also been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Chen Haisong, a professor at the Institute of Environmental Law of Wuhan University, even though the Ministry of Natural Resources has integrated the functions of multiple departments, land-related functions are still the core. “The core of natural resources is land resources,” Chen Haisong said. Therefore, natural resource inspections should focus on the most mature land inspection business and continue to develop in depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Implementation Regulations of the Land Management Law&quot; that came into effect on September 1, 2021 clarified the scope and working methods of natural resource inspection for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The regulations stipulate that the national natural resources inspection agency shall, according to the authorization, monitor the protection of cultivated land, the economical and intensive use of land, and the preparation and implementation of land spatial planning by the people&#39;s governments of provinces (autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government) and the people&#39;s governments of cities determined by the State Council. Supervise the implementation of major national decisions on land management, the implementation of land management laws and administrative regulations, and other land use and land management situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national natural resources inspection agency may also interview the relevant person in charge of the local people&#39;s government under supervision, and may make recommendations to the supervisory authority, appointment and dismissal authority and other relevant authorities in accordance with the law on holding the relevant responsible persons accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike this time when nine city (prefecture) governors were called to Beijing for interviews, most of the interviews conducted by the national natural resources inspection agency were conducted locally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October to November 2022, the national natural resources inspection agency conducted on-site inspections of cultivated land protection and mineral resources in 31 provinces (autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the Central Government) and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, and discovered some illegal and illegal issues . In response to the outstanding problems discovered by the inspectors, with the authorization of the National Natural Resources Chief Inspector, the national natural resources inspection agency stationed in the local area conducted interviews with some municipal governments that had serious violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Chengdu Bureau interviewed Dali, Yunnan, the Beijing Bureau interviewed Xingtai, Hebei, and Jinzhong, Shanxi, the Nanjing Bureau interviewed Jiujiang, Jiangxi, and the Guangzhou Bureau interviewed Qingyuan, Guangdong, and Nanning, Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Chen Haisong’s view, the profound meaning of this interview with the main person in charge of the local government in Beijing is still related to food security. “For a long time to come, the protection of cultivated land and food security will be very important. The problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the interview, Chen Chenzhao, the full-time deputy chief inspector of national natural resources, said: &quot;The task of protecting cultivated land has not been eased, but has become more difficult. Resolute and powerful measures must be taken to continue to strengthen the protection of cultivated land. Firmly hold on to the red line of 1.8 billion acres of cultivated land.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>