<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[南开段峰：“拿着金饭碗讨饭”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261413]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In June 2022, Duan Feng’s team realized the interventional brain-computer interface in the sheep brain for the first time; a year later In May 2023, led by Duan Feng&#39;s team, the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army General Hospital (301 Hospital) and Shanghai Xinwei Medical Technology Co., Ltd. jointly completed the world&#39;s first &quot;non-human primate (monkey) interventional brain-machine&quot; &quot;Interface Test&quot; was a success. This research was considered by many media to have overcome the shortcomings of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces and created the third new paradigm of brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Feng, 46, is currently a professor, doctoral supervisor at Nankai University, and director of the Tianjin Key Laboratory of Interventional Brain-Computer and Intelligent Rehabilitation. Due to Duan Feng&#39;s outstanding achievements in the fields of brain-computer interfaces, artificial hibernation and intelligent aircraft, he was selected as Southern Weekend&#39;s 2023 Scientific and Technological Person of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the Southern Weekend Science and Technology Innovation Conference&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/298bbbf676.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/298bbbf676 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the Southern Weekend Science and Technology Innovation Conference &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of the China Academy of Communications, brain-computer interface (BCI) technology is a revolutionary human-computer interaction. Its mechanism of action is to bypass peripheral nerves and muscles and directly interact with the brain. Establish a new communication and control channel with external devices, which has the effect of monitoring, replacing, improving/restoring damaged or impaired natural central nervous system output and input. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a multidisciplinary cutting-edge technology that can not only assist in the diagnosis and treatment of some neurological diseases, partially or fully realize the compensation of certain human body functions, and is even expected to cure some mental diseases. Medical care is considered to be its most promising field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three main implementation methods of brain-computer interface, non-invasive, invasive and vascular intervention. The non-invasive brain-computer interface mainly refers to the collection of EEG signals in the cerebral cortex without surgery; the invasive type requires implanting electrodes deep into the brain, requiring surgeries such as craniotomy and bone drilling; the vascular interventional type mainly involves the electrode holder. Implanted into the corresponding inner wall of blood vessels to collect EEG signals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, most research on brain-computer interfaces is in the basic research stage, and some clinical results have also been achieved. In June 2022, researchers at Johns Hopkins University completed the world&#39;s first human trial of a bilaterally implanted brain-computer interface. A subject who had been paralyzed for 30 years successfully controlled machinery through EEG signals, completing Deliver cakes and eat independently; in China, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital launched brain-computer interface and deep brain stimulation methods in 2020 to treat refractory depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the participation of star companies such as Meta and Neuralink owned by &quot;Silicon Valley Iron Man&quot; Elon Musk, attention on brain-computer interfaces has been unprecedentedly high in recent years, and Duan Feng will also establish it in 2023 The company is trying to transform the results of brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, since he returned to China after studying in Japan in 2009, he has been on the road of &quot;integration of industry, academia and research&quot; by focusing on teaching and research on one hand and entrepreneurship on the other. For this reason, he often stumbled. &quot;1 billion in 10 years, whether to do it or not&quot; has become his &quot;touchstone&quot; to test whether investors are sincere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Southern Weekend’s interview with Duan Feng:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to build an “industry-university-research integration” platform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From an academic background, you received a bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s degree from the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, and studied precision mechanical engineering at the University of Tokyo, Japan, and received a master&#39;s and doctoral degree. degree, and chose medical rehabilitation equipment to start a business. Is it because you have always been interested in machinery? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>; When I took the college entrance examination in 1998, the major I wanted to study most was actually electronics. I filled out the application form and was transferred to the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University, where I majored in internal combustion engines and obtained postgraduate qualifications in my senior year. Studying in Japan is also an accidental choice. During my master&#39;s degree, my supervisor sent me to cooperate with two engine companies. At that time, the machinery industry was in recession, and one company went bankrupt. It was very embarrassing. At that time, I thought about changing careers and prepared to study abroad. It happened that the University of Tokyo in Japan not only waived the application fee, but also provided scholarships, round-trip air tickets and accommodation. The conditions were very good, so I chose precision manufacturing related to machinery among the majors they admitted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you later turn to brain-computer interface? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I have studied intelligent service robots and unitized flexible production lines in Japan. My professional field has shifted from power machinery to robot control, and further Go to brain-computer interfaces. I first heard about the concept of brain-computer interface in a lecture at the University of Tokyo. I thought it was very interesting at the time, but I had limited energy and could not study it in depth. The biggest reason is that I want to copy Japan’s “industry-university-research” model in China. When I was studying in Japan, I encountered many companies that came to colleges and universities to invite students to dinner to identify talents, provide scholarships to students, and provide funds for scientific research projects to teachers to achieve the integration of &quot;industry, academia, and research.&quot; At that time, this model was relatively common in China. Rare. After graduation, I returned to China and entered Nankai University. After completing my teaching tasks, I could delve into the fields I was interested in, and then started to build a company to industrialize the research results. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you start your business at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I learned about the market while teaching at the university. Specifically, it is to find companies to cooperate to develop things that are urgently needed by the market but there is still half a step in technology development. At that time, a friend introduced some assistive device products in cooperation with small medical device companies, which are types that rely on external force to move the limbs, but they are not independent movements. I hope to make devices that can be independently controlled by people to drive body movements, but I don’t want to sell products because it requires a series of issues such as device registration, quality inspection, and commercial promotion, so I anchored the technology research and development on the front end of the product. When I first returned to China, my monthly salary was only 3,800 yuan. After deducting 2,000 yuan for rent and 1,500 yuan for my children’s kindergarten tuition, I only had 300 yuan for living expenses every month. I think most entrepreneurs should have more money than me. Because I had no money, I had always pinned my hopes of raising money on finding partners or investors, so I took many detours and went through a process of company registration, cancellation, re-registration, and cancellation again. Many times it was dismantled. There was a difficult period when the east wall was repairing the west wall. At first, I considered making some small rehabilitation electrical stimulation equipment. A company talked to me about cooperation and asked me to do front-end research and development. It claimed that after the product was launched, the company would have its own sales channels. I believed it, but after finishing it, I found that this was not the case. Damn, there&#39;s nothing behind it. Some companies also asked me to invest in technology and promised equity. As a result, we advanced money, spent time, and invested a lot of energy. After the technology was formed, the &quot;partner&quot; ran away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to solve the entrepreneurial start-up fund? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;I earned it by selling technology. It is to help companies develop what they need and then sell it for money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Experiencing these things, the impact on you is What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;I am also reflecting and summarizing. Whether I am doing scientific research or doing industry, I just ask myself whether this is the case. If you really want to do what you want to do without anyone&#39;s help, then just do it. When I did not place my hopes on others and relied on my own efforts and persistence to do what I wanted to do, many people who helped me came to me on their own initiative. Some brought money, some brought resources, Others brought some new concepts and ideas, and gradually the matter became a success. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Among the people who took the initiative to find &quot; Liar&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When you have experienced some &quot;stepping into pitfalls&quot;, it will be easier to evaluate people&#39;s risks. Now come and talk to me. Yes, you can tell whether it is suitable or not in just a few minutes. I will not accept investment from others casually now. When someone comes to talk to me, I usually ask a question, &quot;1 billion in 10 years, do you want to do it?&quot; If you don&#39;t want to, then don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. In my case, if it works, it works, if it doesn’t work, it doesn’t work. There is no middle ground. This 1 billion is not just a thought, it is a scientific estimate. I do vascular interventional brain-computer interface experiments. Each electrode is ground out bit by bit by hand. It takes 10 days of grinding 24 hours a day to make one. The cost of consumables, labor costs, etc. in these 10 days add up. The total cost is at least 100,000 yuan; another example is the large animal monkey used for experiments. It costs 200,000 yuan to buy a monkey and 300 yuan to raise it for a day. This cost is very high. &quot;1 billion in 10 years&quot; is only used to test whether investors have the patience and sincerity to accompany the product&#39;s growth. It does not mean that someone must spend 1 billion. If the other party does not have a basic understanding of how much time it will take, how much money it will cost, and the possible return on investment, and they come and say that they are familiar with people from a certain local government and have connections in a certain park, they will talk about it with boastful words, or they will start talking about equity without saying anything. , we need to do due diligence, these are not the partners we would choose. We prefer to cooperate with people who have feelings and ideals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No matter whether it is intrusive or non-intrusive, I am not optimistic about it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Research on brain-computer interfaces has been very hot in recent years. What are the pros and cons of invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Non-invasive brain-computer interface is relatively safe because it is non-invasive. It mainly collects nerve discharge signals that converge on the surface of the scalp. Since this signal collection must pass through the skull and layers of tissue cells, and there are many interference signals in the scalp, the collected EEG signals are not very stable. The action EEG signal is okay, but over time, or when it recognizes finer movements, it won&#39;t work. Invasive brain-computer interfaces implant electrodes into the brain by opening the skull. If you want to collect a certain signal, you need to implant electrodes into the corresponding brain area. Usually, within half a year, the signals collected through the invasive brain-computer interface are more accurate, and the effect of human-computer interaction is also better, such as controlling the robotic arm to grab objects, and the degree of completion is also relatively high. But it’s hard to tell after half a year, because the electrodes are harmful to the brain, may lead to rejection and suppuration, scar tissue can easily accumulate around the electrodes, and the circuits will also generate a certain amount of heat, which can easily cause inflammation, which is harmful to the human body. The damage is also relatively large. Therefore, its sustainability is very poor, and the EEG signals collected later will become weaker, or even no signals can be collected. This is also a fatal shortcoming of invasive brain-computer interfaces. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 2023, Neuralink’s invasive brain The machine interface has begun recruiting human clinical trial subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The intrusive approach will cause great harm, but there are still many companies to deal with. What is a person? Are they silicon-based organisms or carbon-based organisms? What are these electrode materials? People and these materials are fundamentally incompatible. I did an invasive brain-computer interface on mice, and all the mice died. The monkeys in Musk&#39;s previous experiments also died. This direction is problematic in terms of long-term safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why are you doing this &quot;world&#39;s first African &quot;Human primate (monkey) interventional brain-computer interface trial&quot;? How were the animal types selected and what was the testing process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;The trial&lt;span>; will be carried out starting in June 2022. It was originally to verify the feasibility of the interventional brain-computer interface. Although there have been some relevant reports internationally, whether they are true or false cannot be known until verification. In terms of details, such as verifying whether the sensor works and whether it can last for more than half a year in the animal&#39;s brain. For vascular interventional brain-computer interfaces, the blood vessels of animals that are too small, such as mice, are too thin for electrode wires to enter. Although the blood vessels of sheep are thinner than humans, they are relatively thick, and the price is also cheap. Basic movements can be distinguished. Come out; after the experiment is successful, we will test the monkey again, and let the monkey&#39;s active intention control the mechanical arm to grab food. Because monkeys are a species similar to humans, there will be no problem with it. Then we will feel more at ease when we do human experiments. . The overall process is rather tortuous. Finding partners and venues such as hospitals and laboratories is not a problem, because everyone knows that this is a very new research, and it will be easy to publish papers and get projects later, and it also has certain market prospects. The difficulty is that the early stage of this experiment was during the epidemic. Many engineers and students were often blocked and needed to find various ways to coordinate personnel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In January this year, the American Synchron company announced its The &quot;vascular interventional&quot; brain-computer interface clinical trial successfully allowed four paralyzed subjects to control external devices and complete operations such as texting and emailing, personal finance, and online shopping. How do you understand some media describing your research as &quot;creating the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is recommended not to interpret it out of context. This &quot;pioneering&quot; and &quot;world&#39;s first&quot; should be viewed together. When I conduct experiments on sheep, I actually mean to create the third new paradigm of brain-computer interface in China, because no one in China has done relevant research; the world&#39;s first case means that I am the first person in the world to conduct experiments on monkey species. People who do this type of experiment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the success of this experiment, we will bring you What are the impacts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a mental point of view, it has no impact at all. I think it is very dull. According to our plan, this trial will soon enter the clinical stage, that is, it will be tested on humans, but it is still in the ethical review stage of the hospital. But I do get some emails from volunteers. What impressed me deeply was that there was a woman who wanted to save her husband who was lying in the ICU and hoped that her husband could participate in the clinical trial of brain-computer interface; there was also a grandson who wanted to save his grandmother, and the child wanted to be a volunteer; there was also a blind person Ask me to regain my sight... These letters are very touching, but our experimental ethics have not yet passed and we cannot recruit any subjects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some scholars believe that &quot;the development of brain-computer interface We are currently in a bottleneck period, and there is an urgent need for new principles and new technologies to drive research in related fields into the next period of rapid development.&quot; What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The current research on brain-computer interface technology is indeed in a bottleneck period. There are many problems about brain-computer interface. Global problems are not unique to China. Whether it is a non-invasive or invasive track, there are too many players. If they could achieve results, they would have been done long ago. There are too many smart people and many wealthy capital parties. At present, everyone is in a state of relative stagnation. To some extent, it shows that there is a problem with this road, and I suggest you consider changing the track. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Change track? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is invasive or non-invasive, I am not optimistic about it, because I have done it, and there are many domestic companies or institutions. Did. In China, the current focus of the industry is still non-invasive. Everyone is crowded onto this track and there is a traffic jam. But I don’t follow any industry. I am currently focusing on vascular interventional brain-computer interface technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I hope more people can do research in a down-to-earth manner&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people are currently focusing on the industrialization of brain-computer interfaces in rehabilitation medicine. Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is a huge demand for patients in this field and the number of patients is also large. With some auxiliary equipment, partial or complete disablement of limbs can be achieved. Sports, so the market potential is relatively large. In addition, the technical process is not difficult, and some low-threshold products are relatively easy to make. As long as companies can raise funds and obtain corresponding certifications and licenses, they can quickly realize cash. If product prices drop further in the future, for example, a product worth 100,000 yuan becomes 20,000 yuan, then the demand will be even higher. There are two main chains in rehabilitation medicine, one is the innovation chain, and the other is the industrial chain. The industrial chain is to make high-end technologies low-end and turn them into products that are sinking. After sinking, they can be universally applicable to more people. After they are universally applicable to more people, there will be more data in scientific research, and there will be more After the data is collected, it is fed back to the innovation chain to form better technology and better products. What I am currently building is such a double-chain circulation platform. Therefore, we did not rush to make specific products, but calmed down and started working on the electrodes. After the electrode automation is completed, it can serve many products. My entrepreneurship was a relatively stupid situation, equivalent to begging for food with a golden rice bowl. The position I give myself is not to do specific, low-end, repetitive things, but to make the company a platform and a core system for brain-computer interface applications in rehabilitation medicine. This platform will also be open in the future. , allowing more people, companies, and institutions to do things together on this platform. As long as they don&#39;t fool me and want to do things down-to-earth, they are all welcome. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The current overall ecology of China&#39;s brain-computer interface industrialization What is it like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the concept of brain-computer interface is overheated at this stage, and some irresponsible media use gimmicks to gain attention. Change the concept. For example, the flashing pictures are actually brain electrical signals induced by vision, which is a conditioned response. However, in media reports, it is described as controlled by &quot;thoughts&quot;. It seems very fantasy, but it is actually very simple. As far as brain-computer interface companies are concerned, there are actually not many people who can really endure loneliness and do low-level R&amp;D, because low-level R&amp;D is too expensive and there is no cash return in the short term. I sincerely hope that more people in the industry are willing to do basic research in a down-to-earth manner. Today’s investors don’t blindly follow investments because they don’t have much money. Maybe because there are so many people speculating on concepts, there are not many people who really have the patience to accompany the growth of innovative companies. I am not willing to accept investment from such investors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, the domestic brain-computer interface corresponds to In product development, what are the urgent problems that need to be solved? What type of talent is most in short supply? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the ideal brain-computer interface product in the future should be realized through vascular intervention. In order to achieve this goal, it is urgently needed Solve the problem of electrode stability. After the stability is guaranteed, we can then find ways to realize automated production to reduce the cost of the product. Judging from the professional fields involved in talents, more cross-field and compound talents are needed. For example, there is overlap in at least two or more fields in materials, processing, machinery, circuits, medicine and other fields. The most important thing is that these people can calm down and do things in a down-to-earth manner. They will not go to this company where the salary is high today, or to make money in that field tomorrow. People without feelings cannot do good things. Under this premise, you must have good understanding and the ability to think independently and explore. Both are important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to brain-computer interface, you have other research Simultaneously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We are currently also developing intelligent aircraft that can take off vertically and artificial hibernation of rats. In the future, we hope that artificial hibernation experiments can be combined with interventional brain-computer interfaces to use special stimulation signals through electrodes in blood vessels to affect the entire brain, or to modify the brain in this way to make people hibernate. This technology can be used in the future It is used in some medical treatment fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[风波过后，脱口秀行业复苏在望？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant -east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text -align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data-style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 18px;&quot;>;Open mic performance Sharp decline&amp;nbsp;Actors are looking for other opportunities&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot; Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; In May of this year, the talk show industry went through a series of rectifications. Among all cities, Shanghai has been most affected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Informed sources revealed to reporters that since the inventory operation in May , the cultural tourism department of Huangpu District, where most of Shanghai&#39;s talk show clubs are located, has strengthened supervision of performance content, and has become more rigorous in spot checks of performance videos every week. Actors must perform performances strictly in accordance with the approved content. If the performance video is inconsistent with the content submitted for approval, the performance organization will be fined 50,000-100,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This has led to two changes in Shanghai talk show performances. First, there are fewer individual performances or flagship shows for actors, because such performances require high content integrity and it is difficult for actors to delete passages; second, most clubs no longer hold &quot;open mic&quot; performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Open Mic&quot; is designed for new actors to practice as well as experienced actors A talk show where actors try out new jokes. Due to the unstable quality of the performance content, the open mic tickets in most clubs are relatively low, such as 19 yuan, 39 yuan, etc. Actors are not paid for speaking on the open mic. The main purpose is to polish the content and practice skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the reporter’s understanding, the registration form for most open microphones is Actors submit their manuscripts in advance to the agency for approval, and then sign up one to two days before the performance based on their actual situation. Due to factors such as actors&#39; personal creative habits and time, the content and lineup of open mic performances are somewhat uncontrollable. It is common for actors to temporarily revise and adjust new jokes before going on stage or to be unable to go on stage due to unexpected circumstances and need to be replaced by other actors. Therefore, under the current cautious environment, most talk show clubs in Shanghai no longer hold such forms of talk show performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shanghai open mic performances dropped sharply, resulting in no new actors on stage Chances are, veteran actors are unable to update their creative content. Some full-time actors will choose to go to open mics in other cities to try out new jokes, and Hangzhou has become their first choice. &quot;Xie Haihan&quot;, the manager of Ersansan Talk Show Club, told reporters that four or five contracted actors in his club have chosen to develop in Hangzhou. Currently, there are at least 10 talk show clubs in Hangzhou. But this does not mean that actors can make money in Hangzhou, but that they are more &quot;famous&quot; in Hangzhou. &quot;Everyone is willing to go to Hangzhou, mostly because of the open mic. It is difficult to earn performance fees because the market is not that big now, which leads to oversupply.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/JYLbt3xHSAuV1VibyN4mStSWo7dOQZouyqQsJgRo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259815&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot; data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space : normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 Talk Show Club host &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span data -style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;WenQuanYi Micro Hei&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; , Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;From increment to stock&amp;nbsp;Downside and up of the market&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans -serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;During interviews with reporters, many talk show practitioners mentioned Yes, in fact, the talk show market had been quietly declining even before the public controversy in May this year. The manager of a Shanghai talk show club told reporters that the current box office level of his club has returned to the state of 2017 and 2018. The number of weekly performances has been reduced to about 1/3 (when the performances were at its peak), and the attendance rate is almost the same. Cut in half. And this situation seems not only due to the industry earthquake half a year ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial , sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;233 manager &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot; told reporters , in the past two years, the club&#39;s box office has not shown an upward trend, so it began to expand its business to second- and third-tier cities such as Nanjing and Fuzhou. &quot;The size of the entire Shanghai (market) has actually reached its limit. If we want to increase our performance, we must either expand the city or increase the unit price. But now everyone&#39;s ticket prices are falling overall, so it is not particularly easy to raise (tickets). price), you can only expand the city.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>;He mentioned , the current number of performances in the club has not changed much, but the attendance rate has dropped significantly. &quot;An attendance rate of 60 to 70 percent is considered relatively high. Our theater used to be able to accommodate about 300 people, but now it is basically about 100 people, and there are 60 or 70 people. It is better on weekends. There may be 200 people.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -apple-system-font, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PingFang SC&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hiragino Sans GB&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei UI&amp;quot ;, &amp;quot;Microsoft YaHei&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); visibility: visible;&quot;>;&lt;span>; compared to Next, the box office situation of 233 Club in Fuzhou is relatively stable: &quot;Because the competition is not that big, there are only two (clubs) in the local area.&quot; Che Hongjun, the manager of Gao Xiao Comedy, told reporters, &quot;For some second and third tier For the city, they are not as many forms of entertainment as Shanghai and Beijing. The talk show is relatively fresh to over there. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline : 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-ASIAN: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: Normal;-Apple-System-FONT , BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot; &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot; microsoft yah ei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; In the strong observation of the talk show actor, the golden period of the talk show market began in 2019:&quot; After the talk show variety show was broadcast, The talk show takes off online. &quot;In 2020, during the prevention and control of the new crown epidemic, all the performance industries were affected, and the talk show with a relatively small volume&quot; entered &quot;, seizing the share of other types of performance markets, plus the talk show variety show show The phenomenon -level explosion has helped the rapid growth of the offline performance. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/27/6voahmxiiiu9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 797 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.cms/med IAS/IMAGE/23/11/27 /6voahmxiui9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259814 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; in: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant -NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-EAST-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: NORMAL; FONT-FAMILY:-!! t, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; pingfang Sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Talking Show Actor strong. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font- Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quotica N EUE &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans Gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; 1; 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In 2022, with the saturation of the market and the consumption of resources, the slump of talk show performance has begun to appear, and the industry has begun to usher in the bottleneck period. Hercules wrote in Xiaohongshu: &quot;Every year online program broadcasts, offline performance box office will have a significant rise, but this phenomenon is gone in 2022. It has not improved. It is not that the online program is not helpful for the box office. In fact, there are also, but at this time (talk show performance) The natural traffic of the box office is declining. The power is hedged. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; Laughing Comedy Manager Car In an interview with reporters, Hong Jun said that the current talk show market has almost no increase, and everyone is &quot;curling.&quot; Some clubs may start a &quot;price war&quot;, &quot;some brand prices have begun to explore 50, or even lower.&quot; But on the other hand, he still believes that &quot;this industry is upward&quot;, because &quot;everyone is also rolling quality, especially now more popular performances. The quality of the performance is very high. The tide is back, and everyone starts to fight the real knife. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; FONT-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -apple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; The talk show actor also wrote in his little red book:&quot; In the future, the actor can no longer rely on the 15 -minute commercial performance paragraph. To a certain extent, this is a good thing. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -ple-systerm-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot ;, &amp; &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; Microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; backgrous-money: rgbb (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; During the rapid growth of the industry, a large number of clubs and performers who only wanted to make fast money, eat dividends but did not pay attention to content, and saved a few actors to sell tickets to sell tickets. After seeing the online program, I didn&#39;t know the comedy itself. But in the cold environment today, with the withdrawal of this part of the people, after the industry experienced shuffling, it slowly entered a precipitation period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A number of club the principals said in an interview with reporters. Because the overall box office is not good, they are more willing to leave the performance opportunities to actors with better content and stronger ticket ability. &quot;There may be a commercial performance opportunity when a actor&#39;s paragraph can reach thirty or forty. Now if you are less than sixty or seventy, your performance will be very small. Many people can no longer accept the performance. In the past two years, everyone At the wind, there will be no survival of the fittest. Now it is really difficult, but I think this is a way to go by a single (comedy). &quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; Text-Align: &quot;>; &lt;SPAN>; &lt;strong >; &lt;span data -Style = &quot;COLOR: RGB (34, 34, 34); Font-Family: &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , &amp; quot; wenquanyi micro hei &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot; , Arial, Sans-Serif; Letter-Spacing: normal; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); &quot;>; Where is the future? The necessary online traffic and healthy industry ecology &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font -Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot ;, pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino Sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-service: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible ; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; I didn&#39;t take off six this year, but I once dreamed of myself, and the result was not very good. &quot;On November 3, Zhou Qimo, who had won the championship of a variety show of a part of the stall, posted such a Weibo. He imagined a period of his own experience of participating in the show and then being eliminated, and finally summarized: &quot;The root of the talk show is still offline.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; absent from online shows, completely returned to the next offline program. Is the talk show better? In the visits of reporters, almost every practitioner affirmed a point of view: the traffic of online programs is still necessary for the talk show industry, although online programs and offline performances are very different in creative creation. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Che Hongjun mentioned in an interview,&quot; The form of the form will be very internal consumption of actors. The 5 -minute volume is too small, and you need to rejoice with the audience quickly. The topic will be very limited. Traffic to help break the circle, because with the increasingly rich form of offline performances and entertainment, the art of talk show is facing more intense competition. &quot;Our competitors are not compete with talk shows. Our competitors are all popular entertainment methods: watching movies, KTV, short videos ... Everything is your competitors.&quot; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p Data -Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant-Numeric: Normal; Font-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: normal; Fon T-Family: -padle- System-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microS OFT YAHEI UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px ; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; still requires the promotion of online traffic. &quot; Also agree with this view. Online programs can make the offline market do not drop too fast. If there is no traffic to promote it, it will be more bleak in the offline performance market of talk show. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-spie: n Oremal; FONT -Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica NEUE &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; LINE-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In fact, many clubs and actors are trying to create online IP. The &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; club, initiated and established by Fudan University&#39;s &quot;Dankou Comedy Society&quot;, made its own variety show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot; and was broadcast on station B in October; many clubs insist on making podcast programs to perform product publicity And maintain the stickiness of fans, such as &quot;No jokes&quot; of owl comedy, &quot;Hey Talk&quot; of the comedy box country, and &quot;Three words&quot; of Ji San San; more actors are trying to use self -media to create personal IPs and help Offline tickets. But most people have not been able to achieve stable commercial conversion online. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32MZOTGMH9SPBSPBSPBSNOPC5DP.jpg&quot; Border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1066 &quot;height =&quot; 1442 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32mzotgmh9sap3x4dspbsouuP.jpg &quot;Data-key = &quot;259817&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; Club self -made Variety Show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 606 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259813 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Comedy Union Box Country&quot; actor Offline performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; From the perspective of the industry ecology, the domestic talk show The industry has risen and developed with the popularization and development of related variety shows such as &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show&quot;, &quot;Tucao Conference&quot;, and &quot;talk show conference&quot;. When a industry system, the rising channel of the practitioners, the deep binding of a company, a program, there will inevitably be a great risk -the fact has also proved this. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6cax5hxjemyqruueb.jpg&quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1620 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6caxm5hxjemyqrtwcuueb.jpg &quot;data-key = &quot;259816&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show 》. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A talk show actor said in an interview with reporters, Compared to the emergence of the next explosive program, she hopes that the industry can usher in a healthy ecology: &quot;Different companies can bloom all flowers, have mutual competition, and cooperate with each other. Either actors who have a hand or program (online IP), just like other industries. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more to get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:urange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;&quot; &quot; https://feedx.run &quot;style =&quot; color: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉市卫健委：暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261446]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 11:13:23 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 28, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee of Hubei Province issued a notice, which is reflected in Wuhan Pure Hospital reflected by netizens. In the case of surrogacy and Wuhan Ruibo Xiang Judicial Appraisal, the Wuhan Health and Health Commission, in conjunction with the public security and judicial departments, and the appraisal agencies, the Wuhan Municipal Health and Health Committee conducted investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the qualifications for issuance of medical certification in Wuhan Puren Hospital have been suspended to conduct a special inspection of the hospital&#39;s maternity services and the application of birth medical certificates. The Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Appraisal Institute has been instructed to stop its forensic appraisal business and accept investigation and handling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Next, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee will be held accountable seriously in accordance with laws and regulations in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在巴黎十年被抢近50次：移民导致社会治安恶化，法国社会治理失败]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261430]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recent Second-rate. Why bring a decimal number? Because she was robbed three times, she took it back, so it was only half a time, which means that it was actually 49 times. It&#39;s amazing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Relatives and friends in the diplomatic mouth, studied and worked in Paris in the mid -1990s. After retiring, I re -swimming in Europe. I feel that in 30 years, the changes in France can be regarded as people and not: Paris&#39;s urban appearance and infrastructure have not changed much. However, the composition of residents has changed a lot, and the social atmosphere and cultural customs are very different from 30 years ago. The personal feelings of relatives and friends and women&#39;s Internet celebrities are quite different: As immigration increases, France&#39;s law and order worsen significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reason for the high crime rate of immigration: There are many immigrants from Africa from France. Due to the different religious beliefs, cultural traditions, and customs, these immigrants and their descendants in education have made their social status and economy. The status is at a lower level. I long for the wealthy material life in Europe, but it is difficult to support in terms of economy, which will of course lead to an increase in illegal crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A large number of immigrants and illegal immigrants poured into France, which is the reverse sequelae of &quot;colonialism&quot;. It can be said that France is being reverse colonial. In the early 17th to 20th centuries, France occupied a large number of colonies in Africa, becoming the second largest colonial empire in the world after the United Kingdom. Two World War has caused the French population to lose huge losses. In order to make up for the lack of troops, France recruited hundreds of thousands of local young people from colonial French Africa to participate in the French army and fight against Germany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the war, a large number of colonial soldiers remained in France and became early immigrants. The French film &quot;INDIGènes&quot; has a vivid description. Many black soldiers ask: We fight for France, why can&#39;t we stay here? Ask the French government and the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through these early immigrants, their relatives and friends in Africa learned the development and wealth of France. A large number of follow -up immigrants and illegal immigrants continued to influx. Official data: At present, there are more than 8 million blacks in France. Considering illegal immigrants, the actual number may reach 10 million, accounting for 15%of the 66 million total population in France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The changes in the population structure have greatly changed the traditional French religious belief, cultural concepts, and living customs, intensified ideological conflicts, and brought increased crime rate, social turmoil, and both ethnic groups and classes. Street demonstrations protest, smashing and burning, becoming a commonplace for more than ten years, which can be called a wonderful landscape in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The turbulent social environment not only affects the economic development of France, but also affects the personal and property of each life in Paris. In this chaotic environment, throwing a wallet and a mobile phone is common, and such a high crime rate, the police are invincible and ordinary residents are invincible. In helplessness, the way they adopted was to raise the threshold for files: light crimes such as robbery and other serious crimes, regarded light crimes as illegal, and simply try to leave as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The United States also learned this set. In 2014, California passed the bill and stole the less than 1,000 US dollars as a minor crime, which can be guilty through community services. Use this method to avoid police conflicts and reduce the contradiction between police and blacks. This set of legal ideas and judicial practice has spawned the &quot;0 yuan purchase&quot; movement in Europe and the United States: the big group (mainly immigrants) rushed into the store together, took things to run, the store was unable to stop, and the police did not want to control it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to public security issues, there is also a seemingly irrelevant life detail change: French bread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the early years of retention in France, relatives and friends were impressed by French catering. Especially appreciation of French bread: In France, bread is not only a diet, but also a culture. In order to make Xiangsong&#39;s delicious bread, French bakers are very particular about the noodles and ingredients to fermentation and baking. It starts in the early morning to ensure that as the sun rises, the fragrant and hot -baking French bread is released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When he traveled to Paris after the new crown Class B tube, he was surprised to find that France not only was in society and public security, but even French bread became different from 30 years ago. Hardness, fatigue, poor taste, and severe slag ... Later, many ordinary breaders were new immigrants who lacked French culture and cooking traditions. For them, bread is no longer national glory, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage, cultural heritage. Long custom and exquisite life taste, but just a job, no feelings, and not investing too much energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The relatives and friends who like to travel said: Now it is the former French colonies such as Laos and Vietnam in Southeast Asia. French bread is slightly authentic than Paris. There is also stricter labor discipline, there are certain requirements for employees, and they also follow the traditional French bread baking skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Corresponding to it: French people have a 150 -day rest day (116.5 days per year in the United States), and the average of 1490 hours per year (the American is 1791 hours). Probably because there are too many new immigrants, the grassroots work as much as possible from immigrants, and the French aborigines with higher income are getting easier and more reluctant The occupation is too lazy to do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is like: a company that is already going downhill is not a new technology and productive innovation, and trying to reverse the trend, but to reduce working hours, increase salary, weaken performance, give up management ... what will the consequences happen? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The problem of &quot;traditional loss and cultural ebb&quot; in France will not only be in public security nor catering. Those who have made the French proud of it, and have indeed achieved the culture and art of the world&#39;s peak, and they are also facing the same crisis. The former French film actor Dpadio tangled a group of people in the French performing arts industry, scolded Hollywood to engage in cultural aggression, and burned the American flag to vent their anger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Hollywood has neither forced force, nor does it &quot;cultural aggression&quot; against France through an unequal treaty, but people (including French) are unwilling to consume French movies, drama, and games. The French should really save themselves: they are in ideology, ideology, cultural concepts, artistic creations, as well as international political, economic and trade relations, social governance, and even baking bread ... What is going on in all aspects, what is going on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The deterioration of social order brought by immigrants reflects the failure of the French government&#39;s social governance. The cultural impact and ideological collision caused by immigration issues reflect deeper hidden dangers. French social governance failure and ebb to ebb. The internal cause is that the spiritual power of the contemporary French is dissipated, the traditional values ​​are abandoned, and the national culture is lost. The French lived lazy, idle, and happy, and comfortably confirmed the ancient saying of &quot;from good as good as being as good as the evil&quot;. This state of life is worth pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, I also hope that everyone to think about the person, Elon Musk, who is still struggling in middle age: I don&#39;t want to make money with the power of human fall. For example, &quot;Jupiter Ascending&quot; interprets gravity: up is hard, down is easy The success of society and individuals requires a high spiritual core. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261401]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;On the morning of November 14, 2023, a tenant in the middle and community of Run Middle and Community moves. Southern Weekend Weekend. Southern Weekend Weekend. Reporter Zheng Dan &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 736 &quot;data -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/895faa8963.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259769&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On the morning of November 14, 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, a tenant in the middle and medium districts moved. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Supervise the whole people, make public rental housing more &#39;sunlight&#39;.&quot; A banner hangs on the main entrance of Runmi District, November 2023 Since then, the number of residents moved from the community has increased suddenly, and the &lt;span>; handling &lt;/span>; pickup trucks in and out of the furniture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Moving is common. Recently, Lianyuan, a county-level city in Loudi, Hunan. This stems from a centralized consolidation of public officials to occupy public rental housing. In addition to Run Mid -Mid -Community, the phenomenon of large -scale moving also appeared in the Runze Garden Community, Huimin Community, and Runyuan Community. According to locals, these four communities are public rental housing communities in Lianyuan City. Those who move are basically public officials and their relatives of Lianyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A statistical table obtained by the reporter from the Southern Weekend shows that the above four public rental housing communities are investigated and exited 878 public officials, plus 4 households entering the units of public housing Public officials have a total of 882 households, including 28 public officials at the same level and above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Many public officials in Lianyuan said that people on this list must be retired before the end of November. &quot;This is the first time in the past decades, and the residents have been retreated in such a large area.&quot; A staff member of the Lianyuan Housing Security Service Center (hereinafter referred to as the Housing Insurance Center) told the Southern Weekend reporter that this operation was with the Hunan Provincial Inspection Team. Request rectification is related. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Do not replace the past conventions to the current rules and regulations, and must not compete with the people.&quot; On October 20, the secretary of the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee held a meeting and scheduled the scheduling Public rental housing operation management and service work. The &quot;Lianyuan Online&quot; public account released by the public account that the meeting emphasized that public rental housing is a affordable housing, and relevant departments must unify their thinking; to set up a leading group and work class to study, analyze, and find existing problem loopholes and weak links. , Establish a list of ledger in different categories to increase rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main entrance of Run Mid -Mid -Central District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/27/EDFD4A5F6F6F6F.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/ms/imedias/23/11/ 27/EDFD4A5F6F.JPEG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 259770 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In November 2023, Lianyuan, Hunan, the main gate of Runzhongzhong District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How can the residential insurance center have this ability&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; mid-November, the south On weekends, reporters visited public officials to stay in the middle and medium -sized districts and Runze Park Community. Many fences and walls were hung on the wall with red banners that combat illegal use of public rental housing and rented public rental houses. In the two communities, each building was posted with the announcement of the Lianyuan Housing Insurance Center: &quot;The Municipal Party Committee and the Municipal Government are carried out cleanup and rectification of the use of public rental housing in violation of regulations. Public leased housing situation (including actual staying in other methods such as transfers, rents, and resale). Once verified, the reporting units, organizations and individuals will reward 500 yuan/time. &quot;The announcement date of the announcement is October 31. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There are fewer people who have moved these two days, and many people have moved away a few days ago.&quot; On the afternoon of November 13, a resident in the middle and medium districts in Runzhong District Tell the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #000000;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; Public rental housing, full name public rental housing, refers to the limited construction standards and rental levels, Facing the middle -income housing difficulties, households in difficult housing, new employment employees, and affordable housing rented out of the town. According to the &quot;Administrative Measures for Public Rental Housing&quot; issued by the Ministry of Housing and Construction in 2012, the lease period of public rental housing generally does not exceed 5 years. If it does not meet the renewal conditions after the expiration, it shall retire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lianyuan City, this concentrated retreat, according to a number of public officials, it is the 11th inspection team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee to work in Lianyuan City 2 to work 2 During the month (September 7, 2023 -November 7, 2023), some masses reported that public officials reported illegally occupying public rental housing and rents and sold, resulting in poor households who really need houses to live without houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporter obtained a red head document sent by the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee to the municipal units- &quot;Regarding the founding of public officials leased public rental housing investigations The notice also mentioned that the 11th inspection team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee issued a letter to Lianyuan City on October 17, 2023, and feedback that there was a problem of public officials and the people in Lianyuan public rental housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The notice requires all units to conduct investigations and foundation on public rental housing on the public rental housing of the unit, and on October 23, 2023 Before 17:00, the &quot;Statistics Form for Public Officials Leasing Public Rental Housing&quot; will be reported to the Municipal Housing Insurance Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Many ordinary people take this to the inspection team to reflect that the inspection team feels that this is a common problem. Rental). &quot;Lin Min (pseudonym) of the staff of the Housing Insurance Center told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Public officials illegally occupying public rental housing are not unique. According to public information, in May 2021, the Supervision and Inspection of Qingchuan County Discipline Inspection Commission of Guangyuan City, Sichuan Province found that local public officials used 412 units of public housing illegally, including 275 units of public rental housing in violation of regulations and 145 public officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2019, in 2019, the Anhua Discipline Inspection Commission of Yiyang City, Hunan Province also found such phenomena. Four public officers rented public rental housing, and 5 public officials were transferred to public rental housing. There were 28 public officials who did not withdraw the qualification conditions in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the public information of Lianyuan City Rong Media Center, on the evening of October 25, 2023, the members of the Eleventh Inspection Team of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee were at the Standing Committee of the Lianyuan Municipal Party Committee Standing Committee The meeting again emphasized that the public rental housing issues that people reflect strong and highly concerned about the public must be realized and steadily promoted the rectification of the problem steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, before the inspection team arrived, Lianyuan City also tried to rectify the problem. According to a report from Hunan Daily in early 2023, the Lianyuan City Housing Insurance Center launched a special cleanup and rectification operation of public rental housing illegally from January 9th to 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;In January, reported more than ten public officials who were seriously inconsistent, and there were cars and houses in the name. Then After changing some people, a few households were cleared. &quot;Lin Min introduced that according to the practice of Lianyuan City, such special cleanup and rectifications will be organized every two or three years, but the rectification is small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Now so great to retreat, how can we have this ability to live in the insurance center? If it wasn&#39;t for the inspection team, who would move the municipal party secretary? According to Lin Min, the rectification of public rental housing involves a number of cadres, and the Municipal Housing Insurance Center is difficult to implement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, a public official moved away from Run Mid -Mid -Central District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/ CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/27/8C9A7B4242.jpeg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/ 23/11/27/8c9a7b4242.jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259771 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; On the afternoon of November 13, 2023, Public officials moved away from Run Middle District. Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Too many vacant placement and wasting waste? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Is public officials qualified to stay in public rental housing? Nie Chen, an associate professor at the School of Public Management of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, who has long studied housing security, believes that some public officials who have low income and difficult housing &lt;/span>; meet the conditions to stay in public rental housing, which is normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“1998年福利分房制度取消之后，全国大多数省市就不再&lt;span>;由&lt;/span>;单位建房分给职工。的确有一些公务员工资不高，家庭负担比较重，买不起房，那么他就符合申请公租房的条件。”中国建设管理与房地产法研究中心主任王才亮说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但就涟源的情况，有知情人士告诉南方周末记者，入住公租房的公职人员，多数通过摇号入住，少部分则是通过“批条子”拿到入住名额。 “有的在娄底买房的，涟源没房；有的在涟源有房，但他想要这个房；也有的是帮朋友或者亲戚批条子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“重灾区是润中小区，大多数公职人员都在那边，那边靠近市中心，地理位置比较方便。”该知情人士称。南方周末记者对比润中小区三次公租房电脑摇号结果公示名单与涟源市公职人员租赁公共租赁住房统计表发现，润中小区三次摇号总计入住1826户，小区内公职人员有669户，占小区居民总数约37%；其中522户在摇号结果公示名单中，其余147户不在摇号名单之列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者另获得一份涟源市《正科及以上领导干部租赁公共租赁房住房退房统计表》显示，多个单位有28名正科级干部在2023年10月底已退房，家具还在清理中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为什么会有如此大规模的公职人员住进润中小区？上述知情人士透露，润中小区建成后，在2017年、2018年公开摇号时，因为一些特殊原因，“只要参与摇号，都能分到房子”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“润中小区一次盖了2300多套房子，没人住，但它要求入住率达到90%，住保中心要是完不成也会被批评。因为你要盖那么多房，肯定代表有这么大的需求量。”该知情人士称，在配租时，住保部门曾向涟源市政府报告入住率低，后涟源市政府开会商议放宽条件，在涟源无房的公职人员均可申请摇号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月24日，南方周末记者致电涟源市住保中心相关负责人求证该说法，对方以“不需要”为由，拒绝接受采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源市住保中心另一位工作人员告诉南方周末记者，润中小区地处蓝田街道建中村、胡家村，2012年年底开工建设，包括廉租房和公租房，当时称为“建中廉租房、城东公租房项目”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源市政府官网2013年的信息显示，建中廉租房、城东公租房项目是涟源市“十二五”住房保障规划内实施的保障性住房建设重点项目之一。该项目占地188亩，规划总建筑面积达14万平方米，总投资额1.8亿元，计划建设住房共2076套，建成后将成为涟源市住房面积最大、功能最齐全、宜居环境最佳的安居小区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年润中小区一份物业招标书提及，小区房屋总建筑面积14万平方米，共计30栋，其中住宅有2218套，非住宅（服务用房）742个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;“涟源在线”公众号发布的建中廉租房全景图（上）， 《涟源年鉴（2019）》刊载的润中小区全景图（下）。资料图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1223&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/fc0c1983ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“涟源在线”公众号发布的建中廉租房全景图（上）， 《涟源年鉴（2019）》刊载的润中小区全景图（下）。资料图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廉租房，指政府以租金补贴或实物配租的方式，向符合城镇居民低生活保障标准且住房困难的家庭提供社会保障性质的住房。聂辰告诉南方周末记者，“某种意义上，廉租房就是公租房，它面对更低收入的人群，房租比公租房更低。2014年廉租房与公租房并轨，现在基本上都称公租房。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;聂辰分析，2010-2015年，国家大规模推行公租房、廉租房，当时提出目标：2012年末解决1540万户低收入住房困难家庭的住房问题，2015年保障住房覆盖面要达到20%。 “当时各地都有目标要完成，建了大量公租房。”但聂&lt;span>;辰&lt;/span>;在实际调研过程中发现，包括北京、上海、内蒙古包头在内的部分地区出现因公租房位置偏远或其他因素，申请租赁的人较少，导致公租房空置的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“现在有一个趋势，就是公租房在逐渐放宽条件，甚至出现转成保障性租赁住房的现象，将保障的范围扩大。”聂&lt;span>;辰&lt;/span>;说，保障性住房的租金一般不高于同地段同品质市场租赁住房租金的90%，“但不可以直接转成商品房，因为政府对公租房有严格的控制权”&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得注意的是，2020年10月，涟源市纪律检查委员会与涟源市监察委员会通报了一起关于建中廉租房建设的串通投标问题。 2012年11月，涟源市人民检察院原反贪污贿赂局副局长梁某与张某贤(以谭某平为首的黑社会性质组织的积极参加者)为取得涟源市建中廉租住房、城东公租房小区第十四标段的工程建设项目，先后联系湖南涟源湘中工程公司等四家公司串通投标，后中得该工程项目。相关判决书显示，梁某与张某贤二人在该项目工程中违法所得129万余元。 2020年8月，梁某受到开除党籍、开除公职处分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除润中小区外，惠民小区与润泽园小区的公职人员也不少。一位惠民小区的公职人员称，惠民小区也是因为空置房源太多，逐渐对公职人员放宽条件。另有多位公职人员也称，此前涟源各公租房小区的申请条件宽松，只要在涟源没有房子的务工人员，均可参与摇号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“公职人员的工资本来也不高，很多也是符合（摇号入住）条件的。”入住公租房的副科级公职人员陆柯（化名）表示，涟源市城镇常住人口不到30万，让交了社保且名下无房子的贫困户住满公租房存在困难。 “先去照顾低收入人口，如果还有空房，肯定要放宽条件，否则也属于公共资源的浪费。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王才亮认为，应从摇号、批条两种入住方式分别看待涟源案例。 “公租房是从过去的经济适用房发展下来的保障性住房，主要是解决一大批收入不高的工薪阶层，买不起市场化房子的问题。如果还存在批条子这种行为，就是在滥用职权。”而对于符合申请条件、摇号入住者，临时清退或存在违约之嫌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润泽园小区内贴有打击违规使用公租房的横幅。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/1c07446374.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月，湖南涟源，润泽园小区内贴有打击违规使用公租房的横幅。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“打补丁”与“一刀切”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月1日，《涟源市公共租赁住房管理办法》新规发布，提出了更细化的要求。聂辰告诉南方周末记者，公租房的管理条例一般都由地方政府根据当地的经济条件自己制定。但国家有统一规定，承租人需满足“低收入”和“住房差”两个条件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涟源新规条例显示：涟源市城镇低保、低收入、中等偏下收入住房困难家庭，新就业无房职工和在城镇稳定就业的外来务工人员等符合本地公共租赁住房准入条件的应纳入公共租赁住房保障范围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其中，城镇中等偏下收入住房困难家庭是指家庭人均可支配年收入低于上一年度城镇居民人均可支配收入、家庭存款低于18 万元(含公积金)、在县级及以上城市无不动产的住房困难家庭；新就业无房职工是指参加工作5年以内、且在本地就业、家庭在本地无住房的职工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;林敏分析，家庭人均可支配年收入限制和工作不满5年的限制，足以将大部分公职人员排除在外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“有二十多个不满5年的公职人员没有发清退通知，其余全部一刀切。”林敏回忆，住保中心在内部会议上要求，对工作满5年的公职人员一律清退，“上下传达是这样说的，先全部退出来，满足其他入住公租房条件的再申请下一轮摇号”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陆柯也告诉南方周末记者，自己单位入住公租房的公职人员，除了几名工作不满5年的大学毕业生，其余全部腾退. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一名因工作年限超过5年、被要求腾退公租房的基层事业编工作人员，在涟源市政府官网信箱写下：“（本人）原本在涟源无亲无故也无房产，低收入人员，完全符合条件，达不到与民争利，恳请领导酌情考虑外地人员，不要一刀切，基层工作人员也是民。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在新规推出之前，公职人员入住公租房是否真的没有与民争利？南方周末记者随机采访了两户润中小区居民，均非公职人员家庭，当时按正规摇号渠道申请到公租房。其中一位称，自己的哥哥和母亲也是这样申请到了公租房，此前未遇到申请不到公租房的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;林敏认为，后来出现群众反映无公租房可以申请，是新阶段出现的新问题。 “有些当时不需要公租房的，后来儿女成家，又需要房子了，也有的&lt;span>;是发&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;生&lt;/span>;家庭变故。”加之近几年，涟源未再新建公租房。因国家政策调整，2016年以后，原则上不再新建公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月8日，涟源市住保中心发布公告，于当日至11月20日期间集中受理公租房轮候对象申请，符合新规条件的可以申请公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/63cd9e2856.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月13日下午，一位公职人员搬离润中小区。南方周末记者郑丹摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据多位公职人员讲述，2023年11月9日，星期四，在巡视组即将离开涟源之际，城管局一位临近退休的公职人员组织多人前往巡视组办公处反映诉求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“带头那个人（在被腾退的公租房里）搞了一些装修，看看（政府）能不能赔点钱。”一位城管局的公职人员说，去找的有几十人，涉及多个单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位入住润泽园的公职人员告诉南方周末记者，自己家人也跟着去反映情况。 “本来第一次下通知是12月10号前搬，但是他们去（反映情况）以后，第二天就下了通知，11月30号之前必须要搬。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位涟源市发改委的公职人员回忆，星期五（11月10日）早晨，单位组织开会，要求签承诺书，必须在11月30日之前搬离公租房。另一位从事教学工作的公职人员也称学校当天早晨紧急召开会议，“领导让我们签一个承诺书，如果月底不搬，年度考核先评不及格，绩效工资都没得了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们单位开会开得更厉害一些，星期六星期天都在开。”前述城管局的公职人员说，城管局有一二十人去反映诉求，“我们单位的房子大部分都装修了，意见比较大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据林敏所知，入住公租房的公职人员中，装修花钱最多的有二十多万元。关于装修是否给予赔偿，林敏介绍，公租房合同里明文规定“来修去丢”，装修不做赔偿。 “因为它不是毛坯房，卫生间、厨房、灯具都是装好的，达到交房标准就可以基本入住，这是国家补助给贫困户的，你装修跟政府出租还是有点违背的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此外，多位受访者告诉南方周末记者，涟源市转卖公租房的现象比较普遍。 “我听说，一间五十多平米的房子，价格高的有卖到五六万的。”林敏说，之所以有很多人会装修公租房以及转卖，或许是当地一个根深蒂固的观念所To. “在我们涟源有一个思想，就是政府把这个房子给我了，就代表这个房子就是我的了，我从来没担心过这个房子我会住不下去，没想到巡视组来了让我们搬。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随之而来的是，涟源部分靠近公租房小区的房租也有了涨幅。 “幸福路以前两室一厅的房子，一年租金不到四千块钱，现在都涨成五千块钱了。”一位住在润中小区的公职人员告诉南方周末记者，按照公租房的价格，一年只需要交2000元出头。另外两位被清退的公职人员也证实：“突然之间有八百多户人搬出去，（附近出租房）房源肯定是紧张的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月14日，南方周末记者以“不愿退房的租户”身份向一位住保中心工作人员咨询。对方称，如果认为自己符合入住公租房条件，可以提交材料要求重新审核。申请截止时间在当日中午12点，已有八九十户不愿退房者提交材料。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位提交过材料的公职人员说，他于11月18日收到通知，仍须腾退。据他所知，只有一名身体瘫痪、家庭困难的公职人员通过审核，可以继续租赁公租房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎是新冠的变异？张文宏等专家解读误区]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261440]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;当前，随着各地陆续入冬，呼吸道疾病进入高发时期。 How should we prevent and treat it? What are the misunderstandings about respiratory diseases? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总台《健康中国》栏目邀请复旦大学附属华山医院教授张文宏、首都医科大学附属北京中医医院院长刘清泉，以及首都医科大学附属北京朝阳医院副院长、北京市呼吸疾病研究所所长童朝晖三位专家，就当前网络上常见的关于呼吸道疾病误区进行详解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;误区1：今年的冬季呼吸道病毒复杂，叠加感染很可怕？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;张文宏表示，很多人会害怕自己叠加感染。 In fact, sometimes multiple viruses or bacteria are detected because very sensitive detection methods are used, so don’t worry too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;童朝晖表示，尽管测出来了很多病原体，但并不代表每一种都是致病的。 The doctor will comprehensively analyze which bacteria are the patient&#39;s pathogenic bacteria based on the patient&#39;s clinical condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘清泉表示，从中医角度来看，叠加感染是合病或并病。 “比如发烧7天好了，发现是流感。10天左右又发烧了，这次是支原体。这其实不是叠加，而是养护不好，后续发病的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;误区2：支原体肺炎是新冠的变异？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;童朝晖表示，人类在20世纪初就发现了支原体这种微生物，直到20世纪末期才确定它是一种病原体，而新冠病毒在2019年末才被大家知晓，两者毫It doesn&#39;t matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么孩子特别容易感染支原体？ Tong Zhaohui said that children&#39;s immune systems are not fully developed and their resistance is not as good as adults&#39;, so they are more susceptible to infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;误区3：一旦感冒发烧就得赶紧输液？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;童朝晖表示，“感冒发烧输液好得快”，这其实是一个误区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与流感相比，感冒发烧的温度更低，症状也更轻，往往是上呼吸道的症状。 If you have a fever or cough after catching a cold, just take fever-reducing or cough-relieving medicine at home. Pay attention to getting more rest, drinking more water, and supplementing your nutrition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而对于流感来说，部分流感可能引起肺炎，甚至出现重症肺炎，这个时候可能要住院，住院医生会判断你是否需要输液。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张文宏也表示，一般输液只限于住院的重症病人，或者有些药物无法口服，只能通过输液。 For the common cold, oral medications work better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;误区4：支原体肺炎完全可以在家自愈？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;童朝晖表示，大多数情况下，不管是病毒还是支原体，如果它局限在上呼吸道，大部分可以自愈，一小部分可能会发展到肺炎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张文宏表示，一般来说，支原体肺炎在家用一些对症药物就能好转，但需要注意有没有向重症的方向发展。 For example, if your child&#39;s condition improves after taking medicine, you can observe it at home; if your child still has a high fever after taking antipyretics and is sluggish and unwilling to eat, you should seek medical attention as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;误区5：冬季增大运动量发场大汗就可以提高免疫力？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刘清泉表示，从中医的角度来讲，过分出汗会伤人的阳气。 During winter sports, your body will feel slightly warm and you may sweat a little. It&#39;s okay to work up a sweat, but it doesn&#39;t have to be every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张文宏表示，提倡大家维持一定量的运动水平。 “哪怕今天很忙，走个5000步也很好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特别提醒：冬季请关注天气情况，并酌情佩戴口罩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[OpenAI忙宫斗，AI大模型和应用忙上新丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/27/5c1572c356.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 27/5c1572c356.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-to-late November 2023, OpenAI experienced a constant reversal of personnel turmoil, and Sam Altman was re-appointed as OpenAI CEO It&#39;s over for now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plot is complicated and confusing, and it really attracted enough attention. Can a star company and a star CEO really influence the development process of AI in the human world? You might as well take a look at the efforts of more companies in upgrading and applying large AI models. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New large model&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Anthropic, an AI start-up from San Francisco, California, launched &lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. anthropic.com/index/claude-2-1&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Claude 2.1 AI model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; supports the input of up to 200,000 Tokens, exceeding the OpenAI large-scale Model GPT-4 Turbo has 128,000 Tokens, which can handle longer text content, and also has a new system prompt word (System Prompt) function. Anthropic claims that the accuracy of Claude2.1 is twice that of Claude2.0, which enhances the ability to understand text content, especially when processing higher-accuracy documents such as legal documents, financial reports, and technical specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as OpenAI cooperates with Microsoft, Anthropic and Google stand together. In early November 2023, Anthropic announced that it would use Google&#39;s chip Cloud TPU v5e to support its large models and use its cloud computing services. Google promised to invest US$2 billion in it in October 2023, with an initial investment of US$500 million. Dollar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Inflection AI, a company co-founded in March 2023 by Mustafa Suleyman, co-founder of Google’s DeepMind AI research group, Karén Simonyan, chief scientist of DeepMind AI, and Reid Hoffman, co-founder of LinkedIn, in November &lt;a href=&quot;https://inflection.ai/inflection-2&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A new generation of large model Inflection-2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; was released on the 22nd, calling it the world’s second-generation large model. Language Model (LLM). Inflection-2 performs FP8 mixed-precision training on 5,000 Nvidia H100 GPUs, with approximately 10^25 FLOP computing capabilities. It is in the same training computing category as Google&#39;s PaLM 2 Large model, and has been tested on MMLU, TriviaQA, HellaSwag and GSM8k. In most AI benchmark tests, it is better than PaLM 2, and in some tests it is second only to OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone is benchmarking against OpenAI, and OpenAI is certainly not idle either. On November 6, OpenAI released customizable &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/introducing-gpts&quot;>;&lt;strong>;GPTs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>; at its first developer conference , allowing ChatGPT Plus users and OpenAI’s enterprise customers to create customized versions of ChatGPT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Users do not need to master programming knowledge. They can build a GPT with exclusive functions in GPT Builder by relying only on dialogue and a specific knowledge base. This will be more in line with the user&#39;s specific needs and usage scenarios, and will greatly The application threshold is lowered. This service will bring new changes and opportunities in vertical industry artificial intelligence, software applications and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, this &quot;involution&quot; of computing power, data, and models belongs to enterprises. For users, the use value and application scenarios of large models are more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, in office, smart terminal, social media and other scenarios, users can easily get started directly through the built-in large model application, making commercialization faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;AI application implementation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since August 2023, various mobile phone brands have announced plans to access large models. On November 8, Samsung Electronics released a large AI model developed by Samsung Research Institute&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.samsung.com/kr/%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1%ec%a0 %84%ec%9e%90-%ec%82%bc%ec%84%b1-ai-%ed%8f%ac%eb%9f%bc%ec%84%9c-%ec%9e%90% ec%b2%b4-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c-%ec%83%9d%ec%84%b1%ed%98%95-ai-%ec%82%bc%ec%84 %b1-%ea%b0%80&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Samsung Gauss&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;. It consists of Samsung Gaussian language, Samsung Gaussian code and Samsung Gaussian image, and is planned to be integrated into various products in stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, Elon Musk’s AI company xAI released a large model on November 4&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.ai/&quot;>;&lt;strong >;Grok-1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;, with real-time access to X (formerly Twitter), and Internet browsing and search capabilities to obtain more of the latest news on specific topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Google DeepMind team published a paper in Science titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adi2336&quot;>;Learning Skillful medium-range global weather forecasting&lt;/a>; paper introduces their new machine learning weather forecast model Graphcast, which can generate 10-day forecasts in one minute on a single Google Cloud TPU v4 device, and supports forecasts including tropical Cyclone tracks, atmospheric rivers and extreme temperatures. At present, the source code of this model has been made public. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The weather forecasting method (MLWP) is more accurate and efficient than the traditional &quot;Numerical Weather Prediction&quot; (NWP) method. In July 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06185-3&quot;>;Pangu meteorological model developed by Huawei Cloud&lt;/a>;, in the medium and long-term global weather forecast surpass traditional numerical prediction methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the MLWP model can also be extended to other geographical spatiotemporal predictions such as ecology, energy, and animal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, &quot;Nature Medicine&quot; published a paper on the research results of Alibaba Damo Academy and more than ten medical institutions around the world&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature .com/articles/s41591-023-02640-w&quot;>;Large-scale pancreatic cancer detection via non-contrast CT and deep learning&lt;/a>;, for the first time it has been proven that &quot;plain scan CT + AI&quot; technology can effectively detect early stage pancreatic cancer on a large scale Pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pancreatic cancer is a digestive tract tumor with a very poor prognosis. It has the characteristics of difficulty in early diagnosis, low surgical resection rate, and easy recurrence and metastasis after surgery. It is also known as the &quot;King of Cancers&quot; because of its early diagnosis. Symptoms are vague, lack specificity, and are easily overlooked. CT is the most widely used and most sensitive examination method for detecting pancreatic cancer. However, the contrast of plain CT images commonly used in physical examinations and hospitals is low, making it difficult to identify early pancreatic lesions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team built a deep learning framework—Pancreatic cancer early detection model PANDA (Pancreatic cancer Detection with AI), which uses AI to amplify and identify subtle pathological features that are difficult to detect with the naked eye in plain CT images; internal Test evaluation shows that PANDA can achieve 90% pancreatic cancer lesion sensitivity and 99.9% lesion specificity in more than 20,000 clinical cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using AI to accelerate the popularization of early cancer screening, early detection and early treatment, the quality of patients’ lives can be guaranteed to the greatest extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attached are three recent major developments in the field of biomedicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New progress in biomedicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;h5>;Eli Lilly&#39;s weight loss therapy was approved by the US FDA&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 8, Eli Lilly announced that its glucose-dependent insulinotropic peptide ( GIP) and glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) receptor dual agonist Zepbound (tirzepatide) &lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.lilly.com/news-releases/news-release-details/ fda-approves-lillys-zepboundtm-tirzepatide-chronic-weight&quot;>;Approved by the US FDA&lt;/a>; for the treatment of patients with obesity or overweight and weight-related comorbidities (blood pressure, dyslipidemia, type 2 diabetes, obstructive sleep disorders apnea or cardiovascular disease) to lose weight and maintain weight stability. Zepbound is the first approved drug that simultaneously activates two intestinal hormone receptors (GIP and GLP-1), directly targeting the root cause of excess weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The obesity indication approved for Zepbound this time is mainly based on the results of two Phase III clinical trials, one of which targeted 2,539 adults with obesity or overweight and weight-related problems (excluding diabetes). Injecting Zepbound as a dietary and exercise aid, the highest dose group (15 mg/week) lost an average of 48 pounds (approximately 22 kg) in 72 weeks, while the lowest dose group (5 mg/week) lost an average of 34 pounds (approximately 15 kg) , the placebo group was 7 pounds (about 3 kilograms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comment: Zepbound is a GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonist injected once a week. Eli Lilly announced the first new Chinese evidence in the field of Zepbound obesity treatment on October 3, 2023. And has submitted a registration application for long-term weight management indications in adults in China. As of now, there are no GLP-1 drugs officially approved in China for the treatment of obesity or overweight. China has a huge weight loss market, and the market competition in the field of weight loss indications is fierce, which provides more information for individuals seeking effective weight loss treatments. multiple choice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;The world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy was approved&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 16, the US biopharmaceutical company Vertex (VRTX.O) and the Swiss gene editing company CRISPR Therapeutics ( CRSP.O) announced that the UK Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has granted it &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vrtx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/vertex-and-crispr- therapeutics-announce-authorization-first&quot;>;CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy Casgevy (Exa-cel) Conditional Marketing Authorization&lt;/a>; (CMA, applicable to drugs that meet significant unmet medical needs, valid for one year, updated annually Once), for the treatment of patients 12 years of age and older with sickle cell disease (SCD) with recurrent vaso-occlusive crises (VOCs) and transfusion-dependent beta-Mediterranean patients who are unable to obtain human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-matched hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Anemia (TDT) patients. This is the world’s first CRISPR gene editing therapy approved for marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Casgevy is an autologous, ex vivo CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing therapy that modifies the patient&#39;s hematopoietic stem cells in vitro so that red blood cells can produce high levels of fetal hemoglobin (HbF, a hemoglobin that carries oxygen ). Results from two global clinical trials of CASGEVY in SCD and TDT showed that treated patients had no serious VOCs or independent blood transfusions for at least 12 consecutive months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above approvals open the door to further applications of CRISPR therapies in the future, with the potential to cure many genetic diseases. In addition, another American biotechnology company Verve&amp;nbsp;(Nasdaq: VERV)&amp;nbsp; announced its development of a single base editing therapy VERVE-101 based on the modification of the CRISPR system at the American Heart Association on November 12, confirming that gene editing therapy A single infusion of the drug significantly reduced LDL-C levels in people who were at high risk for early heart attacks due to inherited high cholesterol. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;Half natural, half synthetic yeast cells&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On November 9, &quot;Cell&quot; reported on the international cooperation project as a cover story &lt;a href =&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(23)01079-6?_returnURL=https%3A%2F%2Flinkinghub.elsevier.com%2Fretrieve%2Fpii%2FS0092867423010796%3Fshowall%3Dtrue&quot; >;The latest achievement of the &quot;Saccharomyces cerevisiae Genome Synthesis Project&quot;&lt;/a>; (Sc2.0 project): the design and synthesis of all 16 yeast chromosomes and a new chromosome of specially designed tRNA has been completed. The researchers crossed yeast cells containing different synthetic chromosomes and then looked for individuals carrying two synthetic chromosomes in the offspring. After a long hybridization process, the research team gradually integrated all the chromosomes they had previously synthesized (6 complete chromosomes and 1 chromosome arm) into the same cell. The resulting yeast strain accounted for more than 31% of the synthetic DNA and had a normal morphology. ; Later, a newly synthesized chromosome (chromosome 4, the largest of all synthetic chromosomes) was transferred using chromosome replacement, thus obtaining a yeast cell with 7.5 synthetic chromosomes, with the proportion of synthetic DNA accounting for more than 50%. The synthetic yeast cell Survival and replication capabilities are similar to wild yeast strains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/53090e4628.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;▲ VOLUME 186, ISSUE 24&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sc2.0 project initiated by the international scientific community aims to complete the design and chemical reconstruction of complete Saccharomyces cerevisiae The genome, and ultimately the yeast strain synthesized, will be a milestone in humanity&#39;s ability to use and understand eukaryotic genomes. On November 8, the results of the Sc2.0 project were published online in Cell (2 articles) and its sub-journals such as Molecular Cell (1 article) and Cell Genomics (7 articles). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Yeast is the first eukaryotic organism to have its entire genome sequenced. The large-scale design and reconstruction of its genome is a direct test of the authenticity, completeness and accuracy of the current knowledge base in the genome field. The above series of research results are not only a milestone for Sc2.0, but also a key step in the field of synthetic genomics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国人口第一县”两年关停95所幼儿园， 并非只因人口减少]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261432]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73753&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70548&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/103ceb5c9a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111456433091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 2023, No. 1 Institute in Hefei, Anhui The kindergarten is playing the game of &quot;Little Rabbit Transporting Carrots&quot;. In recent years, news of kindergarten closures has appeared in many places. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Pictures&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/103ceb5c9a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259802&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In September 2023, a kindergarten in Hefei, Anhui Province was playing the &quot;Rabbit Transporting Carrots&quot; game. In recent years, news of kindergarten closures has appeared in many places.图文无关。 Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the news that &quot;China&#39;s most populous county has closed 50 kindergartens&quot;, the closure of kindergartens has become a directly related factor to the decrease in the birth population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Linquan County, Fuyang City, Anhui Province, with a registered population of 2.293 million in 2022, is known as &quot;the most populous county in China&quot;. In August 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens had ceased operations, accounting for 24.5% of the total number of private kindergartens in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A decrease in the number of births is considered to be the main reason. A set of government public data has been repeatedly mentioned in online communication. Linquan County has 58,243 children in kindergarten in 2023, a decrease of 9.2% from the previous year. This is the fourth consecutive year of decrease. This is consistent with the national trend of decreasing the number of kindergartens and the number of kindergarten students in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, another set of data did not attract attention. In June 2023, the Linquan County Development and Reform Commission stated that in 2022, the county will build, renovate and expand 9 kindergartens, effectively expanding the number of public kindergarten places by 2,070; simultaneously handing over 7 community supporting kindergartens, adding 2,610 places, completing the annual target tasks 103.5%. According to the plan, the county will add 1,890 new public kindergarten places and 2,000 kindergarten places in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the founders of many closed private kindergartens in Linquan said that the main reason for the closure was the impact of local public kindergartens. “Their environment is better and their fees are higher. Cheap&quot;. However, they have not received policy support and their living space has become narrower. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are fewer children and the policies are not supportive&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the 50 private kindergartens that have terminated their operations in Linquan County, 12 private kindergartens have applied to terminate their operations, and the other 38 private kindergartens have no actual enrollment. , school-running behavior, the school-running license has expired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chengdong Street Yifan Kindergarten founded by Chen Min (pseudonym) belongs to the category with expired school license. Yifan Kindergarten was opened in 2006. Chen Min recalled that there were only more than 20 students at that time. It later gradually developed to its peak, with nearly 230 students enrolled around 2017. &quot;It has been running for more than ten years, and it has feelings.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Min said that the direct reason for the closure of Yifan Kindergarten was that the Linquan County Education Bureau interviewed and informed it that the current kindergarten operating standards had been improved, but the hardware facilities and site area of ​​Yifan Kindergarten did not meet the standards. , if it continues to open, enrollment will need to be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we are given few places, we will definitely not be able to cover the rent, so there is no need to do it.&quot; Chen Min did some calculations and believed that if we continue to do it, there is a high probability of losing money. The number of students enrolled in Yifan Kindergarten has been declining in recent years, while new public kindergartens continue to be built in the surrounding areas. &quot;Public kindergartens have a good environment and low tuition fees.&quot; Chen Min believes that even if the Education Bureau does not stop it, it will have to take the initiative to close it down in two years. After struggling for several months, Chen Min decided not to apply for a license renewal and shut down. Before the closure, Yifan Kindergarten had three large classes and one middle class, with a total of 110 students and 12 teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teaching land of Hongyang Kindergarten in Huangling Town is a private house built by the principal himself. The number of students enrolled has always been around 80. &quot;But the number of small classes will be reduced from 2022 summer vacation.&quot; The principal of the kindergarten said that before the closure, they had a total of three classes, with more than 20 students and two teachers in each class. Since the kindergarten&#39;s operating license is about to expire, applying for license renewal and acceptance requires reinvestment to improve the environment and facilities in the park. She does not want to invest anymore and simply closes down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She believes that the gradual closure of private kindergartens is the general trend. &quot;Young people are unwilling to have children, so the state has increased investment in preschool education and supports public kindergartens.&quot; And she can clearly feel that after the development of public kindergartens, it is difficult for private kindergartens to recruit students. When asked whether the kindergarten had received a request from the County Education Bureau to limit enrollment, she said: &quot;How should I put it, you can&#39;t recruit many people even if I ask you to recruit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaotang Town Kindergarten founded by Yang Hui Jiyangzhuang Kindergarten is one of the 12 private kindergartens that voluntarily applied to terminate its operation. &quot;For various reasons, the funds could not be transferred, so the application was stopped.&quot; Yang Hui believes that the primary reason is that the number of students enrolled is small. In the past, Yangzhuang Kindergarten could enroll thirty or forty children, but in 2022, only 10 children were enrolled in small classes. &quot;It will be less every year, and it will be very few by 2022.&quot; At the same time, the school required &quot;two teachers and one childcare&quot;, that is, each class must be equipped with two teachers and three childcare workers. The income was far lower than the expenditure, and Yang Hui began to go into debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Hui mentioned that another reason is that it is very difficult for private kindergartens to recruit qualified teachers. Yang Hui said that in recent years, more and more kindergarten teachers have been recruited, and all of them have joined public kindergartens, and the supply of kindergarten teachers exceeds the demand. In addition, teachers’ salaries are not high, and young people of appropriate age are more likely to choose to work outside the home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau and the County Party Committee Propaganda Department declined an interview with Southern Weekend reporters. A local official told Southern Weekend reporters that as the number of public kindergartens in Linquan County gradually increased after 2017, the living space of private kindergartens became smaller and smaller. &quot;The impact of population decline is only the beginning of the phenomenon, and it is not the fundamental reason (the closure of private kindergartens).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There will be 45 fewer private kindergartens in 2022&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend Reporter Checking the public data of the local government, it was found that the number of private kindergartens in Linquan County has been decreasing year by year since 2019, and there has been a cliff-like decline for two consecutive years in 2022 and 2023, with a decrease of 45 and 50 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the number of public kindergartens has shown an increasing trend from 2019 to 2021 (data is missing in 2022 and 2023), growing from 160 to 221 in three years, and surpassing the number of private kindergartens in 2020 quantity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned officials said that the increase in the number of public kindergartens is mainly due to central policies. On November 7, 2018, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Several Opinions on Deepening the Reform and Standardized Development of Preschool Education&quot;, which clearly requires provinces with a low proportion of children in public kindergartens to gradually increase the proportion of children in public kindergartens. , in principle, the country will reach 50% by 2020, ensuring that the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens (the proportion of children in public kindergartens and inclusive private kindergartens) reaches 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is also because of the implementation of this policy that we have been able to obtain funds from above and have continued to expand some public schools in recent years.” The official said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Fuyang Daily&quot; report, as early as the beginning of 2020, the Fuyang Municipal Education Bureau formulated the &quot;Fuyang City Preschool Education Deepening Reform and Standardized Development Plan&quot;, proposing to promote the universal, universal, safe and high-quality development of preschool education. We will vigorously develop public kindergartens and build, renovate and expand more than 50 public kindergartens every year. In principle, each town (street) should have one public kindergarten for every 15,000 or more people. By 2020, the city&#39;s gross kindergarten enrollment rate for the three years of preschool will reach 90%, and the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens will reach 80%, of which the proportion of children in public kindergartens will in principle reach 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了2020年底，临泉县委宣传部官方微信公众号发布称，该县已顺利完成上述学前教育“985”攻坚目标任务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;985&quot; goal has further requirements in the &quot;Fuyang City&#39;s &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; Preschool Education Development and Improvement Action Plan&quot;: by 2025, the proportion of children in kindergartens in public kindergartens in the city will reach 70%. %above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that while Linquan County is increasing the proportion of public kindergartens, some places are also building more private kindergartens. On October 18, 2023, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement stating that the study approved the establishment of three private kindergartens in Tupei Township, Guanmiao Town, and Huangling Town. The three new kindergartens are all non-profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned official said that this is the process of natural replenishment in the market. He mentioned that among the 50 private kindergartens that will be closed in 2023, some were newly registered in 2021 and 2022. &quot;It shows that while private kindergartens have discovered that there is a market, the government is also looking at where there are vacancies to supplement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After market elimination&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the closure of the six private kindergartens contacted by Southern Weekend reporters, most of the original students were diverted to surrounding public kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The village party secretary of Zhangmiao Village in Tubei Township told Southern Weekend reporters that after a kindergarten in the village was closed, students were diverted to public kindergartens in several nearby villages. &quot;Public kindergartens charge cheaper, (in this village) The public kindergarten has enrolled more than 90 students in 2023. In the past, it enrolled only a few students, about 30 or 40 people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A parent interviewed in Qizhuang Community, Xingtang Street, also believes that one of the advantages of public kindergartens is that they are cheap. According to his understanding, there is a public kindergarten equipped with a school bus, and the tuition for a semester is more than 2,000 yuan if lunch is provided. If you go to a private kindergarten, the tuition fee will be 4,000 to 5,000 yuan under the same conditions. However, the national chain private kindergartens are more expensive, with tuition fees You get seven to eight thousand yuan per semester. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his opinion, there are not many local students, but now parents pay more attention to education. Parents, whether in rural areas or county towns, tend to send their children to public kindergartens or kindergartens in farther urban areas. The hardware facilities and teaching staff are better. For example, public kindergartens have larger student activity areas, more teaching aids, picture books, and more interest courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“本地的民办幼儿园大都在民房里，自己家盖的房子，有个小院当操场，没啥东西。”上述家长认为，目前关停的大都是本地的民办幼儿园， “Basically, those that have been eliminated by the market, those with better student sources and up-to-standard software and hardware will be converted into public ones, and all will be taken over by the government.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Yang Hui, it is a helpless choice for private kindergartens to withdraw from the market. Yangzhuang Kindergarten has been closed for more than three months. His kindergarten building and playground are abandoned and cannot be rented out. &quot;I am exhausted every day, and I have no choice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reluctantly closing the kindergarten, Yang Hui is working hard to keep his private elementary school. The primary school was founded by his father in 1994 and has a history of nearly 30 years. As a rural primary school, when the surrounding public village primary schools merged and closed down, it still attracted many students to attend due to the quality of its schooling. It was regarded as the &quot;central school&quot; of the surrounding villages. At its peak, the primary school enrolled nearly 600 students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Hui said that the current requirements for running schools in Linquan County have increased. The Education Bureau will give him 18 primary school enrollment places in 2022 and 20 in 2023. The school&#39;s enrollment has now dropped to just over two hundred students. Yang Hui did not dare to close down because the investment in primary schools was greater than that in kindergartens, and the losses caused by closure would be greater. But he had no idea about the way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新内阁成立不到三月，三成员辞职，日本政坛怎么了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261385]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, three Japanese political affairs officials and deputy ministers have died in explosions. A scandal broke out and he was forced to resign. A local opinion poll showed that after the scandal broke out, the approval rate of the cabinet led by Japanese Prime Minister Kishida Fumio fell to 21%, setting a new low since Kishida became prime minister in October 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new cabinet was reorganized in September this year, and three people resigned in less than three months. For Fumio Kishida, he is currently facing a severe political crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is a period of unstable governance.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng, a professor at the Institute of International Relations at the China Foreign Affairs University, told Southern Weekend reporters that other factions within the party will also I&#39;m ready to replace him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height= &quot;1225&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年9月13日，日本东京，内阁改组后，日本首相岸田文雄在首相办公室出席新闻发布会。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Many senior officials were forced to resign&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;Kanda Kenji, 60 years old, is a member of the House of Representatives of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was the Japanese &quot;Bunshun Weekly&quot; that first broke the scandal of the then Japanese Deputy Minister of Finance Kenji Kanda. According to reports, a company under his name defaulted on taxes, and between 2013 and 2022, the company&#39;s land and properties were seized by the tax department four times. The report also stated that as a tax accountant, Kanda Kenji himself violated relevant industry regulations and failed to participate in necessary training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kanda apologized for the relevant scandal and admitted that the reports were true. Since he was &quot;too busy to get involved&quot; in overseeing the company&#39;s tax details, the work had been left to an accounting firm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scandal broke out, it triggered domestic public criticism of Kanda. Japan&#39;s opposition parties put pressure on the ruling party to remove him from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 9, during his defense, Kanda also stated that he would &quot;continue to perform his duties.&quot; However, on the 10th, he changed his words on whether to continue to perform his duties and said, &quot;No.&quot; Comment&quot;. Resigned on the 13th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In just a few days, I changed my words three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is generally believed that Kenji Kanda was essentially replaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In response to rising prices in Japan, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida proposed an economic countermeasure, an annual supplementary budget of over 17 trillion yen. Previously, the leader of the Cadet Party, Kenta Izumi, said that the Cadet Party would not participate in the deliberations on the budget unless Kishida replaced Kanda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the day of his resignation, Kenji Kanda admitted that he resigned because he &quot;did not want his scandal to affect the debate in Congress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first senior figure in Japanese politics to resign due to a scandal in recent times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, the then Deputy Minister of Justice Kakizawa Mitaru resigned due to suspicion of violating the Public Office Election Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kakizawa is a member of parliament elected from Koto Ward, Tokyo. Previously, Koto Ward Mayor Kimura Yayoi and her team were arrested by Tokyo for allegedly violating the public office election law. Search by the District Prosecutor&#39;s Office.柿泽承认向木村提出过违法竞选的相关建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the scandals that broke out in Kanda and Kakizawa were due to tax evasion and other illegal issues, while Taro Yamada, then administrative officer of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, was involved in &quot;extramarital affairs&quot;. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 56-year-old Taro Yamada, who is married and has children, is also a senator of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Just one month before Kanda resigned, on the evening of October 19, the media photographed Taro Yamada spending the night with a young woman in a hotel in Tokyo. , which lasts approximately three hours. After the news came to light, Taro Yamada admitted to having an extramarital affair and apologized, but denied paying the woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the scope of negative public opinion spread wider and wider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 26, Taro Yamada resigned, becoming the first senior government official to resign after Kishida Fumio reorganized the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Japanese politics have long been unclean.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng emphasized that the financial sector provides money to support politicians&#39; campaigns, and once politicians gain power, they will Opening up the financial circle, formulating laws that are beneficial to them, and promoting policies that are beneficial to them, this is the collusion of money and power politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corruption scandals captured by the media as collusion between the financial and political circles are, in most cases, immediately exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chou Yongsheng added that for those in power, this will make them disgraced, or their approval ratings will continue to decline. For them, the media is actually called the &quot;fifth power constraint.&quot; Sometimes it is helpless, and sometimes it can be settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023, in order to save the sluggish support rate, Kishida reshuffled the cabinet again, replacing the existing 19-person list with 13 people, including the Foreign Minister , Defense Minister and other important positions, and declared that this is a &quot;cabinet that transforms change into strength.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three members of the new cabinet, which was established less than three months ago, have resigned, but the public is not surprised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Japanese public is accustomed to scandals in the political world. Ordinary people have developed a &#39;political apathy&#39; and do not pay much attention to the personal integrity and moral character of politicians. Great trust and expectations.&quot; Sun Wenzhu, associate researcher at the Asia-Pacific Institute of the China Institute of International Studies, said that the public does not approve of this open &quot;fertile politics&quot;, but there is a lack of restraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Disapproval rate hits record high&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I must apologize to the Japanese people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, regarding Kanda’s dismissal due to tax arrears, Fumio Kishida publicly stated that he attaches great importance to the responsibility of appointment and will continue to do his best to perform his duties to restore the trust of the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many public opinions believe that the forced resignation of many senior executives was a &quot;double blow&quot; to Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Affected by factors such as the domestic economic downturn, the push to discharge nuclear contaminated water into the sea, and the frequent scandals involving many ministers, the support rate of Kishida&#39;s cabinet continues to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 12, the results of a joint public opinion poll in Japan showed that the approval rate of the cabinet led by Kishida was 27.8%, a decrease of 7.8% from the October survey results. percentage points, setting a new low since the establishment of the Kishida cabinet in 2021. The disapproval rate reached 68.8%, a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the Institute of International Strategic Studies at the China Institute of International Studies, believes that the Japanese people are generally disappointed with the performance of politicians. There is a &quot;domino&quot; resignation effect this time. The people can be said to be &quot;voting with their feet&quot;, and the cabinet&#39;s support rate will naturally decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She added that, in fact, Abe’s support rate has been relatively low since the late period of his administration. It is not Kishida Fumio&#39;s personal deciding factor, this is also the &quot;mess&quot; left by his &quot;predecessor&quot;. Kishida obviously failed to take over this stall, so it is a continuous decline process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Japanese political arena, &quot;the cabinet support rate falls below 30%&quot; is regarded as entering &quot;dangerous waters&quot;; once it falls further below 20%, it means The cabinet is not far away from being dissolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang said that at the beginning, the Japanese people did not have particularly high expectations for Kishida Fumio, thinking that he might not be decisive or particularly innovative. Facts have also proved that many of Kishida Fumio’s ideas have not been translated into very practical policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Liberal Democratic Party, Moriyama, the Liberal Democratic Party&#39;s general affairs chairman, publicly pointed out that the successive resignations of high-level officials were &quot;an extremely abnormal situation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moriyama leads the Moriyama faction, one of the smaller factions within the Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that the so-called &quot;abnormality&quot; is not only to maintain the authority of the Liberal Democratic Party as a whole, but also to be some kind of euphemistic accusation against Prime Minister Kishida Fumio, thus putting himself The Pai clan had a certain cut with Fumio Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This incident further exposed that money issues and style issues have become chronic diseases in Japanese politics.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Early this month, the Kishida cabinet launched an economic stimulus plan of over 17 trillion yen, the main content of which is tax cuts and extended subsidies. The Japanese government estimates that the plan will increase the Japanese economy by 1.2% annually over the next three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Kishida’s “spending money” failed to achieve the expected goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, the Japanese Cabinet Office released third-quarter GDP data. Japan experienced negative quarterly GDP growth for the first time. In addition, Japan&#39;s private consumption declined in the third quarter, net exports fell by 0.1%, and corporate investment also declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;New economic strategies have not been recognized by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Japanese poll shows that more than 60% of the people &quot;disapprove&quot; of the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures. The reason is that since 2020, Japan’s income tax and resident tax have increased year after year. The economic policies formulated by the Kishida cabinet today are not truly “beneficial to the people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It turns out that prices in Japan have not risen for decades. Zhou Yongsheng pointed out, &quot;Because Japan&#39;s imported goods are expensive, it promotes domestic inflation and causes prices to rise rapidly. The Japanese people cannot stand the sudden price increase, and they are skeptical of Kishida&#39;s ability to govern.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What worries the public even more is that the Kishida cabinet has announced plans to significantly increase the defense budget between 2023 and 2027, with a total investment of up to 43 trillion yen. Many people are worried that the Kishida cabinet will use methods such as increasing taxes and misappropriating financial funds to revitalize earthquake-stricken areas to increase defense capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yongsheng believes that people&#39;s concerns are &quot;not unreasonable.&quot; The biggest pressures Kishida&#39;s cabinet currently faces are pressures from domestic economic growth, financial constraints, and mounting debt. Japan&#39;s fiscal budget had to rely on the issuance of government bonds to expand its fiscal budget, causing its debt burden to become further heavy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The financial flexibility of the Kishida cabinet is actually getting smaller and smaller, and coupled with the need to significantly expand armaments, the financial pressure is even greater. .&quot; Zhou Yongsheng believes that armaments are purely a money-burning and money-consuming industry with no benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that Fumio Kishida has been in office as president of the Liberal Democratic Party for two years, and the Liberal Democratic Party will usher in another presidential election in the fall of 2024 at the latest. Judging from the electoral strategy, it is likely that he will take the initiative to dissolve the House of Representatives before the intra-party election and lead the Liberal Democratic Party to win a majority in the House of Representatives to gain points for his re-election. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pressure of governing under the “yellow light”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of the outside world, reorganizing the cabinet cannot bring the Kishida regime back to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“首先，目前日本老百姓的生活处于不安定状态，直接影响了民生，导致支持率有所下降，这对岸田未来能不能够继续Governance is a very big threat.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng said, &quot;Secondly, Kishida has improperly hired officials in governance, and has hired corrupt people one after another. This is also a blow to his own image and the image of the cabinet.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is noteworthy is that this year, despite opposition from the international community, Japan insisted on discharging nuclear contaminated water from the Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant into the sea, causing huge controversy at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu pointed out that in terms of diplomacy, Japan is still essentially strengthening its all-round binding with the United States and relying on U.S. support to highlight its &quot;sense of presence.&quot; What the Japanese people really need to improve Sino-Japanese relations has yet to see practical action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many media reports said that if Kishida wants to be re-elected as president of the Liberal Democratic Party next fall and achieve long-term governance, he must choose the time to dissolve the House of Representatives and hold an election and ensure that the Liberal Democratic Party Achieved good results in the general election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the sluggish support rate of the cabinet, the sluggish support rate of the Liberal Democratic Party, and the reappearance of the &quot;domino&quot; of resignations of senior government officials have lit up a &quot;yellow light&quot; for Kishida&#39;s pursuit of long-term governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, according to many experts and scholars interviewed, this situation will not force Kishida to step down immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Kishida Fumio&#39;s pressure is mainly on how to win next year&#39;s Liberal Democratic Party presidential election, and the possibility of dissolving the House of Representatives early to hold an election to continue to be in power.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said, Foreign Affairs The so-called &quot;political achievements&quot; mentioned above are of little practical significance to the Japanese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chou Yongsheng said that in the past, except for Abe and Koizumi, Japan’s cabinet changed almost every year. Kishida has been in power for two years now. If there are no major mistakes, he is likely to continue to be in power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, Kishida has decided to abandon his plan to dissolve the House of Representatives within the year and go all out to promote the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures and strive to gradually boost public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“自民党大概率仍将维系执政党地位，党内派阀分裂局面下，除岸田外，尚难产生能够平衡各派阀利益、 A candidate for president recognized by all factions,&quot; Sun Wenzhu believed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the Japanese people&#39;s disappointment in the political circles and their &quot;apathy&quot; towards politics are difficult to reverse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend intern Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访央行原副行长李东荣：数字化金融不会改变金融功能属性和风险属性]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261417]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 10, 2023, the State Administration of Financial Supervision’s “Three Certainties” plan was implemented: Supervision of financial holding groups Functions and financial consumer rights protection responsibilities were officially transferred from the People&#39;s Bank of China to the State Administration of Financial Supervision. The People&#39;s Bank of China has taken another step toward a modern central bank system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back on the past, 45 years ago, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance officially had separate offices, and began to exclusively perform the functions of the central bank in 1984. Since then, the central bank system has been continuously transformed and improved along with the pace of economic reform and social development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the four major state-owned banks have transformed into leading benchmarks in the global banking industry, and smart finance has become the forefront of strategic competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internet finance, which was once full of chaos, has now been brought under the regulatory track and is growing into an innovative force in an orderly manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As financial power becomes the new goal, how can the financial industry continue to change using history as a mirror? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A researcher from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center interviewed Li Dongrong, former deputy governor of the People’s Bank of China, for this purpose. In his nearly 40-year financial career, Li Dongrong served as deputy president of the Guangdong Branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China, deputy president of the &lt;span>;Guangzhou&lt;/span>; branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China, deputy director of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, assistant to the president and deputy president of the People&#39;s Bank of China. . In June 2015, Li Dongrong was responsible for the establishment of the China Internet Finance Association and served as the first president for 7 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, he described the fruitful results of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up as &quot;thousands of sails passed by the side of the sinking boat, and thousands of spring trees in front of the diseased trees&quot;, but at the same time, he also described the effectiveness of my country&#39;s financial reform and opening up as &quot;there is still a long way to go&quot;. The road ahead for financial reform is difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/PUPRTSgFE1mMNasbF2YhYywkxzG3rBT5KZlBfgvr.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;436&quot; height= &quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/PUPRTSgFE1mMNasbF2YhYywkxzG3rBT5KZlBfgvr.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Dongrong, former deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, former president of the China Internet Finance Association&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Banks can’t just settle&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;accounts&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;be accountants&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your nearly 40-year financial career, what major financial reform and opening up events have you experienced or witnessed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was fortunate to participate in and witness some financial reform activities since the early 1980s, and participated in 5 national financial reforms since 1997. The Financial Work Conference has personally experienced and witnessed the financial reform and development in this historical stage, with banking system reform as the main feature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was the importance of China’s financial system before reform and opening up? feature? Why is reform necessary? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For a long time before the reform and opening up, my country implemented a highly centralized planned economic system. Compatible with this are the unified fiscal revenue and expenditure and the unified bank deposits and loans. In 1969, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance jointly operated. The main characteristics of the country&#39;s financial system at that time were: the People&#39;s Bank of China was both a state agency that managed finance and a national bank that comprehensively operated banking services. The bank only handles working capital loans, with single business, centralized credit and small scale. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 4, 1979, Comrade Deng Xiaoping pointed out at a symposium with the main leaders of the party committees of various provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities: Banks should focus on the economy. Now they are just settling accounts and acting as accountants, and they have not really played a role. to the role of the bank. Banks must become a lever for the development of economic innovation technology and truly become banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comrade Deng Xiaoping sharply outlined the main problems faced by my country&#39;s economy and finance at that time, timely pointed out the direction for my country&#39;s financial reform at the beginning of reform and opening up, and became an important guide for the reform of my country&#39;s financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Turn state-owned banks into real commercial banks”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand &quot;turning a bank into a real bank&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; It can be summarized into two main lines. One is to turn state-owned banks into real commercial banks; the other is to turn the People’s Bank of China into A true central bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why should we turn state-owned banks into real businesses? bank? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the early days of reform and opening up, due to historical baggage and operational management issues, the four major state-owned professional banks generally faced unclear governance mechanisms. , unreasonable, high proportion of non-performing assets, increased interest receivable and uncollected and other outstanding problems. The Asian financial crisis in 1997 intensified the impact on the four major banks and highlighted the urgency of accelerating the reform of the state-owned banking system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;While serving at the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and the People&#39;s Bank of China, You have gone through the process of transforming state-owned professional banks into commercial banks, especially pioneering moves such as using foreign exchange to inject capital into the four major banks. How were the difficulties overcome? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The State Council established a leading group for the joint-stock reform pilot work of wholly state-owned commercial banks. The office was located in the People&#39;s Bank of China. Zhou Xiaochuan, then president of the People&#39;s Bank of China, He served as the office director and Central Huijin Company was established at that time. In accordance with the arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, starting from December 2003, Central Huijin used its foreign exchange reserves to inject capital into the Bank of China and China Construction Bank respectively. After that, it injected capital into the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and the Agricultural Bank of China respectively, and promoted their listing in mainland China and Hong Kong, gradually realizing the transformation of state-owned professional banks into joint-stock commercial banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was transferred to the State Administration of Foreign Exchange in early 2002. Under the leadership of the Party Committee of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Party Group of the Administration of Foreign Exchange, the then Director Guo Shuqing led us to specifically participate in and witness the preparation for the establishment of Central Huijin and the launch of foreign exchange capital injection. During my participation, I was deeply proud of the correct decision-making of the Party Central Committee and the State Council and the effective implementation of the financial system. It was this series of important and timely decisions that laid an indispensable foundation for the Chinese banking system to get out of trouble and rise rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to fulfill the obligations of investors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I remember that in order to truly fulfill the responsibilities and obligations of investors, on the one hand, we paid attention to strengthening the leadership of the party. Establish a party group to strengthen the construction of the party&#39;s grassroots organizations; on the other hand, actively organize learning, learn from the advanced experience of corporate governance in the international market, explore the establishment of a corporate governance mechanism in line with China&#39;s national conditions, and select comrades with excellent political and professional qualities from various units As a dispatched director, we provide prior training and education on politics, business and other aspects to enhance the dispatched directors’ ability to perform their duties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since then, state-owned banks have continued to transform into commercial banks. You What do you think are the key factors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back, the success of the shareholding reform of my country’s wholly state-owned commercial banks is fundamentally based on two points: First, persistence The party’s leadership in the reform and development of the financial industry; second, establishing a market operating mechanism based on national conditions. The Party Central Committee and the State Council are far-sighted, assess the situation and make correct decisions, and the People&#39;s Bank of China specifically organizes and implements the joint-stock reform of wholly state-owned commercial banks. The establishment of Central Huijin Corporation, especially the creative use of national foreign exchange reserves to inject capital into pilot banks, promoted the final completion of the shareholding reform and listing of wholly state-owned commercial banks, and successfully solved the problems of unreasonable mechanisms and historical burdens of wholly state-owned commercial banks, allowing for transformation The later state-owned banks were revitalized and became real commercial banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historical practice shows that China’s banking system is now of considerable scale in terms of institutions, total deposits and loans, and fund settlement volume, with relatively rich types of products and services, and excellent service means. The trend of intelligence has better supported the development of the real economy and served people&#39;s living needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The People&#39;s Bank of China becomes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;a real central bank&lt;/strong>;&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that another main line of financial reform is to turn the People&#39;s Bank of China into a real central bank. How did you recognize and witness the transformation of human life? Is there anything particularly impressive? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In order to adapt to the new situation faced after the reform and opening up, do a good job in stabilizing the currency value and supporting healthy economic development, the country has accelerated the improvement of the central government&#39;s The pace of banking system reform. In 1978, the central government decided to separate the People&#39;s Bank of China from the Ministry of Finance and take charge of national financial management. Since then, the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s system has been reforming. Until December 25, 1993, the State Council issued a decision on the reform of the financial system and pointed out that turning the People&#39;s Bank of China into a true central bank was the primary task of deepening the reform of the financial system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I was working at the Guangdong Branch of the People’s Bank of China. From June 20 to June 26, 1991, experts and scholars from the People&#39;s Bank of China, various professional banks, other financial institutions, relevant legal departments, financial circles and legal circles gathered in Zhuhai to solicit opinions and opinions from all aspects on the drafting of the Banking Law. suggestion. In 1995, the versions reviewed and approved by the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress were divided into the People&#39;s Bank of China Law and the Commercial Bank Law. They more objectively and accurately reflect the direction and current situation of my country&#39;s banking system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the country clearly defines the functions of the People’s Bank of China as the central bank, the People’s Bank of China How to deepen and improve functional positioning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As the functional positioning becomes increasingly clear, the People’s Bank of China has timely adjusted its credit fund management system, appropriately used monetary policy tools for macro-control, and continuously optimized and enriched the system. Monetary Policy Toolbox. The credit fund management system was changed from the original unified deposit and unified loan to the balance contract, and soon transitioned to &quot;unified planning, divided funds, actual loans and deposits, and mutual accommodation&quot;, thereby realizing the shift from direct management of credit funds to indirect management. The change of ownership laid the foundation for the subsequent macro-control model of asset-liability ratio management. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 1997, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council held the first national financial work conference, which determined the policy of further deepening the reform of the financial system and emphasized that the People&#39;s Bank of China should be transformed into a truly central bank. Banks fully embody the three characteristics of the issuing bank, the bank&#39;s bank and the country&#39;s bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The People&#39;s Bank of China subsequently separated its financial regulatory functions and established the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the China Insurance Regulatory Commission, and the China Banking Regulatory Commission to focus on formulating and implementing monetary and macro-prudential policies and maintaining financial stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reform continues. In 2023, according to the State Council&#39;s institutional reform plan, the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s daily supervision responsibilities for financial holding companies and other financial groups and related financial consumer protection responsibilities will be transferred to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau; the relevant functions of the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s county (city) branches will be transferred to China Prefecture (city) central branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China. This reflects the direction and measures to further accelerate the construction of China&#39;s modern central bank system in the new historical period. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Science&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Technology is an important driving force for reform&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that the service methods of China’s banking system are showing a trend of intelligence. In recent years, it has become a consensus that there is no finance without technology. As a deputy governor of the central bank who was once in charge of the science and technology department, what role do you think technology has played in the reform of the financial system so far? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back on the 45 years of China’s financial reform and opening up, it has been 45 years of accompanying global technological progress and keeping up with the pace of technological progress. It can be said that it is the important driving force of science and technology that enables my country&#39;s financial system represented by banks to continuously adapt to the reform and development of the economy and provide the society with more adaptable and effective financial services. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the early days of reform and opening up, are you interested in applying financial technology? At this stage, what are the characteristics of China’s financial technology? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As early as the mid-1980s, the People&#39;s Bank of China took the lead in establishing a leading group for the electronicization of the financial system and established the &quot;Sixth Five-Year Plan&quot; Make preparations, lay the foundation in the Seventh Five-Year Plan, increase the scale in the Eighth Five-Year Plan, and basically achieve the overall goal of electronics in the Ninth Five-Year Plan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this stage, the financial industry mainly relies on scientific and technological means such as computer technology and network technology to improve the efficiency of traditional financial services and reduce operating costs. One is electronic operation. The second is system networking. The third is standardization. Bank cards are a successful example of unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benefiting from reform and opening up and technological progress, my country&#39;s financial electronic construction has achieved a historic breakthrough of &quot;from scratch, from manual to electronic, from stand-alone to networked&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the guidance of top-level design, my country’s financial informatization construction has begun to enter the fast lane. Financial informatization and financial standardization are also closely linked to international financial regulatory cooperation. I have been fortunate enough to participate in and witness many major informatization events in the financial industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;哪个事件令你印象最为深刻？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The application and promotion of financial IC cards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the increase in the amount of funds managed by bank cards and the continuous development of information technology, magnetic stripe cards have gradually become an attack target for criminals due to their weaknesses such as lack of computing power and easy information copying. object. Technical experiments and global practical experience show that after the UK, France and other countries and regions completed the migration of financial IC cards, the risk of bank card fraud has dropped significantly. On the contrary, those countries and regions that have not carried out the migration of financial IC cards in a timely manner may become a depression for global bank card security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the rapid development of my country&#39;s bank card industry and the completion of the migration of financial IC cards in neighboring countries and regions, some counterfeit card fraud activities have gradually penetrated into my country. Accelerating the application of financial IC cards has become a top priority to improve my country&#39;s bank card risk prevention and control levels and ensure people&#39;s payment safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at the application and promotion of financial IC cards, you What is your greatest experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back on this arduous journey, I deeply realize that the significance of the promotion and application of financial IC cards is not only from the perspective of security protection.角度，降低伪卡欺诈损失，保护了老百姓的钱袋子，还在推动移动金融、普惠金融和绿色金融的发展以及促进国内产业链升级等方面发挥了重要作用。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, it lays the foundation for improving the availability and convenience of financial services for the people; on the other hand, the People&#39;s Bank of China has also been actively supporting my country&#39;s technologies and products with independent intellectual property rights. . For example, we can build experimental environments and pilots to verify the application of national encryption algorithms on financial IC cards. This provides application scenarios and contributes to technological development and progress in key domestic fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Regulation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Mutual Finance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Risk&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;At the same time promote bank digitalization&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Internet finance has grown wildly, but it also represents a trend. What do you think about participating in the special rectification work on Internet financial risks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2015, with the consent of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, ten ministries and commissions including the People&#39;s Bank of China issued the &quot;Guidance on Promoting the Healthy Development of Internet Finance&quot; Opinion&quot;. The document clarifies the need to strengthen self-discipline in the Internet finance industry, requiring the People&#39;s Bank of China to work with relevant departments to establish the China Internet Finance Association and give full play to the positive role of the industry&#39;s self-discipline mechanism in regulating the market behavior of practitioners and protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the industry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I accepted the organizational arrangement and was responsible for the preparation of the China Internet Finance Association and participated in the special rectification of Internet financial risks. I witnessed the process of the industry from chaos, rectification to standardized development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As an industry self-regulatory organization,: China Internet Finance Association regulates Internet finance What are the main principles? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In April 2016, the State Council issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for Special Rectification of Internet Financial Risks&quot;, which was jointly rectified by the People&#39;s Bank of China and other 17 ministries and commissions Illegal and irregular behaviors in the field of Internet finance and promote the standardized and orderly development of Internet finance. Since its establishment, the Internet Finance Association has invested in special risk rectification work in accordance with the arrangements of the State Council and the People&#39;s Bank of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2016, the state has actively promoted the digital transformation of banks while organizing and carrying out special rectification of risks in the Internet financial industry and guiding the standardized development of the industry. As an industry self-regulatory organization, the association mainly works in four aspects to establish self-discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen the construction of basic systems and self-discipline rules. By establishing business systems and system platforms such as statistical monitoring, reporting, registration disclosure, information sharing, and financial advertising monitoring, we provide basic services for the industry to unify standards, standardize operations, and prevent risks, and also provide timely notification and relevant information to central and local financial regulatory authorities. Monitoring information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to formulate and promote the implementation of relevant standard rules. Taking the prevention of Internet financial risks and financial consumer protection as the starting point, we will promote the implementation of regulatory policies and ensure the implementation of policies through standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to carry out statistical monitoring and risk warning. Cooperate with the National Bureau of Statistics to promote the implementation of relevant statistical systems, cooperate with financial regulatory authorities to continuously monitor relevant risk areas, grasp the risk base, and publish risks on virtual currencies, cash loans, initial coin offerings (ICOs), illegal or illegal financial advertising and other activities Early warning reminder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to cooperate with the country in carrying out infrastructure construction in the financial industry. In accordance with the overall plan and regulatory requirements for the development of the national credit reporting market, the association organized all participating units to prepare at all stages, and in February 2018, they obtained the country&#39;s first commercial institution license to carry out personal credit reporting business, and went public for business in the same year. . This provides a new channel for various financial institutions to conduct personal credit inquiries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Handle the relationship between service entity&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;economic&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and risk prevention&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the Internet financial risks are gradually cleared, the financial industry, which is accelerating digital transformation, should What risks are guarded against? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Digital finance will not change the functional attributes and risk attributes of finance, but the inherent attributes of digital technology itself and its wide application in the financial field will bring With the recent openness and interaction, the modern financial field will inevitably face the superimposed impact of multiple risks such as business, technology, network, and data while gaining speed and convenience. During this period, the concealment, suddenness and diffusion of risks will become more prominent, thus posing more new challenges to modern financial supervision and social stability. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The digital transformation of my country&#39;s banks is showing a rapid development trend, as shown in the following: First, technology-driven development is more prominent. Second, demand leadership is more common. Third, industry integration is closer. Fourth, risk management is more urgent. Therefore, in the process of transformation of the banking industry, on the one hand, it must actively face and embrace the opportunities and challenges brought by the application of new technologies, and at the same time, it must establish a stronger awareness of risk prevention and strengthen safety construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for the reform and opening up of the financial industry? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Thousands of sails passed by the side of the sunken boat, and thousands of trees grew in front of the diseased trees. China&#39;s financial reform has gone through 45 years and has achieved great achievements that have attracted the attention of the world. Looking back on the past, I have four profound insights: First, we must always adhere to the leadership of the party and use correct ideological principles to guide financial reform and opening up. Second, we must always adhere to the people-oriented approach. The supply of financial products and services must not be divorced from the reasonable needs of the people at any time, and attention must be paid to protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the people. The third is to always insist on respecting market laws, based on the country&#39;s national conditions, and realistically handling the relationship between serving the real economy and preventing risks. Fourth, we must always adhere to the application of technology to drive financial development and improve the quality and efficiency of financial services and financial supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking to the future, financial reform is still on the way and there is a long way to go. As long as we continue to work in the right direction of reform and opening up, China&#39;s financial industry will continue to forge ahead and write a new chapter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从庇隆主义到奥地利学派：米莱将带领阿根廷走向何方？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261377]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Argentina’s general election was announced, and Javier Millay, the candidate of the right-wing electoral alliance “Freedom Forward Party” won, the news out, domestic critics generally looked down upon it. Argentina has slipped from developed countries and is stuck in the quagmire of populism, inflation and poverty. The president elected now advocates shutting down many government ministries, privatizing prisons, blowing up the central bank... Are the Argentine people crazy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foreign political and economic circles are not so pessimistic. After Milais was elected, governments from all over the world expressed congratulations. Former US President Trump (Millais is often regarded as &quot;Argentina&#39;s Trump&quot;) said that he would make Argentina great again. Musk was more direct: Argentina’s prosperity is coming. The Argentine stock market soared by more than 22% that day. In addition to domestic investors, foreign investors were also very excited. Millay&#39;s election as president of Argentina was seen by many as an opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The domestic media’s introduction of Milai is not a distortion. Those sensational statements do belong to Milai. The expectations of the bullish are also serious. Compared with previous Argentine presidents, Milai is refreshing and is regarded as the most important force for change in Argentina in recent years, and this change does not necessarily lead to disaster. To understand this requires a deep understanding of Millais himself and his philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Millais is a follower of Rothbard&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Millais came from a commoner class. His mother was a housewife and his father was a bus driver. He majored in economics in college and has been making a living doing it ever since. He has taught at universities, consulted for companies, worked as an economist at HSBC Bank, and worked in international organizations... Compared to academics in the academy, Millais has richer experiences.在社交媒体时代，米莱在网上犀利点评，嬉笑怒骂，收获一大批粉丝，成为阿根廷著名的网红经济学家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Millais officially entered the political arena. He joined the &quot;Liberal Party&quot; founded by his supporters as a political amateur, served as the party chairman, and integrated with another right-wing political party to form the influential &quot;Liberal Party&quot; Freedom Forward Party&quot;. In 2021, Milley was elected to the House of Representatives. In 2023, he ran for president and succeeded in one fell swoop. Millais accumulated energy on the Internet, which is certainly an important reason for his success; but his real source of power is his political and economic ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millais is a believer in the Austrian School of Economics - an economic school tasked with defending the free market that originated in the Austro-Hungarian Empire in the 19th century. The Austrian School continued to develop through debates with various interventionist ideas. Its representative figures were the economist Mises and later Rothbard. Rothbard inherited Mises&#39;s economics, also developed libertarian theory, and participated in the founding of the Liberal Party, the third largest political party in the United States today. Millais&#39;s spiritual mentor was Rothbard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millais once said that after reading &quot;Man, the Economy, and the State&quot; (Rothbard&#39;s most important economics work), he deeply realized that the economics knowledge he learned in college was all problematic. The root cause of Argentina&#39;s long-term disaster is that the entire country is shrouded in a haze of interventionism. The previous Peronism and the subsequent Kirchnerism were nothing more than a mixture of populism, trade protectionism, Keynesianism, welfarism and other ideas. These ideas bring about endless inflation, monopoly and scarcity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以奥地利学派为思想武器，米莱常年抨击国内经济政策，吸引大众关注，这是他作为经济学家的本职。 As a true disciple of Rothbard, it is not surprising that Millais sided with absolute individual rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this election campaign, Milley had no intention of concealing his true views when talking about controversial topics (and there was no way to hide it, as he has been known as a loudmouth online for many years). This may be his campaign strategy: to create an outspoken persona and gain more attention. Spread political opinions amidst controversy and build your own base. Trump has also used this strategy. Campaigning is a stage show, governing is another matter. Milley&#39;s real focus is the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Thirteen-point policy plan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, Argentina launched the primary election for the general election, and Milais submitted a policy plan including thirteen measures. Almost all of these measures are related to the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first measure is to significantly reduce Argentina’s 18 ministries and commissions, retaining 8 ministries and commissions including interior affairs, foreign affairs, national defense, economy, justice, security, infrastructure, and human resources. As crazy as it sounds, the reality is that Argentina is currently experiencing economic difficulties, with a large number of departments nearly paralyzed and employees idle. The reform is not about cutting it off, but about stopping new recruitment and not laying off employees in the short term, but about redistributing personnel. Retainers are not subject to renewal unless privileged services (such as bodyguards and drivers) are withdrawn due to absolute necessity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The measure also includes a plan to privatize state-owned enterprises - by selling state-owned assets to fill the government&#39;s shortfall and compensate laid-off workers. It doesn&#39;t seem too outrageous upon closer inspection. The remaining dozen measures include: cutting public expenditures and reducing fiscal deficits; flexibilizing labor laws to reduce employment costs for enterprises; implementing unilateral free trade and canceling import tariffs; canceling the central bank and dollarizing the Argentine peso; implementing energy reforms and reducing investment in new products. Energy subsidies; attracting long-term foreign investment; abolishing exchange rate and export quota controls...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each measure is remarkable and has the same direction: reducing government controls and increasing market vitality. The core and most controversial aspect here is monetary policy. &quot;Blowing up the central bank&quot; and using US dollars has left many scholars, especially the domestic public, stunned. How can a sovereign country not have its own central bank? Those who are surprised do not realize that in the monetary systems of various countries, in addition to the central bank system where the country independently issues currency, there is also a currency board system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The currency board system means that the domestic currency establishes an anchor relationship with the currencies of other countries based on foreign exchange reserves, and the private sector can exchange it at any time at a fixed rate. The national currency becomes the token that anchors the currency. This system has its drawbacks - for example, if a country&#39;s currency is tied to the US dollar, it has to bear the cost of US dollar inflation. The advantages are also obvious: it restricts the government&#39;s power to print money and protects the economy from domestic inflation; if the government wants to have sufficient foreign exchange reserves, it must live within its means and cannot engage in large-scale deficit finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, Argentina also implemented a currency board system, and the inflation rate once dropped to less than 5%. However, the government continued to spend extravagantly, leading to financial collapse. In 2002, the country restarted its central bank and once again launched a currency flood. Today&#39;s Argentina is a country with extremely serious inflation. The annual inflation rate reaches more than double digits, and the monetary system must be restarted every few decades. In 2022, Argentina’s inflation rate will exceed 140%. Under such a monetary system, the banknotes in the hands of the people become useless paper every once in a while, so how can they save and invest? Launching a new binding regime became an acceptable option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To switch the currency system, we must talk about technical solutions. Argentina’s foreign exchange reserves are about 30 billion US dollars, its foreign debt is nearly 300 billion US dollars, and the people have almost no US dollars in their hands. How can we talk about dollarization? Milley&#39;s plan is to sell state-owned assets, introduce foreign investment, fill the debt deficit, and accumulate foreign exchange reserves; suspend the issuance of national currency, allow the circulation of U.S. dollars, and drive out bad currency with market-oriented good currency to form a real exchange rate. After the market stabilizes, the official government&#39;s official exchange rate between the Argentine peso and the US dollar will form an anchor - this is the general framework of the currency board system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentina is a medium-sized country with a population of 46 million, but it allows the US dollar to circulate within the country and its own currency becomes a vassal? It&#39;s hard for many people to understand. But the fact is that dollarization is not unacceptable in some countries where governance has failed. Panama, Ecuador and El Salvador in Latin America all use the US dollar. Venezuela and the United States are sworn enemies. The country’s currency, the Bolivar, has been inflated several times and has become nothing more than useless paper. The public uses U.S. dollars for transactions widely. The government has no choice but to accept the status quo, effectively giving up its monetary sovereignty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通货膨胀是阿根廷经济弊病的症结。 The government issues excessive amounts of money, spends excessively, and distributes welfare benefits indiscriminately, fueling a populist trend. Argentina has difficulty obtaining international aid, and foreign investment is unwilling to go there. The entire country is starving for food. Only by tightening the monetary gate can there be real economic reform. “Blowing up the central bank” sounds crazy, but it’s actually not outrageous. Can the scoffers offer a better solution? At least in the current Argentine political arena, Milley&#39;s thinking is the clearest. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Can Mi Lai succeed? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In other areas, Millais also has solutions. The free market is the principle direction and compromise is the solution. Some people criticize Milais for compromising, but I don&#39;t take it seriously. Millais at this time was not an economist, but a politician. Regardless of whether you are tough or compromise, you have to adjust according to the current situation. A slow, incremental reform is better than a rapid miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next few years, Argentina’s civil servants, state-owned enterprises and public service system, in order to keep their iron rice bowl, will surely stand up to obstruct the reform; people whose interests have been harmed in the economy will also join the ranks of opposition. Argentina is surrounded by mostly left-wing countries, and they are powerful supporters of Millais opponents. If reforms are vigorously promoted in various fields, Argentina is bound to be in a state of upheaval. Does Milai have such trading skills? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reform requires progress, and economic growth also takes time. Even if Milley does everything right, he himself is likely to step down quickly. The &quot;Freedom Forward Party&quot; has no significant advantage during the election and needs to form alliances with other parties to govern. Milley&#39;s own base is not solid, and it is questionable whether he can win over enough supporters in five years. Argentina has a tradition of military coups. Will the military take advantage of the chaos to oust him? These are issues that transcend economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ever since Millais entered politics, it has been destined that he cannot be just a scholar. He needs to become a politician and even a strongman to put Argentina on the track of development. The 21st century is no longer the era of strong men, and Milai is no longer Pinochet. It is worth observing how far Argentina&#39;s reforms can go. Argentina is a model for middle-class countries, and its success or failure in reform will have an exemplary impact on Latin America and even more countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, let’s discuss a topic: In a country like Argentina with a strong left-wing atmosphere for a long time, why can a weirdo like Milai come to power? His outstanding abilities are certainly very important in the social media era.社会思潮酝酿，也是重要的因素。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After World War II, Argentina’s economy stagnated for a long time under the rule of Peronism. Various interventionism took turns, but the economy did not improve. The brief economic bright spot during this period was the liberalization reforms in the early 1990s. Entering the new century, Argentina entered the Kirchner era. Economically, it continued Peronist control habits, and the economy was sluggish for a long time. Politically, the Kirchners took turns in power for more than ten years. In this dull atmosphere, Milai, a political amateur, brought an innovative atmosphere and made people shine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Argentina’s foundation of free thought cannot be ignored. In 1959, Mises, the master figure of the Austrian School, visited Argentina and delivered many speeches, which planted the seeds of free thought in contemporary Argentine academic circles. The Austrian school is not considered mainstream in the international economics community, but it is very active in Argentina. There are elements of economist communication, and the ubiquitous regulations in Argentina often resonate with listeners. Millay&#39;s popularity among young people in Argentina is no accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentina also has its own roots in liberal thought. In the 19th century, a group of politicians who believed in classical liberalism emerged in Argentina. Political thinker Juan Alverdi was a diplomat. He absorbed advanced ideas from Europe and returned to his country to lead the formulation of the constitution, explaining that Argentina should be founded on immigration and trade and integrate into the global market. Sarmiento was the first civilian president. He abolished the hierarchical system left by European colonists and advocated transforming the country through free trade and urbanization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar thinkers were not uncommon in early Argentina. The country&#39;s ability to enter the ranks of developed countries in the early 20th century was the result of generations of forefathers, who enjoyed high prestige in the minds of their own people. Millais was well versed in economic history. He exploited the classical liberal resources of his nation, cited classics, and occupied the moral high ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the election victory, Milai once again called for embracing Alvedi, returning to the concept of limited government, and restoring the glory that the nation should have. &quot;Make Argentina great again&quot; is not just a copycat, but what many Argentines really think. At any time, nationalism is a banner with appeal. The key depends on where it points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>