<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[俄罗斯铝业公司创始人奥列格·德里帕斯卡：没有特斯拉汽车，大家还是会活下去的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259777]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mandarin Oriental Hotel is located on Wangfujing Street in Beijing, overlooking the Forbidden City. On the evening of October 25, 2023, in the luxurious conference hall box on the fifth floor, Oleg Deripaska, the founder of Rusal, was waiting for the visiting media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oleg Deripaska was once the founder of the world&#39;s largest aluminum company. In the interview, he claimed to be a &quot;Soviet-era physicist&quot; and graduated from the Physics Department of Moscow State University in his early years. After the collapse of the Soviet Union, academic funding dropped sharply, and there were no subsidies or grants, which made it impossible for him to continue physics research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving school, he and his colleagues established a trading company to export metals from Russia. Later, he used the first pot of gold he earned to acquire the third largest electrolytic aluminum plant in Russia, which became his The starting point of your career. Later, through asset merger, he established the world&#39;s largest aluminum company, Rusal. This company was listed in Hong Kong in 2015, becoming the first Russian company to be listed in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2018, the United States imposed sanctions on Deripaska and 23 other Russian tycoons and officials, and he was included in the United States&#39; Specially Designated Nationals List (SDN). After entering this list, the Office of Foreign Assets Control under the U.S. Department of the Treasury will freeze its property and property interests within the jurisdiction of the United States. U.S. citizens and entities located in the United States are generally prohibited from conducting any form of transaction or business with individuals or entities on the SDN list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This list affects not only the individuals or entities on the list, but also third parties with whom they do business. Transactions with entities on the list may result in violations of U.S. sanctions regulations, thereby Face legal consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oleg Deripaska was sanctioned by Australia, Canada, EU countries, the United Kingdom and other countries after the Russia-Ukraine conflict began. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1589&quot; height= &quot;1192&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Russian aluminum king Oleg Deripaska. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhou Yubo/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the purpose of your visit to China this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am a member of the Board of Trustees of Lomonosov Moscow State University. We visited BIT Moscow State University in Shenzhen , a joint university founded by Lomonosov Moscow State University and Beijing Institute of Technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have opened an International Business School, as well as a School of Mathematics and Physics. Previously, Moscow State University held an international class. About twenty or thirty students from different countries came to Moscow State University to study mathematics and physics, and 30% of them were Chinese students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russian mathematics education is the best in the world, and we hope to promote such academic exchanges. At the same time, Chinese students can learn Russian, and Russian students can learn Chinese. We need to invest in transportation facilities and financial facilities, but we also need to invest in science education. Some scientific projects may not seem very important now, but in twenty or fifty years, they will become the key to the development of human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you view the current fluctuations in the ruble? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The problem of ruble fluctuations certainly exists because we now have a military conflict, but Russia’s settlement balance is still very powerful. As long as there are no major conflicts in the next two or three years, ruble fluctuations will not be a big problem, because Russia&#39;s resource industry is still quite good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of the year, you thought Russia needed to welcome more people from Investment from friendly countries, so what else can be done to promote cooperation between Chinese and Russian enterprises? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First, it takes time. The foundation of economic cooperation between the two countries is trust. We already have a foundation of trust. . Previously, 70% of Russian industry relied on European technology. Now it still takes time to transform, change our national standards, and cooperate with our friendly countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have a problem, you must solve it in time, and don&#39;t let it accumulate later. Entrepreneurs, including me, have raised this question before, why is Russia’s foreign trade so unbalanced? 80% comes from Europe and 20% comes from Asia. We need to find a balance. In the next two or three years, we will work hard to solve the problems that have not been solved before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, we must invest in infrastructure, not just logistics facilities, but also financial platforms. The financial platform is not just a settlement issue. The two countries have learned how to settle in their own currencies, but the debt market has not yet achieved the results we want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, the Russian automobile industry began to talk about import substitution, but they did not start to do it until the problems had arisen. Five or 10 years ago, it was unimaginable that the United States would do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the sanctions imposed on you by the United States seriously affected your life? Will it affect you psychologically? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a psychological point of view, I don’t think it has a big impact. I served in the army during the Soviet period and encountered even more severe situations. Since then, I have had a different attitude and understanding of danger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why were you sanctioned by the US Treasury Department? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2017, one of my companies was listed in London and successfully attracted US$2 billion in investment. Five months later, my company and I were included in the sanctions list. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They mentioned various excuses, but in fact there was no legal reason to put me on the sanctions list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One excuse is that at the Davos Forum in Dalian, I gave a speech that mentioned the establishment of a unified energy market in the East, but the real theme of my speech was to promote the development of nuclear energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, aluminum prices rose by 70%, and speculators made a lot of money. This goes to show that if you don&#39;t take into account the dangers and hope for a good partnership, sooner or later the dangers will materialize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height= &quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2021, in Washington, DC, the United States, the FBI searched several properties of Oleg Deripaska. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will sanctions affect the lives of you and your family? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For me personally, there is no impact at all. From a young age, I didn’t have many material needs. For others, especially if their children study abroad, the impact is quite large. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have been sanctioned very early. Have any friends come to you to ask for advice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have extensive experience in dealing with sanctions from Western countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My conclusion is to invest in countries that do not rely on the Western financial system. If there is an extreme conflict between any country and the United States, no one will abide by the law, and these real estate and projects will be taken away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you feel sad when your property is taken away? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To be honest, I don’t have any special feelings. I am not a person who cares about material things very much. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How can we not worry about being sanctioned?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Without independence, this will always be a problem. If you just lack certain supplies, you can still survive in five or ten years. I think the world is aware of this danger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is the independence you are talking about a kind of isolationism? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course not. We are facing global problems, such as climate change, poverty, disease, etc. However, sanctions will not promote the development of a certain country. Only trust between countries, only economic cooperation and mutually beneficial development between countries can solve these global problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will Western sanctions make the sanctioned countries change their policies? Will not. Everyone would still be able to survive without Tesla cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, these sanctions will make us rethink our own development and fill some loopholes and shortcomings. For example, promoting the development of transportation and logistics, improving our financial market, and conducting settlement in local currency. We must build a new international security system and a new international relations system to avoid new crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous world was centered on the West, that is, all technologies and investments were initially determined by Western countries, which also led to many regional conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不清楚孩子上了什么学，回家陪读三年仅是一次情感弥补？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259687]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Downstairs where I work, there is a circle of shops, including restaurants, small supermarkets, fruit and vegetable shops, and morning stalls. The shop... is surrounded by an industrial park, and there is only one commercial place around. It is very lively here during meals and commuting, and these shops are running well. I have been working here since the building was built, and most of these shops have been operating here since the beginning, so I know many of the merchants and often chat with them while shopping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years ago, the proprietress of the Shaxian snack bar downstairs returned to Fujian to accompany her children in high school. Recently, I saw her when I was eating at a snack bar in Shaxian County, and asked, &quot;Are you back from studying with me?&quot; She said, &quot;Back!&quot; I asked again, &quot;Which university did your child go to after the college entrance examination?&quot; She scratched her head and answered. : &quot;I don&#39;t know!&quot; I asked: &quot;You have been studying with your child for three years, and you have achieved results after three years. You don&#39;t know what your results are?&quot; She still shook her head and said, &quot;I really don&#39;t know...anyway ...It seems to be from our side...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, I went to the small supermarket nearby to buy something. The small supermarket was run by a couple, they were from Anhui, and the male owner I am explaining to the hostess, don’t forget to transfer living expenses to the child. I asked, &quot;Is your child going to college?&quot; They nodded and said they just went to college this year. I continued to ask: &quot;Which university does the child go to?&quot; The male host lowered his head and thought for a moment, and said, &quot;I can&#39;t remember either.&quot; I looked at the hostess, and she said, &quot;Don&#39;t ask me, I can&#39;t either.&quot; I know...&quot; the male host interjected, &quot;He said he was in Chengdu... studying design... or something else...&quot; I couldn&#39;t help but be dumbfounded and joked: &quot;You two don&#39;t know what&#39;s important! You two only know how to transfer it to your children. Living expenses!&quot; They both looked at each other, not understanding what I was laughing at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, most couples or one spouse works outside the home and the children study in their hometown. If one spouse works outside the home, the life of the spouse at home will focus on the child&#39;s studies and spend time accompanying them to school. Both husband and wife work outside the home, and many people choose to go back to study with their children at some important stages and moments, such as the third year of junior high school, the third year of high school, etc. This is all in the hope that by accompanying them to study, they can help their children learn so that they can get into the ideal school. However, when I heard that the proprietress of a snack bar in Shaxian County accompanied her child to high school for three years and did not know what university the child finally went to, I thought that the effectiveness of accompanying him to study is questionable. It should be about the same whether he studies with him or not. , the three years of accompanying her were probably just an emotional make-up. When I heard that the couple in the small supermarket did not know the school and major their children were studying in, I was thinking that this seemed to be someone else’s business. The essence of university education is to pay for living expenses with your head covered. It is an education that is at a loss. invest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before yesterday, I called a water station downstairs and asked the store to send me a bucket of bottled water. The store responded that it could not be delivered, and there was no one in the store. The child was about to enter high school, and the wife went home to study with the child. If she wanted water, she would bring it herself. Originally, I could call another water station to have water delivered, but after the previous two experiences and my thinking, I immediately decided to go downstairs to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the water station and asked the shopkeeper: &quot;Why does your wife want to go home to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Then everyone is accompanying you, so it&#39;s impossible for us not to accompany you!&quot; the shopkeeper replied . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do when I go back to study with me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do, cook, wash clothes, supervise my children not to play with mobile phones...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Like this Is it interesting to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shop owner chuckled: &quot;We don&#39;t know about that... They say it&#39;s difficult to take the high school entrance examination now... I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t be able to pass...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not an educator myself , but I think there are some basic intellectual things that should be similar. I said to the shopkeeper, take the notes and I will tell you what time it is. I told him with my fingers: 1. Clarify your child&#39;s learning goals, which can be specific to which school he wants to attend, and understand the school&#39;s enrollment plan, enrollment requirements, and performance requirements. requirements and performance requirements as the program; 2. Maintain close contact with school teachers, understand the school’s learning progress and children’s learning situation, and solve possible learning problems in a timely manner. The basic problems should be grasped and the difficult problems should be overcome. ; 3. Your spouse should establish a good work and rest system, and supervise the child to balance work and rest during the learning process. When it is time to study and when it is time to rest, if you want the child not to play with mobile phones, first of all, she must not play with the mobile phone while the child is studying; 4. Don&#39;t use your emotional compensation as a moral standard to ask your children. Encourage your children to learn, but you must also respect your children&#39;s willingness to learn. 5. Caring for your children is long-term. It does not end when you enter high school in the future. Children are independent. However, your child&#39;s study and life are not independent. They are an expression of your family&#39;s common wishes and are closely related to your daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I finished speaking, and the shopkeeper also finished memorizing it, but he blinked, not knowing whether he understood or not. I told him that we would continue the discussion the next time I came to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading to your children is not just about doing laundry and cooking, nor is it as easy a job as sitting aside and playing with your mobile phone while asking your children to do homework and answer mock tests. What is the goal, what are the plans to achieve the goal, how to correct errors in the process of implementing the plan, how to achieve long-term emotional interaction after the plan is realized, how to make up for the failure of the plan, etc. These issues should be considered by the accompanying parents. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a fruit and vegetable shop downstairs. The proprietress of the fruit and vegetable shop also came back from school soon. I asked her: &quot;How did my child do in the exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She replied: &quot;I passed the exam. But the school is not very good, and the child has to repeat the year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked: &quot;Will you no longer accompany me during the repeat year?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said: &quot;I won&#39;t accompany you anymore. , I’ve had enough company, it’s up to him how he does in the next year’s exam, let him go!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s dinner time, people in the industrial park and people upstairs all come upstairs It&#39;s time to eat and consume, and the merchants are busy again. Looking at them being busy, I think about the children behind them who are still studying. I don’t know which universities, high schools or other places of study those children are in. I just hope that they will be healthy in body and mind and make progress every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a practitioner in Shanghai fruit industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦直播间卖假和田玉？谈谈玉的文化、国标及科学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After online anchor Li Jiaqi was accused by JD.com’s purchasing staff of forcing him to “choose one from two” and questioned the alleged monopoly, he went on a professional crackdown on counterfeiting Wang Hai also questioned whether the Hetian jade sold in Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast room was fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jade is a unique culture in China. The Chinese ancestors selected the &quot;beautiful stones&quot; from various stones. Jade is warm, shiny, meticulous and tough, so it is also considered by the Chinese to be benevolent and benevolent. Justice, wisdom, courage, and purity are the five moral qualities. Wearing jade has the effect of preventing evil spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese ancestors’ understanding of jade can be traced back to the Neolithic Age. Humans ground stone tools as tools for chopping and scraping, hunting, and cutting meat. Some ground stone tools showed a smooth and beautiful appearance, and humans began to have a preliminary understanding of jade. This also marks the beginning of the transition of human beings from material needs to spiritual needs. Archaeological research has found that in the late Neolithic Age, many jade products and jade ornaments appeared. At this time, the ancients had realized that jade and stone had completely different functions and aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 3000 BC, jade craftsmanship was separated from stone tool processing technology and became an independent craft category. Based on the production traces left on the jades unearthed from the Hongshan Cultural Site and the Liangzhu Cultural Site, experts have inferred that a rotating jade processing tool - a weight machine - had appeared at that time. This is no different in principle from the jade processing machines we see now. The Shang and Zhou dynasties were the growth stage of Chinese jade art. The scope of use of jade expanded, and the number and types increased significantly. However, the shapes were still very simple, with only sporadic decorations. Hotan jade also appeared in this era for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period, the art of jade carving developed. At that time, scholar-bureaucrats wore a series of jade ornaments all over their bodies. What reflected the spirit of the times at that time were a large number of jade pendants in the shapes of dragons, phoenixes and tigers, with complex and beautiful shapes and strong Chinese style and national characteristics. The jade pieces of the Tang Dynasty are all treasures. The craftsmanship was further developed and refined. The texture is warm and the luster is soft. Gold and jade complement each other, making them rich and elegant. In the Song Dynasty, jade gradually entered people&#39;s lives. Influenced by calligraphy and painting at that time, the style became more realistic and full of life. During the Ming and Qing Dynasties, jade art reached its peak, and various types of exquisite jade articles emerged in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The definition of real jade and non-real jade has long been reflected in the system of jade use in Chinese history. Hotan jade is the highest level of jade, it is real jade, and is used by emperors. After countless years, Hotan jade has just entered the folk world. The one that caused the controversy this time was Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing Wang Hai’s doubts, Yuanyang Jinlou, the owner of the cargo in Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, posted the appraisal certificates, including the National Jewelry and Jade Quality Supervision and Inspection Center (NGTC), Guangdong Gold and Silver Jewelry Testing Center Co., Ltd., National Gold and Silver Products Quality Inspection and Testing Center (Nanjing) Organization, Shenzhen Zhongdi Jewelry Testing Co., Ltd. These institutions are not without authority. So, what is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the question of whether it is fake. According to Wang Hai, GB/T38821-2020 stipulates that the appraisal certificate must have total mass and physical photos, and consumers received 18 appraisal certificates attached to the necklace. Not only are each 40g, but they are also photos of a shared necklace. , then it is suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the problem of counterfeiting is easy to solve, but what is difficult to solve is the second level problem, which is the standard issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standards used by these institutions are the national Hetian jade testing standards GB/T16552-2017 and GB/T16553-2017. This 2017 standard does not clearly stipulate the specific content of tremolite. As long as the main component is tremolite, it can be named &quot;Hetian Jade&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hai adopts another standard, namely GB/T 38831-2020. The GB/T38821-2020 &quot;Hetian Jade Identification and Classification&quot; launched in 2020 was developed by the State Administration for Market Regulation and China Released by the National Standardization Administration Committee, it is the latest national standard for the Hetian jade industry. The mineral composition of Hetian jade is described as: &quot;Mainly composed of tremolite, the secondary mineral can be actinolite, and can contain a small amount of calcite, diopside, pyrite, pyrite, chromite, and magnetite. , quartz, serpentine, chlorite, epidote, wollastonite, apatite and garnet, etc.&quot; According to this standard, the naming rule is: when the percentage of other minerals in the same piece of jade is less than 5%, Hetian jade can be named directly. When the percentage of other minerals is more than 5% (except black jade), if the other minerals contained are evenly distributed and the boundaries of the mineral particles are clear, use &quot;tremolite jade&quot; with a note indicating that it contains other minerals. For example: tremolite jade (including tremolite jade) carbonates). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, things are clear. Both standards are used in the industry. The 2017 standard is more relaxed, while the 2020 standard is more stringent. However, this standard is not mandatory and is only a recommended standard. Jade sellers adopted the loose standards introduced in 2017, saying that their items were Hetian jade; while Wang Hai, who fights against counterfeiters, adopted a stricter standard in 2020, saying that the jade sold by Li Jiaqi was fake and did not meet the standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, jade has been difficult to identify clearly since ancient times. What exactly is jade? In fact, many people don&#39;t understand. When we talk about what a thing is, it is actually a chemical question. Chemistry is the study of the composition of matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a chemical perspective, jade is actually a mixture. When we talk about gold, we refer to the material composed of gold atoms; when we talk about quartz, we refer to silicon dioxide; when we talk about ice, we refer to dihydrogen monoxide. Of course, minerals are mixed with other impurities, but in an abstract sense, these things are composed of single atoms or single compound molecules. But jade, in an abstract sense, is a mixture. For example, just like when we talk about Chinese medicinal soup and borscht soup, even in an abstract sense, it must be a mixture of multiple ingredients. Therefore, jade is a mixture, which is a mixture of two or more compounds and elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this concept, it is easier to understand jade. Jade has different chemical compositions, different colors, and different types. The chemical composition of jadeite is sodium aluminum silicate, the most representative of which is jadeite. The chemical composition of nephrite is hydrous calcium magnesium silicate, the most representative of which is Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Hetian jade has four main mineral components: silicon, aluminum, iron and magnesium. Silicon accounts for a large proportion of Hetian jade, and its main forms are calcium silicate (CaSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), magnesium silicate (MgSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), and sodium disilicate (Na&lt; sub>;2&lt;/sub>;Si&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;5&lt;/sub>;), etc.; the aluminum element is mainly albite (NaAlSi&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>; 8&lt;/sub>;), and also contains a small amount of aluminum silicate; iron mainly exists in the form of potassium ferroaluminate and iron silicate. It can be seen that Hetian jade has many ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charm of jade, its appeal to people in terms of look and feel, stems from this characteristic of jade&#39;s chemical composition. This has also caused various confusions in the naming, identification, and even price of jade. Some people say that the wholesale price of jade sold by Li Jiaqi is only a few dozen yuan. But then again, the wholesale price of tens of thousands of jade in those tourist attractions and jewelry stores may only be a few hundred yuan or less. This is the characteristic of the jade industry. As the old saying goes, &quot;Gold has a price, jade is priceless.&quot; This does not mean that gold is not as valuable as jade, and jade is a priceless treasure. It means that the price of jade has been confusing and confusing since ancient times, and the profits are often abnormally high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room is said to have the lowest price on the entire Internet. Consumers believe it, but there is a gap between their expectations and reality. In fact, if you really want to buy cost-effective jade, the live broadcast room is not a good place. Only knowledgeable people with instruments can identify, and only with the ability to identify can we negotiate a good price. Obviously, most consumers cannot do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[过度加工食物可能成瘾并严重影响健康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCyJ69RpVgzEp0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCy J69RpVgzEp0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over-processing of food refers to industrial production and the addition of at least 5 or more ingredients, additives (usually sugar, stabilizers, preservatives, preservatives, pigments), etc., in this way Processed foods are called ultra-processed foods. Their purpose is to make them delicious and convenient, and more importantly, manufacturers can earn higher profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessively processed foods include soft drinks such as cola, bread, cakes, potato chips, pizza, biscuits, candies, burgers, instant noodles, ice cream, spicy sticks, etc. More and more research results show that the intake of overly processed foods may be harmful to human health and increase the risk of various diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recent study by Brazilian researchers suggests that overly processed foods may harm brain function. The reason is that overly processed foods contain many added and unhealthy ingredients such as sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors and preservatives. Past research has shown that overly processed foods are directly linked to an increased risk of heart disease, metabolic syndrome, and obesity, and now research is linking overly processed foods to a risk of decreased brain function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers collected data on nearly 11,000 men and women in Brazil with an average age of 52 who participated in the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health. The researchers followed them for a long time, with a median follow-up time of 8 years. The results found that participants who consumed more than 20% of their daily calories from ultra-processed foods experienced a 28% faster decline in overall cognitive function and a 25% faster decline in executive function compared to adults over 59 years old. In other words, the decline in cognitive function and executive function is more obvious among adults aged 35-59. Overall, overall cognitive functions include learning ability and memory, while executive functions include language fluency and behavioral agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the researchers admit that they cannot yet explain the mechanism by which excessively processed foods lead to reduced brain function, and there is no neuroimaging to confirm their results. Therefore, future research is to explore which overly processed foods lead to cognitive decline in the body and the molecular mechanisms behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation, however, is that when people regularly consume overly processed foods, they are less likely to get the fiber, microbes, minerals, and plants they need to stay healthy, fight off disease, and reduce inflammation. Nutrients. Ultimately, this may affect a person&#39;s brain function and functioning, as the brain requires a steady supply of these nutrients to function properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed foods have also been linked to cancer. Researchers from Imperial College London have found that high intakes of ultra-processed foods may increase an individual&#39;s risk of developing cancer and dying from cancer. Previously, a large number of studies have revealed that consuming large amounts of overly processed food will increase the incidence of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Now, British researchers have used the British Biobank to collect dietary information from 200,000 young people to study the relationship between body health and diet. This is the first such study to be conducted in the UK. The researchers monitored the people&#39;s health for 10 years, analyzing their risk of developing any cancer and 34 types of cancer, as well as the participants&#39; risk of dying from cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers conducted the most comprehensive assessment to date of the link between overly processed foods and people’s risk of developing cancer, including soda, industrially produced bread, and more. Ready-to-eat meals and most breakfast cereals. These foods often contain high levels of salt, sugar, fat, and artificial additives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that people who eat a lot of overly processed foods are at a greater risk of developing cancer. Overly processed foods are particularly related to ovarian cancer and brain cancer. They also increase an individual&#39;s risk of death from cancer, most obviously. of ovarian and breast cancer. For every 10% increase in a person&#39;s intake of overly processed foods in a person&#39;s diet, the overall risk of cancer increases by 2%, and the risk of ovarian cancer in particular increases by 19%. It is associated with a 6% increase in overall cancer mortality, a 16% increase in the risk of death from breast cancer, and a 30% increase in the risk of death from ovarian cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The association between excessively processed food intake and cancer remained after adjusting for social, economic, behavioral and dietary factors such as smoking, physical activity and body mass index (BMI). Furthermore, previous research has shown that British adults and children consume the highest amounts of ultra-processed food in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the study by British researchers cannot explain the causal relationship and mechanism between over-processed foods and cancer, they believe that existing research evidence shows that reducing the intake of over-processed foods in the daily diet may avoid Higher cancer rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed food has become widespread around the world and is addictive. A research report published in the British Medical Journal on October 9, 2023 by researchers from the United States, Brazil, and Spain pointed out that an analysis of 281 studies in 36 different countries found that 14% of adults and adults worldwide 12% of children are addicted to over-processed foods, and 1/7 adults and 1/8 children may be addicted to over-processed foods. These foods include ice cream, carbonated drinks and convenience foods, which can lead to cancer, obesity and Increased risk of heart disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the consumption of ultra-processed foods is soaring around the world, and now more than half of the daily energy intake in the UK comes from ultra-processed foods. In the United States, ultra-processed foods account for 58% of Americans’ energy intake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that so many people eat over-processed foods suggests that they are addictive. Researchers explain the addiction to over-processed foods as higher levels of dopamine secretion may lead to over-processed foods. of addiction. Extracellular dopamine levels in the brain&#39;s striatum caused by refined carbohydrates or fats are similar to those of addictive substances such as nicotine and alcohol, thus creating a craving similar to alcoholism. Therefore, foods that contain high amounts of refined carbohydrates or added fats are likely to be addictive substances. The speed at which these overly processed foods deliver carbohydrates and fats to the intestines may also play a role in their addictive nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Symptoms of addiction to over-processed foods include: strong desire to eat, withdrawal symptoms, difficulty controlling food intake, and obesity, overeating, poor physical and mental health, and reduced quality of life. Despite this, he continued to eat without restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of this suggests that the relationship between overly processed foods and health, as well as the addictive nature of such foods, should be further studied, and appropriate measures should be taken to protect people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京香山论坛：大国小国，平等对话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 10:06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Ten&#39; means maturity, perfection, harvest, and also indicates a new starting point and renewal. Let’s go.” On the morning of October 30, 2023, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, told officials from the defense departments of many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held from October 29th to 31st, reaching the highest level and largest scale in history - more than 90 official delegations from countries and international organizations participated, including 19 defense ministers , 14 military commander-level representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the podium at the opening ceremony, the &quot;ten&quot; in &quot;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum&quot; was painted in red. In the audience, foreign defense ministers, representatives of international institutions and experts are looking forward to an &quot;international security event&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/01/7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01 /7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256571&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Great powers play a more important role”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nine o’clock in the morning on October 30, the main venue on the second floor of the Beijing International Convention Center was packed with seats. Dozens of defense ministers and senior representatives from various countries in military uniforms sat in the front row of the auditorium; the back row was divided into two floors and filled with nearly a thousand experts, observers or media members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot; is marked with white letters on a blue background inside and outside the venue - this is the theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum and the core idea of ​​the Global Security Initiative in February 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Youxia pointed out that without mutual respect, it will be difficult to coexist peacefully, and common security will be out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 19 defense ministers participating in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu was the first speaker. Before the opening ceremony, Shaoyigu and Zhang Youxia walked into the main venue side by side and sat in the center of the first row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Russia-China relations are exemplary and are increasingly attractive to other countries.” Shoigu mentioned, “The circle of friends between Russia and China who do not want to be involved in the Western confrontation agenda is constantly expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a country involved in the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Shoigu’s attendance attracted much attention. He mentioned that after Russia countered NATO&#39;s eastward expansion, the United States was using Ukraine to attack Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Russia will only use nuclear weapons when it is attacked by a nuclear attack or when its national survival is threatened.&quot; Shoigu said in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the second time that Shaoyigu has attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The last time was in 2019. After the meeting, Zhang Youxia held talks with Shaoyigu at the Bayi Building in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/c2f75269a6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/c2f75269a6.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256572&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speeches of the guests at the first plenary session all closely followed the theme of &quot;Responsibility of Major Powers and Global Security Cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is important to strive for peace. In promoting global peace and security, major powers play a more important role.&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong said in the second half of the first half that major powers promote peace and make war a Obsolete things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“From Asia-Pacific to the Global”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening ceremony, defense ministers and representatives from various countries arrived in Beijing one after another. As the organizer, Zhao Xiaozhuo, deputy director of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum Secretariat, is extremely busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 21:00 on the evening of October 29, when Southern Weekend reporters met Zhao Xiaozhuo, he had just finished the welcome dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the first forum, Zhao Xiaozhuo still has fresh memories. &quot;At that time, most of the participants were scholars, and the total number of participants was only a few dozen, so it was very small.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Xiangshan Forum was founded in 2006 and is hosted by two think tanks from the Chinese military, the China Society of Military Science and the China Society for International Strategic Studies. In 2014, the forum was upgraded from track two (private) to track one and a half (semi-official, semi-private). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since then, military and political leaders and national leaders will appear every year, and the conference has been adjusted from once every two years to once a year.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to online meetings during the epidemic, the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum attracted official delegations from more than 90 countries and international organizations including Russia, the United States, Saudi Arabia, and Iran, with more than 1,800 participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 9 forums, there have been as many as 6 forums with the theme of &quot;Asia-Pacific&quot;. With the major changes in the nature of the forum, the scope of topics has also expanded from Asia-Pacific affairs to global issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xinbo, Dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University, is a frequent visitor to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. Since the first forum in 2006, he has attended the forum almost every year. He said, &quot;The theme of the forum is increasingly consistent with China&#39;s core concepts and basic principles of international security, and the topics of the sub-forums are also increasingly consistent with the current actual international security situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256573&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30 On the same day, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 30, ten small closed-door seminars were held simultaneously, covering topics such as global security governance, artificial intelligence security, and Sino-US crisis management and control. &quot;It has never happened before that ten meetings can be held at the same time.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;It is up to the participating representatives to choose which forum they want to go to, who they want to talk to, and how much they want to talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Chande, a researcher at the Institute for Defense Analyses and former deputy assistant secretary of defense, is an &quot;old friend&quot; of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and a well-known &quot;China expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I pay attention to China every day, and my understanding here may be deeper than that of the United States.” He told Southern Weekend reporters with a smile before the “Northeast Asian Order” sub-forum. The United States first sent official representatives to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum in 2015. Four years later, in 2019, then-U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense Shi Chande led a team to attend the meeting. It was the first time that a current senior U.S. military official appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the early days, the U.S. delegation’s participation in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum was relatively low, and basically only the military attache from the embassy in China was sent to participate.” Wu Xinbo recalled that as the importance and influence of the forum increased, the United States began to start from domestic Send some mid-level delegations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Similar to the Shangri-La Summit and the Munich Security Conference, an official’s rank determines his stage. This is a common international practice.” Zhao Xiaozhuo said, “After lower-level officials arrive, they are often only responsible for collecting information. Various opinions and information.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the U.S. military delegation was led by Owen Lewis, dean of the Joint Forces Staff College of the U.S. National Defense University; previously, the president of the U.S. National Defense University also led a delegation to Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Carles, senior director for China affairs in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense of the United States, took over the &quot;baton&quot; from the head of the delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The levels of Carles and Shi Chande are similar, but in terms of specific ranking, Shi Chande is higher.&quot; During the welcome dinner, Zhao Xiaozhuo specially analyzed the level setting of U.S. officials to the U.S. Navy Feng Dewei, vice president of the center, asked for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calles, the official leader of the US delegation at this forum, kept a low profile and rarely appeared in public. On the evening of October 30, she appeared at a small seminar on &quot;China-U.S. Crisis Management&quot;, but did not speak. She only briefly communicated with the participants after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;the level of the participants in the forum is not the most important matter. The communication between the two parties focuses on the substantive content.&quot; Wu Qian, spokesperson of the Ministry of National Defense, pointed out at a press conference held before the opening of the forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;International Issues &quot;Desktop Collision&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:00 on October 29, half an hour before the official start of the meeting, the conference room with less than 100 people was packed with people from all over the world. Representatives, experts and media, etc. This is a dialogue titled &quot;China&#39;s Role in Maintaining Asia-Pacific Security.&quot; Under the chairmanship of Wu Xinbo, experts from China, the United States, Russia and South Korea took their seats in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why can the Asia-Pacific maintain stability for thirty years?&quot; The host first asked the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, a former Chinese diplomat, shared &quot;the reasons for the Asia-Pacific economic miracle&quot;: peace and stability, focus on regional cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She gave data from the Bank of Asia, &quot;In the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown seven times. Nearly half of it was created by China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the United States&#39; GDP has grown seven times. Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Project at the Western Institute of National Affairs, believes that &quot;the change of power between China and the United States will bring huge uncertainty to Asia. In the next 10 to 15 years, the process of peace and stability in Asia may be disrupted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen&#39;s view was refuted by Fu Ying: &quot;Today, China is the driving force of the development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited greatly from it, but now this has become a problem?&quot; Fu Ying said, The United States has launched a &quot;China-US trade war&quot; that has more gains than losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen during the celebrity dialogue on October 29. (Photo by Yao Yijiang/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256574&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the celebrity dialogue on October 29, Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen. (Photo by Yao Yijiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Russian expert Karaganov mentioned that &quot;Russia wants to create a peaceful and stable Eurasia and Asia-Pacific.&quot; Karaganov is the dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This scene better reflects the current international security situation.” After listening to the whole process, Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Northeast Asia Security Trends and Shaping&quot; parallel forum on the afternoon of the 30th, explosive scenes took place one after another. American scholar Shi Wen and Director of the Asian and African Studies Department of the Japanese Defense Research Institute Masuda Masayuki were criticized by Chinese scholars one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Northeast Asian issue depends on the interaction of multinational relations between China, Japan, the United States, and South Korea.” Shi Wen said. He was the third speaker at this forum, and there were also scholars from China, Russia, South Korea and the UK. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen flicked the tablet on the armrest of his seat, trying to regard the North Korean nuclear issue and the Taiwan issue as the same type of regional conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the moderator of the sub-forum, Vice President of the China Institute of International Strategic Studies, and retired major general Du Nongyi made his point clear, &quot;The core of the Taiwan issue is China&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity. It has nothing to do with North Korea.&quot; Nuclear issues and other issues cannot be compared with each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half, Japanese scholar Masuda Masayuki became the target of public criticism because he blamed China for regional security problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang, senior adviser to the China Institute for International Strategic Studies, took the microphone and changed his original speech. He said that Masuda Masayuki was trying to teach the Chinese people &quot;a lesson&quot;. &quot;It is true that I am a little speechless.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang pointed out that the crux of the problem between China and Japan is rooted in Japan&#39;s psychological imbalance, trying to regard the Sino-US game as a &quot;rare opportunity&quot; to take action, and constantly pointing fingers at the Taiwan issue. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the rebuttal, Masuda Masayuki sat on the stage and smiled awkwardly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let developing countries have a voice&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the international public opinion field dominated by European and American countries, the voices of developing countries are rarely heard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although it is a global village, every country has its own goals.&quot; At the &quot;Chinese and Foreign Young Officers and Scholars Seminar&quot; on October 29, Chief Executive Officer of the Pakistan Balochistan Research and Development Think Tank Official Jawariya Tareen said frankly. The young American scholar next to her had a serious expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than seventy years, the India-Pakistan border issue has remained unresolved, and Kashmir has always been like a thorn in the relationship between the two countries. Jawariya mentioned that every time Pakistan wanted to have dialogue, India did not respond positively, and the relationship between the two sides only stopped at the think tank level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Developing countries face two major problems, one is development and the other is security.&quot; Lieutenant General He Lei of the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences told Southern Weekend reporters that in a sense, developing countries are the most important problems in today&#39;s world. The security demands of the &quot;vulnerable groups&quot; should receive more attention and reasonable concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, internationally renowned security forums include the Shangri-La Dialogue, the Halifax International Security Forum, the Munich Security Conference and the Seoul Defense Dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These forums have obvious &#39;circle&#39; attributes, and developing countries do not have much room to express themselves.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo mentioned that only the Beijing Xiangshan Forum clearly provides a stage for developing countries to fully express themselves safety concerns and demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Representatives from various countries at the main venue (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256575&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Main venue representatives of various countries. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters observed that among the parallel group meetings and seminars, 5 of them were themed on developing countries and the &quot;Global South&quot;, and more than half of the speakers were from the development community. Chinese home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Global South&quot; is not a new concept. The term was first used by American political activist Carl Oglesby as early as 1969. &quot;European and American countries are using the Global South to exclude China from developing countries and isolate China to the maximum extent.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China occupies a very critical or even core position in the global South. China&#39;s success has become the most important driving force for the global South at the international level...China has been promoting peaceful development through the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; initiative, which can What is the United States doing?&quot; Zheng Yongnian, President&#39;s Chair Professor of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), asked on the morning of October 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With concerns about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, Selchuk Chorakkoglu, the founding director of the Asia-Pacific Research Center of Turkey, came to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused nearly 10,000 deaths on both sides, and there are also hidden dangers of spillover.&quot; Selchuk told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes to discuss how to discuss the &quot;new Middle East security architecture&quot; Providing new solutions to Palestine and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessio Patalano has participated in the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore and the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing for many times. He believes that the Beijing Xiangshan Forum is more &quot;pragmatic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This professor at the Department of War Studies at King&#39;s College London is very talkative. As soon as the forum began, Alessio was interviewed for an hour by the media who came to ask for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters that providing a platform for developing countries to speak out is one of the greatest advantages of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Defense ministers and representatives from various countries came to Beijing Xiangshan Forum with the vision of seeking peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Common security and lasting peace are the basis for the common development of all countries.” Itizal Khadim, director of the Afghanistan Development and Peace Research Center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Afghanistan, Itizal is a former government official who is now a professor of modern political history. He joked to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;I came to the meeting wearing two &#39;hats.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36 million people in Afghanistan are suffering from extreme poverty and hunger. &quot;Only by creating jobs for the people, they will not turn to war.&quot; Itizal hopes that China can participate in the reconstruction of Afghanistan. &quot;China can help developing countries promote economic and social development instead of distributing gunpowder.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Liu Yaqi, Lin Xi, Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi, Feng Jiayi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4 P4YXsf2grzoKpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (third from right) in his later years with friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu ended his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; with an encounter in middle age. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At night, he was driving on a narrow highway with only one car in front of him. He lacks confidence in his driving skills, so he uses the taillights of the car in front of him as a guide to gain a sense of safety and comfort. Suddenly the car flashed its right turn signal and turned into a country road. Visible to the naked eye, he was the only one driving on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;So, only my own headlights are left to guide the way. This light can only illuminate a very small area. It is a short road, but this road, farther away, is swallowed up in darkness.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Tuan is a famous geographer and the founder of humanistic geography. One of the people. He intellectually understands the relationship between people and place and considers himself a cosmopolitan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; was written in 1999, when Duan Yifu was 69 years old, and mankind was about to enter the new millennium. He sees &quot;Who am I&quot; as the fashionable question at the dawn of the new millennium. This issue actually received increasing attention as early as the 1960s, &quot;In order to generate a solid sense of self, a person needs the past, not just the present and the future.&quot; It is worth mentioning that &quot;Silent Spring&quot; combined poetry and science in the 1960s to jointly examine the relationship between man and the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu continued to think about it and wrote important works in the next twenty years. &quot;who I am? 》 is a good stage summary, showing sincere self-examination. He seems to be getting closer and closer to a location, but he is not sure when he will arrive, or even further away. The ideal position always changes with time, space and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early 1940s, Duan Yifu and his family were preparing to move from Chongqing to Australia. During the group photo, Yifu Duan (third from left) tried to squeeze away from his younger brother and stay close to his mother to gain more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The world in his eyes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is shrinking inward &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, Yifu Tuan quoted the words of Socrates: An unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before middle age, Duan Yifu had never lived in any city for more than five years. After leaving China, he continued to move around until he moved to Minneapolis at the age of 38 and stopped to engage in academic work. Migration is inseparable from both my father&#39;s work and historical events. He believed he was rootless and &quot;born to examine himself.&quot; He never married and could not fully integrate into American society, and the issue of identity was always there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He considers himself an optimist and &quot;often places the golden age in the future.&quot; He knows that he gained his confidence early, having been relatively unscathed by racism while living abroad, and that later in life he began to question its source. His various ways of dealing with the world are closely related to the events he has experienced and the environment in which he lives. The book reveals his own “sense of place”—emotions and judgments about specific places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his first interview at Indiana University in 1956, an Asian history professor was surprised by his family background. Duan Yifu recalled his childhood memories and was sure that the other party was not joking. According to what he heard, the Duan family was divided into two branches in modern times, both in Anhui. Duan Yifu&#39;s family belonged to the poor branch, and his father Duan Maolan relied on his uncle Duan Qirui from the Hefei branch to fully fund his studies at Nankai Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu was born in Tianjin. From the age of 7 to 10, he lived in a village on the outskirts of Chongqing due to the war. His family was financially distressed. The school is a single room belonging to a power station. The place smelled sour and rancid, and the fetid mud dragged at his shoes. He was disgusted and horrified. Occasionally he encountered a funeral procession, with the bodies of the guards wrapped in bamboo mats. There is a rooster tied to it, which will crow if the corpse is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1954, Yifu Duan conducted field research in Arizona, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small schools are different places, where students learn about the history, Culture and Technology. Wilde&#39;s work &quot;The Happy Prince&quot; left an indelible mark on him, and he knew: &quot;&#39;Good&#39; can no longer be limited to fulfilling social obligations.&quot; These realizations inspired Duan Yifu to think, and he was always exploring how to determine a person&#39;s position in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu mentioned some important historical figures in his narrative. Duan Maolan and his alumnus Zhou Enlai wrestled with each other&#39;s arms to test whether the other&#39;s injured arm was healed. Zhang Boling, the principal of Nankai Middle School, had a rare refrigerator and distributed trays of ice cubes to everyone. In order to keep them for him, his father used the folk remedy of spreading salt to delay melting. The adults are still thinking about how to treat their distant relative Wang Jingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu has conflicting emotions about his father. He longs for love, but is disappointed by his father&#39;s preference for his brothers; he remembers the tenderness of the difficult times, but is also traumatized by his father&#39;s severity or anger. The most profound memory of my father is even just a childhood nightmare, and the scene in the dream has remained for many years:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;I opened my arms and wanted to hug him... What happened? But a ghost stood in front of me. It could be seen that it was my father, but he was covered in mourning clothes. This ghost was in the ever-changing airflow It was moving in the middle, weightless. It was an evil ghost, a corpse, with yellow light in its empty eyes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impression his mother left on him was warm and tough. , it’s a pity that she passed away prematurely. At the same time, Duan Yifu became increasingly sensitive due to his physical condition, and he became very ill for a time. He confessed his cowardice and unwillingness to participate in social change activities. Even in the face of racism and rude boys who treat him as a &quot;little girl,&quot; he has no motivation to actively fight back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world in Duan Yifu&#39;s eyes is shrinking inward. When he was a child, he was exposed to all kinds of extraordinary events. When he grew up, the war ended and he had to face many personal problems. He summed up this growth experience as moving from the universe to the stove, and used beautiful writing to integrate life and academia. He quoted the words of the poet TS Eliot:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All of us, in our lifetime, have heard and seen , why does everything you feel (a bird singing, a fish leaping, an old woman walking on a mountain road) be reproduced with emotion, but other things are not?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;Youth Yifu Tuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you willing to be a lonely captain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Poetry can break through the barriers or boundaries of language logic.” Liu Su told Southern Weekend. He used this to describe the beautiful words written by Tuan Yifu. He translated &quot;Love Land Complex&quot; and &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;Two books by Yifu Tuan, and I am currently translating &quot;The Divided World and Self&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student around 2010, Liu Su often suffered from having no books to read. Many times he was attracted by the ideas mentioned in the book, but could not find relevant Chinese or even English translations. He tried his best to find the original work, went to Douban to ask Douban friends who had read the book, and also went to the library, but he might only be able to make half a copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I might as well translate it myself!&quot; Those experiences inspired Liu Su&#39;s enthusiasm. He thus embarked on the path of academic translation, and future college students will no longer face the dilemma of reading. At the same time, many scholars have also participated in the translation and introduction of geography classics. The Chinese translations of scholars such as Tuan Yifu and David Harvey are enough to be compiled into a collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2021, in the crowded Chongqing subway, Liu Su received a WeChat message from another translator Zhicheng, asking him if he was willing to translate &quot;Who Am I?&quot; 》. Even though the air conditioning was sufficient, he still broke out in a hot sweat: &quot;This book will finally be translated into Chinese!&quot; He had seriously considered that he was not willing to live a lonely life as a &quot;foreigner&quot; in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; ” resonated with Liu Su’s heart. He experienced a long single life. When he got married, the children of his classmates were almost in junior high school. He may have experienced Duan Yifu&#39;s loneliness and his self-statement: &quot;I spent a lot of time in poems and essays about the sadness of spring and autumn, and spent them in places like libraries and coffee shops.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su finished class, said goodbye to the students, and went to the library for a while after walking out of the teaching building. Even if I don’t write anything, I would still like to sit in the corner and experience what Yifu Duan said: “Living on campus almost all my life, surrounded by young people, makes me feel happy physically and mentally.” He sometimes goes to a nearby coffee shop and sits by the window, looking at the pedestrians, vehicles and street lights, feeling that loneliness is far away. The sensibility of exquisite language gathers together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-Fu Tuan in 1998, that is, &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;The previous year&#39;s work &quot;Escapism&quot; asked: What is the greatest escape? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you lower your head and manage the environment around you with a heart that loves your neighbor, you can also look up at the vast starry sky.&quot; Liu Su talked about his understanding of this sentence and added a more realistic side, &quot;As a scholar, like him, I often look up at the starry sky of metaphysical thoughts and theories. However, whenever I look down at my single life, I often feel like I&#39;m in a mess.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot; 1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (1930-2022), an internationally renowned Chinese geographer, was born in Tianjin and graduated from Oxford University. He returned to China in his later years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su is looking for descriptions of single life in books. Yifu Tuan made his apartment simple and warm, dressed modestly and appropriately, maintained good health and longevity, had good interpersonal relationships, and gained precious friendships. However, &quot;he once dreamed that he died alone at home, and no one found his rotting body.&quot; Duan Yifu always writes about his loneliness, a complicated feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps the reason is that loneliness is the most authentic way of human existence. The state of not being lonely is actually the product of escape.&quot; Liu Su quoted the saying of &quot;Escapism&quot;. There are three questions surrounding Yifu Duan&#39;s life: &quot;I am mortal&quot; that has lingered since childhood; &quot;Who am I&quot; related to individual consciousness; and &quot;What is a good life&quot;. Yifu Tuan wrote &quot;Geography saved me&quot;. Geography was like a road that led him to understand himself and the problems of human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Translation of &quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; also allowed Liu Su to gain &quot;a friendship worth cherishing.&quot; After the book launch, he, Zhi Cheng, editors and readers friends braved the heavy rain and went into a noodle shop to chat. Five people each signed five books and kept them. He also wanted to write his feelings into a longer email and share it with Duan Yifu. Before the email was finished, Duan Yifu passed away in August 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tuan Yifu published a new book that year, and finally wrote: &quot;I would like to advise you again, young traveler! You must be full of courage to operate your own ship like a captain, even though it is only Life&#39;s puzzling clues and stars serve as your guide.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su was devastated by his mistake, but would continue to translate classics of humanistic geography. He also asked himself if he was willing to be a lonely captain and walk on a narrow road. No matter what the answer is, Tuan Yifu&#39;s book &quot;will always be projected into the heart of every reader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where is the real home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu recalled in the preface of &quot;Going Home&quot; that people often asked him where he thought the real hometown was. . He answered lightly: &quot;In general, it&#39;s the earth.&quot; &quot;Where on earth is it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the meaning of the question is probably: there must be a place where he is most comfortable, The most yearning, can form the deepest sense of belonging. &quot;Some specific landscapes do have great appeal to me, such as a landscape that transcends aesthetics - the desert. I feel that I am very close to the desert psychologically, and I can even regard it as my home.&quot; Yifu Duan again and again Once I wrote about my love for the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in the winter of 1954, Yifu Tuan was conducting field research for his doctoral thesis in southeastern Arizona. The research object was the desert terrain called the foothill erosion surface. When optimistic British student David Harris joins the group, the physical and spiritual hardships of the wilderness thin out and are gradually replaced by friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This relationship brings me satisfaction, but it also causes insecurity—almost all relationships of any depth involve both. Why? Is there something wrong with me? ?&quot; Duan Yifu asked in the book. In 1962, they collaborated again. He remained single and became a teacher; David married and had two daughters. &quot;The David today is a broader, more elusive personality than I knew before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following description is sensitive and stinging, and such feelings appear repeatedly in the book . They each drove to Chaco Canyon to investigate, with Yifu Duan leading the way and David&#39;s family following behind. At dusk, maybe David knew the route, maybe the children needed care, David&#39;s car honked, kicked up dust and drove ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The distance between us became wider and wider, and soon, all that was left in front of my eyes was the raised The dust was gone, and in the end, even the dust was gone. I fell into a lonely shadow... When I tried to catch up with the Harris family, I felt lonely and painful for the first time. What&#39;s worse, I I even feel ridiculous. What on earth was I doing on a dirt road in New Mexico? Chasing a young family in a car?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yifu Tuan&#39;s eyes, friendship must meet two basic requirements: The conditions—like-mindedness and sympathy—should be balanced in an ideal friendship. &quot;If overly oriented toward shared interests and interests, these two people may become more like colleagues than friends; conversely, they may be more like lovers, staring into each other&#39;s eyes rather than into the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Shy people, unsociable people, or people like me who have their social needs suppressed by eccentric pursuits, perhaps should devote themselves to Nature...maybe only by staying in an inorganic environment, such as deserts and icebergs, can people feel relaxed and happy, and forget the good and the bad.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Duan also wrote about the German Alexander von Humboldt. Humboldt was the founder of modern physical geography. He “made outstanding contributions to the development of geodesy and was the first to use painting and poetry to develop human geographical experience-feelings, emotions and concepts, which are the core of humanities. The starting point of socialist geography”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt lived to be 90 years old and was full of energy throughout his life. In his sixties, he could still travel through Siberia and Central Asia. He enjoys socializing, but has never been married, and has been trapped in emotional entanglements with men three times. He wrote in a letter to the married soldier Reinhard von Haften: &quot;Even if you reject me and look at me coldly, like a stain, I still want to be with you. ...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I leave the universe, or to be precise, leave the harmony of nature and the joy brought by human beings&#39; ultimate achievements, my life will become miserable and I will not be able to survive.&quot; Yifu Duan listed He felt all kinds of human misery, &quot;But, I don&#39;t want to stay in those shadows for a long time...&quot; He believed in the light, the beauty of the universe, and the beauty and kindness of events. The next chapter is &quot;Geography Saved Me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, taking the opportunity of attending an architectural conference, Yi-Fu Tuan returned to China after 60 years of absence and deliberately stayed for a while. He wrote a book called &quot;Going Home&quot;, which was translated into Chinese by Zhicheng. During the trip to Chongqing, he once again mentioned the nightmare that had plagued him throughout his life. When his father passed away in Taipei in 1980, he did not go back to see him for the last time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the autobiography is the contrast between the dim light of the car lights and the vast darkness. That is not despair. Duan Yifu is still looking at himself. He asked the translator to attach his speech notes in 2012 as an updated understanding of &quot;who I am.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no so-called ordinary people in the world. The people you talk to every day are actually people with immortal souls... They joke with us, work together, and get married, but they are also ignored and exploited by us. All people are actually people with immortal souls. Among these people, some are immortal and terrifying, and some are immortal and brilliant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Maybe it has been too long, he I really forgot&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot;Yu Shiyi, the editor of &quot;WeChat,&quot; appeared somewhat silent - just like when communicating with text on WeChat - but soon opened up the situation, became talkative and humorous. His daily schedule was very regular and he even added a short period of time that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later he added that he should not talk too much about his own story, and autobiographers should be given more space. So, this part is an extra chapter of this article. People are always faced with questions such as &quot;Who am I?&quot; The questions and answers constantly change with the situation, each covered with attractive colors. For example, the great director Bergman claimed that he knew less about himself than he did ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi has unique feelings about discrete events. In early 1949, the Taiping shipwreck occurred in the waters west of Daishan Island where he was born. When he was a child, he had no idea about this tragedy. He only learned about it through documentaries when he left his hometown to attend college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, approximately 125,000 young men, soldiers, and 25,000 civilian personnel and civilians moved to Taiwan from Zhoushan, later forming the first generation of Zhoushan people of 20,000 to 30,000 people. The initiators of Taiwan’s Veterans Return Movement in 1987 were Zhoushan people. Before the “Three Direct Links”, it was very difficult for them to contact their homeland. The local historical materials exhibition hall uses an entire wall to display letters forwarded by the Red Cross at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Islands shape cognition. Yu Shiyi left Zhoushan for Ningbo ten years ago, and then went to Shanghai to study. When I was growing up, there was no cross-sea bridge in Zhoushan. When a typhoon came, the island became an isolated island, physically and psychologically isolated from the rest of the world. Compared to county towns, provincial towns, and cities, visitors from small islands seem to be “small” and marginal. At first he longed to merge from the margins into the mainstream, but now he wants to have subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As an immigrant, your regional identity is the first thing that is mentioned when you arrive in a new environment.” Yu Shiyi has a friend who was born in Hubei and grew up in Shenzhen, and later moved to Shanghai. He asked: What is the local accent of “other”? In 1973, 43-year-old Yifu Duan officially became a U.S. citizen. He has been living in the United States for nearly two decades, debugging himself as a &quot;cosmopolitan and a thinker writing about discrete subjects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the little grandpa - my grandfather&#39;s younger brother - talking about the past during the Chinese New Year. He claimed that he once drove a simple diesel-powered boat from Qushan Island to Dongjiadu, Shanghai, in one night. Alone, without a GPS, all I have is experience and a compass. Yu Shiyi could not imagine the plight of the fishermen. Wouldn&#39;t they be scared if they were wandering around without land? He wrote down his boundless imagination in his notes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The lanky man drove a small sampan from the island Set off and drive northwest, through night and day, to Dongjiadu. The lighting system at that time was not perfect, and there was no positioning system. Some waterways were almost dark at night, but he arrived at his destination safely without saying a word about the wind and waves he encountered. I think maybe too much time has passed and he has long forgotten the ups and downs along the way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I remember that there is a famous lighthouse on Flower and Bird Island. I wonder if he passed by it. Under certain conditions, There will also be the wonder of the fluorescent sea. I always feel that the waterway from my hometown to Shanghai is full of mysterious powers. I once took a ferry from the island to Shanghai. I landed ashore at dusk and landed at dawn. That was the first time I saw the waves gurgling like spring water and seagulls soaring in the sky. Looking out from the small round glass of the third-class cabin, there are faint lights. Maybe I have seen the lighthouse of Flower and Bird Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked the tribesmen, have you gone ashore? He said he had unloaded the goods but did not go up. I was so sorry. I wanted to get the secrets of Shanghai in the 1980s from him, but he said, it’s nothing. The Bund is just across the Dongjia Ferry Road. I can’t understand those Western things. At that time, everything could be bought by ticket, and the people were people on the water. , naturally cannot be obtained. He drove the sampan up the Huangpu River and finally reached Jiangyin. This was undoubtedly an adventure. As for what to do there and how to get back to the island, he stopped talking without saying a few words. Maybe it&#39;s been too long and he really forgot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Memories and narratives form fragments one after another, embedded in life. More than thirty years after my grandfather left Shanghai, Yu Shiyi also arrived in Shanghai. During the National Day holiday in 2022, he took a boat to the island with his father. The father was hesitant at first, after all, the house was no longer theirs. Many places are different. Old houses and new ones are popping up one after another. Fortunately, the road remains where it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi returned to the lane where he was born. The commercial house he bought more than 20 years ago was still there, but it was older. The back door was open, he went in and saw the washboard from many years ago. After all these years, it&#39;s still there, like a miracle. There was someone living nearby, and he was too embarrassed to disturb him, so he just wanted to go to the front door to take a look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the resident saw the stranger, he became alert and asked: &quot;Who are you?&quot; Yu Shiyi was stunned, silent for a few seconds, and instinctively replied: &quot;This is my home.&quot; He walked to the front door and took a photo Teru then left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have become the &#39;other&#39;.&quot; He recalled, &quot;There are physical things, and it used to be my home.&quot; He didn&#39;t know how many hands the house had changed. I felt relieved that I could finally say goodbye. For almost twenty years, he always thought of this home, worried about it, and was afraid it would be demolished. Now all the playmates and neighbors have left, leaving only photos and washboards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recognition and memory of your hometown, in turn, become the means for others to identify you. Not long after being asked &quot;Who are you?&quot;, in December 2022, Yu Shiyi took over &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;, the book will be launched at the Shanghai Book Fair in August 2023. The above is always a bit of an unexpected fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天安门下半旗悼念李克强同志]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259779]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:28:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKj lN5UvkjG6D. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Huanzong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 2, in memory of Comrade Li Keqiang, flags were flown at half-mast at Tiananmen Square in the capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”：是一种可鄙的价值观吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There are many serious and serious rumors circulating on the Internet. Some are old and constantly updated versions, and some are new. of. A relatively recent one is: The Chinese student&#39;s thesis &quot;You have to endure hardships to become a superior person&quot;. As a result, the New Zealand professor gave a zero point and asked the soul question, &quot;Why should you become a superior person while others are inferior?&quot; What do people do? Why do you divide your compatriots into three, six or nine grades? Shouldn’t everyone be equal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you do some Internet archeology, it is not difficult to find that this is A piece of Sanwu news concocted by a certain self-media, with no specific time, university or person. The motive of the fabricator is to use the words of foreigners who regard them as authoritative to show how low some Chinese people&#39;s words, deeds, and values ​​are, and how high their own preferred values ​​are. However, there are still many people who believe in this rumor that &quot;foreign monks like to chant sutras&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original version of &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The original version should be &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chapter 32 of &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. Tang Monk said: &quot;Disciples, be careful. If you encounter a high mountain ahead, you may be blocked by tigers and wolves.&quot; Sun Wukong said: &quot;Master, as a monk, don&#39;t talk at home. Do you remember the &quot;Heart Sutra&quot; written by Monk Wuchao, which says, &#39;If you have no worries, you will be free from worries.&#39; No fear, stay away from words that confuse dreams? But it is just to sweep away the dirt on the heart and wash the dirt on the ears. If you don&#39;t suffer in the suffering, it is difficult to be a good person. You should not worry, but there is an old man, even if the sky falls, you can Be safe. What are you afraid of?&quot; This was an education for the master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also from &quot;Warning Words to the World&quot;, &quot;It&#39;s Hard to Meet Your Husband after Spring Falls in the Yutang&quot;. I saw a couplet hanging on the door: &quot;After ten years of suffering in front of the window, he became famous all over the world.&quot; &quot;This is the couplet written by my father-in-law. He passed the national examination and became a minister: Later, our father was When I study here, I will become a minister. I am studying here now, and I also want to climb the dragon and the phoenix to carry forward the ambitions of my predecessors.&quot; I also saw a couplet on the second door: &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the hardships, it is difficult to become a master.&quot; The young master hurriedly returned. Study room...with my mind turned around and my determination to study diligently. This is a lot of self-motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between the two versions is: &quot;Only when you endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The first sentence is a necessary condition for the latter sentence; &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people&quot; is the probability. Expression. The latter seems more rigorous and allows exceptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this kind of saying? If you take &quot;You must endure hardships to become the best&quot; as a full judgment, then it is not difficult to find counterexamples. In a logical sense, this proposition has been refuted. However, after that, everyone thought this was wrong and discarded it? Obviously not, everyone will just think you are making excuses, because this is not the correct way to open the proverb. The use of proverbs is inherently situational: only when specific preconditions are added or placed in a specific context can the proverb be established and can be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a large number of sayings in various languages ​​with completely opposite meanings. Here is an example of Chinese: &quot;A powerful man cannot bend&quot; vs &quot;A man can bend and stretch&quot;; &quot;I will not offend others unless they attack me&quot; vs &quot;Strike first to gain strength, but to attack later will suffer&quot;; &quot;It is better to be broken into pieces than to be left intact&quot; vs &quot;to stay intact&quot; If the green mountains are there, you will not be afraid of running out of firewood&quot;; &quot;Take a step back and the sky will be brighter&quot; Vs &quot;The brave will win when you meet on a narrow road&quot;; &quot;To endure a moment of calm&quot; Vs &quot;It is tolerable, but what is intolerable&quot;; &quot;Everything is inferior, only reading is good&quot; Vs &quot; Three hundred and sixty lines, he will be the number one scholar&quot;; &quot;The blue is better than the blue&quot; vs &quot;The hair on the lips is weak, and the work is not solid&quot;; &quot;Three cobblers are better than Zhuge Liang&quot; vs &quot;Three monks have no water to drink&quot; ...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me, which sentence before and after is right, which sentence is wrong, or are they both wrong? In fact, as long as they are put into the appropriate context, these common sayings with opposite meanings can be used correctly. This is the correct way to use common sayings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become a superior person&quot; or &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer a lot of hardships, can you become a superior person&quot;, there are also common sayings with opposite meanings or different emphasis, such as &quot;One life. &quot;Second Movement and Three Feng Shui&quot;, &quot;Choice is more important than effort&quot;, &quot;Don&#39;t use tactical diligence to cover up strategic laziness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, success is determined by many innate and acquired factors. 1. Fate: when you were born in which country and family, this constitutes your initial conditions and boundary conditions; 2. Wisdom: intellectual endowment, the computing power and algorithm of the brain, which are also innate; 3. God: you Your knowledge system and values, as well as your vitality, motivation, courage and patience, have both innate and acquired components, but the acquired component is greater, because you can always choose your values ​​and choose to be a courageous person; 4. Luck: Factors you have no way of knowing or controlling because you are in a complex random system. In a specific process, &quot;god, wisdom, fate, luck&quot;, which factors are more important cannot be generalized. A person&#39;s success always resonates with the trend of history and personal destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, among the many factors that determine success, hardship, diligence or patience are certainly important, especially for people without background. Other statements such as &quot;The sharp edge of a sword comes from sharpening, and the plum blossoms bloom from the bitter cold&quot;, &quot;There are roads in the mountains of books, and diligence is the path, and there is no limit to the sea of ​​learning, and the boat is made by hard work.&quot; Do they sound more pleasing to the ear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What many people don’t like is “people superior to others”. This needs to be looked at twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, from the perspective of rights or rules, of course everyone should be equal. No one is above anyone else, and no one is subordinate to anyone. It is against anyone&#39;s privileges or slavery. , which is the basic principle of civilized society. In this sense, there should be no &quot;people superior to others&quot; and &quot;people inferior to others&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, there are always certain professions that are more respected in society and have higher social evaluation or reputation. For example, professionals such as surgeons enjoy a higher social status and are not considered &quot;human beings&quot;. What about &quot;Master&quot;? Also, some people are respected and admired by everyone because of their ability, knowledge or virtue, and they even have many followers. For example, people like Xinxiang Xian are the core of society. If neighbors come to him to resolve disputes, does he count? What about &quot;people superior to people&quot;? In a company or organization, whether it has a strict hierarchy or a relatively &quot;flat&quot; management, there is a chain of command and a superior-subordinate relationship. The subordinates must obey the instructions of the superiors to do things. Can senior executives and superiors be considered &quot;superiors&quot;? &quot;Woolen cloth? In a nutshell, from the perspective of power or influence, elites or those with higher social status are often called &quot;dragons and phoenixes&quot;, and there is nothing wrong with being considered &quot;superior&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if you want to be &quot;superior&quot; and pursue the privilege of overpowering others or trampling others under your feet, it is naturally a despicable value; What&#39;s the problem if you deepen your field, improve your talents and virtues, become popular, and gain a higher social status? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[书城伏案的侧影：写在刘世南先生百年诞辰之际]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259765]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3AasqhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;916&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3Aasq hT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Shinan took a photo in front of the Chongshao Library of Jiangxi Normal University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Taosheng)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;People who long for friends who fear friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Shinan Mr. (1923-2021) was a fighter. This is the first impression of him by people who are familiar with him and those who are not familiar with him. He dared to criticize various scholars, including those older than him, those of his generation, and those younger than him. His articles were scattered in various books and periodicals from the late 1970s to the new century, making readers People who feel the enthusiasm and persistence of his criticism are of course embarrassed by the critics, but they do learn from him, and many criticized scholars express their gratitude to him and respect him even more. His criticisms are actually aimed at problems, especially the style of study. His crisp and refreshing writing style contains a profound call for a sincere, simple, serious and down-to-earth style of study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not many people know that he is very eager to be criticized. He criticized Mr. Liu Mengfu (&quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; page 301), and Mr. Mengfu also criticized him. He invited Mr. Mengfu to write a preface to his &quot;Da Luo Ju Shi Cun&quot;. Mr. Mengfu wrote a long preface in which he included his own critical opinions. He criticized it with real swords and guns. Mr. Shinan did not think that Sorry, let it remain in the preface as it is. This is the style of sincerity and magnanimity. He said in a letter to me on July 26, 2005: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Mengfu is in middle age and a poet. Learn the art of poetry and achieve the best of both worlds. He looks down upon him as a servant, looks down upon his followers, and is sincerely afraid of his friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He respects and looks forward to his &quot;fearful friends&quot;. When he heard Mr. Tao Wenpeng mention that some parts of his &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; were a bit &quot;old&quot;, he wrote a letter asking Mr. Tao to point out his shortcomings in detail. Mr. Tao replied, and Mr. Shinan made a copy of the letter. Send me a copy and write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send me a copy of Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s letter, to be compared with Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s book review Although Mr. Yun and Mr. Tao made many mistakes in their compliments, Mr. Tao was able to correct their flaws. I hope Mr. Yun can do the same. In the past, Chen Si once said: &quot;The writings of the world cannot be without disease. I always have good people to ridicule my writings, and if there are bad ones, I should revise them in due course.&quot; He also quoted Ding Jingli and said: &quot;Who in future generations will know that my writings are evil?&quot; I hope that Mr. Zou Zhen, as the editor-in-chief of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, will be able to rectify the shortcomings of my book and inform future generations of those who govern Qing poetry about what to avoid. This is the meaning of an academic public instrument. (January 12, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he is still not satisfied with Mr. Tao&#39;s criticism and hopes to get more and more real criticism. He regards criticism as an &quot;academic official tool&quot;. &quot;To look at it. This allows us to understand more clearly that the reason why he carried out academic criticism with all his might was because he really had no selfish motives and was only dedicated to the healthy and mature development of the academic world. His attitude towards criticism is not only aimed at others, but also aimed at himself, which is conducive to his own improvement and is conducive to clear understanding in the academic community. He sets an example and has a bright mind, which is admirable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan and his &quot;Detailed Notes on Three Hundred Qing Poems&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was very moved by others&#39; corrections to him and expressed his gratitude repeatedly. Our publisher was planning to launch chronological anthologies one after another. Considering that Mr. Shinan was familiar with Qing literature, editor and editor Zhou Xuanlong, then director of the Classics Department, sincerely invited him to annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Considering that time was tight, he asked his Student Professor Liu Songlai assisted. After the manuscript arrived, Ms. Wen Lichen, a graduate student at Beijing Normal University, intern, reviewed it for the first time under my guidance. Then I reviewed it again. After writing two revisions, I sent it to Mr. Shinan for review. He said in a letter written in the Provincial Library on October 1, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 22 and Review comments and copies of book reviews have been received. Please read them. After reading it, I feel ashamed and excited! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the articles of Kuangzheng and Supplement, we can also see that Mr. Wen Lichen and Wen Lichen have made profound achievements in the study of female history, and their admiration for them cannot be overstated! I secretly say that the &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; will be of some benefit to this world in the future. It shows that the cooperation between the four of us is not caused by Song Lai and me. I plan to add a few words to the preface of this book to clarify the meaning and to show that we do not dare to take advantage of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He later insisted on adding words of praise to me and Xiaowen in the preface of the book, which shows that he was happy after hearing about it and had an open-minded and sage mind, which was like a spring breeze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan’s two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Mr. Shinan&#39;s fighting spirit is mainly reflected in his diligent reading and writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He does not have many books, mainly because the collections of two generations of his were destroyed during the special period, which made him extremely sad, and he generally stopped buying books (&quot;Odd Records of Masters and Friends&quot;, page 117). He mainly visits the library. He is a frequent visitor to the provincial library and school library. In 1994, after fourteen years of arduous reading, research, and writing, he finally completed &quot;History of the Qing Poetry School&quot;. When proofreading the manuscript the following summer, he reviewed the process with joy:&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reminiscent of the past, when every year passes, the bookstore is still busy with calligraphy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wan Jiaqing Tuanluan, sitting alone and smiling. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The box is full of cards, and there are more than delicious meals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fourteen years of hard work, the book is finished with a pen and inkstone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Appendix to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; &quot;Proofreading in the Midsummer of Jiaxu&quot; &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; Manuscript...&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Note: &quot;Every Spring Festival and New Year&#39;s Eve, I sit in the library, facing the administrator from a distance.&quot; Our publisher is preparing to publish the simplified version, and I am honored to be responsible. The editor, during the editing process, greeted him and mentioned this impressive scene. He wrote me a reply in the sample library on the evening of December 30, 2003 and the next day:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Thank you for your attention. You still remember that I was still sitting in the library on New Year&#39;s Eve. If school maps were still open, I would indeed do that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;, this is how I have been here all my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, he still couldn&#39;t let go every day. One New Year&#39;s Eve, the curator and he &quot;faced each other from a distance&quot;, which was quite a scene. He wrote to his student Professor Guo Dan: &quot;It is now nearly 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon on New Year&#39;s Eve. Director Zhang and I are the only two people left in the library reading hall; Director Zhang is on duty in person and will accompany me until 4 o&#39;clock with a smile. The bell closes the door.&quot; (Guo Dan&#39;s &quot;The Realm of Scholarship and the Style of Personality - A Note on Mr. Liu Shinan&quot;, &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 237) Such a curator is really a good curator, and such a reader is really a good reader. This is called It is a good story in the contemporary reading world. The postcard he sent me on December 31, 2006 said: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bookstore is sitting at the desk, cocooned and forgotten. Time passes in a hurry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If Hua Yan was not drunk this night, who would have known that the day after tomorrow would be the New Year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Still reading on New Year’s Eve, it is indeed the style of reading seeds. Of course, he didn&#39;t just focus on New Year&#39;s Eve. In fact, every day was precious to him. Letter from June 4, 2004:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; is very busy, I have never been so nervous , because the school will be closed during the summer vacation, so I have to finish this before the vacation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the scene when I was rushing to select and annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; with Professor Song Lai. Later, when there was no urgent work, I still went to the library unremittingly. In the past, revolutionaries had a heroic saying: &quot;Sit through the prison.&quot; Mr. Shinan, in his old age, still insisted on going there regardless of his illness. He really had the spirit to penetrate the library. The letter dated January 10, 2013 said:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​year has passed and I was recently hospitalized for removal of nasal warts. Medical advice It was basal cell carcinoma and had been completely removed. I am already ninety years old and have lived and died for a long time, so after I was discharged from the hospital, I still sat in the library. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Professor Guo Dan called Mr. Shinan to wish him a happy New Year on the morning of the first day of the Spring Festival in Year Yiwei in 2015, the answer he heard was &quot;I am already reading in the provincial library&quot;! (Postscript to the reprint of &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;) Mr. Li Taosheng has been accompanying Mr. Shinan for many years. He said in the article &quot;Unforgettable words from the bottom of my heart&quot;: &quot;Books are all his spiritual sustenance.&quot; &quot;No matter the wind, frost, rain or snow, he always He would always show up at the library on time like a staff member. He said he hoped he could die at his desk in the future.&quot; (&quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 249) This shows how obsessed he is with books. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;From thousands of books&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan has read extensively and is particularly familiar with classics and history, so he can read many treatises We are sensitive to misunderstandings, misjudgments, and corrections and can provide corrections. In addition to helping others publish absurdities, he mainly devoted his energy to the research and writing of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;. In addition, a lot of study was done on the annotations of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. After taking on this task, he devoted himself wholeheartedly to the selection of articles. Although Professor Song Lai was invited to participate in the annotation work, he still did everything personally:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From text selection to punctuation to the comments, I will read them all and revise them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At these times, I was busy selecting articles, mainly from &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot; and &quot;Continued&quot; Choose from &quot;Xiu Siku Quanshu&quot; and &quot;Cunmu Series&quot;, and a few have to be found separately from the thread-bound library. For example, Jiang Shiquan has no text in &quot;Continued Cultivation&quot;, but &quot;Pictures of Night Classes with Sound Machines&quot; must be selected. Others can be deduced by analogy. The selection of the text is time-consuming. After selecting it, it must be photocopied and then hand-copied into simplified Chinese characters. (December 16, 2003) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to concentrate on the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, he served as the chief academic consultant for the compilation of &quot;Yu Zhang Series&quot; in Jiangxi Province universities for several years. (that is, final check) also resigned. This shows his determination to devote himself wholeheartedly to the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Because he was familiar with the collected works of the Qing Dynasty, and he read them day and night, by December 30, 2003, he had &quot;read page by page the Qing Dynasty Collection of Continuing the Complete Collection of Siku Quanshu&quot;, and had reached 154 of the 188 volumes. , there are still 30 volumes left, I can finish them before the winter vacation,&quot; and said, &quot;Then I will read &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot;, there are not many collections. I haven&#39;t read &quot;Cunmu&quot;, so I don&#39;t know how many.&quot; In selecting articles, &quot;Be sure not to show off your hands and eyes, and don&#39;t be attracted by people&#39;s enthusiasm&quot; (letter dated December 30, 2003). In this letter, he still could not hide his critical eye and expressed his opinions on several books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I was reading the collected works of Zeng Guofan today, and I found four books that were annotated by modern people. Take &quot;Yuancai&quot; as an example , Tu Xiaoma&#39;s version, Lai Xinxia&#39;s version, and Guo Yuheng&#39;s version all concluded: &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; On the contrary, Zheng Zhenduo&#39;s &quot;Late Qing Dynasty&quot; &quot;Selected Works&quot; concluded: &quot;Is it true to say that the accusation is not false?&quot; That&#39;s right. Tu, Lai and Guo... I don&#39;t know that the &quot;ye&quot; in &quot;Ke Hu Ye&quot; is actually &quot;ye&quot;. Books such as &quot;Jing Zhuan Shi Ci&quot; make it very clear, and the ancient prose written by Han Yu and Ouyang Xiu is swaying and often colorful. There is this aria. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;king&quot; in &quot;Everyone is king and is ordered to do so&quot; has been misunderstood. &quot;Mistakenly changed to &quot;must&quot;, it is also analyzed. He did not deny your contribution, he just wanted to explain that he would learn from their achievements, but would never simply plagiarize:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Even if we refer to this kind of annotated version, we must analyze every detail, never make vague and influential remarks, but strive to be clear and accurate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are actually very few similar works that we can rely on. Even if we refer to them, they must be adopted with discernment. This is in line with what Mr. Shinan has always advocated: &quot;Speak from the heart, never tamper with a single word.&quot; academic spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By June 26, 2004, it was the final stage of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. He wrote to me to introduce the writing situation of the preface of the book:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The preface can prove that the two of us have a slightly new understanding of Qingwen and do not follow what others say, precisely because we have put a lot of effort into the annotation of the works. For example, &quot;the genre is single but the styles are diverse&quot;, we not only pointed out &quot;how it is&quot; but also explained &quot;why it is so&quot;. This is the characteristic of our learning. It is also aimed at traditional Chinese literary criticism. The traditional method is improvisational and perceptive, and only points out &quot;how it is&quot; without analyzing &quot;why it is so&quot;. We have accepted the influence of Western academics and always like to pursue a &quot;why&quot;. Therefore, with regard to the emergence of the Tongcheng School (including the later Yanghu School and the Xiangxiang School) and the praise of &quot;all the articles in the world can only be found in Tongcheng&quot;, we try to find out its logical inevitability through this phenomenon. There are always laws to follow in phenomena, among which the law of cause and effect is most worth pondering, and the results of pondering are also the most thought-provoking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Tao Wenpeng heard about this preface and immediately asked Mr. Shinan to publish it in &quot;Literary Heritage&quot; in advance. Mr. Shinan said in his letter on January 12, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tao Jun asked to rewrite the preface of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; For the thesis, I have cooperated with Song Laijun. However, Huamei may not be fashionable and Zhu Yi may not nod. But I can be confident that the words and sentences of these two people come from their hearts and come from thousands of books. There is no suppression or similarity. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confidence reflected here comes from his steady reading and long-term cultivation. This spirit is reflected in his works and critical articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The method of popularizing culture through book selection is traditional, but it is an effective method of cultural communication for thousands of years. However, few people are willing to take on such work now because it requires Investing a lot of energy requires a high level of appreciation, extensive knowledge reserves and profound cultural heritage. The art of annotation is extremely difficult to learn, and it can easily lead to mistakes. However, Mr. Shinan resolutely agreed to do the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, which shows his confidence and responsibility. After the publication of this book, readers responded very well. Mr. Shinan was very happy and wrote a letter saying:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What will your company do next year? If there is a new topic that is suitable for me to work with, I hope it will be successful. Although Gai Pu is already old, his spirit has not faded, but he is itching again and again, unhappy and unprepared to do anything. (Written in Provincial Map on October 1, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he has the ambition of &quot;being an old man, but aiming for a thousand miles&quot;. Considering that he is old and cannot be overworked, we did not invite him to do another one. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Young Thinker&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan seems to be a bookworm while sitting in the library, but he is actually a &quot;young thinker&quot; ( Chen Ji&#39;s &quot;Mr. Forever Young&quot;, &quot;Occasionally Diary of Teachers and Friends&quot;). In addition to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; and &quot;Daluoju Poetry and Essays&quot;, Mr. Shinan also has &quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; revised and reprinted, and &quot;Occasionally Diary of Teachers and Friends&quot;. These two books are not &quot;pure&quot; books. ，收录比较杂，形式很随意，但是主题鲜明，都是论学文字，都是“干货”，其中保存了大量来往论学信笺，汇集了一些书评，讲治学方法，更讲治学精神，有意思的是还收集了与世南先生有分歧的一些观点。他在《师友偶记》前言中讲：“&#39;其争也君子&#39;，绝非意气之争，在我是&#39;吾爱吾师，吾尤爱真理&#39;。”他再一次称道梦芙先生，赞他是“诤友”，“佩服他坚持真理的勇气”。关于这部以“我和我所理解的知识人”为主题的书，世南先生说：“这本书的性质，近似《国朝汉学师承记》，是学术性的，它可做现当代学术史、思想史的资料。”的确如此，它的内容超过了一篇篇独立的论文，它包含了当代学者思想交流甚至交锋的丰富材料，学术价值非常大，在形式上无疑也是一种突破和开创。 2004年7月18日来信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您会觉得这是一幅时代风云画卷，它反映出心灵搏击的轰轰烈烈。可以给后代留下一份宝贵的遗产，让后人知道我们这时代知识分子在怎样上下求索。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此书“外编”有一篇《当代知识分子是怎样继承和发扬中国古代士的优良传统的？ 》便体现了他在思想精神层面的探索，让人知道他并非书呆子，而他活跃的思想像他的身体超过了不少年轻人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在学术研究上，他有直接深入的讨论。在诗歌创作上，也寄托遥深，值得体味。 2005年1月12日他来信谈他的《大螺居诗存》：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;先生细加披览，便知拙诗迥非批风抹月之作，而皆痛哭太息之言。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在《诗存》序里说：“凡为诗，必有为而作，决不叹老嗟卑，而惟生民邦国天下之忧。”他的不少诗作直录现实，让人不胜感叹，也让人感动他胸怀的宽广。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有感于先生用了十四年撰成《清诗流派史》，我在该书编辑出版后，写了一篇书评，发表在《海南日报》上，后来修改发表在《光明日报》上。寄呈先生过目，他在2004年6月4日的信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;忙于《清文选》工作，一般信我都搁下以后回。没想到今天得到您的信，更没想到读到您的书评。仔细读了书评以后，我竟感极而泣。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您也许会奇怪：我怎么这样容易激动？关于《清诗流派史》的书评，大约有七八篇，我并没这样激动过。而您，显然是由于身为责编，认真看了《清诗流派史》，因此又细看了《在学术殿堂外》，加上您的高超的鉴赏力和丰富的人生经历，正确的思想认识，才能写出这样一篇使我激动的书评。大作并不长，可都说到了点子上，尤其人文关怀这点，只有您敢于指出。坦白说，我写《清诗流派史》实在是抱着孔子作《春秋》、马迁作《史记》的心态。这一点，只有本校王琦珍教授一篇书评指出了，但该文似尚未问世。而您却与王先生不谋而合，这是我最快慰的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;云波先生，请让我说一句衷心感谢的话：“君为鲍叔能知管，我傲虞卿不客蝇。”这是随手凑成的一联，俱用《史记》，自觉很切。也许有人会质疑：怎么可以人对物呢？那我要大言不惭说：就算自我作古吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先生对我写的书评加以肯定，我有这个自信，但是却想不到引他到了“感极而泣”的地步，还写“君为鲍叔能知管”云云的感谢话来；他径直吐露自己的抱负和追求，可见没有见外。先生2011年录制超星学术视频，讲“我与《清诗流派史》”（后收入《师友偶记》），提到“葛云波先生真是我的知音”。这些都让我非常感动，让我倍感前辈对后辈鼓舞的力量，让我感到踏实做编辑的荣光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上的经历，无疑增加了我们的亲近。当2018年10月6日，我们全家到南昌第一次拜访世南先生，宾主欢然，他有力地握着我的手，久久不放，根本不像96岁老者的手，他能自食其力，还常去图书馆，我们都相信他能轻松度过期颐之年，我们盼望再一次拜望先生。但不成想，2021年8月2日收到了松来教授的短信，获悉世南先生于前一日晚仙逝。我本想痛定思痛之后，写篇感念的文章，然而为出版项目所累，未能如愿。今年是世南先生百年诞辰，我下定决心要写，略表对他老人家的敬仰和感怀，便有了以上不够成熟的追念文字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[娄底7岁女孩遭性霸凌疑云：到底是夸大其词还是轻描淡写？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，湖南娄底一网民称自己7岁的女儿在学校午休时被同班十几名女同学霸凌，甚至伤及下体，引起网络极大关注。而当地通报称经调查确认有女学生短暂打闹，但未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月28日，湖南娄底一家长在社交媒体发帖，称女儿7岁，在湖南娄底某乡镇小学二年级读书，10月20日午休时间，被同班十六七个女同学在操场上霸凌，这些女同学不仅殴打其女，还对其进行性霸凌，导致女儿下体受伤，疼痛难忍。而校方和霸凌方同学家长都对解决问题态度消极。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二年级的小女孩就集体对女同学实施霸凌，尤其是涉及性霸凌，骇人听闻。让人不禁想起几个月之前曝光的山西大同某双语学校9岁小学生性霸凌事件。因此，事件很快成为网络热点，引起了极大的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日，事发地冷水江市（娄底市代管县级市）以联合调查组名义发布情况说明，称发现相关视频后第一时间成立了由市教育局、公安局等部门组成的联合调查组，经公安部门初查，当事女生张某与其他六名女同学为该市某小学二年级同班同学；10月20日中午，因为在操场跳绳时发生争执，发生“相互打闹”约1分钟，其间张某被其他几名同学“短暂围住拍打”；经过调取监控，“保护性”询问涉事女生，调查目击老师和学生，未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一官方通报对事件的定性与受害人母亲的指控天差地别，对事发过程的描述也用词模糊、语焉不详，没有对所指控的关键问题作出澄清。官方如果确有充分证据是女孩家长夸大事实，就应该公开证据反驳，否则，不仅无法消除公众的疑虑，反而会引起更大的质疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是女生张某下体有没有受伤。根据张某母亲发布的信息，张某身体有多处软组织损伤，下体也受到伤害，小便时疼痛难忍，为此被迫憋尿。但官方通报虽然确认发生了“相互打闹”，但对张某是否受伤只字未提。这也是此事中最受网民关注，也是让人最为气愤的一点。官方不应回避，应该对此进行调查并公布结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果张某下体确实受伤，那这是非常严重的侵害未成年人事件，必须查明受伤的原因，如果涉及犯罪行为，要严惩不贷。如果张某并没有受伤，那也要拿出有足够公信力的证据，反驳女孩家长的指控。比如可以在家长陪同下带张某到娄底市以外的三甲医院进行检查，并公布检查结果。如果张某母亲夸大其词或撒谎，也不应回避。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，对当时在操场上发生的事件经过，有必要公布相关视频，以正视听。张某母亲称，张某在操场上被十六七个同班女生殴打。而官方的情况说明则称除张某外只有6名学生涉事，而且多名女生“相互打闹”只有约一分钟时间，而张某只是被几名同学“短暂围住”“拍打”。双方的说法，不仅参与人数相差巨大，而且“殴打”与“相互打闹”之间也存在着性质的巨大差别。既然官方说明中提及警方调取了学校的监控录像，那就是说事发经过是有录像的，并不是张某母亲帖子中校方所说的“监控老化”。既然有录像，那就应该完整地公之于众，让公众自己判断到底是“殴打”还是“相互打闹”，到底持续了多长时间，有没有“故意伤害”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，出于保护未成年人的考虑，对录像中能够辨认的未成年人可以进行保护性技术处理，比如打马赛克、模糊面部等，但应该保证能看出有几个人参与了事件，以及“打闹”的程度到底是怎样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;才7岁的小女孩就会霸凌同学，而且还涉性，似乎有些不可思议。但也并非不可能。在山西大同某双语学校霸凌事件中，霸凌者也不过才9岁，而霸凌并非第一次发生，也是从二年级就开始了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一种刻板印象，好像学校中霸凌别人的就是男生。其实不然，校园暴力事件中，女性施暴的比例并不低。 2023年3月，海南曾爆出一名13岁女孩被一群同性同龄人殴打侮辱的霸凌事件。在大同事件引发极大关注时，刑法学教师蔡某也曾收到爆料，一位女同学被宿舍的其他女同学欺凌，同样有涉性行为，施害者还拍下了视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早年，央视曾报道过一份研究，发现网络上爆出的校园霸凌视频中，八成以上的施暴者是女性。当然这可能和女性霸凌者更倾向于拍下视频并上传到网上羞辱被害人有关，但也说明，校园暴力中女性施暴者绝不少见。而且在女性实施的校园霸凌中，不少是一群人霸凌一个人，而她们霸凌的对象，也是女性居多。还有，女性实施的霸凌中，涉性侮辱的比例不低，比如强制脱光衣服拍照之类。这或许是因为这样会给受害人带来更强烈的耻辱感。这些女性霸凌的特征，与娄底事件中受害人母亲所指控的十几名女生一起殴打、性霸凌其女儿相符。这也是网民更愿意相信受害人指控的原因之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事在网络上引起极大的关注，而官方目前轻描淡写的情况说明，显然难以服众。这不禁让人想起，在山西大同某双语学校性霸凌事件中，学校和主管部门也曾试图大事化小小事化了，但最终，霸凌事件被坐实。这次的娄底疑似霸凌事件也是如此。如果官方有足够的证据支持其情况说明，就应该及时公开，驳斥女孩家长的指控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬(1917-2009)，当代礼学宗师、著名经学家，一生潜心研习三礼之学，在礼学、经学史、文献学、甲骨金石学、版本目录学、古籍整理等诸多领域都有卓越建树，尤其是“三礼”研究，解决了礼学和经学史上许多悬而未决的难题，受到顾颉刚的高度评价。图片摄于1986年5月。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生（1917-2009）在杭州大学是个“隐身人”。 1978年10月，我进中文系读本科，他曾在“古代汉语”课时，给我们讲过几节“古代文化常识”，但大家对他没有什么印象。读研究生时，他是导师组成员，我才开始有所了解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪八十年代初的杭大校本部（今浙大西溪校区），面积不大，高大的法国梧桐树舒展地伸向林荫道，构成一道道穹窿，展示着这个校园所经历的岁月。东南角是几排青灰色砖块砌成的四层楼房，教师集体宿舍和研究生宿舍前后相望。两楼之间是锅炉房，早晨炉火轰然作响，我们每天都要去那里打开水。秋冬时分，梧桐叶已经灰败，锅炉房的行道上撒满了细碎煤灰，映衬着青灰色的砖墙，眼前一片灰蒙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时沈先生就住在一号楼第一单元一楼的一间房子里，大约十五六个平方米，对面是公共厕所，春季潮湿,夏日闷热，冬天阴冷。没有厨房，只能在走道生火，所以二十多年间，他一直吃食堂，偶尔才煮个蹄膀之类改善一下生活。直到1986年分到两居室的房子，搬离此处（那年7月他被国务院学科评议组批准为博导）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从未进过他的住处，只是每次路过时，会有片刻的伫视。后来多次在梦中到过他门外，从门上方的玻璃透过去，仿佛看到了墙上的条幅，却总看不清内里，就像他的为人与为学，十分神秘，望不真切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我经常在去食堂的路上遇见他。那时他年过花甲，宽广的额头，稀疏的头发，花白的胡子，脸色却十分红润。他个子不高，但很壮实。冬天时，他在老棉袄上套一件陈旧的灰色罩衣，左手挎着一个很浅的竹篮子，也像是个簸箕，那双大手，有着粗壮的指节。他总是面带笑容，仿佛挪动似的走在路上，口中略有“呼哧呼哧”的声音。若是遇到旁人注视的目光，他用眼中的笑意作回应，嘴巴似有牵动，并不说出话来。他看起来是温和平静，又如海似渊。他微笑时身上洋溢出能量，让路人也不禁受到鼓舞。所以我觉得那个时候他的心情很不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们这些“新晋”的研究生，那时经常谈论的便是自己的导师和对方的导师：主要做哪个领域，出版过什么著作，在哪里发表了论文，听闻有怎样的评价，对学生有哪些要求，有什么口头禅，在课堂讲了什么新鲜事……自豪地介绍对导师的发现，互相分享，并认真地听别人的补充与议论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;室友陈剩勇是沈文倬先生所带的第一个研究生。我对沈先生的了解，便是通过剩勇同学充满崇拜的解说和大家的议论，慢慢地丰富起来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左起：方建新、沈先生、李解民、王云路(摄于1997年)。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生，字凤笙，号菿闇，江苏吴江人。幼入私塾，长则自习，未获任何文凭。他早年从沈昌直学读古文辞，从金天翮、姚廷杰受文史之学。 1940年代初，从曹元弼专攻“三礼”之学，为其关门弟子，耳提面命达九年之久。曹元弼（1867-1954），人称清代最后一位杰出的经学家，时已年逾古稀，故寄厚望于沈文倬：“善守可望有成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年，他发表了《说高禖》《“蜡”与“腊”》等文章，引起顾颉刚的注意，破格聘其为国立编译馆副编审，主要负责校点经籍、编撰提要、草拟经学词典。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，被派往北京华北人民革命大学政治学院学习。次年6月，分配至上海图书馆，任编目部副主任。我们经常查阅的《中国丛书综录》，极厚的三册，叠起来有一尺多高，就是由他主持编成的。 1960年，《综录》编辑组被评为上海市先进集体，身为组长的他，作为代表出席了上海市群英会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1963年2月，应姜亮夫教授的邀请，调入中国科学院浙江分院的语言文学研究室（设在杭州大学，夏承焘为主任），为专职研究人员，只身赴杭州。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3月，甫抵杭，即往谒马一浮先生；4月下旬，再往。 “以后学求谒前辈学者之礼相见，主亲客敬，融洽无间”。有所悟，也有所思，撰有《蒋庄问学记》以记之。秋后到长春东北文史研究所讲《仪礼》，入冬回杭。欲再谒，未成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年，“谈论古学的风气戛然而止，而情趣也大减”。不久，即下乡参加“社教运动”，到了我的家乡诸暨县的某公社，驻留有时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前，他有多篇论文在《考古》上发表（1961，1963），传言时任中国科学院院长的郭沫若先生见后，评价颇高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“文革”发生后，研究室解散，他转入杭大中文系，在系资料室做资料员。因博闻强记，同事惊为“活字典”。他则独自默处，但从未停止礼学研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1974年，被安排赴安吉参加杭大最后一期“五七”干校“农林班”，白天做“鸭司令”，晚间仍探礼学之奥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1975年3月，将《武威出土&amp;lt;礼&amp;gt;汉简考辨》等四种，寄请顾颉刚先生审阅。顾复信称“台端实为今世治礼经者之第一人也”，同时又叹息，这些成果不知何时才能面世。以上这些话语，当时只是在一个很小的圈子内流传，并不为外界知闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;顾颉刚复沈文倬函。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到“文革”结束, 情况又有了变化。 1979年，他转到教师岗位。次年，评为副研究员，时已64岁。我们82级研究生，是他第一次招生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时杭大对中华书局的《文史》和上海古籍的《中华文史论丛》最为推崇，视为古代文史领域的顶刊，沈先生则是其中的常客。其中如《略论礼典的实行和〈仪礼〉书本的撰作》(《文史》15、16辑，1983)，提出“礼典的实践早于文字记录而存在”，由以阐明礼典与礼书的关系，后来杨向奎先生称此文是“鸿文巨制，成绩空前”。又如《黄龙十二博士的定员和太学郡国学校的设置》（1983）一文,对汉代建立经学博士的复杂史实条分缕析，正皮锡瑞《经学历史》之误，纠王国维《汉魏博士考》之偏，从而详判武、昭、宣三代各经博士官的兴废增缺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有后学称，沈先生的文章视野非常开阔，既有宏观的关照，贯通古今，又有微观的考证，心细如发。同时运用各种方法容纳材料，信息量极大。他对传统礼学中的任何问题，几乎都有独到的见解，文中的每一句话，几乎都凝聚着思考的结果。他的叙述语言非常典雅，几乎与引用文献可以无缝对接，是一种很难达到的境界。对此，我也深表赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，我那时并没有认真拜读过沈先生的著作与论文，也怕读，因为太深奥了。我只是读过他在《中华文史论丛》上的专栏，名为“菿闇述礼”，有时一期刊发数则，所占篇幅，不过一两页，所释则为一字或一物，都属疑难问题之解说，于文史研究关系颇大，而文字典雅凝练，令我叹服不已。这类短文，他从1946年就开始写作了,采山之铜，累积甚丰。很多年后，他汇集成书，仍取栏目之名，不过薄薄一册，十余万字，但甚得好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬先生在书斋中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我开始学写论文时，就知道短论文是最难写的，因为数百字、千余字，要提出一个真问题，罗列材料并且讲清楚，是多么的困难呵！据说沈先生的另一本著作《〈礼〉汉简异文释》，写成时有四十余万字，他并不急于发表，反复压缩，最后出版时，只有十六万字。在我们读研究生时（1982.9-1985.6），他除了一些论文，尚无著作出版。他的第一部专著《宗周礼乐文明考论》,其实是他的论文集，在1999年才问世，写作跨度逾40年，总数也才14篇。那时他已经是耄耋之年了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生一生淡于名利。他说：“治经治礼不易，只有心除&#39;魔障&#39;，胸臆如水，方能专注向学，趋于会通。”他一生的著述其实不多，学者却推许他为“礼学大师”，因为他的文章不靠量的堆积，而是以质取胜。他的每一篇文章都解决了历史上悬而未决的问题，累积起来，便令人叹为观止，且是仰之弥高了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非常幸运的是，沈先生专门为我们开了课。当时我们五名研究生，由五位导师指导，他们每人讲授三堂课，构成了一个学期的研究生课程。他的三堂课，连郭在贻老师也来听了，就坐在后排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生从小患有严重的口吃，连讲一句完整的话，对他而言，都是很吃力的事情。这也是他很少上课的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时老师们所讲的内容是自选的，也都是多年深思所得。印象中，沈文倬先生讲到了先秦诸子流派和古文今文有关问题。在我当时有限的知识里，《论》《孟》《老》《庄》作为独立的著述，稍有涉猎，《墨子》未曾读过，《礼》《书》则不敢碰，至于各家之间的关系，则全无了解。沈先生的课，却讲出了各派思想之间错综复杂的关系，特别是稷下学派、名家，这些几无著述传世的学派，原来也曾在与各家的角逐中占得大势，令其他各家不得不作回应与调整；某些消失的流派，其学说则为他家所融合而流传于后世。这让我忽然明白，原来每一家说法都不是在对某种理论来作完整系统的阐释，而是针对对手发表自己的观点，如果不知道这个论辩的背景，便会觉得其论极偏，像是对着空气作战，不知其所以然。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很像我在篮球场上打中锋，每一次强打，都必须用力把背后顶着我的那个人靠开，才能翻身把球打进。你必须知道那“顶”的力量有多大，才能明白我这一“靠”要花多少的气力。若是将我身后的人物虚化，人们在镜头中只见我对着空气用力地先靠后转，必然会嘲笑我过度使用了蛮力，即所谓“失之偏颇”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的课室里，沈先生“哧哧”地把一个个字从口中用力地迸出来，有些词花了两三次方才说得完整，就用手绢擦一擦汗水，口中依然不停。讲到开心处，他也会带着吃吃的笑声。他先用他自己的考证与解说，重新厘定了旧有概念，然后再作延伸，对一连串的问题提出新的界说，于是相关的人物事件、流派学说，被拂去久积的尘垢，露出了完全不同的容貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们所有人都肃然聆听，唯恐错过了一个音节。因为那一个个迸出来的字，如同一个个阵符在空中翻飞，构成了一个奇妙的阵法，从中显现出历史的真相。那阵势如此波诡云谲，力与力你来我往，波与波争相角逐，声与理相互呼应，这端的是百家争鸣的时代啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四十多年过去了，沈先生的具体解说，我只留下了若干印象，例如“礼书”晚于“礼典”；“古文”最初是指六国文字，“今文”则指汉隶，他从文本书写所用文字的角度，解释各经诸文本在汉代的传承情况；某人的解说，被立于学官，即是“师法”，未立之时，则是“家法”……其他具体的知识，如今大都已经忘记，只有他“哧哧”的声音，偶然还在我的耳边响起，于是他的讲解所引发的那种感触，再次如潮水般漫过我的脑回路，让我感受到一种莫名的震荡。更为重要的是，通过这些讲解，我懂得必须透过文献的表象，去感受时代背后那一道道的“力”及其相互作用，才能依稀看见上帝那只“无形之手”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生在谒见马一浮先生后，撰有一诗：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;儒经释典一炉熔，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;证得心同理亦同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;善美深微容别解，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;舒徐礼乐自圆融。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并记云：“（马）先生知予治姬旦之礼，颇申礼善乐美之旨，为之赞叹不已。予亦进&#39;舒徐&#39;一义，先生颔之者再，不以别解见摒焉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我回忆沈先生的三堂课，记录当时所见所闻的点点滴滴，敬取他的末句为题，以表怀念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>