<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[财富管理榜：29家最活跃金融机构，谁更用心看护您的财富？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261448]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wealth management is one of the core businesses of the global financial industry. It is one of the blue ocean markets where financial institutions are increasing competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Calculated in terms of personal financial assets, China has become the world&#39;s second largest wealth management market. As of the end of 2022, the scale of my country&#39;s wealth management market has reached 118.49 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 8.7%. Among them, the total scale of bank financial management and insurance asset management accounts for nearly 62%. At the same time, the huge potential of the wealth management market has attracted financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the wealth management market heats up and competition intensifies, regulatory agencies have issued new regulations one after another. In particular, the central bank, together with relevant departments, issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Regulating the Asset Management Business of Financial Institutions&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;commonly known as the &quot;New Asset Management Regulations&quot;&lt;/ span>;) is continuing to reshape the asset management market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The wealth management business in 2023 will not be easy. The lack of high-quality assets, the turmoil in the financial target market, and residents&#39; financial management deposits and regular deposits are all testing banks and insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to select evaluation objects? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the huge market temptation, increasingly strict supervision and unfavorable market environment, the competition between my country&#39;s commercial banks and insurance institutions in wealth management in 2023 How is the strength? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, the People&#39;s Bank of China announced the list of domestic systemically important banks. The People&#39;s Bank of China mainly evaluates and identifies systemically important banks from four dimensions: size, relevance, substitutability and complexity. Rated commercial banks are divided into different groups based on their scores. In addition to meeting minimum capital requirements, reserve capital and countercyclical capital requirements, banks in each group should also meet different additional capital requirements. Among them, core tier-one capital has the strongest loss-absorbing capacity and is the core indicator for measuring the comprehensive strength and risk compensation capabilities of commercial banks. It is also an important foundation for the operation and development of the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to statistics from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center, as of the end of June 2023, the total assets of the 20 systemically important banks reached 260 trillion yuan, accounting for the total assets of my country&#39;s commercial banks. About 3/4 of the assets; in the first half of 2023, a total net profit of 1.04 trillion was achieved, accounting for approximately 83% of the total net profit of my country’s commercial banks in the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the 20 most representative domestic systemically important banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also included nine major life insurance companies in the list for evaluation. The total original insurance premium income of the nine companies from January to October 2023 is approximately 1.8 trillion yuan, accounting for approximately 3/4 of the total original insurance premium income of the life insurance industry during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the main force in the wealth management market, how do commercial banks and insurance institutions seize the high ground? Can you provide high-quality wealth management products and services? To this end, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has constructed a wealth management index system to comprehensively evaluate the wealth management competitiveness of financial institutions in the banking and insurance industries. The results of the &quot;Wealth Management Ranking&quot; are intended to provide investors with a decision-making reference and provide useful reference for financial institutions to improve their competitiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank list: Six dimensions&amp;nbsp;Eighteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the wealth management business of twenty commercial banks, Southern Weekend The New Finance Research Center conducts a combined qualitative and quantitative assessment from six dimensions, and assigns appropriate weights to eighteen sub-indicators. The total weight of these qualitative and quantitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/67cc569e2b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2529&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/67cc569e2b.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The above main dimensions are now &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;analyzed&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and explained&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(1)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Wealth management scale&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and capability&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; : Maximum weight&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are 8 secondary indicators under wealth management scale and capability, with a total weight of 35%, accounting for half of the weight of all qualitative and quantitative indicators. Therefore, this dimension is the most important consideration in measuring the competitiveness of commercial banks’ wealth management. Among them, as the basis and prerequisite for carrying out wealth management business, there are five indicators related to the retail business of commercial banks, including: retail customer scale, personal deposit balance and its growth rate, total assets under management of retail customers and its growth rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, in order to gain insight into the profitability of the wealth management business of commercial banks, the fee and commission income generated by related businesses and their growth rate are also important measurement indicators. However, given that my country&#39;s wealth management market has not formed unified regulations for the wide range of businesses included in wealth management, and various commercial banks have inconsistent definitions of wealth management fees and commissions, this list uses the quantitative indicators of each bank&#39;s net fee and commission income and Whether to publish qualitative indicators of data related to wealth management business income to roughly assess the bank&#39;s wealth management profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To sum up, the scale of wealth management embodies the basic scale, competitiveness and profitability of commercial banks’ wealth management business, and is the most important dimension to measure the level of wealth management. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The scale of financial management business: embodies the &quot;two strengths&quot; of financial management products&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are 4 secondary indicators under the scale dimension of financial management business, with a total weight of 16%. Since the &quot;New Asset Management Regulations&quot; were officially implemented in 2022, major commercial banks have basically completed the net-value transformation of their wealth management business, and have established wealth management subsidiaries to undertake the design, development and operation of their wealth management products. Wealth management subsidiaries have thus become the core pillar of wealth management for commercial banks. This list uses four indicators, including the issuance scale and growth rate of wealth management products, net profit of wealth management subsidiaries and its growth rate, to consider the strength of each commercial bank&#39;s wealth management business, and also reflects the market competitiveness of each bank&#39;s wealth management products after the wealth management market is standardized. and the risk-resistance ability of wealth management products after the net-worth transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(3)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Private banking business: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Tinjian’s comprehensive service capabilities&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are three secondary indicators under the private banking business dimension, with a total weight of 12%. In order to attract high-net-worth customers, each bank has deployed private banking business, strengthened the construction of comprehensive private banking services, and enhanced the core competitive advantages of private banking business. This list uses three indicators: the number of private banking customers, the scale of private banking customer assets under management and its growth rate to measure the competitiveness of each bank&#39;s private banking business, thereby demonstrating the comprehensive service capabilities and level of each bank at the top of the pyramid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(4)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Wealth service capabilities: consider professionalism and initiative&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are three secondary indicators under the wealth service capability dimension, with a total weight of 7%. Different from the above-mentioned wealth management scale and wealth management business capabilities, wealth service capabilities mainly consider the professionalism of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business and their &quot;customer-centered&quot; proactive service awareness and capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, commercial banks should promptly explain the fluctuations in wealth management and financial management business income, continue to accompany customers and maintain high-level service capabilities; on the other hand, Commercial banks should attach great importance to the construction of wealth management teams, establish a wealth management talent training system, regularly organize various trainings, continuously improve the professional knowledge and service levels of financial management practitioners, and enhance the professionalism of wealth management business from both the company and client sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who wins the bank ranking? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The bank list of the 2023 wealth management list shows that Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, China Merchants Bank and Agricultural Bank of China occupy the top three. With its comprehensive capabilities and comprehensive strength in wealth management, ICBC ranked first with a total score of 77.40. China Merchants Bank relied on its leading edge in private banking to overtake state-owned banks and rank second on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28 /d67de23e50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2237&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d67de23e50.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, among the four major state-owned banks, the wealth management business of the four major industrial and agricultural banks, China Construction Bank, has strong economies of scale advantages and ranks high overall. Specifically, ICBC ranks first in wealth management scale, net fee and commission income, and overall ranking first; Agricultural Bank of China ranks among the top three in the list because it has the largest retail customer scale, personal deposit scale, and wealth management product scale; China Although the bank leads among the four major banks in terms of the growth rate of personal deposit balances and the growth rate of net fees and commissions, its number of retail customers and its efforts in financial investor education, professional talent team building, and the popularization of financial knowledge are China Construction Bank lost a lot of points due to lack of information disclosure, and finally ranked seventh; China Construction Bank&#39;s wealth management scale and financial business scale are comparable to ICBC, but the scale growth rate and net profit performance of its financial business have become its biggest loss points. Ranked only eighth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2023, although the trend of joint-stock bank residents&#39; deleveraging and deposit regularization has eased, the issuance of financial products and net worth performance have still continued the downturn in 2022. The market conditions have had an impact on the overall bank financial management business. In the first half of 2023, although the growth rate of wealth management scale of China Merchants Bank was negative, it ranked first among joint-stock banks and ranked second overall because its wealth management scale and private banking business performed much better than other joint-stock banks; Ping An Bank&#39;s wealth management scale ranked second among Ranked third among joint-stock banks, ranked first in net profit growth rate of wealth management subsidiaries, ranked first in growth rate of total assets under management of private banks, and disclosed the most complete and detailed information related to wealth management. Its comprehensive ranking surpassed some major state-owned banks and The leading stock bank ranks fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among city commercial banks, except for wealth service capabilities, Bank of Ningbo ranks first in all other indicators. Therefore, it ranks first among city commercial banks and has also been promoted to the comprehensive ranking. Fifth; Bank of Beijing and Minsheng Bank did not fully disclose information related to wealth management, and many key indicator data were not disclosed in the 2023 interim report, which seriously affected their scores and rankings, so they were at the bottom of the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Dimension analysis, wealth management scale and capability dimensions embody the basic scale, competitiveness and profitability of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business. Overall, state-owned banks have a relatively large base in wealth management business, strong ability to attract personal deposits, and excellent profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scale dimension of financial management business highlights the competitiveness of financial management products of various banks after the financial management market is standardized, and the risk resistance ability of financial management products after the net-worth transformation. Overall, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks perform well in terms of scale of financial management business. Some leaders are no smaller than state-owned banks and have good growth rates, highlighting the opportunities for latecomers to overtake in new business areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The private banking business dimension further reflects the capabilities and level of each bank in high-end wealth management services. Generally speaking, state-owned banks have a large private banking customer base and a large scale of managed private banking customer assets, and the private banking business of city commercial banks is also gradually speeding up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The wealth service capability dimension presents the professionalism and &quot;customer-centered&quot; initiative of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business. Overall, the era of wealth management has arrived, and all banks are allocating resources to this line. Each type of bank has perfect cases in this dimension. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insurance list: Five dimensions&amp;nbsp;Sixteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Aiming at the wealth management competitiveness of 9 leading life insurance companies, We conduct a combined qualitative and quantitative evaluation from three dimensions, and assign appropriate weights to the fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of these qualitative and quantitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After adding up the above three scores, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team ranked the total score from high to low to construct the 2023 Wealth Management Ranking Life insurance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking and Life Insurance Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/1aeaf2f52f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2073&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1aeaf2f52f.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking and Life Insurance Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The relevant dimensions are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(1) Channel building capabilities. There are 8 secondary indicators under the channel construction capability dimension, with a total weight of 40%. The construction of various channels is the basic ability of life insurance companies to engage in wealth management business and even the entire life insurance business, and it is also the most important influencing factor. Most of the life insurance companies evaluated have large agent teams and various distribution channels. They have strong sales capabilities and can reach a large number of customer groups, which helps attract customer groups to participate in wealth management business and increase the wealth management customer base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to more accurately consider the comprehensive strength of the nine life insurance companies in channel construction, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team evaluated individual insurance agent channels and bancassurance channels respectively. Quantitative indicators such as the channel’s premium income, new business value, and 13-month and 25-month premium/policy continuation rates are supplemented by qualitative evaluations of distribution channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2) Wealth management scale and capabilities. There are five secondary indicators under this dimension, with a total weight of 25%. Life insurance companies support the development of insurance liability business through wealth management business. Therefore, the scale of assets managed and invested by life insurance companies and their rate of return have become two important dimensions for measuring the wealth management strength of insurance companies. This list uses indicators such as third-party asset management scale, investment asset scale, total investment income and rate of return as quantitative indicators of the competitiveness of the wealth management business of the nine life insurance companies, and the adequacy of wealth management-related information disclosure as the nine life insurance companies. A qualitative indicator of the importance a company places on its wealth management business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(3) Business collaboration capabilities. Major life insurance companies attach great importance to business synergy, which is also an important starting point for strengthening the competitive advantages of related products and services. As competition in the wealth management market becomes increasingly fierce, life insurance companies can build their own &quot;ecosystem&quot; through multi-business collaboration and form a &quot;moat.&quot; Therefore, this list specifically considers the measures and achievements of nine life insurance companies in building ecosystems such as comprehensive health and comprehensive pension, and encourages insurance companies to provide differentiated services to customers through the &quot;insurance + service&quot; model, thereby highlighting relevant life insurance companies comparative advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why does the champion not dominate the rankings in one indicator? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The life insurance list of the 2023 wealth management list shows that Ping An Life, China Life and Taiping Life are among the top three. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the fourteen secondary indicators in the life insurance rankings, Ping An Life is not particularly conspicuous, only in the adequacy of information disclosure and the &quot;insurance + service&quot; model. It received the highest score among the two secondary indicators of category, and none of the other 12 quantitative indicators ranked first. However, in-depth analysis found that most of Ping An Life&#39;s indicators performed at the mid-to-upper level, with very few indicators clearly lagging behind. Specifically, among the twelve quantitative indicators, Ping An Life ranks second in five and third in four. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although China Life is the &quot;king&quot; in premiums in the life insurance industry, it implements more stringent statistics in the two key indicators that reflect the renewal rate. In terms of information disclosure and information disclosure, its scores on related indicators lagged behind those of its peers, dragging down its overall score and ultimately ranking second with a gap of 1.6 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taiping Life ranks first in two indicators: third-party asset management scale and 25-month premium/policy continuation rate, but its total investment return rate The two indicators of new business value and bancassurance channel lag behind peers, dragging down the overall ranking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28 /75a5eb9098.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1188&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/75a5eb9098.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259838&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of wealth management scale and capabilities, the larger the asset management scale, the higher the investment business returns, the stronger the ability to allocate large-scale assets, and the stronger the wealth management retail business will be. China Life and Ping An Life have obvious advantages in this indicator, with investment assets and total investment income significantly ahead of other life insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of channel construction capabilities, China Life’s number of agents in the individual insurance channel, premium income from the bancassurance channel, premium income from the individual insurance channel, and new innovations from the individual insurance channel All four indicators of business value ranked first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The business synergy dimension score shows that each of the nine life insurance companies has its own characteristics. For example, Sunshine Life focuses on the four core needs of family customers such as health care, pension planning, children&#39;s education and wealth management, and concentrates resources to create a multi-level &quot;insurance + service&quot; ecological service system covering the entire family life cycle; Taikang Life Insurance has cooperated with Taikang The layout of the early and high-density high-end retirement communities has formed a positive interaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The list also shows that the life insurance industry will continue to bottom out in 2022. Against the background of lower bank deposit interest rates, bank financial losses, and increased volatility in equity products such as stocks, life insurance products with higher interest rates have been highly sought after for more than half a year, and even experienced a pulse peak effect for a time. However, the rebound momentum is affected by various internal and external factors, and the overall performance throughout the year is unsatisfactory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Especially with the reduction of interest rates in the second half of the year and the implementation of the regulatory authorities&#39; &quot;unification of reporting and banking&quot; regulations, (for details, see Southern Weekend&#39;s &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.infzm.com/contents/259167&quot;>;How come the bancassurance business is deformed all year round when there are large accounts and small accounts?&lt;/a>;》) The competitiveness of product rates has decreased and the handling fees of bancassurance channels have dropped significantly. . The once hot-selling scene of life insurance products has returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth mentioning that the bancassurance channel is one of the important channels for many life insurance companies. The &quot;unification of reporting and banking&quot; will definitely have a long-term impact on the wealth management business of each life insurance company and test the coping capabilities of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江一煤矿发生事故，已有多人失联]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:43:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At around 15:00 on November 28, an impact occurred at the Shuangyang Coal Mine of Heilongjiang Longmei Shuangyashan Mining Co., Ltd. Ground pressure roof accident. The reporter learned from various sources that as of 16:00 on November 28, it was initially understood that many people were lost in the accident and related rescue work was in progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:55:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[MH370乘客家属索赔案开庭，此前已对马航等相关方提起多轮诉讼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was held in Chaoyang, Beijing The District People&#39;s Court holds a hearing. Photo provided by People&#39;s Vision&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the family members of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was opened in the Chaoyang District Court in Beijing. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case filed by the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not a single lawsuit. More than 40 family members independently sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties. The defendants include Malaysia Airlines (old Malaysia Airlines) and Malaysia International Airlines Berhad. (New Malaysia Airlines), Boeing Company, Rolls-Royce Holdings Limited, Allianz Insurance Group, etc. The trial will last from November 27 to around December 5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter learned that on the first day of the trial, the plaintiff and defendant had not yet entered the cross-examination phase, and Malaysia Airlines had not submitted new evidence, and they were all going through the legal process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly ten years after the accident, can this air crash come to a legal end in China? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Lost lawsuits in the United States and Malaysia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first lawsuit against the MH370 incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past ten years, the families of MH370 passengers have traveled to China, the United States and Malaysia, and have filed multiple rounds of lawsuits against Malaysia Airlines and other related parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;MH370&#39;s departure point is Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, and its destination is Beijing, China. There are no transfers or stops during transportation. For this type of international air transport incident, the main international treaties to refer to for the attribution of civil jurisdiction are the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1929 and the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1999 Convention (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the Montreal Convention&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the latter sets the compensation standards for civil aviation accidents and has the effect of priority application. China, the United States and Malaysia are all parties to the Montreal Convention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 33 of the Montreal Convention stipulates that a claim for damages may be brought at the plaintiff&#39;s option to the carrier&#39;s domicile, principal place of business, or the principal place of business where the contract is concluded. , destination and, in certain circumstances, the passenger’s fixed and permanent residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This means that in the MH370 air crash case, both Malaysia and China have jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, from the beginning of 2016 to March 7, Chinese family members sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties in the United States, Malaysia and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the lawsuits in the United States are mainly divided into two categories. One is a claim against Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies based on the Montreal Convention, and the other is a claim against the aircraft manufacturer Boeing. The company filed a product liability lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hao Junbo, a lawyer who has represented the families of an air crash in transnational litigation, told Southern Weekend reporters that the United States has the highest air crash compensation standards in the world, so worldwide, If an air crash occurs in almost any country, as long as the plane has a connection point with the United States, such as an engine or parts manufactured by an American company, attorneys from various countries will strive to prosecute the case in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Senior international aviation lawyer James Healy-Pratt wrote in 2021 that based on the jury’s recognition of unlimited compensation for bereavement, etc. Considering all these factors, the average amount of compensation awarded by American courts for air crash victims is the highest in the world, reaching US$5.2 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Hao Junbo said: &quot;In recent years, the possibility of foreign air crashes being tried by U.S. courts is very low, and they are generally dismissed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2018, the judge of multidistrict litigation in the United States ruled as forum non conveniens (&lt;em>;forum non conveniens&lt;/em>;) (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The principle of forum non conveniens means that after a court accepts a foreign-related case, it considers the many inconvenient factors in the trial of the case and believes that it is more convenient for the court to hear the case in other jurisdictions, so it gives up the case. The court dismissed all lawsuits arising from the disappearance of MH370 on the grounds of jurisdiction (&lt;/span>;), and the court believed that Malaysian courts were more suitable to hear these cases. The family chose to appeal, and in 2020, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit upheld the original verdict and dismissed all the family&#39;s lawsuits in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2017, 15 Chinese family members sued the Malaysian government, the Malaysian military and the Malaysian Civil Aviation Authority for &quot;negligence&quot; in Malaysia, demanding disclosure. the truth. In 2018, a Malaysian court ruled against the family due to insufficient evidence. In addition, from 2016 to 2020, the cases brought by family members against Malaysia Airlines and the Malaysian government in Malaysia were also lost due to insufficient evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The trial will not be affected by the outcome of foreign litigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The domestic litigation of the MH370 case can be traced back to 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced in 2015 that Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 crashed and it was presumed that all people on board were killed, Malaysia Airlines subsequently announced a compensation of 2.52 million to the families of each MH370 crash passenger. Yuan Yuan, but asked the family to give up pursuing responsibility against the Malaysian government, Malaysia Airlines, Malaysian military, and Boeing Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, nearly two-thirds of the families refused to sign the settlement agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, some family members who did not sign the agreement went to the Beijing Railway Transport Court to sue Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia Airlines International Berhad, Boeing Company, and Rolls-Rolls— Royce Holdings plc, Allianz Insurance Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2016, the Beijing Railway Transport Court announced that it had filed and accepted 36 civil claims for compensation from passengers involved in the crash of Malaysia Airlines flight MH370. At the end of 2017, the Beijing Railway Transport Court held a pre-trial meeting on the case, which was later designated by the Beijing High Court to be under the jurisdiction of the Beijing Chaoyang District Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, almost all family members who lost cases abroad returned to Chinese courts to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Qihuai, a lawyer representing some of the family members, said in a previous interview that for more than nine years, the court has actively promoted reconciliation between the two parties, and the family members and Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies have More than half of the cases are waiting for the parties involved to reconcile. As of March 2021, 89 families have refused to settle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, the lawsuits filed by the families of Chinese passengers involved in the crash were not supported by the courts in the United States and Malaysia. Will this result affect domestic litigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the relevant provisions of the judicial interpretation of the Civil Procedure Law, for cases where both Chinese and foreign courts have jurisdiction, one party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court, while the other party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court. If a lawsuit is filed in a Chinese court, the domestic court may accept the case. After the judgment, if a foreign court applies or the parties request a domestic court to recognize and enforce the judgment or ruling made by a foreign court on the case, it will not be allowed, unless otherwise provided for in an international treaty jointly concluded or acceded to by both parties. In addition, if a foreign court&#39;s judgment or ruling has been recognized by a domestic court, and the party files a lawsuit in a domestic court with the same dispute, it will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;An unnamed civil procedure law scholar told Southern Weekend reporters that generally speaking, even if a civil case is successful in a foreign country, the effective judgment must be made in If you apply for execution domestically, you should first apply to the domestic intermediate court with jurisdiction for recognition and execution. After passing the review, the court will rule to recognize its validity and issue an execution order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For civil cases that are lost abroad, first of all, there is no need to apply for enforcement. Secondly, as long as there are no special provisions, the parties can still sue domestically based on the same facts and causes of action. &quot;The aforementioned scholar told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although China and Malaysia have signed a bilateral judicial assistance treaty, namely the Treaty between the Government of the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Government of Malaysia on Criminal Judicial Assistance, the bilateral treaty stipulates that The content covers criminal cases and does not take into account judicial decisions on civil disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This means that the results of previous lawsuits filed abroad by the families of MH370 passengers will not affect the Chinese court&#39;s hearing of the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to CCTV news reports, the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. , a large part of the compensation costs is mental damage solatium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明月与乌皮靴：探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 28/a8b47c1659.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bright moon is a classic image in Li Bai&#39;s poems. The picture shows Li Bai under the moon in the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the screen, Li Bai was pardoned and released, and he was walking on a pole on the Yangtze River. With his temples completely white, he finished chanting &quot;Apes on Both Sides of the Strait&quot; I can&#39;t stop crying, the boat has passed the Ten Thousand Mountains.&quot; When he was excited, he raised his hand and threw the long pole into the water. In the cinema, children happily recited the poems and adults shed tears. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, an animated film &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot; will follow the &quot;National Treasure Season 2&quot; and &quot;Chang&#39;an Ten Thousand Miles&quot; in previous years. Programs such as &quot;Two Hours&quot; once again put Li Bai&#39;s name on the hot search list. Different types of games such as &quot;Hundred Scenes of Jiangnan&quot;, &quot;Glory of Kings&quot; and &quot;Ink Soul&quot; have all invited Li Bai into their own world. Dramas, operas, dance dramas, musicals, and Cantonese operas all use Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning the soul of more than 1,300 years ago in the theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, Sichuan, by Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if he put on black leather boots and entered the court, Li Bai still could not unfold his arms throughout his life. He endlessly expressed in his poems Chanting, &quot;If I don&#39;t look toward the east mountain for a long time, the roses will bloom several times. The white clouds will disperse on their own, and who will the bright moon fall on?&quot; Xie An&#39;s seclusion in Dongshan after his achievements made Li Bai fall in love, and &quot;Ming Yue&quot; became the embodiment of the ideal that Li Bai pursued throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Two years before his death, Li Bai met a Shu monk in Jiangxia, who was about to go to Chang&#39;an. Li Bai wrote, &quot;The moon of Mount Emei returns to you, and the wind blows west to Chang&#39;an. The Chang&#39;an Avenue spans nine days, and the moon of Mount Emei shines on Qinchuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai himself resumed his status as a commoner and never went to Chang&#39;an again, just like he left his hometown of Jiangyou, Sichuan when he was 24 years old and never returned in his life. In October 2023, Southern Weekend reporters revisited the two places to explore his wanderings between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9610ad4dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259843&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Want to go up to the sky and embrace the bright moon&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was 20 years old, he and another writer Zhang Shuo were known as &quot; Su Ting, who was &quot;extremely generous&quot;, went to Chengdu to take up his post. Li Bai took the opportunity to visit him on the way with his poems. Su Ting admired the young man in front of him very much, and said to his staff: &quot;This young scholar has outstanding talent, and his writing style is like a flowing river. Although his current writing is not strong enough, he already has a unique style. If he continues to grow His knowledge will definitely be comparable to that of Sima Xiangru in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Perhaps Li Bai did not expect that this was already the most glorious visit in his life. In the next twenty-two years, he experienced various failures and setbacks in &quot;every prince&quot; and &quot;experienced ministers&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 730, Li Bai first came to Chang&#39;an. He lived in Princess Yuzhen&#39;s villa in Zhongnan Mountain, and also visited other princes and ministers, but to no avail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 734, he passed by Xiangyang, visited Han Chaozong and handed him the &quot;Book of Jingzhou with Han&quot;. Han Chaozong was known as a good scholar, but he was indifferent to Li Bai&#39;s request for recommendation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1120f704f1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an Thirty Thousand Miles&quot;, the wandering Li Bai recited &quot;Quiet Night Thoughts&quot; under the moon. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Throughout his life, Li Bai never participated in the imperial examination, which was an extremely rare phenomenon among literati in the Tang Dynasty. One voice thinks that Li Bai disdains to participate, while the other is that Li Bai cannot participate. &lt;p>; qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Contemporary scholars such as Professor Lang Baoru of Inner Mongolia University interpret that even if it is not a &quot;family of industry and commerce&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s family &quot;hidden back to Guanghan in the early days of Shenlong&quot; and was not in the Ministry of Household Affairs Registration, no genealogy. Xiang Gong needs to provide documents that can prove his family background and identity, such as household registration and genealogy, for review by the Ministry of Household Affairs. People with &quot;unknown origins&quot; like Li Bai were naturally not eligible to be selected as tribute candidates by prefectures and counties and take part in the imperial examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai can only realize his ambition through other means. &quot;Roaming in the mountains and rivers, living in seclusion to study Taoism, making friends with Taoist priests, paying homage to local governors and ministers of the government and the public, all with the purpose of raising one&#39;s worth and creating a sensational effect in becoming famous in the capital and the emperor, and only then was Tianbao summoned to the capital.&quot; Chongqing Xiong Du, a professor at Technology and Business University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taoism was respected in the Tang Dynasty, and the royal family regarded Laozi and Li Er as their ancestors. During the Xuanzong period, respect for Laozi and Taoism reached its peak. From the emperor to his relatives, nobles and bureaucrats, everyone believed in Taoism. Xuanzong&#39;s two younger sisters, Princess Jinxian and Princess Yuzhen, simply became female Taoists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the age of 5, Li Bai lived in Changlong County, Mianzhou, central Sichuan (now Jiangyou City, Sichuan Province) for 19 years. As the birthplace of the Five Pecks of Rice Taoism, Shu Taoism is very popular and there are caves and heavens all over it. According to legend, Zhang Daoling, the founder of the sect, once lived in seclusion in Heming Mountain and preached in Qingcheng Mountain. There is still a Jinguang Cave in Qianyuan Mountain in Jiangyou, which is said to be the place where Nezha became a disciple and practiced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai was immersed in the atmosphere of Taoism. He visited famous Taoist mountains such as Mount Emei, Daitian Mountain, and Ziyun Mountain, and made many unique friends. He once lived in seclusion in the south of Minshan Mountain with Dong Yanzi, raised many birds, and learned the art of calling birds to his palm. Yuan Danqiu later became his best Taoist friend throughout his life, and invited him to visit Taoism in Songshan Mountain several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have traveled to the gods for fifteen years, and they have never stopped traveling. ... The jade boy in Xishan made me refine gold bones.&quot; &quot;Alchemy bones&quot; means refining elixirs. It seems that Li Bai was deeply influenced by Taoism at the age of fifteen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In traditional Chinese philosophy, Taoism is the philosophical category with the deepest exploration of the universe.&quot; Both Ding Ying and her father had an indissoluble bond with Li Bai. The father and daughter successively served as the director of the Li Bai Memorial Hall. She analyzed to the Southern Weekend reporter that Li Bai and Su Shi were both from Sichuan, and their poems were full of elegant and romantic atmosphere. &quot;We are in a basin, and it is difficult to get out. The only exit is the sky. Sichuan people have developed the habit of using their own brains to make up for the reality, so they all have magnificent imaginations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Modern people are no longer sure of the specific locations of the fairy mountains in Li Bai&#39;s works, but they may as well pay tribute and commemorate his enthusiasm. Today, there are more than 20 scenic spots in Jiangyou related to Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/bbdf37ed70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of young Li Bai in front of Longfeng Hall. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown in Qinglian Town, also known as Longxi Courtyard, has a colorful sculpture mountain gate screen wall and a courtyard left over from the Qianlong period of the Qing Dynasty. Residential. The Longfeng Hall, built in 2003, enshrines Li Er, the founder of Taoism, Li Guang, the general of the Western Han Dynasty, and Li Hao, the king of Xiliang in the Northern Dynasty - the latter two are ancestors jointly recognized by Li Bai and the Li Tang family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ef7f9cab54.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259846&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house in Li Bai’s hometown was rebuilt in the 53rd year of Qianlong’s reign in the Qing Dynasty (1788). Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​kilometer away from Longxi Hospital, there is a Taibai Temple. Wen Zaiqiao, director of Li Bai’s hometown, works here. He likes the tranquility here. . He mentioned to Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, when worship was still allowed, before the Mid-Autumn Festival every year, Guangdong businessmen would often come to the ancestral hall with their families and ask Taoist priests to perform rituals for three days. &quot;Li Bai likes the moon.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai never left Taoism throughout his life. However, there were many motivations for learning Taoism. Taoism&#39;s pursuit of freedom and eternity in individual life is exactly in line with Li Bai&#39;s pursuit of a spiritual state of indulgence and freedom. When he was politically frustrated, Li Bai often turned to mountains and rivers and wandering immortals. Taoism undoubtedly gave him spiritual comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The subtle relationship between studying Taoism and seeking official positions is much more secret. While the Tang Dynasty implemented the imperial examination system, it also recruited secluded wise men from time to time, asking them about political affairs, or asking them to come out to assist the king. Many of these people were Taoists. Xiong Du discovered that, compared with the strict scrutiny of family background in the imperial examination, talents specially ordered by the emperor could escape this rule. For example, Taoist figures such as Zhang Guo and Ye Fashan, who were rumored to have the secret of immortality, were recruited by the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also speculated that the reason why Li Bai is good at immortal Taoism may be related to this, &quot;It is to create for Xuanzong that he not only has the talent of Wang Zuo, but also a You really have the impression of being an &#39;immortal&#39; with an &#39;immortal spirit&#39;, so that you can avoid the trouble of tracing your family background and place of origin when you join the officialdom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spirit of taking off your boots is still in your sleeves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Night shrouds Xi&#39;an, and the lights of the &quot;Datang Everlasting City&quot; commercial street at the foot of the Big Wild Goose Pagoda come on. &quot;Prosperity of the Tang Dynasty&quot; performances are being performed all over the street. Amidst the loud drum music, &quot;Li Bai&quot; dressed in white clothes slowly rises from the rotating lanterns. Every night, this NPC (non-player character) will come here to exchange poems with tourists, &quot;Everyone, come and listen to this one again, the most difficult one among Taibai&#39;s poems.&quot; What he throws out is &quot;Thoughts on a Quiet Night.&quot; There is also a &quot;Li Bai&quot; in Xi&#39;an. In the &quot;Twelve Hours of Chang&#39;an&quot; theme district, a certain liquor company has built a Taibai wine shop. He holds a wine bowl and invites tourists sitting at the table to drink with him while reciting &quot;The wine will come in&quot;. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the Datang West Market Museum, a middle-aged lady who came with a group from Anhui told a Southern Weekend reporter that she observed that people traveling to Xi&#39;an pay attention to &quot; The most popular ones are the Terracotta Warriors and Horses, and the current recommendation is Li Yang’s Love.” Her tour guide, Xiao Liu, a native of Xi&#39;an, talked about Li Bai twice in the museum, &quot;casually&quot;. He admitted that he didn&#39;t know Li Bai at all before working, and he had relatively little contact with him after working. Except for a few tourists who like history, most of them People are similar to themselves, &quot;After watching &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, I understand a little bit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai actually did not have a fixed residence in the Tang Dynasty. He neither bought a house, nor was it found in relevant documents that he rented it. So like Bai Juyi, as his official position rose, his residence was from the south of the city to the imperial city, so the status level determines the level of wealth.&quot; Mao Jingru, education specialist of Xi&#39;an Museum, told Southern Weekend reporters that in history, &quot;Chang&#39;an It is not a place where he (Li Bai) has lived for a long time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 742, Li Bai received Xuanzong&#39;s order to enter Chang&#39;an. During the Sui and Tang Dynasties, some northern Hu people&#39;s clothing became popular in society, including the &quot;black leather Liuhe boots&quot; worn by the Hu people. Later, the official officially designated it as the standard wear for officials, which is quite similar to the black leather shoes commonly worn in modern formal occasions. When he first arrived in Chang&#39;an, Li Bai was still wearing the white linen clothes that symbolized the common people. This time, he changed into a round-neck robe and black leather boots and entered the capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai wrote &quot;Nanling Farewell Children Entering Beijing&quot; before leaving, &quot;It is not early to persuade the children to endure the hardships, and ride the whip on the horse for the long journey. ... Looking up to the sky and laughing out loud &quot;How can I be a Penghao person?&quot; Years of depression were relieved, and the ideal of displaying talents and strategies was given the opportunity to be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he had the ambition of &quot;lobbying thousands of people&quot;, and the position he was awarded was Hanlin enshrinement, or Hanlin waiting for the imperial edict. Unlike Hanlin scholars who are in charge of edicts and participate in political affairs, Hanlin ministers are a group of professionals in various fields who stay by the emperor&#39;s side to serve him. They had the opportunity to have real positions after being favored by the emperor. For example, Wang Shuwen, who was good at playing chess, and Wang Qian, who was proficient in calligraphy, waited for the imperial edict, were appreciated by Dezong, and served as attendant readers and calligraphers, and were promoted step by step. However, Li Bai entered the Imperial Academy with poetry and prose as his skills, and he always stayed in the position of a literary attendant and never entered the formal bureaucratic ranks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As time passed, Li Bai, who was living in the Hanlin Academy, found that his political ideals were becoming disillusioned. &quot;It&#39;s easy for blue flies to get together, but it&#39;s hard for white snow to harmonize with each other. It&#39;s meant to be dispersed,&quot; he said. People have repeatedly criticized others and promoted criticism.&quot; Not only could they not be reused, they were also slandered and ostracized by others. Opportunities that once seemed close at hand are actually out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/895515d194.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259847&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai once lamented in a poem that &quot;the road is difficult and divergent&quot;, but then he wrote, &quot;There will be long winds and waves, and the clouds and sails will rise across the sea.&quot; &quot;. The picture shows a still from the movie &quot;Chang&#39;an 30,000 Miles&quot;. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; and Liu Quanbai&#39;s &quot;Li Junjie Ji&quot; both pointed out that there were more than one or two people who slandered Li Bai. Wei Hao&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; names the slanderers: Xuanzong once intended to appoint Li Bai as Zhongshu Sheren, but he was slandered by his consort, Zhang Shuo&#39;s son Zhang Bian, and it was not realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, Li Bai&#39;s own political limitations are gradually being valued and emphasized. Zeng Yueyu and Zhou Shi described Li Bai&#39;s incompetent official performance in the novel &quot;Li Bai Trilogy&quot;: &quot;Li Bai has drafted several official edicts, which are related to the recent personnel changes in the DPRK. Logically, before the official announcement, the content must be strict Keep it secret. Li Bai, who was drunk, didn&#39;t care about that at all. He took advantage of the drunkenness to use the internal information as oral news, spreading it around regardless of occasion or location.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;There is no way to verify whether Li Bai ever drafted official documents, and the degree of leakage may not be as exaggerated as described, but there is evidence for such writing. Fan Chuanzheng, who wrote the inscription for Li Bai, said that he &quot;went in and out of the province while drunk, and had to talk about the greenhouse trees.&quot; Wang Qi of the Qing Dynasty also suspected that he &quot;had leaked the secrets of the ban while drunk, and the Ming Emperor ignored it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin, a professor at Northwest University, researched based on Li Zhao&#39;s &quot;Hanlin Chronicles&quot; that the Hanlin Academy in the Tang Dynasty had particularly strict requirements on work style. Any carelessness in words or deeds would be punished. It may ruin the political future. He concluded that those who served in the Hanlin Academy would be more cautious than bureaucrats in other institutions. He also discovered that Xuanzong himself had personal experience of the harm of drunkenness and had abstained from alcohol for the rest of his life. Therefore, Li Bai&#39;s addiction to drinking could not help but make Xuanzong worry about appointing him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For Li Bai, returning from the political center frustrated, being slandered and alienated can be said to be his true feelings at that time. However, due to his personality and officialdom Political alienation and conflicts led to another reason for his political failure, which was also obscured to some extent. In the final analysis, Li Bai&#39;s frustration in waiting for imperial edicts was the political failure of a talented poet.&quot; Li Fangmin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xuanzong, who once &quot;gave food on a bed of seven treasures and a spoon in his hand&quot;, gave the poet a grand courtesy, but whether he would let Li Bai participate in politics must be marked by a question mark. In Duan Chengshi&#39;s &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Xuanzong said to Gao Lishi, &quot;This man is really poor.&quot; Meng Qi&#39;s &quot;Benshi Shi&quot; records that Xuanzong &quot;used it as a non-corridor temple vessel, so he dismissed it with an imperial edict.&quot; Everyone is saying that Li Bai left an impression on Xuanzong, and that this person was not worthy of elegance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The discord between Li Bai&#39;s celebrity temperament and officialdom is concentrated in the matter of &quot;taking off his boots&quot;. Academic circles have different opinions on whether Li Bai ever asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots. Some scholars regard it as a novelist&#39;s statement and cannot be trusted. Zhou Xunchu, a professor at Nanjing University, believes that although Gao Lishi was the most favored eunuch by Xuanzong, under normal circumstances, Li Bai would not have ordered him to take off his boots. However, &quot;Li Bai was wild in nature and was drunk, so there was no clear reason to exclude this matter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The movie &quot;The Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; combines the two anecdotes of Lishi taking off his boots and writing &quot;Qing Ping Tiao&quot;. Gao Lishi asked Li Bai to compose a poem for Yang Yuhuan, and Li Bai took off his boots. After two rounds of fighting, Gao Lishi reluctantly took off a black leather boot for Li Bai. Li Bai was half drunk and half awake while writing &quot;Qing Ping Diao&quot;, which was praised by Yang Yuhuan, but Li Bai bluntly said that he did not write it specifically for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Tang Dynasty is really amazing if you have you.&quot; In the movie, Yang Yuhuan appreciates this sincerity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The moon shines on Qinchuan on Mount Emei&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 744, on a spring night in Chang&#39;an City where flowers were blooming, Li Bai drank wine alone. There was no one around, but he was determined not to drink the contents of the cup quietly, so he sang and danced wildly, inviting the bright moon in the sky and the lonely shadow on the ground to drink together. He wants to get drunk, and then heaven, earth, and himself will cease to exist, and everything that is not going as he wants will be annihilated. At this time, it was less than two years since Li Bai was waiting for imperial edict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On an autumn night half a year ago&lt;/span>;, he was slandered and shunned in the officialdom, and his ambitions were difficult to realize. The frustrated Li Bai thought of the moon in his hometown: &quot; The dim clouds are falling, and the love of the past is dim. The green rose moon on the autumn mountain, who will see it tonight?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Finally, he left Chang&#39;an, leaving only Read such masterpieces as &quot;Drinking Alone Under the Moon&quot; and &quot;Wine to Ask the Moon&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, Li Bai had gone through two-thirds of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;On the Nine Heavens of Chang&#39;an Palace, this place was once a close minister.&quot; Everything suddenly disappeared and became a memory. Li Bai&#39;s hope of finding a way out in the court was shattered, and he urgently needed to find spiritual sustenance. His deceased wife left behind a pair of children, but the time he spent with the children was far less than the amount of time he spent practicing Taoism in seclusion with the Taoist priests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Ziji Palace of the Taoist Temple in Jinan, Li Bai asked the Taoist priest Gao Rugui to teach him the Taoism and became a Taoist priest. From the time when Tianbao left Chang&#39;an in the late spring of the third year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, to when he traveled south to Wuyue in the fifth year of Tianbao&#39;s reign, this was the period when he was most worldly-minded. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Du Fu and Li Bai also met at this time. Du Fu experienced the blow of failing the imperial examination, and with a common depressing mood, he saw the depth and persistence behind Li Bai&#39;s wild and unrestrained attitude. &quot;We spend our days drinking and singing wildly, who is the hero of flying and domineering.&quot; This sympathy for each other continued in the lives of the two poets, even if they never met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While wandering in the south, Li Bai kept witnessing the disappearance of old friends, and his mentality changed. When he arrived in Siming (now Shaoxing, Zhejiang), he paid homage to He Zhizhang, who died of illness here, and missed the years when they met in Chang&#39;an to exchange wine with each other. While in Jinling, another series of bad news came: his friend Cui Chengfu was demoted, Li Shizhi was forced to commit suicide, and Li Yong and Pei Dunfu were killed with a stick. Li Linfu, who was in power, was imprisoned many times, unjust cases appeared one after another, and the government and the public were filled with an atmosphere of terror. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai could no longer feel safe in seclusion. He often worried about the fate of the country, and his passion for serving the world deep in his heart burned again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He often expressed his longing to retire to the wild mountains and rivers, but whenever he had the opportunity, he always expressed his desire to return to the court immediately. He just couldn&#39;t get rid of going to the emperor&#39;s side. The ideal and desire to achieve great things,&quot; Ha Jin wrote in &quot;The Road to Heaven: The Biography of Li Bai.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After getting married for the second time in Liang Yuan, he went north to the land of Youyan, hoping to seek development by joining the army. In the poem presented to the judge He Changhao, Li Bai&#39;s intention is obvious. He is ashamed to be a scholar of Zhangju, and he is unwilling to be like Geng Yin. He actually wants to rise up with a sword and collect extraordinary achievements in the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On this trip north, Li Bai arrived at the jurisdiction of Anlu Mountain, and perhaps saw clearly the truth that the latter was preparing to rebel. Li Bai returned frustrated. He felt helpless against the internal and external troubles of the Li Tang Dynasty, so he could only seek seclusion in the south again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Besides studying Taoism, Li Bai, who has stars on his temples, is increasingly aware of the importance of one thing. &quot;Knowing what is wrong at fifty is what the ancients have done. If you make up for your mistakes with words, you will live forever.&quot; &quot;I am determined to delete the story and reflect it for thousands of years.&quot; He made it clear that there is no hope of meritorious service, and perhaps his destiny is to make words. It can also be said that Li Bai truly became aware of his identity as a poet when he was around fifty years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s first wandering ended with the scene of entering Chang&#39;an; the last wandering also had an event that brought it to an end, that is, joining the team of Yongwang Li Lin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, the Anshi Rebellion broke out, and people fled the war and were displaced. Wang Changling returned to his hometown, and when passing through Jianghuai, he was killed by the governor who hated him. Du Fu moved his family to Yanzhou for refuge. He heard that after Suzong ascended the throne in Lingwu, he went north to Lingwu and was captured by the rebels on the way and taken to Chang&#39;an. The poet Wang Wei was taken prisoner to Luoyang by the rebels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai and his wife Zong fled south to seek refuge and lived in seclusion in Lushan Mountain. He once planned to lobby the Li Tang clan in Jiangnan to raise troops to serve the king, and had dealings with both Xu Wang Yannian and Wu Wang Zhi. It happened that Yong Wang Li Lin raised his army and patrolled eastward to Xunyang. He repeatedly invited him to be an aide, and Li Bai finally agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is 56 years old and this is probably his last chance. This person with a complex of the Eastern Jin Dynasty feels that the old dream of the previous dynasty is right in front of him. At the end of the Jin Dynasty, the Five Husties disrupted China, and the Eastern Jin Dynasty established its country in Jinling, inheriting the lineage of the Central Plains. Will the Anshi Rebellion achieve Li Bai just like the Battle of Feishui in the previous dynasty achieved Xie An? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Fangmin understood that it was inevitable for Li Bai to join the Yongwang Li Lin. This move combined the objective situation and subjective wishes. He speculated that when Li Lin&#39;s lobbyist Wei Zichun was lobbying Li Bai, he hinted that Li Lin&#39;s actions in Jiangling and even on the eastward tour were in accordance with Xuanyuan&#39;s purpose and had the strategic purpose of managing Jiangnan. With these, he was able to impress Li Bai, who had an old love for Xuanzong as a monarch and a minister, and once again inspired his desire to help the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Lin was defeated, Li Bai was downgraded from a capital crime to a first-class crime, and was sentenced to Changliu Yelang. He set out from Xunyang, traveled to Dongting, and went up to the Three Gorges. When he first arrived in Wushan, he encountered a nationwide amnesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, the counter-insurgency war was still going on. Not only was a large area of ​​land north of the Yellow River in Shi Siming&#39;s hands, but the rebels continued to invade the south. The situation was very serious. After wandering for thousands of miles, Li Bai once again had the idea of ​​​​serving the world. In Jiangxia, the political center of the south, while waiting for news about his friend Wei Liangzai in the capital, he went to visit some officials and waited for several months. , the imperial court showed no sign of conscription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With no hope of meritorious service, Li Bai then thought of writing poems and speeches. &quot;Qu Ping&#39;s poems and poems hang over the sun and moon, and the Chu king&#39;s terrace is empty on the hills.&quot; He compared the two lives of Qu Yuan and the King of Chu: Qu Yuan was loyal and patriotic, but was exiled, but his poems and poems can compete with the sun and moon and are immortal through the ages; while the King of Chu The palaces, towers and pavilions built with extravagance and lust have long since disappeared, leaving nothing but desolate hills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai asked people to compile collections three times during his lifetime. Once he invited Duke Dongqian of the Han Dynasty, once he invited Wei Hao, and once he invited his clan uncle Li Yangbing. The end of Qian Gong&#39;s manuscript is unknown. Wei Hao followed Li Bai all the way, and the two became friends with each other. Li Bai gave him all the manuscripts at that time. Wei Hao was the editor selected by Li Bai when he was in good health and thoughtful. However, the &quot;Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; he compiled for Li Bai were mostly fragments recovered from the Anshi Rebellion where &quot;all the chapters and sentences were exhausted&quot;. Li Bai was seriously ill in his later years and had no time to sort out the drafts. There was only one Li Yangbing around. Entrusting the poem manuscript to the pillow, there is no choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was 60 years old, he returned to Xunyang and climbed Mount Lu again, determined to spend the rest of his years traveling as an immortal and learning Taoism. However, he could not forget about the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he heard that Shi Chaoyi&#39;s power was back on the rise and Li Guangbi sent troops to suppress it, he resolutely asked Ying to participate, but he returned halfway due to illness. Li Bai is old. But the passion that had been ignited in him since his youth had never been extinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;His understanding of things, his political ideals and thinking have been like this throughout his life. He has established his ideas since he was young and implemented them. I think People like us would never know ourselves ten years ago, but from youth to old age, he maintained an innocent young heart.&quot; Ding Ying lamented to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 762, when Emperor Daizong came to the throne, he searched widely for talents and granted Li Bai the official position of Zuo Shiyi. However, &quot;he was not born with enough salary, but he became an official after he was not born.&quot; When the edict came, Li Bai had already passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are different opinions on the cause of Li Bai&#39;s death. &quot;Jumping into the river to catch the moon&quot; or &quot;riding a whale to catch the moon&quot; have always been talked about. Japanese sinologist Tomohisa Matsuura believes that these legends are sensitive to Li Bai&#39;s hobby. Li Bai unconditionally affirmed the existence of the moon and pursued the integration with the bright moon. &lt;p>; There are earth-shattering articles.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A thousand years later, Gong Zizhen said in &quot;The Most Recorded Collection of Li Bai&quot;: &quot;Zhuang (Zhou) and Qu (Yuan) Shi cannot be combined. Combine it with your heart and start from the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e35e8ee3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d4e35e8ee3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 259848&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai’s hometown Taibai Stele Forest contains mainly Li Bai&#39;s poems written by famous calligraphers and painters of past dynasties and couplets praising Li Bai. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Today&#39;s people don&#39;t see the ancient moon, but this month once illuminated the ancients.&quot; The moonlight of Mount Emei is spreading over Chang&#39;an Avenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探寻“光影世界”之外的李白]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261467]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 15:05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Animated movies, TV shows, games, dramas... various works have Li Bai as the protagonist, summoning more than 1,300 people The soul of years ago. Why do people talk about Li Bai in 2023?</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[滴滴“崩了”的12小时：损失千万订单量和超4亿成交额]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At around 10:30 a.m. on November 28, a Southern+ reporter discovered after testing Didi Travel App in Guangzhou , At present, Didi Chuxing&#39;s business, including online ride-hailing and shared bicycles, has returned to normal. However, this comprehensive functional paralysis lasted for nearly 12 hours, which is also the longest failure of Didi Chuxing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Didi Chuxing’s previously announced financial report for the third quarter of 2023, the total transaction volume of China’s travel business in a single quarter was 72.5 billion yuan, and the average daily order volume reached 31.3 million. With this “collapse” Calculating the duration of the failure, it is estimated that Didi will lose over 10 million orders and over 400 million transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As for the reason why Didi Chuxing App crashed for a long time, Didi Chuxing has not responded as of press time. However, judging from the system failure, some relevant people in the industry pointed out that the cause of the failure is likely to come from Didi’s own computer room network problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data shows that as a network service that requires extremely high response speed to data volume, the frequency of Didi Chuxing failures is not low. On September 22, 2022, users reported that Didi Chuxing could not be used normally. At that time, Didi Chuxing responded that &quot;due to a computer room network failure, some Didi services were affected.&quot; The failure had been repaired within half a year. On February 25, 2021, &quot;Didi crashed&quot; also appeared on the hot search. Didi Chuxing responded at the time that it was due to a &quot;system abnormality&quot; and the fault was quickly resolved. Earlier in October 2019, July 2016 and October 2015, Didi also experienced system failures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Didi Chuxing’s cloud services are mainly supported by Didi Cloud. According to Didi Cloud&#39;s official website, Didi Chuxing&#39;s cloud computing services are based on Didi Chuxing&#39;s business technology and experience accumulation. It adopts leading cloud computing architecture, high-specification server cluster construction, high-performance resource allocation mechanism, and refined operation model, and is committed to It provides developers with IT infrastructure cloud services that are simple, fast, efficient, stable, cost-effective, safe and reliable. According to Southern+ reporters, as early as March this year, Didi Cloud no longer provided public cloud services to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Have Didi ride-hailing and other services resumed? Reporter’s actual measurement: Still “paralyzed” in Guangzhou&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 28, according to Southern+ reporters’ experience in Guangzhou, relevant faults have not yet occurred. Completely solved, Didi Chuxing&#39;s online ride-hailing service still cannot accurately locate, and Qingju Bicycle cannot scan the QR code. &quot;The system is out of order, please try again later&quot; will be displayed in the App. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227faf725b916fa85968.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/634912d001c6227faf725b916fa85968.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259865&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739f6a430c50ca5b142bf1bef5b06fff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/739f6a430c50ca5b142bf1bef5b06fff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, Didi Chuxing told Southern+ reporters that it is &quot;very sorry&quot; for the inconvenience caused to users due to the failure of Didi Chuxing App, and is continuing to work hard to solve the problem. Please ask for travel during morning peak hours. Users pay attention to safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Didi Chuxing: Ride-hailing and other services have been restored, and cycling and other services are still being repaired&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 28, Didi Chuxing’s official Weibo posted that after the technical team repaired it overnight, Didi’s ride-hailing and other services have been restored. Cycling and other services are still being restored, and all Qingju vehicles that can be unlocked or unlocked can be ridden for free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8903bee1065a927825016b5e94b0bbff.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8903bee1065a927825016b5e94b0bbff.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259866&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[上班要不要强制穿工服，这是一个问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, &quot;Does your company require you to wear work clothes at work?&quot; Hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A netizen attended a class reunion. A total of ten people came. It turned out that three classmates who worked in different financial institutions were wearing almost identical work clothes. Nowadays, different units have different requirements for dress code. Some require employees to wear work clothes while others do not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This seems to be a small problem, but it is not. For example, in September, the U.S. Senate was in an uproar over whether members should wear formal attire when entering the Capitol. In the end, the U.S. Senate revised the dress code: allowing senators to wear casual attire such as hoodies and shorts. This move attracted criticism from mainstream media such as The New York Times and The Washington Post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Institutions, companies, and organizations around the world are faced with a multiple-choice question when it comes to employee attire: Should they uniformly dress? What are the considerations of whether to do it or not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/TQRExQi6pPp7lbrXzwLPQr6NFmeV6iqB9PvTA67a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Realistic Considerations of Uniform Dressing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;work clothes&quot; are actually people from the same institution or organization wearing uniform styles of clothing to identify them. identity, indicate their profession, and demonstrate their responsibilities. Generally speaking, work uniforms are uniform, rigorous, and depersonalized, and are distinguished from employees&#39; personal attire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a company&#39;s perspective, employees often have practical considerations when wearing uniforms. First of all, this is a need to shape the corporate image. Employees are uniformly dressed and neatly organized, which will leave an initial impression that the company is rigorous, serious, and positive; uniform work uniforms generally have the company&#39;s logo on them, which can play a role in promoting the company&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, for those positions that face customers directly and have more communication with customers, such as the financial industry and the lawyer industry, uniform attire of employees can bring customers A professional look and feel helps to dispel customers&#39; doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Furthermore, for workers, wearing uniform professional work clothes can play a role in psychological suggestion, help them enter the working state, and improve their work performance. execution ability. At the same time, wearing work uniforms can also restrain the employee&#39;s personal behavior, reminding him that his words and deeds represent not only his personal image, but also the image of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also some special professions, and uniform dress is to reflect the authority and seriousness of the profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, our country has put forward uniform dress requirements for some public authorities, including the public security department, national security department, judicial department, court system, procuratorate system, Customs system, tax system, national quality inspection department, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, this time the U.S. Senate relaxed its dress requirements, which attracted criticism because public opinion was worried that this would undermine the seriousness of Congress. The New York Times wrote this: With the United States so divided right now, one of the last signs of harmony in the Senate is the dress code. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While it does not erase the deep differences beneath the surface, it does remind each senator that their goal is still to pursue majority consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also uniform attire for some professions, which are determined by the characteristics of the profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, doctors&#39; white coats were first used to promote disinfection habits in surgical operations. The blood stains on the white coats serve as reminders; in addition, clean and tidy clothes White coats can also help doctors prevent static electricity during treatment. Many medical devices are very precise instruments, and the impact of static electricity on the equipment may mislead the diagnosis and treatment results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When doctors enter the operating room, they usually wear blue or green surgical gowns, which is related to &quot;persistence of vision&quot;. During the operation, when the doctor sees the patient&#39;s red blood and shifts his gaze to the doctor&#39;s white robe, a &quot;complementary color afterimage&quot; will appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As long as the doctor looks at the complementary color of red - such as blue or green, it can immediately alleviate the effect of &quot;complementary color afterimage&quot; and reduce visual fatigue, so the surgery Most servers use blue-green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2F2m5ab8kKdYI9MV0kEF1gEN4PdH8eXeiBZXTEV2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2F2m5ab8kKdYI9MV0kEF1gEN4PdH8eXeiBZXTEV2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; Relaxation requirements are not necessarily bad. &lt;/H4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some units and institutions require unified dress, with reasonable reasons, but this does not mean that uniform dressing is suitable for all all to all of all Units do not mean that uniform costumes are favorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some people who have experienced the 1970s and 1980s may be impressed by the &quot;unified dress&quot; of that era. At that time, there was a name called &quot;law enforcement&quot;, and all a public unit would be uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the one hand, it reflects the sense of honor, &quot;there is a head&quot;; on the other hand, the work uniform is the &quot;invisible benefits&quot; of the unit, and some units take the staff The clothing all year round was packed, but the finances were paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So that some industries and personnel who did not have the functions of administrative management were also uniformly dressed, and they moved closer to the dressing of the law enforcement department. It has damaged the seriousness of the law enforcement department, wasted the finances, and also had a bad impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, starting from 1986, the State Council rectified the unified dress. In 1988, 1991, 1992, 2003, the State Council issued a unified dress issue. Related notices, criticizing those departments that uniformly uniform dressing, &quot;not only affect the seriousness of uniform dressing, but also lead to increasing fiscal expenditure.&quot; Later, the State Council also made clear stipulation on the unified dressing department and personnel. It can be seen that it is not uniform or good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Unified dressing will bring constraints, stereotypes, and uncomfortable feelings to some professionals. Therefore, many employees opposed the unified dress. A British survey showed that 61%of the people looking for new jobs in 2017 said they would have a negative view of any company that executed the decoration specifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In order to fight monotonous uniform clothes, the Western workplace was born in the Western workplace. On the day, at least on this day, you can grasp the autonomy of dressing and be free to be yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another study shows that if the dressing requirements are easier, most British labor will feel higher efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Those big companies that pay attention to creative ideas often do not require employees&#39; dressing, such as Microsoft and Facebook. Although the employees may be different, such as the programmer loves a plaid shirt, Zuckerberg wore the same casual clothes every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These technology companies not only do not require employees, they will also improve the work environment. Stimulate employees&#39; imagination and creativity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In short, it is difficult to generalize whether employees need to be unified. Some occupations emphasize seriousness, and some occupations value the perception that they bring to customers. Some occupations have special occupational attributes, and some occupations are more concerned about how to maximize the creativity ... Different demands are facing pretending to pretend to pretend to be pretending to be. There are different requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the staff, the unified dressing problem is not so big, if the unit is free to send the work service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南开段峰：“拿着金饭碗讨饭”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261413]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; In June 2022, Duan Feng team implemented an intervention brain interface in the sheep brain for the first time; one year later In May 2023, led by Duan Feng&#39;s team, the first &quot;non -human spiritual long animal (monkey) interventional brain machine jointly completed by the Duan Feng team (301 Hospital) and Shanghai Xinwei Medical Technology Co., Ltd. &quot;Interface Test&quot; successful. This study has been believed by many media that the disadvantages of the invasive and non -invasive brain interfaces have been overcome, and the third new paradigm of the brain interface has been created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Duan Feng, 46, is currently a professor, doctoral supervisor, and the director of the key laboratory of Tianjin&#39;s intervention of brain machines and intelligent rehabilitation. Due to the outstanding results of Duan Feng in the fields of brain -machine interface, artificial hibernation and smart aircraft, he was elected as a science and innovation person in the Southern Weekend 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the southern weekend science and technology conference&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/298bbbf676.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/imedias/23/11/27/298bbbf6766 .jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259781 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; November 16, 2023, Duan Feng gave a speech at the southern weekend conference of science and technology innovation conferences &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the definition of the Chinese Communications Institute, the Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) technology is a transformed human-computer interaction. Establish a new communication and control channel with external equipment, which has the effect of monitoring, replacement, improvement/restoration of damage or obstacles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a cutting -edge technology with multidisciplinary interdisciplinary. It can not only assist in the diagnosis and treatment of some neurological diseases, half part or fully realize the compensation of certain human functions, and it is expected to cure some psychological diseases. Medical is considered to be its most market prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are three main implementation methods of brain machine interfaces, non -invasive, invasive and vascular intervention. Non -invasive brain -type interface mainly refers to collecting brain electrical signals in the brain scalp layer, without surgery; invading type requires implantation of electrodes into deep brain parts, and surgery such as craniotomy and drilling bone; Electric electrical signals are collected into the corresponding inner wall of the corresponding blood vessels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the research of the brain interface is mostly in the basic research stage, and it has also achieved some clinical results. In June 2022, researchers at Johns Hopkins University completed the world&#39;s first bilateral transplantation of bilateral -integrated brain interface human trials. A 30 -year -old subject successfully controlled the machinery through brain electrical signals and completed Delivery cakes and autonomous food; in China, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital started the brain -pass interface and deep brain electrical stimulation method in 2020 to treat refractory depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the addition of Meta and &quot;Silicon Valley Iron Man&quot; Elon Musk (Neuralink, Elon Musk, the entry of the brain interface in recent years has increased unprecedentedly. Duan Feng was also established in 2023 The company tried to transform the results of the brain interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, since the return of Japan in 2009, he has been on the way to grasp teaching and research and starting a business with one hand. To this end, he did not plant a few followers. &quot;10 years of 100 billion yuan, do it,&quot; also became his &quot;test gold stone&quot; that he tested whether investors sincerely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The following is the interview with Duan Feng on the southern weekend: &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Want to build a &quot;integrated industry, research, research integration&quot; platform &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; From the perspective of academic background, you obtained a master&#39;s degree from the School of Mechanical Engineering, Tianjin University, and studied for precision mechanical engineering at the University of Tokyo, Japan. Degree, entrepreneurially chose medical rehabilitation equipment because it has always been interested in machinery? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I took the college entrance examination in 1998. The major I want to learn is actually electronics. The file was filled with obedience and distribution, and was adjusted to the School of Mechanical Engineering of Tianjin University. Studying in Japan is also an accidental choice. During the master&#39;s degree, the instructor sent me to two engine companies to cooperate. At that time, the mechanical industry was downturn and went to the family to close the family. It was very embarrassing. It happened that the enrollment of the University of Tokyo, Japan, not only exempt from the application fee, but also provided scholarships, round -trip air tickets and accommodation. The conditions are very good. I chose precision manufacturing related to machinery in their admissions major. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did you turn to the brain interface? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I have studied intelligent service robots and unitized flexible production lines in Japan. Go to the brain interface. I first heard the concept of the brain interface at a lecture at the University of Tokyo. At that time, I felt very interesting, but at that time, I couldn&#39;t share my body to study in depth. The biggest reason is that I want to copy Japan&#39;s &quot;industry -university -research&quot; model in China. During my studies in Japan, I encountered many companies to go to colleges and universities to ask students to eat, use talents, provide students with scholarships, provide teachers with scientific research project funds, and realize the integration of &quot;industry -university -research&quot;. Rare. After graduating, I returned to China to enter Nankai University. After completing the teaching task, I could study the fields I am interested in, and then set out to build a company to industrialize the research results. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did you start a business at that time? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I taught at the university while understanding the market situation. Specifically, it is something that is urgently needed to cooperate with enterprises to develop markets but has half a step left in technology development. At that time, some friends introduced some small medical device enterprise cooperation assistive device products, which was the type of limb movement with external forces, but it was not autonomous exercise. I hope to be an instrument that can be used by people to control the device to drive physical exercise, but I don&#39;t want to sell products, because it needs a series of problems such as equipment registration, quality inspection, and business promotion, so I anchor the technical research and development of the front end of the product. When I first returned to China, the monthly salary was only 3800 yuan, the rent was 2,000 yuan, the child&#39;s kindergarten tuition fee was 1,500 yuan, and there were only 300 yuan per month. I think most entrepreneurs should have more money than me. Because I have no money, I have always pinned the hope of raising money to find partners or investors, so I also took a lot of detours and experienced a process of registering, cancellation, re -registration, and cancellation. The east wall supplemented the west wall, there was a difficult period. Earlier I considered making some small rehabilitation stimulating equipment. A company talked to me about cooperation and asked me to do the front -end research and development. Zi, there is nothing behind it. There are also companies that let me share their technology and promise to give their equity. As a result, we have cooked money, spent time, and invested a lot of energy. After the technical molding, the &quot;partner&quot; ran away. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How did the start-up start gold solved? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; Selling technology is saved. It is to help the enterprise develop what they need, and then sell it. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The impact on you is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is your impact is you. What? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; I am also reflecting and summarizing it myself, whether it is scientific research or industry, and ask myself if this is the matter What I really want to do, if no one wants to do, I want to do it, then it should be done. When I do n’t pin my hope on others, rely on my own efforts and persistence to do what I want to do, many people who help me take the initiative to find it. Some bring money, some bring resources. Others bring some new ideas and ideas, and slowly this matter. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; No &quot; Is it &quot;liar&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When you have some &quot;step on the pit&quot; experience, it is easier to evaluate the risk of the person. Now come to me to talk about In a few minutes, you can know if it is suitable. I will not accept other people&#39;s investment casually. Some people come to me to talk about. I usually ask a question, &quot;10 years of 100 billion, do you do?&quot; If you don&#39;t want, don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. Here, it is okay, no, no, there is no middle area. These 100 billion were not coming to make a picture of the head, and it was scientifically estimated. I do an interface test of the blood vessel intervention -type brain machine. Each electrode is grinded by hand by hand. This takes 24 hours to run for 10 days to make one. Get up at least 100,000 yuan; if you use a large animal monkey for experiments, buy a monkey 200,000 yuan, and you need to spend 300 yuan a day. This cost is very high. &quot;Ten years of 100 billion&quot; is only used to test whether investors have patience and sincerity to accompany the product to grow, not to say that someone must take out 100 billion yuan. If the other party spent how much time and how much money, there is no minimum perception of possible investment returns. Come and say that they are familiar with the people of the governments of other local governments. To do our best, these are not partners we will choose. We also hope to cooperate with ideal and ideal people. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Whether an invasive or non-invasive formula, it is not optimistic. Kaita_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Research on brain interfaces in the past few years is very hot. What are the advantages and disadvantages of invasive and non -invasive brain machine interfaces? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Non -invasive brain machine interface, because it is non -invasive and safer. It mainly collects nerve discharge signals gathered on the surface of the scalp. Because this signal collection must be through the skull and layer of tissue cells, and there are more interference signals of the scalp, so the collected brain electrical signals are not very stable, collect some large large large, collect some large large large, collect some large large, and collect some large large. The action brain electrical signal is okay, but the time is long or the actions are finely identified. The invasive brain interface is to implant the electrode in the brain by turning on the skull. If you want to collect signals in a certain aspect, you need to implant the electrode into the corresponding brain area. Generally, within half a year, the signal collected by the invasive brain machine interface is more accurate, and the effect of human -machine interaction is also better. For example, the completion of the control of robotic arms grasping items is relatively high. But after half a year, it is difficult to say, because the electrode is harmful to the brain, it may be rejected, pus can be used, and the accumulation of scar tissue can be easily formed around the electrode. The damage is also relatively large. Therefore, its sustainability is very poor, and the brain electrical signal collected in the later period will also weaken, and it will not even be a signal. This is also a fatal short board for intrusion brain machine interface. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 2023, the invasive brain of neuralink The machine interface began to recruit clinical trial objects. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Entry -type damage is great, but there are still many companies to do. What is a person? Is it carbon -based creature? What are these electrode materials? People are fundamentally compatible with these materials. I have done a mouse&#39;s invasive brain -type interface, and the mice are dead. Musk also died before the test of Musk. This direction is problematic in terms of long -term security. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body _gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Why do you do this &quot;the first non-world non-world non Human spiritual animal (monkey) intervention brain interface test &quot;? How do you choose animal type and what is the test process? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; Try &lt;span>; Whenever it was done in June 2022, and it was originally to verify the feasibility of the interventional brain interface. Although there are some relevant reports internationally, it is true and false, and only after verification can it be known. In terms of details, such as verifying the sensor, can it last for more than half a year in the brain of animals. For blood vessel intervention -type brain machine interfaces, too small animals, such as mice, the blood vessels are too fine electrode cables. Although the sheep&#39;s blood vessels are thinner than humans, they are relatively thicker and the price is cheap. Basic movements can be distinguished Come out; after the test is successful, then test the monkey, let the monkey&#39;s initiative to control the robotic arm to grab food, because monkeys are a species similar to human beings. There is no problem in it. . The overall process is more tortuous. It is not a problem to find the partners and venues such as the hospital and the laboratory, because everyone knows that this is a very new study. Later, there are good papers, and it is good to get projects. There are also certain market prospects. The difficulty is that during the epidemic period, many engineers and students are often closed and often controlled. They need to think of various methods to coordinate personnel. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot; in January this year, Synchron in the United States announced it. The clinical trial of the &quot;vascular intervention&quot; brain machine interface successfully allowed four paralyzed subjects to control external equipment and completed the operation of sending text messages, personal financial management, and online shopping. How to understand that some media tell your research as &quot;the new paradigm of the third brain interface&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; It is recommended not to interpret it without conmics. This &quot;pioneering&quot; and &quot;the world&#39;s first case&quot; must be seen together. When making sheep test, it actually refers to the new paradigm of the third brain interface in China, because no one has done related research in China; the world&#39;s first case is that I am the first in the world to do it on the monkey species. People with such experiments. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the test was successful, it brought you to you What are the influence? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In terms of mentality, there is no impact, I see very flat. According to our plan, this experiment will immediately enter the clinical stage, that is, to test on people, but the ethical review phase of the hospital is currently in the hospital. But I did receive some volunteer emails. I was impressed. A lady was lying on the ICU, who hoped that her husband would participate in the clinical trial of the brain interface; and a grandson to save his grandma, the child must be a volunteer; there is a blind man, and there are blind people I want to restore me ... These faith are very touching, but our test ethics have not yet been recruited. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Some scholars believe that &quot;the development of brain machine interfaces It is currently in the bottleneck period, and the research of new principles and new technologies to drive related fields into the next rapid development period. &quot;What do you think? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The current research on brain machine interface technology is indeed in a bottleneck period. Many problems about the existence of brain machine interfaces are now. Global issues are not unique to China. There are too many players, whether it is non -invasive or invasive track, if you can make achievements long ago, there are too many smart people, and there are many money capitalists. At present, everyone is in a relatively stagnant state. To some extent, there is a problem with this road. It is recommended that you consider changing the track. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I am not optimistic about the invasion or non -invasive type, because I have done it, and there are many companies or institutions in China. Have done. In China, the focus of the industry is still non -invasive. Everyone is crowded on this track and has to traffic jams. But I do n’t follow any industry, and I am currently focusing on the brain interface technology of vascular intervention. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; I hope more people can do research at ease. , Stkaiti; &quot;>; Many people currently focus on the industrialization of rehabilitation medical brain interfaces. Why? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; Patients in this field are large and the number of patients is large. Exercise, so the market potential is relatively large. In addition, it is not difficult to technology, and some low -threshold products are better. As long as companies can integrate and get corresponding certification licenses, companies can quickly realize. In the future, if the price of products drops again, such as a product of 100,000 yuan becomes 20,000, the demand will be higher. There are two main chains in rehabilitation medical care, one innovative chain and one are the industrial chain. The industrial chain is to low -end high -end technology into product sinking. After sinking, more people can be used. After more people, there are more data in scientific research. There are more data. After the data, it will be fed back to the innovation chain to form better technology and better products. What I currently build is such a dual -chain cycle platform. So I did not worry about making specific products, but calmed down to make the electrode. After the electrode automation was completed, it could serve many products. My entrepreneurship is a relatively stupid situation, which is equivalent to holding a golden rice bowl for meals. My positioning for myself is not to do specific, low -end, and repetitive things, but to make the enterprise a platform and the core system for rehabilitation medical care for brain machine interfaces. In the future, this platform will also be open. , Let more people, enterprises, and institutions do things together on this platform. As long as they don&#39;t flicker me, they are welcome to think of officers. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; At present, the overall ecology of China&#39;s brain interface industrialization What is it? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I think the concept of brain -machine interface is overheating at this stage, and some irresponsible media use gimmicks to steal with gimmicks for the eyeballs. Change concept. For example, the flashing picture is actually a visual -induced brain -electrical signal, which is a conditional response. It is described as &quot;ideas&quot; control in media reports. It seems to be fantasy, but it is actually very simple. As far as the brain -machine interface company is concerned, there are not many people who can really bear loneliness to do underlying research and development, because the underlying research and development is too burnt, and the cash return cannot be seen in the short term. I sincerely hope that more people in the industry will be willing to do a good job in basic research. There is no blindly investing in investors. Because everyone has no money, it may be because there are a lot of concepts of speculation, so there are not many people who are really patient with the growth of innovative enterprises. I don&#39;t want to accept their investment in such investors. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In your opinion, the domestic brain machine interface corresponds What is the problem that needs to be solved urgently? What kind of talents are the most scarce? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I think the future ideal brain -machine interface product should be achieved through vascular intervention. In order to achieve this goal, it is urgent to achieve this goal. To solve the stability of the electrode, after the stability is guaranteed, it will find ways to achieve automated production to reduce the cost of the product. From the professional field involved in talents, more cross -domain, compound talents are needed. For example, at least two or more fields in the fields of materials, processing, machinery, circuits, medicine and other fields. The most important thing is that these people can calm down and do things. They will not go to this house today. To make money there tomorrow, people who have no feelings are not good. Under this premise, there must be a good understanding, independent thinking and exploration. Both are important. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In addition to brain interface, you have other research Simultaneously? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Duan Feng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; We are currently progressing at the same time as the artificial hibernation of smart aircraft and rats that can take off vertically. In the future, we hope that the experiment of artificial hibernation can be combined with the interventional brain machine interface to affect the special stimulus signal, through the electrode stimulation in the vascular, to affect the whole brain, or to transform the brain in this way to make people sleep. In the future, this technology can be used in the future. Apply in some medical treatment fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[风波过后，脱口秀行业复苏在望？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261442]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 11:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;h4 data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-normal: normal; font-variant -east-asian: normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-spie: normal; font-family: -apple-syster-font, blinkmacsyStyStmFont, &amp; quot; helvetica Next &amp;. quot ;, pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ; &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; backgrou ND-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; Text -rign: center; &quot;>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span data-style =&quot; color: rgb (34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , &amp; quot; wenquanyi micro hei &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server-spacing: normal; background-color: RGB (255, 2 2 55, 255); font-size: 18px; &quot;>; Open Mai performance The sharp reduction &amp; nbsp; the actor&#39;s seeking another way &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -ple-systerm-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot ;, &amp; &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; Microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; backgrous-money: rgbb (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In May this year, the talk show industry has gone through a series of rectification. Among all cities, the most affected one is Shanghai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; People familiar with the matter revealed to reporters that since the inspection operation in May The Huangpu District Cultural Tourism Department, where most of the talk show club is located, has strengthened the supervision of the performance content. The spot checks on performances every week are also more rigorous. The actors must perform strictly in accordance with the content of the approval. If the performance of the performance is inconsistent with the content of the approval, the performance agency will be fined 50,000 to 100,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; This has caused two changes in Shanghai talk show. First, the actor&#39;s individual special session or the main show shows that this kind of performance has higher requirements for content integrity, and it is difficult for actors to delete the paragraphs. Second, most clubs will no longer hold &quot;open wheat&quot; performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>;&quot; Open wheat &quot;is a special practice for new actors and old actors. Actors trial to talk about a new paragraph and open a talk show. Due to the unstable quality of the performance, most of the clubs have low open wheat fares, such as 19 yuan and 39 yuan. The actor said that open wheat is not paid. The main purpose is to polish content and practice technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;ban>; The actor submits the manuscript in advance to the institution, and then sign up within one to two days before the performance according to his actual situation. Due to factors such as actors&#39; personal creative habits and time, the content of open wheat performances and lineups have certain uncontrollable. Before the stage came to power, the situation where the actor temporarily modified and adjusted the new paragraph or had a sudden situation that could not be on stage, and the situation of other actors replaced was more common. Therefore, in the current more cautious environment, most of the talk show clubs in Shanghai no longer hold such form of talk show performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; Shanghai Open Mai performances have decreased sharply, resulting Opportunities, the old actors cannot update the creative content. Some full -time actors will choose to go to the new section of the open wheat test in other cities, and Hangzhou has become their first choice. &quot;Thank you Haihan&quot;, the head of the Jiusan Talk Show Club, told reporters that four or five signing actors chose to develop in Hangzhou. At present, there are at least 10 talk show clubs in Hangzhou. But this does not mean that actors can make money in Hangzhou, but they are even more &quot;rolled&quot; in Hangzhou. &quot;Everyone is willing to go to Hangzhou, more because (to be on), it is difficult to make performance fees, because the market volume is not so large now, it will cause the supply to be greater.&quot; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/jylbt3xhsauv1vibyn4mstswo7doqzouyqqsjgro.jpg&quot; width = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;720 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/jylbt3xhsauv1vibyn4mstswo7doqzouyqqsjgro.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259815 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p s Tyle = &quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center; &quot;data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal-spacing: 0 .544px; White-Space : normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Hiragino Sanss Gb &amp; quot; &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; 贰 Three-three talk show the principal&quot; Thank you Haihan &quot; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; Text-Align: &quot;>; &lt;SPAN>; &lt;strong >; &lt;span data -Style = &quot;COLOR: RGB (34, 34, 34); Font-Family: &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , &amp; quot; wenquanyi micro hei &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot; , Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: normal; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);&quot;>;从增量到存量&amp;nbsp;市场的下行与向上&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-s PACE: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot; &amp; quot; B &amp; QUOT, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei UI &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, SANS -Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;SPAN>; Many talk show practitioners mention In fact, as early as the public opinion storm in May this year, the market for talk shows has quietly settled. The head of a Shanghai talk show club told reporters that the current box office level of its club back has returned to 2017 and 2018. The number of performers is reduced to about 1/3 of each week. Step. In this case, it seems not only because of the industry earthquake half a year ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; 贰 贰 Three subjects&quot; Thank you Haihan &quot;told reporters In the past two years, the club&#39;s box office has not risen, so it has begun to expand its business to second- and third -tier cities such as Nanjing and Fuzhou. &quot;The volume of the entire (market) of the entire Shanghai has reached the limit. If you want to increase the performance, it is either to expand the city or increase the unit price. Price), can only expand cities. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pin gfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ; &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Y: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; He mentioned At present, the number of performances in the club has not changed much, but the rate of seats has been significantly reduced. &quot;The upper seat rate can reach 60 % even if it is relatively high. It is no problem to sit at about 300 people in our theater, but now it is about 100 people. It may reach 200 people. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pin gfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ; &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Y: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Comparison Below, the box office of the 俱 Three Three Clubs in Fuzhou is relatively stable: &quot;Because the competition is not so large, there are two local (club).&quot; Qiao Hongjun told reporters &quot; For the city, they are not as many forms of entertainment as Shanghai and Beijing. The talk show is relatively fresh to over there. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline : 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-ASIAN: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: Normal;-Apple-System-FONT , BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot; &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot; microsoft yah ei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; In the strong observation of the talk show actor, the golden period of the talk show market began in 2019:&quot; After the talk show variety show was broadcast, The talk show takes off online. &quot;In 2020, during the prevention and control of the new crown epidemic, all the performance industries were affected, and the talk show with a relatively small volume&quot; entered &quot;, seizing the share of other types of performance markets, plus the talk show variety show show The phenomenon -level explosion has helped the rapid growth of the offline performance. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/27/6voahmxiiiu9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 797 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.cms/med IAS/IMAGE/23/11/27 /6voahmxiui9rwaimcfxtNauyhgcsuwgkg2d9nmx.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259814 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; in: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant -NUMERIC: NORMAL; FONT-VARIANT-EAST-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-SPACE: NORMAL; FONT-FAMILY:-!! t, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; pingfang Sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Talking Show Actor strong. &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font- Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quotica N EUE &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans Gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; 1; 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In 2022, with the saturation of the market and the consumption of resources, the slump of talk show performance has begun to appear, and the industry has begun to usher in the bottleneck period. Hercules wrote in Xiaohongshu: &quot;Every year online program broadcasts, offline performance box office will have a significant rise, but this phenomenon is gone in 2022. It has not improved. It is not that the online program is not helpful for the box office. In fact, there are also, but at this time (talk show performance) The natural traffic of the box office is declining. The power is hedged. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-eleian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; Laughing Comedy Manager Car In an interview with reporters, Hong Jun said that the current talk show market has almost no increase, and everyone is &quot;curling.&quot; Some clubs may start a &quot;price war&quot;, &quot;some brand prices have begun to explore 50, or even lower.&quot; But on the other hand, he still believes that &quot;this industry is upward&quot;, because &quot;everyone is also rolling quality, especially now more popular performances. The quality of the performance is very high. The tide is back, and everyone starts to fight the real knife. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; FONT-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -apple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; The talk show actor also wrote in his little red book:&quot; In the future, the actor can no longer rely on the 15 -minute commercial performance paragraph. To a certain extent, this is a good thing. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style =&quot; margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; : normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-space: normal; font-family: -ple-systerm-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot ;, &amp; &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; Microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-server: 27.2px; widows: 1; backgrous-money: rgbb (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; During the rapid growth of the industry, a large number of clubs and performers who only wanted to make fast money, eat dividends but did not pay attention to content, and saved a few actors to sell tickets to sell tickets. After seeing the online program, I didn&#39;t know the comedy itself. But in the cold environment today, with the withdrawal of this part of the people, after the industry experienced shuffling, it slowly entered a precipitation period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A number of club the principals said in an interview with reporters. Because the overall box office is not good, they are more willing to leave the performance opportunities to actors with better content and stronger ticket ability. &quot;There may be a commercial performance opportunity when a actor&#39;s paragraph can reach thirty or forty. Now if you are less than sixty or seventy, your performance will be very small. Many people can no longer accept the performance. In the past two years, everyone At the wind, there will be no survival of the fittest. Now it is really difficult, but I think this is a way to go by a single (comedy). &quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; Text-Align: &quot;>; &lt;SPAN>; &lt;strong >; &lt;span data -Style = &quot;COLOR: RGB (34, 34, 34); Font-Family: &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , &amp; quot; wenquanyi micro hei &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; helvetica neue &amp; quot; , Arial, Sans-Serif; Letter-Spacing: normal; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); &quot;>; Where is the future? The necessary online traffic and healthy industry ecology &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font -Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; quot ;, pingfang sc &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; hiragino Sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot;, arial, sans-service: 27.2px; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible ; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; I didn&#39;t take off six this year, but I once dreamed of myself, and the result was not very good. &quot;On November 3, Zhou Qimo, who had won the championship of a variety show of a part of the stall, posted such a Weibo. He imagined a period of his own experience of participating in the show and then being eliminated, and finally summarized: &quot;The root of the talk show is still offline.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , sans-server; line-height: 27.2px; widows: 1; background-color: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; absent from online shows, completely returned to the next offline program. Is the talk show better? In the visits of reporters, almost every practitioner affirmed a point of view: the traffic of online programs is still necessary for the talk show industry, although online programs and offline performances are very different in creative creation. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; Che Hongjun mentioned in an interview,&quot; The form of the form will be very internal consumption of actors. The 5 -minute volume is too small, and you need to rejoice with the audience quickly. The topic will be very limited. Traffic to help break the circle, because with the increasingly rich form of offline performances and entertainment, the art of talk show is facing more intense competition. &quot;Our competitors are not compete with talk shows. Our competitors are all popular entertainment methods: watching movies, KTV, short videos ... Everything is your competitors.&quot; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p Data -Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; Font-Variant-Numeric: Normal; Font-Variant-East-Asian: Normal; Letter-Spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: normal; Fon T-Family: -padle- System-font, blinkmacsyStytemfont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; hiragino sans gb &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microS OFT YAHEI UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px ; widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>;&quot; still requires the promotion of online traffic. &quot; Also agree with this view. Online programs can make the offline market do not drop too fast. If there is no traffic to promote it, it will be more bleak in the offline performance market of talk show. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p data-style = &quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white-spie: n Oremal; FONT -Family:-Apple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica NEUE &amp; Quot;, &amp; Quot; Pingfang sc &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei UI &amp; Quot ;, &amp; Quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot;, Arial, Sans-Serif; LINE-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;span>; In fact, many clubs and actors are trying to create online IP. The &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; club, initiated and established by Fudan University&#39;s &quot;Dankou Comedy Society&quot;, made its own variety show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot; and was broadcast on station B in October; many clubs insist on making podcast programs to perform product publicity And maintain the stickiness of fans, such as &quot;No jokes&quot; of owl comedy, &quot;Hey Talk&quot; of the comedy box country, and &quot;Three words&quot; of Ji San San; more actors are trying to use self -media to create personal IPs and help Offline tickets. But most people have not been able to achieve stable commercial conversion online. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32MZOTGMH9SPBSPBSPBSNOPC5DP.jpg&quot; Border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1066 &quot;height =&quot; 1442 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/no32mzotgmh9sap3x4dspbsouuP.jpg &quot;Data-key = &quot;259817&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Smile Comedy&quot; Club self -made Variety Show &quot;Dankou Comedy Comedy&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 606 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/qcmadcyt2b6lehhinnxjclb8fjsvtwq1eg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259813 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Comedy Union Box Country&quot; actor Offline performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; From the perspective of the industry ecology, the domestic talk show The industry has risen and developed with the popularization and development of related variety shows such as &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show&quot;, &quot;Tucao Conference&quot;, and &quot;talk show conference&quot;. When a industry system, the rising channel of the practitioners, the deep binding of a company, a program, there will inevitably be a great risk -the fact has also proved this. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6cax5hxjemyqruueb.jpg&quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1620 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/aqfcdtjrki4imcojvi6caxm5hxjemyqrtwcuueb.jpg &quot;data-key = &quot;259816&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot; Data-Style = &quot;Margin: 16px; Outline: 0px; FONT-VARIANT-NUMeric: Normal; FONT-Variant-ASIAN: Normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; White-Space: Normal; Font-Family: -pple-System-Font, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot; Pingfang SC &amp; Quot ; &amp; quot; Hiragino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; Microsoft Yahei &amp; Quot; ARial, Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); Visibility: Visible; &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; >; &lt;span>; &quot;Tonight Tonight Talk Show 》. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-style=&quot;margin: 16px; outline: 0px; font-variant-numeric: normal; font-variant-east-asian: normal; letter-spacing: 0.544px; white- Space: Normal; FONT-FAMILY: -pple-System-FONT, BlinkmacSystemFont, &amp; Quot; Helvetica Neue &amp; Quot ;, &amp; quot; pingfang sc &amp; quot; hirag; ino sans gb &amp; quot ;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei ui &amp; quot;, &amp; quot; microsoft yahei &amp; quot; , Sans-Serif; Line-Height: 27.2px; Widows: 1; Background-COLOR: RGB (255, 255, 255); VISIBILITY: Visible; &quot;>; &lt;Span>; A talk show actor said in an interview with reporters, Compared to the emergence of the next explosive program, she hopes that the industry can usher in a healthy ecology: &quot;Different companies can bloom all flowers, have mutual competition, and cooperate with each other. Either actors who have a hand or program (online IP), just like other industries. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more to get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:urange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;&quot; &quot; https://feedx.run &quot;style =&quot; color: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武汉市卫健委：暂停武汉普仁医院出生医学证明签发资格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261446]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 11:13:23 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 28, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee of Hubei Province issued a notice, which is reflected in Wuhan Pure Hospital reflected by netizens. In the case of surrogacy and Wuhan Ruibo Xiang Judicial Appraisal, the Wuhan Health and Health Commission, in conjunction with the public security and judicial departments, and the appraisal agencies, the Wuhan Municipal Health and Health Committee conducted investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the qualifications for issuance of medical certification in Wuhan Puren Hospital have been suspended to conduct a special inspection of the hospital&#39;s maternity services and the application of birth medical certificates. The Wuhan Ruiboxiang Forensic Appraisal Institute has been instructed to stop its forensic appraisal business and accept investigation and handling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Next, the Wuhan Health and Health Committee will be held accountable seriously in accordance with laws and regulations in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在巴黎十年被抢近50次：移民导致社会治安恶化，法国社会治理失败]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261430]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recent Second-rate. Why bring a decimal number? Because she was robbed three times, she took it back, so it was only half a time, which means that it was actually 49 times. It&#39;s amazing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Relatives and friends in the diplomatic mouth, studied and worked in Paris in the mid -1990s. After retiring, I re -swimming in Europe. I feel that in 30 years, the changes in France can be regarded as people and not: Paris&#39;s urban appearance and infrastructure have not changed much. However, the composition of residents has changed a lot, and the social atmosphere and cultural customs are very different from 30 years ago. The personal feelings of relatives and friends and women&#39;s Internet celebrities are quite different: As immigration increases, France&#39;s law and order worsen significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;移民犯罪率高企的原因：法国有很多来自非洲的移民，由于宗教信仰、文化传统、风俗习惯不同，这些移民及其后代在教育方面的劣势，使其社会地位和经济地位均处于较低层级。渴望欧洲那种富裕的物质生活，但在经济方面却难以支持，当然会导致违法犯罪行为增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大量涌入法国的移民、非法移民，算“殖民主义”的反向后遗症，可以说法国正在被反向殖民。在17-20世纪初期，法国在非洲占领了大量殖民地，成为仅次于英国的世界第二大殖民帝国。而两次世界大战，使法兰西人口损失巨大，为弥补兵源不足，法国从殖民地法属非洲招募了数十万当地青年，参加法军、对德作战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争结束后，大量殖民地士兵留在法国，成为早期移民。法国电影《光荣岁月》（Indigènes）有着生动描述，很多黑人士兵问：我们为法兰西而战，为什么不能留在这里？问得法国政府和民众无言以对。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过这些早期移民，他们在非洲的亲友们得知了法国的发达与富有，大批后续移民、非法移民源源不断涌入。官方数据：目前在法黑人800多万，考虑到非法移民，实际数量可能达1000万，占法国6600万总人口的15%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人口结构变化，大大改变了法国传统的宗教信仰、文化理念、生活习俗，激化了意识形态冲突，带来犯罪率升高、社会动荡、族群与阶层双双对立。街头示威抗议、打砸抢烧，成为持续十几年不断的家常便饭，堪称巴黎一道奇妙风景线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;动荡的社会环境，不但影响了法国经济发展，而且也影响到每一位在巴黎生活者的人身及财产安全。在这种乱哄哄的环境里，丢个钱包、手机稀松平常，而且这么高的犯罪率，警察根本查不胜查、普通居民防不胜防。万般无奈之下，他们采取的办法是抬高立案门槛：把抢劫之类严重罪行轻罪化，把轻罪视为违法，而对违法干脆就尽量不管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国也学了这一套，2014年加州通过法案，偷窃1000美元以下一律视为轻罪，可通过社区服务抵罪。用这种办法避免警匪冲突、减少警察与黑人的矛盾。这套法律理念和司法实践，催生了欧洲和美国的“0元购”运动：大群人（以移民为主）一齐冲进商店，拿了东西就跑，店家无力阻止，警察不愿管。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在治安问题之外，还有个看似不相干的生活细节变化：法式面包。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亲友早年留法期间，对法式餐饮印象深刻。尤其对法式面包赞赏有加：在法兰西，面包不仅是饮食，更是文化。为做出香松可口的面包，法国面包师从和面、配料，到发酵、烘烤都非常讲究、精益求精，每每凌晨开工，以保证随着太阳升起，香喷喷、热烘烘的法式面包出炉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠乙类乙管后他再游巴黎时，惊讶地发现：法国不仅在社会和治安层面上物是人非，连法国面包都变得与30年前不同了，干硬、疲沓、口感不佳，掉渣严重……后来才得知，很多普通面包师都是缺乏法国文化和烹调传统的新移民，对他们而言，面包不再是国家荣耀、文化传承、悠久习俗和精致生活品味，而仅仅是份工作，没有感情，也不会投入太多精力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位喜欢旅游的亲友说：现在反而是东南亚的老挝和越南等前法国殖民地，法式面包做得比巴黎稍正宗些。那里还有较严格的劳动纪律，对员工有一定要求，还遵循着传统的法式面包烘烤技艺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与之对应的是：法国人每年150天休息日（美国多数州每年为116.5天），每年平均工作1490小时（美国人为1791小时）。大概是因为新移民太多了，基层工作尽可能由移民来干，收入较高的法国原住民，日子过得越来越轻松、越来越不愿意上班，面包师这种曾经有相当社会地位的职业，也懒得去干了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就好比：一家已经在走下坡路的企业，不是进行新的科技与生产力革新、力图扭转颓势，而是削减工时、提升薪资、弱化考绩、放弃管理……后果会怎样? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国的“传统丢失、文化退潮”问题，既不止于社会治安，也不止于餐饮。曾令法国人引以为傲的，也确曾经做到世界巅峰水平的文化和艺术，亦面临着同样的危机。曾经的法国影帝德帕迪约纠结了一帮法国演艺界人士，大骂好莱坞搞文化侵略，还焚烧了美国国旗泄愤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，好莱坞既没有通过武力强迫，也没有通过不平等条约对法国进行“文化侵略”，而是人们（包括法国人）不愿再消费法国电影、戏剧、游戏。法国人真应该自省下：自己在思想观念、意识形态、文化理念、艺术创作，以及国际政治、经贸关系、社会治理，甚至烤制面包……各个方面都出问题，究竟是怎么回事？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;移民所带来的社会治安恶化，体现了法国政府的社会治理失败。而移民问题所带来的文化冲击、意识形态碰撞，则体现出更深层次隐患。 French social governance failure and ebb to ebb. The internal cause is that the spiritual power of the contemporary French is dissipated, the traditional values ​​are abandoned, and the national culture is lost.法国人慵懒、闲散、快乐地生活着，如同坐滑滑梯般惬意地印证着“从善如登，从恶如崩”的古语，这种生活状态值得深思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，也希望大家思考那位人到中年仍在全力奋斗的马斯克（Elon Musk）所言：我不想利用人性下坠的力量赚钱。亦如《Jupiter Ascending》对重力的解读：Up is hard，Down is easy(向上非常难，下坠很简单)。社会和个人的成功，都需要昂扬向上的精神内核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>