<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中小学流行“萝卜刀”惹争议：让孩子没有害人之心，比严防死守害人之物重要得多丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a children&#39;s toy has caused heated discussion in public opinion. According to media reports, almost all primary school students have a &quot;carrot knife&quot;, which is a colorful plastic imitation knife toy that uses its own gravity to slide the knife body. The &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; is available in different colors and sizes, with prices ranging from 5 yuan to 25 yuan. There are also different styles such as &quot;printed flash radish knife&quot; and &quot;luminous gravity radish knife&quot;, which have already sold &quot;400,000&quot; online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports said that some parents reported to the Chongqing Online Political Questioning Platform that primary and secondary school students brought &quot;carrot knives&quot; into school to play together, which posed safety risks. Some parents are worried that if their children imitate actions such as stabbing and poking, it will have a negative impact on their psychology. When interviewed, some experts and scholars said that the &quot;carrot knife&quot; has safety hazards and &quot;subconsciously inspires children to be violent and do the same thing with a real knife.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance, it seems that the carrot knife is a kind of &quot;knife&quot; just like its name, and there is a danger of cutting, scratching and stabbing children. If the carrot knife is really a sharp-edged tool that can easily hurt people, not to mention that minors should not possess it, it should also be classified as a controlled knife in the adult world. However, judging from the actual situation of this toy, I am afraid that its danger is not as serious as that reported by parents and experts. Words such as &quot;danger&quot;, &quot;warning&quot; and &quot;warning&quot; are also exaggerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, judging from the appearance and material of the carrot knife, its &quot;edge&quot; is an obtuse angle and it is also a plastic product. How much harm it can do to humans can only be achieved by piercing white paper and apples with a few pieces. The photos are not convincing, and pencils and ballpoint pens can also be used to pierce them. Are they also banned because they are dangerous? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the innate nature of human beings to play with objects in their hands. Even for common stationery such as rulers and ballpoint pens, children have developed recreational uses for turning pens and placing rulers. If we have to talk about the degree of danger, any of these commonly used stationery items, such as a 30-degree triangle, a thin steel ruler, and a sharp ballpoint pen tip, is probably much more dangerous than a carrot knife. Even long fingernails can scratch the skin. A book page can also cut your finger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if it is just to prevent the possible harm caused by such &quot;blunt plastic knives&quot;, it is obvious that measures such as &quot;playing under parental supervision&quot; and &quot;not allowing children to bring it to school&quot; should be adopted. is to exaggerate the power of a plastic blunt knife toy and devote a disproportionate amount of attention to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the rhetoric of “stimulating children’s violent tendencies” when interviewed by experts and scholars is also worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long years before the advent of the carrot knife, generations of minors would also imitate &quot;stabbing, poking, poking and other actions&quot; because this is something written in human genes. Human ancestors jumped from hunting activities to becoming the spiritual beings and then ruling the earth. It is the nature of every child to imitate and use weapons. A simple wooden sword or a delicate toy sword is almost everyone’s childhood memory. Who hasn&#39;t fantasized as a child about being a superhero, or more or less a general and a vigilante? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing is a way for children to understand the world. Role-playing and imitating martial arts movements are their irrepressible nature. Advertising slogans such as &quot;Show me my carrot knife and defeat the enemy with one strike&quot; In fact, there is no big problem. If children&#39;s behavior of imitating the use of weapons is denigrated as &quot;violent tendencies&quot;, this is definitely inconsistent with formal logic and goes against common sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between small plastic toys and real sharp controlled knives, the difference between simulated games and wounding with a knife, and even the difference between legal violence and illegal violence, children with a little ability to discern After receiving education, they can be easily distinguished. The statement of &quot;stimulating violent tendencies&quot; goes too far, and it also denies children&#39;s cognitive and discerning abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, from the perspective of healthy growth of minors, it is actually unrealistic to over-protect them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Minors will always encounter various risks in their growth process. This is not only the inevitable path of life, but also the price that cannot be avoided. Traffic rules cannot yet eliminate all traffic accidents, sports competitions cannot eliminate all injuries, and even adult society cannot eliminate all risks. On campus, stationery, tree branches, tables, chairs, and benches can all injure people. Should the campus be like a prison, free of sharp objects and hard walls, and tightly controlled? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, &quot;Don&#39;t underestimate children&quot; has long been a consensus in education. Neither parents nor schools should over-protect minors or completely deny their ability to self-manage. Minors will grow up one day, and it is impossible to keep them strictly guarded in a sterile environment and worry about every possible safety risk. The correct approach should be to guide them to correctly assess risks and teach them the ability to fight risks independently. Otherwise, there would not be such a famous saying in the Chinese world as “civilized in spirit, barbaric in body.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in the face of the popularity of &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; toys, the right thing for adults to do is to provide reasonable guidance and teach children correct values. It is much more important to prevent children from harming others than to strictly guard against harmful things. After all, if you have an evil intention, you can harm others and yourself with your bare hands; if you have the right views and knowledge, you can use sharp weapons to defend yourself and protect others. Not only does a small dull plastic knife pose no safety risks, it can actually become an &quot;experience package&quot; for children to view violence correctly and learn to face risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不在景区“人挤人”，批发市场成假期新选宝地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257768]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[车臣的王，可能快不行了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257966]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/Fepy81wVavQ3ougQ4gFwpSQzxZc5lolwHTrulIGm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Fepy81wVavQ3ougQ4gFwpSQzxZc5lolwHT rulIGm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chechen leader Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023 local time, current Chechen President Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Ramzan Kadyrow)&lt;/span>;&#39;s assistant released a video of Kadyrov walking with his family to refute Uzbekistan&#39;s previous statement that Kadyrov was &quot;seriously ill&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier that day, the &quot;Kyiv Independent&quot; quoted a spokesperson of the Security Service of Ukraine &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(SBU)&lt;/span>; Andrei Yusov said that Kadyrov was &quot;seriously ill&quot; and &quot;his illness has worsened, leading to such a serious condition.&quot; According to the report, the source pointed out that Kadyrov had &quot;fallen into a coma&quot; and &quot;is recovering. Waiting to be transferred from Chechnya to &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(possibly the United Arab Emirates)&lt;/span>; for treatment.&quot; Yusof also told the media, &quot;He &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Kadyrov)&lt;/span>; has been ill for a long time and has systemic health problems. His condition has been very poor in recent days. Serious.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Kadyrov is smiling broadly in the video, it can be clearly seen that his facial contour and figure have changed significantly, and he seems to be far fatter than before. Some outsiders have speculated This is the swelling caused by his long-term kidney disease. In short, despite his own personal experience, there is still a lot of speculation and controversy about his health issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kadyrov&#39;s health condition aroused doubts from the outside world in early 2023 - Kadyrov, who claims to be infinitely loyal to Putin and will hardly miss any major events of the Moscow authorities, suddenly disappeared without any notice. Putin was absent from Putin&#39;s annual State of the Union address. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Father&#39;s legacy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ramzan Kadyrov, the current president of the Chechen Republic, likes to call himself &quot;Putin&#39;s little soldier&quot; and is Putin&#39;s most loyal ally. People call him Putin&#39;s fighting dog. In addition to the administrative regions, the Russian Federation also has 24 autonomous republics &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (including the internationally unrecognized territory of Ukraine)&lt;/span>;, Kaiti It is the most special one among the 24 heads of autonomous republics at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes him special is not just his relationship with President Putin, but also that he is a social media influencer. Kadyrov said that while he admired Putin, he also tried to create the same tough guy image as Putin. Therefore, he posted videos and photos of himself firing machine guns and taming tigers on social media, as well as his high-end and luxurious daily life. Kadyrov is not only eye-catching, he is also a person who cannot be criticized casually in the Russian Federation - the leaders of the other 23 autonomous republics obviously do not have this treatment. Any Russian media or individual criticizes him in public, even if he is not there In Chechnya, people will also be asked to be cautious in their words and deeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This unique status comes from his father Akhmad Kadyrov &lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed Kadyrov, the former President of the Republic of Chechnya, his presidential term ended in seven months - he was killed by a bomb in an assassination attempt in May 2004 at the age of 52 years old. Ahmed was the central figure in the Kadyrov family&#39;s rise to become the rulers of the Chechen Republic, and his life was full of ups and downs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed was born into a poor family in Karaganda, Kazakhstan in 1951. At that time, all the Chechens were transferred from Chechnya to Central Asia by the Soviet government to break up their resistance. They are the descendants of this group of immigrants. Later, with the change of the Soviet policy towards Chechnya, the Chechens were able to return to their hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed worked in agriculture and construction during the Soviet era. In the 1980s, he entered the Islamic University of Uzbekistan to study religious studies, and then established the first modern Islamic religious schools in Chechnya, and later more He went to Oman and Jordan for further studies and became a famous religious scholar in Chechnya. In 1993, Dudayev, the leader of the Chechen separatists, declared the independence of Chechnya. Ahmed was a religious leader whom Dudayev relied heavily on. At that time, he also issued a famous declaration of jihad against Russia:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are 1 million Chechens and 150 million Russians. If each Chechen kills 150 Russians, we will win.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then the Chechen war broke out, and Ahmed not only called for war against Russia He launched a jihad and personally led a guerrilla force during the war. His youngest son, the current Chechen President Ramzan Kadyrov, also joined the guerrillas. He later claimed that he had successfully killed someone at the age of 19. One Russian soldier died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Russian army in the First Chechen War ended in failure and suffered heavy casualties, and was forced to make a humiliating retreat. After the war, Ahmed Kadyrov, who had become the chief mufti of Chechnya One of the main representatives of the negotiations with Russia, his guerrillas were also known as the Kadyrov faction due to their outstanding military exploits during the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is strange, however, is that Ahmed broke with the Chechen independence faction in 1999. In the same year, Putin became the president of Russia, and the second Chechen War broke out. Ahmed this time withdrew his last declaration of jihad and led his troops in an alliance with the Russian government to fight the Chechen separatists he had fought alongside. With his help, the Russian army won the second Chechen War, which became Putin&#39;s first military victory after coming to power. This success avenged its shame, and the popularity of the Putin government was unprecedentedly high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for why Ahmed defected to help Russia in the second Chechen War, the outside world generally believes that in addition to personal ambitions and desires, he also had to do with the rise of Wahhabi fundamentalists in Chechnya. Worry. As the supreme religious leader of Chechnya, he is quite resistant to the international jihad claimed by the Wahhabis. From an ideological perspective, he is still a Chechen nationalist. After experiencing the first Chechen war, Grozny, the capital of Chechnya, was not only reduced to ruins, but also suffered a large number of casualties among the local population, causing serious social problems and economic crisis. At this time, the fundamentalists among the Chechen independence faction chose to ally with bin Laden and his like during the rise of global terrorism in an attempt to expand their territory in Russia. This is obviously not something that the Chechen nation with a population of 1.5 million can accomplish. matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on national sentiments and personal safety considerations, Ahmed publicly accused extremists of using Chechnya as a base for terrorist attacks in early 1999, which was dangerous and full of conspiracies. This led him and previous The relationship between comrades quickly deteriorated to the point of tension. At this time, the Russian government extended an olive branch to him, and forming an alliance became a matter of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reciprocating the favor, after the second Chechen War, Putin gave Ahmed the throne of Chechen president until his death in an assassination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to determine whether it was Ahmed&#39;s defection to Moscow that prompted Putin to make up his mind to launch a second Chechen war, or whether Putin wanted to establish his prestige through a war after coming to power, or whether the two complemented each other. result. But looking at Ahmed&#39;s choice now, whether it is based on his personal interests or the interests of the Chechen nation, it is not a mistake. Even if he did not defect and the second Chechen War did not break out at the end of 1999, after the &quot;9·11&quot; incident in 2001, it would be difficult for Chechnya to survive independently under the banner of joint anti-terrorism between the United States and Russia. It may even cause a more serious humanitarian disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Prince&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As Putin’s biggest contributor in the Second Chechen War, Ahmed Kadyrov’s political legacy was successfully passed on to his younger son Ramzan Kadyrov. Derov succeeded, and the latter soon became the real &quot;king&quot; of Chechnya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a process for getting to the top. In November 2005, a year and a half after Ahmed was assassinated, the then Prime Minister of Chechnya Sergey Abramov was seriously injured in a car accident and resigned due to health reasons. The cause of his car accident has not yet been determined, and the possibility of assassination cannot be completely ruled out, because at that time, assassinations of Chechen military and political leaders were common, and Sergei was assassinated in 2004, so the truth may never be confirmed. In any case, the biggest beneficiary of this car accident was the then First Deputy Prime Minister Ramzan Kadyrov. He became acting Prime Minister of Chechnya on November 18, 2005. A year later, he was officially promoted from &quot;Prince&quot; as &quot;King&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ZvIZ8puCKbgy4aB6jOT5UdVh8YhdujEScHCwozQc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;746&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ZvIZ8puCKbgy4aB6jOT5UdVh8YhdujEScHCwozQc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 30, 2004, President of the Chechen Republic Akhmed Kadyrov (right) and his son Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan Kadyrov’s first task after taking power was to rebuild Grozny, the capital of Chechnya. He built the Akhmed Kadyrov Mosque in the center of Chechnya in the name of his father, also known as the Heart of Chechnya. It is the largest mosque in Russia and one of the largest in Europe; it has the most It can accommodate 10,000 people, has a magnificent dome, a towering minaret and hand-painted by Turkish craftsmen. These are the standards for large mosques built during the heyday of the Ottoman Empire. On October 16, 2008, the mosque was officially opened. Ramzan Kadyrov and Putin both attended the opening ceremony and appeared side by side in the news. In addition to the magnificent mosque, the palace-like presidential palace, highways, five-star hotels and casinos have risen from the ground. Now Grozny has become a modern city with many high-rise buildings. Its core business district is even compared with Moscow and St. Petersburg. No less impressive. Funding for these large-scale infrastructure projects comes from the support of the Russian Federation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to reward the loyalty of the Kadyrov family, under the personal care of President Putin, the Russian Federation invested US$18 billion in the Chechen Republic in 2010 alone, with an average per capita income of more than US$1,300. In contrast, the autonomous republic of Dagestan next door to Chechnya spent less than $1.6 billion in federal investment in 2010, but the country has a population of 2.2 million. Relying on financial support from Moscow, Ramzan was able to complete the reconstruction of Grozny as one of the core achievements of his internal rule. However, the heavy economic dependence on Russia has also led to a rather deformed economic structure in Chechnya. The local area lacks core industrial chains and the unemployment rate remains high. In 2010, it even reached an astonishing over 60%. It is obviously impossible to solve the problem by relying entirely on federal funds and large-scale construction projects. The core local issue is the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/alxQC5TrmUCcwFQIdOagoa4PBKvPULr8v5AI7jxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/alxQC5TrmUCcwFQIdOagoa4PBKvPULr8v5AI7jxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 25, 2022, the Chechen armed forces held a swearing-in meeting to prepare for their mission in Ukraine. Chechen leader Kadyrov (middle) takes a group photo with soldiers &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we must note is that La Mzan&#39;s greatest economic achievement in Chechnya is not that he built Grozny into another St. Petersburg through extensive construction, but that he successfully obtained economic autonomy from Moscow. In 2018, Ramzan Kadyrov announced that his government would take over 100% of the shares of Chechen State Petroleum Technology Company, allowing Chechens to develop, extract and sell crude oil on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, 1,100 oil wells and 2,000 land parcels owned by the Chechen State Petroleum Technology Company with a total area of ​​7,740 hectares were all controlled by the Russian state-owned oil giant Rosneft. Ramzan has been fighting for control of oil assets in Chechnya since at least 2015, the year he first proposed to Putin that the Chechen Oil Company be handed over to Chechnya. On the surface, Putin agreed to transfer the equity, but in fact he has been putting it on hold. The reason why Moscow adopts the procrastination strategy is not entirely due to economic considerations, but one of the main means of control over Chechnya for a long time is economic control. During the Soviet era, Moscow firmly controlled the extraction, transportation and sales of local oil. Local people could only engage in agriculture and handicrafts, and were almost unable to enter the oil industry. The result of this was that the local area had to rely on financial subsidies from the Soviet Union&#39;s central government, otherwise infrastructure and public spending would be almost impossible to carry out. During the first Chechen war, Chechen guerrillas obtained military expenses by stealing crude oil from Russian oil pipelines passing through Chechnya. The elites in Moscow certainly know the importance of controlling the oil industry in controlling Chechnya. Therefore, they are not only unwilling to hand over control, but also deliberately do not expand local oil production capacity. However, Ramzan successfully overcame the calculations of the oil oligarchs and economic elites by relying on his personal relationship with Putin. With Putin&#39;s personal intervention, Ramzan got what he wanted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As seen in the fight for control of oil, Ramzan Kadyrov clearly knows what he needs and how to get it from Moscow. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kadyrov&#39;s Chechnya&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chechen high school students are now required to read Akhmed Kadyrov&#39;s biography &quot;The Road Bathed in Light&quot;, according to Chechen state television &quot;, as &quot;supplementary material for the study of Russian history&quot;, the book introduces &quot;the political and spiritual legacy of Akhmad Kadyrov&quot;. Schools are required to organize regular essay and poster competitions featuring Kadyrov and his family. Teachers and school administrators are required to comment on social media posts by Kadyrov and his inner circle as part of their job evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the magnificent Kadyrov Mosque, there are more than 300 streets in the Chechen Republic named after Akhmed Kadyrov. In 2020, Ramzan Kadyrov ordered that images of American comic book superheroes be removed from Chechen children&#39;s centers and playgrounds and replaced with likenesses of his father and other &quot;real heroes&quot; in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan hopes that his father will become the only superhero in Chechnya, and he will become the first Internet celebrity in Chechnya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kadyrov family on the Internet shines brightly, and at the same time they are down-to-earth and full of true nature. Instagram has been Ramzan’s favorite platform for years, where he actively shares his outfits and lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan also opened a Telegram channel to share his carefully recorded videos and his views on the current situation. He even gained millions of followers by feuding with Elon Musk on Twitter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Run by his PR team, his father, Ahmed Kadyrov, became a loving father and hero who saved Chechnya and became a great martyr, revolutionary and Martyr Saint. Ramzan himself is a kind-hearted Chechen brother. Not only does he have an enviable luxurious and cool life, he is also a fan of President Putin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with Vesti-24 TV station in 2018, Ramzan Kadyrov stated that he was rebuilding Putin&#39;s Caucasus native cavalry division, or &quot;Barbarian Division&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very famous allusion to Tsarist Russia. The Caucasus Cavalry Division was affiliated to the Russian Imperial Army. It was established on August 23, 1914. It participated in World War I and was led by Russian Grand Duke Michael Alexander. Rovich conducts. The division earned the nickname &quot;The Barbarians&quot; for its lax discipline, but the unit was a fighting force, distinguished itself during World War I and was loyal to the Tsar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan&#39;s concept of &quot;barbarian divisions&quot; actually has a deeper meaning. Since Putin intends to incorporate Tsarist Russia into the orthodox national historical narrative, Ramzan&#39;s repeated mention of &quot;barbarian divisions&quot; is precisely to borrow from ancient times. Yu Jin showed his loyalty to Putin. In fact, Ramzan has been working hard to maintain an image of himself and the Chechen nation as brave and loyal. The security forces of the Ministry of Internal Affairs controlled by Ramzan not only collaborated with the Russian army in South Ossetia&#39;s war against Georgia in 2008, but also actively participated in the Syrian war. Chechen special forces have frequently participated in various international special forces competitions, and have won the Jordan King&#39;s Cup special competitions many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lzvpOxPRgyNW9F2JGK2lIcNC5q2C7Zx2VReO5K60.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lzvpOxPRgyNW9F2JGK2lIcNC5q2C7Zx2VReO5K60.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 13, 2023, in Moscow, Russian President Putin (left) met with Chechen leader Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to participating in Russia-related military operations, the international community also accused Ramzan of participating in the assassination or intimidation of Russian anti-government figures, but there is not enough evidence to prove this. Prove this. Since the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, Chechnya has sent tens of thousands of troops to directly participate. Although there is no evidence to prove that they played a key role in the war, and they are not even as good as the Wagner mercenary group that successfully captured a city, their posture is undoubtedly very important. in place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What further illustrates Ramzan’s attitude is that when Prigozhin led Wagner to march into Moscow in June 2023, local troops along the way were unable to intercept him. Only Ramzan Kadyrov’s men were the last to stop him. The elite &quot;Akhmat&quot; special forces positioned themselves on a bridge near the town of Kolomna, about 110 kilometers from Moscow, preparing to intercept the Wagner rebels, saying they were ready to fight to defend Vladimir Putin. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Loyal enough, and Ramzan clearly does not look like a threat to Putin&#39;s regime. Not only because of the small number of ethnic Chechens, but more importantly, within Moscow’s power circle, Kadyrov’s only political backer is Putin. If Putin loses his support, there is no guarantee that the next Chechen president’s surname will still be Kadyrov. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it seems that the probability that the future leader of Chechnya will be named Kadyrov is still very high, not to mention that members of the Kadyrov family almost control all important positions in the Chechen government. Like his son Akhmat Kadyrov who is less than 18 years old &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Akhmat Kadyrov)&lt;/span>; was also attacked in March 2023 received an interview with Russian President Vladimir Putin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant reports, this was an informal meeting. Akhmat, who has served as the chairman of the board of directors of Chechnya’s Children and Youth Organization, introduced to Putin the youth policies and activities of Chechnya. status quo. Putin congratulated Akhmat on his upcoming marriage and shared with Akhmat his memories of his relationship with his grandfather, Akhmat Kadyrov. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one knows what they said, but they may have talked about Putin meeting a weeping Ramzan in the Kremlin after Ahmed was assassinated in 2004. News reports at the time said it was also an informal meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[外星人遗体被发现？全世界有几百万人每天都寻找外星人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258006]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021854137506&quot; data-media=&quot; audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Podcast · Some Culture Alien remains have been found? Millions of people around the world are looking for aliens every day.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http:// 1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/4182cccb5576678021854137506/jeaAQMqXAAYA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud. com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/4182cccb5576678021854137506/jeaAQMqXAAYA.mp3&quot;>; Podcast·A bit of culture Alien remains discovered? Millions of people around the world are looking for aliens every day.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play This podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to BitCulture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, a Mexican journalist who has long studied UFOs showed two &quot;mummy bodies&quot; suspected of &quot;alien remains&quot; at a hearing in the Mexican Congress, trying to prove that extraterrestrial Life exists, but its authenticity has also been widely questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this issue, two anchors from our editorial department will talk about the topic of aliens, including the main modes of human beings’ current search for extraterrestrial civilizations, as well as the imagination of extraterrestrial civilizations in literary, film and television works, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excerpts from golden verses&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; At present, no country in the world has officially recognized or claimed that extraterrestrial civilization really exists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, regardless of whether extraterrestrial civilization exists or not, we have made great progress in the process of exploring it. Expanded our knowledge. This search will also make us think about the existence and significance of human beings in the universe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As humans explore space more and more, they will feel that they are actually quite ignorant, so Humanity also slowly emerged with some somewhat modest works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Youxiang Southern Weekend Culture Supplement Editor&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weng Rongrong, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:32 Mexico claims to have discovered the corpses of two aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:35 There was a previous record of using mummified human children to pass them off&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 08:38&amp;nbsp;No country officially claims that extraterrestrial civilization really exists&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 10:18&amp;nbsp;Two hundred years ago, humans began to use modern technology to search for aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:27 Searchlight mode: Humans turn on lights and send out light signals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 15:06&amp;nbsp;Broadcast mode: Millions of people around the world use radio signals to search for aliens every day&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ► 21:20 Letter writing mode: The spacecraft brought a record when traveling in space&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:59 Spend 6.3 billion yuan to send a letter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 28:15&amp;nbsp; Looking for alien images that will make us think about the existence and significance of human beings in the universe&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 29:43 Impressive images of aliens in literary and artistic works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 35:30&amp;nbsp;&quot;Travel to the Moon&quot; &quot;Reflects early humans&#39; imagination of aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37:27 Lao She&#39;s &quot;Cat City&quot; is a long science fiction novel&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 39:24 Theme exploration of science fiction works in different periods &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 46:57 Liu Cixin’s two science fiction works about aliens communicating with humans in literature and art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:08 The image of aliens has been evolving in human imagination&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;► 55:16 Southern University of Science and Technology has coursework on how to grow vegetables on alien planets&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080 ;&quot;>;Audio editing/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operation promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun and Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子被120公斤杠铃砸死，健身房内发生的意外谁来买单？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山东学生身高全国第一？黑龙江人挺直了腰板表示摇头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257651]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;The average height of high school students in Shandong is 1.8 meters&quot; has caused heated discussion. However, netizens in Shandong have posted When the tall man next to him came out, Heilongjiang netizens were not idle either. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the national height competition between boys and girls, the height of boys in Heilongjiang ranks first, while the height of girls ranks first in Shandong Province. With the development of economy and life As the level increases, the average heights of men and women are 174 cm and 161.4 cm respectively. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Height has always been a topic of public concern. What kind of height is best in the eyes of the opposite sex? According to Polish scientist Pokryka, the standard for a perfect woman is an average height of 1.74 meters, and the standard for a perfect man is an average height of no less than 1.82 meters, with leg length equal to the length of the upper body, and a ratio of 1:1 that makes a man Looks stronger. However, the so-called perfect body standard cannot be generalized. In the era of aesthetic diversity, health has a standard definition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what factors determine height? First of all, 70% of a person&#39;s final height depends on genetic factors, but in addition to genes, nutrition, exercise, environment, living habits, etc. all have a great impact on height. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this is only an ideal standard. In reality, there are still relatively few situations that can achieve this state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current aesthetic trend of society pursuing height, many people will have height anxiety and try unconventional remedies to increase their height through injections, medicines, and surgeries. However, these methods have certain risks. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; kindly reminds you how we should treat the height issue rationally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/16cf2dcb0158e649e618c3473a1cca4b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/16cf2dcb0158e649e618c3473a1cca4b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252072&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cac7600c61568750cf1f386f29749055.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cac7600c61568750cf1f386f29749055.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252073&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/6845665a65be5d8656acc2e82b9870f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/6845665a65be5d8656acc2e82b9870f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252074&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7499d3bd6e19e9fe5d1ed72624f40192.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7499d3bd6e19e9fe5d1ed72624f40192.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252075&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/49969dc59efdd5d5c0defbdff8c53615.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/49969dc59efdd5d5c0defbdff8c53615.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252076&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2522bcfd6ff43f2145542646209f877b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2522bcfd6ff43f2145542646209f877b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252077&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c6f26de596a834b79b4e9c493189113a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c6f26de596a834b79b4e9c493189113a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“身心灵导师”学霸猫从者如云：哪类人最容易被收割？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258010]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;New Weekly&quot; reported on the &quot;body, mind and soul mentor&quot; Xueba Mao, triggering an investigation into the so-called &quot; Controversies and discussions about &quot;Zero Limit Cleansing Method&quot; and spiritual practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuebamao taught his followers, such as &quot;People don&#39;t have to work hard, everything will go naturally and smoothly&quot;, &quot;Whatever you do should be easy, don&#39;t endure hardship, don&#39;t get entangled, follow your own preferences&quot;, smell Is it a little bit Lao-Zhuang and Buddhist? According to reports, the theory of &quot;Zero Limit Cleansing Method&quot; comes from &quot;At Zero&quot; written by American Xiu Lan in 2007. It is translated as &quot;Zero Limit: Hawaiian Therapy for Creating Health, Calm and Wealth&quot;, and the mantra is &quot;Sorry, Please forgive me, thank you, I love you.” Doesn’t it sound very positive? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, a group of young people who were inexperienced in the world joined Xueba Mao&#39;s &quot;body, mind and soul community&quot;. &quot;There are thousands of people, and more than 70% of them are women.&quot; Ordinary spiritual practices often teach people to control or let go of desires. Xuebamao does the opposite, allowing students or believers to buy without asking the price or looking at the labels. Debt does not matter. Xuebamao believes that in order to “clear away the fear of money, one must choose a method of flowing large amounts of money to open up one’s own energy.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people believe in it and use their savings to buy or borrow money to buy what they like, and buy various courses and consultations from Xuebamao. &quot;With the expansion of the community one after another, there has been a trend of debt consumption among students. Living in a large flat, driving a luxury car, going to Xinrongji for afternoon tea, and constantly opening credit cards...Xueba Mao Dai With one bracelet, everyone will go to the same store to buy the bracelet. Not only that, everyone&#39;s speaking style is becoming more and more similar.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is Xueba Mao? In 2015, Mao Mao, a top student who graduated from the sociology department of a certain university, tried to start a business; around 2017, she found &quot;body, mind and soul practice&quot;. In 2021, the price of courses began to increase, and Xuebamao changed its original simple style, and the community was renamed &quot;Xuebamao·Hogwarts Lady Branch&quot;. A student discovered that her course had experienced several rounds of price increases, from 199 yuan to 999 yuan in the first quarter, and the price increased to 9999 yuan in the third and fourth quarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This true story makes people feel a lot of emotions when reading it: First, the students believe in Xueba Mao’s spiritual practice theory and spend their own money to buy and buy in order to gain spiritual freedom. Xueba Mao Whose money does it cost me to buy flowers? In this real-person game, who is the real financial freedom and spiritual freedom? Secondly, spiritual cultivation is really a good business. As long as the seller makes people believe in his theory and himself, he can make the buyer &quot;use his body and his arms, and his arms and his fingers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, there is supply only when there is demand. The various spiritual schools on the market actually reflect the spiritual crisis, spiritual crisis and value crisis faced by some people in the modern social environment. To put it simply, it is because it is too short to enter modern society, and many people have suffered from many mental discomforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not to say that traditional societies do not have such crises, but that comparatively speaking, such crises are much less common in traditional societies. This is because traditional societies are basically in a state of scarcity, and people are busy working all day long to provide &quot;three meals a day&quot; for the whole family. In fact, &quot;three meals a day&quot; is just rhetoric here. Only in an era of abundant food can everyone live a healthy life. &quot;Three meals a day&quot; day. In this case, most people are mainly concerned about survival and have no leisure to pay attention to the so-called spiritual life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In modern society, everyone leaves the countryside where they are familiar and in their comfort zone and enters the city full of strangers. On the one hand, the income is much higher than that of their ancestors, and it is not a problem to have enough or even good food. Son, in addition to higher income, there is also more leisure. In fact, people cannot really let themselves be leisurely, so they will inevitably have spiritual thinking and pursuit. But on the other hand, natural blood communities such as families tend to disintegrate. Everyone in the city is atomized and scattered. We come into contact with many people every day at work, but how many people can we have close relationships with? Humans are social animals, which brings a lot of loneliness and insecurity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to get rid of it, some people will look for like-minded people online and offline. People with similar knowledge background or values ​​will come together, as well as common interests and hobbies such as fishing or playing games together. In short, we must &quot;talk with the same voice&quot; &quot;Response, seek each other with the same spirit&quot; to settle their own souls; some people throw themselves into the embrace of spiritual practice and the like. There are all kinds of methods, all of which are used by people to relieve or solve their spiritual atomism, loneliness and insecurity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From Chaoyang District Rinpoche to &quot;Master Wang Lin&quot; to various &quot;body, mind and spiritual teachers&quot;, the routines and profit models of these people are similar: I know that you are facing a spiritual crisis, a spiritual crisis and a crisis of values. , come on, lost lambs, children of lost souls, come to my arms and hand over your body and mind to me. I have the final and definite answer here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the so-called &quot;body-body-spiritual guru&quot; also went through a process of spiritual struggle and internal consumption to enlightenment. &quot;Human, too human&quot;. His personal experience increases the credibility of the narrative and the &quot;truth&quot; he preaches. Credibility. At a certain stage, everyone will be happy, the student will get illusory spiritual freedom, and the mentor will get real financial freedom. But ultimately, you may not be able to live with self-deception and lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each of us must understand: Only by doing meaningful work and living a meaningful life can we discover the meaning itself, establish our own strong core of values, be simple and strong, and have the courage to explore. , to face and fight, for yourself and your family. All this depends on yourself and your family who truly love you. If you can&#39;t buy it, what you buy will be fakes and narcotics. It should be noted that spiritual weakness is the greatest weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张艺谋——工作最happy，放假才emo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257908]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[编剧陈宇：把剧本写到张艺谋舒适区以外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, director Zhang Yimou’s first criminal police film &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; will be released nationwide . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This film is also the beginning of the cooperation between screenwriters Chen Yu and Zhang Yimou. The script was written by Chen Yu. He originally wanted to film it himself, but after writing it, he found that he could not handle such a complex subject matter, so he approached Zhang Yimou and hoped that he would film it. After reading the script, Zhang Yimou liked it very much and immediately pushed back other projects and concentrated on filming &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;. After filming &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, Zhang Yimou collaborated with Chen Yu in &quot;Amores&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot;. The first one to be released was &quot;Sniper&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of his collaboration with Zhang Yimou in three blockbusters, Chen Yu was able to be seen by the public. In addition to being a screenwriter, Chen Yu is a professor at Peking University School of Arts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lwgrSQHcXlLOKJUyA3RzPbtaSIGCxsudpDfm5aRc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lwgrSQHcXlLOKJUyA3RzPbtaSIGCxsudpDfm5aRc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252347&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Yu was interviewed by Southern Weekend in Beijing in late September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Jia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yu majored in history as an undergraduate, and applied for a postgraduate degree in the Directing Department of the Beijing Film Academy. He works at 8 o&#39;clock every day When I wake up, I go to the movie studio to make movies and take classes. &quot;Three solid years.&quot; After graduating with a master&#39;s degree, Chen Yu applied for the Central Academy of Drama, where he studied under the famous theater director Cao Qijing and studied for a doctorate in drama principles and drama aesthetics. He is a typical academic school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his graduate studies, Chen Yu, together with several classmates, had some pioneering explorations of films with the CCTV Movie Channel. At that time, the movie channel was exploring the possibility of making some movies that could be shown on TV. This kind of style has already existed in the West. &quot;Film-made for TV&quot; is the so-called &quot;television movie&quot;, but in China , a TV movie has not yet appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, Chen Yu served as a screenwriter and created a fantasy film &quot;8:35&quot;. This film became one of the most popular digital films on CCTV Movie Channel at that time, and also Therefore, it won the Lily Award for Outstanding Film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yu is also one of the earliest practitioners of Internet film and television. In 2009, he filmed China&#39;s first commercial micro-film, &quot;Always Online: Love·Online&quot;. In this short film created for Japan&#39;s Dentsu Advertising and China&#39;s Lenovo Group, Chen Yu is both a director and a screenwriter. He uses storytelling to incorporate product concepts into it. This short film is considered to be the Chinese online movie with the highest Internet click-through rate in 2008. It also won the international first-line advertising award - the British Crystal Award for Best Online Movie of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Chen Yu stayed away from the film industry. He plunged into various film and drama theories. In his own words, “In order to create his own methodology, he must &quot;The two things of film and drama are combined together.&quot; He spent about ten years &quot;thinking behind the wall&quot; and finally established a systematic methodology. After that, he felt that he could create. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is a genre film that combines a police film + a crime film. For a while, Chen Yu was interested in anti-corruption cases. He saw an official performing his duties in the news, with his resume attached; and later saw news of his dismissal. Chen Yu would imagine this person&#39;s life course in his mind: In which period did he have a problem? What kind of problems could have led to such an ending in his fate? &quot;I think the certain qualities of human nature reflected behind them are very thoughtful and interesting.&quot; Thinking about it from this perspective, Chen Yu wrote &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TB5fUcxCl2n1HoSurtzMVrzmIU08T6zkWWt9UaAz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1920&quot; height=&quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TB5fUcxCl2n1HoSurtzMVrzmIU08T6zkWWt9UaAz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Yu created the script &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; out of his concern for anti-corruption cases. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To sum up, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is about the alienation of people. People in a specific In the environment, in a specific period, in a specific location, he will become alienated over a long period of time. This is a tragedy in the ancient Greek sense, that is, people are watching inevitable collapse, and things are inevitably heading towards destruction.&quot; Chen Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Understanding the psychological activities of the audience when watching movies&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot; have obvious characteristics of genre films, but what about &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is also a genre film. It is not a single genre. I have been engaged in the research and creation of genre films. If you want to make a genre film, it doesn’t necessarily have to be one genre. For example, like &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, I blended two genres. One is the police and gangster genre, which is a messenger of justice such as a police officer or a detective. The truth of a matter, the thematic value behind it is the victory of justice over evil; another type is the crime type, which actually talks about a crime or how a crime occurs. &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; I tried to fuse these two genres. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, the value of understanding and researching genre films is to be able to accurately understand the audience’s psychological process when watching a movie, including whether they can Get enough emotional and psychological satisfaction. So once we adopt genre film theory as the cornerstone and method of creation, we actually default to several things: first, the most important value and meaning is obtained from the perspective of the story; second, you identify with the audience. collusion&quot;. For example, when we make a horror film, we agree on some premises in advance - my film is a horror film, and it may not be so reasonable from the perspective of life principles, but do you agree with the assumptions I gave you? If you accept this hypothesis, I will definitely give you the psychological satisfaction that horror movies get. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NZzdfPeAs03CqiLMUy9wuUvvM8uAmyDyYDkKrgTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NZzdfPeAs03CqiLMUy9wuUvvM8uAmyDyYDkKrgTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Screenwriter Chen Yu believes that the movie &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is a fusion of the two movie genres: police and crime. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are there many practical limitations in making crime films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He (the villain) must have a positive force to collide with him. It is not realistic to just write about how to commit crimes, because any Crime movies must be in a place where there is law and order, and he must be aware of his crime. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it takes place in a place without order or in a place with semi-order, it is another type of film. For example, in a place with semi-order, it is a western. Westerns are set in a place where there is a little bit of order. For example, the Americans built railroads to the west, and then there was a small town with a police chief. The police chief was not strong enough and was often crushed by evil forces and criminal forces. Pressure, the conflicts and stories that arise in this semi-rule of law place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For creators, another problem they will face is , dealing with the ups and downs of the plot and taking care of the characters, which one comes first for you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will change this question into structure and characters that are important to me. I feel like the plot is actually a way the structure unfolds. Of course, as an audience, what we see on the first level is the plot, but in fact the structure behind the plot is determined, so the structure and characters are very important starting points in our creation. Aristotle made a distinction: Which is more important, structure or characters? Aristotle himself thought that he would start from structure. I am a follower of Aristotle, and I feel that what he said is something I agree with, that is, I will start more from the structure, but in the end I will reach the same destination as the characters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You often mention &quot;hard-core narratives&quot;, For example, you said that Korean movies are a combination of three major elements - mature genres, directors&#39; strong styles and social issues. Are these three elements present in &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I’m working hard. &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is a standard genre format. It has its own characteristics in terms of storytelling, imagery, and narrative, and even has a certain authorial quality. Authorship actually does not conflict with genre. For example, Christopher Nolan is a very good Hollywood director. He also makes blockbusters and genre films, but he still has a strong authorial style. This is true not only in movies with a strong sense of form like &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; and &quot;Dunkirk&quot;, but also in standard Hollywood blockbusters like &quot;Interstellar&quot;. You will feel that it is completely different from Marvel&#39;s blockbusters. It has a clear storytelling method and character treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have talked about Chinese academic directors. This is not a manufactured concept, it is a real phenomenon. In your opinion, which academic directors are worthy of attention right now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will talk about some definitions of academic directors in my paper, but in fact we can broaden this concept a little bit, not necessarily He has to work in a university, because there are actually not that many people in this group, such as excellent directors like Director Cao Baoping and Director Xie Fei. To put it more broadly, an academic director is one who has strong self-awareness in film theory. The most prominent sign is that when he makes a film, he will place it in the history of film, the genre of film, and the status of film. There is a clear position in style, and he has a huge tree diagram in his mind. From the perspective of history, country, style, and form, he has the entire map. With this kind of consciousness in his mind, I think he can be Being called an academic director can also be equated with a scholar-type director to some extent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He corresponds to another concept, that is, the studio director. A studio-type director means I don’t have to worry about that. I grew up on the studio. Many people have never even attended a professional film school. They just followed the master step by step. This was the case in the previous film industry, including films like Hitch. Directors like Kirk also used to draw background panels and do art work in studios, including Yasujiro Ozu. I think these two groups of people have different creative methods, working methods and even concepts, and both are likely to produce excellent authors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which directors do you prefer and admire? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was in film school, I was most fascinated by Martin Scorsese. At that time, I was obsessed with audio-visual language and film forms. The forms of Martin Scorsese&#39;s early works were extremely wild and unconstrained, and they had their own style and characteristics, so my graduation thesis at that time was about Martin Scorsese&#39;s films. Research; For a long time after that, I was more fascinated by Hitchcock, who was a super master of telling stories; in recent years, I admired Orson Welles, whose &quot;Citizen Kane&quot; In the 1940s, narrative, profundity of thought, understanding of human social life, including politics, private life, and so many other things were perfectly put into one movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;My job is to say things outside your comfort zone&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is the beginning of your collaboration with director Zhang Yimou. How big of a span is there between the end of &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Soon. The order was to do &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; first. At that time, director Yimou and I met and we worked together. Later, the director said that Chen Yu was good, so we continued to work on it, and proposed the motion &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;. After the synopsis of &quot;River Red&quot; was written, &quot;Sniper&quot; was temporarily inserted. We finished &quot;Sniper&quot; first, shot it and released it, and then went back to expand the synopsis of &quot;River Red&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, during the cooperation, everyone may be familiar with each other and agree with each other&#39;s abilities and characteristics, so he said every day, &quot;We have a good script, and you have to hurry up. You have to work hard.&quot; In fact, I have been trying to keep up with him, but now I am not the only one who can&#39;t keep up, his pace is too fast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/oBeBMIn0wqFzyvd86WW2NgF8d4FE249Z4GtHmKpG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/oBeBMIn0wqFzyvd86WW2NgF8d4FE249Z4GtHmKpG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is the first police crime film directed by Zhang Yimou. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;With director Zhang Yimou’s pace, no one in the Chinese film industry can surpass him? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, he is the hardest-working person I have ever seen, not just in the film industry. The key is, it&#39;s not that he uses a strong will to force himself to work hard, but that he likes this thing. Doing this thing is happy, comfortable, resting and working for him. Sometimes I say we should go on vacation somewhere, let’s visit the country and abroad, and he says, “I won’t be happy there, it’s not a vacation for me.” It&#39;s basically impossible to leave him idle for more than a few days, so his (overall) tempo will be fast. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You and director Zhang Yimou’s narrative aesthetics or your impression of the film There must be differences in understanding. Will there be any disputes over this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, regarding my cooperation with him, I have a learner’s mentality. We learned movies by watching his movies, and we truly recognized his previous achievements from the bottom of our hearts, so in this state, I stole from him. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we have different opinions on how to handle some scenes. At this time, he also mentioned it and I also mentioned it, and everyone pulled the bellows back and forth, but generally in the end The time is almost up. I will write a whole article about why I am like this on this issue, listing several possibilities, the advantages and problems, and give them to the director together, and the director will make the final decision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I told him that my job is to give you the possibility to say more, to say things outside your comfort zone. He has a very large comfort zone, much larger than that of ordinary people, and he can do all kinds of things very smoothly. But what is my responsibility? I said I have to give you something different. Maybe what I mentioned is not necessarily the best choice in my opinion, or maybe your own decision is the best choice, but I have to list this possibility. , in the end you make the choice, this is the director’s responsibility. I also believe that he will make the most appropriate choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the actors are selected for a movie, you will focus on the actors. Any changes to the script? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, we can basically do this work for such mainstream movies or large industrial-level movies. , including &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; too. Director Zhang Yimou said, &quot;Before you act, you will follow the play, and when you are acting, the play will follow you.&quot; I think he said it very well. I used to be a director myself and made some small films. I tried my best to imagine the actor&#39;s state in my mind very accurately. Even after counting for three seconds and asking him to say this sentence, the actor would be at a loss. Now that I think about it, I have a problem. Performance is an organism, and you cannot turn a person into a robot. He should have his own thoughts, his own coherence, and his own rhythm and beat. At this point, I was impressed by the director Yimou. I learned a lot from him. He has many tricks on how to present a scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you change the lines on the spot? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If the script is still undergoing major changes by the time filming starts, it will not start filming, so basically it will be finalized when filming starts. More adjustments are the state of some performances, or the rhythm, or the changes in the tone of speaking. Sometimes there will be some small adjustments to the lines, but generally they won’t change much. This is also a kind of scientific nature of director Yimou’s work. We are similar in that we don’t believe in on-site or temporary inspiration. He even Intentionally reject such inspiration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the filming started in a week, and I suddenly had a very good idea about this scene. I said that this scene would make a big difference. As a creator, Everyone would be very excited, but Director Yimou was very calm and said that your idea is a good idea. If you proposed it three months ago, you would start adjusting it immediately. But now that the filming starts in a week, there is not enough time for digestion. I&#39;d rather keep this thing now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a lesson I learned that had a great impact on me. I think this comes from a long experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After &quot;Amores&quot;, &quot;Sniper&quot; and &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, Will there be a next installment in the &quot;Chen Zhang Series&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We are working on it, planning and writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This combination will become the only option for your creation ? Is there any movie of Chen Yu’s own? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think there will be. Of course, I particularly hope and am willing to continue my cooperation with Yimou, and I will try my best to follow in his footsteps. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“You don’t need to write a script”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Many movies in the past were adapted on the shoulders of literature, but now, the movies you make yourself, including the movies you collaborated with director Zhang Yimou, are all original scripts. Is this habit formed naturally? , or is it an option? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, I think the creation of movies, specifically the creation of texts, has nothing to do with literature. I prefer movies and Literature is two things. We can draw nutrition from literature, but this nutrition may not be unique to literature, such as understanding of society, understanding of people, understanding of human emotions, and understanding of multiple models of character relationships. These things In fact, it can also come from life. It’s just that literature is doing this effectively and has been doing it for a long time, and it is most convenient for us to obtain these things from it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I think the form of literature itself and the text of a film are two completely different things. Even today when I recruit graduate students, students often say that I have been a literature lover since I was a child. The writing is very good. In my case, when I say that your writing is good, it is not an advantage of writing a script, but it is even a disadvantage of writing a script. Because your writing is good, you will use it to cover up the deficiencies in characters, plots and actions. It seems that you have written in a flashy way. Those things are of no use to our movie. I have to pick them up and take a look. What is the dry stuff? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I say that writing a script does not require writing or rhetoric. My own script has no adjectives. It is all about people, actions, and lines. A 30-year-old person, what kind of clothes he is wearing, comes over and sits down. Say...that&#39;s it, without any literary description. If a student comes to me, for example, a man is sitting there eating noodles, showing a melancholy mood. Then I say that melancholic emotions should be deleted. What does depression feel like? You have to show me what he did. Words like melancholy are all literary thoughts, and what I want is visible and concrete expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We know that there are many models in the film industry that are very mature. Will it be replaced by ChatGPT and artificial intelligence one day? Is there anything in this that artificial intelligence cannot replace? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This question is also a question that everyone is thinking about recently. Will artificial intelligence replace some of the film industry after it comes out? My feeling is that it will, but the way it replaces is to replace it back from the terminal. In other words, things that are more technical and procedural, such as computer special effects and face-changing. Nowadays, AI is used to change faces, and calculations of computer special effects are gradually being mastered. I even think that in the next 5 to 10 years there may be some (smart) photography, where I say a few words and keywords, and the image is basically generated for you first, and then you can Make adjustments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I think going back to the earliest stage, the planning and production of the story, it is still very difficult to replace it. From a philosophical sense, the most basic things are difficult to produce by ChatGPT. It is impossible to create. It is just a patchwork and combination of existing information. As a creator, the greatest value of what you have to do is to bring this universe Take out something that has not been there before, and it has a specific meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once criticized Hollywood&#39;s high-concept movies, which are to create audio-visual spectacles of those movies. The Chinese market has indeed experienced a great change in recent years. Chinese audiences used to be very fond of this style, but now things have changed. Movies with classic narratives or themes that are more closely integrated with local elements have defeated the Hollywood model. Is this &quot;defeat&quot; due to a change in audience tastes, or is it that Chinese creators have really come up with something better? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Essentially, I think high-concept movies are generated by the thinking of the modern advertising industry. They use a specific element of the movie as a production Justification for a movie. For example, the earliest reason for making a movie is that the story is good, I enjoy watching the story, or the character is interesting. These are relatively classical psychological needs. But after high-concept movies, probably around the 1980s, the concept of blockbusters appeared, which was different. It was advertising thinking. For example, I made this movie not to tell a story, but to show clothes. I showed the clothes from a fashion perspective. This element is higher than the story and the characters. After watching my movie, you may I was not satisfied with the story, but I saw fashion and fashion in it. Gradually, high-concept movies have become. I have many reasons to make a movie, such as special effects and audio-visual shock. Even if the story and characters are a mess, it doesn&#39;t matter, as long as the special effects are good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Advertising thinking is my own summary of the essence of these high-concept movies. Is this wrong? Yes, but what I am more disgusted with is that it is only this, or it is not enterprising, the originality is getting lower and lower, and it is constantly repeated. For example, I don’t particularly appreciate Marvel movies, including a large number of sequel movies. They essentially pursue extreme safety, cannot take any risks, and stifle originality. The current mainstream Hollywood movies make me very worried and disappointed. This is not to say that in our Chinese market today, our domestic films have far surpassed them. In fact, on the one hand, domestic films are improving, and on the other hand, it is their own fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-concept movies were popular for a long time from the 1980s to the 21st century, but now they are slowly changing. The Chinese film market, including the international film market, has gradually returned to a recognition of the value of narrative. This It&#39;s a change that I&#39;m very happy to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[月亮山：风车、云海与斑斓霞光 | 眼睛在旅游③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在新疆与银河“合影”丨指尖华夏②]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Hami City, Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, the stars in the sky are like diamonds embedded in the sky, emitting bright light and beautiful. . There is an endless stream of tourists, looking up at the sky under the bright starry sky and &quot;taking photos&quot; with the Milky Way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YcLi6BQ8Ypk7wKXKxktOXo04HZu33y7I2RWP3yZb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YcLi6BQ8Ypk7wKXKxktOXo04HZu33y7I2RWP3yZb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Galaxy Arch Bridge&quot; photographed at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Tan Chufan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/ZcPekkA774vhEtQ2eBOEMtsFeExIcUT5KoiyrQhy.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/ZcPekkA774vhEtQ2eBOEMtsFeExIcUT5KoiyrQhy.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Symphony Lake under the starry sky in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/srgi0VASORkuAtMUbUGFHqUarPuLvqpqRiVijsOm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/srgi0VASORkuAtMUbUGFHqUarPuLvqpqRiVijsOm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang, a meteor streaked across the night sky . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Tan Chufan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/pyathfqzuFA77EIIQkryq4pZ5odDknFdHEVdO8o0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/pyathfqzuFA77EIIQkryq4pZ5odDknFdHEVdO8o0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Strange rock mountain under the starry sky photographed in Barkol, Hami, Xinjiang . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/26dYJCr7iDD9mZqvY3mpi0kO8zX677bhCdGTwdWt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/26dYJCr7iDD9mZqvY3mpi0kO8zX677bhCdGTwdWt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way and Yadan taken at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang landforms. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Junfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/eK5AanAgbbhFmSXMKswI2vQNFPz1qhcSAu56H7lB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/eK5AanAgbbhFmSXMKswI2vQNFPz1qhcSAu56H7lB.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way taken at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Kai/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/BqYwYhY910Je1ExFlUEqVXdjnDOBnawcpgdZ0tq4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/BqYwYhY910Je1ExFlUEqVXdjnDOBnawcpgdZ0tq4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/cN5zpB0eMamORlO38JnZ7Hx79n30VNkLTN3pOOfg.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/cN5zpB0eMamORlO38JnZ7Hx79n30VNkLTN3pOOfg.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251998&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way in Yiwu Populus Forest in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Bing/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/pOJfDMkc7TMFxFRmz7ZRIeVnkmRYVcYoDphi1iZf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/pOJfDMkc7TMFxFRmz7ZRIeVnkmRYVcYoDphi1iZf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/qJ3OKnSZUr80eRS41jHm78cvIU6cxZMSb9m3av8b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1144&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/qJ3OKnSZUr80eRS41jHm78cvIU6cxZMSb9m3av8b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251996&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Qiu Bi/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/wySoblf04gubuKiBZpjKnyMikvUdf4l3rFgvv5fD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/wySoblf04gubuKiBZpjKnyMikvUdf4l3rFgvv5fD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251995&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way taken at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Lichun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>