<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[无尽的纷争：雷颐的2023年读书小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261708]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Making reading and writing a career, of course I will not finish reading in 2023 Few books. If we could sum up this year&#39;s reading and thinking with one title, the most appropriate one would be the title of one of the books: &quot;Endless Conflict.&quot; Real-life conflicts and wars have triggered &quot;reading circles&quot; from the international to the domestic, or Talk about the huge disputes in the intellectual and ideological circles. I hope this kind of dispute will bring about more profound discussions and thoughts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Zhu Zheng: &quot;Shi Ling New Collection&quot;, Huacheng Publishing House, June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Mr. Zhu Zheng is a great editor, literary and historical figure who &quot;emerged&quot; after the reform and opening up. He was mainly an editor at first, and later a writer. Editing and writing, writing and editing, complement each other, making him a master of literature and history. His essays often have the sharpness of essays, but also contain many historical facts that essays lack. &quot;Shiling New Collection&quot; released by Huacheng Publishing House collects his main essays from 1987 to 2021. It is only a little over 200,000 words, but each chapter is based on solid historical materials. These dozens of essays form part of contemporary cultural history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Richard Pipes: &quot;Russia under the Old Regime&quot;, Democratic Construction Press, May 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Russia is a big country across Europe and Asia. The &quot;Soviet Union&quot; with Russia as the main body was once one of the two superpowers in the world and had an impact on the world. Tremendous influence. Such a huge country was formed not long ago. It is not a European country, but it is not an Asian country either. Its unique culture and vast territory have formed its own governance model, political and economic systems. &quot;Russia Under the Old Regime&quot; combs through the evolution of Russia from the 9th century to the 1880s, providing a clear description and in-depth analysis of the complex history. Only by understanding its past can we have a deeper understanding of its present and future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Lin Huihuang: &quot;Portrait of Huacun: Peasant Life in Transformation China&quot;, Oriental Publishing House, August 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Beautiful Countryside&quot; is a major rural construction project promoted by the country and an important step in targeted poverty alleviation. &quot;Flower Village&quot; was originally an ordinary village, but after it was selected as a demonstration site for beautiful rural construction, the social ecology underwent major changes and a large amount of project funds were instantly received. &quot;Portrait of Hanacun: Peasant Life in Transformation China&quot; takes real rural areas as examples and discusses some common problems encountered in the development of Chinese rural areas in case studies. By telling the stories of different farmers, the author explores different themes, including farming, working, mechanical farming, crop planting adventures, farmhouse entertainment, agricultural industrialization, rural governance, rural revitalization, etc. The core question is that most of these project funds are used for major issues that county and township governments are interested in, rather than major issues that farmers are really interested in. Why is this? What is the mechanism that creates this situation? The author&#39;s questions are thought-provoking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Walter Isaacson: &quot;The Biography of Kissinger&quot;, CITIC Publishing House, September 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2018, CITIC Publishing House published &quot;Kissinger: The Idealist&quot; by American historian Ferguson, which provided an in-depth analysis of Kissinger&#39;s early thoughts. Research, I have written book reviews, and I have gained some understanding of Chi&#39;s early thoughts, which I didn&#39;t know much about before. This year, CITIC Press released &quot;Kissinger&#39;s Biography&quot; by the famous American biographer Isaacson. What interests me is still Kissinger&#39;s early experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Kissinger is a Jewish refugee who fled Germany to the United States with his family in 1938 when he was 11 years old. Previously, he was discriminated against and persecuted in the German city of Fürth, which he found incomprehensible at a young age. The city of Fürth is not big. Except for the Jewish children, almost all the people in the city are members of the &quot;Hitler Youth&quot;. He and his brother were standing on the street and saw them wearing uniforms, singing in lines and marching in neat steps. They didn&#39;t understand why they couldn&#39;t right to participate. On the contrary, he and his brother were ridiculed and ridiculed everywhere, and soon they were no longer allowed to go to the swimming pool, dance, or teahouse... More and more places had &quot;Jews prohibited&quot; signs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After immigrating to the United States, his parents worked for others and their income was not high. After one year of high school, Kissinger had to switch to &quot;night school&quot;. Work during the day and study at night. His job was to work in a shaving brush factory run by a relative, wearing thick rubber gloves and squeezing the solution and water out of the brushes. The weekly salary was 11 US dollars, and he was later upgraded to a delivery person, responsible for delivering goods, and the weekly salary increased to 30 US dollars. Colleagues recalled that he was often absent-minded at work, reading or doing night school homework whenever he had the chance. His early experiences were quite &quot;inspirational&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The painful childhood experience had an unforgettable impact on him. “For Kissinger, the Holocaust destroyed the link between God’s will and historical progress—a core belief of Judaism and its most important contribution to Western philosophy. For believing Jews, history The meaning of should be understood from its connection with God’s will and heavenly principles. But after witnessing the evil deeds of the Nazis, Kissinger abandoned his Jewish faith. While studying at Harvard, the young student began to focus on academic aspects Explore other ways of finding historical meaning.&quot; His inner academic &quot;module&quot; was always European rather than American. He was fond of Kant, Hegel, Metternich, and Dostoevsky, but never I have expressed my appreciation for the archetypal figures who represent American creativity, such as Mark Twain, Jefferson, and Franklin. His childhood experience formed his basic idea: the pursuit of order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1588&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Perry Miller: &quot;Endless Conflict: American Intellectual Life from the Revolution to the Civil War&quot; , Oriental Publishing House, July 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In recent years, Oriental Publishing House has planned and published the &quot;American Civilization Classics Translation Series&quot;. Qian Mansu, the editor-in-chief of the series and a researcher at the Institute of Foreign Languages, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, is a graduate of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences after the reform and opening up. The first batch of students studying in the United States studied the history of American civilization at Harvard University. This series of books is well-selected, and &quot;Endless Conflict: American Intellectual Life from the Revolution to the Civil War&quot; is one of them. Published in 1965, this book won the 1966 Pulitzer Prize for History. It is Miller&#39;s next grand work on the history of American thought after &quot;American Spiritual Life: The Seventeenth Century&quot; and &quot;American Spiritual Life: From Colonies to Provinces&quot; . This book was published nearly a year ago and has become a classic after the test of time. In this book, Miller attempts to grasp the religious roots of American culture and explain why the spirit of religion and the spirit of freedom, which are often opposed to each other elsewhere, are almost integrated in the United States. The contradiction and conflict between religion and secularity is a global problem. In the era of globalization, can the history of more than a hundred years ago be enlightening? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 09:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[六名中国公民被绑架杀害？海外华人华侨要团结以自保]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 11, 2023, the Philippine police discovered multiple tools in succession near a construction site in Laihu Bay. The remains are suspected by the police to be the six Chinese citizens who were kidnapped on October 30: including Mr. Zeng and his wife who are presidents of local Chinese charity organizations in the Philippines, brother Zeng and his wife, and brother Zeng’s teenage son. son, and one person remains unidentified. On November 28, the Philippine police confirmed the identities of four corpses, including Mr. Zeng’s two brothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, vicious cases involving overseas Chinese have occurred in some overseas countries: In May 2023, a Chinese couple died naked in a Bali hotel; in 2023, a Chinese student was murdered in Thailand on &quot;3·31&quot;... …In addition to these brutal cases, the criminal system of the warlords in northern Myanmar is basically tailor-made for the Chinese people. The number of Chinese people they have killed and the seriousness of their crimes are really too numerous to describe. Recently, the &quot;Ming Family&quot; in northern Myanmar, which specializes in telecommunications fraud, has reached the end of its rope and is about to be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the country&#39;s economic development, foreign economic, trade and cultural exchanges have increased, and Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Opportunities are always accompanied by challenges, and contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure one&#39;s personal and property safety, as well as legal rights, has become increasingly important. Examples of self-security and collective security for overseas Chinese can be found in the Korean community living in North America and the Jewish community scattered around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea has a small population, and even fewer people live in the world. However, a small number of Korean immigrants (mainly immigrants from South Korea) became a bright spot in the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; in 1992: After the U.S. police temporarily gave up protecting communities of color, a small number of Korean immigrants united and armed themselves for self-defense , took up arms to defend the community, resisting the onslaught of thugs, and held on until the National Guard entered the city to quell the violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For decades, Koreans have deeply felt the importance of external unity. Their overseas immigrants have strengthened internal unity, taking advantage of North American citizens&#39; gun-carrying laws to arm themselves for self-defense and strengthen their martial spirit. Therefore, even though the 1.65 million Korean immigrants only account for 0.5% of the U.S. population, North American residents know that Koreans are not easy to mess with and they dare to use guns in critical moments. Therefore, the thugs of the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; were unable to capture the strongholds held by Korean armed forces, so they looted Chinese stores because the Chinese generally lacked the ability to defend themselves at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before World War II, the Jewish community was known for being disunited, disorganized, shrewd and philanthropic, and gentle and cowardly. It is said that there are 12 branches of Judaism since ancient times. There are so many factions and small groups below. The Jews who run banks are greedy for money and are unwilling to help others. Therefore, few people are willing to help them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to better integrate into European society, the Jews not only accepted many Western living habits, but also tried to avoid confrontation when they had conflicts with the indigenous peoples. Therefore, various European ethnic groups have long scorned the military value of the Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During World War II, the Holocaust in Nazi Germany nearly annihilated European Jewry, which changed the spirit, character, and psychology of some Jews. After the war, some Jews reached several consensuses:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, they must build their own country and make it strong, rather than just being nomads in the world. When conflicts involving the Jewish community occur again, it cannot only rely on money, but also on the state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it is still necessary to maintain the simultaneous existence of Jews in various parts of the world to spread the risks of survival in case one country is defeated and the entire race is annihilated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, money alone is not enough. To survive, you must have the ability to defend yourself. The two words &quot;wealth and strength&quot; are indispensable. If we are not rich, we cannot afford advanced weapons and equipment and cannot build a strong army, so we cannot be strong; if we are not strong, we cannot maintain wealth for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, Jews have self-defense groups in many communities around the world. Especially in North America, we make full use of local laws and policies to conduct paramilitary training and have a considerable number of foreign reserve soldiers. On October 7, 2023, just hours after the war in Gaza broke out, a large number of Jewish young people from North America and Australia flew to Israel to join the war, with a total number of tens of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through arduous efforts, the Jews have changed to a certain extent the customs of their ethnic group, which were previously fragmented, fighting among themselves, and trying to undermine each other (but there is still a clear distinction between their modern factions and the &quot;ultra-Orthodox&quot;). It not only engages in &quot;hiding troops among the people&quot; around the world, but also forms an underground intelligence network connecting the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, Israel is a miniature country with a population of only a few million, and its intelligence agency &quot;Mossad&quot; does not have sufficient funds (like the CIA). Especially in the early stages of construction and development, it can be said that there is little money to be had, and even poverty can lead to poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1960, the Nazi war criminal Eichmann was captured; in the 1970s, the &quot;Black September&quot; terrorist organization was hunted around the world. &quot;Mossad&quot; can only send out a small range of troops, and the budget is tight. Each person only has a few dollars per day for food, and cannot afford to live in a hotel or buy a car. They move around the world and live in old houses provided by local Jews. Some of them don&#39;t even have beds and can only make beds on the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With that little activity fund, not only can’t I afford a restaurant, I can’t even afford takeout. I had no choice but to give the money to the local Jewish contacts, who would buy ingredients from the mall on their behalf and cook the food themselves. It is simply impossible for a &quot;Mossad&quot; agent to drive an Aston Martin sports car as elegantly as in spy movies. The vehicles used in many operations were all old cars borrowed from local Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the grass-roots teams in the early days when Koreans and Jews established their own power networks in the world, the number of Chinese people and wealth they have around the world is really much stronger. But it is a pity that Chinese expatriates with huge wealth cannot even effectively protect their personal safety and property safety. Malicious anti-Chinese and crimes against Chinese expatriates occur frequently around the world. As for the large number of violent crimes against Chinese people mentioned above, many Chinese gangsters were involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is really regrettable and heartbreaking. The reason is that there is still internal strife among overseas Chinese and there is serious internal friction in their strength. Some Chinese friends in North America vividly told me how they tried to undermine each other in business, criticized each other culturally, and even colluded with &quot;Ghost Cap&quot; (foreign police) to punish each other. The speaker was very excited, beaming, and dancing. When he was excited, his saliva sprayed into my face. This is really heartbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure their personal and property safety, as well as their legal rights, has become increasingly difficult. The more important it is. The basis of all this is first of all the unity of the ethnic group. In this regard, we should really think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[甘肃酒泉市肃北县发生5.0级地震]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:17:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China Seismological Network officially determined: December 01, 22:55 in Subei County, Jiuquan City, Gansu Province ( A magnitude 5.0 earthquake occurred at 39.30 degrees north latitude and 97.27 degrees east longitude, with a focal depth of 9 kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height= &quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1701443803135-0&quot; data-mce-width =&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔚来“朋友圈”再扩容，车企为何统一换电？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261667]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 battery swap stations around the world .Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 power swap stations around the world. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following Changan Automobile (000625.SZ), NIO (09866.HK, NYSE:NIO) has made another success with its battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Geely Holding) and NIO officially signed a strategic cooperation agreement on battery swapping in Hangzhou. The two parties will work on battery swapping standards and battery swapping technology. , carry out comprehensive cooperation in various fields such as battery swap service network construction and operation, battery swap model R&amp;D and customization, battery asset management and operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the agreement, in the future, the two parties will create two major battery swap standard systems for &quot;private cars&quot; and &quot;commercial vehicles&quot; through the &quot;co-investment, co-construction, sharing, and co-operation&quot; model to promote vehicle-end , station end, battery end, and operation end are connected and coordinated to expand the scale of the battery swap network to meet users with different needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, NIO founder Li Bin revealed in an internal speech to all employees that in addition to Changan Automobile, there are 4-5 potential partners currently being negotiated. In other words, more car companies may join NIO&#39;s &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei, the expert committee of the China Automobile Dealers Association, told Southern Weekend reporters that the expansion of the &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping has a strategic significance higher than the practical level, and it will have a limited effect on improving their respective revenue in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the initial cooperation between the parties is exploratory and may start with operating vehicles such as online ride-hailing. &quot;If the results are good, it may be upgraded to more important models or high-value models.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are only two roads in front of you&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news &quot;NIO lost 76.4 billion in five and a half years&quot; appeared on Weibo&#39;s hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2018 to 2022, NIO’s net profits attributable to the parent company were -23.328 billion yuan, -11.413 billion yuan, -5.611 billion yuan, -10.572 billion yuan and -14.559 billion yuan respectively. In the first half of 2023, NIO&#39;s net profit attributable to its parent company continued to suffer a loss of 10.926 billion yuan, with a cumulative loss of 76.4 billion yuan in 5.5 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although at the recent Guangzhou Automobile Industry Development Conference, NIO co-founder and president Qin Lihong emphasized that &quot;NIO will never go bankrupt, and it is impossible for it to go bankrupt.&quot; But it is undeniable that Weilai has invested too much in “peripheral products” and its sales have declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Li Bin’s internal speech to all employees was also on the hot search. He said that the road to battery replacement is very difficult, but it is difficult and the right thing to do. &quot;Everyone thinks of battery replacement as Amazon doing cloud services in 2003, as well as Alibaba, Tencent, Microsoft, etc. They have suffered losses for many years. Only then did we finally achieve success.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NIO and NIO’s battery swap are always accompanied by controversy. The construction of a service system with power exchange as the core is regarded as the main reason for NIO&#39;s losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, NIO will deploy a total of 2,300 power swap stations in 2023. As of November 28, NIO has built 2,184 power stations around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the cost of each generation of NIO&#39;s three generations of power swap stations is slightly different, if based on a rough calculation of the 3 million yuan cost of each power swap station stated by Qin Lihong at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show, NIO&#39;s power swap performance will be The cumulative investment has exceeded 6.5 billion yuan. This does not include additional expenses such as venue rental, personnel operations and electricity expenses. Based on NIO’s goal of adding 1,000 battery swap stations in 2023, the cost of building the stations alone will be as high as 3 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Fei, NIO’s vice president in charge of NIO Power, revealed at a press conference in March that the battery swap station had to serve 50-60 orders per day to achieve breakeven. At that time, NIO’s battery swap station averaged 35 orders per day. -36 orders. The implication is that Weilai is still in the loss-making stage when it comes to battery replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei believes that NIO positions itself as a luxury brand and provides services such as battery replacement and user rights to make up for the lack of product and brand power. It has indeed played a very good role in brand building in the early stage. However, as investment increased, its sales volume did not increase significantly, but instead became a huge burden. &quot;Keeping it has limited use, just throw it away. It&#39;s a pity.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only two ways in front of Weilai, either to sell more cars and dilute the power exchange network construction from within. or introduce more car companies to participate in NIO’s power swap network to create a scale effect and alleviate financial difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Weilai has already had clues about opening up the battery swap business. At the China Electric Vehicles 100 People Forum held in April 2023, Li Bin said that &quot;the battery swap service has reached the stage where it can be exported to the outside world.&quot; He hoped that other companies can share and build charging and swap infrastructure with NIO, and revealed that there are already Car companies are discussing this matter with NIO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu, honorary chairman of the Society of Automotive Engineers of China, told Southern Weekend reporters that as the current battery swap model has not yet found a profit model, there are only more battery swap stations and a more convenient energy replenishment experience. Only then can more users be willing to buy battery-exchange models, thus forming a positive cycle. NIO&#39;s cooperation with Geely, Changan and other automobile manufacturers will help promote the battery swap model on a larger scale, improve the overall operating efficiency of the battery swap model, and may solve the commercialization problem of battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Or start from online car-hailing services&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The battery swap model laid out by NIO does have many advantages. For example, it only takes less than 5 minutes for car owners to replace the battery at the battery swap station. However, the disadvantage is that the battery swap model still faces problems such as high website construction costs, uncertain commercialization models, and inconsistent industry standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, there are several companies on the market that are trying to lay out the power swap model, but the construction of power swap stations is independent of each other. Since 2020, relevant national departments have continued to promote the formulation of standards for battery swap stations and battery packs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 World Power Battery Conference, Xin Guobin, Vice Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, revealed an important signal. Currently, a battery replacement technology standard system is being studied and compiled to promote battery replacement battery size, battery replacement interface, Standards such as communication protocols are unified. At the same time, relevant departments have also entered into the inspection process for the national battery replacement station standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu believes that each car company has different models and batteries. In the context of cooperation, battery swapping may require a transition period to improve the versatility of the battery swapping network. &quot;However, it can force companies to make better efforts in standardization, which is of key significance to the structural adjustment of the battery swap model.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some people question that unified battery swap operation management may affect Wei Come to the battery swapping experience of existing users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike NIO’s battery swap model, most car companies are betting on high-voltage fast charging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 800V high-voltage fast charging platform is currently regarded as the most likely technology path. In 2019, Porsche launched the Taycan, the world&#39;s first 800V high-voltage platform model. Automobile manufacturers such as BYD, Xpeng, Great Wall, Geely Jikrypton, etc. have all begun relevant layouts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the long term, 800V will be an opportunity to reshape the battery industry,” Li Bin said at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show. “But no company has yet been able to reduce the cost of 800V to close to that of the current 400V. or a slightly higher level.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei also believes that high-voltage charging costs are high and is currently mainly used in relatively high-end models. It is unlikely that the technology will be transferred to low-end models in the short term. In addition, the layout of high-voltage charging piles is still imperfect, and an absolute advantage over the battery swap model has not yet been established in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Liu Jinliang, CEO of Yiyi Internet Technology Co., Ltd., signed the power exchange cooperation with NIO on behalf of Geely Yifang this time. He has led Geely&#39;s travel business in recent years, and has been responsible for Caocao Private Car, Yao Travel and other sectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei said that online car-hailing may be the first area of ​​cooperation between the two parties. Due to cost control, operating vehicles such as taxis and online ride-hailing vehicles mostly use lithium iron phosphate batteries. The batteries are used frequently, so the demand for battery replacement will be higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海底捞“科目三”爆火，有创意还是“辣眼睛”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chatting is not as good as dancing. Making oneself feel comfortable is everyone&#39;s talent...&quot; In Haidilao, watch Dancing seems to be more important than chatting and eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Haidilao has made a splash again with the launch of the &quot;&lt;strong>;Subject 3&lt;/strong>;&quot; dance service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;Subject Three&quot; is not the &quot;Subject Three&quot; of the driver&#39;s license assessment, but a dance that mainly consists of waving hands, twisting hips and half-crotch feet. The music above, the magical dance steps, and the exciting scenes have made the business of many Haidilao stores become booming. Some customers enjoy it: &quot;The fatigue of the day is healed here&quot; &quot;Haidilao can cure social fear&quot; &quot; The boys are so handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &lt;strong>;&quot;Dance&quot; must be reversed&lt;/strong>;, and Haidilao&#39;s &quot;Subject Three&quot; has also caused a lot of controversy. Some customers complained that &quot;the dancing is tacky and noisy&quot; and &quot;it feels uncomfortable to bring children here to eat.&quot; Accompanying the controversy are the feelings of Haidilao employees themselves: “There is no reward commission”, “It’s hard to refuse customers’ requests”, “It’s really embarrassing inside”, “It’s meaningless”, and even a young man from a store in Changxing County, Zhejiang&lt; strong>;I was admitted to the hospital with a bone bruise due to skipping &quot;Subject Three&quot;&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating with atmosphere, singing and dancing to entertain is not Haidilao’s exclusive program. For example, Chongqing Hot Pot Factory is called “Sheniu Hot Pot Restaurant” by customers. Behind the &quot;local flavor social shake&quot;, &quot;fancy decoration&quot; and &quot;grandstanding&quot; is the fierce competition in the catering industry. While trying to acquire customers at a low cost, they also want to speed up breaking out of the circle. However, no matter what, service comes first, and the core of a restaurant should be Still taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Under the sea &quot;Subject Three&quot; became a hit, what do you think? Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数据安全榜：谁在尽心倾力守护您的金融隐私？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:07:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In today’s digital age, financial privacy security is greatly testing everyone’s A financial institution also affects everyone&#39;s most sensitive nerves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But accidental events often produce extraordinary panic and associations. In November 2023, some financial institutions experienced successive risk incidents at home and abroad, and even encountered hackers, and their core data was leaked or hijacked. The incident triggered deep thinking in the financial and technological circles: How can we do our best to protect users’ financial privacy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, regulators attach great importance to the security of national financial data and personal financial information, and have successively introduced a series of regulatory specifications aimed at establishing a system that covers all financial data. Life cycle safety management system mechanism. Among them, the protection of personal financial information has become an important part of the security management of financial data life cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively evaluate the data security strength of the banking and life insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a survey on 20 systemically important commercial banks and 9 mainstream life insurance companies. Conduct systematic evaluation. Consistent with the construction logic of the indicator evaluation system of the wealth management list, green finance list, and digital finance list, the quantitative and qualitative indicators of the data security list account for 70% of the weight, and external expert review and media factors each account for 15% of the weight. In view of the differences in relevant information disclosure rules and actual disclosure situations between banks and insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed quantitative and qualitative indicator systems for data security in the banking and life insurance industries based on the key disclosure points of each bank and insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the strict data security standards of each bank and insurance institution under evaluation, and the rare data security accidents so far, this list focuses on the above-mentioned bancassurance institutions’ The strategic importance of data security, the transparency of information disclosure and the effectiveness of data security work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bank ranking indicator system: the most important performance in four dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banking industry data security ranking The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the evaluation indicator system are divided into four dimensions: organizational construction, institutional processes, technical tools and effectiveness, and include five secondary indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1151&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the banking industry data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Organizational construction&lt;/strong>; refers to the organizational structure of commercial banks in terms of data security. The research team of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center considered the number of relevant responsible departments disclosed by commercial banks. The weight of this indicator accounts for 10%, reflecting the importance commercial banks attach to data security and information protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;System process&lt;/strong>; refers to the degree of standardization of the process of building a data security system for commercial banks. Standardized institutional processes are an important cornerstone and guarantee for commercial banks to build data security systems. Under this dimension, we mainly examine the number of relevant systems and normative documents on data security of commercial banks, divided into two secondary indicators: the number of its own relevant systems and the number of normative documents related to supplier management, with a total weight of 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among them, supplier management refers to when a commercial bank collects, transmits, stores, filters, analyzes, exchanges, and shares all data belonging to the bank. , a management mechanism for effective risk identification, assessment and effective control of relevant external partners. At present, most commercial banks do not pay enough attention to data security when conducting annual reviews of various suppliers. For suppliers who have access to sensitive bank data, once the supplier has security vulnerabilities or misbehaves, it is likely that the information security and data security of commercial banks will be threatened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to encourage commercial banks to pay more attention to the management of suppliers in terms of data security, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has disclosed the relevant supplier management systems disclosed by commercial banks. The number of documents is included in the indicator system, accounting for 10% of the weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Technical tools&lt;/strong>; are a core part of the network security system. This indicator directly reflects the commercial bank&#39;s ability to protect data and privacy and the effectiveness and reliability of data security protection. In view of the fact that the research and evaluation of relevant technical tools in the data industry has been very systematic, we use the number of certification systems disclosed by each commercial bank to determine the bank&#39;s technical strength in data security. The weight of this indicator is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Performance indicators&lt;/strong>; account for 30% of the weight, which is the largest single indicator dimension and the only qualitative indicator to fully reflect the Results-oriented data security ranking evaluation logic. This indicator has a significant impact on the data security evaluation results of commercial banks. For commercial banks that have information security incidents, customer personal information leaks, major IT system failures and other incidents in 2023, we will warn the relevant commercial banks by reducing their scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It needs to be emphasized that in order to encourage commercial banks to increase the transparency of information disclosure in the field of data security and reduce information asymmetry, we have not disclosed relevant information for some banks. In the case of indicator data, the relevant indicator will be given the lowest score. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Data Security&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Big banks dominate the top three&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank data security list shows that Agricultural Bank of China ranks first, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. . The comprehensive scores of the three major banks all exceed 70 points, showing significant advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China has obtained 51 various certifications related to data security, far more than any other bank. The bank was the first among major state-owned banks to issue the &quot;Data Security Management Measures (Trial)&quot; and established a comprehensive data security management system based on this. At the same time, the bank adheres to the &quot;minimum necessary&quot; principle, conducts mining and applications within the scope and authority of reasonable use of data, and encrypts sensitive customer information to maximize data security and privacy and avoid leakage and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking of Banks (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2273&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among joint-stock banks, Ping An Bank and China Merchants Bank ranked fourth and fifth respectively on the list, performing relatively well. Ping An Bank insists on using safe and available tools and technologies for data integration, including using security umbrella technology to automatically desensitize data and automatically protect sensitive groups, and ensure the independence and security of analysis scenarios through data safe houses. The bank&#39;s credit cards use a self-developed privacy computing platform to accurately identify external and debit card customers, effectively reducing customer acquisition costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance ranking indicator system:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Three dimensions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;7&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Sub-indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance is a typical data-intensive industry, with a large amount of personal information, market information and transaction information. Regulators attach great importance to data security in the life insurance industry. Since 2023, regulatory agencies have issued regulatory documents such as the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Consumer Rights Protection in Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Network and Data Security Management in Third-Party Cooperation&quot;, requiring life insurance institutions to establish a consumer personal information protection mechanism. And carry out self-examination and rectification of data risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How is the performance of life insurance institutions? Based on public information such as financial reports, ESG or CSR reports, official announcements, and public reports disclosed by the nine life insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a quantitative analysis of the nine life insurance companies from the three dimensions of data security, internal governance, and external review. and qualitative evaluation, and set up 7 sub-indicators, each with a weight of 10%, and the total weight of quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center integrated expert review scores and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) to build a life insurance data security ranking indicator system . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of data security ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1379&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Life Insurance Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the data security dimension, the emphasis on data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by the number of times &quot;data security&quot; or &quot;data privacy&quot; is mentioned in ESG reports, and the effectiveness of data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by whether major information security incidents occurred in the past year. . The judgment of this indicator is based on the description of major information security events in the annual report or ESG report. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the internal governance dimension, life insurance institutions are qualitatively evaluated based on three indicators: whether to set up an independent data security department, whether to formulate a data security protection system, and whether to conduct an annual information security review. Implementation of internal data security work. The total weight of the above three indicators accounts for 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The external review dimension qualitatively evaluates the acceptance of life insurance institutions in the professional field of data security based on two indicators: whether the App has violated user privacy issues and whether it has obtained ISO/IEC27001 certification. Level of recognition. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Insurance ranking: China Life wins the championship, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;AIA Taikang ranks among the top three&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance data security list shows that China Life leads AIA Life to take the first place with an advantage of 1.59 points, and AIA Life ranks second. The comprehensive scores of both life insurance companies exceeded 80 points, 8 points ahead of the third place Taikang Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1186&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Looking at the scores of quantitative and qualitative indicators, China Life, China Pacific Insurance, AIA Life and Taikang Life all scored over 60. This shows that they perform better overall in multiple dimensions such as data security, internal governance and external review. In the end, China Life won the championship due to its high scores in both external judges&#39; scores and media factor scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life proposed a comprehensive &quot;Technology China Life&quot; strategy as early as 2012, and has continued to increase investment in data security for 11 years. As one of the first batch of pilot financial institutions, China Life took the lead in the industry to migrate and put into production the Xinchuang database of key business systems, achieve 100% distributed architecture transformation of key business systems, and successfully build a new self-controlled distributed cloud architecture digital base. The company also proposed and built the first data center in the domestic life insurance industry and a high-standard underground computer room that obtained T4 certification. In addition, the company has also successfully developed a safe, green and elastic China Life Hybrid Cloud using internal private cloud and external public cloud resources, which integrates computing, storage and containers to significantly improve data security and computing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also found that although the life insurance institutions at the bottom have not yet experienced major information security incidents, they have shortcomings in internal governance and external review obvious. For example, 4 institutions under evaluation did not set up independent data security departments, 2 institutions did not conduct annual information security audits, and the apps of 3 institutions were accused of infringing on user privacy, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that life insurance institutions at the bottom of the list urgently need to pay more attention to the construction and improvement of data security systems, and at the same time adopt more stringent and transparent policies. In the face of public concerns, the public&#39;s information disclosure standards should be strengthened through practical and effective measures to enhance public trust in the data security of life insurance institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的多重面孔：一轮夜空悬，千片秋江月]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261635]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In history, there are few Chinese poets like Li Bai. It attracted much attention during the era in which he lived. Topics, legends, and stories about him were widely circulated when he was alive, and they did not decrease with his death, but became more abundant and mysterious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A scholar did not take the imperial examination, but was recruited to the Jinluan Palace; a commoner did not have the merits of building a large scale, but was favored by the emperor; a person who intended to clarify the troubled times, He was killed by Changliu Yelang; a man who once scattered more than 300,000 yuan a year ended up with nothing in his later years; a poet fought with people in Chang&#39;an City; a Hanlin scholar who was waiting for an imperial edict, drank freely with his craftsmen; A man with lofty ideals who is &quot;willing to serve as the Prime Minister&quot; is keen on refining elixirs and collecting herbs; a madman who looks down on the powerful is excited when facing the common people&#39;s wild rice...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Faced with this prototype that combines many contradictions, people are puzzled and determined to &quot;understand&quot; him. People not only want to understand him, but also &quot;use&quot; him, either to support themselves, to self-explain, to self-comfort, to self-liberate, or to use the past to satirize the present, or to make use of topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does Taibai look like? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No photos or videos can answer the question of Li Bai&#39;s true face. For guessing about Li Bai&#39;s appearance, we can only rely on sporadic descriptions in historical materials and the poet&#39;s autobiography to seek clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The senior poet He Zhizhang exclaimed that Li Bai was &quot;relegated to a fairy&quot; when he first met him. Taoist master Sima Chengzhen commented on Li Bai that &quot;the Jun family has immortal Taoist bones, which can travel with the gods to the eight extremes&quot;. There are many documents written about Li Bai&#39;s contemporaries like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed in &quot;Books with Han Jingzhou&quot;: &quot;Although the body is less than seven feet, his ambition is ten thousand.&quot; The ancients said that tall people are like Zhuge Liang and others are all &quot;eight feet long&quot;, and the seven-foot-long man is only of average height. Even though Li Bai was majestic and magnificent, he was not tall and mighty. He should be a small man. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s fanboy Wei Hao described Li Bai in the preface to &quot;The Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; as having &quot;bright eyes, trembling like a hungry tiger, sometimes belted, The romance is brewing.&quot; His friend Cui Zongzhi&#39;s poem &quot;Gift to Li Twelve Bai&quot; also described Li Bai&#39;s &quot;eyes that illuminate people&quot;. It can be seen that Li Bai&#39;s eyes are indeed bright and special. Li Bai calls himself a &quot;savage&quot;, and the &quot;hungry tiger&quot; is seeing his state of breaking through the restraints, which is in sharp contrast with the &quot;or time belt&quot; below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Tang Dynasty, there have been many portraits of Li Bai left. Although Li Bai&#39;s true appearance has disappeared with history, some characteristics of Li Bai&#39;s image can be directly appreciated from the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the poems of Song Dynasty poets Rao Jie and Chen Shidao, we can know that the Tang Dynasty painter Zhou Fang once painted the image of Li Bai. In Zhou Fang&#39;s writings, Li Bai is a scholar wearing a black gauze hat and a white silk robe, which is highly consistent with the dress of most scholars in ancient times. Wusha was originally a skullcap commonly worn by the people, but it was not until the Ming Dynasty that it became an official hat. The white silk robe, made of white ramie, became the mainstream of fashion in the mid-Tang Dynasty, and people even became obsessed with this kind of clothing. Li Bai&#39;s own description is different from the image in the painting: &quot;Wrapped in grass and covered with black gauze scarf, upside down with purple fur.&quot; ​​He said that he often wore &quot;purple fur&quot;, which was different from the &quot;white fur&quot; described by Zhou Fang &quot;. However, among the many paintings depicting Li Bai&#39;s image in later generations, most painters chose the &quot;black gauze and white gauze&quot; clothing feature. It can be said that Zhou Fang&#39;s &quot;portrait&quot; of Li Bai became a &quot;sample&quot; for later painters to create Li Bai&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stele gallery of the Li Bai Memorial Hall in Jiangyou, Sichuan contains the &quot;Kuangshan Taibai Statue Stele&quot; and &quot;Li Bai Statue Stele&quot; painted by the famous Northern Song Dynasty painter Li Gonglin. The former depicts Li Bai when he was studying in the mountains, clothed in cloth, carrying a bamboo stick, and high-spirited. Many subsequent images of young Li Bai originated from this. In the latter&#39;s prime, Li Bai had a round face, plump ears, and an enlightened, joyful and peaceful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Chanting Picture&quot; is the most representative image painting of Li Bai in existence, and was written by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai. Liang Kai had a willful and informal personality of &quot;hanging over the wall with his gold belt and leaving his job&quot;. Coupled with his fondness for wine, it can be said that he and Li Bai cherished each other. In the painting, Li Bai is wearing loose clothes similar to Taoist robes, and his hair style depicted in burnt ink is slightly tilted back, as if he is reciting a poem in front of the moon. With a few strokes, he captures the subtle moment when Li Bai is reciting a poem, from his head to his head. The feet are almost in one go. The modern painter Zhang Daqian painted many paintings of Li Bai in his life, most of which were based on the shapes in Liang Kai&#39;s &quot;Li Bai Xingyin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2874&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260278&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&#39;s Songs&quot; by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai is now in the Tokyo National Museum. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng used &quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; to express the feelings of the literary people. In the painting, Li Bai is supported by two chamberlains. The servant&#39;s clothes are gray, his eyes are submissive, and his posture is like hiding and peeping. Li Bai wears a bachelor&#39;s scarf on his head, a white bachelor&#39;s coat, cinnabar-colored boots and a belt, with bright colors and a sense of nobility. His beard is flowing, his eyes are open, and he is half drunk and half awake. This portrait is reminiscent of Li Bai, who &quot;got drunk in the palace and made Gao Lishi take off his boots&quot;, revealing his arrogant freedom and boldness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; by Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng, now in the Shanghai Museum. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is said that in the Ming and Qing Dynasty warehouses of the Forbidden City in Beijing, the Nanxun Hall has a particularly impressive collection of calligraphy and paintings, including more than ten small portraits of Li Bai and Du Fu. It is unknown when these small portraits were painted, and the people in the paintings are far from the stereotypes. Du Fu is not the common thin image, but a dark and fat man. Although Li Bai has a fair complexion, he does not have much beard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Taibai Hall in the Li Bai Memorial Hall is home to a bronze statue created by Li Xiangqun, a professor at the Academy of Fine Arts of Tsinghua University. The poet&#39;s slender body stands upright in the hall, with his head raised to the sky, his raised chin and beard fluttering, his lips slightly parted as if he wants to speak. The most special thing is that his eyes are blurred. After the statue was exhibited, it was recognized by the cultural and art circles, and was accepted by young people. However, some people over the age of sixty expressed great confusion about the lack of eyes and the freehand treatment, and some even protested. It can be seen that the folks in Taibai&#39;s hometown have an irreplaceable affection for Li Bai. The image of Li Bai created by tradition has been deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, and it seems that he should be what people imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, author Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;relegated immortal&quot; with &quot;a proud waist&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am a madman in Chu, Feng Ge laughs Confucius.&quot; &quot;A life of arrogance and misery is not harmonious, and kindness and help are a good matchmaker.&quot; &quot;Arrogance&quot; is not only a self-constructed trait of Li Bai in his poems, generations of creators tell Li Bai&#39;s stories, and they are also happy to express it. this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed that &quot;An Neng can crush my eyebrows and bend my waist to serve the powerful, making me unhappy?&quot; He just said that his character was incompetent. Dai Wei&#39;s &quot;Shu Pu&quot; of the Song Dynasty said: &quot;People in the Tang Dynasty said that Li Bai could not bend his body because he had a proud waist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If there are changes in character, there are also bending and stretching changes. , but the physical &quot;arrogance&quot; cannot be changed, which pushed Li Bai&#39;s arrogance to absolute status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;People believe that Li Bai is anti-secular at heart and an anomaly of the times. From inducing the foot of Gao Lishi to take off his boots, to having the prime minister grind his ink, and the concubine holding an inkstone, from riding a donkey into the county government office to fishing for ao at sea, all kinds of extreme deeds are unparalleled in ancient and modern times, both at home and abroad, among which &quot;the strong man taking off his boots&quot; is the most representative. sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The notebook novels of the Tang and Five Dynasties, &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, &quot;Youyang Miscellanies&quot; and &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; all record this story. The difference is that only &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; records that Li Bai was slandered and retaliated by Gao Lishi because of this incident. In &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s behavior of asking Gao Lishi to take off his boots was severely denied by Xuanzong. In the former, Li Bai was directly kicked out by the emperor after he asked to take off his boots. The emperor asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots, which was criticized by the emperor as &quot;he is a poor man&quot;. The former statement has been almost forgotten except for the adoption in &quot;Old Book of Tang&quot;. In subsequent stories, Gao Lishi taking off his boots has become an established fact. Perhaps, the repressed people want to take this opportunity to make a fool of themselves and feel happy by spitting out the blockages in their chests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the notebook novels related to Li Bai in the Song Dynasty, there are also some fictional stories that are almost exaggerated but vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai in Zhao Lingchou&#39;s &quot;Hou Zhenlu&quot; is like a famous scholar in the Wei and Jin Dynasties:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Li Bai visited the prime minister in the Kaiyuan period and sealed a board with the title: &quot;Li Bai, a fisherman on the sea.&quot; The prime minister asked: &quot;Sir, when you go to the sea to catch a giant turtle, what do you use as a hook and line?&quot; Bai Said: &quot;The wind and waves let go of one&#39;s emotions, and the universe controls one&#39;s ambitions. Use the rainbow as a thread and the bright moon as a hook.&quot; He also said, &quot;What can be used as bait?&quot; Bai said, &quot;Take the unloyal husband in the world as bait.&quot; Prime Minister Chang Ran . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shu&#39;s &quot;Qing Suo Gao Yi&quot; writes that Li Bai rode a donkey into the county government office while drunk:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: regular script, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zai said: &quot;Who are you, how dare you be rude?&quot; Taibai said: &quot;Begging for a confession.&quot; When Zai ordered the confession, Taibai did not write his name, but said: &quot;I once got a dragon scarf to wipe my saliva. The emperor holds a spoon, a strongman cleans his boots, and a noble concubine holds an inkstone. I am allowed to walk on horseback in front of the emperor&#39;s gate, but I am not allowed to ride a donkey in Huayin County?&quot; Seeing this, the prime minister was shocked. He stood up and thanked him and said, &quot;I didn&#39;t know that Hanlin was here, so he failed to greet me. &quot;Wanting to stay, Taibai ignored him and rode off on the donkey again. &lt;p>; The warriors and the ministers took off their boots and knotted their socks.&quot; Holding the inkstone and grinding the ink were all performed by Yang Guozhong, which fulfilled the theory that Concubine Yang, as the &quot;king&quot;, could not hold the inkstone and grind the ink for the ministers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously, people&#39;s imagination of Li Bai does not stop at the image of a &quot;madman&quot;. What is more thorough than describing Li Bai&#39;s &quot;smiling man&quot; is &quot;relegating an immortal&quot; to Li Bai. &quot;With his identity firmly established, he came from heaven and returned to heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;About Li Bai&#39;s life and death, from the legend of &quot;Chang Geng entering a dream&quot; to &quot;catching the moon and riding a whale&quot;, it has a profound impact on later generations of creators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;, which blurs the boundaries between feature films and documentaries, is the last work of Dutch director Ivens. It tells the story of his pursuit of wind and Chinese culture. course. Evans walked out of Méliès&#39;s moon mouth and walked on the moon&#39;s surface. In addition to chatting with Chang&#39;e, he also saw Li Bai on the earth through a small hole. Li Bai was lying drunkenly on a small boat, chanting, &quot;If you don&#39;t see me, the bright mirror in the high hall will have sad white hair, and the morning will be like blue silk and it will turn into snow at dusk.&quot; Suddenly a huge moon shadow appeared on the water, and Li Bai wanted to wrap his hands around it, turn over and fall into the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai goes boating with wine on a moonlit night in Evans&#39; film &quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historical materials mostly record that Li Bai died of illness. Bai Juyi wrote a poem &quot;Li Bai&#39;s Tomb&quot;. Although it does not explicitly refer to catching the moon and drowning, &quot;Li Bai&#39;s tomb by the quarrying river&quot; &quot;This sentence is quite fascinating. By the late Tang and Song dynasties, poems and articles on Li Bai&#39;s death had been extensively discussed, such as Hong Mai&#39;s &quot;Essays of Rong Zhai&quot;: &quot;It is said in the world that Li Taibai was quarrying stones in Dangtu. He was drunk and boating in the river. He looked down and took some stones in the shadow of the moon, and drowned. Therefore, there is a catching platform on the ground.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stars and the moon depend on each other. Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; said that Li Bai was born because his mother dreamed that Chang Geng was pregnant, so he was named Bai, the word is too white. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the writing of Zhang Dachun, a contemporary Taiwanese writer, the origin of this name for Li Bai is his devout identity. &quot;Li Bai in his childhood has already Knowing that he is a star who has fallen into the mortal world, looking at his parents from this point of view is just a tool that God had to borrow to cultivate him in this mortal life; looking at his brothers from this point of view is only a matter of ten years. A companion who accompanies children in spring and autumn.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As a star, it emits fairy sounds. The guest&#39;s heart is not abiding, and the lingering sound is silent.&quot; Zhang Dachun With this sentence, Li Bai is identified as a person who is like a passer-by in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fake Taoism and true Confucianism? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Part of Li Bai&#39;s story immortalizes Li Bai, while another part of Li Bai&#39;s story increasingly highlights his mortal qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The inspirational legend of &quot;an iron pestle ground into a needle&quot; was recorded in &quot;Fangyu Shenglan&quot; by Zhu Mu of the Song Dynasty. This story shows that Li Bai&#39;s talent is not innate. It is not something that comes from a dream, but is accumulated through hard study. The genius in the eyes of the Tang people was so down-to-earth in the eyes of the Song people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tu Long of the Ming Dynasty wrote Li Bai&#39;s family life in the legendary &quot;Cai Hao Ji&quot;, describing his wife Xu Xiang&#39;e and son Bo Qin, showing Li Bai as a husband With his father, he released the aloof poet into the secular life. This was unheard of in operas of the Yuan Dynasty, and the theme did not appear again in operas of the Qing Dynasty. However, contemporary literary and artistic works often depict Li Bai&#39;s relationship with his hometown and relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is interesting is that the emphasis on Li Bai&#39;s entry into the world and the image of him as a man of lofty ideals who made great achievements are almost overwhelming in today&#39;s literary and artistic works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai stood at the entrance of the altar. When he stepped onto the altar, he broke with yesterday. Yesterday was the life of the human world. In the life of the human world, he Pursuing: &#39;I am willing to serve as an assistant to make the country peaceful and the people peaceful, and the country peaceful.&#39; He wants to be Guan Zhong, Lu Zhonglian, Zhuge Liang, Xie An, Jiang Ziya... &#39;Abandoning the world&#39; means abandoning all these.&quot; Jiangyou writer Wang Huiqinghua said She completed the novel &quot;Li Bai&quot; with more than 700,000 words in 2018. She attributed the reason why Li Bai entered Taoism to avoid being hunted by Li Linfu&#39;s minions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Taixuan, who presided over the ceremony, quoted a famous line from &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; to warn Li Bai: &quot;If you want to avoid punishment, it is better to abandon the world.&quot; But Li Bai knew that he most What is difficult to do is to give up the world. Li Bai in the novel once said to the grass-roots sage Zhang Xu when he was young: &quot;Confucius said, &#39;Heaven moves vigorously, and a gentleman should constantly strive for self-improvement.&#39; I don&#39;t believe there is no such thing.&quot; It is completely Confucian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The chapter &quot;Li Bai: The Gambler&quot; in Bei Mingyu&#39;s novel &quot;A Guest from Chang&#39;an&quot; is written more straightforwardly, &quot;Li Bai said a lot of things that flattered others in his life. The scenes and words are all based on the Taoist&#39;s realistic outlook on life of &#39;for my own use&#39; - in order to realize his ideal of becoming a high official, there is nothing he cannot do. But as he gets older, he becomes more and more attached to the silly pursuits of Confucianism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was young, he thought of himself as the roc in Zhuangzi&#39;s works. He once again mentioned it in his last work &quot;Song on the Road&quot;: The great roc flies to inspire the eight descendants, and the sky destroys the power. Not good. The remaining wind is stirring for eternity, and the fusang is hanging on the stone gauze. Later generations will pass this on, who will cry when Zhongni dies? Bei Mingyu lamented: &quot;Since he was young, he has firmly believed that this big bird that shakes eight generations and stirs the world is himself. He has a high and far direction, but he is in the middle. According to Zhuangzi&#39;s carefree , It’s good to fly, it’s good to fold, so just fold. However, Li Bai thought of Confucius in such a tragedy. ... Li Bai spent his life seeking immortality, and when he was about to die, he found that he was still with him in the end. Confucius stands together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&quot; premiered in 1991 and has been performed for more than 30 years. It can be called a classic of Beijing People&#39;s Art Theater. The play is based on Li Bai&#39;s more than sixty years of life, and chooses the five or six years in his later years to form the background of the whole play. It also expresses the secular side of Li Bai&#39;s hesitation between &quot;official&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;. Screenwriter Guo Qihong pointed out in Li Bai&#39;s character introduction: &quot;&#39;Piaoran Taibai&#39; seems to be the consensus of people all the time, but I think it is not always the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing People&#39;s Art In the drama &quot;Li Bai&quot;, Pu Cunxin plays Li Bai. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The play opens with the scene of Li Bai coming to the throne for King Yong. Li Bai carried &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; and &quot;Li Sao&quot; with him. Taoist friend Wu Yun teased him, thinking Using Zhuangzi&#39;s free and easy mind to complete Qu Yuan&#39;s tragic career is the opposite. Li Bai responded with a smile: &quot;If you walk south, you will reach the north; if you walk north, you will reach the south!&quot; After Yelang was released, Li Bai was about to enter Taoism with his wife, but the day before, he encountered Guo Ziyi&#39;s visit and faced the opportunity to serve in the army. , 60-year-old Li Bai decided to change his mind and joined Guo Ziyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai-related works launched in 2023, represented by the animated film &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot; and the musical &quot;Journey into the Wine&quot;, all chose not to write poetry. Xian Taibai dwells too much on the free and easy dance, but instead pushes a lonely and frustrated Li Bai in front of the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/730e64747a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/730e64747a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the musical &quot;Let&#39;s Enter the Wine&quot;, Zheng Yunlong plays Li Bai. Photo courtesy of the show&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Li Bai in &quot;Jinjinjiu&quot; came to Beijing, he did not see the emperor, but instead saw Gao Lishi and Yang Guifei, who complained sadly Di said to Li Bai, don&#39;t take it seriously, he and she are just playthings in this palace. The play ends with Li Bai leaving Chang&#39;an in despair and returning to his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In-depth attention to Li Bai&#39;s inner world and life pursuits originated from the drama &quot;Caishiji&quot; written by Jiang Shiquan of the Qing Dynasty. Previously, composers in various dynasties paid much attention to the description of Li Bai&#39;s character. Jiang Shiquan was very dissatisfied with this and was eager to rectify Li Bai&#39;s name. This dissatisfaction is also a kind of dissatisfaction he has with his own identity. The two people have very similar experiences. They both became famous, were praised by the rulers of the dynasty, entered the Imperial Academy, but were not reused, and neither wanted to live as just a scholar. Down the line, they all grow old as literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jiang Shiquan once expressed in an article that when future generations read his works, they will say that he is an excellent poet. This kind of short-sightedness is so short-sighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, how would Li Bai view himself? This biggest mystery may never have a clear answer. Only the revolving lantern of history continues to rotate, gradually illuminating different aspects of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Part of the content of this article is referenced from: &quot;Born to Be Talented: Biography of Li Bai&quot;, &quot;The Foundation and Trajectory of the Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s Image&quot;, &quot;The Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s Image in Paintings&quot;, &quot;Research on Li Bai Stories in Tang and Song Note Novels&quot;, &quot;Li Bai-themed Operas of the Yuan, Ming and Qing Dynasties&quot; Research&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国考连续6年“扩招”，大专生可报考岗位减少106个丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 26, 2023, at the Wuhan Wenhua College examination center in the Hubei National Examination Area, Many candidates review during lunch break. (Photo provided by People&#39;s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989d7b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;596&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989d7b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On November 26, 2023, at the Wuhan Wenhua College examination center in the Hubei National Examination Area, many candidates were reviewing during their lunch break. (Photo courtesy of People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 26, 2023, the 2024 written examination for civil servants recruited by central agencies and their directly affiliated agencies officially started in 87,682 examination rooms in 237 cities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Civil Service Bureau, a total of 3.033 million people passed the qualification review of recruitment units, and the number of applicants exceeded 3 million for the first time. Among them, 2.613 million candidates confirmed their registration before taking the exam, and 2.252 million actually took the exam, with a reference rate of approximately 86.2%. This &quot;National Examination&quot; plan recruits 39,600 people, and the ratio of the number of people taking the exam to the number of people admitted is about 57:1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting through historical data, it is not difficult to find that the overall scale of &quot;National Examination&quot; recruitment is on the rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1993, the State Council promulgated the &quot;Interim Regulations on National Civil Servants&quot; to establish and implement the civil service system in national administrative agencies at all levels. In June 1994, the former Ministry of Personnel issued the &quot;Interim Regulations on the Recruitment of National Civil Servants&quot;, which marked the formal establishment of the national civil servant examination and recruitment system, and organized the first civil servant recruitment examination for central state administrative agencies that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first &quot;National Examination&quot; provided 490 places for more than 30 state agencies. In the end, 4,400 people officially applied for the exam, which is equivalent to 9 people competing for one position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the number of people recruited for the &quot;National Examination&quot; has continued to increase. The number of recruits from 2019 to 2024 is 14,500, 24,100, 25,700, 31,200, 37,100, and 39,600 respectively. It has been &quot;enrollment expansion&quot; for 6 consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Lianchang, former executive deputy minister of the Ministry of Personnel and leader of the national civil service system implementation leading group, personally experienced the process of establishing and implementing the civil service examination system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He once recalled that the previous recruitment system was through recommendations, handing out notes, introductions, transfers, etc. &quot;That is, whoever wants to join, find someone and recommend anyone.&quot; In his view, this lacks openness, impartiality and scientificity, often resulting in a situation where the people the national government departments want cannot be found and the people they don’t want are forced into them, which cannot be said to be meritocracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-nine years after the first &quot;National Examination&quot; was held, the requirements for academic qualifications for civil servant recruitment are getting higher and higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Youzhen, chief researcher of Huatu Education, noticed that there are 56 positions that college students can apply for in the 2024 national examination, a decrease of 106 from the previous year. The number of positions requiring a master&#39;s degree and the number of recruits has increased significantly. The number of positions requiring a master&#39;s degree or above has reached 2,046, an increase of 814 over the previous year; the number of positions requiring a doctorate is 24, an increase of 14 over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grass-level positions are still the most popular. This &quot;National Examination&quot; has nearly 27,000 plans to be supplemented to directly affiliated institutions at the county (district) level and below, and the application conditions such as academic qualifications, majors, working years and experience for grassroots positions in difficult and remote areas will be appropriately adjusted according to the actual situation. Further enrich the ranks of grassroots civil servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing worth paying attention to is the &lt;span>;State Financial Supervision and Administration’s first recruitment in 2024&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions.&quot; It was decided to establish the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau on the basis of the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission. On May 18, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau was unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau has a total of 1,166 positions this time and plans to recruit 1,660 people, ranking fifth among all systems. As of one hour before the end of registration, the total number of applicants exceeded 80,000, and the maximum competition ratio was 591:1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission’s recruitment was conducted at the same time as the national examination for other positions, but in fact it was a public institution managed with reference to the Civil Service Law, and the positions were essentially public institutions. However, after the reform, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau became an agency directly under the State Council, and the positions were already in the administrative establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Liu Youzhen, this year Huatu Education has opened 22 customized classes at top universities such as Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China to provide special training for students who are committed to taking public exams. Among them, students attending classes at Tsinghua University The number of people reached more than 2,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that while the number of applicants for the &quot;National Examination&quot; has reached a new high, the number of applicants for the 2024 postgraduate entrance examination has dropped by 360,000 after eight consecutive years of increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liu Youzhen’s view, under the severe employment situation, seeking stability is still the primary factor for most candidates to choose to take the public examination. Many candidates believe that the purpose of the postgraduate entrance examination is for better employment. “After graduating from graduate school, I still If you want to take the public examination, you can simply avoid the increasingly difficult postgraduate entrance examination and directly join the public examination army. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Personnel Trends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hu Jinglin is appointed as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;News from the State Administration of Taxation, on November 28, 2023, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Taxation and announced that Hu Jinglin was appointed as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation, Wang Jun was removed from his position as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Jinglin, born in June 1964, holds a Ph.D. in economics. He has served as deputy director of the State-owned Assets Administration, deputy director, director of the Ministry of Finance, director of the general office, assistant minister, deputy minister, etc. He served as the first director of the National Medical Security Administration in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tang Fangyu no longer serves as Chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, updated information on the official website of the Chongqing CPPCC shows that Tang Fangyu served as chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC from January 2023 to October 2023 and no longer serves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Fangyu, male, Han nationality, born in August 1963, graduate student, member of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Tang Fangyu has served as deputy director of the Party Building Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, director of the Political Research Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, director of the Research Office of the General Office of the Central Committee, deputy director of the General Office of the Central Committee, and researcher of the General Office of the Central Committee Office director and other positions. In January this year, he served as chairman and party secretary of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhang Chunlin is appointed deputy secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Shanxi Satellite TV&#39;s &quot;Shanxi News Network&quot;, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China recently approved Zhang Chunlin&#39;s appointment as member, standing committee member and deputy secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Committee. Previously, Zhang Chunlin served as deputy secretary of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Zhang Chunlin, male, Han nationality, born in February 1965, from Deyang, Sichuan, started working in August 1986, joined the Communist Party of China in January 1986, Xinjiang University School of Economics and Management Population, Graduated with a major in resource and environmental economics, an on-the-job postgraduate degree, a PhD in economics, and is an alternate member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many places welcome new vice-governors&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 30, the second plenary meeting (closing meeting) of the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Shaanxi Provincial People’s Congress was held. It was decided to appoint Chen Chunjiang as deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. Chen Chunjiang previously served as Assistant Minister of Commerce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also on November 30, the Standing Committee of the Hebei Provincial People&#39;s Congress decided to appoint Zhao Dachun as deputy governor of the Hebei Provincial People&#39;s Government. Zhao Dachun previously served as deputy general manager of China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the WeChat public account &quot;Hubei People&#39;s Congress&quot;, on the morning of December 1, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Hubei Provincial People&#39;s Congress voted and decided to appoint Wei Shengbin as deputy director of the Hubei Provincial People&#39;s Government. Governor. Previously, Wei Shengbin was a member of the Party Leadership Group of Hubei Provincial Government and Secretary-General of the Provincial Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vice Minister of Science and Technology Zhang Guangjun returns to college&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023, Huazhong University of Science and Technology held a meeting of teacher cadres and announced that Zhang Guangjun was appointed as Secretary of the Party Committee of Huazhong University of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Guangjun, born in March 1965, is an academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering. He once served as vice president of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics and president of Southeast University. In November 2021, Zhang Guangjun served as Vice Minister of Science and Technology and a member of the Party Leadership Group until this adjustment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Admitted to the Youth Class of the University of Science and Technology of China at the age of 15, Anhui post-80s generation official took up a new position&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti ;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the official website of the Anhui Provincial Forestry Bureau has been updated to show that Zhou Mi has been appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Anhui Provincial Forestry Bureau and Deputy Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Provincial Department of Natural Resources, responsible for the overall work of the Bureau. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Mi was born in Wuwei, Anhui Province in September 1982. He is a doctor of science, postdoctoral fellow in economics, and a professor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1997, at the age of 15, he was admitted to the Junior Class of the University of Science and Technology of China, where he continued his master&#39;s and doctoral studies. After graduating in 2006, he served as a chief staff member in the General Division of the Development Research Center (Research Office) of the Anhui Provincial Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2011, 29-year-old Zhou Mi was appointed deputy secretary of the Anhui Provincial Committee of the Communist Youth League. According to the Beijing News, he became the youngest department-level cadre in the country at that time. At the end of 2019, he went to Xinjiang to participate in Xinjiang aid work and served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Xuancheng City Party Committee and the commander-in-chief of the Anhui Provincial Xinjiang Aid Front Headquarters. In January of the following year, he was appointed deputy secretary of the Xinjiang Hotan Prefectural Committee, member of the Standing Committee of the Xuancheng City Committee, and commander-in-chief of the Anhui Provincial Xinjiang Aid Front Headquarters. In May 2021, he was confirmed to be at the department level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing, was arrested&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing, suspected of accepting bribes, was investigated by the National Supervisory Commission and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Xiong Xue on suspicion of bribery in accordance with the law. The case is under further processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported that Xiong Xue had lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original intention and mission, had apathy in political consciousness, was inconsistent with the Party Central Committee on major principle issues, and was a clique. Forming factions, distorting views on political performance, engaging in formalism, making false reports, resisting organizational review, and engaging in superstitious activities. Xiong Xue was also accused of having a bad family tradition and being indifferent to her spouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;[&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;More than a month after the first round of inspections of the financial regulatory system, the former director of the Shenzhen Insurance Regulatory Bureau was dismissed&lt;/span>;&lt; strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 27, according to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision According to the news, Zhang Huiye, the former party secretary and director of the Shenzhen Supervision Bureau of the China Insurance Regulatory Commission, is suspected of serious violations of disciplines and laws and is currently under review and investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that from October 10 to October 12, the Party Committee of the State Administration of Financial Supervision held the 2023 Inspection Mobilization and Training Meeting. The meeting pointed out that this inspection was the first systematic inspection since the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China and the establishment of the State Administration of Financial Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The professional and technical personnel of the sixth-level post who were immoral after drinking were dismissed from their posts, and many people were punished&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hunan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision reported on November 29 that the Hunan Provincial Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition will be held in Xiangxi Prefecture on the evening of August 18, 2023 After the semi-finals of biomedicine, Tang Songbo, deputy director of the Management Committee of Xiangxi High-tech Zone, and Weng Lizhi, deputy director of Xiangxi Prefecture Science and Technology Bureau discussed and invited Li Yangbao (probationary period), director of the Provincial Torch Entrepreneurship Center, and Liu Jian (level six post), a professional and technical staff member guided by the competition organization, gathered for a meal and drinks at a restaurant in Jishou City. The expenses were paid by the competition hosting company from the conference fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dinner, Weng Lizhi contacted the Jishou East High-speed Railway Station and sent Li Yangbao, Tang Songbo, Liu Jian and other six people into the station VIP room. While waiting for the bus, Liu Jian lost his temper after drinking and repeatedly harassed two waitresses, causing a negative impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2023, Liu Jian was given a serious warning within the party (with an impact period of two years) and removed from office. Tang Songbo and Li Yangbao were given serious warnings and dismissed from office. Weng Lizhi was Serious warnings were given within the party, and others were given warnings or admonitions within the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ministry information&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;National Bureau of Statistics: Some cities and counties have not yet realized the extreme dangers of statistical fraud&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 30, 2023, the &quot;Statistical WeChat&quot; WeChat public account announced the National Bureau of Statistics&#39; 2023 special projects The No. 1 Statistical Inspection Inspection Team provided feedback on the special statistical inspection opinions to Shaanxi. The inspector found that some city and county party and government leaders in Shaanxi Province have not yet deeply understood the extreme harm of statistical fraud from a political perspective and the extreme importance and urgency of preventing and controlling statistical fraud. In some areas, they excessively pursue data rankings and are impulsive and impulsive in their political performance. Assessment pressure promotes statistical falsification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;National Health and Medical Commission: Acute respiratory diseases continue to rise, and efforts are made to open more clinics&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti; &quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 26, Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, introduced at a press conference that acute respiratory diseases in our country have continued to rise recently, and are related to a variety of The superposition of respiratory pathogens is related. All localities should strive to open more relevant clinics and treatment areas, appropriately extend service hours, and strengthen drug supply guarantees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;People&#39;s Bank of China: Continue to increase the monetary policy&#39;s preference for private small and micro enterprises&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The People&#39;s Bank of China released a report on November 27. The People&#39;s Bank of China will continue to increase the tilt of monetary policy towards private small and micro enterprises. Annual service targets for private enterprises, increasing the weight of services related to private enterprises in performance appraisals, increasing financial support for private enterprises, and promoting the reduction of comprehensive financing costs for enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Supreme People&#39;s Court issued a typical case against domestic violence, and psychological violence also belongs to domestic violence&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 25 is the &quot;International Day for the Elimination of Violence against Women&quot;. The Supreme People&#39;s Court issued a batch of anti-Violence Day on that day. Typical cases of domestic violence further clarify that psychological violence also belongs to domestic violence. In trial practice, in addition to regular verbal abuse, intimidation and other mental infringements, threats of self-harm and self-injury such as drinking pesticides and jumping off buildings are also mental infringements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A total of 2,430 hacker-related crimes have been detected since 2022&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/ span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 30, the Ministry of Public Security held a press conference. Li Tong, deputy director of the Cyber ​​Security Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security, introduced at the press conference that since 2022, public security agencies across the country have solved a total of 2,430 hacker-type criminal cases, arrested 7,092 criminal suspects, and severely cracked down on illegal seizures of train tickets, hospital registration, Social resources such as scenic spots and concert tickets, and hacker crimes that invade family and personal privacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the first ten months, more than 34,000 people were prosecuted for electronic fraud crimes, and the number of crimes involving people with higher education levels increased&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312 , SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 30, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate released the case handling work of the procuratorial organs. From January to October 2023, procuratorial organs across the country prosecuted more than 34,000 people for telecommunications and network fraud, a year-on-year increase of nearly 52%. The characteristics of criminals who are young, low-income, and low-educated are still obvious, but the crime-related crimes of those with higher education levels are on the rise. In the first three quarters of 2023, procuratorial organs nationwide prosecuted more than 4,400 people with a college degree or above (including bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree, and doctoral degree), more than 5,900 people, and more than 7,600 people among the three categories of criminals: telecommunications network fraud, trusting, and concealment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Science and Education News&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lei Jun personally donated RMB 13 to Wuhan University billion in cash, setting a national record for colleges and universities&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 29, 2023, is the 130th anniversary of Wuhan University. Lei Jun, a 1987 computer science alumnus and founder of Xiaomi Group, personally donated 1.3 billion yuan to Wuhan University, setting a new record for the largest single donation since the founding of Wuhan University. It is also the largest individual cash donation from an alumni received by universities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;[&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Beijing Municipal Education Commission: There are no mandatory requirements for homework during students’ illness&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 25, the WeChat public account of the Beijing Municipal Education Commission &quot;Capital Education&quot; According to the release, Beijing has entered a period of high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, and the number of children infected has increased. Schools do not impose strict requirements on homework for students during illness. It is not recommended to rush or make up for homework during illness. Children&#39;s health is the first priority in everything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first batch of Xiongan campuses of the four colleges and universities to be relocated have all started construction&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;] &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 28, the first batch of mobilization meetings to start construction of the Xiongan campus of the universities affiliated with ministries and commissions in Beijing were held in Xiongan New Area, marking the beginning of the mobilization of Beijing Jiaotong University, University of Science and Technology Beijing , Beijing Forestry University, China University of Geosciences (Beijing) and other four universities have all started construction on the Xiongan campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Local political situation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yunnan: Reduce conference expenses from the source, reduce conference duration and number of participants&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Yunnan Provincial Department of Finance website announced that the meeting will implement classified management and hierarchical approval. Strictly control the number, duration and number of participants of meetings. The duration of various meetings shall not exceed one day. The upper limit of expenses for the first, second, third and fourth types of meetings is 600 yuan, 500 yuan, 400 yuan and 300 yuan per person per day respectively. At the same time, it is encouraged that all units adopt the form of online meetings on the premise of meeting confidentiality and network information security requirements, and give priority to existing application systems such as internal TV telephones and e-government intranets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhejiang Lishui issues coupons for house purchases, which can be deducted up to 40,000&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; 】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 28, 2023, Lishui City, Zhejiang Province announced that it would issue housing purchase coupons valid for 60 days and with a total amount of 18 million yuan to home buyers in three phases. Promote reasonable housing consumption”. This is the first prefecture-level city in Zhejiang in recent years to issue consumer vouchers that can be deducted from home purchases. According to the rules of use, for the 42 local properties registered to participate in the event, the purchase price of a property in the urban area is more than 3 million or the purchase price of a property in the development zone is more than 1.5 million, which can be offset by 40,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Fujian: Taiwan compatriots aged 65 and above can ride urban public transportation for free&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti ;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 27, the Taiwan Affairs Office of the Fujian Provincial Committee, the Provincial Development and Reform Commission and other departments held a press conference to announce Fujian Province’s implementation of the &quot;Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council&quot; Opinions on Supporting Fujian in Exploring New Roads for Cross-Strait Integrated Development and Building Cross-Strait Integrated Development Demonstration Zones” The first batch of 15 policy measures, including free use of urban public transportation for Taiwan compatriots aged 65 and above. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sound&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mao Weiming: &quot;Even if there is a month in a foreign country, it is not as good as a lamp in my hometown.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 27, 2023, Mao Weiming, Deputy Secretary of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee and Governor of Hunan Province, visited some Hunan business enterprises in Beijing . &quot;Even if there is a month in a foreign country, it is not as good as a lamp in my hometown.&quot; Mao Weiming said that his hometown will always be a strong &quot;backing&quot; and a warm &quot;harbour&quot; for Hunan businessmen. We will uphold the concept of &quot;making Hunan businessmen more popular in Hunan&quot;, guide and support enterprises with complementary resource advantages and in line with Hunan&#39;s development needs to transfer to their hometown, and achieve mutual benefit and win-win results in the two-way journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from The Paper, Jimu News, Daily Economic News, China News Network, Caixin.com, Hunan Provincial Party Committee Supervisory Committee website, China Youth Daily, Beijing News, CCTV News, &quot;Wuhan University&quot; WeChat public account, &quot;Capital Education&quot; WeChat public account, etc.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉56项违规行为，中信银行被罚没超2.24亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:40:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The State Administration of Financial Supervision’s administrative penalty information disclosure table shows that CITIC Bank was fined 224 million yuan. Involved in 56 violations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1102&quot; height=&quot;3895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260389&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[基辛格，时代纵横者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK6BbyenF3EB9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK 6BbyenF3EB9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023 local time, the former US National Security Assistant and Secretary of State was a famous diplomat, politician and politician who profoundly influenced the development of US foreign policy and geopolitics in the 20th century. Family and scholar Henry Kissinger died at the age of 100. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger and his brother Walter&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1923, Heinz Alfred Kissinger was born in a German-Jewish family in Fürth, Bavaria, Germany. His father was a teacher and his mother was a housewife. A year later, a younger brother was added to the family, Walter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a child, Kissinger was keen on playing football and once joined the youth training of Fürth Football Club. But with Hitler coming to power in 1933, the Nazi regime&#39;s oppression of the Jewish community intensified. Because he broke into the stadium to watch games in violation of Jewish segregation regulations, Kissinger was often scolded and beaten by guards, and he was also kicked out of the team. Later, Kissinger&#39;s father was also dismissed from his teaching position without reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before everything got worse, Kissinger&#39;s family immigrated to the United States in 1938, and he later changed his name to Henry Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;627&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 10, 1971, U.S. President Richard Nixon (left) and National Security Advisor Kissinger talked in his office at the White House&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1969, Nixon appointed Kissinger as National Security Assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before entering politics, Kissinger was already a well-known international political scholar, and had served in many institutions or think tanks with a background in the US government. He served as the candidate for Nelson Rockefeller’s presidential campaign three times. foreign policy adviser, during which he sharply criticized Nixon as &quot;the most dangerous presidential candidate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after Nixon became president, the two dramatically became a tacit understanding partner. Faced with the turbulent global situation in the 1960s, Nixon gave Kissinger great room for action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 1971, Kissinger secretly flew to Beijing during his visit to Pakistan, and facilitated Nixon&#39;s visit to China in 1972 that shocked the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 25, 1972, in Beijing, US President Richard Nixon and his wife attended the dinner and took a group photo. Kissinger was on the right in the front row&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260333 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 3, 1974, in the Moscow Kremlin, during the seven-day summit, U.S. Presidents Nixon (middle), Secretary of State Kissinger (left) and Soviet leader Brezhnev (right) toast &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1972 On February 21, 2011, US President Richard Nixon arrived in Beijing and began his visit to China. On February 28, the Sino-US Joint Communique was released, announcing the normalization of relations between China and the United States. Later studies generally believed that the normalization of Sino-US relations greatly affected the Soviet Union’s diplomatic strategic considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Kissinger&#39;s promotion, shortly after Nixon&#39;s visit to China, he visited Moscow in May of that year and met with Soviet leader Brezhnev, which contributed to the &quot;Soviet-US Joint Communique&quot; and &quot;Soviet-American Joint Communique&quot;. The release of 9 documents including the Principles of Mutual Relations between the United States and the United States. In the following years, leaders of the United States and the Soviet Union had frequent exchanges and reached positive consensus on the use of offensive strategic weapons and nuclear weapons testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The improvement of relations between China, the United States and the United States and the Soviet Union directly drove the overall global situation to a positive direction. Kissinger’s diplomatic thoughts on balancing the balance of power among major powers to achieve national interests and international peace were fully reflected in this process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;January 23, 1973, Paris, France, Special Advisor to the Delegation of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam Le Duc Tho (front row, second from right) and U.S. National Security Advisor Kissinger (back row, second from left) Signing the &quot;Paris Peace Accords&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger traveled to Vietnam twice from 1965 to 1966 . During his visit, he realized that the United States &quot;neither knew how to win wars nor how to end them.&quot; In the end, the war that dragged the United States into the quagmire ended in his hands. After Nixon came to power, Kissinger conducted a series of difficult negotiations with the leaders of North and South Vietnam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The normalization of Sino-US relations has greatly promoted the easing of the situation in Indochina. In October 1972, Kissinger and Viet Cong leader Le Duc Tho achieved a decisive breakthrough in secret negotiations in Paris. Kissinger announced that &quot;peace is close at hand.&quot; Nixon&#39;s popularity surged during the presidential election. Finally, he Re-elected by overwhelming margins in 49 states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 1973, all parties signed the Paris Peace Accords. A ceasefire between North and South Vietnam, the United States withdraws all troops from Vietnam, and the North Vietnamese release all American prisoners of war. Kissinger and Le Duc Tho were also awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Le Duc Tho refused to accept the award, and Kissinger announced that he would donate the prize money to the children of American servicemen killed or missing in the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;651&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 1, 1975, Kissinger looked at the scenery at the hotel in Jerusalem&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 6, 1975, on a round-trip flight between Egypt and Israel, Kissinger was reading a newspaper when his wife Nancy patted him on the head&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot; (the Fourth Middle East War) broke out in 1973, Kissinger once again ran for mediation First line. Out of American political interests and his own blood, he tried to delay the ceasefire to give the Israeli army more time to expand its results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, Kissinger once tried to delay the United States&#39; arms and material compensation to Israel, and was committed to promoting UN Security Council Resolution 242 to achieve peace. After the Middle East oil-producing countries, led by Saudi Arabia, imposed an oil embargo on the United States, Kissinger ended up trying to mediate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1973 to 1975, Kissinger traveled between the leaders of Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Syria and Israel, carrying out &quot;shuttle diplomacy&quot; and successfully obtained the support of Egyptian President Sadat and others. trust, and promised to sell arms in exchange for Saudi Arabia lifting its oil embargo, leading to two agreements on the Sinai Peninsula issue - Israel would withdraw from parts of the Sinai and gave up its demand to end the state of war, and Egypt agreed to The opening of the Suez Canal with non-military supplies is considered one of the few diplomatic achievements of the United States during the Ford administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260340&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 11, 1995, from left: Kissinger, Princess Diana, Colin Powell and news anchor Barbara Walters attended the 41st World Cerebral Palsy Federation Association Awards Night. Princess Diana received the UCP Humanitarian Award at the gala &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was arrested during the Watergate scandal under Nixon After being forced to resign, he continued to serve as National Security Assistant and Secretary of State in President Ford&#39;s administration. But not long after the Sinai Agreement was reached, Kissinger was replaced as National Security Assistant by Brent Scowcroft in a cabinet reshuffle known as the &quot;Halloween Massacre&quot; in November 1975. . After Ford lost the 1976 presidential election, Kissinger resigned as Secretary of State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Kissinger has traveled in the three circles of politics, business and academia: he established the China Venture Capital Company and served as chairman and CEO; served as &lt;span>;Philip MacMoran&lt;/span>; ( Freeport-McMoRan); served as chairman of the National Commission on Terrorism in the United States... In addition, he has also included principals, political consultants or board members of various institutions, some of which are even controversial positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, he also released at least 7 books, including his own memoirs, political commentary, and even an observation about artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height= &quot;1367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 12, 2000, Texas Governor and Republican presidential candidate George W. Bush (left) and former U.S. Secretary of State Kissinger waved to reporters on the porch of the Governor&#39;s Mansion in Austin Regards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 10, 2017, US President Trump (right) Meeting with former US Secretary of State Kissinger at the White House &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a man with outstanding contributions and rich experience in American history As a veteran politician with extensive connections in the political and business circles, Kissinger has basically become the “mountain” that every U.S. president since Nixon has consulted or paid a visit to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, 2016, Kissinger met with President-elect Donald Trump. They discussed global affairs, and they met again the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later in an interview on August 17, 2017, Kissinger said helplessly when talking about the president who the whole world could not figure out and who often took eccentric opinions: &quot;I hope (Special) Trump) had an Augustinian moment. For St. Augustine...he behaved completely differently in his early years than he later did, but one day he was suddenly inspired and became the saint he became. Of course people don&#39;t expect the president to be like that, but You can always think about it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1985, Kissinger visited Qingping Street Market in Guangzhou&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(An Ge/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 12, 2005, in Xuchang, Henan, former US Secretary of State Kissinger came to the home of Liang Shuhua, a villager from Group 7, Xuzhuang Village, Dengzhuang Township, to experience the family life of local farmers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/01/A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, former US Secretary of State Kissinger held a meeting in New York Speaking at the annual awards dinner of the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until he entered the political arena, Kissinger He has never shown much interest in China, but after gaining an in-depth understanding of China through his work, he began to have a new understanding of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After deciding to promote the development of Sino-US relations, Kissinger carefully studied Chinese culture, history, politics and other national conditions, and paid close attention to China&#39;s political and economic development. From 1971 to 2023, Kissinger visited China more than 100 times, a record unique among Western politicians. He once said, &quot;China is the country with which I have the longest and most in-depth exchanges. China has become a very important part of my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Kissinger&#39;s death, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said, Dr. Kissinger is an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of Sino-US relations. &quot;He has long been concerned about and supported the development of Sino-US relations, and has visited China more than a hundred times, making historic contributions to promoting the normalization of Sino-US relations. The Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger&#39;s sincere feelings and important contributions to Sino-US relations. Contribution.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“电玩捕鱼”涉赌案：矛盾的时间点，反转的证词]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was banned by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau Identified as gambling. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260322&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was recognized as gambling by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Monopoly Video Game Fishing” is a game developed and operated by a game company in Beijing. In more than two years, players have recharged a total of approximately 157 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of the public security organs in Cangwu County, Guangxi, this &quot;fishing&quot; is not a game, but gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 18, 2022, the actual controllers of the gaming company, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and seven employees were arrested by the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau on suspicion of opening a casino. On October 23, 2023, the first instance verdict of the Cangwu County Court was that Zong Chao was sentenced to 6 years and 10 months in prison, Zhong Liuqing was sentenced to 5 and a half years in prison, and the remaining 7 people were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 2 years to 2 years and 11 months. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment stated that the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau, based on the clues discovered during the work, confirmed after preliminary inspection that some players of the game involved were from Cangwu County, and the reporter and three witnesses were also from Cangwu County. They The testimony confirmed that the game involved was suspected of gambling, and Cangwu County was the place where the crime was committed and had jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people who attended the trial that, coincidentally, two of the witnesses were held in the same cell as the defendant. During the first-instance trial, the defendant&#39;s statement of situation showed that both witnesses stated that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and that they had not been exposed to this game before making the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when the two witnesses were later questioned by the detention center, they overturned their statements in the description of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing refused to accept the verdict and have submitted an appeal to the Wuzhou Intermediate Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Gray areas and luck&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The persons involved, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and the start-up employees of the game company were all former colleagues of a major Internet company. In 2018, they resigned from their original units and established Beijing Sihai Interactive Entertainment Technology Co., Ltd. to jointly operate fishing games. In the second half of 2019, the game will be launched online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gameplay of the fishing game is that after users recharge RMB to obtain game gold coins, they then use the gold coins to fire fish. After successfully fishing, they win gold coins at a multiplier rate. At the same time, in the &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; mode, users can obtain &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; when fishing, and &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; can be exchanged for phone bills, physical goods, JD shopping cards, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance verdict quoted a defendant’s confession. He had an online group with Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing and others as well as lawyers to discuss whether this game would hit a legal red line. The opinion given by the lawyer is that the gameplay of this game is in a gray area. There is no law that says you can do this, and there is no law that says you can&#39;t do it this way, so you just took a chance at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of the defendants and their lawyers, the reason why this game cannot be considered gambling is that although the gold coins won by fishing are proportional to the &quot;explosion rate&quot; and &quot;multiplier&quot;, the gold coins It cannot be used to exchange RMB. The lucky beans that can be converted into RMB have their own generation mechanism, which has nothing to do with &quot;explosion rate&quot;, &quot;bet size&quot; and &quot;magnification&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The case will be heard in public on &lt;/span>; March 28, June 25, and June 29, 2023. Zong Chao&#39;s defense lawyer defended his innocence. The lawyer pointed out in court that the essence of gambling is to achieve &quot;big gains with small things.&quot; In order to ensure that the game operation does not fall into the scope of the crime of opening a casino, the game operator has a limit on the proportion of the recharge amount for the lucky beans that come with the game, and the operator has set up a blacklist to intercept players who try to &quot;compromise with small things&quot;. Outside the game. Therefore, this game cannot achieve &quot;using small to gain big&quot;, so it is not gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the court found that when players use cannons that consume more gold coins and have higher multiples when fishing, the energy bar will grow faster, and different levels of lucky beans can be produced correspondingly. There is &quot;a small way to make a big difference&quot;. It has a cash withdrawal function and is recognized as a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;&quot;A moment of negligence&quot;? Conflicts occurred at multiple points in time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:50 on January 2, 2022, local Pan Jianfeng went to the Shiqiao Town Police Station in Cangwu County to report that he had downloaded the &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; App at home. After registering with a real name, I found that this game can be recharged online, and then you can win &quot;Fu Beans&quot; by playing the game, and the &quot;Fu Beans&quot; can be exchanged for RMB and withdrawn. He told the police that he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan, so he thought it was a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, on December 20, 2021, 13 days before Pan Jianfeng reported the case, the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau had noticed this App and conducted a preliminary inspection. After verification, it was found that there were Cangwu members. 41 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cangwu County Public Security Bureau opened a case for investigation on the day Pan Jianfeng reported the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case will be heard in public from March 28, June 25 to June 29, 2023. During the trial, defense attorneys for several defendants raised questions about the close time between Pan Jianfeng’s game registration, cash withdrawal, and crime reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Game background data shows that Pan Jianfeng registered for the game at 15:15:56 on the day of the report. The screenshot of the withdrawal interface he provided showed that he withdrew the money at 15:49:17. In other words, he had just registered for the game 25 minutes before being questioned, and the time of withdrawal was only 43 seconds after being questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for Pan Jianfeng, the defendant’s defense lawyer believed that there were contradictions in the time when witnesses Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao withdrew cash from the game and were interviewed by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao started at 10:25 on January 7, 2022, 12:10 on January 7, 2022, and 10:30 on January 10, 2022. Shiqiao Police Station for questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai said when questioned that he had recharged 54 yuan in the game and withdrawn 2 yuan; Qin Jun said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan; Chen Tao also said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan. 2 yuan. All three stated in the inquiry that they could provide screenshots of the withdrawal page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the lawyer pointed out that in the screenshots provided by the three people, the withdrawal times of Wang Kai and Qin Jun were both at 21:31 on January 8, while Chen Tao made the withdrawal at 13:27 on January 10. . In other words, their withdrawal time was later than the time when they were asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the above time issue raised by the lawyer, the prosecutor issued a statement from the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This document explains that Pan Jianfeng first played games at home and reported the case to Shiqiao Police Station around 15:00 on January 2. He cashed out after an on-site operation demonstration. The police station accepted the case at 15:50. The defendant&#39;s defense lawyer also pointed out the issue with the timeline: Pan Jianfeng arrived at the police station around 3 p.m., so the game should have been registered at the police station. During the trial, the prosecution and defense debated this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation statement also pointed out that when the case investigators produced the interrogation transcripts of Wang Kai and Qin Jun, they used the version of the transcripts dated January 7 and forgot to modify the interrogation time. The actual time was January 9; production When Chen Tao took notes, he was also &quot;slip and careless&quot; and wrote down the time of the inquiry incorrectly. The correct time was from 14:30 to 15:40 on January 10. According to this explanation, Chen Tao completed the withdrawal one hour before accepting the inquiry. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reversal of witness statement&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, witnesses Qin Jun and Chen Tao were later detained at the Cangwu County Detention Center on suspicion of provocation and were detained together with the defendants Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing respectively. In a prison cell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both witnesses said that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and even signed the transcript without reading the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, Zong Chao submitted a handwritten statement by Qin Jun, describing the process of reporting the case: At the end of 2021, his friend Wang Kai from the same town called him and asked him to take someone to the Shiqiao Police Station. Play a fishing game together. He took Pan Jianfeng to the police station. Wang Kai shared the game download link with them on WeChat, and then they registered, recharged and cashed out, then sent screenshots of the relevant game to the police, and signed and left after all was completed. He said that he had not been exposed to this game beforehand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Tao is detained in the same cell as Zhong Liuqing and other three defendants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, all three defendants submitted their own handwritten explanations. One defendant said that four days before the first trial, he received a subpoena in the prison cell. Chen Tao noticed the name of the game company on it and said, &quot;I think I reported it.&quot; The defendant asked Chen Tao why he reported it. Chen Tao&#39;s answer was, &quot;I haven&#39;t played it. I was just called to the police station to sign the transcript.&quot; He also said that he had not read the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the two men’s statements were reversed in the interviews recorded by the detention center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the record on May 15, 2023, Chen Tao said that after the court session at the end of March, Zhong Liuqing came to him and asked him to write a written certificate or testify in court to prove that he went to the public security organ to report online gambling. The situation is false and does not actively reflect the facts. He didn&#39;t agree because what he said before was true. After that, Zhong Liuqing wrote a written material and asked him to sign it, proposing that as long as he agreed to testify in court and overturned his previous record at the public security organ, he could be given 50,000 yuan, 100,000 yuan or even 500,000 yuan, but he did not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qin Jun said in the conversation three days later that his statement of situation was &quot;written in a confused way&quot; and &quot;They spoke so artistically and literately, but I don&#39;t know why they were dismissed.&quot; Brainwashed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the Cangwu County Court held that the testimonies of Pan Jianfeng, Qin Jun, Wang Kai, and Chen Tao were objective and true and relevant to the case, and they were recognized. The above-mentioned description of the situation and other materials provided by the defendant are inconsistent with the facts ascertained in the case and will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Pan Jianfeng, Chen Tao, Qin Jun, and Wang Kai are all pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>