<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[贺州交警警棍砸倒电动车：不应让暴力执法伤害政府公信力丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 14:58:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of a traffic policeman using a baton to knock an electric car driver to the ground has caused intense anger on the Internet. focus on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is circulating on the Internet is a picture captured by a camera in a shop along the street. The video showed that on the road outside the door, a man in a traffic police uniform waved a stick in his hand and smashed it down hard. An electric car fell to the ground. The driver fell to the ground and hugged his legs, unable to stand up. Another video showed a man being carried on a stretcher into an ambulance, with a heavily armed police officer standing next to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This video quickly aroused public doubts about the violent law enforcement of the traffic police. On November 30, the traffic police in Hezhou, Guangxi issued a notice admitting that the incident took place in the city. They said that the traffic police were conducting traffic violations at the time. A man drove an unlicensed electric vehicle to evade inspection. The police officers used batons during the interception. The electric vehicle lost control and the driver fell to the ground and was injured. The report also stated that the police supervision department has been organized to investigate the incident, and the traffic police involved have been suspended from duty and will be dealt with seriously in accordance with the law and disciplines based on the investigation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar violent law enforcement incidents have been repeatedly exposed, and this is not the first time that violent law enforcement has caused serious personal injuries. Also this year, an auxiliary police officer in Zhuzhou, Hunan was filmed pushing a moving motorcycle multiple times. The man on the bike was pushed down a slope and injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is of course illegal to ride an unlicensed electric vehicle or motorcycle without a helmet. It is also the duty of the traffic police to investigate and deal with these illegal acts. However, the ultimate goal of investigating and punishing illegal activities is to maintain road traffic safety. Using dangerous means to intercept cyclists who commit minor violations may result in more serious consequences, which runs counter to the fundamental purpose of traffic police law enforcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these cases, although the cyclist broke the law first and may have been injured in the accident, the improper interception behavior of the police officers made this small possibility immediately become a reality. This kind of improper interception on the road may also cause more serious traffic accident risks. The injured may not only be the intercepted offender, but also the traffic police or a third party. In another video circulated on the Internet, an electric car with an illegally installed awning was driving left and right on the motorway to avoid being chased by the police. It was almost rear-ended by a car. It was a dangerous situation. In the end, the chasing traffic policeman was killed by a car on the inside lane. The car failed to brake and crashed to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Precisely because forcibly intercepting vehicles on the road may bring great risks, the traffic police road enforcement regulations formulated by the Ministry of Public Security clearly stipulate that when traffic police investigate and deal with illegal activities, they encounter motor vehicle drivers who refuse to stop. When driving, &quot;you are not allowed to stand in front of the vehicle and forcibly intercept it, or step on the vehicle pedals, put your head, arms, etc. into the vehicle cab or climb on the vehicle to force the driver to stop&quot;; except when the driver escapes and &quot;may cause damage to the vehicle&quot; Unless there is a serious threat to public safety and the life safety of others&quot;, traffic police are not allowed to drive motor vehicles to pursue. The purpose of these regulations is to regulate the law enforcement behavior of traffic police and avoid greater accident risks caused by improper law enforcement behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously there are law enforcement regulations that explicitly prohibit it, and there are many previous cases as a reference. Why do some people always &quot;continue to do it&quot;? The reason may be that the cost of violating the regulations is too low. In a similar incident, the police report did not mention any responsibility for the on-duty officer who intercepted the vehicle with a stick. Instead, the injured motorcyclist who fell to the ground was criminally detained on suspicion of obstructing official duties. In response to the Hezhou incident, the Hezhou traffic police initially said that the traffic police involved were &quot;young people who are ignorant and have a bit of a temper.&quot; The implication was that they did not think this was a big deal, but that young people were ignorant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Explained from organizational behavior, on the one hand, an organization will naturally tend to safeguard the interests of individuals in the organization in order to protect the work enthusiasm of &quot;its own people&quot; and maintain the centripetal force of the organization. On the other hand, in the current public system, it is not easy to punish a formal public official, and it requires the approval of unit leaders, organizational departments, etc. This is a cumbersome process that may require the preparation of a lot of materials. Even if subordinates are punished for violating laws and disciplines, it may have a negative impact on the work evaluation of the relevant leaders. Therefore, within the organization, there is always a tendency to turn major issues into small ones, and do not punish them if possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, protecting &quot;one&#39;s own people&quot; in this way may give the public a very bad impression and seriously damage the government&#39;s credibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to the Hezhou incident, judging from the video, the traffic policeman drew out his baton and viciously hit the electric car, almost in a manner that would kill people. This is no longer normal law enforcement, but more like It is to vent the anger in your heart. In the eyes of ordinary people, stopping illegal activities is just an excuse, but in fact it is law enforcement breaking the law and intentional harm. Hezhou Traffic Police said it has launched an investigation and will deal with it seriously based on the results of the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the incident of pushing down a motorcycle in Zhuzhou, Hunan, the auxiliary policeman who directly pushed the motorcycle and injured the rider was fired. The policeman who led the team was also given a demerit and was removed from the position of deputy squadron leader. This result was well received by netizens. Hezhou traffic police should learn from their counterparts in Zhuzhou, make handling conclusions as soon as possible and make them public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“五月天”假唱？文化市场稽查部门启动调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:24:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a social media blogger released a video expressing doubts about whether the 12 songs from the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert are true. Sing expressed doubts, and the information quickly rose to the top of a social media trending list. &quot;Mayday&quot; has not yet responded to this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the social media blogger used human voice extraction to conduct the analysis, and the result is the blogger’s unilateral judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters learned this morning (December 4) that the original video and audio of the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert have been submitted to the Shanghai Municipal Culture and Tourism Bureau Law Enforcement Team, which will review the provided audio and video content. Conduct scientific evaluation and analysis and publish the survey results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Measures for the Self-Discipline Management of Entertainers in the Performance Industry&quot; stipulates that &quot;performers are not allowed to deceive the audience by means of lip-syncing or performing during commercial performances.&quot; The &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Commercial Performances&quot; also requires that &quot;Actors shall not deceive the audience by lip-synching, and the performance organizer shall not organize actors to lip-sync. No unit or individual shall provide conditions for lip-synching. The performance organizer shall send a dedicated person to supervise the performance. Prevent the occurrence of lip-syncing behavior.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the ticket price for the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert is 355 to 1,855 yuan, and the number of attendees for the 8 concerts exceeded 360,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访国务院发研中心金研所原所长张承惠：应更好利用监管科技，避免“一放就乱，一管就死”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:43:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In 45 years, China has transformed from a small financial country to a large financial country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many financial indicators are among the best in the world. What is particularly commendable is that the scale of green loan stock ranks first in the world, and digital financial innovation has always been at the forefront of international peers. At the same time, both the bond market balance and wealth management scale rank second in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is no denying the current situation that finance is big but not strong. On its new journey from a financial power to a financial power, what leading indicators can China achieve to become a financial power? At the same time, risks always accompany the development of the financial industry. In the new process of deepening reform and further high-level opening up, how to resist the transmission of international financial risks? How to resolve local risks and avoid internal systemic risks? How can financial supervision improve efficiency in the digital era? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Financial Research Institute of the Development Research Center of the State Council. She is currently the executive director of the China Society of Modern Finance and a member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. Zhang Chenghui has been engaged in financial research for 30 years. He has participated in more than 30 major and key projects of the Development Research Center of the State Council, including the &quot;Overall Concept of Financial System Reform&quot;, and presided over dozens of projects such as &quot;Research on the Supervision, Control and Management of China&#39;s Money Market&quot;. , won many awards such as China Development Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, she said that building a financial power must meet at least five conditions, such as: financial institutions must be internationally competitive, the RMB must become a mainstream international currency, and China&#39;s financial market must be in the international financial market. They must have a voice in formulating rules. She also hopes that, with the rapid development of digitalization, technology should be better used to improve regulatory efficiency after the regulatory system is established, the regulatory framework and regulatory policies are clear. The use of modern regulatory technology can, to a certain extent, avoid the situation of &quot;if you let it go, it will lead to chaos, but if you put it under control, it will die&quot;, and better improve the efficiency of financial institutions in serving the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Financial Research Institute of the Development Research Center of the State Council, current executive director of the Modern Finance Society of China and member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f16024cc02.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1993&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f16024cc02.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;State Council Development Research Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Central Institute of Finance, executive director of the Modern Finance Society of China, and member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rectifying the financial order has laid a solid foundation for financial stability&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans -serif;&quot;>;You have been engaged in financial research at the Development Research Center of the State Council for many years. This period was a critical period for China to promote the reform and opening up of the financial industry. What&#39;s the thing that impressed you most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was transferred to the Development Research Center of the State Council in 1993. I initially studied finance in the Macroeconomic Department because there was no Established a financial research institute. Since 2003, I have served as deputy director and director of the Institute of Finance. So far, I have been engaged in research work on financial reform for thirty years. What impressed me most during this period was attending the first national financial work conference in 1997 and listening to the passionate unscripted speech of the then State Council leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;Why this meeting deep impression? &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;span>;The general background of this meeting is that after China&#39;s reform entered the fast lane in the 1980s, the original administrative controls were relaxed, but the regulatory logic and regulatory structure in line with market rules have not yet been established, which has led to financial disorder and financial risks. The three typical problems at that time were random fund-raising, random financial institutions and financial business. In terms of market access management for financial institutions and quasi-financial institutions, various financial markets such as bill markets, regional over-the-counter securities markets, and futures markets have flourished everywhere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around the core of controlling financial chaos, this meeting introduced a series of measures, focusing on rectifying and standardizing financial order, preventing and resolving financial risks. For example: the People&#39;s Bank of China reformed its own institutions; approved the establishment of the Central Financial Working Committee; canceled the control of loan limits of state-owned commercial banks; issued special treasury bonds in a targeted manner to replenish the capital of state-owned commercial banks by 270 billion yuan; replenished the capital of commercial banks; established The four major asset management companies, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The series of decisions made at this meeting are of far-reaching significance. For example, the approval of the establishment of the Financial Working Committee of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China not only shows the importance of financial work, but also strengthens the party&#39;s leadership over financial institutions. This is a big reform; the central bank&#39;s restrictions on the loan quota of commercial banks are cancelled, and the restrictions on commercial banks&#39; loan quotas are replaced. Banks implement asset-liability ratio and risk management, and the regulatory model is closer to the direction of market economy development; capital replenishment of state-owned banks and the establishment of four major asset management companies have laid the foundation for solving the problem of deterioration of the balance sheets of the four major state-owned banks. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It now appears that these measures laid a solid foundation for domestic financial stability at that time. During the outbreak of the Asian financial crisis in 1997, some Southeast Asian countries suffered heavy losses, but the domestic financial market was not directly affected, and the finance and economy continued to remain stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reports are often years ahead of reality because they are forward-looking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;China has been promoting financial reform and opening up. Financial reform has also been one of your main research directions. Among the major key projects that you have participated in or chaired by the Development Research Center of the State Council, which research reports have given you a particularly sense of accomplishment? Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;span>;The State Council’s positioning of the Development Research Center is “four characteristics”, namely forward-looking, strategic, overall, and comprehensive. Therefore, one of the characteristics of our reports is that they are forward-looking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among our many reports on financial risk prevention, capital market reform, small and medium-sized enterprise financing and green finance, the most fulfilling one was completed with my colleagues during the 1997 Asian financial crisis. Asian Financial Trends Tracking Report. At that time, the Development Research Center of the State Council selected eight Ph.D.s to set up an Asian financial trend tracking group, and I was one of the members. As an advantage, the Information Center of the Development Research Center of the State Council began to establish an information system in the 1990s. This is the first among government departments, allowing us to track overseas financial trends in real time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We work overtime every day, producing one report or even two or three reports in one or two days on average, reflecting international financial trends in a timely manner and putting forward response suggestions. These reports were promptly delivered to the prime minister or deputy prime minister in charge. These reports were later compiled into two books. This was the first time since my country&#39;s reform and opening up that China had to deal with a financial crisis originating overseas. Some of our suggestions played a good role at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second thing that gives me a sense of accomplishment is that I organized and wrote several reports on the full circulation of China&#39;s stock market in 2002, and conducted an in-depth analysis of the congenital institutional defects of the capital market, namely split shares. Calling for the advancement of equity split reform in the capital market. It was in 2005 that the State Council made the determination to promote the share-trading reform. The third is that based on the examination of international experience and in-depth research on the domestic financing guarantee industry, it was found that my country&#39;s commercial financing guarantee system is not sustainable, and it is recommended to establish a policy financing guarantee fund at the national level. This suggestion was later adopted and implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because we are forward-looking and because reform decisions require careful design, our recommendations often precede the implementation of policies by several years. In addition, I write a lot of reports, so I don’t pay much attention to the implementation of each report. &lt;strong>;Financial risk prevention needs to be considered in a specific context&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In addition to the major reform and opening up In addition to this topic, you have also participated in or chaired research on many major topics on financial risk prevention. Why is there so much focus on this aspect? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is very important to China. If financial risks cannot be controlled, all opening up and deepening reforms will be empty talk. Once financial risks detonate and systemic financial risks occur, it is a financial crisis, which will have a huge impact on a country&#39;s wealth, economy, financial order and financial markets. Risk prevention is the first concern of all regulatory authorities in the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are some dialectical relationships that need to be handled here. For example, how to properly handle the relationship between financial openness and financial risks, and how to properly handle the relationship between economic development and financial risk prevention and control. In different periods, the forms and degrees of risk are different, and the strategies and measures to deal with risks are also different. Therefore, attention to this area is a dynamic and dialectical work that needs to be considered within a specific historical context. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the first National Financial Work Conference, every government has paid great attention to the issue of financial risks and invested a lot of energy and resources in preventing and resolving financial risks. As a national think tank, the issues that the leaders of the State Council are concerned about are the focus of our research. Therefore, the prevention and resolution of financial risks has always been one of the important contents of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the 45 years of reform and opening up of the financial industry, our country has been affected by international economic crises or financial crises many times. , but there is no internal systemic financial risk. What do you think is the main reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Over the past forty years, there have definitely been local or certain industry risks. Being able to deal with local risks in a timely manner will have a positive impact on the entire industry. There has been no major impact on the financial system, which is an important achievement of China&#39;s financial supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two main reasons: First, my country has controlled the pace of opening up the financial market and opened up to the outside world in a more prudent and steady manner. When the country does not have regulatory capabilities and financial institutions are not competitive, hastily opening the market will only bring many opportunities for international financial predators and put great pressure on domestic financial stability. This is the case in some Southeast Asian countries. National history lessons. In contrast, my country&#39;s opening up to the outside world is prudent and steady. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, after the risks are discovered, the central government’s macro-control is relatively powerful and can deal with and resolve the risks in a timely and effective manner. Taking the four major state-owned commercial banks as an example, after undergoing three major steps: financial restructuring, corporate governance reform and capital market listing, state-owned banks have successfully resolved financial risks and ushered in a new stage of reform and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Better use of financial technology and regulatory technology&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed, There are still many hidden economic and financial risks, and we must persist in preventing and defusing risks. In addition to strengthening supervision, what do you think can be done more effectively? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, it must be clear that as long as you engage in finance, there will always be risks. Because the essence of finance is to allocate financial assets across regions, time, and markets. In this process, risks such as maturity mismatch and risk-return mismatch will definitely arise. The key is how to manage financial risks. Secondly, financial supervision is to prevent individual, small-scale financial risks from spreading and developing into regional risks. Sometimes regional risks are unavoidable, so it is necessary to prevent them from becoming systemic risks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the financial history of various countries around the world, there was no financial supervision at the beginning. It is precisely because of the risks that it has had a great impact on the economy and finance. Slowly, countries have begun to establish and improve financial supervision systems. What financial supervision needs to solve is how to better handle the relationship between efficiency and risk so that finance can better serve the real economy. We can neither control financial institutions in order to control risks, nor allow them to engage in various self-liberating financial innovations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the construction of a regulatory system is very important. Today, with the rapid development of digitalization, after the regulatory system is established, the regulatory framework and regulatory policies are clarified, technology should be better used to improve regulatory efficiency. The use of modern regulatory technology can, to a certain extent, avoid the situation of &quot;if you let it go, it will lead to chaos, but if you put it under control, it will die&quot;, and better improve the efficiency of financial institutions in serving the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, the Financial Regulatory Authority of Singapore established a chief technology officer. The latest establishment of my country’s State Administration of Financial Supervision includes a chief risk officer, chief prosecutor and chief lawyer, but does not have a chief technology officer. I feel a little regretful. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have a say in the formulation of international financial rules&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Since the reform and opening up, China has grown from a small financial country to a big financial country, and many of its financial indicators are among the best in the world. Which financial indicators do you think deserve special attention? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After more than 40 years of reform, opening up and financial development, my country has transformed from a weak and small country to a big financial country. The scale of our financial market, the size of financial institutions and the number of financial assets rank among the top in the world. This is something to be proud of. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, China is now the world’s largest deposit market and loan market, the world’s largest commercial banking system, the world’s second largest insurance market, the world’s second largest bond market, and the world’s second largest Wealth management market. The 2023 Top 1000 World Banks released by the British &quot;Banker&quot; magazine shows that ICBC, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Bank of China have ranked among the top four for the sixth consecutive year. Overall, China holds 32.67% of the world&#39;s first-tier capital and 27.69% of its assets. China&#39;s finance has become an important force that cannot be ignored in the international financial market. In addition, China’s financial technology is also far ahead of other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed for the first time that we should speed up the construction of a financial power. What is the most fundamental difference between a financial power and a financial power? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A few years ago, I did relevant research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that a financial power must meet at least the following five points:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, financial institutions must be internationally competitive. At present, most of the business of major domestic financial institutions is concentrated in the domestic market. The business volume in the international market is not large, and the competitiveness of profitability is relatively insufficient. For example, in the field of wealth management, domestic asset management institutions have basically no reputation among their international peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the RMB must become a mainstream international currency and be more widely accepted by the international financial market. Data released by the Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication shows that in September 2023, in the ranking of global payment currencies based on amount statistics, the RMB accounted for 3.71%. Although this proportion has set a new historical record, it is 40% more than the US dollar and 20% more than the euro. There is still a large gap in the proportion of %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, China’s financial market is influential in the international financial market. At present, the domestic commodity market and gold market have begun to have some influence in the international market, but there are still quite a few commodities that lack pricing power in the international market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, on the premise of effectively controlling risks, it can attract international capital to enter our country&#39;s capital market and capital market, serve the real economy and promote financial development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, we must have a say in formulating rules for international financial markets. For example, financial regulatory rules, ESG standards, etc. To achieve this goal, you must first do your own things well. Only by doing better than others can you have a say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed that “efforts should be made to promote high-level financial opening up” ” and “steadily expand institutional opening up in the financial sector.” What do you think are the differences between &quot;high-level openness&quot; and &quot;institutional openness&quot; compared to the past? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>; &quot;High-level opening up&quot; focuses on the market access level, opening up to foreign financial institutions including capital markets, capital markets, insurance markets, etc. Factor markets have lower entry thresholds and fewer constraints than before; institutional opening up must be based on international economic and trade rules and international financial market rules to form some institutional environments that are conducive to China&#39;s opening up to the outside world, especially high-level opening up to the outside world, and improve China’s institutional supply capacity. At the same time, the role of rule-maker is transformed from participant to rule-maker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a dialectical relationship, &quot;high-level opening to the outside world&quot; is the premise of &quot;institutional opening to the outside world&quot;, and institutional opening to the outside world is the guarantee of &quot;high-level opening to the outside world&quot;. Compared with the opening of commodity and factor markets, institutional opening is a higher level of opening and is an inevitable choice to achieve high-level opening to the outside world. Through institutional opening, we can further deepen the connotation of high-level opening up and improve the quality of opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If China wants to transform from a financial power to a financial power, what do you think it should do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;How to build a financial power is a big topic. I can&#39;t answer in a few sentences. To summarize at a high level, in one sentence, we must further deepen reform and opening up in the financial sector. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Chen Meixi also contributed to this article.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨宝璋：平生就会说个相声丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261262]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Dd34cho2HqZvGA39Sg3sgxnASTbJoXvgeQ5P3IhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;778&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Dd34cho2HqZvGA39Sg3sgxnASTbJoXvgeQ5 P3IhT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259266&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yang Baozhang (1925-2023), Henan cross talk actor&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The life of cross talk master Yang Baozhang is very similar to the script of traditional opera: he comes from a poor family and does not study hard. He often goes to Kaifeng Xiangguo Temple not far from his home to listen to cross talk, and he becomes famous. Fascinated, he finally gave up on literature and art and became a crosstalk actor. At that time, it was still the Republic of China, where storytelling, singing, juggling and fortune-telling were all commonplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Baozhang was in his teens and had no professional training. He formed a grass-roots team with several other car repairmen and hairdressers who were fond of cross talk. In 1943, Tao Xiangjiu, a famous crosstalk artist from Beijing, came to perform in Kaifeng, and Yang Baozhang officially became his apprentice. After he opened the business in 1945, he stopped going to school. He got up early and memorized the passages &quot;Geographic Map&quot;, &quot;Reporting the Names of Dishes&quot; and &quot;Eight Screens&quot; three times every day. Once the technology is over, the cultural foundation becomes thin again. There is a section of a letter written by Zhuge Liang to Cao Zhen in &quot;Eight Screens&quot;. Yang Baozhang only knew how to recite it but did not understand the meaning. He did not recognize many words in &quot;Geographic Map&quot;. He had been reading &quot;Quebei River&quot; for many years. When talking about these in his later years, Yang Baozhang, who has become a master, does not hide it. He came from a grassroots background and has never left the folk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1960s and 1970s, he could no longer talk about cross talk, so he went to the construction site and made cement. The foreman knew that he was good at jokes, and in turn advised him to save his energy during the day so that he could have the energy to talk long stories at night. . At that time, there was no stage decoration. There was a light in the barn, and there were cows and horses around. You could stand or sit in any position. If someone listened, you would open your mouth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 10 years of doing this, my performance style has become more simple and natural. Although what he talks about is all literary, such as &quot;Su Dongpo Eats Fish Three Times&quot;, &quot;Confucius Eats Yuanxiao&quot; and &quot;The Legend of Liu Luoguo&quot;, they are either historical allusions or intellectual jokes, but Yang Baozhang can always speak in a homely and homely way without leaving any trace. After the 1980s, Yang Baozhang resumed performing. In 1993, he was invited by CCTV to record 20 episodes of the stand-up comedy &quot;The Legend of Liu Luoguo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many famous crosstalk masters have passed away, and Yang Baozhang has become almost the only living fossil in the crosstalk world. In 2010, Kaifeng City held an event for Yang Baozhang&#39;s &quot;86th Birthday Celebration, 68 Years in the Arts&quot;. Yu Qian went to celebrate his birthday, and Yang Baozhang performed a piece of &quot;Ghost Story&quot;. When Yu Qian returned, he sighed: &quot;Master Yang has so many things in his belly.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On his 90th birthday, Guo Degang also went to celebrate his birthday. During his speech, he joked: &quot;I will definitely come to Mr. Yang&#39;s 90th birthday. Today I have promoted a commercial performance worth 80 million.&quot; &quot;Two years later, courtesy reciprocated, Yang Baozhang went to attend the 20th anniversary celebration of Deyun Society. When he came on stage, he threw away the &quot;baggage&quot;: &quot;In order to participate in this event of Deyun Society, I recommended a 160 million yuan. Tanghui, why? It’s the acupuncture point set by my senior brother Baolin, and I don’t dare to go there!” Hou Baolin is also a famous master of the Bao generation, and he left Hexi in 1993. Two things in one sentence made the audience laugh instantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 12, 2023, Yang Baozhang still could not escape the &quot;tang meeting&quot; and passed away. According to actor Yi Cun&#39;s recollection, Yang Baozhang lost his hearing and speech in his later years, and relied on others to take care of him for food and movement. Fortunately, his descendants did their best and Yang Baozhang died peacefully. His funeral was simple and simple, just like what he often said during his lifetime: &quot;I am an artist. I only do one thing in my life, and I know how to talk about cross talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访巴基斯坦参议院国防委员会主席穆沙希德·侯赛因·赛义德：“一带一路”为巴基斯坦打开新世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261799]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[越南申奥片，七年磨一剑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261793]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;When it comes to Vietnamese movies, we first What comes to mind may be &quot;The Taste of Green Papaya&quot; by Chen Yingxiong. The girl is gentle and supple, and her thoughts are as moist and ambiguous as the strong green in the movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The ubiquitous water in the movie is also a symbol of Vietnamese women, a surging silence and implicit lust. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/ea049b68c19f969a0219eff2dac222e6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;678&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/ea049b68c19f969a0219eff2dac222e6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260566 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the appearance of the movie &quot;Bright Ashes&quot; makes people seem to relive this style on the screen again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/bcd8c8d6de526420e2c37ceb72b44877.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;957&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/bcd8c8d6de526420e2c37ceb72b44877.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260567&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Bright Ashes&lt;/span>;&quot; was adapted from two short stories by writer Nguyen Van Thi and was completed by director Pei Shuojuan over a period of 7 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a highly acclaimed work that has been shortlisted for the Tokyo International Film Festival and is Vietnam&#39;s representative film competing for the Oscars next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film mainly revolves around three women, telling their&lt;/span>; love and hate, Forbearance and loneliness, beauty and cruelty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film begins with a wedding in a water town. The protagonists are the beautiful and gentle bride Ayan and her silent and humble husband. The men ate wine and discussed how such a taciturn man could win the heart of a beautiful woman, and their words were filled with envy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f13d3db91e874cbc78d946c6de024486.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;586&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f13d3db91e874cbc78d946c6de024486.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260571&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The camera turned and came to another couple at the banquet. They were still a silent man and a bright, chattering girl. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Then the common disappointments in love suddenly appeared on the screen: the male Atang who only cares about doing &lt;/span>; food is one of Ayan’s admirers, the goddess’ The wedding is undoubtedly the funeral of love for him. Ahou, the pretty woman beside him, fell in love with &lt;span>; him even though she knew he had someone in his heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/65c5cd9856623a5f7a1f1e70500eda98.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;920&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/65c5cd9856623a5f7a1f1e70500eda98.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260568 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For women, it is often dangerous to fall in love with someone: &quot;A man&#39;s laziness can especially be explained. A woman&#39;s laziness cannot be explained.&quot;&lt;/p span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ahou was still sinking. She tried to put her love into words and tell it to the man who was always silent, even if she would never get any feedback. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/52beb87c6234628db7d38c638a93a169.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/52beb87c6234628db7d38c638a93a169.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260570 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One night, in the endless reed swamps, Ahou became Ayan&#39;s substitute on a small boat, satisfying Atan&#39;s frustrated and frustrated desire. desire. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/936506666e56b723c1ea3819b6c038bd.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;513&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/936506666e56b723c1ea3819b6c038bd.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260569 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Soon, Ahou became pregnant. She lay on the table and let her father&#39;s whip fall on her back. But she didn&#39;t seem sad, because it meant that she could marry Atang. It’s okay not to be seen, it’s okay not to respond. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/25dc5fb830d8c949f248bf43f589f5ff.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/25dc5fb830d8c949f248bf43f589f5ff.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260578 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After hearing the news, A Tang rushed home from the fishing boat where he was working, and hurriedly married A Hou expressionlessly. Ahou is very happy. She is wearing a pure white wedding dress. The girl&#39;s clean face and flowing eyes are telling her joy and love. The boat is swaying and swaying, giving off a poetic cruelty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After marriage, Atang still rarely went home and spent most of his time at sea. The man is silent and runs away, while the woman guards an empty home for him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/7dcf1e699409c1af3f186528d1c02697.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1287&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/7dcf1e699409c1af3f186528d1c02697.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260573 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ahou gave birth to a daughter. She took care of her daughter and mother-in-law alone, silent and hardworking most of the time. Only when Atang came home, she became nagging again and kept talking about the trivial things in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b2a3084a1472ac6973678b6226891b85.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b2a3084a1472ac6973678b6226891b85.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260579 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In those lonely times, she would always shout &quot;Ayan&quot; to a myna who liked to talk dirty, and then listen to it say &quot;Fuck you&quot;. Only then would she laugh, comforting herself with a trivial malice and self-deception. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/95ceeac68af5f776e93061f43bd1d04d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/95ceeac68af5f776e93061f43bd1d04d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260576 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With those Compared with his ulterior malice, Ahou actually envied Ayan most of the time. Women&#39;s emotions are mostly like this, dense and complicated, but in the end they are still kind. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ahou actually hated herself even more. She hated that she was not Ayan and could not be loved by her husband, so she always used Ayan to please her husband. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She will ask Ayan how to make fish soup, and then make it for her husband; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/76b2fb660185b3723bb6dfe3ff73819e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;802&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/76b2fb660185b3723bb6dfe3ff73819e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Will know that her husband is pretending When the car broke down just to take a peek at A Yan, I didn’t expose him and let him see;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/12/04/9afb0556c8cf6c66b644ebcddda6c8a1.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/12/04/9afb0556c8cf6c66b644ebcddda6c8a1.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260580&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When her husband comes home, he will fill the silence with everything about Ayan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b2f7a47e4114b46609dde40209efc27d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b2f7a47e4114b46609dde40209efc27d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260581 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ayan looked indeed very happy. Although her husband is dull, the interaction between the two is full of love. She manages everything at home and prepares meals for her husband to take to work every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/e13043be3eebd5a1b7f9b2a1df7b70c6.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/e13043be3eebd5a1b7f9b2a1df7b70c6.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260575 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Only one time when my husband was eating with his co-workers, a co-worker’s words illuminated his character: Silent people are even more frightening when they explode. As a result, it became a prophecy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In an accident, Ayan&#39;s daughter unfortunately drowned. After that, the husband went to extremes: he first burned his own arms with fire, and then fell in love with burning his own house. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/eb450c4d3f4023cb345d7c5aa923f695.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/eb450c4d3f4023cb345d7c5aa923f695.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260587 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, he burned it once, and Ayan covered it once; he burned it once, and Ayan covered it again. As the fire progresses, there are fewer and fewer ashes, because there are fewer and fewer things left in the house. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/e8b57f67f4e5b1ba74879554791b8f84.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;940&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/e8b57f67f4e5b1ba74879554791b8f84.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260574 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Everyone around said, leave that madman. But Ayan just said that since her daughter&#39;s death, her husband&#39;s happiness can only be seen when the house is burning, so let him burn it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/a8df77866cf6cf1ae4382245d77c2416.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/a8df77866cf6cf1ae4382245d77c2416.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260577 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to Ahou and Ayan, there is also a crazy woman in the film. She became crazy because she was raped by a man in the village when she was 12 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Everyone sympathized with her experience, but everyone also pointed fingers at her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;More than ten years have passed, and the rapist was released after serving his sentence and returned to the village. He still eats fast and chants Buddha&#39;s name every day to repent. Somehow, the crazy woman fell in love with him and desperately wanted to marry him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b771fbc512999b22e9a768f18df0f83c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/b771fbc512999b22e9a768f18df0f83c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260588 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is it really love? maybe. Rather, the mad woman is unlovable and unloved. The only thing she could do was to mix her day and night hatred with the concept of chastity, and then transfer her sustenance to the rapist. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; In &quot;Bright Ashes,&quot; a man is selfishly and cowardly obsessed with his own pain. Atang couldn&#39;t accept A-yan marrying someone else; A-yan&#39;s husband couldn&#39;t get over the shock of his daughter&#39;s death; the rapist didn&#39;t even solemnly apologize to the crazy woman. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Women take care of the heavy housework. While swallowing all the pain in front of him,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;hiding his desires and compromising. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the end of the film, Ayan’s husband once again set the house on fire. This time, Ayan may have been too tired and never came out of the fire. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A Tang finally spoke to A Hou, but she was silent&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Perhaps at this moment she began to understand that in this land, women His destiny has already been written. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Whether it’s being raped, falling in love or making a desperate move, the endings are all the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>; Different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/06bf33b38ac8b8630cdc3bf88300de10 .gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;508&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04 /06bf33b38ac8b8630cdc3bf88300de10.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;260589&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, this dilemma is not explored further in the film. There is no value judgment in this movie, only presentation, which may also be a kind of powerlessness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Besides the story, the poetic and fresh scenes add a lot of color to the movie. The sparkling water towns at night, unique weddings and even daily life can basically satisfy outsiders. A vision of the wonders of Vietnam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Generally speaking, this is not a hearty movie. There is basically no outlet for women’s pain and desires. They can only borrow the mouth of the myna when no one is around. Own. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽芜湖一医院违规使用医保金，官方通报：涉事护士长已被停职检查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 11:02:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Microsoft Yahei;&quot;>;About Wuhu Report on the illegal use of medical insurance funds by the Municipal Second People&#39;s Hospital&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitate the Song Dynasty, imitate the Song Dynasty_GB2312; &quot;>;On November 30, 2023, online news about Wuhu Second People&#39;s Hospital aroused social concern. The Wuhu Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government attached great importance to it and established a joint investigation team headed by the person in charge of the municipal government. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitate Song Dynasty, imitate Song Dynasty_GB2312;&quot;>;Yang Moumou in&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Fang Song, Fang Song_GB2312;&quot;>;Admitted from March 19 to July 12, 2022 due to spontaneous cerebral hemorrhage, chronic renal failure (uremic stage), hypertension level 3 (very high risk) and other diseases&lt;/ span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitate Song Dynasty, imitate Song Dynasty_GB2312;&quot;>;Enter Wuhu Second People&#39;s Hospital&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: imitation Song, imitation Song_GB2312;&quot;>;Inpatient treatment in the Department of Critical Care Medicine&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitation Song, imitation Song_GB2312;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitation Song, imitation Song_GB2312;&quot;>;Transferred to the Second Affiliated Hospital of Wannan Medical College on July 12, 2022, October 14, 2022 He died after ineffective treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitation Song Dynasty, imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312;&quot;>;On July 18, 2023, Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau received a request from the Provincial Bureau The report handed over to Yang Moumou revealed that Wuhu Second People&#39;s Hospital illegally and illegally used medical insurance funds through fabrication and exchanging diagnosis and treatment services while his father was hospitalized for cerebral hemorrhage. Under the guidance of the Anhui Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau, and on the basis of good data screening and analysis, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau and the Anhui Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau formed a provincial and municipal joint inspection team of more than 20 people to station in the hospital on August 8 and investigate the reporter’s father. Comprehensive verification of hospital charges and medical insurance reimbursement during hospitalization. Through medical record verification, on-site questioning and data comparison, it was verified that 10 of the 15 issues involved in the report were basically true. After investigation, the hospital had problems such as over-diagnosis and treatment, over-examination, over-prescription of medicines, repeated charges, fraudulent charges, and excessive charges, involving illegal medical expenses of 218,200 yuan, of which 187,000 yuan was illegally used of medical insurance funds. In order to maintain the safety of the medical insurance fund and protect the legitimate rights and interests of patients, according to the medical insurance service agreement for designated medical institutions signed between the hospital and the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Department, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau first handled the matter in accordance with the agreement: First, the medical insurance fund used in violation of regulations was recovered in full , and a penalty of 56,074.41 yuan was deducted at the maximum rate of 30%; second, the relevant person in charge of the hospital was interviewed and ordered to make immediate rectifications; third, the case was handed over to the public security and health departments for further verification and processing. At present, all the above treatment measures have been completed. At the same time, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau has initiated administrative penalty procedures in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Supervision and Management of the Use of Medical Security Funds&quot;. While verifying the reported issues, the provincial and municipal joint inspection teams drew inferences from one example and conducted a comprehensive extended inspection of the hospital&#39;s use of medical insurance funds from April 1, 2022 to May 31, 2023, which is currently being further verified. On September 25, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau, in accordance with the &quot;Implementation Rules for Handling Reporting Clues in the Supervision and Management of Anhui Medical Security Fund (Trial)&quot;, gave written feedback on the verification and handling to the whistleblower in the form of a supervision notice. In accordance with the &quot;Measures for Reporting Rewards for Illegal Use of Medical Security Funds in Anhui Province&quot;, the whistleblower was given a reporting reward of RMB 5,364.04. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: imitate the Song Dynasty, imitate the Song Dynasty_GB2312;&quot;>;At present, the Wuhu Second People&#39;s Hospital has investigated the head nurse involved. The director of the Department of Critical Care Medicine, who has management responsibilities, will be given a warning and the director of the hospital&#39;s Medical Insurance Office, who has supervisory responsibilities, will be given a warning and his position will be adjusted. The Municipal Joint Investigation Team is further investigating and verifying the matters involved in the report, and all verified issues will be dealt with seriously in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[灵魂画手列宾和他的模特托尔斯泰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261787]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/kuO3l02pZo5rPXz14sZopTogRsfBXxcXhNVfPB5R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;672&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/kuO3l02pZo5rPXz14sZopTogRsfBXx cXhNVfPB5R. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rebin Self-portrait, oil on canvas, Ilya Yefimovich Repin Repin, 1894, collection: State Leo Tolstoy Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Today&#39;s youth are willing to learn about Repin and Tolstoy Is it Thai?&quot; Chen Danqing wrote in the preface to the special exhibition &quot;Tolstoy in Repin&#39;s Works&quot; at the Muxin Art Museum, &quot;The characters painted by the former each constitute an outstanding literary narrative (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is why Western Europe does not agree with him&lt;/span>;), Tolstoy&#39;s pen always brings out moving pictures (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When Flaubert read &quot;War and Peace&quot;, he admired: painter, painter, first-class painter&lt;/span>;). Throughout the 19th century, old Russian literature and painting gradually entered the golden age. Tolstoy to Repin is the intersection of literature and painting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a &quot;long-planned&quot; exhibition. The coordination and communication work alone lasted more than four years, with many gaps in between. After an epidemic, these precious works were finally officially unveiled on November 11, 2023 in Wuzhen, a water town in the south of the Yangtze River. In order to borrow the exhibition, Chen Danqing contacted the Moscow State Leo Tolstoy Museum in 2018. In a letter to the director, he wrote: At my age, I have no chance to meet Tolstoy himself, but When I write to you now, I feel like I am writing to Tolstoy...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/29/rIqziyHN4h8Rx2pAZxCBw7YjwpIED9AfqFGoOHPM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/rIqziyHN4h8Rx2pAZxCBw7YjwpIED9Afq FGoOHPM .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Tolstoy in the Plowed Field&quot; (copied from Repin&#39;s original work), published Oil painting, Andreev Vladimir Ivanovich, 1887, collection: State Leo Tolstoy Museum&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When Repin met Lev&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Danqing said that Mu Xin keeps three or five pictures of world literary figures on his desk all year round, including Tuo Weng. Mu Xin was sincerely convinced of Russian literature and Tolstoy. He once said enviously: Look, that big bearded book is densely packed with literature. But as a painter, Mu Xin looked down on Russian paintings, including Repin. &quot;His paintings are deeply hidden in the world of Fan Kuan and Ni Zan, and he was impatient with the cumbersomeness and complexity of Russian paintings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;But for me This is another kind of experience. I started reading Tolstoy and copying Repin when I was 13 years old. I never imagined that one day I would be able to see their original works and invite their original works to Wuzhen to share them with everyone. For me Said, this is a very special exhibition.&quot; Chen Danqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For generations of Chinese readers, the name Leo Tolstoy carries considerable weight and carries a lot of imagination. He is a &quot;monster in the history of world literature.&quot; In the minds of many people, Tolstoy looks like a tall and tall man, including Repin. When Repin saw Tolstoy for the first time in 1880 in the Bolshoi Alley in Moscow, he was startled and realized that he had been deceived by the pictures and portraits he had seen in the past. He always thought that Tolstoy was a tall noble count, but the Tolstoy in front of him looked like a weirdo and preacher, short and stocky, but with a huge head! He has a beautiful gray beard and wears a long black dress. Repin, who was proficient in painting, soon realized that it was this huge head that made Tolstoy appear tall and burly in portraits - people would judge his height from the usual head-to-body ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rebin also played with the same optical illusion. His Tolstoy still gives people the impression of being tall and towering, coupled with the deep, ascetic expression on his face , to create a sense of moral loftiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tolstoy left a deep impression on Repin when they met for the first time. Repin later recalled the situation when they met: Tolstoy said excitedly like a speech throughout the whole process. What are you talking about, denouncing the tragedy of injustice in life and people&#39;s consistent indifference. This strange eccentric was also a staunch preacher. &quot;He spoke in a deep, sincere voice... He was excited about something and was in a bad mood. There was a sad tone in his voice. Under the formidable thick eyebrows, there was a serious and penitent expression. Eyes flashing green.&quot; The writer&#39;s strong personality and extremely radical remarks made Repin feel fresh and creepy, &quot;as if we were on the eve of the final judgment.&quot; When he went home that night, he had insomnia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Q2Uhm806kb5oJ7cXTOAtYV5hLNEMcpTyuiDnybzH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;691&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Q2Uhm806kb5oJ7cXTOAtYV5hLNEMcpTyuiDnybzH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259998&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tolstoy and Repin sitting in armchairs in the hall of Yasnaya Polyana House, photo, Sofia Andreyevna Tolstoy , 1908, Collection: State Leo Tolstoy Museum&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Count who is keen on plowing fields&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Curator Wo from the Moscow State Leo Tolstoy Museum Volosevich Olesia said that when Repin and Tolstoy first met, Tolstoy was nearly 50 years old and Repin was only 35 years old. The achievements can basically be equated with Tolstoy&#39;s achievements in literature, but in the first 10 years of their acquaintance, Repin looked up to Tolstoy as if he were looking up to God. Repin once said: Everything Tolstoy said should be engraved in gold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years after Repin met Tolstoy, he got the opportunity to paint Tolstoy. In 1891, when Repin came to the Polyana Manor where Tolstoy lived, he saw that Tolstoy had become a complete civilian. This count, one of the best in the province, no longer wore formal clothes. He was wearing a black shorts and trousers made of rough and worn fabric. He wore a badly worn white skullcap on his head and wore slippers on his bare feet. But Repin found his appearance even more awe-inspiring than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tolstoy did not like his private life to be disturbed, nor did he like to have his portrait painted, except for Repin, because Repin was a good friend of his eldest daughter Tatiana. Tatiana herself was an artist, loved painting, and was deeply influenced by Repin. They maintained frank correspondence and friendship for a long time. Tolstoy tolerated Repin painting from his family estate. At first, it was entirely to give face to his beloved daughter, but later, Repin won his approval. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of this recognition that Repin was able to contribute an image of Tolstoy other than a literary giant that the world has never seen before: a man who skillfully used a sword and a lasso to drive away the horse gangs. Widow farmer plowing fields. Farm work was Tolstoy&#39;s best entertainment and relaxation - it is said that every time Tolstoy returned to the dining table after farm work, the mud on his legs and the smell of horse manure on his body made the whole family secretly complain, and his wife Sofia would She complained that he ruined her fine carpet and had to open the windows to ventilate the smell so that it would not affect the family&#39;s meal. While Repin was sketching for him, he clearly noticed that the passing farmers and village women expressed puzzlement and sarcastic smiles about the count&#39;s plowing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rebin asked to try plowing. He soon lost the battle. His painter&#39;s hands were unable to cope with the heavy farm work. Repin was very diligent and worked almost all the time at Polyana Manor. He never thought that he was a genius and believed that everything he did was based on hard work. &quot;He didn&#39;t want to waste a minute and was working every moment. He said that I had such a great opportunity and was so close to Tolstoy that I should spend every minute portraying the image of this master.&quot; Lecia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/FZCTmHWphh1kB6RCDH0OQOH6MhhcubbYYICfaSBf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;747&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/FZCTmHWphh1kB6RCDH0OQOH6MhhcubbYYICfaSBf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Special exhibition &quot;Tolstoy in Repin&#39;s Works&quot; at Muxin Art Museum, handwritten letters from Tolstoy and Repin&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bathing together and praying together&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It was this kind of personal companionship that allowed Repin to draw Thor working in the fields. Tolstoy, Tolstoy writing in his study, Tolstoy with his family, Tolstoy listening to music, Tolstoy participating in the census, Tolstoy with the poor , Tolstoy in prayer... What is particularly precious is that Tolstoy usually did not let anyone see him praying alone in the forest, but Repin captured this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tolstoy allowed Repin to walk two miles with him to take a bath in a very cold river. As soon as he walked out of the courtyard, Tolstoy would take off his old homemade slippers and walk very fast with bare feet. The branches and gravel on the path could not help his calloused feet. Repin had to hurry up and walk slowly. Follow his footsteps. After marching for two miles, they were already sweating profusely when they reached the river. Repin suggested sitting for a quarter of an hour to sweat, and immediately jumping into the ice water would cause you to catch a cold. But Tolstoy had quickly stripped off his clothes and jumped into the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is all prejudice, nothing will happen.&quot; Towen said as he stuck his huge head out of the ice water. Before Repin finished sweating, Tolstoy had already taken a shower, put on his clothes, picked up a basket and went to pick mushrooms. His figure disappearing into the forest left an extraordinary impression on Repin: &quot;He looked like a homeless man carrying a basket in the woods, but also had the air of a soldier&quot; - Repin wrote in his later memoirs . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time he was in the woods, Tolstoy asked a person to step away for a while. He told Repin that he would stand alone in the deep forest and pray. This kind of monk-like spiritual practice would often pass by without even realizing it. Finally, Repin plucked up the courage and asked if he could hide behind the bushes and sketch his long prayers. He was prepared to be flatly rejected. But Tolstoy said kindly: &quot;Ah, there is nothing immoral about this. And when it comes to using me for painting, I am now like a girl who has lost her virginity and shame. I will not refuse anyone who comes. That&#39;s the thing, no.&quot; Relationship! Paint as long as you need it.&quot; By this point, Repin had completely won Tolstoy&#39;s trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the exhibition hall, you can see this painting of Tolstoy in prayer. From the initial sketch to the final oil painting, Repin painted it for a full 10 years. Tolstoy in the painting is as beautiful as Wearing a white robe, barefoot, with his hands in his belt, his expression was solemn and solemn like an ascetic monk. In his pocket, there was a thick book with a red cover. It was unclear whether it was the Bible or not. Tolstoy firmly believed that believers should have real communication with God on a regular basis instead of being rigid in rituals. He denied the superficial rituals of the Orthodox Church. When Repin was finally able to exhibit this painting &quot;Tolstoy Praying&quot; in 1906, Tolstoy was expelled from the religious committee by the Orthodox Church because his views were not in line with the teachings. People who came to the exhibition and young people Students laid flowers around the portrait of Tolstoy who was praying alone, silently expressing their support for Tolstoy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Y2J1xeElcFjOqQOcDaBbynytPBvfRbV6kPwze542.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Y2J1xeElcFjOqQOcDaBbynytPBvfRbV6kPwze542.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Tolstoy on the Other Side of Life&quot;, oil on canvas, Repin, 1912, collection: State Leo Tolstoy Museum&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;He Drawing Tolstoy after his death&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Rebin played an important role in promoting Tolstoy’s image to the world. It is precisely because of him that Tolstoy’s appearance appeared in Russia He became a well-known icon in many daily necessities: calendars, covers, prints, and even chocolate wrappers... Tolstoy was initially suspicious of the large-scale dissemination of his portrait, and especially disapproved of exposing himself plowing the fields, but Finally he gave in. He said to Repin: I respect your opinion, after all, you are a great painter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s interesting is that Repin wrote many times in his memoirs how contagious Tolstoy’s smile was and how high-spirited and happy he was when galloping on his horse. But in his writing, There is no portrait of Tolstoy with a smile. He always has a serious, staring, introspective and profound face. It seems that this is the face of Tolstoy&#39;s spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1907, Repin once again returned to Polyana Manor and met Tolstoy in his twilight years. This year Tuo Weng is 79 years old and can still ride a horse and run wildly. Repin once again painted him. This important portrait, completed in 1909, almost freezes for us the last appearance of Tolstoy during his lifetime. He was sitting in a pink armchair. His beard and hair were white, his face was majestic, simple and solemn, his eyes were distant and almost transparent, and he seemed to have seen things that mortals could not see. Repin did not draw the piano next to Tolstoy, nor did he draw the person playing the piano. His Tolstoy may be listening to music, or he may just be immersed in his own world through music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is how Repin described Tolstoy&#39;s appearance in the last years of his life: &quot;looks like a Scythian chief&quot;, &quot;an unshakable look - a living statue of the Stone Age&quot;, &quot;How strange! High cheekbones, a rough nose chopped by an ax and a chisel, a long unkempt beard, big ears...the eyebrows on the eyes are like carapace, the appearance is majestic and terrifying, majestic. However, this chief and his followers They have long since destroyed any tools for the promotion of violence, and their arms are only the docile belief in defending a peaceful life and a free spirit.&quot; Lev Nikolayevich (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tolstoy&lt;/span>;) himself showed with his own personality and complexion that the spirit has triumphed over the selfish desires of life. His eyes shine with the bright light of this victory.&quot; &quot;He understands everything and forgives everything. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this period, Tolstoy, with his selfless love for the poor and his thoughts on social injustice, was preparing for the liberation of the serfs, dispersing his family wealth and finally running away. Repin felt that it was precisely because of his long-term communication with God that this old man, who was once full of frightening passion, became calm in the last stage of his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have to pay attention to these two paintings, this portrait (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Tolstoy sitting in a pink armchair&quot; &quot;&lt;/span>;) was painted by Repin a year before Tolstoy&#39;s death. After Tolstoy&#39;s death, he painted another ( ;&quot;>;&quot;Tolstoy on the Other Side of Life&quot;&lt;/span>;), Tolstoy is in heaven, Tolstoy went to see God.&quot; Chen Danqing pointed to the two most eye-catching masterpieces in the exhibition hall, and Between these two masterpieces hangs Repin&#39;s self-portrait. &quot;In this exhibition hall, when you stare at Repin, please note that more than a hundred years ago, this painter was staring at the great Tolstoy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two paintings are far apart in the exhibition hall, on the left The pink armchair, corresponding to the pink flowers on the right, Tolstoy stood in the pink glow, standing with his hands down, as if he had confessed everything to God and the world, the light of heaven reflected on his face, a picture The face is not human, it is old, but it is new again. Among all Tolstoy&#39;s paintings by Repin, there has never been one with so many dazzling bright colors. Tolstoy stared at the sky in the brightness and once again saw things that we cannot see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sketch, sketch, sketch repeatedly, and then create oil paintings based on the sketch. Before that, this was Repin&#39;s path to realist painting. A series of small drafts and sketches about Tolstoy in Polyana cross-corroborated this faithful path. This is also the path of Russian painting and Russian literature. However, there is no evidence that Tolstoy posed for the portrait &quot;Tolstoy on the Other Side of Life&quot; during his lifetime. The realist master Repin lost his model after his death, but in the end he painted the appearance of Tolstoy&#39;s soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆检察机关依法对焦小平涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261795]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 10:07:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate today (4th) that the former Party Committee Standing Committee and Deputy Commander of the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps The case of Jiao Xiaoping, former deputy general manager of China New Construction Group Corporation, suspected of accepting bribes, was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the Fifth Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate. Recently, the Fifth Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chongqing Municipal Fifth Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ notified the defendant Jiao Xiaoping of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Jiao Xiaoping, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecutor&#39;s office charged that the defendant Jiao Xiaoping used his position as deputy director-level secretary in the Office of the Minister of the General Office of the Ministry of Finance, director-level cadre of the Fund Statistics Division of the International Department of the Ministry of Finance, deputy director and director of the China Clean Development Mechanism Fund Management Center, Ministry of Finance With the convenience of the director of the Government and Social Capital Cooperation Center, as well as the convenient conditions created by his authority and status, he seeks benefits for others and illegally accepts property from others, and the amount is particularly huge. He should be held criminally responsible for the crime of accepting bribes according to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[短剧整治众生相：编剧改稿，出海加速，女演员不担心擦边了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;December 2, 2023. The shooting scene in front of a hotel in Hengdian, the plot is The actor is slapping the actress. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/c85aacdc01.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/c85aacdc01.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 2, 2023. The filming scene at the entrance of a hotel in Hengdian showed a male actor slapping an actress. Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Mingshe&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Notice - when the news of the rectification of micro-short dramas came, freelance screenwriter Deng Zhuye had just returned to Dali from a visit to Hengdian. She received a reminder from the creator&#39;s WeChat group. Realize the seriousness of the problem: you cannot be careless and must take it seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experiencing the critical moment of this industry, while she was adjusting the script urgently, she could still feel that the entire short drama market was still booming. &quot;Everything is lacking, and the producers keep asking me to recommend writers.&quot; Deng Zhuye said that the country&#39;s introduction of governance measures shows that the market size of short dramas has begun to receive attention from the outside world. &quot;If it can be regulated in the future, it can develop for a long time, which is a good thing.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 15, 2023, the China Online Audiovisual Program Service Association published an article stating that the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television will once again launch a month-long special rectification of online micro-short dramas. This series of rectifications has exposed a secret but flourishing cultural industry to public view: in 2021, the number of micro-short dramas registered throughout the year was 398, and in 2022 the number was close to 2,800, an increase of 600%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special rectification has pressed the pause button on the chaotic and barbaric situation, but the entire industry is still in the stage of rapid development of &quot;go big and go fast&quot;. While producers are adjusting scripts and standardizing content, some big directors, big actors and big companies are also actively participating in the short drama industry, and the pace of entering overseas sinking markets is also advancing rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Shady maids&quot; are not allowed&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, the competent authorities have carried out multiple rounds of rectification. According to media reports, starting from late November 2022, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television will use a concentrated period of three months to organize and carry out special rectification work on online micro-short dramas. As of February 28, 2023, a total of pornographic, vulgar, bloody, violent, and low-style dramas have been offline. There are more than 25,300 micro-short dramas with content such as aesthetics, vulgarity, etc., &quot;forming a deterrent effect and effectively curbing the barbaric growth of online micro-short dramas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the short drama industry has ushered in another wave of rectification. On November 16, Douyin announced that it had recently removed 119 illegal micro-short dramas in its mini-programs, and dealt with 1,188 Douyin accounts that illegally promoted micro-short dramas. On November 18, WeChat had removed illegal micro-short dramas from its mini-programs. There were 114 short plays, and 163 mini-program accounts were dealt with for publishing micro-short plays in serious violation of regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Those themes that are more sensitive are definitely subject to great restrictions, such as time travel and extreme revenge.&quot; Lu Liwen&#39;s company is located in Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province, and she has also stepped into this trend and started making short plays. She is a screenwriter. , because the company&#39;s business has developed too fast, the transformation is responsible for &quot;receiving the script&quot;. The country has introduced new policies that have a direct impact on its business. For example, she said that popular &quot;story synopses&quot; such as &quot;The Dark Maid&quot; will no longer be allowed. &quot;Adjustments should be made according to the requirements of radio and television. It is not so easy to publish a story that is too old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She told Southern Weekend reporters that the short dramas on the market are basically the same and not particularly eye-catching. A story that shines before your eyes, &quot;bound in a system.&quot; The themes of short plays mainly focus on several categories such as boss, romance, and son-in-law. Lu Liwen said that due to market and increasingly strict regulatory considerations, people generally do not dare to make new attempts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the short drama market, which is already highly homogeneous, has become more crowded with themes. In order to avoid this problem, they will cast a wide net and select the best among the same types of themes. &quot; If we can accept 100 books, we will basically sign about 10 with the same theme, and then we will not accept any more.&quot; Lu Liwen said that if the project is major, she will also go with the team to modify the lines according to the scene. Temporary changes to the play to make it more realistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(The rectification) mainly targets vulgar content such as bloody violence and pornography.&quot; Mr. Huang is a producer of a film and television company in Zhejiang. He is known as &quot;Brother Hua&quot; in the circle. He is stationed in Hengdian all year round to film with the team. . He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that the rise of short dramas has a certain relationship with the epidemic. The impact of the epidemic on the traditional film and television industry is well known, and the past few years have been a period of rapid development of short video platforms, and the short drama genre was born. During this period, there was no clear requirement for registration when shooting vertical screen short dramas, so all kinds of dramas with exaggerated and uninformed plots became chaotic and expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called the short drama market during this period the first stage of barbaric growth. &quot;I&#39;m telling you now clearly what can and cannot be photographed.&quot; Hua Ge said that in fact, national supervision has never been interrupted, and his company&#39;s business lines have also been adjusted. In his view, short plays, like movies, TV series, and &quot;online movies&quot;, are a cultural product designed to meet the spiritual needs of the audience. The introduction of policies to standardize development will help improve the production level and &quot;clear out those Low quality stuff”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the barbaric growth in the barbaric period will reach its final climax in November 2023. On November 16, the paid mini-series &quot;Black Lotus&#39;s Advancement Manual&quot; was launched. According to media reports, the paid amount reached 20 million yuan within 24 hours of its launch, and its ability to attract money is staggering. This micro-short drama with the theme of revenge of a concubine has a fast pace and many twists and turns. It is regarded as a combination of &quot;The Legend of Zhen Huan&quot; and &quot;Story of Yanxi Palace&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, less than a week after its launch, the show was removed from the shelves by multiple platforms for &quot;exaggerating the bad values ​​of extreme revenge and using violence to counter violence&quot; and &quot;confused the concepts of right and wrong.&quot; Around this time, a new round of special rectification was unveiled, and the short drama market bid farewell to its first stage of rapid growth, which was barbaric and disorderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The filming scene of a short play in Hengdian. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/ 03/d2d23e078a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/d2d23e078a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The filming scene of a short drama in Hengdian. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;You can kneel when you get married, but not housekeepers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The SARFT’s rectification work on online micro-short dramas involves seven aspects, including accelerating the formulation of &quot;Internet micro-short dramas&quot; &quot;Short Drama Creation, Production and Content Review Rules&quot;, and micro-short dramas containing pornographic and vulgar content, bloody violence, low style, vulgar aesthetics, etc. will be offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Squatting in the WeChat group all day long, Deng Zhuye constantly asked for advice from his predecessors to understand the spirit of the document, &quot;For example, the notice said not to kneel down at all times, which is promoting feudal ideology.&quot; So, what kind of kneeling is reasonable? A novice screenwriter raised this question in the group. A mature screenwriter who has been in the industry for two or three years analyzed that paying homage to the dead and ancestors, as well as the marriage plot of costume dramas, are all legitimate needs for kneeling. &quot;However, in the Ba Zong drama, the eldest young master asked the housekeeper to kneel down, which is obviously not allowed.&quot; Deng Zhuye explained that the policy is not one-size-fits-all and needs to be reasonably arranged according to the plot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rectification work mainly focuses on the content. If you understand the spirit of the policy, it is not difficult to comply with the regulations. &quot;I stayed up all night and kept revising the script.&quot; After repeated self-examination and self-correction, Deng Zhuye deleted all the money involved in his script or changed it to imaginary numbers to eliminate the possibility of &quot;showing off wealth.&quot; She said that the producer is currently only requesting changes to the draft, and has not rejected the draft or reduced the supply due to reduced demand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Zhuye is a fan of Yu Hua and Mo Yan. At the same time, she maintains the habit of reading Western classics. She often reads &quot;La Traviata&quot; and &quot;Anna Karenina&quot;. She loves literature and writing. I hope to write my own serious literature in the future. But now, she had to follow the production company&#39;s revisions and push herself to move forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a period of observation, in the view of 24-year-old &quot;Hengdiao&quot; actor Xing Jialin, the industry rectification is &quot;good news&quot; for herself, &quot;at least the requirements for &#39;bordering&#39; are much less.&quot; The so-called borderline refers to a kind of soft pornography, which is a vague area between platform bans and non-bans. In order to attract people&#39;s attention, some directors will set up some nudity scenes. Relatively speaking, the salary of side actors will be much higher than that of regular actors. &quot;If you don&#39;t do side work, it will be 300 yuan a day. If you do side work, it will be 700 to 800 yuan a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The crew once gave Xing Jialin a low-cut sling to play a female prisoner. Sometimes, intimate scenes will be added temporarily. She believed that these scenes were just for the sake of edging and had nothing to do with the needs of the plot, so she instinctively resisted. &quot;Actually, the scale of the scene is not too big, and the intimate scenes are also performed in different places, but I just feel disgusted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xing Jialin has a background in acting, so she will figure out how to improve her acting skills. However, when it comes to short play sets, it’s often a one-step process, and there’s no time for the actors to memorize their lines. “Just give a rough idea on the spot.” &quot;Micro-expressions and movement details are all cut off.&quot; She said that in one scene, she needs to push the heroine into the water with another character. The normal operation should be that the two people would make eye contact to show their insidiousness and intentions. Ghost fetus, on the set of the short play, these are not needed at all, the director asked to push it directly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xing Jialin receives an average of six or seven short plays every month, and the filming is often completed before she even remembers the title of the play. The busiest time was from 9 a.m. to 6 a.m. the next day. In order to keep up with the schedule, the director asked her not to take off her makeup, so she wore her makeup for three days in the stuffy studio, &quot;shooting right after waking up.&quot; Xing Jialin had previously mainly participated in horizontal-screen film and television dramas, and had roles with lines in two major productions. However, because of her starring role in &quot;Collapse of the House&quot;, both of them could not be broadcast later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry rectification has not stopped the operation of this assembly line. However, Xing Jialin no longer has to worry about whether to wear suspenders or not, and has doubts about her acting career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On December 1, 2023, extras rested on the set of the short drama crew. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/2ad3578e64.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/03/2ad3578e64.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 1, 2023 Extras take a break on the set of the skit crew. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Foreigners are also very popular”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past half month, the number of manufacturers who have come to inquire about the overseas business of short dramas has suddenly increased. Zhu Haicong realized that the short drama market has reached a new node. &quot;In the past, it was mainly the leading companies that were producing (overseas short plays), but now some small and medium-sized manufacturers are also interested.&quot; He is the manager of a company in Shenzhen that specializes in producing overseas short plays. His experience in just over half a year has made him He couldn&#39;t help feeling that the short drama market was really changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The export of short plays overseas has become a trend, and industry regulation is intensifying the development of this trend. &quot;The rectification is the direct reason, mainly because the domestic production volume is too high.&quot; Zhu Haicong told Southern Weekend reporters that their company originally mainly undertook the promotion business of domestic brands in overseas markets, and had many shooting resources in Europe and the United States. About half a year ago, companies began to come to me, wanting to film short dramas adapted from online articles. After some market research, their company determined that this was indeed an outlet, and they naturally expanded their business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local shooting, a local crew was assembled, and after filming was completed, the crew was disbanded on the spot. Because of years of resource accumulation, Zhu Haicong&#39;s company quickly solved the problem of the shooting team. The core problem was the cultural differences between East and West. &quot;Essentially, short plays are a kind of cultural export, and foreign directors were not very understanding at first.&quot; He recalled that the first short play undertaken by the company told the story of a takeaway boy&#39;s counterattack: The boy discovered that a girl A friend had an affair with a rich second-generation man and was humiliated by him. However, he quickly counterattacked and slapped the &quot;bad couple&quot; in the face. But for such a simple plot, the director couldn&#39;t convey the emotions fully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s not because the director has no skills, it’s probably because his skills are too high.” He explained that in order to get the feeling of satisfaction after the counterattack, he needed to give many close-ups of the actor’s eyes and expressions when he was being humiliated. , but the foreign director used a lot of medium shots and long shots. &quot;If the camera is not moved properly, the violent conflict cannot be expressed.&quot; Zhu Haicong had to change directors and cinematographers to achieve the effect he was satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are still strong emotional similarities between Eastern and Western audiences. &quot;Some localization will be done, but the core is the same.&quot; Zhu Haicong said that the Chinese can understand the setting of the delivery boy at a glance, but in North America and Europe, there are not many full-time delivery boys. In comparison, In other words, the story shell of werewolves and vampires is naturally easy for foreigners to understand. However, no matter which type of setting, the core of the story is the boss, revenge, and &quot;foreigners are also very good&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s very strange and outrageous, but it&#39;s also very exciting. I want to know how the story will develop next.&quot; Zhu Haicong said that currently short dramas from China have occupied a place in the Western cultural consumer market. However, the manufacturers that have achieved success are all major companies that have been exporting online content overseas for many years, because the cost of filming short dramas overseas is much higher than in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that in China, two to three hundred thousand yuan can be used to shoot a 100-episode short drama, but in the North American market, the cost of manpower, material resources and venue rental are much higher than in China. The cost of a short play is converted into RMB, which is at least 1 million yuan. This figure is the cost line after the number of filming reaches at least seven or eight, and the cost line is evenly divided, plus operations and promotion, it is at least 10 million yuan or more. Only with the project size can we consider going overseas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He noticed that more and more short drama manufacturers are waiting to see and participate in going overseas. &quot;This shows that domestic short drama manufacturers are actually developing very fast.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A short drama filming site in Hengdian. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/03/fdac0abbd5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;669&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/03/fdac0abbd5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hengdian No.1 The filming scene of the short drama. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Ming&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Big capital has entered the market&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xia Xia (pseudonym) is a screenwriter who has switched from traditional drama series to short dramas. After several content adjustments, She is keenly aware that centralized rectification may be an opportunity for the industry to transition to high-quality products. She explained to Southern Weekend reporters that traditional dramas will also have counterattack plots, but they need to be foreshadowed before and after the counterattack. The plot has main and subplots, and the characters have growth arcs. However, short dramas do not need these foreshadowings, and short dramas need to be in the shortest possible time. Achieving reversal within time, this routine is the &quot;essence&quot; of the short play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the era of short dramas, the audience’s emotions need “instant gratification”. &quot;It&#39;s just an emotional PPT. The upper and lower PPTs are not very coherent, but they are all OK.&quot; Xia Xia said that the audience does not want to see the protagonist being wronged or insulted. If the heroine is slapped, the heroine&#39;s husband must immediately slap him twice. He returned it and said, &quot;There is no logic, just keep reversing and slapping me in the face.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You slap me, I slap you. No one likes to write this kind of script all the time, right?&quot; She said that after the industry became standardized, those who were particularly exaggerated, completely brainless, illogical and out of touch The actual drama series will be limited. If big capital comes into the game and attracts better talents to join the industry, the quality of short dramas may also increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the booming short drama market is attracting more and more talents. According to media reports, veteran TVB artists and actors continue to join in the filming of micro-short dramas; and leading Internet platforms have also stopped filming short dramas to seize the market. &quot;The addition of good actors will definitely improve the quality.&quot; Hua Ge said that the addition of a leading platform will have a profound impact on the development of the short drama market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that the current main profit model of short dramas is concentrated in the paid viewing stage. In order to get exposure, producers have to &quot;stream&quot; on a large scale on the platform to obtain traffic. This expenditure accounts for a large amount. Big cost. The addition of large companies and large platforms will bring new account sharing models and IP incubation models. Even some brands are in direct contact with short drama producers, and brand-embedded short dramas are also booming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, large capital parties are increasingly joining this feast. &quot;We are also actively in contact with private equity institutions.&quot; Hua Ge said that the company will promote the filming of multiple short dramas at the same time, and has just completed four of them. Hengdian is also a prosperous scene due to the rise of the short drama market. Because the actors&#39; schedules are tight and there are many plays lined up at the venue, the crew often has to stay up late to catch up. Therefore, the company plans to invest in the construction of two filming studios. Such heavy assets require a large amount of capital investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brother Hua and the crew are stationed in Hengdian all year round. He said that once the script and actors are in place, the filming of a short drama can be completed in a week. Earlier, a drama series could be produced with a cost of more than 100,000 yuan, but later it cost about 200,000 to 300,000 yuan. Now, the production cost has reached one million yuan, and dramas worth two million yuan are also appearing in large numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海独生女继承两亿遗产被诉离婚？婚姻不应成为财富再分配的工具丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261768]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;November 30, 2023, published by &quot;Shanghai Rule of Law News&quot; The article states: The woman comes from a well-off family and serves as the director of a foreign-funded company; the man is the receptionist at the hotel where the woman’s company’s annual meeting is held. The man violently pursued the woman, and later they got married. After the marriage, the woman&#39;s parents died in a car accident while traveling. Half a year later, the man filed for divorce and requested a division of the woman&#39;s inheritance from her parents. The woman&#39;s parents own nine properties and shops in Shanghai, as well as more than 10 million yuan in bank deposits and financial products, with a total value of about 200 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This article once reached the top of the hot search, with a main tag having more than 600 million views, and popular comments including &quot;I even suspected that the car accident...&quot; You can spend 10 million to deal with it, and I guarantee that the man will not get a dime.&quot; He also accused the man of &quot;taking advantage of the poor&quot;, and in short, scolded him for being shameless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This is actually a story told by lawyer Tan Fang. He neither gave a specific timeline nor presented credible evidence including judicial documents. Some netizens discovered that when she shared this story on Zhihu in 2022, she had the label &quot;the content contains fictional creations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For this reason, some media interviewed Ma Lei, a partner at Tan Fang&#39;s law firm, who said that the case was real and only involved the client&#39;s privacy. , will fabricate sensitive information such as names. However, it is very common to use pseudonyms in news reports. Journalists only need to mark it in the text or at the end of the article. They will not consider themselves to be &quot;fictional creations&quot; by using pseudonyms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In summary, the authenticity of this case is doubtful and needs further confirmation. But the emotions and reactions triggered by this story are real and strong: as can be seen from the massive online comments, the public generally does not agree with and find it difficult to accept the legacy left by the man&#39;s parents and the girl&#39;s parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Moreover, there are indeed such cases in judicial practice. In March this year, the Guangxi High Court issued a property dispute case. In 2021, Zhang and his wife Wang agreed to divorce, and their daughter lived with Wang. On the grounds that Zhang failed to pay child support, Wang filed a post-divorce property dispute lawsuit with the court. During the trial, Wang learned that Zhang’s mother died during the cooling-off period of their divorce and left behind a property. Zhang sold the above-mentioned house, and Wang requested to divide the sales proceeds obtained by Zhang from selling the house. In the end, the court ruled that Zhang should pay more than 2.18 million yuan in the sale price of the house inherited by Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the relationship between husband and wife, it is legal for one party to request a division of the parental estate inherited by the other party. The marriage and family section of the current Civil Code stipulates that &quot;property inherited or donated&quot; is the common property of husband and wife and owned jointly by husband and wife (Article 1062). This is the default principle; only when &quot;it is determined in the will or gift contract that only one party will own it&quot; &quot;Property&quot; is the personal property of one spouse (Article 1063). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Such provisions in statutory law are intended to expand the scope of joint property between husband and wife, allowing the economically weaker party to have more property to divide in the event of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The problem is that when marriage becomes a tool for wealth redistribution, both marriage and wealth become unsafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As far as marriage is concerned, under statutory laws and judicial practices that expand the scope of joint property between husband and wife, if two people with a huge gap in property and income get married, the marriage will become It’s even more unstable because it promotes the stereotype that “marriage is to start a business, divorce is to get rich”. Whether it is adding one&#39;s name to the property before marriage (= giving away half of the property), one of the parents did not make a will and left an inheritance, or one party in the marriage has too strong wealth creation ability or becomes rich overnight, these are only the joint property of the husband and wife during the marriage. One party may not have substantial control and dominance, but as long as there is a divorce, the other party can actually obtain control and dominance of half of the property. If a person obtains a large amount of wealth through divorce, achieves financial freedom, and feels so happy, this will inevitably inspire evil in human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of wealth, a property in first-tier cities often costs tens of millions, and is often the accumulation of wealth for at least two generations. Just because a marriage certificate costs Losing half of a house is very unfair and makes people who hold real estate in big cities very insecure. Therefore, more and more people ask for a match before getting married, or just hold a wedding without getting a certificate, so as to avoid being &quot;exploited&quot; in the event of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Back to the issue of inheritance, it is natural and reasonable for parents to hope that their property will be left to their children or other blood-related descendants a hundred years from now. Consistent with natural law and customary law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the absence of a will and legal inheritance, in accordance with natural law and customary law, the inheritance left by parents to their children should of course be inherited by their children. personal property. However, as mentioned above, current statutory law and judicial practice stipulate that it is joint property of husband and wife by default. If one parent dies suddenly without leaving a will, the greed of the other parent may be aroused. Through divorce, they can divide half of the other parent&#39;s inheritance, achieve financial freedom, and reach the peak of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Of course, many people believe in love, and also believe that being economically disadvantaged does not necessarily mean being morally despicable, but don’t test human nature, as long as a certain proportion of economically disadvantaged people can make progress Taking this step is enough to destroy the trust that should exist in marriage and make everyone fear marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Elderly people who are knowledgeable, educated and understand the law know what to do. Some media reports: Recently, 85-year-old Grandma Liu came to the China Wills Library to make a will and wanted to give her property to The granddaughter, son and daughter-in-law all know and agree. She said she lived a happy life in her later years and was not afraid of making a will. She was once the coach of a modeling team. The consideration is roughly like this: leaving it directly to the son is natural, but the daughter-in-law may be unhappy and complain &quot;you don&#39;t trust me&quot;; leaving the son directly to the granddaughter perfectly solves this problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;China Will Library White Paper (2022)&quot; shows that 99.8% of the elderly who make wills state that the inheritance will be inherited by the children alone and does not belong to the joint property of the heirs. It is the so-called &quot;protection against daughter-in-law and son-in-law&quot; clause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the final analysis, it is all forced by the current statutory law and judicial practice. The elderly have worked hard all their lives to accumulate real estate, and most elderly people cannot accept it psychologically if &quot;outsiders&quot; who are not related by blood and may divorce and leave at any time take away half of the house. However, more elderly people do not have this awareness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>