<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[输得起的郭宝昌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258484]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 18:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/9e016650df2ccce6b9fb2a03776f8df6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1624&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/9e016650df2ccce6b9fb2a03776f8df6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;During the 1927 Hebei disaster, carpenter Guo Shaochen fled to Beijing with his wife and daughter. After Guo&#39;s death, his 10-year-old daughter was sold into the wealthy Le family, and at the age of 23, she was married to the 70-year-old Le Si master. The daughter had no children, so she bought Li Baochang, the son of a beggar, in 1942. (Baochang lost his father when he was young and was first sold to a family named Wu by his biological mother, and then sold to the Guo family by his third aunt for two hundred yuan). From then on, Li Baochang was raised in his &quot;natal family&quot;. The fourth master Guan Yue called him aunt, and his adoptive mother Guo Rong called aunt. It was not until 1953 that she changed her name to mom and changed her name to Guo Baochang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang’s life before he was 12 years old is frozen in this short description of about 100 words. After that, after stepping into the mansion, he suddenly changed from a beggar to a &quot;superior&quot;, but he still had to experience the warmth and warmth of human relationships: in the third room, the adoptive mother Guo Rong was originally the girl who held the pet dog for the third old lady. After taking the position, she was careful in the cracks. , taught his son how to roll around in a crowd, and also helped him establish the ambition to &quot;do big things&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Gate of the Great House&quot;, which was written in four drafts, is like a miniature version of the Legend of Red Mansions in the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China. In the play, Guo Rong becomes Xiang Xiu, his adoptive father Le Jingyu (the Fourth Master Le of Tongrentang) becomes Bai Jingqi, and Guo Baochang himself becomes Li Tianyi. Viewers are talking about the correspondence between the plot in the play and the traditional Chinese medicine family. He said frankly: The script is 30% false and 70% real, and there are still a lot of stories that have not yet been written. &quot;Such a national bourgeois family closely follows the changes of the times and the political situation, and the relationships between the family characters are also constantly changing. If I have the ability to write it down and make some film and television works, it can better reflect the impact of history on human nature. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Compared with the prominent relatives in the house, Guo Baochang cares more about the little people who are rarely looked at carefully: Master Wang, the bodyguard who taught him real kung fu, the down-and-out San&#39;er, the lively and straightforward second sister Zhang Fei and the eccentric Gen Luobo, the gardener Qian Erye who makes cigarette paste and boils eagles, and the &quot;eldest brother&quot; whom he admires deeply but later goes to extremes...&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;They were like the leaves in the thick hardcover books he collected. &quot;I like to collect leaves. The leaves are calmer, indifferent, and unobtrusive than flowers, and the taste is a little lonely and bitter. The veins, textures, and patterns of the leaves are articles, history, and all living beings in the large forest family. They are easily ignored. The real past.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f37d28b50e2eca913e27b9de59bd0441.png&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f37d28b50e2eca913e27b9de59bd0441.png&quot; data -key=&quot;253922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These little characters have become the protagonists in his collection of essays &quot;All Big Characters&quot;. The other protagonist is the author himself, who has gone through many ups and downs: he was admitted to the film school and excelled, but was labeled a &quot;reactionary student&quot;. He was reformed through labor and implicated his mentor Tian Feng, a life-long regret; after arriving at the Guangxi Film Studio, He worked hard to support the fifth generation of directors, paving the way for their collective guest appearance in &quot;The House Gate&quot; in the future. He wanted to write about the experience of the house gate, but the result was frequent changes. The manuscript was destroyed and rewritten several times, and it took 40 years of his life to finally come out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The people in the house call him &quot;Master Bao&quot;, which is the old family identity. In the film and television industry, people use the honorific title &quot;Master Bao&quot; to respect his sincerity, seriousness, and heroic spirit. Mr. Bao, who is over eighty years old, has deeper bags under his eyes and white eyebrows, but his figure has not been compromised. He launched the Peking Opera &quot;Mansion Gate&quot; tour and continued to write books, but he showed no signs of enjoying a happy life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a treasured master should always be satisfied? But he shook his head. &quot;I have never opened my arms in my whole life&quot; is not only talking about the second master, but also seems to be writing about myself, who is ambitious. For Guo Baochang, all his hard work and unwillingness in this life are not only to realize his ambition, but also to shed tears of repentance for his revered adoptive mother and mentor: &quot;Look, I know I was wrong. I hope you will be proud of me in the end.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The following is spoken by Guo Baochang:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;I don’t think they &quot;Noble&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Actually, before I was 12 years old, the house door was quite mysterious to me. Occasionally, I would go in and let me eat fruit, or suddenly it would be said that it was the Spring Festival and fireworks would be set off, and someone would bring me in and send them out again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After my grandma passed away, my mother took me in, and I officially entered the house. The impression was very deep and I will never forget it in my life. Because I suddenly escaped from my poor family, I clearly realized that a new life had begun, and my identity was different: you could ask the kitchen to eat whatever you wanted, and people could cook it for you. I will give you a fixed pocket money every month. In the 1950s, I was given 40 yuan a month. At that time, a worker&#39;s salary was only 36 yuan a month. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c2a5b9683c9a244f13dbc862682615f4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c2a5b9683c9a244f13dbc862682615f4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253921 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang’s cadre school years&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Children from other families still When I was kneading mud in the courtyard, Master Wang, who taught me boxing, often took us shopping, buying big knives and painted faces, going to the overpass, drinking noodle tea, shaving our heads, and taking a bath. I also learned to smoke, drink, watch theater, boxing, watch ballet, and changed my bicycle one after another. My mother said: &quot;Without this skill, you won&#39;t be able to deal with those bastards at the banquet.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But in the end, I have no status in the family. Because people think you are a &quot;bastard&quot; and suddenly come in to share the cake. Although they call you &quot;Young Master&quot;, their family has family rules and cannot have children with other surnames. So I have a deep...not so much inferiority, but a deep resentment. In fact, no matter in terms of life, interpersonal relationships, or attitude towards servants, I look down on those young masters and ladies. I don&#39;t think those people are noble. This is probably directly related to my later acceptance of the party’s education. But I had to endure a lot of things that I was unwilling to endure, and grew up slowly in the eyes of contempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My mother also knows it very well, so she must make me strive for success - the way to make me strive for success is not to let me study hard, do my homework, and take the college entrance examination. Teach you to be an independent, dignified person, to become a master, and to get rid of all kinds of servility. My resistance was very strong at that time, I just thought that I must be successful and I must be better than you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;(Is the adoptive mother neither humble nor arrogant to other people?) &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She gave it to me The overall impression is to be vigilant at all times. I can say without exaggeration that in the entire family, except for the old man, almost everyone is her enemy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because she has the lowest status among the wives, why can a girl with a dog suddenly give orders? They were unconvinced and tried every means to carry out all kinds of destruction. She had to be alert to everyone around her at all times. Over the past few decades, she has always been in such a high-pressure state, which is not easy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I also hope that I can stand behind her, as the strength behind her, so that people will not dare to bully her. This is a big wish of mine when I was a child. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1953, this big family finally couldn&#39;t support it anymore. Each house owner bought his own house and established his own portal. The old man and my adoptive mother and I moved to Donghuamen, while my grandmother and her family moved to Luogu Lane. I wanted a pipa in the warehouse, but Miss Wen flatly refused and said in a very unpleasant way: &quot;It&#39;s not your turn to choose! You&#39;ve come to take advantage of me!&quot; As soon as the funeral was over, Wen immediately took the lead in negotiating with several housemates. The boss jointly listed the so-called &quot;ten crimes&quot; against my mother. To put it bluntly, they wanted money. My mother focused on the overall situation, kept things quiet, and listed the family property and distributed it equally among the houses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is natural to divide money, but it is really spectacular to divide things. Let&#39;s start with calligraphy and painting, which are overwhelmingly displayed - no one wants Qi Baishi&#39;s or Chen Banding&#39;s paintings. Each room is allocated through negotiation based on the number of rooms. Then divide into fans, then jade, inkstones, snuff bottles, copybooks, furs, and materials. For three whole days and nights, there was a lot of traffic in front of the door, and no one looked tired. This is what the tree falls and the hozens scatter. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/747c065c81d4ad01d34eefbc449f2b96.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/747c065c81d4ad01d34eefbc449f2b96.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253924 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Confess to my mother every day&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course my mother has her limitations. She looked down on Yang Jiuhong and called her &quot;Sister Yao&quot;. She also tried her best to hide my life experience. Later, she firmly opposed my making family affairs public. &quot;Isn&#39;t this exposing my family&#39;s scandal?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;You ask me how I feel about her now? Very complicated, more of a guilt. There are many photos of my mother hanging in my house. I walk back and forth every day and confess to her every day. Because I betrayed my mother, I once severed ties with her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At that time, I was undergoing labor reform at Nankou Farm and went home to celebrate the New Year. In order to get rid of my bourgeois background, I forced my mother to ask who my biological parents were. After she told me, I immediately went to the farm and told the organization my true identity. Unexpectedly, the management staff said: &quot;You grew up on exploited food. You have all the bones in your body, so your background has nothing to do with you.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I even forced my mother to do so. After handing over all her property and working for a long time, she agreed to give up half of her dividends. But I felt it was not enough, so I tried to persuade again. She felt hugely insulted and said to me: &quot;Don&#39;t you think it&#39;s disgraceful to have such a capitalist mother? You can disown me, make your own home, and live your life. I won&#39;t pay. &quot;I picked up my old school bag and left, which broke her heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I had a lot of selfish motives at the time, and wanted to use her &quot;handover of property&quot; to perform meritorious deeds and alleviate the punishment brought about by my background. This idea is very strong, thinking that as long as we don&#39;t eat outside the house, my punishment can be reduced, which is also a sign of meritorious service. Looking back now, it was a dirty idea. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;(Did you express regret before she died?)&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Repented, I just didn’t have time to express it. Why is it so difficult for someone to admit their mistakes? Why is it so difficult to apologize alone? I later learned that people like to gloss over their faults and refuse to admit they are clearly wrong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason why I write and speak out is to let everyone know that I was once ugly. Everyone will have mistakes and shortcomings of one kind or another, but only by facing them can you be reborn. If you lose, you have to admit defeat. Don&#39;t grit your teeth and refuse to admit defeat. Knowing what we have done wrong is of great benefit to us in treating the world sincerely. Of course, I also think this is too cheap. If you admit it, will you redeem your mistake? No. I did a lot of things I shouldn&#39;t have done, and the damage caused was fatal. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/48f8a869ca997dae8ffa69867018d2d4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;877&quot; height=&quot;1230&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/48f8a869ca997dae8ffa69867018d2d4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253925 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang’s adoptive father Le Jingyu (also known as &quot;Le Jingyu&quot;), everyone in the family calls him &quot;the old man&quot; ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I am more in awe of Mr. Le. Why didn’t I write a chapter for him in the book? Because everything was written in the TV series, &quot;Seventh Master&quot; is a role model for me throughout my life: when it comes to quitting smoking, a manly man will stop smoking if he doesn&#39;t want to, and he survives. Every time he visits my grandma, he doesn&#39;t have the airs of a big capitalist and is very peaceful. It wasn&#39;t until 1953 that he suffered from amnesia and collapsed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But when I entered elementary school and received a new education, I felt that exploiters like the old man were tyrants and hooligans. When I thought about this issue while writing the novel, I began to look at him through class analysis and no longer respected him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I don’t understand my mother’s obedience to him. For example, he suddenly said that I wanted to go to the street. At that time, he was already blind - he had cataracts. My mother helped him walk around the street and come back. In fact, he couldn&#39;t see anything. I thought it was superfluous, and I especially sympathized with my mother. Therefore, in the first draft of &quot;The Gate of the Mansion&quot;, I wrote the image of my mother as &quot;insulted and damaged&quot;. At that time, Hugo and Dostoyevsky had a great influence on me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One time when my mother was away, I took the old man’s hand and walked around the house. I said okay, look at the street and that’s it. Do you see it? OK, sit down. My mother slammed the table at that time, &quot;You dare to treat this old man like this, who are you?&quot; He has been such a hero all his life, can you treat him like this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When I was a child, I couldn’t understand why my mother wanted to marry you at such a young age. How can there be love? I do not believe. I thought it was just a matter of bearing the humiliation and having no choice but to be sold there as a maid, and finally marrying such an old man in order to survive and have food to eat. After this incident, I realized that my mother truly loved him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;“In old China, no matter how powerful women were, they were still empowered by men”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;You said the story of Miss Qin and Miss Wen is particularly embarrassing? Yes, even the editors can&#39;t create such drama. It is so colorful and bizarre, beyond the imagination of ordinary people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Qin and Wenben are the two beautiful young ladies at the head of our house. Wen is very talented in art, plays the guqin well and has a sweet singing voice. When Qin was in school, she fell in love with a college classmate of her second brother. This person and his second brother had similar interests and advanced ideas, which made Qin know that there is another world outside. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6983b099477946550d887ccd57d8b896.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1056&quot; height=&quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6983b099477946550d887ccd57d8b896.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253928 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Miss Qin (left) when she was a child&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Second brother In order to escape his family&#39;s arranged marriage, he resolutely ran away, followed this classmate to join the revolution, and joined the party. He did not enter the city with the People&#39;s Liberation Army until Peking was liberated. That classmate and Qin were privately engaged for life, but he was unable to stay in Beijing and soon followed the army south, and the two met and exchanged letters. As a result, Qin never received his letter, and it took more than half a year to realize that their correspondence had been seized by her mother. In the last letter, the boy said that Qin had probably changed his mind and had found another partner and got married. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Qin immediately raised his knife and struck at her mother. The old man hugged Qin and took away the knife. From then on Qin went crazy. Wen became surly, withdrawn, willful and selfish. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Later, Qin married a seventy-year-old man and a farmer in Daxing, because she could not support herself at all. After arriving at the Wen family to implement the policy, Qin went back to her natal family and asked her mother and sister to help her, but she was refused. After taking the five yuan donated by Wen and walking out of her parents&#39; house, she actually swung the knife again at night, intending to kill her mother and sister Wen. Qin died in detention a few days later. People say: &quot;Thirty years ago, Qin&#39;s ghost head was not cut off with a knife, but it was made up for this time.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this story, sisters, mother and daughter, Family love, money...all are in it. But it&#39;s not over yet. I never imagined that there would be a story later. In 1998, an unexpected guest came to visit and said he was Qin&#39;s son. It turned out that his father was not an official of the People&#39;s Liberation Army, but an official of the Kuomintang. He fled to Nanjing with the army and then to Taiwan. He did not know that Qin was pregnant. Qin gave birth to him in a foreign country and carried him to Taiwan, acting out the tragedy of searching for her husband thousands of miles away. As a result, because her husband had remarried, Qin had no choice but to abandon her children and return to the mainland. Qin&#39;s son has since respected Wen as a relative. When he was in Beijing, he accompanied Wen to see a doctor and took care of her. After returning to the United States, he still sent money to help Wen with her medical treatment. He placed all his thoughts and love for his mother on his aunt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wen lived to be 71 years old and never married. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1be4b404dfa104f69cb919f6692dd3da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;769&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1be4b404dfa104f69cb919f6692dd3da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253929 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang and Miss Wen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Speaking of this Gratitude and resentment are normal in a big house. Every room has its own story, but Qin and Wen impressed me the most. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I grew up among women because my mother was in power at the time. Her main target at home is the female relatives of each house. It is easier to control the fate of the entire family through such channels, so I have more contact with grandmothers, aunts, young ladies, and ladies. I have quite complicated emotions towards them. Like my mother, I have to treat every member of the family and every woman with a different attitude. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of female consciousness, she has received various educations since she was a child, especially in Peking Opera. In plays like Wang Baochuan, she and the princess are both Xue Pinggui’s wives. In the end, it seems Both of them succeeded in making the decision, but in fact it was given by Xue Pinggui. I feel that the issue of women&#39;s rights has not been solved in China, let alone in our family. The story of Yang Jiuhong is very typical. She and Xiangxiu seem to have power, and they have always been in control of a family, which is still given by male power. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But I really didn’t expect that among the thousands of comments on &quot;The Mansion Gate&quot;, Yang Jiuhong probably gave the most comments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I have never met the second grandma, but the prototype of Yang Jiuhong has indeed lived with me for 20 years. For example, my second grandma was not allowed to wear mourning when she was about to die. Countless people in the house told me about this. That is not an ordinary injury, because both cats and dogs must wear mourning. You are not worthy of it. You are worse than cats and dogs, and you have no dignity at all as a human being. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The second mistress also said that if you become a good person and redeem yourself, you are still a prostitute! When I was filming a movie some time ago, I asked the young people on the crew, I said, if you get married and have children, and your child brings back a prostitute from other places to get married, will you agree? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Let’s not talk about such profound principles, ethics and morals. Don’t talk about these, just use yourself as an example. Who can do it? Do you think this is feudal consciousness? It’s such a complicated issue. When any of us looks at any work or evaluates any character, we should not use formulaic explanations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the later years of Yang Jiuhong&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (prototype) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, there was an old man in the front yard of our courtyard, who was very elegant and a gentleman. A man who likes to wear robes and often comes to our house to play. As soon as we went back and forth, our Yang Jiuhong fell in love with him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Do you think that an old lady who has gone through so many ups and downs can have someone who really sits next to her and is willing to listen to her in her twilight years? No matter what she says, I will listen. She is already very satisfied without expressing her opinion. I can understand this emotion very well. But then something happened, causing a huge fuss, and she suddenly became the joke of the entire family. I am the only one who sympathizes with her very much. I am the only one who can sit and chat with her in the mansion and is willing to listen carefully to what she says. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Walking back and forth in the river of little people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the summer of 1963, I followed Fishermen go out to sea and &quot;catching fish&quot; in their fishing boats. &quot;Liu Zi&quot; is the river in the sea. The boundary of the river is the sea, the flow is hidden, but the color of the water is different. Only fishermen who have lived and died with the sea for many years can identify it. When they caught up with Liuzi, the fishermen spread dozens of miles of large rope hooks to catch fish. They all stripped naked and lay on the boat deck to enjoy the sun, waiting for the fish to take the bait. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Facing the sea, people are so small, and I can’t help but sigh, man, who do you think you are? ! I sang &quot;I am originally from Wollongong&quot; in the Peking Opera &quot;Empty City Strategy&quot;, and the boss of the boat squatted on the bow and cheered for me while shitting, which was full of poetry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/42f5d33ae873ea35a3f771cfe0edfe3e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/42f5d33ae873ea35a3f771cfe0edfe3e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253930 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Revisit the mansion gate. The three windows behind Guo Baochang were the concierge, and Old Fart Zheng lived in them&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At that time, I liked to stay in the concierge, and in the kitchen, listening to what they said. All kinds of family things are just like listening to stories. In this book, I just want to bring to the front these characters who impressed me deeply and cannot be represented in the script of &quot;Mansion Gate&quot;, and give each of them a close-up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, Master Wang, the bodyguard who taught me martial arts, is not tall, has a shaved head, and always wears country boy shorts; he always walks close to the wall in the alley. , with his head lowered and not looking away, just looking at the road in front of him; his face was calm and courteous, his eyes were squinted and he was smiling but not smiling, always as if he was sorry for someone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When encountering a vicious desperado, Master Wang would rather lose some money than kill anyone. As the saying goes, &quot;if you can&#39;t help it, don&#39;t do it.&quot; I remember that one night, a dark figure walked quickly from the roof of the small courtyard in the northeast. It jumped up to the ridge of the upper room in the north house. When it reached the northwest corner, the black shadow stopped for a moment. He bowed slightly to the people in the yard, and suddenly the old man shouted: &quot;Reward!&quot; A servant handed a small bag with Da Yang to Master Wang, and Master Wang hung the small bag on the knife of Guitou Dao. On the tip, he swung upwards hard, and the bag was thrown towards the black shadow, and happened to fall on the black shadow&#39;s raised hand. The black shadow kowtowed on the ridge of the roof, shrunk and disappeared. It turned out that he was a passing thief who took the opportunity to greet Master Wang, a martial arts master. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is also a young man from an oil and salt shop who is good at painting landscapes, flowers and birds. He has also watched &quot;How Steel Was Tempered&quot; and &quot;Zoya and Shu&quot;. &quot;La&#39;s Story&quot; has too much in common with me. More importantly, he talks about benevolence and righteousness. He didn&#39;t think much of the people in the house, saying that everyone was the same and there was no distinction between high and low. He gave me a copy of &quot;The Story of Lenin&quot; and said that if you look at Lenin, he didn&#39;t bring his ID, and the guards still wouldn&#39;t let him in. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is also Mr. Zheng, who loves to eat and fart, and can do rough work. For many years, Mr. Qian, who is disabled, has trouble getting into the hut, so Mr. Zheng helps him. He wears his belt. I have never smoked, drank, or gambled my whole life. I have never watched plays or movies, so I just listen to books. He is that kind of country man who is simple, kind, thrifty, loyal, but ordinary and ordinary. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The people I have met in my life are indeed all kinds of people. Of course, the weirdest thing is my &quot;big brother&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He is not my eldest brother, but a classmate in high school. The family is extremely poor, and even if the younger brother steals a piece of garlic, he will be beaten by the elder brother. He is talented and has unique ideas. We had a close friendship, but he never refused my help. He said that he was so kind to me because he saw me as a rare talent, so he would never let me fall into the hands of the bourgeoisie and must pull me into the ranks of the proletariat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Later on, both of us experienced various ups and downs, worked hard, and went to prison. Compared with him, I have believed, worshiped, repented, and been cleansed. And he has always been so &quot;transparent&quot; and so pure. I really don’t know which one of us is the tragedy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But in his later years, the eldest brother actually made a 180-degree turn. Bewitched by others, he began to borrow endlessly, from home to friends, almost everywhere. I also lent it to him and didn&#39;t expect him to pay it back. The worst thing is that he did not squander the money himself. He did not enjoy it. It was all passed on to those scammers. I told him it was all a scam and to stop it. One time he went too far, and I kept scolding him for about an hour... His daughter said: Uncle Guo, can you please stop scolding my dad? There was nothing he could do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/319713849bc3670c65412fa24e05f9b6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/319713849bc3670c65412fa24e05f9b6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253931 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The later &quot;eldest brother&quot; (the one who wears glasses) is almost a completely different person&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My eldest brother passed away a few days ago. He did not &quot;wake up&quot; until his death. Therefore, people&#39;s way of thinking cannot go to extremes. He has gone to one extreme since his youth, and then he has gone to another extreme and fallen down all of a sudden. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;Wealth&quot; at the cost of life&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some people say I am lucky. Yes, my life has been full of ups and downs, and this is a great wealth. But this wealth comes at the cost of life. No one wants to repeat this kind of luck. This kind of struggle is not something ordinary people can bear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1959, I was admitted to the Directing Department of the Film Academy and joined the Youth League. My status in the family suddenly changed dramatically. Most of the young masters and young ladies in the family are living the food of their ancestors and staying at home. People like me who are both academically and politically enterprising are considered very promising. In the words of those gangsters: &quot;Okay, Mr. Bao, college students are still in the party.&quot; Yes!&quot; Wen&#39;s attitude changed especially. It may be difficult for people today to understand, because such an environment no longer exists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A few years later, when I was studying in the fifth grade of the Directing Department of Beijing Film Academy, I was classified as a &quot;reactionary student.&quot; He went through four years of labor reform and four years of life and death supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After returning from the labor camp, I stood at Donghua Gate. After I came out, I stood on the street. I didn&#39;t know where I was going, or where my mother and other family members were. I had no idea that the rebels were already living in the front and back yards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After that, I was assigned to Guangxi for controlled use. Later, I gradually heard the news about the implementation of the policy, and the materials and deposits that had been confiscated were returned. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back, the time in film school was the happiest time in my life. At that time, I really felt that there was a bright road ahead of me, paved with flowers, but suddenly I fell into hell. You were no longer a human being, and you lost even the basic human dignity. Suddenly a work &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (&quot;The Mansion Gate&quot;) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; comes out, and suddenly everyone starts to pursue you again. It&#39;s such a life of ups and downs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I wrote that I cried bitterly four times in my life, and the most painful thing was when Tian Feng passed away. It was the kind of crying, crying and squealing. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(Pause, face to one side, choked for a long time)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At that time, Tian Feng was the director of the directing department of our school. He vouched for the school: &quot; I am from a working-class and peasant background, and I will reform him (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;. At that time, I was writing the novel &quot;The Mansion Gate&quot;, and two-thirds of it was confiscated after I had written it. I was charged with writing a book and biography for a capitalist. While waiting for the school to deal with it, I did the work of cleaning toilets, sweeping the theater, and weighing briquettes. One afternoon when I came out of the briquettes factory, I bumped into Teacher Wadafeng. Both of them had their heads lowered. He was so thin that he lost his appearance. I didn’t expect that that would be the last time we saw each other. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be said that emotionally, I have not only felt guilty, self-blame, and regret for many years, but I have also been in a state of despair, helplessness, confusion, and confusion. I am really not happy about being &quot;rehabilitated&quot; because what is lost is lost forever. No amount of words or actions can make up for the guilt I feel towards the teacher. He gave me special training at that time and made small mistakes for me, including the fact that he took on responsibilities that he shouldn&#39;t bear because I did something wrong, which really made me miserable later. Later, everything I did was to strive for our teacher and not let him live up to his expectations of me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cffb27ac924d4ffdf78c586e6b32165a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cffb27ac924d4ffdf78c586e6b32165a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253933 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guo Baochang directed at the filming site of the TV series &quot;Dongsi Pailou East&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;I also respect my mentor’s wife, Teacher Yu Hua. For a while I fell into sadness and frustration, and couldn&#39;t figure it out. In addition, after the reform and opening up, various ideological trends poured into the country, and I also made some strange remarks. She once said to me very sternly, &quot;You have been persecuted and feel aggrieved. This is understandable. Everyone has been through this. But you are still here, and you still have more than half of your life to go. You have to live all day long.&quot; How can you do great things with a complaining mentality?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I just want to say, how do people get through this life? She has suffered so many grievances, but she still lives so strongly and has such firm faith. I can&#39;t do it. I often think of what my old friend Uncle Du told me, &quot;No matter how dangerous the road is, you can still fight through it. You have to be different and learn to control your own destiny.&quot; Just when others are dawdling and don&#39;t know what to do, No matter how you go, you must persevere and still do your best. I think this means not admitting defeat, and having the desire to win while not admitting defeat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;(You wrote that the second master in the house &quot;has never opened his arms in his whole life.&quot; What about yourself?) &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;(Shakes head)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;My ambitions are too great, and there are many things that have not been realized. When I was a kid doing fortune telling, my husband told me that you will never be able to achieve your own wishes in your life. I only started when I was 40 years old, and it was too late to do many things. I just relied on my breath to hold on there, always a bit unwilling to admit defeat. No matter how you hit me, you can&#39;t knock me down. No matter how crooked you are, I have to stand up, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;span>; (Reference materials: &quot;All Big Characters&quot;, &quot;Amazing Game&quot;. Thanks to Chen Xi and Wei Chun for their help with this article) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海老年相亲圣地，常客们不谈爱情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/qrJ2C4yqUr1iCcG3uGXG27rxSzDTODrZgFIVC1pB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/qrJ2C4yqUr1iCcG3uGXG27 rxSzDTODrZgFIVC1pB. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253723&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of September 12, 2023, Shanghai, elderly people in the IKEA restaurant. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A meal served for 9 people, 13 dishes, and the average cash per person was 72 yuan. Wiping his mouth and getting up, another day passed by. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;68-year-old Hong Jianming stood in front of the neon-lit hotel lobby, watching old friends walking in twos and twos, supporting each other across the zebra crossing until they disappeared. He took steps in the darkness across the road. &quot;They don&#39;t know that I live nearby, and I don&#39;t want them to know.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are single old men whom Hong Jianming met at the IKEA restaurant in Xujiahui, Shanghai. In order to &quot;eat more diverse dishes&quot;, we get together to eat together every Tuesday. Neither of them knew each other&#39;s names, and they seldom asked because there was no need. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of the single elderly people who go to IKEA restaurants want to find a companion. While they boldly express their love for the person they like, they can&#39;t help but be suspicious and wary out of self-protection, lest they suffer a loss. As time goes by, everyone has become acquaintances who maintain a sense of boundaries, and they get together just for fun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Loneliness is ultimately the background here. &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;Private land&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Lack of a communication platform for the elderly&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;It is rainy in Shanghai in early autumn, but the IKEA Xuhui Shopping Mall at No. 126 Caoxi Road is bustling with people. On the afternoons of Tuesdays and Thursdays, the young people dining in the restaurant on the second floor slowly dispersed, and crowds of elderly people poured in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 3 pm on September 12, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters first arrived at the IKEA restaurant. At first glance, the dining area with nearly 700 seats was scattered. It was completely occupied by elderly people sitting apart, and there were always people walking around in the aisles, chatting with each other.偶尔有人走到记者跟前，打量着年轻的新面孔问道：“是来找伴的不？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这是一处上海老年人自发设定的相亲角。 Xuhui Mall, opened in 1998, is IKEA&#39;s first store in mainland China. It&#39;s hard to explain how its restaurant came to be occupied by a group of singles. As long as you buy a cup of coffee for 7.9 yuan and get free refills, you can hang out in the restaurant with the mug in hand all day long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;71岁的陈翠霞记得，18年前，徐汇商场还是一栋很小的两层楼，单身的她和姐妹6人来玩，底下商场兜一圈，发现二楼还有饭吃。 “这边蛮好的，完了以后我们就讲好，下次再来好不好？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来，人越聚越多，最多的时候，三百多号单身老人聚过来，都是来找伴的，整个大厅得靠喊话沟通，“声音吵&lt;span>;得&lt;/span>;能把房顶掀翻”。 Someone suggested that everyone pick a day to get together. Tuesday is the big day and Thursday is the small day. Chen Cuixia feels that the elderly actually have no other place to chat&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;“除了这里，就是人民公园，缺乏一个供老年人交流的平台。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上海是全国老龄化程度最高的超大型城市。 According to the 2022 Shanghai Municipal Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for nearly 40% of the total population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone 300,600. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;宜家餐厅无疑成了他们排遣寂寞的一块自留地。每周二，一位90岁的老太太会乘坐456路公交，从三林出发，花40多分钟时间来到餐厅后，只是默默坐在角落看人头攒动；旁边另一位上了年纪的女人与老太太以姐妹相称，她用塑料袋&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“消失”的婴儿牵出代孕贩婴暗网：涉多名儿童与东南亚代孕妈妈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258433]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252367&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月13日，浙江湖州，邱佳红再次来到陈美凤住处。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;胎龄8个多月，早产，头发黑黑的，是个男婴。关于未谋面的孩子，这是37岁的邱佳红知道的全部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年9月16日23时35分，刚经历剖腹引产的邱佳红从全身麻醉中醒来，孩子的父亲郑小兵告诉她，取出来的婴儿是死的，被医生抱走了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在邱佳红的讲述中，自己原本健康的胎儿临产时被医院告知“孩子缺氧，脑神经不正常，要打掉的”。半年后，她突然意识到不对劲。在剖腹引产手术的头天下午，她接到过一个显示为浙江湖州号码的电话，连续打来两次，电话那头的老太太问她，孩子送人吗？“莫名其妙，我说怎么可能送人，就挂了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随着诸多疑点一点点浮现，邱佳红怀疑自己是中了人贩子的圈套。成为“猎物”并不是没有缘故，那是一个让她难以启齿的原因——自己未婚生育的孩子，是郑小兵的私生子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱佳红相信孩子还活着。她决定顺着那串陌生号码寻子，没曾想，阴差阳错掀开一起地下代孕、贩卖儿童大案。截至2023年9月13日，侦办该案的警方查明涉及多名被买卖儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;雇私家侦探寻子&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;雨下了一早上，灰蒙蒙的粮油批发市场里人少，安静，成排的卷帘门大多被拉下来，偶尔几个外卖员来去穿梭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身材瘦小的邱佳红领着南方周末记者，在市场里三拐两拐，熟练地钻进靠边的一幢居民楼，顺着贴满牛皮癣小广告的楼道到203室门前。这家住户就是当初给她打电话的老太太，如今已经置身于看守所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老太太名叫陈美凤，58岁，福建莆田人。那张脸邱佳红记得清楚，文两道弯眉，耷拉着深眼袋，圆脸盘，高颧骨，挨肩炸开的一头灰发用发箍卡紧。她体型偏胖，冬日里时常裹一件黑色貂皮大衣，蹬一双黑筒靴，脚底有劲儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;半年前，2023年2月，邱佳红雇佣两名私家侦探，三人驱车从上海前往浙江湖州找到陈美凤的住处，试图在这里找到当初从医院消失的儿子。她回忆，挨着冻在楼下蹲点一周，也没有见到陈美凤抱着五六月大的男婴出没过一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与陈美凤的正面对峙，发生在他们蹲点的第8天。2月23日，邱佳红一早在203室门口堵住了散步回来的陈美凤：“陈阿姨，你认得我吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不认得”，陈美凤的普通话里夹杂着浓重的莆田口音，她客气地将来者请进屋里坐，老头子在给小孙女烧饭，屋里有些杂乱。邱佳红目光扫了一圈屋子，没有男婴。她又问一句，“那我的号码你从哪里来的？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈美凤才明白邱佳红的来意，“没打过”，她说，一会儿又咕哝，“不记得了”。在邱佳红的执意要求下，陈美凤被陪同前往附近一处移动营业厅调取半年内的通讯记录，邱佳红的电话号码果然出现在其中，通话时间为2022年9月15日16时29分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252368&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年2月一天清晨， 陈美凤抱孙女回屋。（受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时的邱佳红并没有注意，在陈美凤给她打电话前后，还和同一人打过3通电话，后来发现是浙江美福宝妇儿医院（以下简称美福宝医院）院长陈勇进的号码。2022年9月16日，邱佳红就在杭州的美福宝医院生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来邱佳红从警方得知，这二人是莆田老乡。陈勇进就此事的回应是，“有可能是我告诉陈美凤（邱佳红联系方式）的，我不确定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱佳红想起，剖腹产手术后第三天，开刀医生于艳芬走进她的病房拉家常，“我当时痛得有点迷迷糊糊，她跟我聊了有两小时，问我家里兄弟姐妹都是做什么的，先生是做什么的，怎么认识的，聊得跟自己人一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“一系列回想以后觉得不对，她到我病房肯定是来打探消息的。”邱佳红认定，孩子活着，但被陈美凤跟美福宝医院卖了；男友郑小兵也有把孩子“送出去”的嫌疑，两人因此闹僵，分道扬镳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;面对邱佳红和私家侦探逼问孩子下落，陈美凤带着哭腔，“我真的不记&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武打演员孟海患食道癌去世：当关注高危因素“烟、酒、烫、腌”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258469]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，武术指导、武打演员，洪家班重要成员孟海去世。他不幸确诊食道癌后，仅仅一年就去世了。他的去世，当引起大家对食道癌的关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国居民食道癌、胃癌发生的危险因素主要是：热烫饮食、喜油炸食、腌制饮食、重盐食、三餐不定时和饮酒抽烟，特别是边抽烟边饮酒；而吃大蒜、新鲜蔬菜以及饮温茶是保护因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌是常见的消化道肿瘤，其典型的症状为进行性咽下困难，先是吞咽食物时有哽咽感、异物感，然后难以咽下干的食物，最后，连半流物甚至水也不能咽下。食道癌还会引发胸骨后疼痛，如果发生转移或侵犯邻近器官，被累及器官会不适和疼痛。通常可能侵犯喉部，引起声嘶，所以，嗓子不舒服，未必是说话说多了，也可能是身体的紧急信号。如果侵犯下段食道癌可累及胃食管结合部，可能引起呕血或便血；如果侵犯气管可引起呼吸困难或咯血。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全世界每年约有30万人死于食道癌，中国是世界上食道癌高发地区之一，发病率与病死率都相对较高。发病率在全部恶性肿瘤中排第6位，死亡率约为第4位，平均每年病死约15万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌的发病因素很多，年龄、性别、职业、种族、地域、生活环境、饮食生活习惯、基因、炎症与创伤、微量元素，都有一定关系。从性别看，男多于女，发病年龄多在40岁以上，但值得警惕的是，近年来40岁以下发病者有增长趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从地域看，农村食道癌发病率高于城市。但这里的地域实质是经济发展水平。一般来说，在相对发达的地区，肺癌、结直肠癌、乳腺癌、甲状腺癌和前列腺癌高发，而在经济相对落后地区，则是消化道肿瘤如胃癌、食道癌和肝癌等恶性肿瘤高发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从单纯的地理分布看，中国食道癌高发区主要集中在太行山脉附近：河南、河北、山西、山东、安徽、江苏苏北区域。这种发病的地域性在癌症中很常见，比如鼻咽癌的高发地区就是广东、广西、福建、湖南等南方地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一种地理分布，其实是基因分布。食道癌的其他高发区域与中原移民有关，包括四川南充、四川盐亭、广东汕头、福建福州等地区。这是因为特定人群带有易感基因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;食道癌的高危因素，日常生活中最常见，可以总结为四个字：烟、酒、烫、腌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流行病学调查发现一些食道癌高发区居民吸烟相当普遍，一些地区居民不吸烟，食道癌则很少见。在嗜好吸黑檀叶烟和咀嚼萎叶的印度穆斯林、基督教徒和印度教徒中，食道癌发病率高，而无此嗜好的拜火教徒中食道癌则很少见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流行病学调查，还发现许多食道癌患者有大量饮酒史。英国和中国香港科学家调查了香港食道癌患者的吸烟及饮酒情况，经过详尽对比分析，发现饮酒可能比吸烟更容易导致食道癌发生。中国食道癌主要为鳞状细胞癌，吸烟与重度饮酒是引起食道鳞癌的重要因素，对于食道鳞癌，吸烟者的发生率增加3-8倍，而饮酒者增加7-50倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我国食道癌高发区中，许多居民和食道癌患者都有好吃热食习惯。研究者测量了高发区居民的食物温度，发现可高达70℃-80℃，最高为80℃-88℃。这是一个非常烫的温度了。75℃热水就可以导致小鼠上皮细胞变性，黏膜炎症和细胞核酸代谢受影响，所以长期过烫饮食造成的局部炎症和热刺激，可能是食道癌发病的促发或诱发因素。在日本，喜吃烫粥烫茶人群均有较高的发病率。除了吃烫的食物，暴饮暴食、快速饮食、干硬食，也会刺激食道，引发癌症。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚硝酸盐也是导致食道癌、胃癌的重要因素，长期食用腌制食物，亚硝酸盐摄取过量，也会导致食道癌。在食道癌高发区，粮食和饮水中的亚硝胺含量明显高于其他地区。六十多年前，胃癌是日本主要的癌症，在1970年代普及冰箱后，人们吃腌制的食物少了，日本胃癌发病率大幅下降。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，食道癌虽然可怕，也是可以预防的，避免高危因素，如吸烟、重度饮酒，少吃腌制食品，少吃烫的东西，如果当地饮水质量不好，可以加装净水器。住在高发地区、年龄在45岁以上、有直系家属食道癌或消化道癌症病史，或其他癌症病史、有食道癌的癌前疾病的人，要进行食道癌筛查，可以早发现早治疗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[外交部：已确认有3名中国公民在巴以冲突中不幸遇难 2人失联]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258473]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 15:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022427116074&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;19.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg &quot; data-url=&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/rxPYRAIDGO8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://125143450 7 .vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/959fffc55576678022427116074/rxPYRAIDGO8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Wang Wenbin hosted a regular press conference. A reporter asked: According to reports, the new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused more than 10,000 casualties, including many foreign citizens in Israel. So far, 22 US citizens have died and more than 10 British citizens have died or are missing. Does the spokesperson know the current casualties of Chinese citizens?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wenbin said that it is understood that three Chinese citizens have been confirmed to have been unfortunately killed in the conflict, two people have lost contact, and several people were injured. We are deeply concerned about the victims. Expressing deep condolences and sincere condolences to the families of the victims and the injured. Relevant Chinese diplomatic missions abroad are making every effort to coordinate the treatment of the injured, do a good job in the aftermath of the victims, urge foreign parties to make every effort to search and rescue the missing persons, and take all effective measures to ensure the safety of Chinese personnel and institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汇金出手增持四大行 系时隔8年再出手]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258427]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Central Huijin&quot;) increased its A-share holdings. It has been eight years since Central Huijin last increased its holdings in the four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks was approximately 477 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to announcements from the four major banks, this increase in holdings is just the beginning. Central Huijin will continue to increase holdings in the secondary market in its own name in the next 6 months (counting from the date of this increase in holdings). The four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin is a wholly state-owned company established in 2003. It has strong capital strength and holds shares in nearly 20 leading companies in four major categories, including banking, insurance, securities, and comprehensive institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This increase in holdings of the four major banks is of great significance to insiders in the securities industry. It sends a positive signal of stabilizing the capital market. It is also expected to drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve the rhythm of the sector. Large with small, the floor pushes the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Operation again after 8 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin increased its A-share holdings by 37.2722 million shares, 27.61 million shares, 24.8879 million shares and 18.38 million shares, and planned to increase its A-share holdings in the next 6 months (from the date of this increase). It continued to increase its holdings of the Bank’s shares in the secondary market in its own name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much is the amount of this increase? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, the four major banks increased their holdings by a total of 477 million yuan. Among them, the highest is 136 million yuan from Agricultural Bank of China, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China with 130 million yuan, China Construction Bank with approximately 117 million yuan, and Bank of China with 94 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Central Huijin increased capital for the four major banks was in 2015, at a total cost of nearly 20 billion yuan. In 2015, Central Huijin increased its holdings in Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank by 1.255 billion shares, 1.014 billion shares, 1.810 billion shares, and 497 million shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has also led some market participants to predict that Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks is only the beginning, and the proportion of subsequent holdings may be further increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has strong financial strength. According to the 2023 semi-annual report, its total assets and net assets are as high as 6.71 trillion yuan and 6.21 trillion yuan respectively. Its operating performance is also remarkable, with operating income of 323.615 billion yuan and operating profit of 316.607 billion yuan in the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Affect geometry? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has increased its holdings in the four major banks, and its market impact cannot be underestimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yifeng, chief financial analyst at Everbright Securities, said that Huijin’s increase in holdings sends a positive signal to stabilize the capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the four major banks have stable profits and high dividend rates, but they are at very low valuation levels. Huijin&#39;s increase in holdings demonstrates the controlling shareholder&#39;s confidence in state-owned financial institutions with low valuations and high dividends; secondly, the four major banks have a larger weight in the Shanghai Composite Index, and continued increase in holdings is expected to have net-breaking valuations but stable operations and dividends Companies with high profitability will form support, which will help boost market confidence; finally, the four major banks play the role of &quot;lead goose&quot; in credit extension, and this increase in holdings will also help convey confidence in the stability of my country&#39;s financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Ma Kunpeng, chief analyst of CITIC Securities Bank, this will drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve large and small stocks, and the floor will push the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, he believes that the four major banks are the cornerstone of the banking sector and have key guiding significance for the overall prosperity of the sector. They are also the core of the banking industry’s valuation system with Chinese characteristics. They are important for today’s increase in holdings and The proactive announcement of the willingness to increase holdings in the future and the entry of real money into the market are not only an overall support for the banking sector, but also a high degree of affirmation of the special valuation of banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It suggested that we should attach great importance to the systematic revaluation of the banking sector starting from the special valuation of major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng regards the special valuation of major state-owned banks as a systematic revaluation supported by real logic and believes that it has three major logical pillars: First, the risks of major state-owned banks in key areas such as real estate and urban investment Not high, significantly better than the industry average; secondly, historical bad debt has been completely cleared, and the full-caliber bad debt rate has fully reflected and digested the bad debt implied by the current valuation, and has peaked; furthermore, the ROE of major banks has been at the bottom, promoting The profit growth rate at the critical point of ROE recovery is very close to the current profit growth rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng believes that on the one hand, the current macro economy is at a critical turning point for stabilization and improvement, and the macro turning point is more beneficial to major banks that are more biased towards sector beta. On the other hand, the main line logic of the special evaluation of major banks this year is also conducive to major banks taking the lead in performing. Therefore, unlike the previous rhythm of first anchoring the sector&#39;s ceiling valuation and then driving low valuations, this year&#39;s rhythm should be the opposite, first raising the sector&#39;s floor valuation and then pushing the ceiling higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的一则班内社会学调查：为何现在的年轻人不喜欢回家了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258419]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A recent post is very popular. The original text says this, &quot;When you are helpless, you often have thoughts in your mind. I said &#39;I want to go home&#39;, but it seems that it is not the real &#39;home&#39; in reality, but a safe, comfortable place in my imagination, without pain and trouble.&quot; I estimate that the posters are most likely young people, and the people who post and comment on them are also mostly young. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Home, also known as home in English, is different from house, which is only a building with residential functions. Home is a word with obvious cultural and geographical color, often associated with family, family, affection, warmth, shelter, arms, harbor, etc. Going home, the so-called going home, is also full of positive energy, a sense of justice and legitimacy, such as &quot;go home often&quot;, &quot;rich or not, go home for the New Year&quot;, &quot;fallen leaves return to their roots&quot; and other popular This can be seen in the song titles or sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, I must go home during holidays, especially long holidays. The simple truth is that it was very difficult for my parents to raise and train me as an adult. Now that they are older, I have no reason not to take the time to go home to visit and accompany them. In other words, if I don’t go home during the holidays and only play by myself or play with my wife and children, I will feel guilty and feel that I am a selfish and heartless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Times have changed, and today’s young people, especially those born in the 1990s and 2000s, have completely different understandings and perceptions of home and returning home. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My sociological investigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;My nephew is a freshman. During this past holiday, he only stayed at home for three days and asked his friends out on the fourth day. Have fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I randomly asked the 18 people I teach, including sophomores and juniors, 7 of them &quot;did not go home during this holiday&quot; and 7 of them &quot;stayed home for 7 days or more&quot;. 1 person, 3 people &quot;stayed home for 5-6 days&quot;, 4 people &quot;stayed home for 3-4 days&quot;, and 3 people &quot;stayed home for 1-2 days&quot;. Among the 7 people who did not go home, 5 people directly expressed that they &quot;didn&#39;t like going home&quot; and 2 people said that &quot;I had other arrangements during the holiday, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot; Among the 11 students who went home, 92% held the view that they “like to go home, but don’t like to stay at home for too long.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One conclusion is that the young people I observed do not like to go home very much, or do not like to stay at home for too long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering returning home as a population movement phenomenon, even if it is a temporary population movement, we might as well borrow the push-pull theory of demography to explain: Going home proves that there is something attractive to me at home, which makes me Things that feel comfortable, this is the &quot;pull&quot;, pull me home; if I don&#39;t want to go home, don&#39;t go home, or want to leave home after a few days, there must be something I don&#39;t like at home that makes me feel The uncomfortable place, this is the &quot;thrust&quot;, pushing me away from home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For young people, what are the main components of the “pull” to go home? &quot;It&#39;s holiday, I want to go home and eat something delicious&quot;, &quot;Studying at school is too stressful, I want to go home and rest for a few days&quot;, &quot;I miss my parents and want to go home to spend a few days with them&quot;, &quot;They It’s not easy to support my studies, so I have to go home and spend time with them during the holidays.” The students generally gave their answers in terms of emotional expression and feedback, as well as self-repair and relaxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are obviously many &quot;push&quot; components of not going home, not wanting to go home, and wanting to leave home soon after returning home. Here are some of the answers I got, and I divided them into categories according to the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have other more important arrangements: &quot;I traveled with my boyfriend during the holidays. We went to Xi&#39;an to watch a concert, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save money ’s: “If I don’t go home, I can save a lot of money. For example, if I stay at school for eight days, I can get it for 500 yuan, but the high-speed rail ticket alone costs more than 500 yuan for me to go home. Not going home is a big deal for me. A kind of financial savings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who feel that there are communication barriers with their parents, cannot talk together, or feel that they are not free and uncomfortable: &quot;Communicating with parents is obviously not as pleasant as communicating with roommates or peers. , my real sense of gain is also much different.&quot; &quot;I want to relax when I go home, such as watching a movie with my friends. I like to put on makeup before going out. My mother likes to keep asking, who are I with and what are I doing? , What time will you go home? I’m very annoyed by it. I feel like I don’t have any freedom at home. I don’t like this feeling.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common ones are those who have thoughts about their parents’ thoughts, or want to get rid of their parents’ judgment on their own lives: “It was fine for the first two days when I went home. I ate the food cooked by my mother. I was very happy and relaxed, but Later, my parents, especially my dad, always asked me about my life plans and future plans, which made me feel even more stressed.&quot; &quot;As soon as I came back, my dad kept nagging me in my ears to take the postgraduate entrance examination and public entrance examination. , saying that a certain job has security and will be relatively stable in the future, and that that job is not good and has no future, etc., &quot;My mother gave me some instructions on how to find a boyfriend, telling me not to find a boyfriend in such and such a place, but to find a fellow villager. I&#39;m about to collapse.&quot; &quot;In the eyes of my parents, I am always a child. Once my ideas are inconsistent with theirs, they will think that I am disobedient, rebellious, and unfilial, and they will criticize me and scold me. &quot;I don&#39;t like this.&quot; &quot;My dad is a local teacher in our area. He wants me to return to my hometown to be a teacher after graduation, which will be stable and relaxing. The problem is that I don&#39;t want to go home, and I don&#39;t want to be a teacher.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that among the various elements of &quot;push&quot; in the eyes of the students, the differences in ideological concepts and lifestyles between the two generations, parental authority, and (excessive) control of children&#39;s rights to free development and self-determination Intervention is the most obvious manifestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the acquisition and growth of students from professional fields has also made the parent-child relationship relatively tense, and conflicts or contradictions have become apparent. Some students said, &quot;I am studying sociology. I have a certain theoretical understanding of power asymmetry and discipline. When I went home and heard what my parents said to me, I clearly felt that their words were full of PUA, and their words and deeds reflected obvious power discipline. The traces of what I learned in school are vividly reproduced in my home, and this feeling makes me extremely distressed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, some students also pay attention to strategies when communicating or confronting their parents. One student mentioned, “When my parents talk about topics I don’t want to talk about, such as finding a partner, my The strategy is usually to use other topics to divert the topic. I will say that I am very busy, I have to study, I have to study, I have no time to fall in love, etc. to prevaricate them. I generally do not have head-on or direct conflicts with them, and I will selectively avoid them. Something I don’t want to talk about”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;push&quot; is greater than or significantly greater than the &quot;pull&quot;, the realistic choice for young people is naturally that they don&#39;t really want to go home, or they want to leave home after they can&#39;t stay home for a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It’s okay to go home; it’s not okay to stay for a long time”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, most young people will not resist going home, but they are limited by the differences in thoughts and concepts between generations. , there are obvious differences in the understanding and cognition of some things and problems, which often leads to some problems when young people and their parents stay under the same roof for a long time. Young people have the mentality of doing more than doing less, so they choose not to Go home, or go home less often, or reduce the number of days you stay at home. In a nutshell, &quot;It&#39;s okay to go home; it&#39;s not okay to stay for a long time.&quot; This is the choice of most young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the students I surveyed, regarding the frequency or probability of going home during the holidays, I observed: It seems that young people who were born and grew up in a good family or a wealthy family have a relatively low frequency, and those who think they are in a higher position have a lower frequency. Parents who are powerful or well-connected will have more future expectations and life plans and designs for their children. They are more likely to overstep their authority and suppress and restrain their children more frequently. The latter will certainly be more uncomfortable and less free. A classmate said, &quot;My dad always talks in a bossy and arrogant way. I hate it. &#39;You must take the postgraduate entrance examination&#39;, &#39;You must take the public examination&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t need to spend time putting on makeup&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t &quot;I always go out to drink&quot;, &quot;I have eaten more salt than you have traveled&quot;, &quot;If you don&#39;t listen to the old man&#39;s words, you will suffer a lot&quot;, I feel annoyed when I hear these words.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, for those families with average economic conditions, after the children come home, the main thing for the parents is to cook for the children and have fun with the children. The atmosphere is relatively harmonious, and the communication topics are not involved or rarely involved. Children&#39;s future, children&#39;s real feeling is that they are comfortable and comfortable, and they feel no or little pressure. The holidays are real companionship for them, and they fulfill the original meaning of the holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real life, there are still a small number of young people who don’t like to go home. They have fierce arguments with their parents as soon as they come home. They show contempt for their parents. Even when they go home, they are locked up. They go out to watch movies and play games without any verbal or other communication with their parents. For families with average or poor economic conditions, some young people turn a blind eye to the objective fact that their parents save money on food and clothing to support their education and college. They think this is what parents should do and it is a matter of course. &quot;I am Your children, it is only natural that I spend your money.&quot; In their view, parents are synonymous with old traditions, old ideas, decadence and backwardness. Their strategy is usually to &quot;not work together if they have different paths&quot;, that is, to &quot;cut off the relationship&quot; in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, such children are not grateful to their parents for their upbringing. Faced with such a child, the other parent naturally feels disheartened and laments that his fate is bad and his family is unfortunate enough to have raised such a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Problems with parenting styles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not to mention &quot;raising children for old age&quot;, parents work hard to cultivate and support their children. As children, we must have a basic sense of gratitude. Bar? Why is it missing? What is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the root lies in parents and their training methods. Many parents think that the standard of a good parent is to provide their children with basic or relatively superior material living conditions. I will try my best to satisfy my children&#39;s needs. This is even what good parents are all about, but this is not the case. In the process of raising and educating their children, parents cannot stop at purely financial support, but also involve all aspects, such as the source of value and the arduous process of creating value. Parents are too doting on their children. They have always known to give and give away since they were young. Children, let them feel that the material conditions they have are taken for granted, and do not instill in them values ​​such as a sense of responsibility, equality of rights and obligations, and the other side of freedom is self-responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As children, they never know or understand how difficult it is for their parents to make money. Their parents do not give their children the opportunity to experience and appreciate the hardship of their parents making money. Another example is paying attention to the inner world of children and the psychological changes during their growth. Many parents think that it is enough to feed and clothe their children, but they seldom pay attention, care and concern to their children&#39;s spiritual world and spiritual life. They seldom pay attention to, respect and listen to children&#39;s way of thinking and ideas. This is a common problem in so-called &quot;East Asian families&quot;. The common point is that both parties only focus on or care about material supply and acceptance, and do not care about each other&#39;s psychology. State, especially no or very little attention to the other person&#39;s mental state and personality traits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the solution to similar problems, from an economic perspective, when young people grow up and become adults, they theoretically have their own economic and behavioral capabilities. Shouldn&#39;t they completely &quot;cut off the relationship&quot;? Okay, is it okay for you to support yourself now? Then repay me all the fees I paid you after you turned 18, and then talk about &quot;breaking up the relationship&quot;. This may sound harsh, but it is the truth. Parents are adults, and their children are also adults, so they should get along with each other according to the contract in the adult world. If you borrow something, of course you have to repay it. This is only natural. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the question of whether young people are willing to go home, how often they go home, and how many days they stay home essentially refers to the relationship between young people and their parents. Young people and their parents have different values, different cultural levels, different starting points, and different life experiences, which will inevitably lead to different views and opinions. This is a normal phenomenon. In the process of communication or getting along, both parties should adhere to the basic principle of empathy, consider issues from the other party&#39;s perspective, respect the other party more, care more about the other party, especially respect and care about the other party&#39;s inner feelings and experiences, and advocate effective communication between the two parties. and communication to gradually resolve or eliminate the inner barriers and gaps between each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those &quot;rebellious children&quot; or &quot;parasites&quot; who only know how to take without knowing anything in return or feedback, I think parents can consider reducing or even stopping the material support for their children. In the past, they only focused on the material aspects of their children. Conduct in-depth examination and reflection on the parenting methods that focus on life but neglect the spiritual world of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, I would like to return to a concept from the perspective of anthropology - making a home. The corresponding English word is home making, which means that home is not natural or naturally generated. Home is more than just a physical level. It refers more to the social level. Home is the result of social construction. Home requires the joint efforts of parents and children to build, build and operate. Only parents and children adopt common behaviors, actions, consultations and Only through collaboration can a true home be formed, and only then can the home in young people&#39;s imagination truly exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大熊猫野化放归，都要上啥“培训课”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258425]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Giant Panda National Park has beautiful scenery. The picture shows the Liziping area. Photo courtesy of the State Forestry and Grassland Administration&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driving from the urban area of ​​Dujiangyan, Sichuan, along the winding winding mountain road to the west, after driving for more than an hour, we arrived at the China Giant Panda Conservation Research Institute Center (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Panda Center&quot;) Wolong Hetaoping Base. The climate here is cool, rainy and humid, and it is located in the natural living environment of giant pandas. It is very suitable for wild training and captive breeding of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reintroduction of captive giant pandas into the wild is a key technology pioneered by the Panda Center, which is mainly divided into the stages of reintroduction training, release and monitoring. Over the years, generations of scientific researchers have devoted a lot of effort to establish a complete technical system for giant panda wild training and reintroduction monitoring, which has achieved good results in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why should giant pandas be reintroduced into the wild? What significance does this have for the protection of the giant panda population? From captivity to release, what &quot;training courses&quot; do giant pandas need to take? Recently, reporters conducted on-site visits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253798&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers conduct a health check-up on a giant panda cub. Photo by He Shengshan&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild giant panda population&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The mountains and forests are green and the streams are trickling. In the rewilding training area of ​​​​Hetaoping Base, except for a path that the staff walked up and down the mountain, there are almost no traces of human activities, and the original ecology is preserved. In order not to disturb the silence, the reporter turned his cell phone to silent and walked in quietly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the dense jungle, giant panda &quot;Bosi&quot; and his cub are sleeping soundly. Not far away, keepers in &quot;panda suits&quot; were using this time to clean the pens and replenish fresh bamboo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In order to mask the human smell, the &#39;panda suit&#39; is sprayed with extracts of panda feces and urine.&quot; He Shengshan, director of the Field Research Animal Management Department of the Hetaoping Base, told reporters that unlike captive giant pandas, the The breeders are close to and dependent on them, and the breeders trained in the wild must remain &quot;invisible&quot; at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild population of giant pandas, and is of great significance to the protection of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, my country has vigorously implemented natural forest protection, wildlife protection projects and the construction of giant panda national parks to protect giant pandas and their habitats, with remarkable results. The results of the fourth national giant panda survey show that the number of wild giant pandas has increased from 1,114 in the 1970s and 1980s to 1,864, distributed in Qinling, Minshan, Qionglai Mountain, Daxiangling, Xiaoxiangling, Liangshan, etc. Six major mountain systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, natural geographical barriers isolate these wild giant pandas in six major mountain systems, and human activities have divided these six major habitat populations into small local populations that cannot interact with each other. &quot;Habitat fragmentation has resulted in the inability of genetic exchange between isolated populations, reducing the genetic diversity of small local populations and accelerating the disappearance of endangered small populations,&quot; said Wu Daifu, director of the Hetaoping base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To save a species, the integrity and stability of the community in which it is located and the genetic diversity within the species must be protected. &quot;Currently, the main measures taken to protect giant pandas in our country are in-situ protection and ex-situ protection.&quot; Wu Daifu said that the connection point between the two methods is to release giant pandas bred in captivity after rewilding training. Return to small endangered populations in the wild, thereby improving their genetic diversity, reducing the risk of extinction, and reviving the wild giant panda population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As global breeding problems such as difficulty in mating and conceiving and raising young to survive have been overcome, artificial breeding of giant pandas has achieved fruitful results, and the captive giant panda population has achieved self-sustainment. In 2003, the Panda Center launched the training and reintroduction of captive-bred giant pandas into the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2006, the male sub-adult giant panda &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was released into the wild after independent rewilding training. However, less than a year later, workers found its body in the snow. After analysis and judgment, &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; fell from a height and was seriously injured and died during a fight with a wild giant panda for territory and food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Panda Center summarized the failed rewilding case of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; and believed that maybe it was the lack of suitable learning objects that led to the lack of survival ability of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; in the wild; maybe it was because the population in the reintroduction area was saturated, and &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was not able to survive in the wild. &quot;Lack of enough living space; the competition for territory and mates among adult male giant pandas in the wild is extremely fierce. &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; may not have enough fighting experience and cannot resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sum up experience and make persistent efforts. In 2010, with the stable growth of the captive giant panda population, the Panda Center launched the second phase of the captive giant panda rewilding training project, and proposed for the first time a new rewilding training method of &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253797&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The giant panda &quot;Qin Xin&quot; was released into the wild. Photo by He Haiyang&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Helping giant panda cubs learn wild survival skills as soon as they are born&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“At 1:16 in the morning, the cub screamed, &quot;The mother lay on her side to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 4:53 am, the mother adjusted her sleeping position to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 8 am, the mother ate 9 bamboos in the morning and drank water twice. The cub screamed loudly and defecated once, but there were no abnormalities.&quot; ...In the monitoring room of the Hetaoping base, the work log of the keepers records in detail the daily activities of the giant panda &quot;Hui Hui&quot; and her newborn cubs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are 4 giant panda cubs in the first stage of rewilding training at the Hetaoping Base: &quot;Zhichun Zai&quot; and &quot;Bosi Zai&quot; who are over 1 years old, and two newborn cubs . &quot;All organs of newly born giant panda cubs are not fully developed. We must always pay attention to them and conduct video surveillance around the clock, and take timely measures if any abnormality occurs,&quot; said breeder Zhang Dalei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the growth and behavioral development characteristics of giant pandas, rewilding training is divided into two stages. From birth to about 1 year old, in a small training circle of about 2,000 square meters, the cubs eat breast milk. ; From about 1 year old to before release, in a large training circle of 200,000-300,000 square meters, the cubs gradually learn to eat bamboo independently. The large-scale training enclosure is located in the wild habitat environment of giant pandas, where there are tall trees, dense bamboo forests and complex terrain, in a completely natural state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on long-term practice and research, the Panda Center creatively implements &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot; training. &quot;From birth, the cubs live with their mothers and gradually learn survival skills such as foraging for food, finding water sources, and avoiding natural enemies in nature. In the past, breeders could not teach pandas to climb trees in a few days. Now panda mothers use their mouths to climb trees. Just push the baby up the tree, and the panda baby will learn to climb the tree twice.&quot; He Shengshan said that giant pandas can be released into the wild only after completing a series of training and undergoing expert evaluation. &quot;At this time, two or three-year-old pandas will learn to climb trees. Giant pandas are in the post-weaning and pre-adult stage, and as sub-adults, it is easier to integrate into the wild giant panda population.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The selection of female animals is very particular. &quot;It is best for the mother animal to be a multi-parous giant panda with experience in wild life, or an individual with strong ability to raise young.&quot; He Shengshan said that at the same time, the body of the mother animal must be kept in good health, and factors such as age and genetic background must also be considered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid &quot;imprinting behavior&quot; in giant panda cubs, the impact of human activities must be minimized. &quot;Every time the female panda is fed food, the keeper will put on a &#39;panda suit&#39; to prevent the cubs from becoming dependent on humans.&quot; Zhang Dalei said that pandas should be made to avoid humans as soon as they sense humans instead of actively approaching them. Only then can they return to the jungle smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to feeding food, cleaning the enclosures, etc., keepers are also responsible for observing and recording the growth, development and behavioral performance of giant pandas, such as the time of first walking, first climbing, first eating bamboo, etc. Since 2012, Zhang Dalei has raised 7 giant pandas for rewilding training. &quot;Although the work is hard and tiring, as long as they return to the wild and live a healthy life, I will feel a sense of accomplishment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Accompanying giant pandas all year round is an enviable job, but it also contains risks and challenges that few people know about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In summer, mudslides often occur in the mountains, and the wild training circle is often put to the test. &quot;The mudslide that occurred on August 20, 2019, was less than 100 meters away from the cabin where we were resting. The situation at that time was very thrilling.&quot; He Shengshan still has lingering fears. Encountering wild animals in the wild is also common. &quot;Wild boars, snakes, etc. are often encountered in the mountains. Only by accumulating rich experience and being fully prepared can we avoid danger again and again,&quot; He Shengshan said. Now, he and his colleagues always make prevention plans in advance, bring enough supplies before going up the mountain, and carry satellite phones with them to ensure smooth communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researcher Wei Hua almost lost his life while training giant pandas in the wild. In December 2016, the cub &quot;Baxi&quot; who was trained in Tiantai Mountain was close to the age of release, but no sign of &quot;Baxi&quot; was found for two consecutive days. Wei Hua and his colleagues were very worried and entered the training circle to search, but found no trace of him. Thinking of being attacked and seriously injured by the giant panda mother &quot;Ximei&quot; who was eager to protect her cubs. Even so, Wei Hua still believes: &quot;&#39;Ximei&#39; biting me shows that it is wild and maternal. This is exactly the goal we pursue when releasing giant pandas into the wild.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Giant panda mother teaches her cub to climb a tree. Photo by Xue Yubin&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Carry out the reintroduction of giant pandas in an orderly manner to improve the genetic diversity of small populations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After giant panda rewilding training, how to determine Release back into the habitat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao, senior engineer of the Investigation and Monitoring Department of the Panda Center, said that scientific researchers will comprehensively consider various factors such as suitable habitat quality, area, staple food bamboo biomass, and genetic background of released giant pandas to determine the release site. . In 2018, giant pandas &quot;Qin Xin&quot; and &quot;Little Walnut&quot; were released into the Longxi Hongkou National Nature Reserve in Dujiangyan City, located in the Minshan Mountains, after undergoing wild training and scientific evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to monitor the survival status of giant pandas after they are released? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao said that when giant pandas are released, they will be put on an electronic collar that can be tracked and monitored, and their movement trajectory, health status and other information will be tracked through satellite signals. &quot;However, the collar It will fall off in about a year and a half, and long-term tracking and monitoring cannot be carried out. We must rely on infrared cameras, feces sampling and other methods to collect more data.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wherever the giant panda is, we will follow it.&quot; Xie Hao He said that the monitoring team members searched for giant panda feces in the deep mountains and old forests, recorded relevant detailed information, and analyzed the giant pandas&#39; gender, age, population, and genetic relationships by extracting DNA. &quot;In the mountains and valleys, we often walk for more than half a month, resting wherever we catch up at night. Sometimes we can&#39;t keep up with food supplies, and we have to go hungry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 2021, Dujiangyan During field monitoring, staff of the city&#39;s state-owned forest farm captured images of wild giant pandas through infrared cameras, which were suspected to be giant pandas released in 2018. A team of experts went to the site to inspect and collect fecal samples for further testing. Through the DNA extracted from it, it was determined that this female giant panda over 5 years old was the giant panda &quot;Little Walnut&quot; released in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253801&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers use radio equipment to track and monitor the movements of giant pandas. Photo courtesy of China Giant Panda Conservation and Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingchun, deputy director of the Wild Ecology Research Office of the Panda Center, was excited when he saw the image of &quot;Little Walnut&quot;, &quot;This giant panda has a round body and a good mental state.&quot; Normal and living in good condition in the wild. When the DNA identification results confirmed that it was indeed &#39;Little Walnut&#39;, the rewilding training team was very excited. This showed that the rewilding training of &#39;Little Walnut&#39; for more than two years was successful. I hope it can be It thrives in the wild, and we look forward to finding a suitable husband, breeding offspring, and bringing us more surprises!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the Panda Center has released 11 captive-bred giant pandas, and 9 are still alive. , 7 of which were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Xiaoxiangling Mountain System that are at risk of extinction, and 2 were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Minshan Mountain System.放归的大熊猫中，有1雄4雌共5只已满6岁，处于可以繁殖的壮年阶段。 “放归大熊猫融入野生种群并且繁育后代，才能达到壮大野生种群的目的。但要找到放归大熊猫有后代的明确证据，需要耐心和时间。”吴代福表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，我国正在构建国家公园天、空、地一体化监测体系。 “我们以此为契机，在大熊猫野化放归的区域内增加摄像头、红外相机等监测设备，提升大空间监测能力。”熊猫中心调查监测处处长杨建说，同时加强颈圈研发，努力提高电池使用寿命、提升定位精准度、实现录音实时回传，以掌握大熊猫野外动向等更多野外生存信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们将通过种群的动态监测，评估遗传贡献。”杨建说，通过“猫脸识别”及DNA个体识别等技术，从大熊猫亲缘关系、年龄结构及遗传水平等方面开展动态监测，建立区域种群数量、结构和地理分布数据库，验证放归个体是否繁育后代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴代福表示，将在大熊猫国家公园范围内，从遗传多样性、种群动态、群落特征及人类干扰等多方面，解析局域濒危小种群复壮受限制因素，科学制定规划，有序开展大熊猫放归，改善微小种群遗传多样性。同时，通过在生态廊道开展放归，增强种群间的基因连通性，为实现大熊猫种群的野外复壮提供关键支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，大熊猫野化培训梯队已经建立，未来每年将有培训合格的大熊猫个体放归野外，并努力复壮大熊猫小种群。 “我们将加快大熊猫野化培训、放归、监测等关键技术的创新和推广应用，力争每年放归大熊猫3至6只，并通过引种加大野生大熊猫濒危小种群资源保护，逐步建立野生大熊猫遗传种质资源库，实现圈养种群与野生种群基因双向交流。”吴代福说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列情报机构睡着了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258423]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W519uIJUPDbL0XMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1436&quot; height=&quot;958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W519uIJUPDbL0XMu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253630&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，加沙城，巴勒斯坦武装分子向以色列发射火箭弹&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月7日起，巴勒斯坦抵抗组织哈马斯对巴以边境地带的以色列多个城市发动了复合偷袭，不仅发射了大量的火箭弹，同时还进行了猛烈地面攻击。根据目前统计，以色列方面至少有700人死于哈马斯的攻击，这是1973年赎罪日战争以来，以色列军民在战争中死伤最惨重的一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列总理内塔尼亚胡向人民承诺将对哈马斯施以“可怕的复仇”，并宣布进入战争状态，这也是1973年赎罪日战争结束后以色列50年来第一次宣布进入战争状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然本次袭击事发突然，但如此大规模的攻击事发前应该会有不少蛛丝马迹可循，拥有号称世界上最高效情报机构摩萨德的以色列，为何却未能提前预警呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在讨论这个问题之前，我们首先需要了解，巴以控制区内的情报工作在以色列的定位是国内安全业务，因此主要负责机构并不是赫赫有名的摩萨德（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;情报特务局&lt;/span>;），而是负责国内安保的辛贝特（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;国家安全局&lt;/span>;）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛贝特在加沙地带过去的工作一直被认为是低调且有效的，比如在“绿王子行动”中，他们曾成功策反哈马斯高层哈桑·尤素福的儿子摩萨卜·哈桑·尤素福，自1996年后的十多年里，通过他获得了大量来自哈马斯组织核心决策层的情报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列之所以将巴以地区的主要情报工作划分给辛贝特，实际上是因为两地人员往来比较频繁，因此有很多行动和检查需要警察部门配合，而摩萨德主要负责对外情报和秘密行动，旗下人员与地方警力配合较少，并不利于无缝衔接。辛贝特除了对内反情报工作和反恐之外，还有要人及重要部门的警卫保护工作，与警察部门衔接紧密，显然更利于开展工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以真要追究对此次哈马斯突袭应对不力的责任，辛贝特难辞其咎，但归根结底，本次事件也暴露了以色列军警情报安全系统结构性的失败。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据一些内部人员向我提供的信息，这次以色列方面应对不力的主要原因有几点：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是以色列从2022年开始的宪政危机，导致军警情报安全系统人心惶惶。内塔尼亚胡领导的右翼政府进行的司法改革，可能已经动摇了以色列民族团结的国本，导致有经验的情报人员和军警提前退休辞职，移民海外，在职人员也难免士气低落，削弱了整体的作战能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次是以色列内部治安最近一年多形势严峻，阿拉伯裔黑帮在街头仇杀枪战已经严重影响以色列的社会安全，导致辛贝特和警察部门疲于奔命，大量资源被用于应对有组织犯罪调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外也有技术上的原因，近年来辛贝特和警方更倾向依赖信号情报和技术侦查，由于广泛的电子监听和空中侦察业务，以及大数据人工智能情报分析，能够获得远比过去更为海量的情报信息，并且自动化处理十分快捷。像“绿王子行动”这样古典的人工情报获取手段已成了“过时”的手艺，不再是工作重点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然信号情报近年来让以色列占尽优势，也符合情报工作的发展方向，但现在已经被哈马斯组织找到了应对的方法。由于加沙地带并不大，大量信息传递大可以通过原始的人传人方式逃避信号侦察，既然没有电子通信，再强大的监听技术也无用武之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;造成现在的结果，对于以色列而言可以说是士气低落、人员流失、资源倾斜和对手进化等综合原因造成的。实际上情报工作的复杂性远远超出了外界的想象，有人用大海捞针来形容，其实并不准确，此类反恐情报工作更像是在一个充满针的大海中，找到那根有毒的针。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对手的反情报工作其实并不限于保密，同时也会放出大量真真假假的威胁信息以混淆视听，犹如不断喊“狼来了”的牧童，让人无所适从。这次以色列遭受重大损失，当然要追究情报和安全机构的责任，然而从专业角度审视，情报与反情报的对抗从未停止过。通过网络渗透、人工智能、大数据分析所获得的信号情报，并非未来军事、反恐的唯一方式，多手段侦察、多维度审视，才能降低战争迷雾的负面影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从费翔到蔡国庆，年轻一代为什么狂追“妈妈严选”男偶像？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/302c6f1c787a6b4c0b7f30a6519e0044.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/302c6f1c787a6b4c0b7f30a6519e0044.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;最近，两位60后明星费翔和蔡国庆，在互联网上“翻红”，深受年轻人的喜爱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们都曾是妈妈年轻岁月时的偶像，被网友称为“妈妈严选”。很多网友感慨，这个夏天是自己“质疑妈妈、理解妈妈、成为妈妈”的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两位“妈妈严选”曾经有多红？为什么如今的年轻人会跟妈妈一样，被他们圈粉？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“妈妈严选”的偶像曾有多火&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这个夏天之前，在很多年轻人眼里，费翔、蔡国庆都属于“过气”明星——至少在年轻人群体里是如此。然而，在上世纪八九十年代，在很多妈妈青春年少的时候，费翔和蔡国庆的人气可以匹敌今日的顶流。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;费翔1960年出生于中国台湾，1978年，费翔从台北士林美国学校毕业，以优异成绩考入美国斯坦福大学念医科。一年后转入斯坦福大学戏剧系。 1981年费翔回到台湾，出演张艾嘉导演的台视单元剧《十一个女人》，踏入演艺圈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1982年，费翔加入EMI唱片（百代唱片），在台湾推出首张个人专辑《流连》，开始走红，在新加坡评选的亚洲十大歌星，费翔与台湾歌星刘文正、费玉清、凤飞飞、江玲同时入选并居前五名。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1986年，费翔陪母亲回北京探望外婆，这个契机激起了费翔深切的家国情怀，他转赴中国大陆发展，并出版了在大陆的第一张个人专辑《跨越四海的歌声》，成为第一位跨越海峡进军大陆歌坛的台湾艺人，磁带发行一举突破百万大关。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1987年，费翔以第一位回到祖国大陆的台湾歌手身份在中央电视台的春节联欢晚会上演唱歌曲《故乡的云》《冬天里的一把火》，一夜之间，费翔在大陆的人气达到巅峰。其洋气、开放、自由、奔放的形象、曲风&lt;/span>;和表演风格，让人耳目一新，也令千千万万的少女为之疯狂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;费翔一连在大陆发行多张专辑，张张火爆。 1989年，费翔在中国大陆12个城市共举办了65场演唱会，中央电视台和中央新闻电影制片厂还专门拍成录影带和影片向全国播放。 1990年费翔前往纽约，在百老汇发展，并成功转型为有扎实演唱功力的百老汇演员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以说，1980年代的费翔在国内的地位堪称顶流中的顶流，对于当时的观众来说，费翔&lt;span>;不仅仅是一个明星，他的身上更是承载着人们对于美好、未来与希望的想象，如同冬天里的一把火，照亮了很多人的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1968年，蔡国庆出生，而且他年少就成名。 7岁加入中央人民广播电台少儿合唱团，9岁出版首张唱片，1986年，蔡国庆参加第一届全国百名歌星演唱会，开始自己的歌唱生涯。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1990年，北京举办第四届全国青年歌手大奖赛，蔡国庆以一首《北京的桥》获得了通俗唱法组的银奖。同一年的北京亚运会，这是我国第一次举办的综合性的一场国际体育大赛，蔡国庆在闭幕式的晚会上领唱了《今夜&lt;/span>;星光灿烂》，进一步为全国观众所熟知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991年，蔡国庆第一次登上中央电视台春节联欢晚会的舞台，演唱《去远方》。 1991年至1995年，蔡国庆连续五届以主要演员身份参加。蔡国庆是春晚的常客，至今他已23次登上春晚舞台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入新世纪以后，蔡国庆仍然活跃在歌坛，参加各种重要的文艺演出，也不时以评委的身份参加一些综艺节目。蔡国庆儒雅、庄重的形象，仍然是妈妈的心头好，但也让一些年轻人觉得有点距离，所以他在年轻一代里人气并不高，很多人知道&lt;span>;他，并不会特别去喜欢他。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d8c7f22596c2ea307d89512e69702a61.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d8c7f22596c2ea307d89512e69702a61.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253564&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“理解妈妈，成为妈妈”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;两位“妈妈严选”都曾红极一时，只是在互联网时代和粉丝经济时代，他们的影响力更多局限于妈妈辈。这样的局面在这个夏天发生了改变，为何年轻人纷纷对“妈妈严选”上头了？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;首先是从明星的角度来看。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当内娱捧出的&lt;/span>;许多年轻顶流，天价片酬、演技差、不敬业、私德不佳等丑闻一再暴露，“妈妈严选”的出现让年轻人发现：老一辈的艺人，是如此的自律、敬业、专业，这才是明星的榜样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果费翔饰演的殷寿没有立住，也就不会有《封神第一部》的成功。观众也在电影中看到了费翔的身材，那简直不像是一个六十多岁的中老年男性的身体，肌肉线条是如此分明，看不到赘肉的痕迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要保持健康而良好的身材，离不&lt;span>;开自律。费翔一进组就严格控制饮食，进行马术&lt;/span>;、武术、健身等魔鬼训练，拍戏时间长达一年半时间，他的训练也持续一年半时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;费翔业务能力很强，还非常敬业。早在2012年，他与乌尔善合作的《画皮II》上映，他就参与了《画皮II》的多次宣传，更是一人承担了电影在台湾的宣传。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一次《封神第一部》的路演&lt;span>;，29城、33天、170场，费翔29个城市路演都参与了，一共参与了164场路演，强度如此之大，他依然亲力亲为，奋战在第一线。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;威尼斯电影节，他一开始也是一个人代表了一整个剧组前往，在当地上映的《封神第一部》的英文字幕甚至是费翔通宵参与翻译的，第二天还要去出席活动……内娱如今有多少大小明星能够敬业到如此程度？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这一次蔡国庆参加了&lt;/span>;《披荆斩棘3》，很多人以为他会躺在功劳簿上睡大觉，蔡国庆却丝毫没有架子，没有包袱。初舞台上，他挑战了周杰伦的《Mojito》，让观众第一次如此清晰地听清这首歌的歌词，但蔡国庆的演唱也有别于周杰伦的风味，他的业务能力仍然在线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，无论是练歌还是练舞，蔡国庆都是保持积极昂扬充沛的精神状态，他努力、谦虚而清醒：“有突破后拿出有水准的作品，对我就是天大的好事；能得到今天观众的认&lt;span>;可，就是莫大鼓励。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;年轻人追捧“妈妈严选”，还有一个是晚辈看待长辈的视角。就比如年轻人之所以亲切称呼费翔为“费翔daddy”，不仅仅在于他在《封神第一部》中饰演的就是一个父亲，也在于他是很多年轻人心中理想的父亲形象、理想的长辈形象。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;现实生活中，很多长辈往往热衷于以长辈的身份对年轻人说教，对年轻人的生活方式指手画脚。而从费翔的一系列访谈中，我们可以看出他对每个人生活方式的尊重，他对于婚姻、爱情以及其他关键的人生议题都有深刻的洞察。他不干涉，不说教，睿智又优雅。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;也有一些长辈，热衷于以长辈的身份倚老卖老，什么都是我老我说了算，年轻人就得听我的，年轻人就得尊重我、得捧我……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在《披荆斩棘3》中，很多年轻人才第一次看到一个那么真实、那么私人的蔡国庆：他一点架子没有，很放得开，完全能够跟年轻人打成一片，别人提的建议他都愿意“听劝”，也随和亲切得不得了……这样的“长辈”谁不爱处？年轻人不会有下位者的压力、尴尬与煎熬，他们内心中依然对长辈有敬重，他们也依然能够自由轻松地做自己。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;总之，年轻人追捧“妈妈严选”的背后，是年轻人对于时下内娱生态的不满，是年轻人苦一些长辈的压力久矣却无力挣脱或敢怒不敢言的无奈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在寄望于这样的“妈妈严选”能够多一些的同时，年轻人倒也不妨以“妈妈严选”为榜样，成长为一个更好的人，最后也能成为更好的长辈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从张亮和杨国福说起：特色县的产业聚集为何常常以乡情亲缘为纽带？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258299]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;网上曾传言两大麻辣烫巨头张亮和杨国福是亲戚：张亮本来在舅舅杨国福的店里打工，后来出去单干，创立了张亮麻辣烫。后来，张亮对此：“没有血缘关系，是亲属关系。”杨国福也作出了和张亮一致的表述。所以，有一点多半是肯定的，那就是张亮的确受到了杨国福的启发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张亮和杨国福也启发了当地人，两人的老家哈尔滨宾县，发展成了麻辣烫行业的集聚地，除了张亮和杨国福之外，还有许多其他品牌，堪称“麻辣烫之都”。用杨国福公司生产负责人的话就是：“一个村子干，大家都跟着干，这个行业就起来了。”不难想见，无数个宾县有野心的年轻人，正是顺着他们的足迹，进入麻辣烫行业创业，从而改变自己的命运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，这并非特例。很多人会记得，上高中的时候，学校周围的打印店是湖南人开的；几千里之外的大学，学校里与周边的复印店还是湖南人开的；读研究生，换一个地方，打印店仍然是湖南人开的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些湖南人都来自娄底市新化县，著名的复印之乡。新化县位于湖南省中部，境内山脉纵横，环境恶劣，人均耕地不到0.15亩。恶劣的自然环境，逼迫新化人走出去，早在改革开放之前的1960年，新化人易代兴、易代育兄弟在四川涪陵偶然学会了机械打字机维修技术，就此成为新化人复印机产业的发端。新化人把日本和美国的二手复印设备通过国际贸易扩散到国内，提供维修、耗材的支撑，通过专业市场销售到复印店，形成了一条“国际贸易+专业市场+专业店”的完整产业链。凭着这条产业链，凡是有了新化人的地方，复印价格飞速降低，把其他地域的人赶出市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的现象还很多，桐庐快递、成都小吃、沙县小吃、福建莆田医疗、曹县汉服、灌云内衣等等。某种程度上，这是产业聚集与中国式人际关系嫁接所形成的一个独特现象：产业的亲缘、地域聚集。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些产业聚集的形成路径都差不多，最初，是某个当地人在某个行业获得成功，事业扩大，拉更多的亲戚朋友加入；在产业链上也顺着熟人人脉寻找供应商或经销商。再后来，亲戚朋友很可能自立门户，或者其他人看到了也模仿，更多的人加入。最后形成了产业集群。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;形成这个现象的原因是多方面的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社会学有一个六度分隔理论，即世界上任何两个人，通过六个相互认识的人就能连接起来。简单地说，你通过六个人就能认识美国总统。这看起来不可能，其实说穿了不难，比如其中一条路径：任何人都可以轻易地认识一个大学生，通过大学生的老师，就能连接到校长。大学校长已经是非常高层的关系，再通过两三个人就能上到更高层面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在六度分隔的基础上，有学者提出了三度分隔理论，就是说，相距三度之内是强连接，强连接可以引发人的行为。相距超过三度是弱连接，而弱连接只能传递信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;强连接能引发行动并不难理解。强连接首先开阔了人的视野，提供了选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;B站有一个叫“非洲飞哥”的up主，拍非洲风土人情的视频，赶上了短视频的风口。他文化程度并不高，但因为他有一个在非洲务工超过十年的父亲，所以，他去非洲打工。他人聪明又勤奋，先是打工，后来做生意，再后来发现短视频。显然，没有他父亲，他的人生基本上不可能接触到“去非洲”这个选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;强连接还能刺激“自己身边的人”去追求成功，哪怕你只是发了一个小财，你周边的人也非常敏感，产生出羡慕之情。另一方面，身边的人，可能是自己的发小、同学、亲戚，或者朋友的朋友，比较了解，不会神化，会让人觉得是一种可以模仿的对象、可以企及的成功，进而刺激自己也去追求这种成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种强连接是传递资源的。有一次，去南通参加一个活动，走访家纺城。遇到一位1997年出生的年轻老板，当时24岁，开一辆宝马五系，经营的家纺店做得很大。活动完了，大家一起吃饭，老板说自己16岁就出来做事了。我问他是什么时候从打工转变为自立门户做生意的。之所以这么问，我的想法是：16岁就出来闯荡，学历不高，肯定是家里经济条件不好，所以才早早出来打工，积累了第一桶金，有了行业经验，然后自己创业，获得成功。但他说：我从来没有打过工，一出来就独立做生意了，我爸妈、我哥哥、姐姐都是做这个的，他们带着我，就自己开店了。这就是强连接提供选择、提供资源的典型例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;商业本身，也追求这种强连接。经济学中的产业聚集，指在一个适当大的区域范围内，生产某种产品的若干个不同类企业，以及为这些企业配套的上下游企业、相关服务业，高度密集地聚集在一起。相同行业的企业聚集在一起，搜索原料产品的成本，获得配套的产品和服务的成本，交通、沟通的成本，都因地理距离变近而变小，带来更大的竞争力，由此导致了产业聚集。本质上，降低成本是推动产业聚集的最基础动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陌生人之间要建立信任是很难的，企业在经营过程中很大的成本就是沟通成本、信任成本。那么，同样的，从降低成本的角度出发，产业链上的企业就会沿着人际关系聚集。这也是家族企业在各国久盛不衰的原因所在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，换个角度，这就是人们所说的圈子。当然，人从圈子获益也取决于自己，有些人要爹妈送到手上都干不好，有些人只是听说了，就立马行动起来，跟随、学习、模仿，最后获得成功。所以，说到底，最大的因素还是人本身。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>