<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[马航MH370乘客家属索赔案今天开庭审理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:52:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Malaysian Airlines flight MH370 is a Boeing 777 aircraft formerly operated by Malaysia Airlines. It was flown by Malaysia on March 8, 2014. Contact was lost en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing. There were 239 passengers and crew on the flight, including 154 Chinese passengers. On January 29, 2015, the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced that MH370 had crashed and 239 people on board were presumed to have died. Today (November 27), this air transport damage liability dispute case was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that more than 40 family members of passengers have filed lawsuits, and the cases will be heard in Beijing Chaoyang Court from November 27 to December 6. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attorney for the passengers’ families said that there are five defendants in this case, namely Malaysia Airlines, also known as the old Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia International Airlines Co., Ltd. also known as the new Malaysia Airlines, Boeing Company of the United States, and Aircraft Engines Manufacturers: Rolls-Royce in the UK and Allianz in Germany. The claims of the more than 40 passengers&#39; families are different, but they mainly focus on two points. One is to find out the truth about the missing incident of flight MH370 through case trial, and the other is the issue of compensation. It is understood that the biggest difficulty in the trial of this case is to ascertain the truth of the incident. &lt;p>; . The current inability to produce evidence, insufficient evidence, or incomplete evidence is a huge hole left in the trial process of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. A large part of the compensation fee is mental damage solatium. , the highest is 30 to 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also understood that in addition to the family members of more than 40 passengers who filed the lawsuit in Beijing Chaoyang Court, the family members of more than 110 other passengers have reached settlements with the five defendants and signed settlement agreements. The amount received ranged from 2.5 million to 3 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人民银行等八部门联合印发《关于强化金融支持举措 助力民营经济发展壮大的通知》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261389]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:37:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and the requirements of the Central Financial Work Conference, comprehensively implement the &quot; The Opinions of the Central Committee and the State Council on Promoting the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; adhere to the &quot;two unwavering principles&quot; and guide financial institutions to establish the concept of &quot;equal treatment&quot; and continue to strengthen financial services for private enterprises. Recently, the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the China Securities Regulatory Commission Eight departments including the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Finance, and the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Financial Support Measures to Support the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), proposing that 25 specific measures to support the private economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; clarifies the goals and priorities of financial services private enterprises. In terms of total amount, by formulating annual service targets for private enterprises and increasing the weight of services related to private enterprises in performance appraisals, we will increase financial support for private enterprises and gradually increase the proportion of loans to private enterprises. Structurally, we will increase support for key areas such as technological innovation, &quot;specialization, specialization, specialization, green and low carbon, and industrial base reengineering projects, as well as for private small, medium and micro enterprises.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; emphasizes the need to proceed from the characteristics of private enterprises&#39; financing needs and strive to unblock diversified financing channels such as credit, bonds, and equity. Banking financial institutions should increase their support for first-time loans and credit loans, actively carry out industrial chain supply chain financial services, and proactively provide fund continuity services for private enterprises. They should not blindly suspend, suppress, withdraw or cut off loans, and at the same time Promote development and prevent risks. Optimize the registration mechanism for private enterprise debt financing instruments, give full play to the role of private enterprise bond financing support tools, and expand the scale of private enterprise bond financing. Encourage and guide institutional investors to actively and scientifically allocate private enterprise bonds and increase investment in private enterprise bonds. Support the listing financing and mergers and acquisitions of private enterprises, give full play to the supporting service role of regional equity markets and equity investment funds for private enterprises, and expand the scale of equity financing for high-quality private enterprises. Increase the supply of foreign exchange facilitation policies and services, and support private enterprises in &quot;going out&quot; and &quot;bringing in&quot; by improving the level of facilitation of current account receipts and payments, improving cross-border investment and financing facilitation policies, and optimizing cross-border financial foreign exchange special services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; proposes that monetary policy tools, fiscal incentives, insurance guarantees and other measures should be comprehensively used to enhance the enthusiasm of financial institutions in serving the private economy. Strengthen departmental cooperation, improve credit information sharing, financing guarantees, convenient bill discounting, accounts receivable rights confirmation, taxation and other supporting policies and mechanisms, and enhance the private economic and financial carrying capacity. Financial institutions should strengthen publicity and interpretation, and proactively push financial support policies, financial products and service information to private enterprises. Local financial management, development and reform, industry and information technology, finance and taxation, federation of industry and commerce and other departments have strengthened communication and coordination, strengthened supervision and guidance, and improved policy effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the People&#39;s Bank of China and other departments will guide financial institutions to promptly implement the requirements of the &quot;Notice&quot; and formulate specific implementation rules. At the same time, they will strengthen statistical monitoring and policy effect evaluation to ensure that the policy benefits private enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;760&quot; height=&quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/dc1c48c7099df8f07e8e225042aef088.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259746&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Website screenshot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融业“百模大战”正酣，如何在合规中突围？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261381]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The financial industry is entering a big model moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2023, China Merchants Union Finance and Sun Yat-sen University jointly developed and launched the first 13 billion parameter open source large model in the consumer finance industry-&quot;China Merchants Union Smart Deer&quot;. This is the fourth public large-scale model of the consumer finance industry after Du Xiaoman, Masha Consumption and Ant Financial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, traditional financial institutions are also accelerating the application of large models. Some large technology companies are looking to cooperate with financial institutions. The “battle of hundreds of models” in the financial industry is in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How effective is the implementation of large-scale financial models? What are the challenges? What impact will it have on the future financial ecosystem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center investigated various mainstream financial institutions, tested the apps of various financial institutions, and reviewed the speeches of guests at major professional forums in 2023. They found that in the second half of 2023, financial institutions will accelerate Lay out large-scale models, and the main application areas are intelligent customer service, investment strategies, risk control, investment consulting and investment education, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But currently, cooperation between technology companies and financial institutions is the mainstream model. In this cooperation, financial institutions are not only worried about the business effects of large models, but also have concerns about data security and compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that large models in the financial industry are still in the trial and promotion stage, but the trend is irreversible. A researcher at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions for this: promoting &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration, accelerating legislation, and paying attention to talent training. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Financial large models are blooming everywhere&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is special about financial large models? The authoritative international artificial intelligence magazine &quot;Nature Machine Intelligence&quot; believes that large models refer to &quot;deep learning pre-training algorithms&quot; with parameter scales reaching more than 100 million levels. General-purpose large models require huge computing resources and data volumes, and require extremely high technical teams and financial support. They are key projects for major domestic and foreign technology companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vertical domain model focuses on specific industries, fields or scenarios. Therefore, large models in vertical fields have relatively low requirements for computing power and algorithms, but have higher requirements for data in specific fields. Financial large models are typical large models in vertical fields. As a modern high-end service industry, the financial industry has the characteristics of huge data volume and rich scenarios, which is naturally consistent with the large model&#39;s demand for massive high-quality data. Therefore, the financial industry has become one of the first scenarios where large models have been implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2023, domestic financial institutions will accelerate the layout of large models. In addition to banks, insurance companies and leading securities firms have gradually joined the &quot;Battle of Hundreds of Models&quot;. It is worth noting that consumer finance companies have also begun to compete in the battle for large models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incomplete statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center show that among the 19 systemically important banks, more than half have announced that they have released large models or are in the process of intense preparations. Consumer finance companies such as Masha Consumption, Ant Financial and China Merchants Union Financial have also successively released large financial models and claim to be in a leading position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;425&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/TAZxT7BMDWTBFDbso4wRVgvJjAFCEpyPES4cNKpx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different financial institutions What are the similarities and differences between large models? Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that from industry practice, except for a few leading financial institutions such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China that are developing large models of the financial industry, other small and medium-sized financial institutions generally choose to cooperate with large cloud vendors. Pilot a certain business scenario. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further research by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that smart customer service has almost become a standard feature of financial institutions, such as the &quot;smart teller&quot; of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, the &quot;Bank&quot; of China Construction Bank, and the &quot;digital employee sisters&quot; of Bank of Communications. &quot;Jiaojiao&quot; and &quot;Xiaojiao&quot;, Jiangsu Bank&#39;s &quot;Smart Xiaosu&quot;, etc. In addition, different financial institutions use AI technology in the fields of investment, risk control, investment consulting and investment education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development models, cooperation with third parties is still the mainstream model for financial institutions to develop large models. Financial institutions currently mainly cooperate with technology giants such as Baidu, Tencent, Alibaba and Huawei, as well as universities such as Tsinghua University and Peking University, as well as financial technology companies such as Hundsun Electronics and Yuxin Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with independent research and development, cooperative research and development is relatively cost-effective. Xu Dongliang, CTO of Duxiaoman, said that training a general-purpose large model with a scale of hundreds of billions costs tens of millions per time. Earlier, some institutional media reported that GPT-4’s training time was close to 100 days, and the training cost was as high as 63 million US dollars. In other words, training can be carried out up to three times a year, and each time costs about 450 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can small and medium-sized financial institutions implement large models? Huawei released a report titled &quot;Digital Finance: Leading Intelligent Change and Building the Future of Digital Finance Together&quot;. It is recognized in the industry that when the number of large model parameters reaches 62 billion parameters, there will be a surge in capabilities. At present, many open source large models have directly supported parameter sets of tens of billions or even 62 billion, significantly lowering the threshold for AI training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/Qx8S0ybfmS8cDHVoJ4Gt1pUK81Mbjh3UMzQCeRDZ.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a technical perspective See, pursuing large model parameter scale is not the best choice for small and medium-sized financial institutions. Although in theory, the larger the parameter scale of a large model, the stronger its capabilities, but the purpose of developing large models is to empower business and serve customers, not to show off skills. Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that small and medium-sized financial institutions do not need to &quot;roll out&quot; technology. They can choose billion-level, tens of billions, or even billion-level large-scale model pilots for a certain business scenario, giving full play to the organizational flexibility advantages of small and medium-sized financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Under the cooperation model, the two parties have great differences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;With the support of AI, the digital transformation of the financial industry is accelerating, but large models have a negative impact on financial business. The empowerment needs to be further verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that under the cooperation model, financial institutions are mainly concerned about three issues: first, efficiency; second, security; and third, compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of efficiency, digital and intelligent overall solutions that integrate the front, middle and back offices are the core demands of financial institutions. In the recent Financial Street Forum, industry experts also discussed this issue. When Zhai Chenxi, former vice president of Tianfeng Securities, served as a judge for the finals of the third global financial technology application scenario competition, he pointed out that the biggest problem faced by financial institutions is that no one does the integration, resulting in inconsistent data interfaces in the front, middle and back offices, and data cannot be shared. This leads to an increase in internal communication costs to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center tested a number of financial institution apps and found that even in the customer service business where large models are most widely used, there are still many problems. For example, inaccurate answers, repeated answers, etc. Some can only accept &quot;yes or no&quot; answers and cannot understand synonymous expressions. In addition, financial institution apps use intelligent customer service to over-market, such as using robocalls to frequently harass customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang pointed out at the Financial Street Forum that when implementing large-scale financial model scenarios, five key issues still need to be addressed: first, how to choose the basic model; second, how to use the financial institution’s own business data Integrating into large models; the third is how to control model defects such as hallucination problems; the fourth is how institutions can build competition barriers when every institution will deploy large models in the future. The fifth is how to ensure the safety and compliance of the model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to security, financial institutions have large amounts of market data, transaction data, and customer data. The importance of data security and privacy protection is self-evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Jifeng, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, once pointed out at the 2023 INCLUSION Bund Conference that the security issues of large models are mainly the collection, use and disclosure of personal information without consent. Privacy issues may occur during the training process or during use, and the generation ability of large models diversifies the ways of &quot;privacy leakage&quot;, making privacy protection more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of compliance, although cooperating with cloud service providers and purchasing their model training services is a shortcut for financial AI training, the financial industry is a highly regulated industry, and data involving key businesses is often subject to compliance pressure. And it is difficult to upload to the public cloud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jun, senior vice president of Bairong Yunchuang, also said that there are two main trends in data compliance. One is external risks, including whether data use is in compliance with laws and regulations, hackers and criminal gangs Malicious attacks, etc.; the second is internal risks, especially data leakage risks caused by operational risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; that will be implemented from August 15, 2023 balances technological development and regulatory needs and reflects the equal emphasis of legislators on encouragement and supervision. concept. It is expected that the implementation of the &quot;Measures&quot; will bring more legal protection and institutional innovation to the development of China&#39;s generative artificial intelligence service field. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ecological co-construction is the way out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How can large-scale financial models that are still in the trial and promotion stage move toward industrial-level R&amp;D applications? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hundsun Electronics’ survey found that 67% of financial institutions prefer cooperation at the application layer, and the application areas they are most concerned about are investment advisory assistants (56%), compliance and internal control (44%), and investment research (25%) ), while customer service accounts for only 10%. This is partly due to the deep application of AI in the customer service field, but more importantly, it reflects the expectations of financial institutions for large models to empower core businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As financial large models move toward industrial-level research and development, ecological co-construction should be emphasized. This point has been repeatedly echoed in the opinions of experts at major professional forums in 2023. For example, the 2023 China Intelligent Finance Forum even launched the &quot;Financial Large Model Ecological Plan&quot; on-site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Dongliang believes that the industrial application of large financial models requires the joint construction and participation of scenario users (financial institutions), model providers, training tool providers and other parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is the key. At the Financial Cloud Special Session of the 2023 Tencent Global Digital Ecosystem Conference, Tencent Cloud Vice President Hu Liming pointed out that leading financial institutions are now recruiting algorithm PhDs. Although they can leverage cloud vendors, in the end financial institutions must have independent use and innovation Ability to lead the construction, optimization and continuous addition of new application scenarios for large AI platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Cunchao, Director of the Third Department of the North Research Platform of the R&amp;D Center of the Agricultural Bank of China, also said that in the in-depth application of large models in the financial industry, especially in-depth applications embedded in financial scenarios, data is the core and security is the prerequisite. , computing power is the foundation, scenarios are the driving force, talents are the key, and collaboration is the guarantee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the application of large models is an irreversible long-term development trend and a key strategy to accelerate the transformation of digital finance and promote high-quality financial development. However, this is a holistic, It is a systematic and long-term project, so we cannot rush for quick success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compliance and data security cannot be ignored. In the process of digital finance transformation, financial institutions need to be alert to compliance risks and balance the relationship between innovation and security. In data governance, clear boundaries and clear rules are the basis for consensus among all parties. Otherwise, differences will be amplified and development will be hindered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center put forward three suggestions: First, promote &quot;industry-university-research&quot; collaboration. Strengthen peer and cross-sector exchanges and cooperation, formulate standards, standardize processes, and create and share together. The second is to speed up legislation. The European Artificial Intelligence Law has been implemented, and the draft of the Chinese version of the Artificial Intelligence Law is also under review. The third is to attach importance to talent cultivation. Talent reserves restrict the implementation of AI development, because not only early-stage R&amp;D requires professional talents, but later-stage operations and maintenance also require talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[该在小学阶段把体育变主科吗？不要忘掉强身健体的初衷丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261373]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The official website of the Ministry of Education shows: Representatives of the People&#39;s Congress proposed &quot;About changing the physical education subject from a minor subject to a main subject, and providing free distribution to primary school students&quot; Physical Education Textbook Suggestions”. The Ministry of Education responded: There is no priority among the subjects prescribed in the national curriculum plan. Each subject has its own unique educational value and cannot be substituted for each other. At the same time, each subject cooperates with each other to educate students collaboratively to ensure the achievement of training goals. Physical education and health courses are an important part of the basic education curriculum system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the reply from the Ministry of Education, &quot;there is no distinction between primary and secondary subjects&quot; avoiding the distinction between major subjects and minor subjects; the statement that &quot;each subject has its unique educational value&quot; is also correct. However, it is still necessary to discuss the common understanding of what is a major subject and what is a minor subject. As far as primary schools are concerned, the main subjects generally recognized by the public are nothing more than Chinese, mathematics and foreign languages, and the minor subjects are nothing more than physical education, art and music. There are two specific criteria for classification: first, teaching time, the main subject generally has more teaching time than minor subjects; second, the main subject will have a closed-book examination, and the results will be included in the total score of the mid-term, final and entrance exams to become an outstanding student or to be promoted. The standards of a good school. The latter criterion is more commonly used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compulsory Education Curriculum Plan and Curriculum Standards (2022 Edition)&quot; stipulates that the proportion of total class hours in nine years is 20%-22% for Chinese, which is very high, 13%-15% for mathematics, and 13%-15% for foreign languages. 6%-8%, physical education and health 10%-11%, exceeding foreign languages, science or physics, chemistry 8%-10%, according to the Ministry of Education, this proportion, &quot;higher than the United States , Australia, Germany, Russia, South Korea, Japan, Finland, the United Kingdom, Canada and other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, from the perspective of teaching time, physical education is already the main subject in the compulsory education stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the primary promotion from primary school to junior high school is mainly based on interviews and admissions to the nearest &quot;good junior high school&quot; and admission by lottery, there is no unified examination for primary school to junior high school. In this sense, it seems meaningless to talk about major subjects and minor subjects at the primary school level. Because there are no exams. However, there are also some good schools that conduct the so-called &quot;secret test&quot; or resume + interview to obtain good students. Of course, the test is still on traditional cultural subjects or main subjects such as language and mathematics, and will not test physical education. In this sense, primary schools Stage physical education is a minor subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, junior high school is very different. Physical education must be included in the total score of the high school entrance examination. The original intention is to make children pay attention to sports. The score is not low. Under one physical education subject, there are many test items, which is essentially equivalent to taking several tests. In order to get high scores or even perfect scores, schools and parents force children to take exams, which increases the academic burden instead of reducing it. &quot;Junior high school students in the gym&quot; have even become a strange sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially parents in urban areas spend a lot of money to hire private tutors for their children, which has led to a skyrocketing fee for various sports coaches. This essentially requires junior high school students to be trained according to athlete standards. Extensive training and overtraining have resulted in a large number of sports injuries for children, such as knee meniscus injuries, which is detrimental to children&#39;s physical health, growth and development, and is contrary to physical fitness. The positioning of fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because mass sports and competitive sports are completely different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Popular sports are suitable for everyone. They are designed to allow the body to have necessary activities, to allow muscles to exercise, move the muscles and bones, and strengthen the body. Even if you participate in certain ball games or track and field events, the level of It is also amateur-level; at the same time, exercisers can breathe fresh air outdoors, establish a connection with nature, and repair their body and mind; it is also often a social activity that meets the need for interactive connections with others and helps promote mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competitive sports are played by a very small number of people with athletic talent. They are essentially a breakthrough in the limits of human physical ability. Among many competitive sports, many commercially successful industries and profit models have emerged. Including selling tickets + selling broadcast rights + advertising endorsements, etc., the income of top sports stars is very high; large-scale events such as the Olympics are participated in by countries and regions, and they have a higher meaning. Athletes winning medals are regarded as bringing glory to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the sports for students in ordinary primary and secondary schools should be a type of mass sports, which allows students to go outdoors more and strengthen their bodies. It is best to have their own favorite projects and get the benefits from sports. Fun and spiritual joy, under the blue sky and sun, soothing the body and mind and cultivating the spirit, this is something everyone can do. Children who are talented in sports and are interested in making a career in competitive sports can enter specialized sports schools to bring out their talents and potential. Being physically strong is only a very basic requirement. In short, the two types of schools have completely different requirements for student physical education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If physical education is included in the total score of mid-term and final exams at the primary school level and becomes the so-called &quot;main subject&quot;, it will only be counterproductive. Working hard to train in events you don’t like in order to get high scores. Overtraining and improper training often lead to sports injuries. Physical education classes will become hard labor and children will not feel the joy of sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, recess has this tendency. It was originally intended to allow children more time to exercise, but many schools insist on making it ritualistic, pursuing uniformity and grandeur. Instead, children view recess as a daunting prospect. Sports activities should be relaxing and fun, so that they can exercise the body and mind. Fun, meaningful physical activity is itself a natural medicine for maintaining and promoting mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, many children have psychological problems. One of the reasons is that families and schools force children to take exams in knowledge education, and parents neglect character education and values ​​education for their children. The second reason is that children generally need to Strengthen the cultivation of physical and mental repair mechanisms and habits. In fact, what children now lack is not physical activity time, but physical activity time that is fun, meaningful, can release their nature, and can soothe the body and mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the high school entrance examinations in ordinary junior high schools, it is the right direction for various places to change the physical education examination from a merit-based examination to a standard examination in 2022, so that children do not need to work hard on the physical education examination items, consume too much or even Destroy your own body just for high scores; only specialized sports schools need to select the best to stimulate the talents of good talents and continue to work towards challenging the limits of human physical fitness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川两县禁止“私熏腊肉”：尊重民众传统权利，或可推无烟熏制丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261371]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two counties in Bazhong, Sichuan have banned citizens from smoking bacon privately and required them to smoke bacon at designated centralized smoking points. Officials The response was to prevent air pollution. To ban a traditional food preparation method and folk custom that has lasted for more than a thousand years on the grounds of environmental protection is to ignore the traditional rights of the people and is even suspected of rent-seeking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tongjiang and Nanjiang counties in Bazhong, Sichuan, have recently issued notices prohibiting self-smoking of pickled products in urban areas. Those who need to smoke must go to designated centralized smoking points for smoking. Violators may be fined. There is a service charge for curing bacon at centralized smoking sites, and of the two centralized smoking sites announced in Tongjiang County, one clearly states that it only smokes meat products purchased from the company. The officially designated centralized smoking point is suspected of administrative monopoly and profit transfer, which has attracted great attention on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau responded that smoking bacon during the winter festival is a local custom, but the smoke produced during smoking seriously affects the ambient air quality. In order to improve the urban ambient air quality, Eliminate safety hazards and therefore set up centralized smoking points. The response also stated that the statement in the original notice that a centralized smoking site only smoked meat products purchased from the company reflected lax control and work errors. After consultation with the company, the smoking site was opened to the public. Staff of the Nanjiang County Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau also told the media that they have paid attention to the online discussion, and leaders are meeting to study it, and the results will be announced to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Tongjiang and Nanjiang counties, but also Bazhou District, Jingkai District, Enyang District and other places in Bazhong City have also previously designated 10 bacon smoking sites. In October, due to the frequent occurrence of bacon smoking, which resulted in insufficient performance of air pollution prevention and control work, four local sub-district office principals were interviewed and reported to the whole district. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bacon has a long history. Legend has it that bacon was available during the battle between Huangdi and Chi You, and there are records of bacon in classics such as &quot;The Book of Changes&quot;, &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot; and &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Sichuan smoked bacon also has a history of one or two thousand years. Originally, bacon was made to extend the preservation time of meat, but now, bacon has become an important folk custom. For many Sichuan people, bacon is the taste of home and the New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many places in Sichuan have their own signature bacon products, such as Qingchengshan bacon, Guangyuan Qingchuan bacon, Liangshan Mianning bacon, Beichuan bacon, and Dazhou bacon, all of which are famous local specialties. In 2013, the former Ministry of Agriculture approved the implementation of agricultural product geographical indication protection for “Wanyuan Old Bacon” in Dazhou, Sichuan. However, as efforts to control smog intensify, many places in Sichuan have banned the traditional method of smoking bacon, and many local specialty products are facing the dilemma of disappearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Smoking bacon is a custom that has been passed down for thousands of years, but now it has to be stopped because of &quot;polluting the air&quot;. Is this reasonable? Even if smoked bacon does cause air pollution, but people tolerate it, is it necessary for the government to ban it across the board? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much impact smoked bacon has on air quality requires scientific evaluation. Did smoking bacon bring down the air quality of the entire city? Or is there actually another more important factor in air pollution, and bacon is just a scapegoat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, how much pollution can centralized smoking reduce compared with private smoking? According to the official statement, dedicated smokehouses have been built at centralized smoking sites and are equipped with corresponding environmental protection equipment to reduce pollution. So, how much pollution can centralized smoking reduce? Do environmentally friendly equipment really work? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, just banning self-smoked meat in urban areas, how much impact can it have on environmental protection? In the county, many people&#39;s hometowns are in the countryside. If fumigation is not allowed in the city, then go back to your hometown and the countryside to smoke. Wouldn&#39;t it also cause pollution? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mandatory centralized smoking and the charging of service fees will undoubtedly increase the cost of smoked meat for citizens. Although officials say that centralized smoking points only charge cost fees, because centralized smoking points are designated and there is no market competition at all, the owners of centralized smoking points will inevitably tend to charge more. In the process of formulating smoking sites, whether there is rent-seeking or not is also a matter of public concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the traditional method of smoking bacon is indeed seriously polluted, it is not impossible to properly manage it. However, management does not prohibit self-smoking meat across the board, nor can smoking points be determined in a designated way. In fact, not only large-scale smoking companies can build special smokehouses and add environmental protection facilities such as smoke filtration to reduce pollution, but small smokeless and environmentally friendly bacon smoking machines have also been available for a long time. As early as 2018, a smokeless and environmentally friendly bacon smoking machine appeared in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to testing by the Chongqing Ecological Environment Testing Center, using this environmentally friendly smoker, the concentration of particulate matter in the air has been reduced from 400 to 500 mg per cubic meter in traditional open smokers to about 3 mg. It has been reduced from 40 mg per cubic meter to about 0.6 mg. Such a small smoking machine only sells for 20,000 to 30,000 yuan, and ordinary merchants can buy it to smoke bacon for customers. It is even possible for someone to buy one by themselves or in partnership. Although the smoking machine requires a certain cost, the sealed machine can reduce the spread of smoke and reduce the use of wood to a certain extent. Taken together, it is not much more expensive than the traditional open smoking method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Chongqing City also banned citizens from smoking bacon in the name of environmental protection, which also caused a lot of controversy. After the successful development of a smokeless and environmentally friendly smoking machine, citizens&#39; demand for smoked bacon has been met, and air pollution has been greatly reduced, getting the best of both worlds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, environmental protection is a very important task of the government. However, environmental protection should not come at the expense of public convenience and traditional customs. In the past, some places banned the burning of coal for heating in rural areas in winter, and instead used natural gas or electricity for heating. But even with government subsidies, the cost of heating is still much higher than burning coal, and farmers are overwhelmed. In some places, farmers have even been stripped of their firewood stoves and are not allowed to burn firewood, only gas. In some places, people are prohibited from burning paper money during sacrifices, and it is prohibited to burn paper houses, paper horses and other traditional funeral objects. These have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The environmental protection government has KPIs, but they cannot override folk customs and people&#39;s livelihood. After all, talents are the measure of all things. The government&#39;s environmental policies and measures must fully consider the lives of ordinary people and should not grossly interfere with people&#39;s living habits and interrupt thousands of years of traditional folk customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[扶持招商引资企业？四川通江指定集中熏肉点，是什么来历]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261361]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/26/d36424a746.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 26/d36424a746.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 18, 2023, villagers in Shiyi Village, Mianyang, Sichuan There are more than 2,000 kilograms of sausages and bacon hanging in the house, and the aroma of bacon is fragrant to welcome the New Year. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, Tongjiang County, Bazhong City, Sichuan Province issued a notice stating that private smoking of cured products, smoked bacon, sausages, etc. is prohibited in the urban area. It needs to be sent to two designated centralized smoking points. On the evening of November 23, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau issued an apology announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the apology only addressed the statement in the notice that &quot;smoking is limited to meat products purchased from the company&quot; and did not revoke the regulations prohibiting residents from smoking meat privately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the practice of &quot;smoking bacon at designated points to prevent air pollution&quot; has been practiced in some areas of Sichuan for many years, and the necessity and effectiveness have been controversial. The announcement of the passage of the river has attracted attention, partly because the centralized smoking points designated by the government are also associated with enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Their charging standards are not low.&quot; Qian An is from Tongjiang County and is engaged in information self-media work there. He learned from the government that these two companies were local investment projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The price of bacon was questioned&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first announcement that caused controversy was released on November 15. The announcement stated that with the arrival of the peak season for smoking wax products, the smoke and dust produced by smoking will pollute the air and pose fire safety risks. In order to respect tradition and facilitate citizens, while protecting the ecological environment and ensuring the safety of smoking, it will be prohibited to sell smoked products in farmers’ markets, county towns, Cured products are smoked in non-designated places such as courtyards, corridors, balconies, roofs, and beside rock slopes, roadsides, river ditches, etc. It is prohibited to build cured products smoking facilities without authorization in the county. Cured products in the county are smoked at designated locations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The announcement lists the addresses and contact information of two designated smoking sites. Among them, the second smoking site specifically states that “smoking is limited to the company (Bashan Mu). meat products purchased by the industry). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s too far.&quot; After receiving the news about the ban on privately smoked meat, a resident of Tongjiang County&#39;s first reaction was that it was inconvenient because there was something wrong with him at home. The elderly and children need to be taken care of. If you are running back and forth specifically to smoke bacon, you won&#39;t have time to take care of it. Later, he noticed that one of the centralized smoking sites did not allow bringing in meat. He believed that there was suspicion of bundled sales and forced sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The statement in the original notice that &#39;smoking is limited to meat products purchased from this company&#39; reflects our lax control and mistakes in our work.&quot; On November 23 In its apology announcement on the 2nd, the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau revised this regulation, saying that after consultation with the company, the smoked site will be opened to the public at the same time. The announcement also explained that centralized smoking points are located outside the smoking control area and are equipped with spraying, filtration and other related environmental protection equipment, and cost fees are charged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters called the contact numbers of the two centralized smoking sites announced in the notice to inquire about the charging standards, but received no reply. According to CCTV, the prices at the first centralized smoking point are divided into two types. If you bring your own marinated meat, it will be charged at about 1.6 yuan to 2 yuan per catty; if you need to pickle it, it will be charged at about 4 yuan per catty. Charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian An learned that the processing fee for smoked bacon from Bashan Animal Husbandry is 3.5 yuan per catty, and the packaging fee is additional. &quot;Smoking alone costs 3.5 yuan per catty. A pig sometimes has two to three hundred catties of meat. If you smoke it once, it will cost nearly a thousand yuan. It is quite expensive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Tongjiang County has a permanent population of about 500,000, of which the county population is about 200,000. In response to residents’ complaints that the designated smoking point is far away, the apology announcement mentioned that the first centralized smoking point has five convenience collection points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Winter folk custom of smoked bacon. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;941&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dc3db80ae8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259735 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Smoked bacon is a folk custom in winter. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We want to support our enterprises”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the announcement from Tongjiang County, the first centralized smoking point is located in Bizhou The first community in Chengdong Village, sub-district, covers an area of ​​2,000 square meters. It has a smokehouse, management room, oil fume purification equipment and related supporting facilities. The construction area is about 600 square meters. The daily smoked wax products volume is about 5,000 kilograms. The construction has been completed. , the equipment is being debugged and will be put into use on November 25. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the industrial and commercial information and found that the mobile phone number left at the smoking site was the registered phone number of Jinyu Building Materials Business Department of Damian Street Office in Longquanyi District. The company was registered in Chengdu and its main businesses are building materials and hardware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We are a company, and bacon is one of our businesses.&quot; On November 24, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the number, and the other party replied that the smoking point had just opened It has been built but has not yet been fully put into use. In terms of its scale, it can meet the requirements of nearby residents; they provide door-to-door collection services, and residents can also go there on their own with the meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people called me and scolded me. I was really scared.&quot; The person in charge of the company said that in recent days, he had suffered Violence on the Internet has caused great trouble to oneself. &quot;They (netizens) may have some misunderstanding. Another company said that you have to buy their meat before it can be smoked, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another thing in the notice A centralized smoking point is located next to Gaokeng Power Station in Chunzai Industrial Park. It is a self-built wax products smoking point for Bazhong City Bashan Animal Husbandry Co., Ltd. (referred to as Bashan Animal Husbandry), with a daily smoked wax product volume of about 2,000 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bashan Animal Husbandry is a leading local agricultural and animal husbandry enterprise and has been listed on the New Third Board. According to the company&#39;s official website, Bashan Animal Husbandry was established in May 2011 and is headquartered in Tongjiang County Industrial Park. It specializes in Qingyu pig breeding and the development of the entire industry chain. Cold chain logistics, marketing, and brand creation create whole-industry chain standards and systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why are these two companies designated to smoke meat for residents? Qian An consulted the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau and provided the recording to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian An said that the Tongjiang County Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau responded that the designated smoking point is a government investment promotion project and an investment promotion enterprise. &quot;(Bashan Animal Husbandry) is an enterprise that has made outstanding contributions to local economic development. From an emotional point of view, our local government also wants to support our local enterprises, but now it is difficult for enterprises to develop.&quot; In the recording, a member of the bureau the staff said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters did not find the public bidding information for setting up centralized smoking points in Tongjiang County; they called the reporting hotline on the notice and Tongjiang County’s comprehensive administrative law enforcement multiple times None of the office calls were answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Smoked bacon is a tradition in the Sichuan and Chongqing regions with a history of more than 2,000 years. In recent years, it has faced questions about air pollution. As early as 2015, after the Environmental Protection Bureau of Dazhou, Sichuan stated that &quot;smoked bacon is the main cause of poor air quality,&quot; the local government set up centralized smoking points in the central city. At that time, the media explained that centralized smoking did not replace the widespread smoke from cooking with concentrated pollution. Its biggest advantage was that it made it easier for the government to identify problems and standardize management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Che Zhenming, a professor at the School of Food and Bioengineering at Xihua University, believes that family-style, small-scale, and small-scale smoked bacon will not have much impact on the environment. . He told CCTV that because the air is flowing, especially in a city like Bazhong, which is not densely populated, even if some pollution occurs, it will dissipate quickly. However, if smoked bacon is carried out industrially and on a large scale, its impact on the prevention and control of air pollution needs to be taken seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南周口联通以断网逼用户换光猫？是否涉嫌诈骗罪，主管部门应严肃调查以正视听丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261355]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it was exposed that Henan Zhoukou China Unicom Company fired engineers who did not complete marketing tasks and forced users to replace optical modems, causing extensive attention. Zhoukou China Unicom stated that provincial and municipal companies have set up special work teams to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report on the Henan TV Metropolis Channel program, a fired China Unicom engineer revealed to the program that in order to force users to replace optical modems, Zhoukou China Unicom Company would first stop users’ broadband accounts in the background, and then come to visit engineers. They will falsely claim that &quot;the optical modem is damaged&quot; and require the user to replace the device, charging 299 yuan. After replacing the optical modem, restore user network services from the background. This China Unicom engineer said that when installing computers for new users, China Unicom Zhoukou Company will also use the old optical modems replaced by other users to install computers for the new users. After the new users have used them for a period of time, the engineers will come to the door and tell them that the optical modem model is too old. &quot;No longer matches&quot;, the user will be asked to reinstall Sunbeam Cat. The engineer also said that starting from June 2023, Zhoukou China Unicom requires each engineer to complete terminal replacement tasks for 10 households per month. Because he failed to complete the task, the company unilaterally terminated the labor contract without any compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that this engineer chose to reveal the &quot;shady story&quot; of China Unicom because he was dissatisfied with being fired. This incident involves two different issues. One is a labor contract dispute. Whether it is reasonable to assign marketing tasks to technical staff, and whether it is legal to dismiss employees because they cannot complete the tasks, this issue can be resolved through the labor dispute resolution mechanism, resorting to labor arbitration or the court. Regardless of whether the engineer is a regular employee who has directly signed a labor contract with China Unicom, or is dispatched to China Unicom through a labor dispatch company, his legitimate rights and interests should be safeguarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another question, which is more related to the public interest, is whether China Unicom has used technical means to force users to replace optical modems. If this question is true, it is very bad and suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the fired engineer’s revelations, in order to force users to replace optical modems, China Unicom Zhoukou would first stop users’ broadband in the background, preventing users from accessing the Internet, creating the illusion of a network failure. After the user reported the problem, they lied that the optical modem was broken and asked the user to pay for a new optical modem. After the replacement, the broadband was restored. It looked like the fault was repaired after the optical modem was replaced. For new users, they will deliberately use the old optical modem during installation. After a period of time, they will ask the user to replace it with a new one on the grounds that the optical modem does not match. Otherwise, they will not be able to access the Internet normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is undoubtedly a serious accusation. Compared with ordinary users, operators have absolute technological and information advantages. When broadband fails, ordinary users have no way of knowing the specific cause and can only rely on operators. It is very bad if operators rely on information advantages to defraud users, charge users, or achieve other goals. The deputy director of the office of Zhoukou China Unicom said that if you disconnect the Internet privately, induce users to change terminals, and maliciously charge fees, it is an illegal operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this matter is true, I am afraid it is not just a violation of regulations. First of all, this violates the service contract with the user and is a breach of contract. Users sign a broadband service contract with a telecom operator, and the operator is obliged to do its best to provide stable and up-to-standard broadband communication services. If a fault occurs, it should be repaired as soon as possible. If there is no fault in the first place, using technical means to create the illusion of a fault in order to achieve one&#39;s own goals, which prevents users from accessing the Internet smoothly, is undoubtedly a serious malicious act and is a fraudulent act. In addition, users are also charged a fee for exchanging bare cats. Although the amount per household is not much, the more users there are, the more the total amount is. Using fraudulent means to defraud others of property may constitute a crime of fraud if certain standards are met. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, whether this allegation is true remains to be investigated by the relevant departments. Nowadays, the communication control system in the operator&#39;s backend is very complete, and every operation will be recorded in the log, so it is not difficult to find out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, there are indeed complaints about &quot;forced replacement of optical modems&quot; on the consumer complaint platform, and some of them directly name the Unicom branch in Henan Province. Some netizens who claim to be veteran employees in the communications industry said that this kind of behavior is the default &quot;hidden rule&quot; in the industry. If customers insist on not changing terminals, the company will reduce the Internet speed. In fact, this behavior not only exists among telecom operators, but also among Internet companies. An Internet giant that provides email services once &quot;interfered&quot; with users who used other email clients to receive their own emails, making them more likely to receive garbled emails in order to induce users to download and use their own email clients. This has even been regarded as a successful marketing case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what the reason is, telecom operators want users to update their optical modems and other communication equipment. They should use incentives to attract users to voluntarily update. For example, users who replace optical modems can be upgraded to a higher network for free. Wait. It is difficult to achieve goals by setting KPI indicators for engineers. If the pressure to complete the indicators is too great, engineers may &quot;find another way&quot; to complete the task through non-compliant means, harming the interests of consumers. Some telecom operators have been exposed to malicious &quot;competition&quot; methods such as deliberately cutting off competitors&#39; optical fibers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how fierce the market competition is, work tasks should not be completed in a way that harms the interests of consumers. In response to the Zhoukou Unicom incident, the Henan Provincial Communications Administration Bureau has intervened in the investigation and conducted the first interview with Zhoukou Unicom. The management department should find out the relevant situation as soon as possible. If the situation in the revelations does exist, China Unicom should be severely punished to safeguard the interests of consumers and prevent operators from defrauding consumers by relying on asymmetric information and technological advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[监督“八小时之外”：红黄橙三色如何管住干部]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission published a report titled &quot;&quot; &quot;Besides eight hours, we must control it!&quot; article. (Photo source: &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot;)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 26/dfe4ccb610.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/dfe4ccb610.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259713&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission published an article entitled &quot;Eight Hours&quot; &quot;Except&quot;, we must also take care of it! &quot;Article. (Photo source: &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three colors of red, yellow and orange have another use. In Wucheng District, Jinhua City, Zhejiang Province, they have become a way to supervise cadres &quot;eight hours away&quot; means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, a department-level cadre in Wucheng District was assigned a &quot;red code&quot; for management because he made mistakes in his life style. The cadre had an inappropriate relationship with others and was later reported by his family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong, director of the Cadre Supervision Office of the Wucheng District Party Committee Organization Department, said that the cadre was transferred from his original post after the incident and his position was demoted from a principal position to a deputy position. Its file information has been given a &quot;red code&quot; in the cadre supervision and management system and has become a key supervision object. Unless the &quot;red code&quot; in the system is lifted, the cadre&#39;s rank and position cannot be promoted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mechanism is the &quot;red, yellow and orange three-color management&quot; system, which is an important part of Wucheng District&#39;s eight-hour supervision and management method for leading cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2015, starting with Guangdong Province, many places have issued opinions on the supervision and management of &quot;eight-hour outing&quot; activities of leading cadres, and some government agencies have also formulated implementation plans. On September 12, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission published an article titled &quot;Beyond Eight Hours,&quot; We Must Control It! &quot; article emphasized the importance of supervising leading cadres&#39; &quot;eight hours away activities&quot;. Six days later, another article was published titled &quot;Refined and practical supervision and management to ensure the &quot;eight hours away&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Peng Xinlin, director of the International Anti-Corruption Education and Research Center of Beijing Normal University, this is an important means to strengthen the construction of party style and clean government and the fight against corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;3 circles, 21 items not allowed&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2023, two cadres in Wucheng District were coded for &quot;drinking&quot; manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cadre of the Discipline Inspection Commission went home from work and drank alcohol during the working day, and was discovered by the disciplinary inspection and supervision department during a temporary inspection. Because he violated the rule of &quot;no drinking during working days&quot;, he was reminded to talk and given a &quot;yellow code&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another cadre got into an argument with someone in the community after drinking, and the other party called the police. Because his behavior damaged the image of party members and cadres, he was admonished and given an &quot;orange code.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, during the eight-hour supervision process, &quot;red codes&quot; were assigned to cadres who had caused serious consequences or were suspected of violating laws and disciplines; &quot;yellow codes&quot; were assigned to cadres with symptoms and tendencies. cadres; those involved in minor disciplinary violations will be assigned an &quot;orange code.&quot; According to the color of the code, cadres will be transferred to the Discipline Inspection Commission, reminded to speak, and letters of advice and admonitions will be dealt with to varying degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The inspiration for this mechanism is actually traffic lights, which were first used in village cadre management.&quot; Qian Hong said that there is a &quot;three-color management&quot; interface in the local organization department cadre supervision and management system, which can be viewed The situation of assigned cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for what behaviors cadres are not allowed to do outside of eight hours, the &quot;Measures for the Supervision and Management of &quot;Eight Hours Outside&quot; Activities of Leading Cadres of Wucheng District, Jinhua City are listed in detail. This management method is governed by the District Commission for Discipline Inspection and the District Jointly issued by the Organization Department of the Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 21 prohibited behaviors, which are divided into social circle, life circle and rest circle. Each circle has 7 items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behaviors that are not allowed in social circles include not adhering to party principles and making irresponsible remarks on the central government&#39;s policies; forming cliques and forming &quot;small circles&quot; through activities such as sororities, fellows&#39; associations, classmates&#39; associations, comrades-in-arms associations, etc., or There is no distinction between relatives and pure people, and there is collusion between officials and businessmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first prohibited behavior in the life circle is to condone and acquiesce in spouses, children and children&#39;s spouses violating regulations to run businesses and engage in profit-making activities. The behavior of having improper sexual relations with others is on the same level as blind comparison and pursuit of vulgar taste. In addition, violating family ethics and failing to respect and support parents are not allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating and drinking with public funds, traveling with public funds, entertainment with public funds, and using public cars for private use are not allowed in the leisure circle. In the leisure circle, another thing that is not allowed is using one&#39;s authority to act as a protective umbrella for illegal activities or evil forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The extent to which a specific behavior is serious enough to be &quot;coded&quot; must be determined based on the actual situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong used &quot;participating in a banquet for management service recipients&quot; as an example. If the banquet for management service recipients is not reported, at least a yellow code must be assigned; if the meal money is paid by the management service recipient, that is Orange code; if you use your authority to provide some economic convenience to the other party during this period, a warning or a serious warning or above will be given, a red code will be assigned. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Qian Hong’s view, no matter what kind of coding mechanism is essentially not a punishment system, but a cadre management system, “It’s not that cadres who committed crimes in the past There is no punishment system for mistakes, but instead of just settling the matter, problem cadres are managed as key targets to make the management of party members and cadres more standardized.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong also noticed that there are &quot;eight problems&quot; within the system There are concerns that supervision after hours may infringe on personal privacy and affect normal interpersonal interactions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When we issued the document, we explained to everyone that the supervision of the &quot;eight-hour outing&quot; activities of leading cadres will protect personal privacy within the scope of the law and will not affect their legitimate interpersonal interactions and spare time life. For example, having a meal with family and friends or going out to play, situations like this are not within the scope of our supervision.&quot; Qian Hong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From advocacy to implementation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the implementation of the coding system, one day in August 2023, Qian Hong received an &quot;angry &quot;Ms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She went to report her husband, a department-level cadre in a township in Wucheng District. The couple were both over fifty years old. She had previously suspected that her husband had inappropriate relationships with other women, but she had no evidence. This time she checked her husband&#39;s mobile phone while he was sleeping and confirmed the fact that her husband had cheated on her through chat records and transfer records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong asked her why she went to the organization department to report first. Her answer was that in July 2023, the Wucheng District Party Committee Organization Department took the lead in launching a &quot;double advancement&quot; campaign, and she knew that she could go to the Organization Department if she had any opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Double entry&quot; means that in order to fully understand and grasp the &quot;eight hours away&quot; situation of party members and cadres, the District Party Committee Organization Department extends the supervision and management of cadres from &quot;unit compounds&quot; to &quot;community courtyards&quot; and &quot;families&quot; backyard&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, &quot;the concept of &#39;eight-hour supervision&#39; was first mentioned by local leaders 20 years ago, and later gradually became a popular saying.&quot; Zhuang Deshui, deputy director of the Integrity Construction Research Center of Peking University, introduced that in the early days , this concept appeared more in the speeches and reports of some leaders. Later, some places introduced some relevant bans and regulations, but most of them were advocacy and lacked specific implementation agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that around 2001, the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China launched a pilot study of cadres’ living circles and social circles in Huzhou, Zhejiang. In 2004, the Organization Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee formulated and issued the &quot;Opinions on Implementing the Inspection of the Living and Social Circles of Leading Cadres&quot;, which stipulated that officials&#39; mahjong and gambling in their spare time, neighborhood relations, and the composition of their friend circles would all be included in the inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangdong Province was the first place to elevate &quot;eight-hour supervision&quot; to the level of rules and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2014, after the Eighth Inspection Team of the Central Committee inspected Guangdong, it was recommended to strengthen the daily management of party members and leading cadres and the supervision of activities &quot;outside eight hours&quot;. In August 2015, the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, the Organization Department of the Provincial Party Committee, and the Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security jointly issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Supervision and Management of &quot;Beyond Eight Hours&quot; Activities of Party Members and Leading Cadres&quot;. , supervision mechanisms are clearly stipulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Guangdong selected 147 pilot units across the province, including Yantian District of Shenzhen, to explore and trial the supervision and management of activities of leading cadres &quot;outside eight hours&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the then Secretary of the Yantian District Committee of Shenzhen City wrote an article in the &quot;Study Times&quot; introducing that Yantian District established a list of (negative) reports on &quot;three circles&quot; issues, community supervision, contact with cadres&#39; families, and eight A series of supervision mechanisms such as linking extra-hour activities with selection and appointment, and integrity assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that in the past six years, including Wucheng District of Jinhua City, Zhejiang Province, Pinghu City, Zhejiang Province (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Jiaxing City), Fengxin County, Jiangxi Province, Zhijiang City, Hubei Province, and Qixian County, Henan Province , Youxian District of Mianyang City in Sichuan Province, Jianning County of Fujian Province and other places formulated the &quot;Eight-hour Oversight Supervision Implementation Measures for Leading Cadres&quot;. The specific content also has many similarities with the relevant mechanisms in Yantian District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinghu City&#39;s &quot;system for contacting cadres&#39; families&quot; is mainly responsible for the Cadre Supervision Office of the Organization Department of the Pinghu Municipal Party Committee. &quot;We are used to calling it a &#39;home visit&#39;, during which we will focus on listening to some indicative and tendentious content.&quot; .&quot; said Gan Keyi, deputy director of the Cadre Supervision Office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as Gan Ke remembered, during a &quot;home visit&quot;, a family member complained that his &quot;other half&quot; rarely ate at home from Monday to Friday, and the home visit team asked him if he ate at work. The cadre said that sometimes he worked overtime and sometimes he went out to socialize. The home visiting team then asked about the specific entertainment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In response to this situation, we will verify through multiple channels. If we find that some entertainment may affect the performance of our duties, we will take further measures.&quot; Gan Keyi introduced that after verification by the Organization Department , and did not find that the cadre&#39;s entertainment affected his performance of duties, he had a separate conversation with him and did not make any other treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mobilizing community forces to supervise the activities of cadres outside eight hours is also a method commonly adopted in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinghu City has set up three categories of &quot;eight-hour outside supervision and observation points&quot;: Category A is located in municipal agencies and departments, Category B is located in townships and streets, and Category C is located in communities and village-level units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Gan Keyi, about 90% of the leading cadres in Pinghu City live in the main urban area. They have set up two community supervisors in each of the 21 communities where cadres live relatively densely. Generally, they are led by highly respected local officials. , social figures with high political quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Community supervisors play the role of information collectors. They only need to collect and feedback information. As for the authenticity of the information, the basic verification work is the responsibility of the B-type supervision point.&quot; Gan Keyi said, related After the implementation of the mechanism, a supervisor reported to the town street supervision point that a cadre living in the community caused a neighborhood dispute due to illegal stacking of debris in the corridor. Finally, it was verified and confirmed by the town street supervision point, and the organization department gave a reminder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A deputy division-level cadre from a northwest province expressed his recognition of the community supervision mechanism to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;If it can be truly implemented, it should still be very effective.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In his opinion, community security guards can also consider hiring community supervisors. &quot;Although they may not necessarily live in the community, they have no clue which leader comes back after drinking too much every day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&quot;One vote veto&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the process of exploring the &quot;eight-hour out-of-hours&quot; supervision of leading cadres, in order to ensure the effectiveness of supervision, supervisory departments in many places will combine the &quot;eight-hour out-of-hours&quot; supervision situation with the selection and appointment of cadres, The unit leadership team is linked to accountability for performance of duties and unit assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant implementation measures issued by Youxian District of Mianyang City, Sichuan in 2020 require that the personal &quot;eight hours&quot; of party members and cadres and their performance of supervision and management responsibilities shall be used as the basis for cadre selection and appointment, rank promotion, and performance appraisal. An important part of the evaluation and annual assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wucheng District of Jinhua City also has similar regulations. Qian Hong introduced that the connection between the results of eight-hour supervision and party disciplinary sanctions will directly affect the promotion of leading cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Hong gave an example: Those who have been severely warned within the party shall not be promoted within one and a half years, those who have been warned by the party must not be promoted within one year, and those who have been warned and spoken shall not be promoted within six months. In addition, the results of party discipline will also affect the year-end bonus of cadres to varying degrees. Once they are severely warned, the bonus will be reset to zero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the implementation measures of various places, intra-party supervision is the primary supervision method. Party committees at all levels have the main responsibility for the supervision and management of party members and cadres in their respective regions, systems, and units &quot;outside eight hours&quot;. The party committee secretary He is the first person responsible for holding accountable the leadership team and cadres who fail to perform their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gan Keyi told a case: a cadre of a unit in Pinghu City was included in the &quot;red list&quot; due to a problem eight hours away. Due to issues such as insufficient timely collection of after-hours supervision information and insufficient reminders to the unit&#39;s cadres, the organization&#39;s officers were also admonished and included in the &quot;yellow list.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;red and yellow list&quot; is similar to the coding mechanism in Wucheng District. Being included in the &quot;red list&quot; means that the cadre has been investigated and investigated by the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, while the &quot;yellow list&quot; shows that the cadre is suspected of committing crimes. There are many tendency issues, and the organization department needs to intervene early to understand the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can’t wait until the Discipline Inspection Commission has opened a case for investigation and the public security has notified us before reporting.” Qian Hong said that the unit’s party group failed to fulfill its main responsibilities, and eventually something went wrong. The assessment of the unit’s party style and clean government construction will be affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In terms of cadre supervision, when it comes to issues related to integrity, self-discipline and life style, we will deduct points very severely, which is almost equivalent to a veto. If a member of the leadership team of this unit has made a mistake this year, If there is a problem, we will push it to the last level.&quot; Qian Hong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is no clear explanation in the relevant measures from various places on how to measure the effect of eight-hour supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gan Keyi said frankly that at present, to measure the effectiveness of supervision outside eight hours, it still depends on whether leading cadres can regulate themselves outside eight hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Eight-hour supervision is not to deal with cadres, but to protect cadres, prevent small problems from turning into big problems, and nip big problems in their bud.&quot; Gan Keyi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the supervision of &quot;top leaders&quot; has always been a difficulty in anti-corruption. &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot; pointed out in an article analyzing &quot;How to manage &#39;eight hours away&#39;?&quot; that the supervision of top leaders is often due to the fact that superior supervision is too far away, peer supervision is too soft, and subordinate supervision is too difficult. Facing the dilemma of ineffective supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That&#39;s true. This aspect is a little more difficult. In the end, superiors are in charge of subordinates.&quot; Qian Hong said frankly. Gan Keyi also discovered that compared with supervising ordinary cadres, there are some particularities in how to supervise the activities of &quot;top leaders&quot; outside eight hours. &quot;From a social perspective, the &#39;top leaders&#39; will involve communication with some merchants and brother units. Sometimes they participate in some entertainment. In this process, it is indeed difficult to distinguish whether the entertainment is for business or private.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is often possible for them to supervise others, but it is more difficult for them to accept supervision themselves. It’s difficult.” Zhuang Deshui recalled that a cadre once expressed a “relatively pessimistic” attitude to him, believing that supervision eight hours away was useless. “Many things cannot be effectively supervised, and the real corruption is under the table.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some grassroots cadres are also worried about the durability and effectiveness of the policy. &quot;I&#39;m afraid that after a period of strict implementation, it will be loosened. (As time goes by) there are policies at the top and countermeasures at the bottom.&quot; Qian Hong said that even now, some problems have caused trouble for the eight-hour supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, he gave the example that some cadres would avoid places that are the focus of regulatory authorities and go to more private places; although there is community supervision, some cadres may have houses in several communities or even other urban areas; In terms of family supervision, some cadres have a bad relationship with husband and wife. They live their own lives and ignore each other; the power of social supervision is still weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In general, our means of actively grasping clues are not enough, and the efficiency of information screening is not high enough.&quot; As a colleague, Gan Keyi also feels the same way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Mao Zhaohui, director of the Anti-Corruption and Integrity Policy Research Center of Renmin University of China, eight-hour supervision can be a supervisory method to improve the conduct and discipline at the grassroots level, but it is limited by manpower, material resources, resources and means. It&#39;s not yet a regular job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Zhaohui’s suggestion is, “If we want to achieve better results through eight-hour supervision, we should effectively introduce social supervision, including public opinion supervision and media supervision.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“每一个蚌里都可能藏着一颗奇妙的珍珠”——第十届乌镇戏剧节青年竞演]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261257]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ05K1v0a0Mwo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/IGoaZnhErhcYd1kqBeoNHzM1QQUoZ 05K1v0a0Mwo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Clam and Pearl&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by the Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the day from October 20 to 26, 2023, at the entrance of the Bengwan Theater in Xizha, Wuzhen, there was always a queue waiting to watch the show. The queue can sometimes stretch to the river. In September, free tickets for online reservations for the Wuzhen Theater Festival Youth Performance Competition (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Youth Competition&quot;&lt;/span>;) will be available at the beginning of the ticket sales It was robbed. This is one of the most important units of the Wuzhen Theater Festival every year, and it is also the only competition unit. Among the works of 18 groups of young dramatists, the Small Town Award for Best Drama, Best Individual Performance Award, and Special Attention Award will be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a sign in front of the fence outside the Bengwan Theater, indicating that ⅩⅩⅩ spectators can be admitted for this youth game. In the theater, the works of 18 groups of young dramatists were performed in turn; a screen was temporarily hung on a stone wall outside the theater for audiences who were unable to enter to watch the live broadcast. Under the scorching sun, there were always five or six rows of enthusiastic audiences sitting on the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, the Wuzhen Theater Festival has been running for 10 years, and the Youth Competition has also been running for 10 years. Bengwan Theater is named after the earliest place name here. Huang Lei thinks it is good, &quot;There are many clams in Bengwan, and each clam may hide a wonderful pearl.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuzhen Theater Festival One of the initiators, actor Huang Lei, who has taught at the Beijing Film Academy for many years, has &quot;deep gratitude&quot; and &quot;profound reflection on the shortcomings&quot; of traditional art education. He brought some ideas that could not be implemented in school to the Wuzhen Theater Festival. This year, two days before the opening of the 10th Wuzhen Theater Festival, in a handwritten letter to the youth competition, Huang Lei wrote, &quot;In the beginning, when the Wuzhen Theater Festival was just a small idea, young people were already fans of this festival. The protagonist, the origin and goal of everything is for the young people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Youth Competition is open to young people who are interested in engaging in the theater industry. The rules are very simple: each of the three founders of the Wuzhen Theater Festival will bring a prop to form the group. The annual proposition - use these 3 props to rehearse an original play with no more than 5 people in 20-30 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May this year, Huang Lei, Lai Shengchuan, and Meng Jinghui, the founders of the Wuzhen Theater Festival, proposed the topic for the youth competition: world-famous paintings, train tickets, horses. &quot;The fundamental purpose of the three props is not to test how you use the props, but to test how you use the environment, find effective stage fulcrums, and maximize the energy density of the play per unit time.&quot; Youth competition judge Li Bo said. In August, more than 500 works were submitted; in September, 18 groups of shortlisted works were announced; in mid-October, the group lottery for performances at the Wuzhen Theater Festival was released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The stage of Bengwan Theater is small and the layout is simple: ceiling light and curtain. The audience formed a semicircle, surrounding the stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The small stage of Qingsai has produced many theater people over the years. In 2013, &quot;Baba Mama&quot; directed by Chen Minghao won the first prize. This year he is well-known to the public for his performance in &quot;The Long Season&quot;; in 2015, Wu Bi won the Best Drama Award for &quot;Stillness&quot;. This year he is also a judge of the Youth Competition , is also an actor in Lai Shengchuan&#39;s new drama &quot;Long Alley&quot;. Wu Bi once said that Wuzhen was the biggest turning point in his career. &quot;You can have no cost and nothing, but you can do what you want to do and give everyone a stage for so many people to watch.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/M6Z6ezjdpK9vyrDYsgTZsLoWe4HSqc0pmODUU6Bw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259261&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wuzhen Theater Festival Youth Competition Unit Judge Li Bo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bo participated in the first three Youth Competitions as a contestant, and his works all entered the top three. From the fourth time, he became one of the judges of the Youth Competition, responsible for selecting 18 groups of shortlisted works from hundreds of works; and then selected from the 18 groups. There will be 6 sets of final works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in his early 20s, Li Bo studied in the Performance Department of Beijing Film Academy and enjoyed freedom and romance in the ivory tower. Later he became a university teacher. &quot;I always felt that I had no goals and no outlet, so I was very confused.&quot; Participate The Wuzhen Theater Festival has directional significance for him. He said that it is a way for more people to understand his theatrical concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the 10 days in Wuzhen, I spent a lot of time at the Bengwan Theater. From these youth plays, I can see the disappearance of love between men and women, the love between mother and daughter, and father and son. The hidden pain caused by the bondage, and the individual&#39;s reflection on the tearing of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story of &quot;Fifth Floor, Ninth Floor&quot;, which won the Best Drama Award, is set in a malfunctioning elevator. For half an hour, a boy on the fifth floor and a girl on the ninth floor reflect on their intimate relationship. , one feels that he is trapped by his boyfriend, and the other may be trapped by his girlfriend. They all wanted to run away and take imaginary train tickets to the north to see the auroras. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/YTBsOeV8Us98w43JUFXAKA3juucRsaCWN6MX13mP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259258&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;Fifth Floor and Ninth Floor&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Provided by Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Clam and Pearl&quot; won the Special Attention Award and the Best Individual Performance Award. The protagonist is a very controlling mother. With the help of a psychologist, she reveals the trauma of being violated as a girl. At the end, the daughter takes a photo of her mother, and the mother looks back and turns into a picture of &quot;Girl with a Pearl Earring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Me and Liu Hongmei at the Station&quot;, which also won the Special Attention Award, has only one actor from beginning to end. &quot;I&quot; left the big city and returned to his hometown to become a staff member of the amusement park carousel project. We met several times. &quot;She&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;grandma who has lived her whole life in her hometown&lt;/span>;), when she was 15 years old, she wanted to secretly go swimming in the river; when she was in her twenties, She wanted to go to Beijing and Shanghai, and she cried anxiously when she lost her train ticket; she was 82 years old, thin, silent, and old, and time passed quickly on her; in the end, &quot;I&quot; took the 6-year-old &quot;she&quot; everywhere Carousel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fU6jjhR6Sz0KwolNzteM4YohY6FGSerkhP5iORe0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still photo of &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Provided by Wuzhen Theater Festival Organizing Committee/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;One night during the drama festival, Li Bo queued up to watch Meng Jinghui&#39;s new play at the Zhenshui Carving Hall, and heard an audience member complain about a certain Qingsai play. Li Bo found it quite interesting. This just reflects the diversification of the youth competition standards. &quot;It is true that the audience has mixed reviews of that play, but it is the only one-man show performed in this way on the youth competition stage in the past 10 years. We must encourage it, maybe in the future It will form a unique style. Young people should do a lot of exploration in their plays. If the plays are done very neatly, then it is Teacher Lai, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/Uzl3RRMgJu8UzwrzdxTezjUAsrdeAxd7cscXsI7f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This Youth Championship Finals The crew of the shortlisted work &quot;Open the Unopenable Window&quot; took their final bow&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the finalists were announced and After the theater festival, Li Bo was interviewed twice by Southern People Weekly. The following is Li Bo&#39;s dictation:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Qingsai is a school that allows you to have cute flaws&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;On October 26, we discussed the 6 shortlisted plays, and we wanted to take an official photo of the judges discussing the finalists. We all sat upright, holding the play review list. Later, someone came up with a point. Director Cheng Er was the first to stand up and said, no, this stage is so rare, this play must use the language of drama. Later, they all stood up and argued: what is reverence for the stage, what is the language of drama, how to perform in a small theater, how to use the three props, what to do if the performance times out...&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are more than 500 works registered, and we have to take care of a variety of themes, styles, and expressions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qing Sai is a school that allows you to have cute flaws. However, the dramas that were shortlisted for their flaws at the time were almost out of shape on the youth competition stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a play, the registration deadline is August 20th, I think they recorded it on August 19th , it’s too late if we don’t record it again. The video was taken at a piano store, and the first shot is still shaking. What they were performing was a light comedy, and the actors had to be absolutely relaxed. They probably acted as if they were not shortlisted. They came across a lot of spiritual and advanced comedy lines on the scene, so the ear guide team brought this up to the scene. . I was having a meeting out of town and was really bored, so I just put on headphones and watched the video. They were presented in a relaxed and playful way, and I was particularly happy to see them. The actor forgot his lyrics and laughed loudly, and so did I. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The finalists were announced later. The organizing committee called, signed the confirmation letter, designed the poster, and went to Wuzhen. Arrange three public rehearsals, an interview, a few more rehearsals, and then three rounds of performances. They began to realize that this was a competition and became nervous. When people are nervous, they become unfree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The official Weibo announced the finalists, and there was a message saying that each of these six plays Solid, congratulations to them. This evaluation is the greatest encouragement for our work. Some plays may look good and rich, but they are too fluttery and tasteless at first glance; some may look steady, but the whole presentation has a poise that is rare for young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year is the highest overall level I have seen in the 7 years I have been a judge. This year, we can really choose 6 out of the 6 finalists. In the end, we are making a choice. It happened that I came across a play that I liked very much, but some judges didn&#39;t like it very much, so the two of us kept arguing, but this was academic and not personal. When I work in an office, I tend to answer &quot;yes&quot; and &quot;yes, you are right&quot;, but this problem does not exist at the Wuzhen Theater Festival. Teacher Lai and I also argued about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year’s props are a horse, world-famous paintings, and train tickets. In addition to performance and text, the most important thing is to see how the three elements are used, because this game is supported by three elements. When we judge, if the performance of the two plays is similar, we will look at the props. Each of the three teachers was given a prop to prevent them from adapting old works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The use of props particularly tests the professionalism of a crew. For example, we were fighting without a winner, and a knife suddenly appeared, and everyone wanted to grab it. This knife caused a turning point in the drama and changed the direction of the drama. This is a relatively common usage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As for the props, I only mention it. This is the simplest; it also plays a role in the turning point of the play. Key role? Or is it an image and symbol that lingers in your mind throughout the play? These are three completely different levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The most difficult props this year are world-famous paintings, because we Chinese rarely have the experience of going to art exhibitions . Some of the plays are parodies of &quot;Girl with a Pearl Earring&quot;, some have her family treating her works as world-famous paintings, and some have actors imitating &quot;The Scream&quot;, all of which are quite cute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;, all of us judges passed the finals. I think its entry into the finals is inseparable from the use of props. The image of horses is present throughout. When we learn acting, whether props serve as the fulcrum of the stage or are key items that promote the development of the plot, they must appear on the stage, but they did not appear in this play. The script mentioned the carousel game. &quot;I&quot; walked around the stage like a merry-go-round and met &quot;my&quot; grandma. Every time I walked around, &quot;I&quot; saw Liu Hongmei in different stages. It all happened. Different things are related to Liu Hongmei&#39;s fate. Finally &quot;I&quot; returned to work and drove the merry-go-round for other children. So fresh, so natural. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/fn6iCX3PjfK5PEwyTNT8zLsIN7JTjdJqDHwyIQ9o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259260&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The performance of &quot;Then Tide, Sun, Moon&quot; has ended&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Don’t be cool or showy, just focus on the story&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;I also said at the reading meeting that day that you can get chicken soup with 140 characters on Weibo, and you can achieve all your desires in one minute on TikTok. Why would someone waste two hours of their life in the theater to go to the theater? First of all, this play must have warmth. Second, the things you talk about in your play are things you don’t often see on Douyin, Kuaishou and Weibo. You need to lead the audience to pay attention to people in life that we have never paid attention to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Up to now, I have selected one play in the previous youth competitions, and I think it is the best It is &quot;Gama&quot; in 2016 (Reporter&#39;s note: The title of the Youth Competition that year was A Drop of Blood, a Suitcase, and a Shooting Star. The protagonists of &quot;Gama&quot; are a mother and daughter. For many years, my mother has been unable to let go of leaving home to practice medicine. , the father who became a living Buddha, the living Buddha is dead, and the mother firmly believes that the living Buddha can be reincarnated and return home within 49 days, and hopes that her daughter Karma will be pregnant; but the child that Karma was pregnant with was the reincarnation of Kelsanghua, and the child also died. The mother The two women planned to go on their own pilgrimages and finally reconciled on the way to the sacred lake). Two graduate students from the Shanghai Theater Academy made it the only time in the history of the youth competition that the best individual performance award and the grand prize were all given to a team. When performing beliefs on the stage, they usually tend to be complicated, but that play was very simple, with one chair and two girls. One of the girls played two roles (the grandmother who never forgets her husband, and the reincarnated granddaughter of Kelsanghua). ), so simple yet so clear. After they kowtowed, they looked into the distance and saw a cold light coming over them. Wow, it was a lake. Tibetan music sounded, and it felt like we were in the snowy plateau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the first to the present, all the dramas that have won the grand prize are small and big. Talk about life down to earth. If you pick up a random person from Xizha, they can understand it even if they are over 10 years old or under 90 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The stage of the youth competition is very close to the audience. Really, it is the most important thing. Is the core of your drama told to us through a small incident, or is it a fake philosophical event? I especially don&#39;t like to tell us something in a pretentious manner, or forcefully instill something. Including the judges&#39; votes, the results of this kind of drama are not good. Young people&#39;s dramas don&#39;t need to be so complicated. Let&#39;s discuss To be or not to be. I&#39;m sorry, you really don&#39;t have that skill. Sometimes what you think and what you perform are two different things. I still hope that the story can be told clearly: it has the story&#39;s ups and downs, characters, conflicts, and themes. Even if there is no intention, it is very rare. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Look at Liu Tianqi&#39;s &quot;Chicken and Rabbit in the Same Cage&quot; (Reporter&#39;s Note: Youth Competition Best Drama Award Award-winning work) How simple, the son went to prison to visit his father, and the two had a conversation. There is a big world in a small play. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I still think that young people don’t need to be cool or showy, they should be down-to-earth and focus their energy In terms of story, how to structure and unfold the story; the performance must be restrained. I especially hate the kind of badass performances that can be seen in short videos, but many people may be affected and feel that our scenes must be &quot;acting&quot;. I told the contestants in the youth competition that it is the most difficult to act in a scene where the inner world is turbulent and the outer surface is as calm as water. When Marlon Brando, Robert De Niro, or Al Pacino encountered something that shattered his faith, was any one of them howling? His emotions are a reservoir, and as much as he wants can come out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We also need to learn this on the stage. The performance must be subtle, restrained, and forbearing. Don&#39;t let the audience&#39;s shouts and applause make the play fly away and take over the show. Some plays were very popular, but we felt that they were a bit pleasing to the audience. After performing it once, we knew which baggage was in which place, but the second time we performed it with all our strength, without even control or rhythm. &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot; is particularly stable and does not cater to the audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not easy to perform a one-man show. One person has to interpret many people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We watched the registration video and there were a lot of one-man shows. A lot of it is like what we did when we were in school - a person encounters a dilemma within a unit of time, and through the struggle between people and the natural environment, the problem is pushed to a certain climax. But we should show new and real things to the audiences who come to Wuzhen. We have selected three one-man shows this time, such as &quot;Liu Hongmei and I were at the Station&quot;, which are not one-man shows in the traditional sense. They are more often talking and revealing, in a particularly dull state, but the inner feelings are There is content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think the Bengwan Theater and Qingsai Theater in Wuzhen are an experimental field for young Chinese dramatists. As long as you have the ability, you can put your own experiments on the stage. The audience is tolerant, and so are our judges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/mzOLwjXxuTifmIoAYAslcXEBXGJc6iobwlg9OBsw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside the Bengwan Theater, posters of all the works of this youth competition are pasted on the gray stone wall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(South People Weekly reporter Zhang Yuxin/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;If we don’t do drama, of course we can understand&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;When I was 33, 34, and 35 years old, I participated in the Youth Championship as a player. It was very unforgettable and worthwhile. In the first year, I did the only comedy among the 12 plays; in the second year, I did the only physical drama, without lines; in the third year, I did the only montage drama, relying on light to explain the performance. Now I am still a teacher, but I definitely can’t rule out things like those three years. People’s experiences are getting richer and their courage is getting smaller and smaller. Especially when working in a university, your imagination is not so wild. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the first year of the Youth Voting Competition, we waited in line at school until two or three o&#39;clock every night. The students were lined up to give up, saying that the standards of these judges must be high and they would not be shortlisted. I said, after being a teacher for so many years, I have also done scientific research and participated in awards. A competition that does not charge an entry fee must be a good competition. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I teach at a second public school, and students are recruited from the same school as Nortel Chinese Drama. There is a gap. The &quot;survival rate&quot; of my first class of students competing together is very high. One is in Happy Twist, one is in Dalian Repertory Theater, and one is now a delivery anchor. He is doing very well. I have seen his Live broadcast, his live broadcast skills are linked to his performance. He can hang up and smash up. Rather than watching his live broadcast, it is better to say that he is watching him perform a play. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I also rehearsed plays in college and Wuzhen plays. Sometimes one brain can be divided into two types ideas. All universities in China are actually the same, and university education has university characteristics. Therefore, when young people get the props from the Wuzhen Theater Festival, they may be very excited because they finally have the opportunity to make a comedy, tragedy or absurd play that they really like and have a sense of life. Let me put it in a very unpleasant light, Wuzhen&#39;s drama does not mean that after you perform in Wuzhen, you can perform it every day. If you win a grand prize in just 10 days, the chance of it being performed (continued) is very small. Some of the plays are very immature, but because the scenes are grand enough, they continue to be performed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I still encourage young people to go to drama festivals to watch plays and compete. Drama lovers from all over the country come together in one place to talk about drama. This kind of preciousness is something that will linger in your mind for the rest of your life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The goal of the Wuzhen Theater Festival is very clear. By capturing 5% of the people, this theater festival can manage. There is no way for us to have a chain of support like some film festivals, providing money to film, screen, and go online. Drama is still a niche, and the number of screens across the country is definitely much greater than the number of theaters. But we just want to give them a shot in the arm. Every year in the audience of the Wuzhen Youth Championship, there are contestants who were shortlisted in previous years. Those who did not vote this year, or who did not win, return to Wuzhen to watch the show. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everyone has his or her own life choices. Of course we can understand if we don’t do drama, because It&#39;s good to be alive. If you&#39;re going to make a drama, make it a good one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[考研人数八年来首降：高校招生计划扩张时代正在走向尾声丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the official website of the Ministry of Education announced matters related to the 2024 National Master’s Degree Admissions Examination. According to statistics, the number of applicants for the national master&#39;s degree examination in 2024 is 4.38 million, a decrease of 360,000 or about 7.6% from the 4.74 million applicants for the postgraduate examination in 2023. This is also the first time in eight years that the number of applicants for the postgraduate examination has increased compared with the previous year. fall back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why has the number of postgraduate entrance examinations declined? The outside world has summarized some possible reasons: some graduates turned to the public entrance examination, striving to get an iron job in one step, and withdrew from the postgraduate entrance examination track; some graduates no longer regard the postgraduate entrance examination as a choice, thinking that it is just a matter of paper. A postgraduate diploma may not necessarily lead to a good job, so it is better to enter the job market in advance to save opportunity costs; the postgraduate recruitment policies of major universities have changed. &quot;The number of places for professional masters has increased and the number of places for academic masters has decreased&quot;, which has reduced the cost-effectiveness of postgraduate studies, and some prices Sensitive candidates give up in the face of high tuition fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that these reasons all stem from the rational choices of candidates as &quot;economic people&quot;: studying has increasingly become an investment, and the consumption attribute of higher education is also strengthening. If the candidates believe that studying for graduate school cannot improve the competitiveness of the job market and cannot bring good economic returns in the future, then the candidates will rationally consider &quot;whether studying for graduate school is worth it&quot;, thereby reducing the &quot;supply&quot; of the higher education market. There is a rumor going viral that a famous postgraduate entrance examination teacher successfully predicted the decline in the number of people taking the postgraduate entrance examination. In fact, this also shows that his &quot;preaching&quot; over the years has achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a statistical point of view, the change in candidates&#39; attitudes has also taken several years, which is essentially a &quot;reverse incentive&quot; brought about by changes in the job market. Statistics on the number of applicants for postgraduate entrance examinations over the years show that this number declined in 2014 and 2015, but has shown an upward trend since 2015, reaching a peak in 2023. The year-on-year expansion of postgraduate enrollment and the increase in the number of graduates have made the job market supply unable to keep up with the employment demand of graduates. This imbalance in supply and demand has naturally been transmitted to the upstream higher education market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be admitted that in reality, only a small proportion of people go to graduate school to satisfy their personal enthusiasm for knowledge or for scientific research. Most students go to graduate school for employment, which can be subdivided. Further studies to postpone employment, and &quot;gold-plated graduate school&quot; for better employment. Unfortunately, both of these options are facing great challenges amid a weak job market. Of course, students are not fools and will also adjust their life strategies according to social reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key factors that affect the supply and demand of the job market are the economic cycle and industrial structure. The feedback from the job market also determines the cost-effectiveness of graduate school. None of the three parties, students, employers, or universities, can answer the question of “is graduate school worth it” alone? In the face of sluggish demand in the job market, both employers and candidates have begun to take action to answer this question: companies have reduced the scale of school recruitment, while candidates have seen a decline in the number of applicants. What is worth asking is, how will universities respond? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this century, the number of postgraduate students enrolled in China has increased year by year, from 220,000 in 2003 to more than 1 million in 2020, and now accounts for about 10% of undergraduate graduates that year. Major universities have expanded their enrollment of master&#39;s degree students so rapidly over the years. On the one hand, they are of course adapting to the growing needs of the job market. On the other hand, they can also apply for more funds for themselves, charge more tuition fees, and improve various evaluation indicators. In short, it is to strive for more benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;reverse incentives&quot; in the job market, the sluggish fertility rate is destined to continue to reduce the number of postgraduate entrance examinations in the future, and the phenomenon of &quot;the merger of primary and secondary schools&quot; will sooner or later spread to higher education. field, this will be a more decisive factor in the future than &quot;candidates choose not to take the exam&quot;. In other words, the decline in the number of people taking postgraduate entrance examinations is an irreversible trend. In the future, colleges and universities may face a new enrollment gap of one million levels every year and have to face the severe situation of &quot;competition for existing students&quot;. This is a serious issue that colleges and universities need to deal with urgently. challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reducing enrollment for master&#39;s degrees and expanding enrollment for associate&#39;s master&#39;s degrees&quot; and &quot;extending the academic system for associate&#39;s and master&#39;s degrees&quot; are the response plans that some colleges and universities have come up with. In this way, they can not only maintain the original enrollment scale, but also increase enrollment. Collect tuition fees. But the question is, when colleges and universities make a fuss about the academic system and quota of associate and master&#39;s degrees, can they really &quot;ensure the quality of training and improve employment competitiveness&quot;, or can they just &quot;charge one more year of tuition&quot; or even &quot;delay one year&quot;? &quot;Employment&quot; itself is quite debatable and deserves reflection. Some candidates&#39; doubts about the cost-effectiveness of master&#39;s degrees may be one of the reasons for the decrease in the number of postgraduate students this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the principles of organizational behavior, &quot;organizations will work hard to create jobs for themselves, and employees of organizations will work hard to create jobs for each other.&quot; Since an organization has been established, it will do everything possible to maintain its existence, especially The public sector eats up financial resources. Public universities have long relied on taxpayers&#39; money to operate and do not need to directly face market competition. Naturally, they will find ways to maintain their existing graduate spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, changes in supply and demand in the job market and the impact of declining fertility rates will be transmitted sooner or later. The arrival of the enrollment gap has become an irreversible trend. The decline in the number of postgraduate entrance examinations this year is a timely warning to major universities. Comply with the needs of the job market, comprehensively consider social needs, adjust the recruitment plan for graduate students, and better serve the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从不被理解到亚运项目，中国电子竞技20年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On November 18, 2003, e-sports was listed as the 99th sports competition event by the State Sports General Administration. Now 20 years have passed, although the e-sports industry has various problems, it is probably the most commercialized and professional competitive sport in China.</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>