<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[盗用上亿公款打赏主播：“榜一大哥”的名头，何以如此引人入歧途？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257456]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, &quot;A guy with a monthly salary of 6,000 yuan rewarded a female anchor with 90 million yuan for meeting a female anchor&quot; became a hot search topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Mingsheng (pseudonym) works as an accountant in a private company in Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province. After downloading a certain chat software, he entered the live broadcast room of female anchor K Bao and became obsessed with it after just one look. According to the rules of the platform game, only by becoming the &quot;big brother&quot; can you be qualified to meet the anchor. His monthly salary was only 6,000 yuan, so he took advantage of his position to secretly transfer public funds for rewards. After becoming the &quot;big brother&quot; in K Bao&#39;s live broadcast room, he became an offline lover with K Bao as he wished, and had a sexual relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2022, when the group company reconciled its accounts, it was discovered that the accounts managed by Liu Mingsheng had a large capital deficit. According to an investigation by the public security agency, he embezzled a total of about 123 million yuan in public funds from the company&#39;s accounts, rewarded K Bao with 90 million yuan, and also rewarded two other anchors with several million yuan each. In the end, most of the huge amount of approximately 123 million yuan misappropriated by him was recovered, with a total of 122.68 million yuan recovered. Liu Mingsheng was sentenced to 14 years for job embezzlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;you will die if you have too much fun&quot; energy is staggering. In fact, there are many cases of cashiers misappropriating public funds to reward anchors, and there are both male and female cashiers. Ru Yin works as a cashier for a real estate development group in Guangxi. Starting from 2020, she fell in love with a male anchor on the Douyin APP and rewarded him crazily. When she had no money, she used public funds. Police investigation found that her Douyin account was recharged with more than 5 million yuan in the second half of 2020, and more than 4.3 million yuan was used to reward male anchors, of which more than 1.44 million yuan was the company&#39;s public funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is that Li served as the cashier of a company in Zhuhai in the Jinan Region. From December 2018 to April 2020, he took advantage of loopholes in the company&#39;s financial management to transfer 48.264303 million public funds to his personal account for rewards. Female anchors, game recharges, entertainment consumption, girlfriends, etc., including live broadcast rewards of more than 20 million. After the incident, the &quot;big brother on the list&quot; was sentenced to 12 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A common feature of this type of incident is that the cashier’s income is not high, but the money he hands over is a lot. If an individual does not have good character and professional ethics, it is easy to fall into an unbalanced mentality, and the cashier understands the company best. Where are the financial loopholes, so once they &quot;calculate mentally but not intentionally&quot;, the company&#39;s financial system will be ineffective at least for a period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another direction worth thinking about is: What kind of industry is online live broadcasting, and whose needs do it mainly meet? What is the mentality of those people who squander their own money, their parents&#39; money, and even the company&#39;s money to reward anchors of the opposite sex? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Online live broadcast includes several different business formats, one of which is the ascendant live broadcast of goods. It would be wrong to regard it as just a new distribution channel, because compared with offline channels or other &quot;traditional&quot; e-commerce channels, anchors sell more than just goods. Especially those anchors who are more successful, while selling &quot;personality&quot; and providing emotional value, have a celebrity-fan relationship, which often satisfies the best imagination and even sexual fantasies of fans of the opposite sex about their other half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Or, it can even be said that those popular anchors clearly have a quiet, warm or beautiful &quot;personality&quot; to collect money from their fans, but they even give some extra rewards. It’s so “kind” to have products that can be used. Therefore, along this path, part of &quot;live streaming with goods&quot; will evolve into &quot;live streaming with rewards&quot;. Since you can make money without bringing goods, then you will not bring goods or sell goods, but sell &quot;characters&quot; directly to fans. &quot;That&#39;s it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, &quot;live streaming rewards&quot; also come from many different sources, with very different audiences and properties, so they need to be discussed separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, another evolutionary path is that in the past, flyover juggling, street busking and begging have moved from offline to online. Their main audience is either the grassroots or the unspecified public. This article will not go into details. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another evolutionary path is to make the desire to share and peek into the Internet and further videoize it. Some people share their work, life, hobbies or skills with everyone through videos. Some are live broadcasts, some are recorded, and there are also successful cases, such as fishing masters, trap tying kings, &quot;hand-made people&quot; and so on. Let everyone It increases your understanding and knowledge of unfamiliar areas, or allows everyone to experience the life they long for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;live broadcast reward&quot; we focus on here has a significant anchor-fan relationship, and is generally a male anchor-female fan, female anchor-male fan relationship, which is inevitably somewhat sexual. Meaning&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eat and drink, men and women, are where the great desires of man exist&quot; and &quot;eating and sex are also the nature&quot;. Needless to say, a large part of human vitality is tied to sexual energy or sexual desire. The &quot;talent&quot; who has fascinated countless middle-aged and elderly women, the &quot;alluring smile&quot; who has fascinated countless middle-aged and elderly men, and the celebrities who have fascinated countless young men and women are all the same in essence. When it comes to the appearance, appearance, etc. of these anchors or celebrities. Temperament and &quot;personality&quot; satisfy the opposite sex&#39;s best fantasy about their partner. This is the origin and dynamics of this type of &quot;pure live broadcast reward&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xun said that dissatisfaction is an upward wheel. Very few people are completely satisfied with their current lives. They are dissatisfied with their jobs, their boyfriends, or their spouses, so they expect an ideal life, including an ideal spouse. This is human nature. But first of all, you must understand the boundaries of your abilities and how you are ranked in this society. This way, you will have an objective judgment of whether your current life is &quot;worthy of you&quot; and whether the world is &quot;worthy&quot;. , He who knows himself will understand. Then for the current situation, change it when it needs to be changed, and accept it when it needs to be accepted. This is reconciling with yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And if for the sake of spiritual satisfaction, you reward a host of the opposite sex with a large amount of property at home or even your own property, it is actually not improving but ruining your life. The above-mentioned male and female cashiers misappropriated public funds to reward anchors of the opposite sex. This is exactly the case. In short, everyone should use their strong vitality to improve themselves, so that they can get more and more good things worthy of them. This is a way to make positive use of their own life energy, rather than consuming all their resources and even their vitality. Fulfill your fantasies. Regardless of personal honor and future, just to &quot;die for the fun of it&quot;, this is a good opportunity to live in this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美成立经济领域工作组]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to implement the important consensus reached by the heads of state of China and the United States at their meeting in Bali, according to the Vice Premier of the State Council, China and the United States According to the consensus reached by He Lifeng, the Chinese leader of the economic and trade side, and Janet Yellen, the US Secretary of the Treasury, China and the United States agreed to establish an economic working group, including an &quot;economic working group&quot; and a &quot;financial working group.&quot; The &quot;Economic Working Group&quot; is led by officials at the deputy ministerial level of the Treasury Department of China and the United States, and the &quot;Financial Working Group&quot; is led by officials at the deputy ministerial level of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the U.S. Treasury Department. The two working groups will hold regular and irregular meetings to strengthen communication and exchanges on issues related to the economic and financial fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《红色天空》：在侯麦与王家卫之间]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256843]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPhaaMY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qREaPt1m0u1fMC3ZO4Teszy6wrUZVg5tiIPha aMY. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250592&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Concept-oriented Petzold&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among contemporary German film directors, Christian Petzold may be the most eye-catching of one. The previous &quot;Ghost Trilogy&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Abode of the Heart&quot;, &quot;Ghost&quot; and &quot;Yela&quot;&lt;/span>;) and &quot;Immigration Trilogy&quot; &quot;Music&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Barbara&quot;, &quot;Phoenix&quot; and &quot;Transit&quot;&lt;/span>;), which has earned him a good reputation in the international film industry . So he struck while the iron was hot and continued to launch a series of works with the theme of &quot;Elemental Elves&quot;. &quot;Undine&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020&lt;/span>;) with the theme of the water goddess is the first film in the series; it won the jury award at the 2023 Berlin Film Festival The grand prize of the group, &quot;Red Sky&quot; with the theme of the fire elf Salomanda, is the second installment in this series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By sorting out Petzold’s creative trajectory, we can find some obvious characteristics. His works are highly intellectual, and he will provide almost essay-like explanations around certain specific themes. At the same time, he places great emphasis on the core position occupied by concepts. Under the guidance of such creative concepts, the fate of classical mythological characters overlaps with the situation of modern Germans (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;Phoenix&quot;&lt;/span>;), the plight of the Jews during World War II also collided with the fate of Arab refugees in contemporary Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;Transit&quot;&lt;/span>;), stirring up a wonderful chemical reaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But we also have to point out that although the concept of Petzold&#39;s film is charming, it is slightly rigid in terms of flesh and texture, and lacks some real and perceptible vitality. This problem is particularly exposed in Undine: an attempt to combine a water spirit from classical mythology with the life of a contemporary German industrial diver, which is very interesting on paper, but fails to translate into images In the end, it is easy to fall into the predicament of wildly swinging between the metaphysical and the physical, and end up relying on neither. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Petzold must have realized his mistake in Undine. Therefore, when filming his new work &quot;Red Sky&quot;, he sought a lighter brushstroke: the metaphysical mythological elements are hidden deeper, while the metaphysical daily life is pushed to the foreground. The plot is set during a summer vacation. Leon, a troubled young writer, is invited to his friend Felix&#39;s seaside holiday home to try to finish the novel in a quiet environment while waiting for the publisher&#39;s decision. But during this period of time that should have calmed him down, he passively got acquainted with the beautiful and lively girl Nadia, and her lover Devi who had a close relationship with her. Leon&#39;s heart was stirred up, but the approaching deadline (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Deadline&lt;/span>;) and the burden of intellectuals made him Nadia&#39;s emotions become tangled and twisted, creating a series of comedies and dramas in the lives of four people. At the same time, a wildfire is spreading inland, becoming the disturbing background sound of the entire story. No one knows whether this light vacation will eventually end in raging flames. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like the titles of many of Petzold&#39;s previous films, &quot;Red Sky&quot; is also full of potential. It not only refers to the sky dyed red by wildfires on a concrete level, but also metaphorically alludes to the sexual tension that is about to emerge between the several protagonists, as well as the overwhelming sexual tension in the &quot;Revelation&quot; volume of the New Testament. Apocalyptic scene. But the film&#39;s story ultimately fails to live up to the full potential of its title. The huge destructive power of wildfires is almost wiped out by a shot of wild boars running in the forest and the off-screen deaths of two supporting characters; and &quot;Memento mori&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;will die&lt;/span>;)-style death warning also fails to be integrated with the character&#39;s desires. In the final analysis, &quot;Red Sky&quot; still tells the story of a self-centered male protagonist chasing the heroine and awakening during the pursuit. Whether it is his friends, publishers, the fire and death, or even the heroine herself, they seem to be tools that lead him to self-awakening. And there remains a huge gulf between Petzold&#39;s prowess in seductive concept-building and what can only be described as a barely above-average narrative articulation. Red Skies is an improvement over its predecessor, but there&#39;s a gap that still needs to be filled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Zh1Vsz896cTN46UvPe0CjDwWeYJydBhnwEzqf2Qb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250590&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hide And the master of melodrama&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with his meek performance in narrative and expression, Petzold&#39;s ability to write romantic relationships and set off the love atmosphere is outstanding. It is easy to forget that Germans have always been famous for their seriousness, whether they are romantic poets like Goethe and Holderlin or melodrama masters like Douglas Sirk and Rainer Werner Fassbinder. He grew up nourished by the Rhine River. To a certain extent, Petzold is also the heir to the romantic mantle of his predecessors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the valuable thing about Petzold is that his writing about love relationships not only has a German-style desperate romance, but also has a subtle temperament that is rare among European and American creators. Petzold&#39;s male protagonists always seem to be more interested in the souls of their admirers than in possessing their bodies, but they are always so shy and clumsy in their pursuit of each other that The end of happiness seems forever out of reach. In contrast, Petzold&#39;s heroines are always as erratic as wandering spirits, unable to be defined or captured. They are free souls who make no secret of their feelings for the person they love, but they always refuse to be defined as immutable symbols and never become objects. Therefore, in Petzold&#39;s film, the dislocation game of chasing and dodging has been going on. This game seems to have been going on since the birth of men and women, and it will continue until the end of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Red Sky&quot;, the setting of summer vacation and country holiday house, the lighter tone compared with Petzold&#39;s previous works, and the characters&#39; artistic and intellectual atmosphere The conversation will more or less remind us of those in Eric Rohmer&#39;s films, those satirical ridicules of hesitant straight men with good intentions, and those under the comedic tone, which are emotionless and emotionless. perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the other hand, Petzold’s talent for creating romantic situations, his intense love for female characters, and the emotional relationships between male and female characters in his films become more intense because of evasion and restraint. , will remind people of another film master who is good at creating romantic atmosphere-Wong Kar-wai. Perhaps Paula Bell, the actress in &quot;Transit&quot;, &quot;Undine&quot; and &quot;Red Sky&quot;, has quietly become Petzold&#39;s Maggie Cheung. The plots of these movies may soon disappear from our minds, but Paula Bell&#39;s bright smile and red dress will remain in our memories for a long time. Through the male director&#39;s way, we cannot fully understand what they mean. Thoughts and feelings, but still (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;or - precisely because of this&lt;/span>;) eyes full of admiration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[餐厅员工发顾客打娃视频后赔1万离职，警方如此调解令人费解]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to reports, on September 19, a Western restaurant stopped a mother from beating her daughter and posted the relevant video online. The employee, Mr. Jiang, resigned and left Changsha after compensating the other party 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surveillance video that Mr. Jiang previously posted online showed that the woman involved, Hu, was holding a shopping bag and yelling at the little girl. Later, she took her child to the Western restaurant where Mr. Jiang worked and asked her child to explain to her the process of causing trouble. At this moment, Hu lost control. He put down the shopping bag in his hand, lifted the chair next to him and tried to hit the girl. Mr. Jiang and his colleagues stepped forward to stop him. A nearby merchant revealed in an interview with a reporter from Hunan TV that when the mother and daughter passed by his store, the girl suddenly fell down and the ice cream in her hand spilled on the floor, causing her clothes to be stained. Immediately, Hu lost control of his emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Jiang said that after the incident, Hu came to the restaurant many times, saying that he should not have spread the video online and threatened to die in the restaurant. After mediation by the local police station, Mr. Jiang paid the other party 10,000 yuan in compensation for mental losses and medical expenses, and then voluntarily submitted his resignation to his boss. Netizens expressed: &quot;Those who hit people are fine, but those who stopped them will be punished&quot;, &quot;I really feel sorry for this doll when I see this video&quot;, and some netizens said, &quot;It&#39;s really chilling.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The restaurant employee got into trouble when he prevented the woman Hu from beating her daughter in public and uploading the video to the Internet. This matter involves many aspects, including domestic violence, public supervision, privacy rights and law enforcement issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it must be clear that Hu’s behavior of beating his daughter in public is a typical act of domestic violence. It not only violates public order and good customs, but also violates relevant laws. According to Article 2 of the Anti-Domestic Violence Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, domestic violence refers to physical, mental and other violations committed by family members in the form of beating, binding, mutilation, restriction of personal freedom, regular verbal abuse, and intimidation. Article 5 stipulates that minors, the elderly, disabled people, pregnant and lactating women, and seriously ill patients who suffer domestic violence shall be given special protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the duty of the police station to deal with Hu’s illegal behavior as soon as possible. Article 33 of the Anti-Domestic Violence Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China stipulates that if the perpetrator commits domestic violence and constitutes a violation of public security management, he shall be subject to public security management penalties in accordance with the law. It can be seen that when parents beat their children, law enforcement agencies cannot turn a blind eye on the grounds that &quot;honest officials cannot handle household matters.&quot; In this incident, Hu publicly beat his daughter, which caused a very bad public perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the restaurant employee Mr. Jiang’s behavior of publishing the video, from a legal perspective, he did not infringe on Hu’s portrait rights. Because this is an exposure of illegal activities in public places, Mr. Jiang is exercising the citizen’s right to supervise. Article 1020 of the Civil Code stipulates that the following acts may be reasonably carried out without the consent of the portrait right holder: other acts of making, using, or disclosing the portrait of the portrait right holder in order to safeguard public interests or the legitimate rights and interests of the portrait right holder. By exposing his video, Mr. Jiang obviously hopes to draw social attention to the phenomenon of domestic violence and jointly protect the rights of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a step back, even if Hu believes that his rights and interests have been violated, he should protect his rights and interests through legal means such as litigation, rather than through improper means such as making trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu made trouble in the restaurant many times. However, the police station did not hold him accountable. Instead, through mediation, Mr. Jiang was asked to compensate 10,000 yuan for mental damages and medical expenses. This move not only chilled Mr. Jiang&#39;s heart, but also sent a wrong signal: If illegal acts can be resolved through mediation, or even reverse compensation can be obtained, wouldn&#39;t it condone more people&#39;s willful behavior? In this way, the law loses its majesty and justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a law enforcement agency, it should be based on the law, focus on protecting the rights and interests of minors and the courageous behavior of citizens, and have zero tolerance for illegal activities, so as to form a legal deterrent and guide social atmosphere. Improve the quality of citizens through legal education. Regrettably, the police station allowed the parties’ emotions to influence the outcome of the case, acquiescing to the woman’s behavior of “getting more and more unreasonable”. Such mediation is inconsistent with legal principles. Netizens generally questioned this mediation and expressed their simple view of justice. Law enforcement agencies should re-investigate the matter and hold the offenders accountable, rather than letting those who bravely act for justice lose money and jobs. Only in this way can people&#39;s faith in judicial authority not be damaged. After all, the majesty and credibility of the law are often reflected in the daily actions of law enforcers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如果你导弹打得不够准，是因为你人靠得不够近丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257374]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/gup4AaFCsszUqfElPfxsoCHZgB5ey11TUdvQehIu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/gup4AaFCsszUqfElPfxsoCHZgB5ey11TUdv QehIu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Sevastopol, Crimea region, Smoke billowed out from the attacked shipyard &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Ukrainian news said that the Ukrainian military In the early morning of September 13, 2023, 10 missiles and 3 unmanned boats launched an attack on the Sevastopol military base in the Crimean Peninsula, causing a fire at the Sevastopol Shipyard and two ships under repair were damaged. The losses include the Russian Black Sea Fleet&#39;s Ropcha-class landing ship &quot;Minsk&quot; and the Kilo-class diesel-powered submarine &quot;Rostov-on-Don&quot; which cost up to US$300 million and was commissioned in 2014. Rostov-on-Don). Satellite images of the scene showed that the two ships were severely damaged and were extremely difficult and expensive to repair. Considering that such a project was difficult to complete under the wartime system, they basically had to be scrapped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russia also admitted that it was attacked by Ukrainian missiles and that some ships were damaged. The situation announced by both sides basically confirmed the results of this attack. This is the largest loss suffered by the Black Sea Fleet since the sinking of the flagship Moskva after the war between Russia and Ukraine. It also sets a record for the first time in history that a submarine is hit by a missile. What’s even more amazing is that just two days after this attack, Ukraine announced that it had used missiles and drones to attack the S-400 air defense missile system on the Crimean Peninsula. This system has always been considered the strongest in Russia. Currently in active air defense weapons, Turkey even had tense relations with the United States and NATO in order to purchase this system. This time, it was beheaded by Ukraine behind enemy lines in actual combat, which was shocking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This round of continuous attacks with a combination of punches is obviously not the result of an accident, but a joint military operation between the Ukrainian intelligence agencies and the Ministry of Defense, in which the actions of the Ukrainian special forces can be said to be indispensable. without. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before launching the missile attack, that is, on September 11, the Ukrainian intelligence agency announced that the special forces had successfully seized two offshore oil and gas drilling platforms in the Black Sea and successfully removed Russian equipment from the platforms. military installations. The map shows that the two platforms captured by the Ukrainian special forces are about fifty kilometers away from the Crimean coastline. The Russian army has set up air and sea warning radars on them to control the Black Sea area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This attack did not attract much attention from domestic public opinion. Some media even believed that it was a political show after Ukraine’s counterattack failed, because the battle to seize the two platforms was not fierce and not too big. military value. However, in my opinion, the battle to seize the sea platform is the prelude to this attack, because Ukraine does not have stealth fighter equipment that can penetrate the enemy&#39;s air defense network, so it must try to shorten the reaction time of the opponent&#39;s air defense weapons, and these two This platform happens to be Russia&#39;s peripheral observation point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the start of the 2003 Iraq War, the U.S. military used special forces to successfully seize three Iraqi offshore drilling platforms in the Persian Gulf. On the other hand, it is to prevent Iraq from dumping oil into the Persian Gulf and polluting the environment like it did during the Gulf War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the operation that year, in addition to the British and American special forces, the Polish Thunder Special Task Force also assumed the offensive mission of a platform. This kind of battle to seize maritime platforms is referred to as VBSS (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Visit, board, search and seize&lt;/span>;) in the field of special operations. VBSS The mission is often only accomplished by elite maritime special operations units. The complexity of such operations lies in the fact that it involves combat maneuvers from underwater to the surface, and also includes extremely close indoor combat. It not only requires a large amount of pre-war reconnaissance, but also requires a large amount of targeted actual combat training by operational units before they can make up their minds to implement it. This kind of maritime point-taking operation generally cannot be just a political statement mission, because the risks and costs are too high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the missile attack two days later that Ukraine&#39;s action to seize the Black Sea drilling platform is only part of its huge action plan. In fact, the follow-up actions are the key to victory. After the submarine and landing ship were attacked by missiles, Ukraine launched a missile attack one day later. The battle rhythm seemed not compact enough. But in fact, the U.S. special forces did not delay after seizing the platform. Another attack team quietly landed on the Crimean Peninsula under the cover of night, approached the submarines and landing ships in the shipyard, and used thermal imaging Shoot it from multiple angles. After the attack, these latent special operations personnel conducted reconnaissance and assessment of the bombing effects before quietly withdrawing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because air-launched missile attacks involve issues with the angle of incidence, it is necessary to construct a three-dimensional image of the target, and the inspection needs to confirm its radar information or thermal imaging information, all of which require multi-angle technical reconnaissance. The United States may be able to rely on its powerful satellite and reconnaissance aircraft platforms for reconnaissance. For Ukraine, which lacks technical reconnaissance means, using special forces or covert operators to conduct close reconnaissance is a good alternative. And even for a country like the United States with strong technical reconnaissance capabilities, close-in reconnaissance by special forces is still one of the optional methods. For example, during the Gulf War, the United States sent multiple special operations teams into Iraq in order to find Iraqi Scud missiles. Conduct close reconnaissance from the rear. In addition, for collecting the signal characteristics of enemy air defense weapons, deploying special operations personnel for close detection is also a very feasible method, because with only a set of signal receivers, these lurking personnel can obtain the spectrum information of surrounding warning radars for a long time , and can also obtain more comprehensive signal intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people believe that the emergence of drones can replace special operations personnel, but in fact it is people, not machines, who win wars. Only when the quality of people matches technical means can we defeat powerful opponents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 20:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10人遇难，强龙卷风突袭江苏后，救灾与保险赔付正进行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/22/d0f40bac84.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/d0f40bac84. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251665&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, the scene of the tornado disaster in Nancai Township, Suqian City. Visual China Map &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tens of seconds&quot;, &quot;Just a few minutes&quot;, &quot;Ten minutes or so&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the tornado passed through, local residents could not remember how long the strong winds blew. This sudden disaster hit parts of Suqian City and Yancheng City, Jiangsu Province on September 19, 2023. According to official reports from the two places, a total of 10 people were killed and 8 injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, on Liyuan Road, Nancai Township, Suqian City, Li Peng had been immersed in picking up all kinds of debris at home and in the supermarket, and cleaning the passage; in another town in the city, Daxing Town North Street, a 68-year-old Chen Jianqiang climbed up to the roof of his house, collected the tiles blown by the tornado, and prepared to re-roof the roof. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two-kilometer-long Nancai Township South Street has generally returned to its usual order. Downed trees and broken glass have been cleared away, and temporary stalls are ready to be set up. Among the photos provided by local residents on the 20th, only the pears on the small truck were half burnt and blackened by the high-voltage cables that fell on the day of the tornado, and they were still stacked neatly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this tornado, the tornadoes in Daxing Town, Suyu District, Suqian City and Nancai Township, Economic Development Zone were EF2, and the tornadoes in Lupu Town and Banhu Town, Funing County, Yancheng City were EF3. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Jiangsu Provincial Meteorological Service Center’s official Weibo account “Jiangsu Meteorology”, the intensity of tornadoes is divided into levels from EF0 to EF5. Tornadoes of level EF2 and above are generally called strong tornadoes, and tornadoes of level EF2 are generally called strong tornadoes. It can cause considerable damage, it can uproot trees; an EF3 tornado can even knock over a train. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Suqian, tornadoes are not a common natural disaster and they come and go quickly. In Yancheng, according to the Propaganda Department of the Funing County Party Committee in Yancheng City, an average of 4.8 tornadoes occur in Jiangsu every year, of which 2.6 occur in Yancheng. Yancheng is the urban area with the highest frequency of occurrence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I was so scared at that moment”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the tornado hit at around 5 o’clock in the evening on September 19, Luo Qi was picking up his children from school and did not notice it. figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I got home, the street was in a mess. Luo Qi saw that on South Street, electric wires were blazing and cars were on fire. There is a small market on the street every day, right in front of Luo Qi&#39;s house. One of the sheds in front of her house was blown away and disappeared, and the other one was tied to a tree with a rope, but it hit the freezer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Qi checked the surveillance video at home and found that the three minutes before the tornado struck were unusually calm, with only light rain falling. Starting at 17:11, the surveillance video recorded a loud wind noise, and the shed at the door was blown. Then the wind became louder and louder, a red four-corner tent floated by the roadside, the big box was blown away, and all the small objects on the ground began to fly everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Qi said that the child&#39;s grandmother was washing vegetables at the door. When she saw something was wrong and wanted to go back into the house, the tricycle was blown up by the wind and pushed against the wall. The car window glass penetrated her elbows and feet, and she went to the hospital that night for stitches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The stall owner next to Luo Qi’s house was not so lucky. He was picked up by the wind and fell to the other side of the road. At that time, a wrist-thick main cable suddenly fell down on the street, bursting into flames, and everyone was afraid of being electrocuted. &quot;I was so frightened at that moment.&quot; Luo Qi said that it was the first time in more than 30 years that she had seen such a violent tornado. The stall owner&#39;s wife kept asking for help, but no one dared to rescue her. Later, the police cordoned off the scene, and the cables were still on fire after the power was artificially cut off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Liyuan Road, which intersects with South Street, Li Peng opened a small supermarket. In his memory, the tornado lasted no more than a few minutes. But in those few minutes, the tornado tore off almost all the roofs on both sides of the street. &quot;Those asbestos tiles and sheds were hanging in the sky, as high as an airplane, blowing everywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Peng’s home is a 16-year-old tile-roofed house. Since the house has never had any problems before, Li Peng has not reinforced or renovated the house. The tile-roofed house suffered heavy losses in this tornado. The roof kept leaking and the furniture and doors inside were smashed. &quot;I haven&#39;t calculated the amount of damage. I can only make detailed statistics when repairs start.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the tornado moved all the way to Daxing Town, it was already around 6 o&#39;clock. Fante, a 14-year-old girl, just came home from school. She saw a black thing slowly rolling up from a distance. &quot;It seemed to be connected to the sky, very long.&quot; During dinner, the lights at home flickered on and off, and soon the power went out. A strong wind blew into Fanter&#39;s house. Grandma went to block the two glass doors, but she couldn&#39;t close them. Fanter ran to help, &quot;but there was a strong suction that sucked me to the door and blew me into the tree.&quot; Fanter, who weighed 85 pounds, hugged the big tree outside the door and did not dare to move. He did not come down along the trunk until the wind stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Jiangsu Weather&quot; news on September 20, Jiangsu was affected by two tornadoes on September 19. The first tornado was in Suqian Economic Development Zone and Daxing Town from 17:00 to 18:00; the other was in Funing County, Yancheng City from 20:16 to 35:00. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official public account of the Suqian Emergency Management Bureau, the tornado disaster mainly occurred in towns and villages, with densely populated areas, complex building structures, and the occurrence period coincided with off-duty hours. According to preliminary statistics, 5,512 people were affected by the strong tornado, 1,646 houses were generally damaged, 137 houses collapsed, 41.8 hectares of crops were damaged, 405 people were temporarily relocated, and some walls of more than 2,000 square meters of pig houses collapsed and the roof collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/9a3ba8adc3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/9a3ba8adc3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the roadside in Nancai Township, electric workers are repairing lines. Visual China Picture &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Public housing insurance is verifying compensation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Wei, assistant captain of Suqian Blue Sky Rescue Team, told Southern Weekend Reporter, a common disaster in Suqian is heavy rain. Relatively speaking, tornadoes occur more frequently in Yancheng City. The private rescue teams along the Jiangsu coast have conducted targeted training on thunderstorms and hurricanes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 6 pm on the 19th, 13 members of the Blue Sky Rescue Team rushed to Nancai Township, Economic Development Zone. The local fire rescue team had arrived at the scene. The Blue Sky Team members assisted in clearing down fallen trees and scattered debris. etc., to open up a smooth road; at the same time, we checked the power supply lines to prevent secondary disasters such as leakage. &quot;We continued working until two o&#39;clock in the morning the next day.&quot; Road cleanup in Nancai Township was basically completed on the 20th. Suqian Blue Sky Rescue Team sent 12 reinforcements to Daxing Town in the afternoon to investigate the disaster situation, mainly assisting township staff to verify whether there were any people who had lost contact after the disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Wei said that after the tornado passes through, another task is to clean up the debris on the facade of the building. For example, the air conditioner on the edge of the eaves was blown to the outside of the bracket and needs to be adjusted. The severely damaged roof There are broken tiles on the floor, which should be cleaned as soon as possible. &quot;Prevent the heavy rain after the tornado from falling down the originally skewed items, causing secondary disasters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chen Jianqiang and his wife, residents of North Street in Daxing Town, the main problem is that after the roof tiles are broken, How to fall asleep at night. Daughter Chen Guo said that the roof of her parents&#39; house had just been renovated a few days ago, and they spent three to four thousand yuan to replace it with new tiles. Unexpectedly, the tornado ripped through most of the roof, and the electrical appliances in the house were also soaked in rain all night. Fortunately, the corridor was made of hard cement boards, so the two old men laid several layers of quilts on the corridor and spent the night. On September 20, my uncle, who was in his seventies, came to help repair the roof. I didn’t know when it would be repaired. Someone from the village registered the loss of the house, but the old man didn&#39;t know how to subsidize it in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 20, the Suqian Emergency Management Bureau issued a WeChat article stating that it had insured urban and rural residents of Suqian City with public safety urban and rural assistance insurance, which would cover urban and rural housing in Suqian City due to floods and typhoons. Compensation for house losses caused by natural disasters such as landslides, landslides, fires and explosions. The compensation standard is that for urban housing, the main structure insurance amount is 180,000 yuan/household, and the interior decoration insurance amount is 120,000 yuan/household; for rural housing, the main structure insurance amount is 180,000 yuan/household, and the interior decoration insurance amount is 40,000 yuan/household. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The underwriter of this project is mainly the Suqian Branch of the People&#39;s Insurance Company of China Co., Ltd. Zheng Xinbo, the company&#39;s contact person, told Southern Weekend reporters that this private housing insurance is purchased by the government, and each household pays 2 yuan. , have been purchasing continuously for many years. After the disaster occurred, they sent more than 30 staff to the villages and towns on the 20th to verify the damage and determine the damage. The first batch of compensation will be completed before the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relatively speaking, Yancheng City has more experience in dealing with tornadoes. Public information shows that on June 23, 2012, Yancheng &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: none;&quot;>;City&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;file://item/%E9%98%9C%E5% AE%81/871643%3ffromModule=lemma_inlink&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text-decoration: none;&quot;>;Funing&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text -decoration: none;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;a href=&quot;file://item/%E5%B0%84%E9%98%B3/871862%3ffromModule=lemma_inlink&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; text-decoration: none;&quot;>;Sheyang&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;An EF4 tornado occurred in some areas, with winds exceeding level 17. 99 people were killed and 846 injured. The local government built the Yancheng Memorial Hall for Fighting the &quot;6.23&quot; Tornado. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Funing County Party Committee Propaganda Department stated that Funing County has also formulated corresponding emergency plans for natural disasters that occur more frequently. After the tornado, the &quot;9.19&quot; Typhoon Emergency Rescue Command was established in the affected town as soon as possible; special teams were arranged to go to each disaster-stricken village to find out the situation, grasp the disaster situation as soon as possible and report it quickly. Four rounds of sifting search and rescue operations were carried out overnight on September 19. In addition, 129 disaster-stricken people were urgently relocated and resettled by staying with relatives and friends, staying in hotels, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiangsu is a tornado-prone area in the country. According to &quot;Jiangsu Meteorology&quot; news, from 1956 to 2015, a total of 109 tornadoes occurred in Jiangsu, with the highest proportion occurring in summer, reaching 79.8%, with an annual average of 1.5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Jiangsu is prone to tornadoes is that the province has a flat terrain, dense rivers and lakes, and is located in the north-south climate transition zone. Cold and warm air currents frequently meet, which can easily form strong convective weather including tornadoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meteorological experts in the above article said that Jiangsu is usually less prone to tornadoes in mid-to-late September, but recently due to higher temperatures and the influence of the Jianghuai cyclone, relatively strong tornadoes have occurred. dynamic conditions. Against this background, a relatively rare tornado event occurred in Jiangsu on September 19. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 21st, Wang Xiaohua, deputy director of the Jiangsu Provincial Meteorological Observatory, said in an interview with CCTV that the Jiangsu Provincial Meteorological Observatory has built a strong convection and strong wind demonstration system from 2021 to 2023. , some preliminary forecast and warning capabilities of tornadoes. In the next step, the meteorological department will use multi-source observation data such as multi-band radar collaborative observation to improve and optimize tornado early warning technology and indicators based on the characteristics of climate change, and further improve forecast and early warning capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Local residents are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白切鸡寿司走红，年轻人流行的“中餐日作”是真香吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257296]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:30:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[钱锺书回避鲁迅？No，他开启了“悄悄关注”模式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257339]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B0asgnIe8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height=&quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B 0asgnIe8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251595&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Lin Yutang, Lu Xun, Soong Ching Ling, Smedley, Li Peihua (Secretary of Soong Ching Ling) ). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Qian Zhongshu rarely talked about Lu Xun publicly, he could not &quot;avoid&quot; Lu Xun. Crystal once said in &quot;Miscellaneous Notes of Shi Qian&#39;s Throwing Books&quot; that at a symposium, Qian Zhongshu praised Lu Xun&#39;s short stories for being well written, but not suitable for long stories. The most well-known person is Qian Zhongshu&#39;s opening speech at the &quot;Lu Xun and Chinese and Foreign Culture&quot; academic seminar. This article was later published in &quot;Literary Journal&quot; on October 23, 1986, and collected in &quot;The Edge of Life&quot;. In his opening speech, Qian Zhongshu said a few words &quot;as usual&quot; based on people&#39;s &quot;public opinions&quot; on Lu Xun at that time: &quot;Lu Xun was a great man. The greater the figure, the more aspects can be observed; &#39;Chinese and foreign culture&#39; is a big The bigger the topic, the wider the scope of the problems that can occur.&quot; The main spirit of his speech was to hope that everyone can &quot;speak freely without bending the meaning to seek common ground&quot;, and could not see the true evaluation of Lu Xun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun also had a period of time in the same city. In September 1927, Lu Xun left Guangzhou and lived in Shanghai until his death in October 1936. Qian Zhongshu graduated from Tsinghua University in the summer of 1933 and taught at Guanghua University. He began studying at Oxford in the autumn of 1935, so he spent more than two years in Shanghai. However, they were only from the same city, and the two of them had never been seen crossing paths. However, as a later scholar and because of Lu Xun&#39;s huge influence, Qian Zhongshu inevitably had to &quot;encounter&quot; Lu Xun intentionally or unintentionally when writing. &quot;On the Parallel Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu&quot; written by Liu Yukai and &quot;On the Comparative Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu Literature&quot; written by Sui Qing&#39;e have all made comparisons from an academic level. Scholars such as Xie Yong, Wang Peijun, Li Guotao and Qian Zhijun have made comparisons in their writings. There are also elucidations from time to time, and I would like to unearth several examples related to Lu Xun from Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writings, which may fill the gaps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Besieged City&quot;, Sun Roujia&#39;s uncle and aunt hold important positions in a large cotton factory and have always looked down upon Fang Hongjian. Once, Fang Hongjian and Sun Roujia quarreled again over the arrival of his aunt. When he learned that his aunt wanted to find a position for him in the factory, he jumped up and shouted: &quot;Who wants her to find trouble for me? I can&#39;t even beg for food.&quot; Don&#39;t ask her for it! Isn&#39;t it enough that she has two lackeys, Bobby and you, Sun Roujia? You tell her that Fang Hongjian &#39;has no skills but a very bad temper&#39;, and you won&#39;t be a lackey of a capitalist lackey.&quot; This paragraph of text , immediately reminds people of Lu Xun&#39;s famous article &quot;&quot;Bereaved&quot; and &quot;The Capitalist&#39;s Lacking Lackey&quot; published in 1930, which criticized Liang Shiqiu. Although Qian Zhongshu was studying in Tsinghua University at the time, he would not have missed the articles on the Lu-Liang debate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 84 of the first volume of the Commercial Press&#39;s &quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot;, reading the notes of Yue Ke&#39;s &quot;History&quot;, Qian Zhongshu excerpted the following paragraph in Volume 12 and added a note:&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the summer of the 10th year of the reign of Emperor Xizong (Wanyan) of the Jin Dynasty, Long Jian (present) in the Yuzhai Palace, there was a heavy thunderstorm Arrive, break the pillar and go away. Everyone was shocked, thinking it was ominous, and wanted to look at it in disgust. Some people thought that a general amnesty should be granted, so they called Zhang Jun, a bachelor, to draft the imperial edict. Among them are the words &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Looking at Yu Xiaozi&quot;. The translator did not know the meaning of Tuo Qianchong, so he said: &quot;Han&#39;er is strong in knowledge, and he relies on words to criticize my Lord&#39;s ears.&quot; When asked why, he translated and explained its meaning: &quot;The widowed is lonely and has no relatives; the ignorant is ignorant of human affairs; the eyes are blind; the brat is a child.&quot; He was furious and summoned Jun to question him, but he failed to answer him. , slash (cut) its mouth with a hand sword, and dig it with thorns. I didn&#39;t know that it was translated as &quot;foolishness&quot; or &quot;treachery&quot;. So... According to this, Lu Xun is also the ancestor of literal translation. &quot; (&quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot; page 146)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Xizong Wanyan Dan was the third emperor of the Jin Dynasty. It is said that he studied under Han Fang before he came to the throne and was able to write poems in Chinese. After he came to the throne, he was particularly diligent in studying Chinese classics. According to this article in the &quot;History of the Emperor&quot;, Wanyan Quan did not seem to be very proficient in Chinese, and the translator could only &quot;literally translate&quot;, taking out of context the commonly used imperial edicts. Formulas such as &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Xiao Yu Xiaozi&quot; can be &quot;directly interpreted&quot; as cursing the Lord, thus losing the original meaning of &quot;retreating, trusting, and rushing&quot;, and Zhang Jun was convicted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Zhongshu&#39;s note &quot;This is the ancestor of Lu Xun&#39;s literal translation&quot; naturally reminds people of the &quot;Lu-Liang Controversy&quot;. In September 1929, Liang Shiqiu published &quot;On Mr. Lu Xun&#39;s Life&quot; in &quot;Crescent&quot; &quot;Hard Translation&quot;&quot;, Lu Xun refuted it by publishing &quot;&quot;Hard Translation&quot; and &quot;The Class Nature of Literature&quot;&quot; in &quot;Jinya Monthly&quot; in March of the following year. The debate has exceeded the boundaries of translation. As far as translation is concerned, Lu Xun advocated &quot;literal translation&quot; (or &quot;hard translation&quot;), such as the translation of &quot;The Symbol of Depression&quot;, which &quot;is translated sentence by sentence, or even word for word according to the rules&quot;, and its purpose is to &quot;prefer to believe rather than obey.&quot; Qian Zhongshu is obviously familiar with translation However, his views were different from those of Lu Xun, so Qian Zhongshu went on to write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yu Reading &quot;Shuowen&quot; to the &quot;Kou&quot; part of the 26th word &quot;囮: 译也&quot;, Chang sighs Ji Chang (Editor&#39;s note: refers to Xu Shen), a true saint, foresees Tradutore, traditore! Wang Yuanzhi&#39;s &quot;Little Animals Collection&quot; Volume 14 &quot;Translation Dui&quot; says: &quot;Translation means Yi. It can change one&#39;s mind if it is big, but it can only change one&#39;s words if it is small. &quot;So on and so forth. After liberation, the trend of translating books became more and more popular. They did not know how to make mistakes, but they were eaten alive. Not only were they changed beyond recognition, but their hearts and minds were completely changed. They were the so-called &quot;great translators&quot; in Xun Yuan Dynasty. Gu Tangsheng&#39;s &quot;Records of Zhang Wenxiang&#39;s Shogunate&quot; Juan Xia said: &quot;Chen Lanbin envoy to the United States, one of his attendants, Xu, is not familiar with Western languages. One day, he suddenly picked up the Western Newspaper and seemed to be reading it with gusto. His colleagues asked him strangely. Xu said: I can&#39;t understand the Western Newspaper. I read Zhu Jun&#39;s translation. Also puzzled. If you still don&#39;t understand, it would be better to just read the Western newspaper. &quot;In this way, both this and Zhang Jun&#39;s incident can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators. (ibid., pp. 146-147)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This note is related to the fact that &quot;after liberation&quot; the translation industry &quot;does not know what to do. Talking about &quot;eating alive&quot; is also a denial of &quot;literal translation&quot;. Regarding translation, what Qian Zhongshu pursues is the realm of &quot;translation&quot;, although &quot;thorough and complete &#39;translation&#39; is an unattainable ideal.&quot; Therefore, Qian Zhongshu pursues In the article, Zhongshu praised Xu Shen (Jianchang) as a &quot;true saint&quot; and said that he could predict that the translation would be &quot;囮&quot; (false) and that the translator (Tradutore) was a traitor (traditore). For details, see &quot;Lin Shu&#39;s Translation&quot; and There are several discussions in &quot;Guan Zhui Bian&quot;. The following part of this article is based on Gu Hongming&#39;s story of Xu reading a Western newspaper, and combined with Zhang Jun&#39;s view, he believes that &quot;all can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators.&quot; It is humorous without losing irony, which is quite obvious. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writing style is consistent. The most eye-catching part of the whole note is the note &quot;the ancestor of literal translation&quot; and so on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1920s and 1930s, Lin Yutang was trying to change the &quot;Chinese-style humor&quot; &quot;Joking attitude&quot; to reshape the virtues of gentlemen, so he advocated &quot;humorous literature&quot;. Unexpectedly, it backfired, as Qian Zhongshu criticized in his essay &quot;Joking&quot;: &quot;Since the promotion of humorous literature, joking has become a literati career. &quot;Lin Yutang helped the &quot;current ills&quot; by rescuing &quot;current ills.&quot; The actual effect of &quot;humorous literature&quot; ran counter to its original intention. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s &quot;Jokes&quot; was inspired by &quot;humorous literature.&quot; As for Lin Yutang&#39;s ideas, Lu Xun In &quot;One Thought and Action&quot;, he once criticized: &quot;Boom, there is no shortage of humor and sketches in the world. &quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;, Volume 5, page 473) also pointed out in &quot;Explanation of &quot;Funny&quot;&quot; that humorous literature just gives &quot;slick, frivolous and obscene&quot; the &quot;title of &#39;humor&#39;&quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;) &quot;Volume 5, page 342). Some people therefore believe that &quot;Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu really echo each other in their views on promoting humorous literature&quot; (Li Qinye, &quot;Reading &amp;lt;Writing on the Edge of Life&quot;), This statement is specious.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the history of modern literature, Lu Xun, Lin Yutang and Qian Zhongshu are all famous for their humor. Lu Xun&#39;s humor is like a dagger, with the edge of a scalpel to remove tumors, while Lin Yutang&#39;s humor is The breeze is like a purifier for the soul. At that time, Lin Yutang&#39;s humorous literature was naturally not as powerful as Lu Xun&#39;s essays, so it seemed out of date and was publicly criticized by Lu Xun. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s humor was like cold rain hitting his face, cold and thorny, like a pretender The embarrassment and uneasiness after his soul was exposed. However, although Qian Zhongshu also criticized Lin Yutang, if you compare his &quot;Laughing&quot; with Lin Yutang&#39;s &quot;On Humor&quot;, you will find how similar their views on humor are: Qian Zhongshu It is said that a person who is really humorous will have a &quot;knowing smile&quot; about humor. Lin Yutang said that a calm and distant bystander will give a &quot;knowing smile&quot; to humor; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;funny and wise&quot; , Lin Yutang said, &quot;wisdom has begun&quot; and &quot;there is humor&quot;; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;a breath of breath for the dull life&quot;, Lin Yutang said that humor is &quot;a part of life&quot;. Humor originates from wisdom, famous humorists It is not surprising that Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang have similar concepts but different expressions and effects. Because of this view of humor, Lin Yutang advocates humorous literature to cultivate the people&#39;s sense of humor and cultivate educated citizens, while Qian Zhongshu believes that true humor can &quot; &quot;Anti-bowing and laughing at oneself&quot; will become a laughing stock once advocated, so he said: &quot;Humor is at most a kind of temperament and can never be labeled as an idea, let alone a profession.&quot; ” It can be seen that although Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun both criticized the “humorous literature” advocated by Lin Yutang, it cannot be said that their views on humor are of the same origin. On the contrary, Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang’s views on humor are “similar to each other.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As a witness and participant in the same literary and artistic trend, although Qian Zhongshu never had direct contact with Lu Xun, it even made people think that he sometimes deliberately &quot;looked sideways&quot; at Lu Xun, and followed the trend to find out the source. If we open the &quot;fog&quot;, we can still see their figures at the same time in major events in the history of modern literature, and then we can see Qian Zhongshu&#39;s consistent indifferent attitude towards Shi Xian, including Lu Xun, &quot;It&#39;s like seeing from flying sand, wheat waves, and ripples &quot;The posture of the wind&quot; (Qian Zhong&#39;s calligraphy). (The original title of this article was &quot;The posture of the wind&quot;, the current title was proposed by the editor)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get More RSS: &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4.2千年事件”：地球大降温，华夏新生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257310]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of this century, with the advancement of molecular biology, we were able to explore the origin of rice through gene testing - detection The results show that cultivated rice was first domesticated in the Yangtze River Basin about 13,500 to 8.2 thousand years ago, and then spread to Southeast Asia and South Asia. After hybridizing with wild indica rice in South Asia, cultivated indica rice was produced and returned to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the process of studying the origin of rice, genetic testing has brought questions. Scholars suddenly discovered that there are many strange things about its spread time: after rice was domesticated, it stayed in China for thousands of years and did not spread outside. However, around 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, almost at the same time, rice suddenly appeared on the Japanese Islands, the Korean Peninsula, the Philippines, Indo-China Peninsula and the South Asian subcontinent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This makes people wonder: What happened more than four thousand years ago? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from ancient Chinese books, 4,000 years ago was around the time when the Xia Dynasty was established. It is said that after Emperor Yu controlled the floods, he sent envoys to measure &quot;the whole world&quot; and finally calculated that the distance from east to west and north to south of the earth was 233,500 miles and 75 steps. Although this is just a myth in the &quot;Book of Mountains and Seas&quot;, mythical stories often have prototypes: Maybe after Dayu established the Xia Dynasty, he sent envoys to explore the unknown world and spread rice to surrounding countries by the way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an archaeological perspective, the world between 4.2 and 4,000 years ago was suffering unprecedented disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you pay attention to Chinese archeology, you may have heard the saying &quot;a sky full of stars&quot;, which describes ancient civilizations before the Xia Dynasty: China between 5000 and 4300 years ago was full of archaeological sites. There are Hongshan in the western Liao River basin and Longshan in the Yellow River basin. These two are already city-state civilizations; in the Yangtze River basin there are Liangzhu and Shijiahe, both of which have entered dynastic politics. At that time, the earth was in the famous &quot;Holocene Warm Period&quot;. The humid and warm climate allowed civilizations all over the world to thrive. Even the deserts of Central Asia and the Sahara Desert of Africa were livable places with widespread forests and lakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, the civilizations in the three major river basins all collapsed, and the entire land of China fell into chaos:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cities in Shijiahe and Liangzhu in the Yangtze River Basin collapsed one after another Destroyed and abandoned, the territory shrank sharply. By 3800 years ago, the original core area had almost become a no-man&#39;s land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many settlements in the Xiliao River Basin disappeared completely, and the population was directly replaced: genetic testing found that the Xiajiadian lower-class culture that later emerged in the local area had no genetic connection with the previous residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yellow River Basin is also full of victims: Archeology shows that the number of settlements in the middle and lower reaches of the Yellow River decreased by nearly 90% during this catastrophe, and the population may only be 1/10 of its original size. The exquisite and brilliant Longshan black pottery disappeared, and it was not until more than a hundred years later that a very rough gray pottery culture appeared - which means that the original civilization, the original knowledge and technology inheritance were also lost in this catastrophe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the origin of this catastrophe, the most common hypothesis is the Great Flood: Based on archaeological evidence, some scholars speculate that about 3920 years ago, a huge barrier lake formed in the upper reaches of the Yellow River, blocking the Yellow River. nearly 9 months. Afterwards, the barrier lake burst its banks, and about 16 billion cubic meters of lake water poured down instantly. The flood almost flattened the entire Yellow River Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this hypothesis has some truth, it cannot explain the great collapse that also occurred in the Yangtze River Basin during the same period - in fact, not only the Yellow River and the Yangtze River, but also the whole world experienced a great collapse of civilization at that time. This was obviously a Climate disasters affecting the world:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The forests and Saharan lakes in Central Asia disappeared, and the great desert was born; in the Nile River Basin of North Africa, the early dynasty that had flourished for five hundred years came to an abrupt end, severe drought led to the collapse of agriculture, and Egypt fell into The century-long famine and civil strife is known to history as the &quot;First Intermediate Period&quot;; in the two river basins of West Asia, the Akkadian Empire completed its unification for the first time. A large amount of farmland was abandoned and was immediately attacked by foreign barbarians; in Central and Northern Europe, The cooling made the climate cold and humid, leading to the great migration of many ethnic groups...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This climate catastrophe is now called the &quot;4.2 Millennium Event&quot;, a catastrophe that can be called the end of civilization. . The superposition of turbulent ocean currents, super volcanic eruptions and El Niño may be the culprits of this natural disaster. The 4.2 millennium event manifested itself differently in different regions. Some places experienced severe droughts, while others experienced floods, but generally speaking, major cooling occurred. In fact, this event occurred from the end of the &quot;Younger Dryas Little Ice Age&quot; until the end of the Little Ice Age. Today, humanity has experienced the most severe cooling. The temperature in many places has never returned to the level of the Holocene Warm Period, and the good days of comfort and warmth are gone forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, it was the 4.2 Thousand Years Incident that exterminated the ancestors of the Western Liao River, severely damaged the ancient city-states of the Yellow River, and destroyed the two ancient dynasties in the Yangtze River Basin. Agriculture collapsed, famine was rampant, and mourning was widespread. In just a few decades or even a few years, 90% of the population has been lost. This is a doomsday scene that we today cannot imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The few survivors in South China, namely the ancient farmers of the Yangtze River and their descendants, had to take their rice seeds with them and flee in search of new land that could barely be cultivated. They crossed the sea to the east and reached the Korean Peninsula and Japan, becoming the ancestors of Koreans and Japanese immigrants; they reached the Philippines to the south and became the first stop for the Austronesian people to conquer the Pacific; they crossed the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau to the west and reached the Indochina Peninsula and India. , and the local hunter indigenous people, merged to form the Mon-Khmer language family (South Asian language family)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, misfortunes and blessings depend on each other, and new life is also born in the doomsday disaster. After the catastrophe, China bid farewell to the &quot;starry sky&quot; and began to unite: the ancestors of South China (ancient farmers on the Yangtze River) who fled famine, and another group arrived in the northern Central Plains. Here they met the ancient farmers of the Yellow River who had also fled here. The two integrated and communicated to build a new home together - the north and south areas of Songshan Mountain where Erlitou in Henan is located were not prominent during the Holocene Warm Period, with only some scattered small settlements. However, hundreds of years after the Great Collapse, probably ancestors who had fled from various places gathered here, and the place rapidly revived and grew. About 3,800 years ago, Erlitou had developed into the largest settlement in the entire Yellow River Basin and became the undisputed master of the Central Plains. It immediately began to expand aggressively, and soon became an unrivaled and powerful dynasty in the entire East Asia - many scholars believe that it is the Xia Dynasty in ancient books, and the era of unification of China has arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[凉山警方破获特大贩运毒品案，缴获各类毒品146千克、抓捕31人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the summer public security crackdown and rectification operations of public security agencies across the country, Liangshan Public Security focused on the characteristics of summer social security laws , focusing on prominent local illegal and criminal activities, using the &quot;Sharpening Sword&quot; operation as the starting point, strengthening crackdowns and rectification efforts, and implementing special work measures to effectively protect the peace of people&#39;s lives and maintain the overall stability of social security. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/5e015de2df5bfed8a0005a8fd8d1b0e2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;466&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/5e015de2df5bfed8a0005a8fd8d1b0e2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251585 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 20, the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau held a press briefing on the summer public security crackdown and the &quot;Strengthening the Sword&quot; operation, focusing on reporting on the results of the operation and typical cases. Zhao Peng, deputy secretary of the Party Committee and executive deputy director of the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau, attended the meeting and reported the overall work results. Yu Xing, member of the Party Committee and Director of the Political Department of Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau, presided over the briefing meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the deployment of the operation, the public security organs across the state have carried out 14 centralized inspections, dispatching a total of more than 48,000 police officers, effectively promoting the &quot;sharpening sword&quot; operation and achieving &quot;two reductions and three improvements&quot; (telecom network fraud, theft The incidence rate of similar cases has dropped, and the number of cases involving drugs, pornography, and gambling has increased). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating drug crimes. As of August, 112 cases had been solved, 149 people had been punished, 139 people had been detained administratively, and 42 people had been forced to quit. On August 31, the &quot;2022.10.12&quot; major drug trafficking case was successfully uncovered. A total of 31 suspects were arrested in the case, a total of 146 kilograms of various drugs and more than 800,000 yuan in drug money were seized. The most complete drug network involving Yunnan and Myanmar drug cases. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating telecommunications network fraud. From March 1st to August 31st, a total of 537 telecom network fraud cases occurred across the state; 325 cases were solved; 950 people were arrested; more than 71.8064 million yuan was lost; 2.218243 yuan was recovered and the loss was recovered. We insist on &quot;prevention first&quot; in cases of electronic fraud &quot;, the state&#39;s &quot;Anti-Fraud Center&quot; issued an average of more than 3,228 early warnings per day, stopped payment for 9,958 accounts involved, stopped payment of more than 211 million yuan, and froze 1,242 accounts involved, freezing funds of more than 45.5635 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on illegal crimes such as theft. A total of 824 theft cases occurred across the state, and a total of 314 theft cases were solved across the state; 680 suspects were arrested and 543 were punished. Successfully solved the case of &quot;the theft of cables from the main engineering station of Huaneng Butuotuojue Wind Power Project&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on Internet-related crimes. The crackdown rate on online rumors reached 100%; 137 cases of major sensitive public opinions were safely handled, and negative public opinions related to the Cold War dropped by 30% compared with the same period last year. As of August, 24 cases had been solved and 27 people had been punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on pornography-related crimes. The public security organs across the state insist on taking the &quot;anti-pornography operation&quot; as the primary task of crackdown and rectification. So far, a total of 636 pornography-related cases (527 administrative cases, 109 criminal cases) have been handled, and 787 people have been punished (651 administrative cases, 136 criminal cases). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating illegal gambling crimes. As of August, 838 cases have been solved, 2,882 people have been punished, 19 people have been criminally detained after detecting the &quot;Zhang Moumou and others gathering gambling case&quot; in Muli, 32 gambling participants were investigated and dealt with, and more than 60,000 yuan of gambling funds were seized; In the &quot;2023.8.11 crowd gambling case&quot;, 32 people were criminally detained, and the amount involved was more than 200,000 yuan; the two courts jointly prosecuted 15 cases successfully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listing rectification. In April 2023, the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau launched the first batch of 50 online fugitives publicly offering rewards, and 42 of them have been brought to justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白客：像水一样的演员]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Most of the time, Baike doesn&#39;t know where the boundaries of his abilities are and relies on his feelings. Taking on a role is not that particular about rules and regulations, it’s about getting along well. In the past few years, he has acted in many movies and dramas that focus on reality, and appeared in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; and &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot;. He said, &quot;The abilities contained in my body were discovered by the producer and director. Thank them.&quot; And he quietly does his job as an actor, using his skills, emotions, and talents to be responsible for every performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/254252&quot; title=&quot;Baike: A &quot;cowarded and frustrated&quot; &quot;The actor&#39;s way of survival&quot;>;Bake: The way of survival of a &quot;cowardly and frustrated&quot; actor&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 9, 2023, the Shanghai International Film Festival opened On the red carpet, actor Bai Ke appeared three times. In the screenings that lasted for 10 days, he was Gan Yaozu in &quot;Looking for Her&quot; and &quot;The Annual Party Can&#39;t Stop!&quot; &quot;Ma Jie&quot; and Pan Congcong in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;, whether he is the protagonist or supporting role, comedy or drama, he has appropriately expressed the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Baike, becoming an actor was unexpected. On the eve of his graduation from college, he became famous for his dubbing work. In 2010, after graduating from Nanguang College of Communication University of China, he briefly worked in a television station, and then quickly went north to join the film and television company Wanhe Tianyi. When the company was on the verge of collapse and everyone was planning to go their separate ways, they filmed the short play &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, which saved the company and made the director and actors an instant hit. The male protagonist of &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, the narcissistic, self-deprecating, grassroots Wang Dachui, was played by Bai Gugu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of becoming popular in his early years was intertwined with the family teaching of &quot;live your own little life&quot;, and finally derived a happy-go-lucky character. He has his own comfort zone and feels good staying there. After work, I play football with my friends, watch football, read comics and TV shows, and spend time with my parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only time he experienced stepping out of his comfort zone since he was a child was when he decided to apply for the broadcasting major because he liked football and wanted to be a football commentator. After studying media for four years, although he failed to become a commentator, he became sensitive to the matter of &quot;recording&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also related to this that Baike liked the script of &quot;Looking for Her&quot;, a female self-awareness exploration in a traditional village. He said: &quot;This kind of thing is very meaningful to me. I think the topic needs to be recorded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The filming of &quot;Looking for Her&quot; was not easy for Baike because he had to memorize Cantonese lines and play opposite Shu Qi. There was a scene where he and Shu Qi quarreled, and there was a lot of dialogue in Cantonese. It was originally going to be filmed after the actors got used to each other. However, the crew encountered a typhoon as soon as they arrived in Huizhou, the filming location. In order to avoid the bad weather, director Chen Shizhong planned to shoot the quarrel scene indoors first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He would not say that I was scared before shooting, nor would he say that I would definitely be able to do it, and then he would do it very well. He was very relaxed, but he had strong energy inside.&quot; Later Chen Shizhong said Then I realized that Bai Ke was nervous, but he hid it. Chen Shizhong had seen a journalist role he played, and on the day after watching it, he posted on WeChat Moments: Bai Ke can give the director a great sense of security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He is an actor like water. He can be matched with any actor. He is very malleable.&quot; Chen Shizhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>