<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[山西安泽县永鑫通海铁路物流公司施工事故导致7人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 19:41:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Propaganda Department of Linfen Municipal Party Committee, Shanxi Province that the construction of Shanxi Yongxin Tonghai Railway Logistics Co., Ltd. in Anze County Seven people buried in the accident have been confirmed dead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter saw at the scene that there were eight nearly 30-meter-high column buildings arranged in a &quot;one&quot; shape in the north-south direction. The roof of the first building on the south side collapsed. Search and rescue personnel were working on the building. Wooden boards were built at the bottom to prevent secondary collapse of the overhead scaffolding. There was a large amount of concrete accumulation in the search and rescue area at the bottom, and on-site search and rescue personnel were carrying out demolition construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 22:00 on the 24th, a concrete support model for pouring a corridor fell off at the construction site of Shanxi Yongxin Tonghai Railway Logistics Co., Ltd. At around 20:30 that day, 30 cubic meters of concrete was poured into the beam and slab at the 28.5-meter mark of the 8th section of the raw coal shed constructed by Chinalco International (Tianjin) Construction Co., Ltd. The scaffolding suddenly collapsed at about 22:00, and six workers were involved. and a concrete pump truck commander fell to the bottom and were buried in reinforced concrete. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一“码”就医，人均省43分钟：医保码如何更好用更智能？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261330]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/25/f5352e97c9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 25/f5352e97c9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259632&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On June 2, 2020, residents’ mobile phones in Shangshui Lakeside Community, Luyang District, Hefei City, Anhui Province Scan the QR code to activate the &quot;Medical Insurance Electronic Voucher&quot;. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Yunqing, executive vice president of the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, also understands that queuing is the most troublesome thing for patients in the process of seeking medical treatment-registration, payment and appointment queuing consume a lot of time. As soon as they entered the outpatient hall of the hospital, the crowds and the hot air made the patients who were already sick inevitably feel even more depressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to the medical insurance code (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;i.e. &quot;medical insurance electronic voucher&quot; &lt;/span>;), even if you are affiliated with Zhejiang University The First Hospital has more than 7 million outpatient visits a year, and the outpatient hall &quot;will not seem so crowded.&quot; &quot;Patients will settle the registration fees through the mini program through medical insurance in advance and report online. After the treatment, they will directly settle the medical insurance fees through the mini program.&quot; Qiu Yunqing told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data provided by Qiu Yunqing shows that patients can complete the entire medical process by holding the medical insurance code, which significantly improves the efficiency of patient treatment and hospital operation efficiency. In 2023, the settlement rate of the medical insurance code of Zhejiang University First Hospital will reach 45.67 %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Same as the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, 31 provinces across the country (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Municipality and autonomous region&lt;/span>;) and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps have supported medical insurance codes for medical treatment and drug purchase, with access to more than 800,000 designated medical institutions and more than 1 billion users of medical insurance codes. At the press conference of the National Medical Insurance Administration on November 24, 2023, Fu Chaoqi, deputy director of the National Medical Insurance Administration Office, provided the above data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Chaoqi pointed out that judging from the activation status of medical insurance codes in various provinces, Zhejiang and Qinghai provinces have taken the lead in achieving coverage of insured persons in the province, and the activation rate of medical insurance codes in more than half of the provinces exceeds 75%. Data from Tencent Health Calculation shows that for an ordinary insured person, he can make an appointment through the WeChat public account before seeing a doctor, and use the medical insurance code to complete online medical insurance payment during settlement, saving an average of 43 minutes for each patient. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Break barriers and use the whole process of medical treatment and drug purchase&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When purchasing drugs in hospitals and pharmacies, the &quot;bright code&quot; on the mobile phone can be traced back to four years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 24, 2019, the first medical insurance code (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Medical Insurance Electronic Voucher&lt;/span>;) was launched in Shandong Jinan City, Province, is activated. At that time, the National Medical Insurance Administration hoped that the medical insurance code would not only be simply electronic, but also realize the vision of &quot;seeing a doctor without a card, only using the medical insurance code&quot;, with unified standards across the country, cross-regional mutual recognition, and one electronic voucher. All medical insurance business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four years later, these visions have not only been gradually implemented, but also new attempts are being made. Take Zhejiang Province as an example. In the past, there were 54 medical insurance systems in Zhejiang, which were separated from each other and not shared with each other. Until March 2022, Zhejiang Province’s “Smart Medical Insurance” system will be fully connected to the national medical insurance platform, realizing the unified medical insurance settlement in Zhejiang Province. system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cao Cen, deputy director of the Zhejiang Medical Insurance Bureau, said that Zhejiang requires all designated medical institutions to transform their HIS (hospital information management system) to support the use of medical insurance codes throughout the process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, in Zhejiang Provincial Hospital, everything from registration, medical treatment, payment, inspection and testing, printing reports, to getting medicines, handling hospitalization and medical insurance settlement and other services can be completed by just scanning the QR code; in pharmacies, , the medical insurance code supports prescription circulation, drug purchase and dispensing, and medical insurance settlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The medical insurance code also breaks down the barriers inside and outside the hospital. Jinhua Central Hospital of Zhejiang Province mentioned in a paper that by applying medical insurance codes to achieve electronic prescription circulation, patients can choose &quot;dual channels&quot; (through two channels, designated medical institutions and designated retail pharmacies, and be included in medical insurance payment simultaneously if conditions are met) ) Purchase prescription drugs at designated retail pharmacies and enjoy the same reimbursement treatment as those at hospitals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The service scenario has changed from ‘single point’ to ‘full process’.” Xie Zhangshu, deputy director of the Department of Regulation, Finance and Law of the National Medical Insurance Administration, said that the application of medical insurance codes for the entire process of medical treatment and drug purchase is a key task of the medical insurance department in 2023 One is to promote the medical insurance code from being only available in the settlement process to being used in the entire process of appointment registration, sign-in for medical treatment, diagnosis and treatment, report inquiry, and pharmacy retrieval. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Families work together to make it convenient for the elderly and children&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Most of the patients in the hospital are elderly, so it is particularly important for modern technology to take into account the needs of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A paper from the Zhejiang Provincial Cancer Hospital mentioned that the average age of medical insurance patients in Hangzhou in 2021 is 55 years old, of which about 40% are patients aged 60 and above. “On the one hand, elderly patients are smart The usage rate of mobile phones is low; on the other hand, compared with young people, elderly patients are less proficient and fluent in using smartphones.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of aging-friendly transformation, WeChat Medical Insurance Code has launched an accessible version to support visually impaired people to use the medical insurance code through voice. At the same time, family account services have been launched in many provinces, and facial recognition and other technologies have been applied to support relatives. Agency business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Yunqing told Southern Weekend reporters that most elderly people are accompanied by their family members when they seek medical treatment. Through the medical insurance family account function, accompanying family members can bind the elderly person’s medical insurance code to their own accounts to facilitate appointments and payments for the elderly. cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, according to the medical insurance policies of Zhejiang and other places, the balance of the personal account of the insured person over the years can be used to directly pay the spouse who participates in the basic medical insurance in the same coordinating area in the province through the &quot;Family Mutual Aid Filing&quot; , children and parents’ medical insurance expenses. For example, if a young person’s personal account is not used up, they can give it to their parents. “(&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Parents&lt;/span>;) prepare a medicine today. The medical insurance will just send you a text message to tell you what medicine was prescribed and how much it cost. It is also very convenient after binding, and you can use the money from your personal account to pay your relatives.&quot; Qiu Yunqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have also paid attention to the medical insurance service needs of some groups such as the elderly and minors who have difficulty using smart technology. We have effectively integrated traditional services with smart methods, launched family accounts, and registered on behalf of others for medical treatment in other places. function, and added the service of offline activation of medical insurance codes in medical insurance agencies to help special groups obtain and enjoy mobile medical insurance services and improve the accessibility of convenient medical insurance services.&quot; Xie Zhangshu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Be wary of fraudulent use of medical insurance codes to ensure the safety of medical insurance funds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, while medical insurance codes are convenient, how to ensure the safety of medical insurance funds also brings challenges to all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Guangzhou Medical Insurance Service Center pointed out in a paper that the medical insurance electronic voucher does not currently have the photo information of the insured person, and it is difficult to verify whether the person who holds the medical code is the insured person when seeking medical treatment, which is a problem for the medical insurance fund. Supervision brings difficulties and challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Putian police detected a case of fraudulent use of medical insurance codes. After a villager died, his relatives fraudulently used the medical insurance codes to seek medical reimbursement, defrauding the medical insurance fund of 1,232.73 yuan, and was eventually sentenced to three days of administrative detention. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Junjie, general manager of Alipay’s medical and health division, said that the system will conduct multi-factor security technical analysis on the insured’s usage habits, account changes and other information. Once an abnormality is discovered, it will be immediately reported to the Medical Insurance Bureau and the risk control system will be activated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the National Medical Insurance Administration issued the &quot;Work Plan for &quot;Two Combinations and Three Empowerments&quot; of Medical Insurance Data, which requires vertical and horizontal integration of medical insurance data to achieve comprehensive supervision of medical insurance funds. The National Medical Insurance Administration also requires that all coordinating regions will launch an intelligent supervision subsystem by the end of 2023. By the end of 2025, an intelligent audit and electronic monitoring system will be basically established, and the &quot;medical insurance code&quot; will be used to allow users, medical institutions, insurance handling units, and pharmaceutical and device companies to The data are closely connected to form a normalized supervision system that handles daily audits and on-site inspections, big data analysis, full-scenario intelligent monitoring and other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the number of medical insurance code users exceeded 1 billion, the National Medical Insurance Administration is also promoting the transformation of the service function of medical insurance codes from &quot;available&quot; to &quot;easy to use&quot;. &quot;Currently, the public&#39;s demand for medical insurance services is multi-layered, diversified, and personalized. Based on the actual needs of the people, the medical insurance department has launched a number of &#39;Internet + medical insurance services&#39; that are easy to use and popular with the public, such as online inquiries Medical consultation, one-click prescription refill, follow-up prescription dispensing, online settlement, home delivery of medicine, etc., to better meet the people’s needs for medical treatment and drug purchase.” said Xie Zhangshu, deputy director of the Department of Regulation, Finance and Law of the National Medical Insurance Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Xi Lijie also contributed)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[父亲带脑梗儿子跑网约车感动万千网友：灵活就业让赚钱与陪伴得以两全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This is news that will make all middle-aged fathers feel sad after reading it. In Chongqing, Yi Heping, a 53-year-old online ride-hailing driver, takes his son who has suffered a cerebral infarction every day. Every time he takes an order, he will apologize to the passenger first: &quot;I&#39;m sorry, the co-pilot is my son, he is sick...&quot; In September this year, the media mentioned that he had apologized more than 1,800 times. It is estimated that this data will continue to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His son is unfortunate. In 2021, Yi Heping&#39;s son was admitted to the hospital due to cerebral infarction; in early 2023, Xiao Yi was sent to the emergency room again due to cerebral hemorrhage. After treatment, Xiao Yi&#39;s physical condition gradually recovered, but he lost his ability to take care of himself. In order to better take care of his son, Yi Heping took Xiao Yi &quot;on the road&quot; with him. He has experienced order cancellations and has been understood and cared for by more passengers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as Yi Heping&#39;s destiny and personality are concerned, he has two &quot;facets&quot;. One is a loser in the ups and downs of the business world. Yi Heping used to be &quot;Boss Yi&quot;. In 1996, he went to Shenzhen to start a business and became one of the first people to operate communication equipment. He then entered the construction industry and logistics business... After getting tired of the life of attending various business banquets every day , he decided to return to his hometown and start a business in Chongqing. At that time, he still had more than 20 million yuan in his personal account, and he had everything from villas to luxury cars, as well as his own full-time driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Yi Heping’s investment failed, leading to the company’s bankruptcy, and years of hard work came to nothing in the blink of an eye. This trajectory is desolate and sad, filled with the frustration of a middle-aged man; the other is a father who is struggling between earning money to support the family and taking care of his son. The wife is unable to take care of her son due to diabetes, coronary heart disease, etc. This burden can only be shouldered by the tired father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a story is of course an &quot;only copy&quot;, but Yi Heping is not the only one who takes his children or relatives &quot;on the road&quot; to make a living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Anhui takeaway boy Li Yuanyuan put Fei&#39;er, who was only six months old, in a takeout box to deliver takeout, which attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2022, the media reported that Xiao Xin, a young man from Guizhou, took his 3-year-old son to deliver food. Life was not good to him, divorced, having a second child, raising a baby, and working hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, a video with 100,000+ views and comments, &quot;Encountering the Inspiring Mother of the Post-000&quot;, attracted attention. The mother in the video, whose husband died in an accident, was still less than one year old and was pulling alone. child and took her to deliver food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, Modern Express reported that Fu Zhenyang, a &quot;bald uncle&quot; from Lu&#39;an, Anhui, started driving a sports car in Suzhou with his sick wife in 2017, and he has been running for 6 years. Fu Zhenyang has to pay off a debt of more than 200,000 yuan and take care of his paralyzed wife. He is under great pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No need to give examples one by one. What these stories have in common is that most of the protagonists came to the city from rural areas to work hard. They all encountered huge twists and turns in life, and they all chose not to abandon or give up. They struggled to withstand the heavy pressure and endless tests of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The direct reason for their difficulty is that they are far away from their family areas and blood ties. The strong and optimistic post-00s mother was ruthlessly pushed out of the house by her mother-in-law. More often than not, some people had to come to big cities to make a living in order to change their circumstances. Obviously, in a rural and family context, when a person has difficulties, others can help him. When you go to work, someone can help you take care of your children. When you fall ill, someone brings hot meals to your home. This reflects your inability to a large extent. But after coming to the city to work alone, all the &quot;reinforcements&quot; disappeared. In a situation where the neighbors &quot;don&#39;t know each other&quot;, the only one you can rely on is yourself. The first thing you do when you wake up every day is to think about your loved ones who rely on you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What they encountered was essentially &quot;atomization.&quot; As experts say, social atomization mainly refers to the process of changes in the state of social connection during the change of unit systems. Mainly manifested by phenomena such as the weakening of connections between individuals and the alienation of individuals from the public world. These busy situations every day are exactly the realistic portrayal of the &quot;post-work unit&quot; and lonely individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are actually on an isolated island, isolated and helpless, and are not even qualified to fall down. What Yi Heping is most worried about is what will happen to his son once he is no longer there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earning money and companionship are both important and cannot be given up, but how to have both is a problem. Obviously, it is difficult for them to enter a &quot;regular unit&quot; in the secular sense and clock in from nine to five. Even if they have the ability, the fact that they need to care for a loved one who cannot care for themselves will discourage them from working. What&#39;s more, almost no unit will allow employees to bring their children or wives to work. Regardless of the company&#39;s system or order, it will say &quot;no&quot; to this situation. After all, the employer has no such obligation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, they have found a place to stay in the flexible employment sector. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the harsh reality, the &quot;dilemma&quot; hanging over their heads forced them to find other ways. The rise of platform employment and freelancing has given them great hope. This is a way of working where you don’t need to clock in and you can use your time freely. It can be said that the Internet economy, including the takeout economy, provides the final guarantee for this group of people. What is shown behind this is actually a new way of thinking developed by a society to help solve the practical difficulties of a certain group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this group, this is the only way for them to break the &quot;atomized&quot; state and get out of the predicament. Only those who desperately fight against misfortune and hardship can find this arduous but practical path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, those wanderers who take their children &quot;on the road&quot; also set an example for their children to persevere and shine in the face of adversity. Children who have this life course are better able to appreciate the true meaning of life, and will become sensible earlier than their peers. A recent video posted online showed that a mother with paralysis of her lower limbs accidentally fell down while getting into a wheelchair in Yan&#39;an, Shaanxi Province. Her 4-year-old son tried his best to help her up again and again. On November 14, Li Yuanyuan posted a video on the video platform of her three-year-old daughter Fei&#39;er helping to wash the dishes, which once again sparked discussion among netizens. Netizens called the little girl&#39;s &quot;smile so healing.&quot; Enduring hardship is also the best tutor. I firmly believe that those who run around with their children in the streets have also done a good job in raising their children psychologically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While we are exploring social assistance mechanisms to protect groups in need, we should also see the extraordinary significance of ordinary people gritting their teeth to shoulder the burden of a family and holding up an umbrella to protect their loved ones. This kind of narrative seems to be sporadic, scattered and atypical, but through the &quot;symphony of destiny&quot; of many individuals, it gathers a vivid sample of fighting uncertainty and dissatisfaction, becoming a society in the process of dissolving &quot;atomization&quot;. &quot;An indispensable force in the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成长的烦恼：中国电子竞技20年观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261254]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/t1G2je6q32XCmPWjVlGVou4ntF4YHClLlLAGiSce.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1598&quot; height=&quot;915&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/t1G2je6q32XCmPWjVlGVou4ntF4YHCl LlLAGiSce. png&quot; data-key=&quot;259255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hukou&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2002, 258,315 fires occurred in China, causing 2,393 deaths. However, the fire at the Lan Jisu Internet Cafe on Xueyuan Road in Beijing on June 16, which killed 25 people, was undoubtedly the most discussed accident that year and had the greatest subsequent impact. All Internet cafes in Beijing were closed for rectification after the accident, and then Internet cafes across the country joined the ranks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Juveniles, arson, Internet cafes, video games... a series of keywords surrounding this case, which the media called &quot;the most serious juvenile crime since the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, turned mainstream public opinion on electronics almost overnight. The game&#39;s rage was heightened to its maximum. In the next two years, relevant departments issued a number of regulations to strengthen the standardized management of Internet cafes. This directly caused Li Xiaofeng, an avid &quot;StarCraft&quot; player in Ruzhou, Henan at that time, to be unable to find an Internet cafe where he could play the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;E-sports&quot; has become a proper noun at this point in time, and has become an emerging entertainment industry that cannot be ignored globally. It is even regarded as a &quot;cultural nation&quot; by South Korea next door. &quot;An important component of strategy. But for Chinese society, which has just joined the WTO and is unfamiliar with the Internet, e-sports is not only more unfamiliar, but also appears to be quite negative because of its association with games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, those in China who had a positive attitude towards e-sports included a group of elites with broad vision in the cultural and sports system, and more were a group of ignorant teenagers with pure love on the fringes of society. The former is a highbrow one, while the latter is not taken seriously. Based on common interests, the two groups formed a wonderful resonance in the same time and space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prove themselves, the teenagers began to attack the championship. Ma Tianyuan and Wei Qidi won the first WCG &quot;StarCraft&quot; doubles championship in South Korea in 2001, and wore the five-star red flag to receive the award in Seoul. The deeds slightly shocked their hometown and those who saw the relevant news at the time - including the later WCG world champion Li Xiaofeng who was still in middle school in Ruzhou at the time. They learned that playing games actually There are also competitions, and you can also win glory for the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TV stations began to have e-sports programs, which introduced game culture, e-sports events and players, and also broadcast some events from time to time. From 2002 to 2003, programs such as &quot;Games&quot; on Travel TV, &quot;Gamers&quot; on Shanghai TV, and &quot;E-Sports World&quot; on CCTV Sports Channel were launched one after another, and quickly became the top-rated products on their respective channels. It has refreshed many people&#39;s understanding of e-sports - it is a mental activity based on electronic games but completely different from electronic games that emphasizes competition, honor, professionalism and teamwork. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such an unfriendly environment and with sparks everywhere, e-sports was listed as the 99th sports competition event by the State Sports General Administration on November 18, 2003. The issue of registering for residence has been resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mainstream games or their prototypes that built the later e-sports landscape had also appeared one after another before this point in time. &quot;StarCraft&quot; and &quot;Counter-Strike&quot; were already mainstream e-sports projects at that time; &quot;Warcraft 3&quot;, released in July 2002, would become the new mainstream in the near future; a player named Eul took advantage of &quot;Warcraft 3&quot; The included map editor created a battle map called Defense of the Antients&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(《卫士》)&lt;/span>;. Later, players directly Call it DOTA. This map, which seemed very rudimentary at the time, would soon incubate a new game type, as well as two games that hold up half of the global e-sports world, &quot;DOTA2&quot; and &quot;League of Legends&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The predecessor of &quot;Armed Assault&quot;, &quot;Operation Flashpoint&quot;, was released in 2001. This military simulation game was developed by a Czech studio and officially released in mainland China for a period of time. In order to pursue a high degree of simulation, The operation was extremely complicated, resulting in a mediocre market response. However, it won a group of military enthusiasts, one of whom was Brandon Greene &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Brandon Greene)&lt;/span>;. This game created a &quot;battle royale&quot; battle map, in which dozens of people would parachute into a map and fight each other until the last person wins - he later put this gameplay into the game he participated in the development of &quot; PlayerUnknown&#39;s Battlegrounds&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This start doesn&#39;t look perfect, but it&#39;s not bad either - if nothing else goes wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Broadcast ban&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 14:00 on September 25, 2023, CCTV Sports Channel broadcast the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports project &quot;Glory of Kings&quot; Asian Games version of the Chinese team and the Thai team. In the final, the Chinese team defeated the Thai team 2-0 to advance to the final. It has been nearly 20 years since the last e-sports event appeared on a satellite TV channel in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Successful registration did not bring any visible policy support or funding to China’s e-sports. Compared with the official management of other sports, it can be said that no one cared about e-sports—until 2004 On April 12, 2018, less than half a year after e-sports officially became a sports competition, the management department issued the &quot;Notice on Prohibiting the Broadcast of Computer Online Game Programs&quot;, stipulating that after May 1 of that year, including &quot;E-Sports World&quot;, All video game-related programs on all Kailu TV channels across the country have been suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of these programs set brilliant ratings records before they were suspended. Take &quot;Games and Things&quot; as an example. Since its launch on July 28, 2002, it has long occupied the top spot in the ratings of Travel TV. The number of users who regularly watch this program every day has reached about 4 million. The program team receives hundreds of enthusiastic letters from viewers across the country every week, and some people put five and ten yuan notes in envelopes to encourage the program team to continue the show. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yang, a senior e-sports practitioner and the author of &quot;The Behind-the-Scenes History of Chinese E-sports&quot;, believes that e-sports already had a very good mass base in China at that time, and the impact of the ban on broadcasting was quite serious. &quot;The entire The most critical media link in the monetization process of e-sports has been directly blocked.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ban policy actually leaves a certain amount of room. For example, it does not prohibit paid encrypted channels from playing video game content, which also made it possible later Paid channels such as &quot;Game Fengyun&quot; emerged. However, it is obvious that with this cut, the audience market that e-sports can drive will be greatly limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/acaHXCcFzTJRMvP58XdBUKHOaMww9OuBcMoMUXP7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;626&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/acaHXCcFzTJRMvP58XdBUKHOaMww9OuBcMoMUXP7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 21, 2003, Zhengzhou, Henan Communications’ first CS (&quot;Counter-Strike&quot;) competition, players compete&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E-sports had almost only one commercial route that was proven to work at the time - just like traditional sports, relying on competitions to sell television broadcast rights, attract sponsorship, and Sponsorship and advertising, it is this classic model of traditional sports commercialization that has made Korean e-sports, which has been developed for less than 10 years, become a blockbuster. Of course, no one can guarantee that China’s e-sports will succeed in applying this model, but at that time no one knew how to take other paths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yang believes that in addition to the monetization needs related to survival, whether e-sports programs can be broadcast on Kailu TV channels, especially national channels like CCTV, will depend on its symbolic meaning and the market effect it can drive. Very different. Even today, even though there are dazzling live broadcasts, videos and other communication platforms everywhere, as long as CCTV starts broadcasting e-sports programs, it will still have a different impact. &quot;Advertisers will always calculate its actual monetization ability and influence. For example, why does Netflix adopt a subscription system? Why can&#39;t it just sell ads? Because the scale and influence of the Internet are not so big that it is enough to sell ads on it. To the point where it can support the entire system.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Realization&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today, 20 years after successfully registering, Chinese e-sports has basically solved the problem of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this road is not easy to walk. Chinese e-sports practitioners have been forced to explore the road that no one has traveled since the beginning. Maybe God will open a window when he closes a door. In 2004, when Kailu Channel banned the broadcast of e-sports programs, P2P live streaming technology also began to appear in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;P2P live broadcast technology, which uses limited bandwidth to ensure smooth video playback to the greatest extent, has almost become the core channel for e-sports communication. Of course, this channel is far less influential than television, but it is worse than nothing. It can be said that an entire generation of e-sports audiences have almost all watched various events through P2P live video platforms and witnessed Sky Li Xiaofeng and wNv team becoming world champions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this group of viewers is also large, the traffic has not found an effective way to monetize during this period, and few people in the entire e-sports industry can see money. In 2005, Li Xiaofeng earned a salary of 1,800 yuan a month in the club. The bonus for becoming the world&#39;s top game champion was only 20,000 US dollars, and 30% of the tax was deducted - this was after eliminating thousands of masters. reward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then the 2008 financial crisis hit us again. Sponsors who had not taken their investment in the e-sports field seriously in the first place have withdrawn their investment. Events have been suspended, budgets have been reduced, and sponsorships have been withdrawn. Next, clubs have laid off employees and disbanded, and practitioners have begun to look for other options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What finally extended the life of e-sports was a new way at the time - bringing goods. After 2010, the basic conditions for bringing goods were already in place: the first generation of e-sports viewers gradually entered the society and had salary income; the habit of online shopping became popular; video websites rose and live broadcast platforms emerged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yang has been deeply involved in monetizing the attention of e-sports content. At first, they tried to sell gaming-related accessories such as keyboards, mice, and headphones, but these items were consumed very slowly, and the repurchase rate in the online store was not ideal—until they started selling a snack, meat floss. &quot;It&#39;s very cheap, costing less than a dime each, and the profit margin can reach 20%-30%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to bringing physical goods, you can also bring virtual goods. Many web games are also eyeing the traffic in the e-sports circle, and they are quite generous. For example, the web game &quot;Shenxian Dao&quot; even announced that 70% of its revenue will be allocated to promotion channels. From players like Li Xiaofeng to anchors like &quot;Starboy&quot; Huang Xudong who explain their origins, they have all become beneficiaries of this model. But it was not easy to take this step back then. When Li Xiaofeng announced a joint venture with &quot;The Way of the Immortal&quot;, it once caused a lot of criticism in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amidst the controversy, web game joint operation and meat waffles successfully saved the e-sports industry, which is difficult to monetize. After some video commentators tried their hand at connecting web games or selling snacks such as meat waffles, and became very successful, well-known current and retired players began to follow suit. In 2014, some enthusiastic netizens specially compiled the online store data of &quot;Ruofeng&quot;, the former captain of the League of Legends team WE, and believed that his monthly profit was conservatively estimated at around 800,000 yuan. The income from online stores directly marked the net worth of Internet celebrity players or commentators. Later, during the period when live broadcast platforms were burning the most money, news of various live broadcast platforms signing e-sports anchors for tens of millions of dollars began to spread. out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Manufacturer Era&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is obvious that e-sports, which had just figured out its monetization path around 2012, could become a huge industry with revenue of over 100 billion yuan in 10 years. Meat floss and live broadcast rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 4, 2010, Tencent launched the &quot;Tencent Game Competition Platform&quot;, namely TGA. Many leagues that have been hatched by this platform are more famous than it, such as the &quot;Cross Fire&quot; event CFPL, the &quot;League of Legends&quot; event LPL, and the &quot;King of Honor&quot; event KPL. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tencent’s start in e-sports also means the emergence of a new model in which game manufacturers conduct events in person. This new model also caters to the marketing of a new generation of games. In the era when games such as &quot;Counter-Strike&quot; and &quot;Warcraft 3&quot; were popular, game manufacturers could basically leave the game behind after selling copies of the games. It was difficult for e-sports events to bring any follow-up benefits worth mentioning to the manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it is different for online games such as &quot;League of Legends&quot; and &quot;Honor of Kings&quot;. They are originally free to download and play, and they make money by in-game purchases of additional products, such as character skins. . As a result, game sales have become an infinitely stretched process in which demand is constantly being created. Since then, e-sports has had the function of bringing goods to game manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhuang Minghao, a senior e-sports practitioner, believes that it is almost inevitable for a game manufacturer to personally dominate its own game e-sports competition. “Even if a strong enough third party appears, it will slowly change. We have talked with the first party.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the focus of manufacturers’ own events is inevitably ambiguous. Do you want to do event business or game marketing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this issue was not important 10 years ago. No matter what the purpose of the manufacturers, they may still be the most motivated to make the event well-esports has begun to usher in an era of manufacturer dominance. In the early days, Third parties emerged one after another, and scuffles continued. The era of a grassroots team in which any manufacturer spent some money to organize a tournament and then invited several clubs to compete was over. It was also during this period that leagues such as the LPL began to organize club alliances, cancel promotion and relegation and establish a seat bidding system, bring offline games to the Bird&#39;s Nest Stadium, and implement a regional home and away system... A decent e-sports league is What does it look like? There is a template for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;LPL has become the largest e-sports league in the world in terms of scale and influence. The industrial scale and social influence of Chinese e-sports have also achieved the greatest growth during this period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Pan Jie, CEO of LGD Club, the quality of e-sports content is one of the core values ​​​​of whether the vitality of the game can be sustained. Under such underlying logic, manufacturers will do their best to ensure the fairness of events, play a good role as managers of large-scale e-sports leagues, and attract more sponsors and fans for this e-sports league to ensure the integrity of the entire e-sports content. healthy growth. &quot;Manufacturer-led events are more durable, more standardized, and more professional than previous third parties, and can better guarantee the rights and interests of all participating parties. Players, clubs, fans, media, sponsors, and game brands can all get what they want. , this is a very good thing for the e-sports industry ecology itself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cake&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is indeed easy to enjoy the shade under the big tree, but if there are too many people enjoying the shade, there will always be people who are Sunburned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2022 China E-Sports Industry Report&quot; released by the E-Sports Working Committee of the China Music and Digital Association shows that the revenue of China&#39;s e-Sports industry in 2022 will be 144.503 billion yuan. But of the 144.503 billion yuan in revenue, 81.52% was from the game itself. Of the remaining 18%, 15.28% is revenue from live broadcasts of e-sports content; the rest is basically equally divided between clubs and events. Excluding game revenue, the actual revenue of the e-sports industry is approximately 25.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that game manufacturers have made most of the money, and the manufacturers may not be willing to divide it up. Then the problem began to become acute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Pan Jie’s view, the income structure in which manufacturers earn the lion’s share is very reasonable. As for whether manufacturers are sincerely engaged in events or just want to rely on events for marketing, the two are not necessarily contradictory. &quot;Only a more standardized, healthier and more benign e-sports ecology can help game manufacturers and the upstream and downstream e-sports industries jointly make the pie bigger, thereby continuously producing higher-quality content and hot topics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The club’s earning power has indeed increased with the influence of e-sports events. Zhuang Minghao remembers that from 2013 to 2014, an Internet company wanted to buy a chest title for an LPL club uniform for only 200,000 yuan a year. &quot;Today, if there is no 20 million yuan, no one will talk to you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, There are still not many clubs that really make money from e-sports, and the traditional sports business that revolves around events and club operations has obviously not really taken off yet. In 2021, Pan Yibin, general manager of EDG E-sports Club, revealed in an interview that there are currently no more than 5 domestic e-sports clubs that are self-financing. According to the &quot;China E-Sports Industry Report from January to June 2023&quot; released by the E-Sports Working Committee of the China Music and Digital Association, as of June 2023, there are 191 e-Sports clubs in China that can be queried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Xudong believes that the commercial potential of domestic e-sports has not been fully tapped. &quot;I have always wanted to ask, can basketball, football or traditional sports such as table tennis have as much influence in the country as e-sports today?&quot; Can we compete? I think basketball and football can compete. Which of the remaining projects can compete with e-sports? But it is strange. Although some traditional sports projects cannot compete in terms of traffic, their income is much higher than that of e-sports. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the environment has improved significantly compared to 20 years ago, social recognition is still an issue. &quot;I still feel that you are not doing your job properly. Young people may recognize it, but for people who have some social resources, &quot;In fact, his recognition of this thing is still not as high as traditional sports.&quot; Huang Xudong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/vbHCEfsdmr4LfNjeBubF97TZpEODJIiJlDSxMbI3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/vbHCEfsdmr4LfNjeBubF97TZpEODJIiJlDSxMbI3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Interstellar Old Boys&quot; Sun Yifeng and Huang Xudong&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;Lifespan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Even if all aspects of the manufacturer-led competition system make money and everyone is happy, there is still another problem: there is more than one game manufacturer, and the game life is bound to be limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which game will be popular and will become the next dominant e-sports project? Which game should each link in the industry - manufacturers, event operators, clubs, players, anchors or commentators - choose? There may be many ways to talk about betting, but in the final analysis, &quot;Looking at fate is really just looking at fate.&quot; Huang Xudong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Blizzard, which was so popular with &quot;StarCraft&quot; and &quot;Warcraft 3&quot;, would never have thought that a map editor included with &quot;Warcraft 3&quot; would actually hatch DOTA, which is far more popular than the original game. . And Guinsoo&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Guinsoo）&lt;/span>; and Ice Frog&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Icefrog)&lt;/span>;When I was still generating electricity for love for free and constantly updating the DOTA map in &quot;Warcraft 3&quot;, I would not have thought that one of them would later go to Riot Games to work on &quot;League of Legends&quot;, and the other would go to Vale Fu makes &quot;DOTA2&quot;. Blizzard would never have imagined that a great idea hatched by its own game would give birth to two great games, but in the end it had nothing to do with itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next dominant e-sports game project is something that most current e-sports practitioners dare not relax for a moment, even if it has not yet appeared. The two most popular e-sports games in China today, &quot;League of Legends&quot; was released in 2009 and &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; was released in 2015. They have been on the center stage longer than almost all previous popular e-sports games. , &quot;DOTA2&quot; and &quot;CSGO&quot;, which are in the second echelon, are bundled together, and their income cannot keep up with either of the first two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is of course inseparable from the careful layout of game manufacturers in event operations, the manufacturer-led event model, and the improvement of event operation levels, which has effectively extended the lifespan of many popular e-sports projects in this era, and may It also raises the threshold for new game projects to change dynasties. Pan Jie commented on this, “In fact, it is because the recent e-sports game projects are not that good and are not enough to have an impact on the current popular projects. This forces new e-sports projects to come up with new ideas. Come.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/O7IperkYCoU0x1xf9UxIr9uEz8XHtcnqtQYWqek3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795 &quot; height=&quot;1198&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/O7IperkYCoU0x1xf9UxIr9uEz8XHtcnqtQYWqek3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in the final of the Asian Games version of the e-sports &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; at the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team 2-0 and won the championship&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The revenue of these games that are the mainstay of China&#39;s e-sports today is almost all declining. Ordinary players feel that the qualifying time of &quot;League of Legends&quot; has become longer, and the number of robots in the &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; rankings has obviously increased, which is a sign that is not very optimistic. In terms of macro data, e-sports game revenue in 2022 will be 117.802 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 15.96%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;PlayerUnknown&#39;s Battlegrounds&quot;, which was born in 2017 and had high hopes in the e-sports circle, has been entangled with the domestic version number issue. The mobile version of &quot;Peace Elite&quot; was not released until 2019, and it was not released. It did not open up a new situation as expected, and the revenue of &quot;Peace Elite&quot; will show a downward trend starting from 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decline of the old king is only a matter of time. Before the new succession game comes, &quot;I can only hope that the decline will be extended.&quot; Zhuang Minghao lamented. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Saudi Arabia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sometimes the decline is gentle and silent, and sometimes the decline is like lightning and thunder. For example, in &quot;StarCraft 2&quot;, with the closure of Chinese servers on January 24, 2023, the manufacturer terminated all operations in the mainland Chinese market, and all Chinese players who logged in through normal channels disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The irony is that almost half a month later, on February 13, 2023, Chinese player Li Peinan, who was not optimistic at all before the game ;&quot;>;(Time)&lt;/span>;In the &quot;StarCraft 2&quot; IEM Katowice finals, he defeated South Korean player Maru with a score of 4-1 and won the world championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is uncertainty in expecting the manufacturer to do well in the event. As long as the manufacturer is reliable, what if the manufacturer goes crazy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Pan Jie hopes that professional manufacturer events and high-standard third-party events can be effectively combined in the future. “Next year’s Kazan Future Games in Russia and the E-sports World Cup in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia will also mark the launch of high-standard third-party events. Third-party events will return to center stage.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the largest third-party events ever has emerged. On October 23, 2023, surrounded by FIFA President Infantino and star Cristiano Ronaldo, who is playing in the Saudi league, Saudi Crown Prince and Prime Minister Mohammed bin Salman announced that Saudi Arabia will launch the annual Esports World Cup &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Esports World Cup）&lt;/span>;, the first event will be held in Riyadh in the summer of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young prime minister, who is said to be a veteran player of the FPS game &quot;Call of Duty&quot;, made a clear goal: &quot;The E-Sports World Cup is a natural next step in Saudi Arabia&#39;s journey to become the world&#39;s premier gaming and e-Sports center. One step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the annual e-sports event Gamers8 hosted by Saudi Arabia will kick off. By 2023, it has become the e-sports event with the largest prize pool in the world, and is nicknamed the &quot;Oil Cup&quot; by Chinese netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this third party is unprecedentedly powerful, the pattern of game manufacturers dominating the competition may not change overnight, and a new round of gaming is bound to happen. Huang Xudong discovered that &quot;League of Legends&quot; has never appeared in the two Gamers8 sessions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although game manufacturers&#39; competitions have proven to be a relatively successful path, Huang Xudong believes that not every manufacturer has the effort. When faced with the choice of whether to conduct competitions, manufacturers&#39; mentality is also very complicated. . &quot;Some manufacturers want to do it themselves, and some manufacturers just want to make good games. As for e-sports events, they can cooperate. If there is a third party like Saudi Arabia, it does a good job and invests a lot, and the manufacturers don&#39;t have to spend any money. Money, you can even make money in it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Xudong thinks that perhaps the biggest advantage of the Saudis is that e-sports is part of the national influence strategy. They do not expect to make money from the event itself, but want to He wants the hundreds of thousands of tourists who flock to the Saudi E-sports World Cup every year, as well as the establishment of game companies in the country, and other bigger gears. &quot;They have money, they can afford it, and they don&#39;t want short-term gains. They want the long term, and they want 2030.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(referring to Saudi Vision 2030)&lt;/span>;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given time, no one is sure whether Saudi Arabia will always be just a third party. In 2022, the Saudi Mohammed bin Salman Foundation MiSK also acquired 96.18% of the shares of the Japanese game company SNK through its game development company EGDC, thereby mastering the copyright of the well-known fighting game &quot;The King of Fighters&quot;. In the past two years, capital from Saudi Arabia has continued to invest in game manufacturers and e-sports event operating companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Eggs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, at least Chinese e-sports players no longer need to eat fried buns or eggs in order to save money to practice like the players of Li Xiaofeng and Su Hao. The bread is getting better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the 29-year-old retired &quot;League of Legends&quot; player Alan, when he debuted, he did not need to go back and forth like in the past to find a club that opened in an Internet cafe and could collapse at any time. . Talented players like him will naturally be contacted by the club after gaining game points or ranking in the rankings. When joining the team, they will receive a basic salary of 4,000 yuan plus room and board, and they can basically start the life of a professional player without any distractions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Alan found that his age was not an advantage, and his talent and strength were not high enough for him to move to a higher level, he started as an analyst and assistant coach at the club&#39;s suggestion and began to move from player to coach. transformation. Now he works as a coach at a youth academy, cultivating fresh blood for higher-level competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The youth training camp has also unintentionally produced another function: many children who think they have e-sports talents or who simply cannot distinguish between the concepts of gaming and e-sports enter the youth training camp and train like professional players. After training, living, and seeing the real world, I realized that I was not the material, so I honestly went home and went to school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Today at least there are many practitioners in the (e-sports) industry. You don&#39;t have to worry about not having food tomorrow, right? If you are a player today, you can also transfer to some related tracks tomorrow, upstream and downstream The number of manufacturers is also increasing...Although everyone may have a hard life, at least there is more division of labor, right?&quot; Zhuang Minghao feels that it is not easy for an industry that has only developed for 20 years to achieve such a situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly than not having to eat fried buns and egg pancakes, there are fewer drastic changes and shocks in the industry, and the new generation of e-sports practitioners have more choices and retreats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Older generation practitioners like &quot;Interstellar Old Boy&quot; Huang Xudong still dare not slack off. Facts have proved that he is right. He has been playing &quot;StarCraft 2&quot; as a streamer for 10 years. If he said it would stop the service, he would stop it. &quot;From the first day, I felt that the project we were working on was not a particularly top-notch project, so We have a strong sense of crisis.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in recent years, in addition to anchors, there have been other activities such as MCN anchor incubation, Internet celebrity management, game advertising, game production, and even live broadcasts that have nothing to do with e-sports, and even medical Beauty, &quot;Starboy&quot; are all involved. &quot;We have tried many things, and some have failed, but we always believe that eggs should not be put in the same basket.&quot; Huang Xudong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Reference materials: &quot;&quot;Loser&quot; Li Xiaofeng&quot; &quot;When Li Xiaofeng Became SKY&quot; &quot;The Behind-the-Scenes History of China&#39;s E-Sports&quot; &quot;The Ban on Online Game Shows Given by the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television &quot;Perfect&quot; Reasons&quot; &quot;&amp;lt;Game Stuff&amp;gt; Past Events&quot; &quot;Twenty Years of Chinese E-Sports: From Being Misunderstood to &quot;National Business Card&quot;&quot; &quot;E-Sports Industry Needs the Next &quot;Meat Floss Pancake&quot;&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[连酵母都要种了？面包怎么变成你吃不起的样子？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, &quot;a monthly salary of 10,000 yuan cannot afford bread&quot; Hot searches have stung the hearts of many working people, and the lingering heat has not dissipated. Recently, a RT-Mart &quot;Potato Bread&quot; originally priced at 18.9 yuan for 4 pieces was once raised to 100 yuan on behalf of the purchaser. People can&#39;t help but complain, how can the bread be more expensive? Is it getting more expensive? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the public&#39;s pursuit of a healthy eating lifestyle, the Chinese people&#39;s dietary structure is becoming diversified, whether it is old-fashioned, new Chinese, or European. And Japanese style, bread, as a major branch of baked goods, is undergoing a transformation from snack to staple food or meal replacement food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, the competition in China&#39;s baking market, which is becoming saturated, is fierce, the market size is still expanding, and the requirements for updating the baking track will increase in the future. For example, the consumption of zero-sugar products has become popular, and the demand for sugar substitutes has caused huge changes in the baking industry chain. Upgrading technology, updating equipment, innovative products and sales channels will become new challenges facing the baking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, consumers have formed regular purchasing habits for baked goods. Coastal areas and first- and second-tier cities have strong spending power. Among them, female users and middle-aged Young people have become the main force driving the consumption of baked goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Baked food not only meets the daily needs of consumers, but also occupies the public&#39;s attention as a cultural symbol, identity mark and social currency, such as &quot;citywalk+coffee+Beijing&quot; The combination of &quot;fruit&quot; has become one of the trendy lifestyles of contemporary young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind the iteration of consumer trends is a kind of self-reinforcement of collective action - which has led to rounds of reshuffles in the baking industry. The predecessors have left the scene and the successors have taken the stage. The bakery market is showing a trend of ice and fire: &quot;store closing wave&quot; and &quot;financing boom&quot; coexist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The industry is undergoing a major reshuffle. What remains unchanged is that the &quot;Baking Assassin&quot; is still standing, and the Sword of Damocles hanging over consumers&#39; heads has not disappeared. . According to industry insiders, for certain high-priced baking keywords, 5 yuan will be added every time one appears. So, do young people buy into this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As mentioned by Japanese scholar Miura Exhibition in &quot;The 4th Era of Consumption: Sharing Economy, a Major Trend that Makes People Happier&quot;, the &quot;4th Era of Consumption&quot; The trend is towards simplicity, reality, low prices and low consumption desire, and consumption values ​​tend to be social, local and shared. This consumption characteristic seems to be emerging among China&#39;s young consumer groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Faced with &quot;baking assassins&quot;, they refused to be &quot;cut off leeks&quot; and chose simpler pre-made baking products. They refused to be charged by scalpers and set their sights on Community bakeries, hold group meetings online to grab bread; refuse long queues and enjoy the fun and deliciousness of baking at home. Some advanced baking players have even started to grow yeast to create the spiritual interest of baking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Know&quot; talks to you about how young people will cope when bread becomes more and more unaffordable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/12945c742d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/12945c742d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258909&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9aa6f41590.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9aa6f41590.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258910&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/85f66a37db.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/85f66a37db.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258911&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/2fcb670f45.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/2fcb670f45.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258912&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/0afba86876.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/0afba86876.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/04558a91ad.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/04558a91ad.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/9f1d9e5be5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9f1d9e5be5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/d754baba8e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/d754baba8e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258917 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你好，两眼炯炯有神的外星生物丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VHmTK17O6xJf358f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VH mTK17O6xJf358f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, the main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention-Chengdu People walk in the &quot;Space-Time Tunnel&quot; at the Science Fiction Museum &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260297&quot; title=&quot;Humans please answer: Can science fiction keep up with the magic of reality&quot;>;Humans please answer : Can science fiction keep up with the magic of reality?&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw UFOs when I was a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was a few days before the 2008 Beijing Olympics. There is always a ten-year gap between the time in the county and the big cities. UFO exploration and the mystery of aliens that are popular in big cities did not reach me until the year I graduated from junior high school. That summer I was particularly fascinated by UFOs and aliens. I read a lot of books about aliens in Wenhui Bookstore, and watched programs about searching for ghosts and aliens on local TV. When I was walking, I often stopped suddenly and looked up into the sky. I feel like there must be something in the sky looking at me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One evening, I finally saw a UFO when I looked up. They were two fireballs stuck together, orange in color, flying at a constant speed in high altitude, and the tail of the aircraft seemed to be spitting fire. &quot;You finally came to pick me up.&quot; I happily followed the aircraft in the sky, completely forgetting that I was in a strange city until it completely disappeared. Later, when my parents found me who was lost, I didn&#39;t say anything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, I attended the 81st World Science Fiction Conference in Pidu, Chengdu. The UFO often came to my mind. I don’t think any science fiction fan present would laugh at me. The sci-fi conference was really lively for a few days. The most popular elements in the Chengdu Science Museum were pandas and Liu Cixin. I read less science fiction, but during the interview I became more and more curious: why is it science fiction, why is it in Chengdu, and why is the rise of science fiction happening? In China in the past ten years? At the same time, I felt like I was awakened to the vague emotions about the universe that I had as a child. Yes, we have been guessing about the truth of the world and the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People’s expectations for science fiction writers also come from the history created by science fiction writers in the past, and their imaginations about the future are constantly being fulfilled in their works. After the on-site interview at the science fiction conference, I went to a friend&#39;s new bookstore before leaving Chengdu. New bookstores have emerged in Chengdu in the past few years. This bookstore that is still in trial operation is called &quot;Baidu&quot;. 3 of the 6 founders Bit is for web3. The first row of large book walls in the store is quite special and very smooth. It covers technology first, then machines, then the Internet and artificial intelligence. At the end of the whole row of books is a series of science fiction literary works - the imagination about the future network society. There are only Two books by Chinese science fiction writers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I heard that my business trip was to cover a science fiction conference, the girl who worked on web3 held me in question for half an hour until I had to rush to the airport to catch my flight. This year, she and her partners attended a conference in the Bay Area. Cutting-edge network technicians from all over the world expressed their fear that AI will change the destiny of mankind. She kept asking me almost eagerly: Artificial intelligence is already unstoppable. Why haven’t China’s top science fiction writers pointed out the profound changes that are about to occur in human society? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But why would such a requirement be placed on a literary genre? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No other literary genre should be given such expectations. It seems that these network practitioners know what technology will create next, but they do not know where technology will ultimately lead mankind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More and more literary forums discuss writing under new technologies and the meaning of human existence. The panic caused by ChatGPT is something I didn’t expect. “The previous industrial revolutions created all material things. , what is being created this time is the spirit.&quot; Han Song, a science fiction writer who works for Xinhua News Agency, said in an interview, &quot;Earlier when big machines appeared, people felt that they would lose their jobs, and nuclear weapons appeared, and they felt that human beings would be exterminated, but this time It&#39;s different.&quot; This is more like a species crisis for humans, which may be replaced by more intelligent creatures. What if this is part of evolution? It really cannot be considered pessimistic to point out the laws of evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is all really curious. At the science fiction conference in Pidu, I would still suddenly stop and look up while walking, feeling overjoyed. For extraterrestrial creatures, it would be a shock to see these guys holding a science fiction convention on Earth, looking at their big round heads one by one. &quot;These alien creatures with bright eyes are going to... How to write about us.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们需要怎样的图书馆？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the one hand, there is news about the decline of paper books. Many people even made it clear that they will no longer buy paper books. Don’t read paper books, only e-books. On the one hand, many people still suffer from the lack of convenient ways to borrow books, and there is an urgent need for community libraries and other borrowing places that are close to life. What should the future library look like?</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清华博士当占星师：算命作为职业，合法吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261198]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to media reports, in the face of the increasingly fierce competition for graduate employment, Mary, a PhD graduate in history from Tsinghua University Ann chose an unexpected career path and became a full-time astrologer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Ph.D. graduate from a prestigious university and a senior intellectual, with these unattainable titles, gave up jobs that were relevant in the traditional sense. Many people felt that she was not worth it and criticized her for wasting her quota at Tsinghua University. Marianne also admitted that she did not expect to transform from a historian to a full-time astrologer today. However, she believes that career choices should be based on one&#39;s own interests and abilities, and should not be restricted by traditional career boundaries. You should be brave enough to try and find your own professional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She spent 5 years studying astrology and worked as an astrologer for 2 years. Her customer base is mainly young people, who found her through friends&#39; introductions or Internet searches. In the past two years, she has done very well, receiving nearly a thousand customers, and her monthly income has just exceeded 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To judge her choice, the first question to be faced is: Is it illegal to use fortune telling, astrology, tarot cards, or other methods that claim to be predictive to predict people&#39;s fortune and destiny? This question is simple, but the answer is more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what form of fortune telling, whether it is illegal or not depends on whether the specific behavior is illegal. Courts generally give a certain degree of respect to traditional Chinese Feng Shui, Zhouyi and other cultures and customs, and do not make scientific or superstitious judgments. Instead, they regard them as legitimate consulting services. As long as the fees are within the normal range, they are regarded as normal labor expenses. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foundation of Chinese fortune-telling is the &quot;Book of Changes&quot;. Telling people&#39;s fortunes based on the Four Pillars, Five Elements and Eight Diagrams seems to be regarded as the research, discussion and practice of traditional culture. According to a kind of saying, some money must be paid for these leaks, otherwise it will be more detrimental to the fortune teller. So, if you receive dozens, hundreds, or even hundreds of yuan, the person receiving the money will be happy, but the person giving the money will not matter. , both parties are consensual, and there is no fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Five Elements and Eight Trigrams are allowed, birth dates are allowed, and divination and burning turtle shells are allowed, then even though horoscopes, crystal balls, and Tarot cards are passed down from foreign countries, they are still not illegal and can be regarded as An advisory or entertainment. Take this astrologer who graduated from Tsinghua University as an example. His current monthly income is just over 30,000 yuan. It may not have been that much before. His two-year income is estimated to be only 200,000-400,000 yuan. With a thousand customers, the average income per person is two to three hundred yuan. . This amount is obviously not illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if a fortune teller pretends to be a god or a mage, commits fraud, fraud, extortion and other illegal acts, or defrauds money by exaggerating or falsely advertising, or charges a large amount, it is considered a crime. Illegal conduct. The court will determine that this kind of &quot;fortune-telling&quot; is unjust enrichment and is not a legitimate reason for obtaining benefits under the law. At the least, it will apply the civil law&#39;s unjust enrichment to return the property and return the unjust enrichment to the injured person. At worst, it will involve a criminal offense. . For example, using tarot cards, crystal balls, astrology and other methods to introduce physical, mental and spiritual fraud courses is an out-and-out crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the legal issues are complex, they are well-founded. A more difficult question to answer is, how should we view the rise of this type of profession? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern society is developing at a fast pace, interpersonal relationships are tense, and it is full of opportunities and challenges, but it is also accompanied by great uncertainties, such as the rise and fall of stocks, profit and loss of business, rising or unfinished real estate prices, and so on. There is the eternal topic of good health. Faced with these complex uncertainties, there is always an indescribable uneasiness permeating the hearts of contemporary people. Many people believe that their own destiny is not completely within their control. There is a supernatural power that affects the direction of their destiny. People do not accept this as their fate with peace of mind. They desire to control their lives and seek certainty. There are also some people who have achieved great success. Looking back at the past, their fate is full of coincidences. They feel that many things are beyond human control. While thanking God for his blessing, they will naturally worship this power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, religion and fortune telling became the way for them to seek spiritual comfort. Various fortune-telling and predictions are how they seek comfort and certainty from this unknowable power. For modern people, fortune telling is relatively familiar, but tarot cards and crystal balls are more advanced because they are rarely seen and come from foreign countries with exotic customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are degrees of distinction in seeking various fortune tellings. Some people don&#39;t necessarily believe in the results of fortune telling, but just treat it as entertainment and seek psychological comfort. For example, if you want to share something tomorrow, or conduct a live broadcast, or take an exam, you can find someone online and spend dozens or hundreds of dollars to tell your fortune, or look at a crystal ball or tarot cards, and get a As a result, Quan is happy. If the result is good, take it as a positive psychological hint to yourself, and don&#39;t take it personally if it&#39;s not good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of this astrologer who graduated from Tsinghua University, astrology is not just prediction, but a tool to help people better understand themselves and life. She said: &quot;Astrology has allowed me to see the bigger world and give me a deeper understanding of human nature. Every time I see a client feel relieved or inspired by my help, I feel very satisfied.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There is some truth in what she said. Astrologers are actually providing psychological massage to a certain extent. An excellent astrologer understands the ancient astronomy and mythology related to astrology itself, but also involves philosophy and psychology. Only in this way can he provide comprehensive psychological support to his clients. This is obviously the advantage of a historian as an astrologer. This is similar to traditional Chinese fortune telling. Three scholars asked the fortune teller about the results of the imperial examination. The fortune teller raised a finger: one of them passed the exam; only one failed; and none of the three passed. One finger corresponds to three results. This is a kind of deception, but it is also a psychological suggestion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, can these methods really bring long-term comfort to people? In fact, fortune telling is more of an escape. True courage is to maintain courage and determination after going through hardships, to find solutions and face uncertainty based on reason and courage. Turning to psychological counseling, psychotherapy and other methods to adjust your mentality and face reality is more reliable than fortune telling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周依然：偶然的，不确定的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261270]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/cykfx0ZM4x1a0rqZ3LwAEN3ubgEWFqEANGjPwSm8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cykfx0ZM4x1a0rqZ3LwAEN3ubgEWFq EANGjPwSm8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Yiran was discovered on the day after attending the dance teacher’s birthday party. When she was less than 20 years old, she was walking home wearing an exquisite short skirt. A stranger who claimed to be the casting director of the film crew appeared in front of her, handed her a business card, and took a photo of her on the spot. &quot;Front, side, 45 degrees, back. That was my first group photo, and I was wearing steel teeth.&quot; Zhou Yiran laughed, &quot;It&#39;s very dramatic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said in confusion. After taking the business card home, the whole family studied it, and the next day they took her to Chongqing for an interview and entered the crew&#39;s training camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of chance is like having the opportunity to learn dance when I was 11 years old. During recess, a teacher from outside the school came and walked around, named a few students, and said he would wait nearby after the exercise. &quot;We are still doing radio gymnastics down there.&quot; Zhou Yiran danced and gestured, &quot;I was selected. Then they said seriously, we are from the dance academy, you have great advantages and innate conditions, we all think it is very good , I hope you will come.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She took the dance school&#39;s flyer home to her parents, and her mother went to discuss it with her aunt. After a round of discussion, she decided to let Zhou Yiran learn to dance. After that, she really studied classical dance for nine years without stopping. Daily practice is boring and unbearable. “I can only grit my teeth and persevere, and then over time, I will really get used to it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Zhou Yiran didn’t worry about decisions and results, even though he was training with the same batch She was never able to star in that drama after she was born. She just felt it was very fresh, a life different from practicing hard in the dance studio all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I am a late bloomer when it comes to such a big life decision. I have never considered the proposition of life. Even if I don’t find a job after graduation, I am not in a hurry. I will follow myself more. On the day of the graduation performance, Zhou Yiran finished dancing &quot;Red Lips&quot; and ushered in the highlight of his life. She knew this wasn&#39;t the end for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She knew that she didn’t want to be a dance teacher or dancer, but she just didn’t know what to do. There was a scene in the TV series &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot; in which she later starred: Zhao Sanyue was idle at home for a year. After an argument with her mother, she left home and moved to rent a bed in a B&amp;B. She was lying on the bed, filled with resentment and doubts. &quot;Why can&#39;t we let people who like to work work, let people who like to lie down lie down, roll as hard as they want, and practice as much as they want to become Buddhas.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only Zhao Sanyue&#39;s confusion, but also Zhou Yiran&#39;s of confusion. &quot;Before graduation, I had an idea, play, really.&quot; But as she grew up, she vaguely felt another thing, &quot;Don&#39;t lie down, the meaning of life still has to move.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 , the online drama &quot;The Sky of the Wind Dog&quot; was broadcast, in which Zhou Yiran played a girl named &quot;Dali Jiao&quot;. &quot;Dali Jiao&quot; is the only girl in Daxing Village. She is born with supernatural powers, speaks loudly, is straightforward and has a quick mind. This character is so deeply rooted in the hearts of the people that Zhou Yiran is often asked by people he has just met, why are you different from what you imagined? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Yiran&#39;s natural aura is just like what director Li Mo, who she worked with, later said about her: &quot;I have always felt that she is a very spiritual actor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Not long after finishing the filming of &quot;The Sky of the Wind Dog&quot;, Zhou still received the script of the movie &quot;Crossing the Angry Sea&quot; directed by Cao Baoping, playing the role of Jin Lina, an international student who was killed in a foreign country, the ultimate crazy girl. She started taking language classes and going to bookstores every day, &quot;just like going to KFC or McDonald&#39;s to do homework when she was a kid.&quot; She went to sushi restaurants, drugstores, or to the homes of international students to chat, so that she could feel the characters, understand, empathize, and express them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2019, the filming of the movie started. Zhou still sometimes had to put on special effects makeup for five or six hours, lie in the morgue of the funeral home, or be forced to the edge of the balcony with his body hanging in the air. &quot;I felt like I was being squeezed dry at the scene.&quot; But before the filming is completed, Zhou Yiran&#39;s only worry is still whether he will be replaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, it seems that all the big turning points were decided by my mother for me, but in fact, everything I did later was my own idea.&quot; Zhou Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since entering the industry, Zhou Yiran has participated in many movies and TV series. In March 2023, she won the 36th Huading Award for Best Actress in a Chinese Drama Series for &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot;. &quot;When the award was announced, I couldn&#39;t believe those words were true.&quot; So far. , Zhou still felt, &quot;This is definitely a milestone for me. I like the sense of solidity of taking one step at a time. This is also a huge force that pushes me to continue the next step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Growing up is farewell&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhao Sanyue in &quot;Sanyue has a new job&quot; You resisted working, which overlaps with what you said about your mentality when you graduated, but you also felt that you couldn&#39;t lie down. Why did you feel that you couldn&#39;t lie down? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The word &quot;lying down&quot; was not popular at that time. At that time, people would think that lying down was an inactive behavior. You still have to turn around, only then will there be new opportunities or surprises, only then will there be hope and some new discoveries. And at that age, you basically can’t lie down, you are very energetic, and you have to move. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was the environment like when you were growing up? Woolen cloth? What imprint has dance practice left on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was a child, my environment was relatively primitive. I would often get in touch with nature. I would always finish my homework quickly. Then I went downstairs to play with friends of the same age, growing up relatively freely. Dance is very challenging, and you can find the meaning of perseverance in dance. For example, pulling a ligament is a step-by-step process that cannot be accomplished overnight. If you don&#39;t do it for a long time, it will become stiff. Some of the characters I honed in dance still help me a lot in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are your fun stories growing up? Can you share? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The things I played when I was a child are different from the things kids play now. For example, pretending to be a household, now all the pots and pans are It was mini and very delicate, but at that time I went outside with my friends to build a stove with stones, using wild grasses and the like as vegetables, and leaves as tableware. It was very original. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I grow up, I will travel after graduation. Going to each city to experience the local cultural characteristics is also a way for me to relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think about the outside world describing you as having &quot;aura&quot;? thing? Where do you think &quot;reiki&quot; comes from? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If I want to talk about my impression of Reiki, it is that everything has animism. When integrated into nature and into this world, different lives will actually have their own behaviors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether for personal growth or as an actor, self Cognition plays a very important role in this. I’m curious, has your self-perception changed or been updated in the past two years? Why did such a change occur? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am a slow-tempered person and a late bloomer. All major decisions in life are made with my family, even teething. They were two months later than other children of the same age. Until they graduated from college, they were quite heartless and immersed in their own world. I just focus on what I want to do, and rarely step out to look at my life or even my plans from God’s perspective. But in the past two years, my understanding will be more objective, and I will not be as immersed in my own world as before, although in fact it is happier! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I am very satisfied now, because growing up is saying goodbye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any plans or expectations for the future? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I hope to live a good life while taking care of my work. You can continue to challenge different types of roles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“很多男生一个引体向上都做不了”——部分高校大学生身体素质下降现象调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261292]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I was dangling on the horizontal bar and couldn’t pull up even a pull-up. I ran 800 meters in more than 5 minutes. Mi went upstairs and her legs were trembling...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from &quot;Xinhua Viewpoint&quot; recently visited some colleges and universities and found that the physical fitness of some students is worrying. Many boys find it difficult to do pull-ups and cannot do long jumps while standing. Many students lack explosive power in sprinting and have a &quot;fear of long-distance running.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Basic Standards for Physical Education in Colleges and Universities&quot; issued by the Ministry of Education in 2014 requires strengthening the management of physical education in schools, innovating education and teaching methods, guiding students to exercise scientifically, conducting physical health tests on all students every year, and guiding students Carry out targeted physical exercise. How to implement relevant requirements and continuously improve the physical fitness of college students? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;No energy&quot; &quot;Can&#39;t run&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;40% of the boys in our school failed to score in the pull-up event in the physical test, and many boys could not do any of them. The excellent rate of physical tests is declining every year.&quot; The person in charge of the physical education department of a university in Shandong said that more than ten years ago, most of the boys You can get 10 or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter once went to Yunnan University to conduct on-site research on the physical examination class. Most of the boys&#39; 1000-meter scores were below the passing mark; a girl in a certain class ran 800 meters, and in the last 50 meters, it was obviously very difficult. After crossing the finish line, she bent her back with a painful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259555&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In November 2021, girls from Yunnan University ran 800 meters. (Imposed photo) Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin, director of the Key Laboratory of Sports and Physical Health of the Ministry of Education at Beijing Sport University, once participated in the revision of the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and has long been concerned about the physical fitness of college students. Health status. &quot;Even though the passing standards for some projects have been lowered based on the students&#39; physical condition, the physical test results are still unsatisfactory,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin said that taking the university men&#39;s 1,000 meters as an example, the 60-minute pass in 1989 was 3 minutes and 55 seconds, and in 2014 it was 4 minutes and 32 seconds, a decrease of 37 seconds. This is equivalent to the fact that students who just passed the long-distance race in 1989 have reached the finish line, while students in 2014 are still running hundreds of meters away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the results of the Eighth National Student Physical Fitness and Health Survey released by the Ministry of Education showed that college students’ physical fitness is seriously declining, and problems such as obesity and lack of endurance are prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A physical education teacher in Beijing said that in order to avoid physical examinations, some students will buy &quot;medical records&quot; and pretend to be sick to take leave, claiming that they have hydrops in the knee joints and meniscus damage. &quot;We cannot distinguish the authenticity of the &#39;medical records&#39; one by one, and we are also afraid that students will have accidents, so the number of students exempted from the test remains high.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some students even find &quot;shooters&quot; to pass the physical test. The reporter saw on social media that some college students posted &quot;asking for a substitute test&quot; or &quot;take the test&quot;, mainly focusing on middle and long-distance running and other events. Some college students said that on the one hand, they are looking for a &quot;substitute&quot; because of their poor physical fitness, and on the other hand, because the physical test scores are linked to the evaluation of excellence and awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Why has physical fitness declined? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s investigation found that the decline in physical fitness of college students is not only due to students’ unwillingness to exercise, but also related to the fact that some colleges and universities do not pay attention to physical tests and have unreasonable physical education classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities do not strictly implement the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and do not pay attention to physical tests. According to the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot;, when students from ordinary high schools, secondary vocational schools and ordinary colleges and universities graduate, those whose test scores do not reach 50 points will be treated as completed or dropped out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the sports department of many colleges and universities said that due to various considerations, this regulation is not strictly implemented in many colleges and universities, and some even directly ignore it, causing students to have psychological problems with physical exercise and testing. slack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin revealed that in response to random inspections and reviews of college students&#39; physical health tests, some colleges and universities learned that when the expert team came, they would specifically look for students with good sports scores to cooperate, resulting in distortion of the physical test data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities have unreasonable physical education courses. To improve the physical quality of college students, college physical education classes play an indispensable role. The reporter&#39;s investigation found that the current physical education courses in many colleges and universities are similar, out of touch with the sports needs of college students, and affect their enthusiasm for class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nowadays, physical education classes basically still take track, field, football, basketball, etc. on the playground, which is similar to more than ten years ago.” Some college students reported that young people now like yoga, exercise for fat loss, and outdoor development. There are almost no such &quot;new physical education classes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhang Yimin, compared with the physical education and health curriculum standards for primary and secondary school students, there is no unified curriculum standard for physical education classes in colleges and universities. Many undergraduate colleges usually only offer physical education classes in the first and second grades, and students have obviously insufficient time for physical exercise and poor results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Education’s student physical health sampling review data shows that as of 2020, the failure rate of college students is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some college students are not willing to exercise. The interviewed physical education teacher said that some students were playing mobile phones on the side of the playground during physical education class. “In the past, students were often seen fighting for space on the football field, but now there are only a few people here and there.” “During morning exercise time, there are very few students doing exercise”…&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Li Jinglei, a graduate student at a university in Shandong, said that there are no physical education classes at the graduate level of the school, and sports are all dependent on individuals. Only one-tenth of the students in the class do regular physical exercise, and even if they want to play basketball, there are not enough people. Either it’s too hot in the summer and too cold in the winter, or there are other entertainment activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some college students interviewed even said: &quot;If you are too lazy to walk to the cafeteria to eat, why do you exercise?&quot; &quot;How can you go for a morning jog when you can&#39;t even get up to attend professional classes at 8 o&#39;clock in the morning?&quot; Is it fun or is surfing the Internet boring?&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Take multiple measures to improve the physical fitness of college students&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewee said, Improving the physical fitness of college students not only requires &quot;self-pressure&quot; of college students, but also requires joint promotion by relevant departments and schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that relevant standards should be strictly implemented to increase students&#39; attention. In 2021, the &quot;strictest physical education regulations&quot; issued by Yunnan University have triggered heated discussions on the Internet: starting from freshmen enrolling in the fall of 2021, if they fail the physical test in any academic year, they will not receive a diploma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not the first initiative of Yunnan University, but a regulation of the Ministry of Education.” Wang Zongping, dean of the School of Physical Education of Yunnan University, said that after the school strictly implemented relevant regulations, the passing rate of students’ physical examinations has increased significantly, from 2018 to 2018. 68.6% increased to 90.3% in 2022. &quot;Now students pay more and more attention to physical exercise. Every night at eight or nine o&#39;clock, they can be seen exercising on the school playground.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259556&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On November 21, 2023, the male 1000-meter physical test site of Yunnan University. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Bo, director of the Physical Education Department of Tsinghua University, suggested that schools can offer more special courses based on their own conditions to help students increase their interest in sports. At present, Tsinghua University insists on offering physical education courses for four-year undergraduate students, involving more than 50 courses such as competitive sports, leisure sports, traditional ethnic sports and physical therapy courses, and offers sports elective courses for graduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the composition and evaluation methods of physical education classes should be optimized to prevent falsification of physical tests. Cheng Shouyun, a physical education teacher at Hefei University of Technology, said that the school has carried out an integrated reform of physical education inside and outside the classroom, and has included &quot;physical fitness&quot; as one of the required modules in the &quot;Second Classroom Transcript&quot; as a hard indicator for student graduation. Physical education class scores are linked to students&#39; extracurricular exercise. In-class tests and final assessments in physical education classes account for 60 points, theoretical study accounts for 10 points, and extracurricular fitness accounts for 30 points. In extracurricular fitness, running exercises account for no less than 60%. Other appointments can be made through the smart system. Sports should not exceed 40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prevent fraud such as taking exams on behalf of others, Hefei University of Technology adopts the method of verifying student ID cards, and the test can only be carried out when the person and ID are combined; Anhui University uses dual authentication of ID card and facial recognition detection. Once a substitute exam is found, The phenomenon will be investigated seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is particularly important to integrate physical education with education to develop good exercise habits. At Tsinghua University, undergraduate freshmen will gather together to experience the sports tradition and spirit of &quot;without sports, there is no Tsinghua University&quot; through the &quot;First Physical Education Lesson&quot;. There are also many students who have found their favorite sports and gained their own sense of accomplishment and belonging by participating in the Freshman Barefoot Games and Campus Marathon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Colleges and universities can help students master 1 to 2 sports skills and develop lifelong exercise habits through measures that suit their own characteristics, and create a campus that is open to all students, runs through the entire process, and educates people in all aspects Sports culture.&quot; Liu Bo said: &quot;The inherent educational value of physical exercise can be transformed into excellent qualities promoted in social life, which will benefit students throughout their lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 12:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国全额缴清联合国会费，缴费比例33年增长19倍丨漫热点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261308]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;776&quot; height=&quot;10000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259589&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>