<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[白切鸡寿司走红，年轻人流行的“中餐日作”是真香吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257296]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:30:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[钱锺书回避鲁迅？No，他开启了“悄悄关注”模式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257339]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B0asgnIe8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height=&quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/Al0NA8piZmtUhLaOo6f35jIRv7oOmF4B 0asgnIe8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251595&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Lin Yutang, Lu Xun, Soong Ching Ling, Smedley, Li Peihua (Secretary of Soong Ching Ling) ). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Qian Zhongshu rarely talked about Lu Xun publicly, he could not &quot;avoid&quot; Lu Xun. Crystal once said in &quot;Miscellaneous Notes of Shi Qian&#39;s Throwing Books&quot; that at a symposium, Qian Zhongshu praised Lu Xun&#39;s short stories for being well written, but not suitable for long stories. The most well-known person is Qian Zhongshu&#39;s opening speech at the &quot;Lu Xun and Chinese and Foreign Culture&quot; academic seminar. This article was later published in &quot;Literary Journal&quot; on October 23, 1986, and collected in &quot;The Edge of Life&quot;. In his opening speech, Qian Zhongshu said a few words &quot;as usual&quot; based on people&#39;s &quot;public opinion&quot; of Lu Xun at that time: &quot;Lu Xun was a great man. The greater the figure, the more aspects can be observed; &#39;Chinese and foreign culture&#39; is a big The bigger the topic, the wider the scope of the problems that can occur.&quot; The main spirit of his speech was to hope that everyone can &quot;speak freely without bending the meaning to seek consensus&quot;, and could not see the true evaluation of Lu Xun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun also had a period of time in the same city. In September 1927, Lu Xun left Guangzhou and lived in Shanghai until his death in October 1936. Qian Zhongshu graduated from Tsinghua University in the summer of 1933 and taught at Guanghua University. He began studying at Oxford in the autumn of 1935, so he spent more than two years in Shanghai. However, they were only from the same city, and the two of them had never been seen crossing paths. However, as a later scholar and because of Lu Xun&#39;s huge influence, Qian Zhongshu inevitably had to &quot;encounter&quot; Lu Xun intentionally or unintentionally when writing. &quot;On the Parallel Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu&quot; written by Liu Yukai and &quot;On the Comparative Study of Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu Literature&quot; written by Sui Qing&#39;e have all made comparisons from an academic level. Scholars such as Xie Yong, Wang Peijun, Li Guotao and Qian Zhijun have made comparisons in their writings. There are also elucidations from time to time, and I would like to unearth several examples related to Lu Xun from Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writings, which may fill the gaps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Besieged City&quot;, Sun Roujia&#39;s uncle and aunt hold important positions in a large cotton factory and have always looked down upon Fang Hongjian. Once, Fang Hongjian and Sun Roujia quarreled again over the arrival of his aunt. When he learned that his aunt wanted to find a position for him in the factory, he jumped up and shouted: &quot;Who wants her to find trouble for me? I can&#39;t even beg for food.&quot; Don&#39;t ask her for it! Isn&#39;t it enough that she has two lackeys, Bobby and you, Sun Roujia? You tell her that Fang Hongjian &#39;has no skills but a very bad temper&#39;, and you won&#39;t be a lackey of a capitalist lackey.&quot; This paragraph of text , immediately reminds people of Lu Xun&#39;s famous article &quot;&quot;Bereaved&quot; and &quot;The Capitalist&#39;s Lacking Lackey&quot; published in 1930, which criticized Liang Shiqiu. Although Qian Zhongshu was studying in Tsinghua University at the time, he would not have missed the articles on the Lu-Liang debate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 84 of the first volume of the Commercial Press&#39;s &quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot;, reading the notes of Yue Ke&#39;s &quot;History&quot;, Qian Zhongshu excerpted the following paragraph in Volume 12 and added a note:&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the summer of the 10th year of the reign of Emperor Xizong (Wanyan) of the Jin Dynasty, Long Jian (present) in the Yuzhai Palace, there was a heavy thunderstorm Arrive, break the pillar and go away. Everyone was shocked, thinking it was ominous, and wanted to look at it in disgust. Some people thought that a general amnesty should be granted, so they called Zhang Jun, a bachelor, to draft the imperial edict. Among them are the words &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Looking at Yu Xiaozi&quot;. The translator did not know the meaning of Tuo Qianchong, so he said: &quot;Han&#39;er is strong in knowledge, and he relies on words to criticize my Lord&#39;s ears.&quot; When asked why, he translated and explained its meaning: &quot;The widowed is lonely and has no relatives; the ignorant is ignorant of human affairs; the eyes are blind; the brat is a child.&quot; He was furious and summoned Jun to question him, but he failed to answer him. , slash (cut) its mouth with a hand sword, and dig it with thorns. I didn&#39;t know that it was translated as &quot;foolishness&quot; or &quot;treachery&quot;. So... According to this, Lu Xun is also the ancestor of literal translation. &quot; (&quot;Notes of Rong&#39;an Pavilion&quot; page 146)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Xizong Wanyan Dan was the third emperor of the Jin Dynasty. It is said that he studied under Han Fang before he came to the throne and was able to write poems in Chinese. After he came to the throne, he was particularly diligent in studying Chinese classics. According to this article in the &quot;History of the Emperor&quot;, Wanyan Quan did not seem to be very proficient in Chinese, and the translator could only &quot;literally translate&quot;, taking out of context the commonly used imperial edicts. Formulas such as &quot;Gu Zi is ignorant&quot; and &quot;Xiao Yu Xiaozi&quot; can be &quot;directly interpreted&quot; as cursing the Lord, thus losing the original meaning of &quot;retreating, trusting, and rushing&quot;, and Zhang Jun was convicted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Zhongshu&#39;s note &quot;This is the ancestor of Lu Xun&#39;s literal translation&quot; naturally reminds people of the &quot;Lu-Liang Controversy&quot;. In September 1929, Liang Shiqiu published &quot;On Mr. Lu Xun&#39;s Life&quot; in &quot;Crescent&quot; &quot;Hard Translation&quot;&quot;, Lu Xun refuted it by publishing &quot;&quot;Hard Translation&quot; and &quot;The Class Nature of Literature&quot;&quot; in &quot;Jinya Monthly&quot; in March of the following year. The debate has exceeded the boundaries of translation. As far as translation is concerned, Lu Xun advocated &quot;literal translation&quot; (or &quot;hard translation&quot;), such as the translation of &quot;The Symbol of Depression&quot;, which &quot;is translated sentence by sentence, or even word for word according to the rules&quot;, and its purpose is to &quot;prefer to believe rather than obey.&quot; Qian Zhongshu is obviously familiar with translation However, his views were different from those of Lu Xun, so Qian Zhongshu went on to write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yu Reading &quot;Shuowen&quot; to the &quot;Kou&quot; part of the 26th word &quot;囮: 译也&quot;, Chang sighs Ji Chang (Editor&#39;s note: refers to Xu Shen), a true saint, foresees Tradutore, traditore! Wang Yuanzhi&#39;s &quot;Little Animals Collection&quot; Volume 14 &quot;Translation Dui&quot; says: &quot;Translation means Yi. It can change one&#39;s mind if it is big, but it can only change one&#39;s words if it is small. &quot;So on and so forth. After liberation, the trend of translating books became more and more popular. They did not know how to make mistakes, but they were eaten alive. Not only were they changed beyond recognition, but their hearts and minds were completely changed. They were the so-called &quot;great translators&quot; in Xun Yuan Dynasty. Gu Tangsheng&#39;s &quot;Records of Zhang Wenxiang&#39;s Shogunate&quot; Juan Xia said: &quot;Chen Lanbin envoy to the United States, one of his attendants, Xu, is not familiar with Western languages. One day, he suddenly picked up the Western Newspaper and seemed to be reading it with gusto. His colleagues asked him strangely. Xu said: I can&#39;t understand the Western Newspaper. I read Zhu Jun&#39;s translation. Also puzzled. If you still don&#39;t understand, it would be better to just read the Western newspaper. &quot;In this way, both this and Zhang Jun&#39;s incident can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators. (ibid., pp. 146-147)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This note is related to the fact that &quot;after liberation&quot; the translation industry &quot;does not know what to do. Talking about &quot;eating alive&quot; is also a denial of &quot;literal translation&quot;. Regarding translation, what Qian Zhongshu pursues is the realm of &quot;translation&quot;, although &quot;thorough and complete &#39;translation&#39; is an unattainable ideal.&quot; Therefore, Qian Zhongshu pursues In the article, Zhongshu praised Xu Shen (Jianchang) as a &quot;true saint&quot; and said that he could predict that the translation would be &quot;囮&quot; (false) and that the translator (Tradutore) was a traitor (traditore). For details, see &quot;Lin Shu&#39;s Translation&quot; and There are several discussions in &quot;Guan Zhui Bian&quot;. The following part of this article is based on Gu Hongming&#39;s story of Xu reading a Western newspaper, and combined with Zhang Jun&#39;s view, he believes that &quot;all can be used as the motto of today&#39;s translators.&quot; It is humorous without losing irony, which is quite obvious. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s writing style is consistent. The most eye-catching part of the whole note is the note &quot;the ancestor of literal translation&quot; and so on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1920s and 1930s, Lin Yutang was trying to change the &quot;Chinese-style humor&quot; &quot;Joking attitude&quot; to reshape the virtues of gentlemen, so he advocated &quot;humorous literature&quot;. Unexpectedly, it backfired, as Qian Zhongshu criticized in his essay &quot;Joking&quot;: &quot;Since the promotion of humorous literature, joking has become a literati career. &quot;Lin Yutang helped the &quot;current ills&quot; by rescuing &quot;current ills.&quot; The actual effect of &quot;humorous literature&quot; ran counter to its original intention. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s &quot;Jokes&quot; was inspired by &quot;humorous literature.&quot; As for Lin Yutang&#39;s ideas, Lu Xun In &quot;One Thought and Action&quot;, he once criticized: &quot;Boom, there is no shortage of humor and sketches in the world. &quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;, Volume 5, page 473) also pointed out in &quot;Explanation of &quot;Funny&quot;&quot; that humorous literature just gives &quot;slick, frivolous and obscene&quot; the &quot;title of &#39;humor&#39;&quot; (&quot;The Complete Works of Lu Xun&quot;) &quot;Volume 5, page 342). Some people therefore believe that &quot;Lu Xun and Qian Zhongshu really echo each other in their views on promoting humorous literature&quot; (Li Qinye, &quot;Reading &amp;lt;Writing on the Edge of Life&quot;), This statement is specious.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the history of modern literature, Lu Xun, Lin Yutang and Qian Zhongshu are all famous for their humor. Lu Xun&#39;s humor is like a dagger, with the edge of a scalpel to remove tumors, while Lin Yutang&#39;s humor is The breeze is like a purifier for the soul. At that time, Lin Yutang&#39;s humorous literature was naturally not as powerful as Lu Xun&#39;s essays, so it seemed out of date and was publicly criticized by Lu Xun. Qian Zhongshu&#39;s humor was like cold rain hitting his face, cold and thorny, like a pretender The embarrassment and uneasiness after his soul was exposed. However, although Qian Zhongshu also criticized Lin Yutang, if you compare his &quot;Laughing&quot; with Lin Yutang&#39;s &quot;On Humor&quot;, you will find how similar their views on humor are: Qian Zhongshu It is said that a person who is really humorous will have a &quot;knowing smile&quot; about humor. Lin Yutang said that a calm and distant bystander will give a &quot;knowing smile&quot; to humor; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;funny and wise&quot; , Lin Yutang said, &quot;wisdom has begun&quot; and &quot;there is humor&quot;; Qian Zhongshu said that humor is &quot;a breath of breath for the dull life&quot;, Lin Yutang said that humor is &quot;a part of life&quot;. Humor originates from wisdom, famous humorists It is not surprising that Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang have similar concepts but different expressions and effects. Because of this view of humor, Lin Yutang advocates humorous literature to cultivate the people&#39;s sense of humor and cultivate educated citizens, while Qian Zhongshu believes that true humor can &quot; &quot;Anti-bowing and laughing at oneself&quot; will become a laughing stock once advocated, so he said: &quot;Humor is at most a kind of temperament and can never be labeled as an idea, let alone a profession.&quot; ” It can be seen that although Qian Zhongshu and Lu Xun both criticized the “humorous literature” advocated by Lin Yutang, it cannot be said that their views on humor are of the same origin. On the contrary, Qian Zhongshu and Lin Yutang’s views on humor are “similar to each other.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As a witness and participant in the same literary and artistic trend, although Qian Zhongshu never had direct contact with Lu Xun, it even made people think that he sometimes deliberately &quot;looked sideways&quot; at Lu Xun, and followed the trend to find out the source. If we open the &quot;fog&quot;, we can still see their figures at the same time in major events in the history of modern literature, and then we can see Qian Zhongshu&#39;s consistent indifferent attitude towards Shi Xian, including Lu Xun, &quot;It&#39;s like seeing from flying sand, wheat waves, and ripples &quot;The posture of the wind&quot; (Qian Zhong&#39;s calligraphy). (The original title of this article was &quot;The posture of the wind&quot;, the current title was proposed by the editor)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4.2千年事件”：地球大降温，华夏新生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257310]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of this century, with the advancement of molecular biology, we were able to explore the origin of rice through gene testing - detection The results show that cultivated rice was first domesticated in the Yangtze River Basin about 13,500 to 8.2 thousand years ago, and then spread to Southeast Asia and South Asia. After hybridizing with wild indica rice in South Asia, cultivated indica rice was produced and returned to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the process of studying the origin of rice, genetic testing has brought questions. Scholars suddenly discovered that there are many strange things about its spread time: after rice was domesticated, it stayed in China for thousands of years and did not spread outside. However, around 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, almost at the same time, rice suddenly appeared on the Japanese Islands, the Korean Peninsula, the Philippines, Indo-China Peninsula and the South Asian subcontinent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This makes people wonder: What happened more than four thousand years ago? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from ancient Chinese books, 4,000 years ago was around the time when the Xia Dynasty was established. It is said that after Emperor Yu controlled the floods, he sent envoys to measure &quot;the whole world&quot; and finally calculated that the distance from east to west and north to south of the earth was 233,500 miles and 75 steps. Although this is just a myth in the &quot;Book of Mountains and Seas&quot;, mythical stories often have prototypes: Maybe after Dayu established the Xia Dynasty, he sent envoys to explore the unknown world and spread rice to surrounding countries by the way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an archaeological perspective, the world between 4.2 and 4,000 years ago was suffering unprecedented disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you pay attention to Chinese archeology, you may have heard the saying &quot;a sky full of stars&quot;, which describes ancient civilizations before the Xia Dynasty: China between 5000 and 4300 years ago was full of archaeological sites. There are Hongshan in the western Liao River basin and Longshan in the Yellow River basin. These two are already city-state civilizations; in the Yangtze River basin there are Liangzhu and Shijiahe, both of which have entered dynastic politics. At that time, the earth was in the famous &quot;Holocene Warm Period&quot;. The humid and warm climate allowed civilizations all over the world to thrive. Even the deserts of Central Asia and the Sahara Desert of Africa were livable places with widespread forests and lakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by 4.2 to 4,000 years ago, the civilizations in the three major river basins all collapsed, and the entire land of China fell into chaos:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cities in Shijiahe and Liangzhu in the Yangtze River Basin collapsed one after another Destroyed and abandoned, the territory shrank sharply. By 3800 years ago, the original core area had almost become a no-man&#39;s land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many settlements in the Xiliao River Basin disappeared completely, and the population was directly replaced: genetic testing found that the Xiajiadian lower-class culture that later emerged in the local area had no genetic connection with the previous residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yellow River Basin is also full of victims: Archeology shows that the number of settlements in the middle and lower reaches of the Yellow River decreased by nearly 90% during this catastrophe, and the population may only be 1/10 of its original size. The exquisite and brilliant Longshan black pottery disappeared, and it was not until more than a hundred years later that a very rough gray pottery culture appeared - which means that the original civilization, the original knowledge and technology inheritance were also lost in this catastrophe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the origin of this catastrophe, the most common hypothesis is the Great Flood: Based on archaeological evidence, some scholars speculate that about 3920 years ago, a huge barrier lake formed in the upper reaches of the Yellow River, blocking the Yellow River. nearly 9 months. Afterwards, the barrier lake burst its banks, and about 16 billion cubic meters of lake water poured down instantly. The flood almost flattened the entire Yellow River Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this hypothesis has some truth, it cannot explain the great collapse that also occurred in the Yangtze River Basin during the same period - in fact, not only the Yellow River and the Yangtze River, but also the whole world experienced a great collapse of civilization at that time. This was obviously a Climate disasters affecting the world:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The forests and Saharan lakes in Central Asia disappeared, and the great desert was born; in the Nile River Basin of North Africa, the early dynasty that had flourished for five hundred years came to an abrupt end, severe drought led to the collapse of agriculture, and Egypt fell into The century-long famine and civil strife is known to history as the &quot;First Intermediate Period&quot;; in the two river basins of West Asia, the Akkadian Empire completed its unification for the first time. A large amount of farmland was abandoned and was immediately attacked by foreign barbarians; in Central and Northern Europe, The cooling made the climate cold and humid, leading to the great migration of many ethnic groups...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This climate catastrophe is now called the &quot;4.2 Millennium Event&quot;, a catastrophe that can be called the end of civilization. . The superposition of turbulent ocean currents, super volcanic eruptions and El Niño may be the culprits of this natural disaster. The 4.2 millennium event manifested itself differently in different regions. Some places experienced severe droughts, while others experienced floods, but generally speaking, major cooling occurred. In fact, this event occurred from the end of the &quot;Younger Dryas Little Ice Age&quot; until the end of the Little Ice Age. Today, humanity has experienced the most severe cooling. The temperature in many places has never returned to the level of the Holocene Warm Period, and the good days of comfort and warmth are gone forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, it was the 4.2 Thousand Years Incident that exterminated the ancestors of the Western Liao River, severely damaged the ancient city-states of the Yellow River, and destroyed the two ancient dynasties in the Yangtze River Basin. Agriculture collapsed, famine was rampant, and mourning was widespread. In just a few decades or even a few years, 90% of the population has been lost. This is a doomsday scene that we today cannot imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The few survivors in South China, namely the ancient farmers of the Yangtze River and their descendants, had to take their rice seeds with them and flee in search of new land that could barely be cultivated. They crossed the sea to the east and reached the Korean Peninsula and Japan, becoming the ancestors of Koreans and Japanese immigrants; they reached the Philippines to the south and became the first stop for the Austronesian people to conquer the Pacific; they crossed the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau to the west and reached the Indochina Peninsula and India. , and the local hunter indigenous people, merged to form the Mon-Khmer language family (South Asian language family)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, misfortunes and blessings depend on each other, and new life is also born in the doomsday disaster. After the catastrophe, China bid farewell to the &quot;starry sky&quot; and began to unite: the ancestors of South China (ancient farmers on the Yangtze River) who fled famine, and another group arrived in the northern Central Plains. Here they met the ancient farmers of the Yellow River who had also fled here. The two integrated and communicated to build a new home together - the north and south areas of Songshan Mountain where Erlitou in Henan is located were not prominent during the Holocene Warm Period, with only some scattered small settlements. However, hundreds of years after the Great Collapse, probably ancestors who had fled from various places gathered here, and the place rapidly revived and grew. About 3,800 years ago, Erlitou had developed into the largest settlement in the entire Yellow River Basin and became the undisputed master of the Central Plains. It immediately began to expand aggressively, and soon became an unrivaled and powerful dynasty in the entire East Asia - many scholars believe that it is the Xia Dynasty in ancient books, and the era of unification of China has arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[凉山警方破获特大贩运毒品案，缴获各类毒品146千克、抓捕31人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the summer public security crackdown and rectification operations of public security agencies across the country, Liangshan Public Security focused on the characteristics of summer social security laws , focusing on prominent local illegal and criminal activities, using the &quot;Sharpening Sword&quot; operation as the starting point, strengthening crackdowns and rectification efforts, and implementing special work measures to effectively protect the peace of people&#39;s lives and maintain the overall stability of social security. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/5e015de2df5bfed8a0005a8fd8d1b0e2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;466&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/5e015de2df5bfed8a0005a8fd8d1b0e2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251585 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 20, the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau held a press briefing on the summer public security crackdown and the &quot;Strengthening the Sword&quot; operation, focusing on reporting on the results of the operation and typical cases. Zhao Peng, deputy secretary of the Party Committee and executive deputy director of the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau, attended the meeting and reported the overall work results. Yu Xing, member of the Party Committee and Director of the Political Department of Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau, presided over the briefing meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the deployment of the operation, the public security organs across the state have carried out 14 centralized inspections, dispatching a total of more than 48,000 police officers, effectively promoting the &quot;sharpening sword&quot; operation and achieving &quot;two reductions and three improvements&quot; (telecom network fraud, theft The incidence rate of similar cases has dropped, and the number of cases involving drugs, pornography, and gambling has increased). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating drug crimes. As of August, 112 cases had been solved, 149 people had been punished, 139 people had been detained administratively, and 42 people had been forced to quit. On August 31, the &quot;2022.10.12&quot; major drug trafficking case was successfully uncovered. A total of 31 suspects were arrested in the case, a total of 146 kilograms of various drugs and more than 800,000 yuan in drug money were seized. The most complete drug network involving Yunnan and Myanmar drug cases. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating telecommunications network fraud. From March 1st to August 31st, a total of 537 telecom network fraud cases occurred across the state; 325 cases were solved; 950 people were arrested; more than 71.8064 million yuan was lost; 2.218243 yuan was recovered and the loss was recovered. We insist on &quot;prevention first&quot; in cases of electronic fraud &quot;, the state&#39;s &quot;Anti-Fraud Center&quot; issued an average of more than 3,228 early warnings per day, stopped payment for 9,958 accounts involved, stopped payment of more than 211 million yuan, and froze 1,242 accounts involved, freezing funds of more than 45.5635 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on illegal crimes such as theft. A total of 824 theft cases occurred across the state, and a total of 314 theft cases were solved across the state; 680 suspects were arrested and 543 were punished. Successfully solved the case of &quot;the theft of cables from the main engineering station of Huaneng Butuotuojue Wind Power Project&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on Internet-related crimes. The crackdown rate on online rumors reached 100%; 137 cases of major sensitive public opinions were safely handled, and negative public opinions related to the Cold War dropped by 30% compared with the same period last year. As of August, 24 cases had been solved and 27 people had been punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Crack down on pornography-related crimes. The public security organs across the state insist on taking the &quot;anti-pornography operation&quot; as the primary task of crackdown and rectification. So far, a total of 636 pornography-related cases (527 administrative cases, 109 criminal cases) have been handled, and 787 people have been punished (651 administrative cases, 136 criminal cases). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combating illegal gambling crimes. As of August, 838 cases have been solved, 2,882 people have been punished, 19 people have been criminally detained after detecting the &quot;Zhang Moumou and others gathering gambling case&quot; in Muli, 32 gambling participants were investigated and dealt with, and more than 60,000 yuan of gambling funds were seized; In the &quot;2023.8.11 crowd gambling case&quot;, 32 people were criminally detained, and the amount involved was more than 200,000 yuan; the two courts jointly prosecuted 15 cases successfully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listing rectification. In April 2023, the Liangshan Prefecture Public Security Bureau launched the first batch of 50 online fugitives publicly offering rewards, and 42 of them have been brought to justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白客：像水一样的演员]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Most of the time, Baike doesn&#39;t know where the boundaries of his abilities are and relies on his feelings. Taking on a role is not that particular about rules and regulations, it’s about getting along well. In the past few years, he has acted in many movies and dramas that focus on reality, and appeared in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; and &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot;. He said, &quot;The abilities contained in my body were discovered by the producer and director. Thank them.&quot; And he quietly does his job as an actor, using his skills, emotions, and talents to be responsible for every performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/254252&quot; title=&quot;Baike: A &quot;cowarded and frustrated&quot; &quot;The actor&#39;s way of survival&quot;>;Bake: The way of survival of a &quot;cowardly and frustrated&quot; actor&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 9, 2023, the Shanghai International Film Festival opened On the red carpet, actor Bai Ke appeared three times. In the screenings that lasted for 10 days, he was Gan Yaozu in &quot;Looking for Her&quot; and &quot;The Annual Party Can&#39;t Stop!&quot; &quot;Ma Jie&quot; and Pan Congcong in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;, whether he is the protagonist or supporting role, comedy or drama, he has appropriately expressed the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Baike, becoming an actor was unexpected. On the eve of his graduation from college, he became famous for his dubbing work. In 2010, after graduating from Nanguang College of Communication University of China, he briefly worked in a television station, and then quickly went north to join the film and television company Wanhe Tianyi. When the company was on the verge of collapse and everyone was planning to go their separate ways, they filmed the short play &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, which saved the company and made the director and actors an instant hit. The male protagonist of &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, the narcissistic, self-deprecating, grassroots Wang Dachui, was played by Bai Gugu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of becoming popular in his early years was intertwined with the family teaching of &quot;live your own little life&quot;, and finally derived a happy-go-lucky character. He has his own comfort zone and feels good staying there. After work, I play football with my friends, watch football, read comics and TV shows, and spend time with my parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only time he experienced stepping out of his comfort zone since he was a child was when he decided to apply for the broadcasting major because he liked football and wanted to be a football commentator. After studying media for four years, although he failed to become a commentator, he became sensitive to the matter of &quot;recording&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also related to this that Baike liked the script of &quot;Looking for Her&quot;, a female self-awareness exploration in a traditional village. He said: &quot;This kind of thing is very meaningful to me. I think the topic needs to be recorded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he had to memorize Cantonese lines and play opposite Shu Qi, the filming of &quot;Looking for Her&quot; was not easy for Baike. There was a scene where he and Shu Qi quarreled, and there was a lot of Cantonese dialogue, which was originally going to be filmed after the actors got used to each other. However, the crew encountered a typhoon as soon as they arrived in Huizhou, the filming location. In order to avoid the bad weather, director Chen Shizhong planned to shoot the quarrel scene indoors first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He would not say that I was scared before the shooting, nor would he say that I would definitely be able to do it, and then he would complete it very well. He is very relaxed, but has strong energy inside.&quot; Later Chen Shizhong said Then I realized that Bai Ke was nervous, but he hid it. Chen Shizhong had seen a journalist role he played, and on the day after watching it, he posted on WeChat Moments: Bai Ke can give the director a great sense of security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He is an actor like water. He can be matched with any actor. He is very malleable.&quot; Chen Shizhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会主媒体中心里有什么？南周记者带你去探营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张家界一景区多名身着警察制服人员殴打游客？警方回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Police Information Report&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 12:49 on September 20, 2023, the Yongding Public Security Bureau received a call from a tourist claiming to have been injured. After receiving the alarm, the Yongding Public Security Bureau quickly dispatched police to deal with the incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, tourist Feng had a dispute with Yang Mouyi and Qin &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; when he was buying rain gear at a shop near the parking lot of Tianmen Mountain. Feng&#39;s husband Liu was beaten and suffered eye injuries. At the time of the incident, Yang Mouyi was wearing a blue uniform, and another person, Zou Moukang, was illegally wearing a police armband. There were no public security police officers or auxiliary police officers at the scene of the incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, the public security organs have detained Yang Mouyi and Qin for beating others, and Zou Moukang for illegally wearing police armbands and uniforms. , the case is under further processing. The police will handle the case strictly in accordance with the law, resolutely safeguard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the legitimate rights and interests of the victims, and investigate and correct the illegal wearing of imitation police uniforms in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yongding Public Security Bureau&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span >;September 21, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冲着漫改来，意外被他圈粉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257320]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Recently, there are two comic dramas that attract people Pay attention to: One is the live-action version of &quot;One Piece&quot; on Netflix, and the other is &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; on Youku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared to &quot;One Piece&quot;, the broadcast process of &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has been full of twists and turns. It first premiered on August 4 with 4 episodes, and then stopped airing the next day due to &quot;media reasons&quot;, setting a record for the &quot;fastest offline&quot; of a domestic drama. It did not resume broadcast until September 6, dispelling the audience&#39;s doubts that it disappeared out of thin air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5a25a4a369827783352e693c7158d38e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5a25a4a369827783352e693c7158d38e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Stranger&quot; &quot;Under&quot; is adapted from the well-known Chinese comic &quot;Under One Person&quot; created by Mi Er. The original work is not only well-received but also extremely popular. Since the animated version came out in 2016, it has been broadcast for a total of five seasons, with an average score of 8.4 on Douban. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;qi (qi) warrior&quot; in traditional fairy tale novels was fictionalized by Mi Er into a &quot;stranger&quot; hidden in the real world in the original work. &quot;Extraordinary people&quot; are gifted with special abilities and can skillfully control their own &quot;qi&quot;, thus possessing special abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that during the Jiashen period (1944), several strangers discovered the &quot;Eight Wonderful Skills&quot; such as the Origin of Qi Ti, Ju Ling Qian Jiang, Fenghou Qimen, and the Tongtian Rui, which caused the strangers to People in the world fought for it, which triggered a bloody storm, known in history as the &quot;Jiashen Rebellion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/0c12eb18e51067c31c3f414d93f0f34f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;638&quot; height= &quot;270&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/0c12eb18e51067c31c3f414d93f0f34f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251573&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comic is adapted into Dramas have a natural barrier, which is mainly reflected in the degree of casting and adaptation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the live-action version of &quot;One Piece&quot;, &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; also experienced a difficult casting controversy when it first aired. Zhang Chulan, played by Peng Yuchang, was questioned for her poor appearance and lacked the ruffian spirit in the original work; Feng Baobao, played by Wang Yinglu, was questioned for her dull acting skills, like a humanoid AI; Zhang Lingyu, played by Bi Wenjun, had inconsistent appearance and temperament , was criticized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/3e397c0a9ab9647b08e98a436e959af9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;736&quot; height= &quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/3e397c0a9ab9647b08e98a436e959af9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251570&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although these doubts It&#39;s not unreasonable, but it&#39;s also common for people to have difficulty in choosing the right characters for comic book adaptations. Since the audience watches the original work first, they are bound to have preconceptions and view the comic-adapted drama with resistance. When the domestic comic drama &quot;Soul of Chess&quot; came out, it was labeled as &quot;ruining childhood&quot; due to casting and styling issues. It was not until the story got better in the later years that the reputation changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/36a6d71ccad0a47b673eee745a80a5f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/36a6d71ccad0a47b673eee745a80a5f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, select Whether the corner sticks to the face or not is very important, but one move will not determine life or death. Because there is still a plot, and a good storyline can also turn the tide. And this involves the &quot;degree&quot; of adaptation: too few adaptations, and it is suspected of copying and pasting; too many adaptations, and the characters and famous scenes are not restored enough, and it is easy to fall into the misunderstanding of &quot;magic modification&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comic drama &quot;Under the Stranger&quot;, the male protagonist Zhang Chulan accidentally got involved in the world of strangers because his grandfather Zhang Huaiyi&#39;s bones were stolen. In the process of searching for his grandfather&#39;s body, he first met Feng Baobao, a girl who behaved strangely, and then was recruited by the mysterious organization Nadu Tong. He passed the trial of the Tianshi Mansion in Longhu Mountain and got the opportunity to participate in the Alien Martial Arts Competition. Opportunity...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the descendant of the &quot;Eight Skills&quot; Qi Ti lineage, Zhang Chulan quickly became a popular star in the alien world, attracting the attention of all forces. In the process of wrestling with various forces, he gradually came to face the various alien abilities that his grandfather had taught him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e74900efbaca076c702130cdaa78d40b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;727&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e74900efbaca076c702130cdaa78d40b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251574&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Original author Mi Secondly, &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has restored the rich world view constructed with imaginative settings to a greater extent, including various sects, families and stunts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disguised as a logistics company, &quot;Everywhere Connect&quot; has employees who are all composed of aliens. They are responsible for maintaining the balance and stability of the alien world and ensuring that ordinary people will not be aware of the existence of aliens. It is a bit like a cartoon. S.H.I.E.L.D. in the Marvel Universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the alien world, the ten men with the highest say are from the Tianshi Mansion, the Lu Family, the Lu Family, the Tianxiahui, the Wang Family, the Mu Family, and the Chen Family. Zhang Zhiwei, the Celestial Master of Longhu Mountain, is the leader of the ten men. He has a very high level of cultivation and is over a hundred years old. He is the ceiling of combat power in the alien world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/bb791c56359d86ea510d67e0cf69b036.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;302&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/bb791c56359d86ea510d67e0cf69b036.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251575&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don&#39;t talk about it &quot;Quan Xing&quot;, who has no principles and no rules, is an alien organization that does all kinds of evil. &quot;Complete nature&quot; has been around for thousands of years. It was founded by Yang Zhu, one of the hundreds of scholars in the Warring States period. It originally emphasized &quot;preserving integrity and not burdening the body with things&quot;. Unfortunately, it gradually went astray in the later period and became an evil spirit in the alien world. group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the number of episodes currently aired, the overall quality of &quot;Under the Strangers&quot; is still good. First of all, director Xu Hongyu set a clear main line for the whole play, changing the unit-style narrative habit of the original work, using the male protagonist Zhang Chulan as the entry point, allowing him to lead the audience into the world of strangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, as the plot progresses, several suspense points in the original work become clear and intriguing, such as the reasons for the &quot;Jiashen Rebellion&quot; and the mystery of Feng Baobao&#39;s life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, in addition to restoring the characters and famous scenes, the main creator also showed good subjective initiative, such as rationalizing the popular character Wang Ye in advance. Under the interpretation of actor Hou Minghao, this The charm of the character continues in the play. Many viewers said that they came for the comic adaptation and eventually became fans of Wang Ye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the entire plot is dense and fast-paced. The plot has advanced to the 20th episode, and the content of the first two seasons and extra chapters of the animated version has been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e1f0d2c3443b5dc9a4c30ec286e96262.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e1f0d2c3443b5dc9a4c30ec286e96262.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251577&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the core idea It seems that &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has firmly captured the essence of the original work, that is, &quot;What is a Stranger?&quot; Mi Er once mentioned in an interview that this story began with the word &quot;foreigner&quot;. He wanted to express the theme of &quot;if one day you find that you are different from others, how should you deal with yourself and how should you get along with the world?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone will encounter such torture when growing up. Some people choose to stick to themselves, while others choose to blend in with others. There is no right or wrong way to do this. No matter what choice you make, the ultimate goal is to find your own place in this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/cba1cf717be21996e7db64fffed47ee5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;789&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/cba1cf717be21996e7db64fffed47ee5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251576&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“异人”一词本身有两种释义，一种是拥有特异功能的人，另一种是被排斥的异类。而男主角张楚岚，刚好具备了这两种特性。但他一心向往的，却偏偏是做个普通人，过平凡的一生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，他足足忍了12年，为了不暴露实力，也为了活下去。但树欲静而风不止，他越想平静，却越无法平静。最终事到临头，他放弃忍耐，对异人界的真相展开探查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e75c9fa1134fb62283f569f81e90c661.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;248&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e75c9fa1134fb62283f569f81e90c661.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251578&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说前22年，身为异人却甘于平凡是一种强大，那之后正视自己的能力，选择守住尊严、有底气的活，则是另一种强大。剧所强调的并不是“异人”，而是“人”——人的选择，人与命运的对抗，以及人对真相的追索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，这并不是一部无可挑剔的剧，如果你对“中二感”本身就比较排斥，多半会接受无能。但假如你喜欢这种风格，喜欢少年热血，那它大概率能给你提供快乐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李硕：直面历史深渊，再现惊心动魄的华夏新生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256821]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;《翦商》一书在考古学界、史学界及文史爱好者圈掀起了一阵阵波澜，让作者李硕成为2023年表现最亮眼的学界新秀。李硕以极具天赋的想象力、强有力的分析和推理，依据碎片化的考古信息、零星的上古文献，推理、想象、勾连，为我们描绘出华夏文明诞生初期一种可能的全貌。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jBfKO2fDHmO3El3jxoPilMbISTLgrpdP1esrH0bD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jBfKO2fDHmO3El3jxoPilMbISTLgrpdP1esrH0bD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月15日下午4时左右，沉闷无风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我挂在一个网络工作会议，手指随意滑动了一下手机微信，一则令人愕然的“临终遗言”跃入眼帘——是两个月前相识的青年学者李硕。他说因自己朋友圈没有分组，故此发消息告知友人们：如有欠债，请联系他，至于其他留言，概不回复了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个期待数月、马上将要相见的人，忽然很可能再也没有机会见到了。之后一周，我一直处于精神恍惚状态，体味着日本茶道那句平淡至极的话——“一期一会，世当珍惜。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李硕的“生死遗言”被好事者截屏转发，加上媒体跟进，公众的关注汹涌而至。这也使得他的新作《翦商》意外“破圈”，几天内销售一空。一时间，各大图书网站上，《翦商》和李硕过去的几本著作都标注着“预售”两字。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一部天才的奇书&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自2023年初，李硕就被我们列入重点关注的学者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使后来没有发生引起公众关注的遗言事件，《翦商》一书足以让李硕成为2023年表现最亮眼的学界新秀。自2022年底出版以来，该书在考古学界、史学界及文史爱好者圈掀起一阵阵波澜。据出版方提供的数据，到2月底印数已达10万册。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前二里头考古队队长、考古学家许宏用“震撼”来描述自己读完书稿后的感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一部带着血腥气息的奇书，李硕借此揭开了华夏文明早期的一段黑暗过往。在考察新石器时代末期至商周易代时期的考古挖掘结果后，他发现：殷商时期存在着全民性、大规模、常态化的人牲血祭现象，各种虐杀、献祭的方式非常成熟；但从周代开始，这一现象突然近乎完全消失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在分析这一时期的甲骨文、金文并重新释读《周易》后，李硕认为人祭的消失与周灭商直接有关。武王灭商继而病故后，辅政的周公旦取缔了商人的人祭风俗，几乎完全抹去了有关血祭的记录和历史记忆，代之以礼、乐为核心的“德性”和“天命观”，由此再造了以和平、宽容为特征的新华夏文明，并延续至今。从此，关于人祭的历史在中原大地有长达三千多年的记忆空白。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对“商周之变”的洞察和认识，始于清末民初的王国维。他在《殷周制度论》中提出“中国政治与文化之变革,莫剧于殷周之际”的观点，并从嫡长子（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以及产生的宗法、丧服、分封等&lt;/span>;）、庙数、同姓不婚三方面论述殷周之间的差异，拉开了“商周之变”研究的序幕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《翦商》则是对静安先生之见的进一步发展。李硕紧紧围绕着“血祭人牲”，以此阐述在商周易代中，商人的神权政治何以如此激烈地变革为周朝以“德”为中心的世俗道德-政治体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;素有著述之才的李硕也展现了他出色的写作才华。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了对考古发掘中的人祭现场大型杀戮进行冷静、不动声色的还原，他还雕刻出商周易代中富有戏剧性的故事线——譬如周人曾为商王捕猎人牲的“黑历史”，文王长子伯邑考和姜太公之女邑姜之间的恋爱与婚姻，血祭给文王家族带来的黑暗记忆和伤痛，以及文王在昏暗地窖里用龟骨小心推演、谋画灭商大业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，《翦商》重新理解和塑造了周文王、周武王、周公旦等人。尤其是儒家经典里那个看起来迂阔的“道德化身”周公旦，呈现出丰富复杂的面相。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李硕早年写过《孔子大历史》，他把两位相隔五百年的儒家圣人勾连起来，并推测：孔子很可能发现了周公刻意抹去的那段血腥历史以及背后的用心。由此，颇具说服力地解释了一位春秋时代的学者何以会对周公顶礼膜拜，以及人至暮年那份“吾不复梦见周公”的伤感和沉重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQOWYvUQtlpFaN27HtwaRxiP225au4c8TbRLnN0J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQOWYvUQtlpFaN27HtwaRxiP225au4c8TbRLnN0J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李硕在巴基斯坦拉合尔市巴德夏希清真寺&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;拼图游戏超级玩家&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;第一次得知李硕这个名字，是在10年前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年起，在文史爱好者网络社群流传着一篇数万字的文章《周灭商和华夏文明的再生》，作者是李硕。其观点之新颖独特、想象之奇诡、叙事之生动给许多人留下了难忘印象，该文也成为文史圈持久热议的名帖。也因为过于奇、诡，我当时更多把它当作一篇脑洞大开的“历史可能性小说”，类似畅销书作家马伯庸早年创作的《殷商舰队玛雅征服史》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后十余年间，李硕继续探求，彻底钻进新石器时代与夏商考古的专业领域，探访考古遗址现场，并重新释读《周易》，最终将这篇充满灵感和创见的“奇文”发展为近50万字的著作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《翦商》既得到了学界权威如许宏的激赏和力荐，也在经史领域引发了不小争议——主要是质疑李硕在构建整部书的逻辑和论据中，运用推理和想象的成分过大，即所谓“脑洞太大”。一些偏保守的学界人士甚至认为：《翦商》不宜归类为严肃的学术著作，更像是一部精彩的小说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这令人不由想起一位秦汉史名家说过的话：历史记载能有不到10%留存下来，已是幸事。而文明本身还在孕育、初生期的上古时代，历史重建几乎完全依赖于零星的考古发掘结果，由此留下茫茫一片的巨大空白。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为万灵之长的我们，如此渴望了解我们的祖先和过去。当面对年代久远、记载缺乏、文物有限而难以构成完整而令人信服的叙事的现实，该如何寻找、还原我们的过去呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李硕给出了一种富有个人色彩的全新研究和书写方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《翦商》里，他就像一位摆弄拼图游戏的超级玩家：以极具天赋的想象力、强有力的分析和推理，依据碎片化的考古信息、零星的上古文献，推理、想象、勾连，为我们描绘出华夏文明诞生初期一种可能的全貌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不夸张地说，对于早期华夏文明的成型和变革，李硕拿出了一个完整而逻辑自洽、也是目前最具说服力的解释模型。正如考古学家许宏指出的：李硕的研究和书写当然不是“完美的”；但相较而言，当下很多对上古时期的研究则是无甚价值和意义的庸作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采访中，多位青年学者都认同一点：在上古史研究和书写中，《翦商》是一部真正意义上的里程碑之作。未来如有更多的考古发现和研究，他的诸多推论和想象将会得到检验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无论是证实、补充，或是部分证伪，都是很有价值的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/iBkO5ZxbWsP0L4wnSODOV8lMvFDYULlf5ApSlkLR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/iBkO5ZxbWsP0L4wnSODOV8lMvFDYULlf5ApSlkLR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;向死而生&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我和李硕相识于2023年1月，当时是为了《翦商》一书约访他。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那年冬天，李硕在巴基斯坦采风、调研，路上信号时好时坏。我提议等他回国后我们见面聊：除了通讯问题，最主要是因为我在《翦商》之外有很多想和他交流的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对李硕和他的文字了解得越多，就越发地好奇：一位原本出身主流精英、怀抱天赋的青年学者，完全可以拥有一种更舒适从容、更易功成名就的人生，为何选择一条如此边缘、艰辛、危险的歧路——他也自嘲是个“不着家的无赖汉”，常年游荡在外，年届四十，没房没车没票子，时有生计之累。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李硕生于1977年，本科就读于北大文科实验班，做过数年记者，后入清华大学历史系硕博连读。博士毕业时，他完全有机会在内地大城市高校拥有教职，却跑到边疆地区谋职。工作之余，他常年游走于外喜马拉雅和南亚，那里是地缘政治的敏感地带，民族、宗教、军事冲突频繁发生。在旅途中，他被当地军警当可疑分子盘问、“贴靠”，但也由此结识了一些有趣的新朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年春节，巴基斯坦国内爆发危机、局势骤然紧张。朋友们都为他路上的安危担心，他每天记录跟沿途军警打交道的“囧途”遭遇，谈笑中颇不以为意，直至他突然失联、消失了十多天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我当时有很不好的预感，觉得他有生命危险。”他的一位朋友回忆说——后来得知李硕在路上突然病倒、昏迷，在当地抢救之后被紧急送回国内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与他相交颇深的青年学者张诗坪说：李硕并非单纯的冒险家，他之所以常年在那些看上去不安定的地域游历，是出于对史上丝绸之路以及对多元文化、种族交汇地带的兴趣和热情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“事实上，他的研究和写作路径，正是继承了东西方自古以来的历史书写传统。无论是西方的&#39;历史之父&#39;希罗多德，还是中国的司马迁，在交通不便捷、旅行充满危险的古代，他们都是四处游历、实地勘察的。”“在交通、通讯这么便捷的今天，很多历史研究和写作者倒丢弃了这一传统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李硕的心很野，他的情怀很大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十多年来，他一直用生命行走、思考和写作。在写作《翦商》的几年里，因为长时间面对那段极为血腥暴力的黑暗历史，李硕一度陷入抑郁状态。他的朋友、游记作家随水认为：这很可能是导致他患上凶险之疾的主要因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年对李硕而言，是极不平凡的一年。在这场个人劫难中，他面对生死的坦然和淡泊，让很多认识他或不认识他的人心生敬意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与死神擦肩而过，他的身体和精神状态在手术后有明显好转，目前一边接受治疗，一边开始动笔写他准备已久的一本新书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“《诗经•彼阳》”引人爆笑之余：伪诗伪文何以走红网络？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257308]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一起“伪诗事件”引发关注。华中师大历史文化学院公众号发表了一篇宣传文章，刊出了一名学生参加军训时的感想，“接受采访时则用《诗经•彼阳》来表达自己的感受”，随即全文登出了这首“《诗经•彼阳》”：“彼阳若至，初升东曦。绯雾飒蔽，似幕绡绸。彼阳篝碧，雾霂涧滁。赤石冬溪，似玛瑙潭。 彼阳晚意，暖梦似乐。寐游浮沐，若雉飞舞。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文章刊出之后，引发全网爆笑群嘲：所谓的《诗经•彼阳》根本就不存在，这首诗根本就是今人伪作，且已在网上流传多时。受访学生“引用”这首“彼阳”，意在以“谐音梗”吐槽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;舆论发酵后，华中师大历史文化学院公众号很快删除了这篇文章。 9月19日，学院在《情况说明》中表示“把关不严，一篇推文造成不良影响，深表歉意”，“学院深刻检讨，已对相关人员予以批评教育”，并将“深入开展问题整改”“举一反三”“加强学生教育引导”“加强公众号管理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事在引人爆笑之际也带出了一个问题，那就是这种“伪诗伪文”的内在机理与前世今生：它们因何出现，又如何走红？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，伪诗伪文在互联网兴起之初就已出现，并在新媒体时代得以“发扬光大”。比如韩寒在小说《三重门》里提过的那首“卧梅又闻花，卧知绘中天。鱼吻卧石水，卧石答春绿”，曾引发不少笑谈，还有不少“改编”“再创作”，转发者在不经意间就着了道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“起于网络，著者不详”往往是这些伪诗伪文的一大特征。多数伪诗伪文都是在网络上快速传播，根本找不到作者是谁。原因也很简单，因为这些“诗文”本来就是要伪托古人而作，真正的作者自然要隐匿身份。互联网兴起之初的天然“匿名性”，更是伪诗伪文得以兴盛的天然土壤。互联网孕育了大量的伪诗伪文，伪诗伪文也因互联网而广为传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不胫而走，不觉其伪，这是伪诗伪文的又一大特征。尤其是，伪诗伪文可以在不经意间让高学历人士都被骗得云里雾里，在2009年的“《战国策》事件”中，上海某博士接受采访时脱口而出“&#39;卧槽泥马&#39;一词出自《战国策》，形容虚有其表、窃据名位者”，也引来网上一片哗然。其实，这句话出自的所谓“《战国策•楚策》”纯属网友的恶搞段子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古已有之，至今不衰，伪诗伪文写的是此时此刻的现实事物，但要刻意包装上一层文言的外衣，以谐音、双关、藏头、藏尾等修辞方式完成。也就是说，其投射的对象虽是当代，但其文法与修辞却是不折不扣的“古已有之”，而其“伪托之术”更是古人早就熟用的手法。 “《诗经•彼阳》”从效果来看还契合了《诗经》的真义，“《诗》可以兴，可以观，可以群，可以怨”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在著名的“高考满分作文”《赤兔之死》中，作文者巧用《三国演义》的“人设”，敷陈以“诚信”大义，本质上也是一篇上乘的“伪诗伪文”，而其伪托之术无疑还要比前述案例高明得多，甚至颇有苏轼杜撰典故“皋陶为士，将杀人。皋陶曰杀之三，尧曰宥之三”的神韵：上古没有这个典故，但苏轼的杜撰无疑符合尧的“人设”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伪诗伪文因互联网勃兴走红，却也终将因为技术迭代注定衰落。比如网上李白的伪诗层出不穷，社会上不乏有知名文学教授亲自出马，依据平仄、押韵来鉴定此诗，也有不少网民“翻遍《李太白全集》”以求证真伪；“《战国策》事件”也惊动了文学教授来证伪这段伪托文章。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在今天，各种大语言模型已经横空出世，人工智能的强大算力既可以成规模地制造类似伪诗伪文，也可以轻而易举地爬梳古代文献、鉴定真伪。 “《诗经•彼阳》”已经流传多年，资深网民也练就了“一眼假”的鉴别能力。此次公号小编被骗得云里雾里，只能说他本人的网络“段位”有待提高，也没有利用好丰富的网络资源做好辨别工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《世说新语•排调》载，“习凿齿、孙兴公未相识，同在桓公坐。桓语孙：&#39;可与习参军共语。&#39;孙云：&#39;蠢尔蛮荆，敢与大邦为仇？&#39;习云：&#39;薄伐猃狁，至于太原。&#39;”孙绰嘲笑习凿齿是出身楚地的“蛮荆”，习凿齿反唇相讥孙绰籍贯是匈奴人出没的太原，这里两人各自引用了一首《诗经•小雅》，恰到好处而又机锋暗藏，足见《诗经》的永恒魅力。伪诗伪文终究无法再像之前那样让人轻易上钩，但古典诗文衍生的文化趣味仍将延续下去，无论它是这种单纯的谐音骂人，还是更高段位的“以诗相戏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20家银行净利占A股1/3强，“利润王”对抗息差压力分化加剧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;中国A股市场“利润王”——主要商业银行正面临空前的盈利压力，因为整体息差已降至历史低位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但中国人民银行自2023年9月15日起实施2023年内第二次降准，一定程度上缓解了商业银行负债成本，而此前两度非对称降息也适度保护了商业银行的利差空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管央行呵护心态毕现，但在2023年复杂而特殊的经济情势下，商业银行盈利能力正备受考验。哪些银行韧劲较强？哪些银行四面受压？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员以各商业银行2023年中报为基准，对资产规模在2万亿元及以上的国内20家大银行（其中18家获评2022年度国内系统重要性银行）进行纵向和横向比较研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次研究所指国内20家大型商业银行（文中均称为“20家银行”）包括6大国有商业银行（工、农、中、建、交、邮储）、9家全国性股份制商业银行（招商、兴业、中信、光大、浦发、平安、华夏、民生、浙商）和5家城市商业银行（北京银行、宁波银行、上海银行、江苏银行、南京银行），其资产规模均超2万亿元。（因未披露半年报，广发银行未被纳入此次统计分析。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在上述对比研究的基础上，南方周末新金融研究中心研究员还调研国内大型券商银行研究团队，并结合各银行中期业绩发布会（既包括媒体发布会，也包括投资者交流会），深度分析上述银行的核心经营指标异动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究发现，在上半年货币政策稳健偏宽松的背景下，20家大银行整体营收同比下滑3.9%，且个别银行面临资本压力。从影响因素看，息差缩小是主要拖累项，但净息差降幅边际已收窄。20家银行净利润却同比上升3.3%，主要系不良率下降，拨备反哺利润所致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在国有行、股份行和城商行三个梯队之中，各银行对抗周期的竞争力已呈现明显分化状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;规模和拨备&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;VS&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;息差&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;城商行净利增速最高&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员统计20家银行中报数据得知，2023年上半年，20家银行营业收入合计2.92万亿元，同比减少3.8%，但净利润不降反升，归母净利润高达1.03万亿元，同比增加2.9%。而A股市场所有公司同期归母净利润合计2.95万亿，20家银行净利占A股所有上市公司净利1/3强，可谓真正意义上的“利润王”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/h6rabkaDOJa8s94SO41VwKdKJeAyVlPlmwxcY0mw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;577&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/h6rabkaDOJa8s94SO41VwKdKJeAyVlPlmwxcY0mw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从规模看，国有行占绝对优势。上半年，6大国有行平均营收约3078亿元，平均归母净利润1150亿元；9家股份行平均营收894亿元，平均归母净利润300亿元；5家城商行平均营收310亿元，平均归母净利润135亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有行、股份行和城商行均呈现明显的分化趋势。比如，国有行中的工行净利润为1747.20亿，交行则为465.55亿；股份制行中的招行为764.37亿，浙商银行则为79.65亿；城商行中的江苏银行净利润高达176.26亿，超过了不少股份行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅增速一项，城商行表现更优。上半年，5家城商行营收同比增加3.4%，归母净利润同比增加10.9%。而6大国有行和9家股份行营收同比下滑，利润同比微增。其中，6大国有行营收同比下降4.8%，归母净利润同比增加2.5%；9家股份行营收同比下降2.7%，归母净利润同比增加2.0%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员对各大券商银行研究团队调研发现，从业绩影响因素看，规模是主要驱动力，其次为拨备，而息差是主要拖累项，其次是成本。据中信建投证券测算，规模增长正向贡献净利润12.2%，拨备计提和其他非息分别正向贡献净利润4.4%和2.2%；而息差缩窄和营业支出加大是主要拖累项，分别拖累利润下降13.2%和2.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特别值得注意的是江苏银行。该行2023年上半年归母净利润增速同比达到27.2%，且营收增速达到10.6%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/2g1Shb7xfx5xkjvO84lmRoEouIspBIYAzur2KeL0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/2g1Shb7xfx5xkjvO84lmRoEouIspBIYAzur2KeL0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这与江苏银行注重小微业务的经营策略密切有关。该行中报显示，小微贷款余额6250亿元，占贷款总额比例为35.80%。与此同时，江苏银行不良贷款率0.91%，较上年末下降0.03个百分点；拨备覆盖率378.09%，较上年末提升6.43个百分点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江苏银行为何能在快速增长的同时保持不良率下降？从内部看，一是江苏银行重视金融科技，提出打造“最具互联网大数据基因的银行”战略，行长兼任首席信息官。二是渠道网点分布广。江苏银行在江苏省内有460家遍布县域的营业网点，熟知当地经济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在外部生态中，江苏强劲的民营经济是该行发展的基础。截至2022年末，江苏省私营企业和个体工商户累计1360.8万户，占全省经营主体比重达96.4%。2022年全省民营经济增加值达7.1万亿元，占江苏省GDP比重达57.7%，对全省GDP增长贡献率由上年的63.1%提高到72.2%。这点在南方周末新金融研究中心“苏州金融生态深调研”系列中亦可得到印证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;商业银行规模扩张往往伴随着资本消耗。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员发现，总体而言，商业银行核心一级资本充足率仍然较高，但少数银行面临一定的资本压力。如股份行的中信、华夏和浙商银行，其核心一级资本充足率逼近监管红线。但根据&lt;span>;证监会&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;最近发布的“救市&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;组合拳&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;证监会最近对商业银行融资持谨慎态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;企业贷款占比提升&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;经营贷成&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;个贷新&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;增&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;主力&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;存贷业务是银行的基础业务，资产扩表是银行重要的增长策略。2023年上半年，20家银行总资产260.04万亿，同比增长11.9%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/RyZrGgDlIodsSjTWd8XENxoij9sZk8IT0zjwnKvY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/RyZrGgDlIodsSjTWd8XENxoij9sZk8IT0zjwnKvY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从资产结构看，6大国有行整体相对稳定；9家股份行金融投资占比提升、贷款略有下降，同业资产分化；5家城商行差异较大。宁波银行和南京银行资产占比同比分别上升1.95%、1.39%，北京银行金融投资占比同比增加5.4%，上海银行存放同业同比增加28.8%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从贷款结构看，呈现零售贷款占比下降，企业贷款占比提升的特征。2023年上半年，20家银行企业贷款占比为57.89%，同比上升3.8%，零售贷款占比为37.60%，同比下降6.0%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员发现，其主要原因是政策驱动下，大基建和核心制造业等信贷需求率先复苏，而零售贷款受居民收入水平和消费意愿拖累，有效需求不高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在零售贷款中，按揭贷款占比下降，经营贷成为主要贷款增加来源。从披露经营贷数据的银行看，2023年上半年，国有行中，建行、工行和交行分别同比增加98.2%、44.8%和39.1%；而在股份行中，兴业银行同比增加26.4%；城商行中的上海银行和江苏银行同比分别增加60.8%和53.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经营贷利率较低是其增加迅速的原因之一。经营贷是否违规流向其它用途一直备受关注。央行、国家金融监督管理总局在8月31日联合发布的《关于调整优化差别化住房信贷政策的通知》和《关于降低存量首套住房贷款利率有关事项的通知》中明确表示，降低存量房贷利率“还可压缩违规使用经营贷、消费贷置换存量住房贷款的空间”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，目前经营贷利率依然低于房贷利率，借款人依然有置换空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;存款定期化延续&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;国际化竞争力待提升&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在优质资产较少的情况下，银行管理负债成本的任务迫切而现实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心对比研究发现，负债端存款定期化延续，主要是个人存款定期化占比提高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年上半年，20家大银行中，对公定期存款出现分化。从增速看，农业银行、工商银行和建设银行增速较快。但个人定期存款占比普遍上升。其中，兴业银行同比上升最多，达到45.4%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/kmKuJtGFXhLoifcQne7694knOWVsg7jXlc1s8rSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/kmKuJtGFXhLoifcQne7694knOWVsg7jXlc1s8rSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，短期来看，银行资产扩表与上半年货币政策稳健偏松有关，稳增长措施持续出台，实体经济部门开始加杠杆。数据显示，杠杆率由2022年末大幅提升10.8pcts，商业银行整体实现了扩表提速。但从长期来看，中国银行业需要改善收入结构。对比海外，中国银行业的营收主要靠资产业务扩张来实现，轻资本的非息收入占比仍然不高。中国银行业需要进一步强化在金融市场、财富管理、投资银行、交易银行等方面的产品创新、人才培养和业务开拓能力，进一步提升非息业务创收水平，提升资本回报率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大型银行还需提升国际化业务能力。以工行为例。财报显示，工行连续十一年位列英国《银行家》全球银行1000强榜单榜首，连续十一年位列美国《财富》500强榜单全球商业银行首位，连续七年位列英国Brand Finance全球银行品牌价值500 强榜单榜首。但工行主要依赖于国内业务市场的支撑，国际化程度和国际业务竞争力落后于排名靠前的欧美日大型银行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据显示，截至6月末，工行已在49个国家和地区建立了415家境外机构。但工行境外机构总资产仅占集团总资产的7.3%。其中，港澳地区资产占境外机构资产46.41%。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;净息差降幅收窄&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在优质资产稀缺和存款定期化的双重夹击下，银行息差降至历史新低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究发现，2023年上半年，20家银行中，农业银行息差同比降幅最大，减少36BP，南京银行降幅最小，仅下降2BP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5xSlElZOjPJajX05FgPbOhhrSycH1ooUOr7BvJqs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;583&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5xSlElZOjPJajX05FgPbOhhrSycH1ooUOr7BvJqs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央行数据显示，2022年，我国商业银行的净息差为1.91%，2023年上半年甚至低至1.74%，连续两个季度低于基准线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但净息差收窄趋势在减缓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;短期来看，主要受益于政策驱动下的资产和负债两端压力缓解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;资产端利率下行压力有望减轻。央行二季度货币执行报告指出“商业银行维持稳健经营、防范金融风险，需保持合理利润和净息差水平。这样也有利于增强商业银行支持实体经济的可持续性”，2023年二季度新发企业贷款利率环比持平为3.95%，新发按揭利率环比略降3BP至4.11%，降幅已逐渐收窄。8月31日，存量首套房贷利率政策正式落地，规定调整后房贷利率不得低于“原贷款发放时”“所在城市”首套房贷款利率政策下限。这体现了央行对商业银行息差的呵护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;银行负债端成本也调降。9月1日，国有行和多数股份行年内第三次主动下调人民币存款挂牌利率，中长期存款利率下调幅度较大，将有效对冲存量首套房贷利率下调影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，银行对净息差目标的设定，应该在自身风险偏好范围内进行合理规划，因为信用风险偏好对商业银行净息差水平有着直接影响。在利率市场化和金融脱媒的环境下，负债成本相对刚性，同时传统大企业客户表内信贷需求出现萎缩，银行迫切需要寻找新的信贷增长点，如小企业贷款、小微贷款和消费贷款等。尽管此类贷款定价水平偏高，但其信用风险也相对较高。因此银行不能为追求短期提升净息差而提高风险偏好。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不良率改善，拨备回升&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在各商业银行的中期业绩发布会或投资者交流会上，社会各界对房企开发贷和地方平台贷等可能引发的不良率上升普遍担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，银行整体不良率改善，拨备覆盖率稳定。2023年上半年，20家银行不良贷款率几乎全部下降，仅有平安银行不良贷款率上升1BP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20家银行拨备覆盖率整体健康。仅有邮储银行、宁波银行和上海银行同比降幅较大，但基数仍然较高，系银行主动反哺利润所致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/hEBOcg8EYODEm1gDCDMAufgCOiO6z7piSlZLzGPU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/hEBOcg8EYODEm1gDCDMAufgCOiO6z7piSlZLzGPU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;房地产不良率较年初延续上行。其中，6大国有行房地产不良率平均数为4.46%，为各类银行最高；股份行则上升最为明显；而城商行受影响更小，主要是对房地产涉足不多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种情况下，银行通过发行不良资产证券化产品进行指标管理和资产负债表调节的需求趋于增加。根据Wind 统计，2023 年上半年不良贷款资产支持证券共发行47单，发行总规模为200.98亿元，同比分别增加67.86%和89.07%。同期，银行间市场信贷资产证券化产品发行单数和发行规模分别为86单和1538.48亿元，不良贷款资产支持证券的占比分别升至54.65%和13.06%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此可见，不良贷款率下降系银行主动管理所致。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中收&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;延续&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;负增&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;保险成为热门&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;利息收入之外，各商业银行最近几年一直把非息中间业务收入作为战略重点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但上半年这块收入难如人意。其主要原因是居民投资意愿偏低。银行代销基金和理财收入等业务收入下滑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;银行业理财登记托管中心发布的《中国银行业理财市场半年报告（2023年上）》数据显示，2023年上半年银行业理财产品存续规模较年初减少2.4万亿至25.3万亿，依然处于下滑阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从营收结构看，交通银行、招商银行、宁波银行和兴业银行的非利息收入占比营收较高，均超35%。其中交通银行和招商银行的非息收入主要来自于手续费，兴业银行和宁波银行的非息收入则主要由交易类资产投资收益所贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/NfhzU102CgEo6B3y4VDXZsTj5qGqM3962B5NwVxB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/NfhzU102CgEo6B3y4VDXZsTj5qGqM3962B5NwVxB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从增速看，招商银行手续费及佣金收入同比下滑11.8%，但代理保险收入同比增长3.07%，达到92.60亿元。这反映出居民倾向于将资金配置在保险产品。其中，兴业银行、平安银行上半年代理保险收入同比增长分别为123.47%、107.2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这与预定利率为3.5%的增额终身寿险在6月底被要求下架有关。高预定利率产品在当前情况有较强吸引力。但随着高预定利率寿险产品下架及监管机构持续整肃银保渠道手续费，银行下半年代理保险的手续费收入或不及上半年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，居民配置资产呈现一定顺周期性，当股市、房市前景低迷或严监管打压某一类收益可观的存量资产时，居民投资保险的规模会大幅上升。但我国居民家庭资产配置中国房产占比仍然较高，金融资产也以保本型的存款和固定收益类理财产品为主。从海外居民资产配置发展历程看，未来国内居民金融资产配置结构将更加多元化，权益类、产业基金和另类资产等资产种类配置比重将逐步提升。一方面，房产投资需求将会逐步回归理性；另一方面，理财刚性兑付被打破，存款利率调降，居民迫切需要优质理财产品。商业银行应加大创新力度，开发更优质的理财产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>