<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTp OzxQVWlMy0o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009), a contemporary master of rituals and a famous Confucian scholar, dedicated his life to Studying the study of the three rites, he has made outstanding achievements in many fields such as etiquette, history of Confucian classics, philology, inscriptions on oracle bones, bibliography, and compilation of ancient books. In particular, the study of the &quot;three rites&quot; has solved many problems in the history of etiquette and Confucian classics. Many unresolved problems were highly praised by Gu Jiegang. The picture was taken in May 1986. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009) was an &quot;invisible man&quot; at Hangzhou University. In October 1978, I entered the Chinese Department as an undergraduate student. He once gave us a few lectures on &quot;Common Knowledge of Ancient Culture&quot; in the &quot;Ancient Chinese&quot; class, but no one had much impression of him. When I was in graduate school, he was a member of the mentor group, and I started to get to know him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The headquarters of Hangzhou University (today’s Xixi Campus of Zhejiang University) in the early 1980s was small in area. Tall plane trees stretched out towards the boulevard, forming domes, showing the history of this campus. years. In the southeast corner are several rows of four-story buildings made of blue-grey bricks. The teachers&#39; dormitory and the graduate student dormitory face each other. Between the two floors is the boiler room, where the fire roars in the morning and we go there every day to turn on the water. In autumn and winter, the sycamore leaves have faded to gray, and the walkways of the boiler room are covered with finely crushed coal ash. Against the blue-grey brick walls, the vision is gray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Mr. Shen lived in a room on the first floor of the first unit of Building No. 1, about fifteen or six square meters, opposite the public toilet. It was humid in spring, sultry in summer, and cold in winter. . There was no kitchen, so he could only light a fire in the corridor, so for more than 20 years, he had been eating in the canteen, occasionally cooking hoof bones and the like to improve his life. It wasn&#39;t until 1986 that he was assigned a two-bedroom house and moved out of here (in July of that year, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor by the State Council&#39;s Discipline Review Group). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have never entered his residence, but every time I pass by, I will stop for a moment. Later, I visited his door many times in my dreams. Through the glass above the door, I seemed to see the banners on the wall, but I couldn&#39;t always see clearly what was inside. It was like his personality and education were very mysterious and hard to see clearly. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I often meet him on the way to the cafeteria. He was over sixty years old at that time, with a broad forehead, sparse hair, and a gray beard, but his face was very rosy. He is not tall, but very strong. In winter, he put on an old gray smock over his old cotton-padded jacket, and carried a shallow bamboo basket in his left hand, which also looked like a dustpan. His big hands had thick knuckles. He always had a smile on his face and seemed to be moving as he walked on the road, making a slight &quot;huffing&quot; sound in his mouth. If he encounters the gaze of others, he responds with a smile in his eyes, his mouth seems to be moving, but he does not speak. He looked gentle and calm, yet as deep as the ocean. He beams with energy when he smiles, inspiring passers-by. So I think he was in a good mood at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we &quot;new&quot; graduate students often talked about at that time was our own supervisors and each other&#39;s supervisors: which field we mainly worked in, what books we published, where we published papers, and what we heard about them. What are the requirements for students, what are the mantras, what new things were said in class...proudly introduce the findings of the instructor, share with each other, and listen carefully to other people&#39;s additions and discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Roommate Chen Shenyong is the first graduate student led by Mr. Shen Wenzhuo. My understanding of Mr. Shen gradually enriched through classmate Sheng Yong’s admiring explanations and everyone’s discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Fang Jianxin, Mr. Shen, Li Jiemin, Wang Yunlu (photographed in 1997). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo, whose courtesy name is Fengsheng and nickname is Yinan, is from Wujiang, Jiangsu. He entered a private school when he was young, and studied by himself when he was older, without obtaining any diploma. In his early years, he studied ancient Chinese poetry from Shen Chang, and studied literature and history from Jin Tianhe and Yao Tingjie. In the early 1940s, he specialized in the study of &quot;Three Rites&quot; from Cao Yuanbi and became his close disciple, teaching and mentoring him for nine years. Cao Yuanbi (1867-1954), known as the last outstanding Confucian scholar of the Qing Dynasty, was already in his seventies, so he placed high hopes on Shen Wenzhuo: &quot;If you observe well, you can expect success.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1946, he published He wrote articles such as &quot;Shuo Gao Le&quot; and &quot;Wax&quot; and &quot;Wax&quot;, which attracted Gu Jiegang&#39;s attention, and he was hired as the deputy editor and reviewer of the National Translation and Translation Center. He was mainly responsible for proofreading classics, compiling summaries, and drafting classics dictionaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, he was sent to study at the Political College of North China People&#39;s Revolutionary University in Beijing. In June of the following year, he was assigned to Shanghai Library as deputy director of the Cataloging Department. The &quot;Zhongshu Zonglu&quot; we often consult, which is three very thick volumes and is more than a foot high when stacked, was compiled under his leadership. In 1960, the editorial team of &quot;Zonglu&quot; was rated as an advanced collective in Shanghai. As the team leader, he attended the Shanghai Heroes Meeting as a representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 1963, at the invitation of Professor Jiang Liangfu, he was transferred to the Language and Literature Research Office of the Zhejiang Branch of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (located at Hangzhou University, with Xia Chengtao as the director) as a full-time researcher and went to Hangzhou alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March, as soon as I arrived in Hangzhou, I went to pay a visit to Mr. Ma Yifu; in late April, I went again. &quot;From now on, we will learn to pay homage to our predecessors and scholars, and when we meet each other, we should treat relatives with respect and be harmonious.&quot; I had some enlightenment and thought, and wrote &quot;Jiangzhuang Wen Xue Ji&quot; to record it. After autumn, he went to the Northeastern Institute of Literature and History in Changchun to teach &quot;Etiquette&quot; and returned to Hangzhou in the winter. I wanted to visit again, but I couldn&#39;t. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following year, &quot;the trend of talking about ancient studies came to an abrupt end, and the interest was greatly reduced.&quot; Soon, I went to the countryside to participate in the &quot;Social Education Movement&quot; and stayed in a commune in my hometown of Zhuji County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, he had published many papers in &quot;Archaeology&quot; (1961, 1963). It is said that Mr. Guo Moruo, then president of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, spoke highly of him after seeing him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; occurred, the research office was disbanded, and he transferred to the Chinese Department of Hangzhou University and worked as a document clerk in the department&#39;s reference room. Because of his extensive knowledge and strong memorization, his colleagues were shocked to call him a &quot;walking dictionary&quot;. He lived alone in silence, but never stopped studying etiquette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1974, he was arranged to go to Anji to participate in the &quot;Agricultural and Forestry Class&quot; of the last &quot;May 7th&quot; Cadre School of Hangzhou University. He worked as a &quot;Duck Commander&quot; during the day and explored the secrets of etiquette at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 1975, four types of works, including the &quot;Review of the Han Bamboo Bamboo Bamboo Slips Unearthed in Wuwei&quot;, were sent to Mr. Gu Jiegang for review. Gu Fuxin said that &quot;Taituan is actually the first person in the contemporary world to organize the Book of Rites&quot;, but at the same time he lamented that he didn&#39;t know when these results would be available. The above words were only circulated within a small circle at that time and were not known to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gu Jiegang replied to Shen Wenzhuo&#39;s letter. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, the situation had changed again. In 1979, he transferred to teaching position. The following year, he was rated as an associate researcher at the age of 64. Our 1982 graduate student is his first enrollment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Hangzhou University highly regarded the &quot;Literature and History&quot; of Zhonghua Book Company and the &quot;Chinese Literature and History Series&quot; of Shanghai Ancient Books as the top journals in the field of ancient literature and history, and Mr. Shen was a frequent reader. Among them, &quot;A Brief Discussion on the Practice of Rituals and the Writing of Books on Rituals&quot; (Wenshi, Series 15 and 16, 1983) states that &quot;the practice of rituals existed earlier than written records&quot;, thus clarifying the relationship between rituals and ritual books. Mr. Yang Xiangkui later called this article &quot;a monumental work with unprecedented achievements.&quot; Another example is the article &quot;The Enrollment of the Twelve Doctors of Huanglong and the Establishment of the Taixue Prefecture and State School&quot; (1983), which analyzes the complex historical facts of the establishment of the Doctor of Confucianism in the Han Dynasty, corrects the mistakes in Pi Xirui&#39;s &quot;History of Confucian Studies&quot;, and corrects Wang Guowei&#39;s &quot;Han and Wei&quot; &quot;Doctoral Examination&quot;, thus making a detailed analysis of the rise, fall, increase and lack of doctorates in the three dynasties of Wu, Zhao and Xuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Referred to as a later scholar, Mr. Shen&#39;s articles have a very broad vision. They have both macroscopic concerns, covering ancient and modern times, and microscopic research, and are as meticulous as hair. At the same time, various methods are used to contain materials, and the amount of information is huge. He has unique insights into almost any issue in traditional etiquette, and almost every sentence in his article embodies the result of his thinking. His narrative language is very elegant and can be almost seamlessly connected with the cited documents, which is a state that is difficult to achieve. I also deeply agree with this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, I did not seriously read Mr. Shen’s works and papers at that time, and I was afraid to read them because they were too profound. I have only read his column in &quot;Chinese Literature and History&quot;, titled &quot;The Secret of Rituals&quot;. Sometimes several articles are published in one issue, and the length is only one or two pages, and the explanation is one word or one thing. , are all explanations of difficult issues, and are of great relevance to the study of literature and history. The elegant and concise writing impressed me endlessly. He has been writing this kind of short essays since 1946, and he has accumulated a lot of copper from the mountains. Many years later, he compiled it into a book, still named as a column. It was only a thin volume with more than 100,000 words, but it was well received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo is in the study. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I started learning to write papers, I knew that short papers were the most difficult to write because they were hundreds of words long. , more than a thousand words, how difficult it is to ask a real question, list the materials and explain it clearly! It is said that Mr. Shen&#39;s other book, &quot;An Interpretation of Different Texts on Chinese Bamboo Slips of &quot;Li&quot;&quot;, had more than 400,000 words when it was written. He was not in a hurry to publish it and repeatedly compressed it. When it was finally published, it only had 160,000 words. When we were graduate students (1982.9-1985.6), except for some papers, he had no published works. His first monograph, &quot;An Examination of Zongzhou Rites and Music Civilization,&quot; is actually a collection of his essays. It was only published in 1999. The writing spanned more than 40 years, and the total number was only 14 articles. He was already an octogenarian by then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen has always been indifferent to fame and fortune. He said: &quot;It is not easy to manage the classics and rituals. Only when the mind is clear of &#39;devil obstacles&#39; and the mind is as clear as water, can one focus on learning and become more general.&quot; In fact, he did not write much in his life, but scholars praised him as &quot;the master of rituals.&quot; , because his articles do not rely on accumulation of quantity, but win on quality. Each of his articles solves an unsolved problem in history. Cumulatively, it is breathtaking and even more admirable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We are very fortunate that Mr. Shen opened a class specifically for us. At that time, we were five graduate students, guided by five tutors. Each of them taught three classes, which constituted a semester&#39;s graduate course. Even Teacher Guo Zaiyi attended his three classes and sat in the back row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen has suffered from a severe stutter since he was a child. It is very difficult for him to even speak a complete sentence. This is why he rarely attends classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The content the teachers taught at that time was self-selected and derived from years of deep thinking. In my impression, Mr. Shen Wenzhuo talked about issues related to various schools of thought in the pre-Qin period and ancient and modern texts. In my limited knowledge at that time, &quot;Lun&quot;, &quot;Mencius&quot;, &quot;Lao&quot; and &quot;Zhuang&quot; were independent writings, and I had a little dabbling in them. I had never read &quot;Mozi&quot;, and I dared not touch &quot;Li&quot; and &quot;Shu&quot;. As for each There is no understanding of the relationship between families. Mr. Shen&#39;s class revealed the intricate relationships between various schools of thought, especially the Jixia School and the famous schools. These schools, which had few works handed down to the world, used to dominate the competition with other schools, making other schools Each school had to respond and adjust; some schools that disappeared had their doctrines integrated by other schools and passed down to later generations. This made me suddenly understand that each argument was not a complete and systematic explanation of a certain theory, but an expression of its own views on the opponent. If you don&#39;t know the background of this debate, you will feel that its argument is extremely biased, like It&#39;s fighting against the air, I don&#39;t know why. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is very much like when I play center on the basketball court. Every time I hit hard, I have to push the person behind me away so that I can turn over and score the ball. You have to know how powerful the &quot;top&quot; is to understand how much effort it takes for me to &quot;rely on&quot;. If the person behind me is blurred, and people only see me turning backwards and forward into the air, they will definitely laugh at me for using too much brute force, which is the so-called &quot;biased approach&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our classroom, Mr. Shen burst out each word from his mouth vigorously. Some words took him two or three times to complete, so he wiped the sweat with a handkerchief. Still mouthing. When he talks about happy things, he will also chuckle. He first used his own research and explanation to redefine the old concepts, and then extended them to put forward new definitions for a series of issues. As a result, the related characters, events, schools and theories were swept away from the long-accumulated dust and revealed. A completely different appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all listened attentively, lest we miss a syllable. Because the words that burst out one by one were like formation symbols flying in the air, forming a wonderful formation from which the truth of history emerged. The formation was so turbulent, with forces coming and going, waves vying with each other, sounds and principles echoing each other. This was the era of a hundred schools of thought contending! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than forty years have passed, and Mr. Shen’s specific explanation left only a few impressions on me. For example, “Book of Rites” is later than “Lidian”; &quot;Jinwen&quot; refers to Han Li, who explains the inheritance of various texts in the Han Dynasty from the perspective of the characters used in writing the texts; someone&#39;s interpretation is established as an academic official, which is &quot;learning from the law&quot; before it is established. , it is &quot;Family Law&quot;... Most of the other specific knowledge has been forgotten now. Only his &quot;chichi&quot; voice occasionally still rings in my ears, so the feeling caused by his explanation came again. It flowed through my brain like a tide, making me feel an inexplicable shock. More importantly, through these explanations, I understand that I must look through the surface of documents to feel the &quot;forces&quot; and their interactions behind the times, in order to vaguely see the &quot;invisible hand&quot; of God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After meeting Mr. Ma Yifu, Mr. Shen wrote a poem:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Confucian Classics and Interpretation Canon 1 Furnace melting, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Prove that the mind is the same and the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Goodness, beauty, depth and subtle appearance can be understood in different ways,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shu Xu&#39;s rituals and music are harmonious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also recorded: &quot;Mr. (Ma) knew about Yu&#39;s etiquette for treating Ji Dan, and he expressed the purpose of the etiquette, kindness and beauty, and was amazed by it. I also introduced the meaning of &#39;Shu Xu&#39;, No matter how hard you look at Mr. Shen, don’t dismiss him with different opinions.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now I recall Mr. Shen’s three classes, record every bit of what I saw and heard at that time, and respectfully take his last sentence as title to express my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解聘247名自聘科级干部：萍乡经开区“瘦身”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPA zbx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone was established in 1992 and upgraded to a national-level economic and technological development in 2010 district. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a major choice in my life.&quot; In April 2023, Zhang Shichun chose Give up his status within the system and stay to work in a large state-owned enterprise in Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone, Jiangxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, he had worked in this state-owned enterprise for 4 years, but retained the establishment of a public institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone announced the cancellation of 19 self-established institutions and the dismissal of 247 self-employed section-level cadres based on the personnel system reform plan adopted by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A considerable part of the dismissed personnel were originally on-staff personnel. After their self-employed positions in the Economic and Technological Development Zone are dismissed, they can choose to retain the establishment and have the Economic and Technological Development Zone coordinate the arrangement of new jobs, or they can Give up the establishment and work in an enterprise. The dismissed persons who were originally non-staff personnel can participate in the full-scale competition for recruitment, or they can choose to resign. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun is a department-level cadre self-employed by Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. Facing the reform, he has two choices. Abandon the establishment.&quot; After a family meeting, he decided to stay in the business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons why Zhang Shichun became a self-employed cadre are not complicated. As one of the earliest economic development zones established in China, after 31 years of development, the population of Pingxiang Economic Development Zone has increased from the initial 10,000 to about 250,000 now, and its functions have also expanded from solely economic development to taking into account social management and public affairs. Services, etc., have set up their own management agencies, established their own positions, and hired their own personnel during the development process. This has both objective reasons and subjective reasons such as previous organizational establishment management was not standardized and personnel were highly arbitrary. This is also a common phenomenon in domestic development zones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot;, clarifying that both the central and local governments must streamline their staffing. On this basis, many places have begun to clear out non-staff personnel. Harbin City in Heilongjiang Province, Shiyan City in Hubei Province, Chuxiong Prefecture in Yunnan Province, Huizhou City in Guangdong Province, Zhuzhou City in Hunan Province and other places have introduced plans to clear out non-staff personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingxiang Economic Development Zone has comprehensively standardized personnel management. Among the 247 dismissed cadres, 63 people who were illegally borrowed were dismissed, 17 people were dismissed, and another 8 people gave up their business establishment to work in enterprises. After the reform, all employees will implement &quot;host management&quot; (a personnel management method in which staff and non-staff staff are hired as hosts at all levels), rather than simply &quot;throwing out&quot; non-staff staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fired deputy minister&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun, who was born in 1970, worked as a teacher for 10 years after joining the workforce. His original identity was in the professional establishment. After leaving school, Zhang Shichun worked in the Education Bureau. In 1997, he was transferred to Pingxiang Economic Development Zone and later became deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department of the Economic and Technological Development Zone Party Working Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, due to work needs, Zhang Shichun was adjusted to a large state-owned enterprise in the Economic Development Zone as deputy secretary of the party committee and secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission, and the establishment was still retained in the Party and Mass Work Department of the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There were quite a lot of situations like Shichun at that time.” Yu Zhifeng, deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department, explained that from the economic development zone agencies to working in enterprises, there are still such personnel established by the agencies. , seven or eight in total. State-owned enterprises do not have public institutions, but they still retain the status of public institutions and are self-employed department-level cadres in the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-employment means self-employment. Without filing with the superior organizational department, the superior organizational department will not recognize it. If a civil servant or public servant is appointed as a deputy section-level cadre through normal organizational procedures, the superior organizational department needs to register for it, but the Economic Development Zone hires him to a full-section level without filing with the superior organizational department based on work needs. In fact, His rank is still deputy section level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020 and 2022, the Jiangxi Provincial Party Committee inspection team pointed out this problem during its two inspections of Pingxiang. Take 2022 as an example. In April of that year, the Fourth Inspection Team of the Provincial Party Committee inspected Pingxiang. On July 28, the Fourth Inspection Team reported the inspection situation to the Party Working Committee of Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. The third of the four main opinions was on the economic development. In the organizational work of the open area, “there is a big gap in improving the organizational system that is connected from top to bottom and has strong execution.” The inspection team put forward suggestions and suggestions for rectification, &quot;focusing on solving key issues in the personnel field of the institution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Zhifeng introduced that the more prominent problems in the personnel field of the Economic Development Zone are that there are too many self-established institutions and too many self-employed cadres: after years of development, the number of self-employed section-level cadres in the Economic Development Zone has reached 247. There are three main categories: on-staff personnel in the Economic Development Zone, cadres transferred from higher-level agencies or brother districts and counties, and self-employed non-staff personnel in the Economic and Technological Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the personnel reform work was launched, the Economic Development Zone organized relevant leading cadres to conduct one-on-one interviews with the 247 self-employed cadres, led by the main leaders of the Economic Development Zone Party Working Committee. Yu Zhifeng said that the one-on-one conversations lasted for several months, mainly to explain the urgency of policies and reforms, and to &quot;patiently and meticulously do the ideological work of the dismissal target.&quot; For self-employed cadres who are already on staff, we should give them the right to choose whether to give up their staff and choose to work in enterprises or retain their staff and work in government agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shichun prefers to give up his official position and stay in the company, but he also made it clear to his family the risks of working in the company: once the company encounters difficulties in its development, his income will also drop, and may even Unemployment, &quot;After discussion, we finally decided that I would stay in the company. I also believe that the company will develop better after the reform of the Economic Development Zone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yu Zhifeng, who carried out the dismissal work, was also a self-employed cadre. Before his dismissal, he served as party branch secretary and deputy director of the Party and Mass Work Department. After his dismissal, he remained the business editor, but only retained the position of deputy director of the Party and Mass Affairs Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Little horse and big cart&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;While dismissing 247 self-employed cadres, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone also dissolved and merged 19 self-established institutions , including the District Political and Legal Committee, District State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, District Letters and Calls Bureau, etc. Yu Zhifeng explained, “In the course of the development of the Economic Development Zone for many years, with the continuous increase in social affairs and service population, the Economic Development Zone set up its own institutions and hired a large number of cadres in violation of regulations without obtaining the consent of superiors.”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone was established in 1992. It was upgraded to a provincial development zone in 1995 and a national economic and technological development zone in 2010. After the area adjustment and expansion at the end of December 2021, the total area under its jurisdiction is 119 square kilometers. The permanent population is about 250,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of June 2021, there are 230 national-level economic and technological development zones. The GDP of Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone has been ranked among the top 100 economic and technological development zones in the country for five consecutive years, ranking 62nd in the country in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like other economic development zones across the country, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone is also a dispatched agency of the municipal government and is a functional area rather than an administrative district. &quot;At the beginning of its establishment, the functions of the economic and technological development zone were single, mainly economic development tasks, so the higher-level departments approved a small establishment for the economic and technological development zone.&quot; Zhu Min, director of the Party and Mass Department of the Party Working Committee of Pingxiang Economic and Technological Development Zone, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Materials provided by the Economic and Technological Development Zone to Southern Weekend reporters show that the specific regional scope was not delineated at the beginning of the economic and technological development zone. After it was upgraded to a provincial development zone in 1995, the Pingxiang Municipal Government decided to divide the six The administrative village is designated as a direct development area with a development area of ​​10 square kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“With such an area and population, the Economic Development Zone did not need much establishment at that time.” Zhu Min said, but in the process of development, the area of ​​Pingxiang Economic Development Zone gradually expanded, and with the agglomeration of industries , Pingxiang City’s old urban area population relief and other factors have led to a sharp increase in the population of the Economic Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to official data released by Pingxiang City, the permanent population of the Economic Development Zone has increased from 110,000 in 2011 to 250,000 in 2021. In the same year, the permanent population of Luxi County under the jurisdiction of Pingxiang City was 260,000, and the permanent population of Lianhua County was 210,000. This means that the population managed by the Economic Development Zone is equivalent to that of an ordinary county town in Pingxiang City. In terms of economic scale, the 2022 New Year&#39;s message of the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone shows that the economic development zone completed a regional GDP of 22.3159 billion yuan in the first three quarters of 2021, ranking first in Pingxiang City. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many establishments does the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone have, which manages a population of 250,000? Zhu Min introduced that in 2022, the superior establishment department re-examined the establishment of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee. There are currently 102 public employees and 138 business employees, for a total of 240 employees. Southern Weekend reporters learned from authoritative channels that a certain district in a surrounding city has more than 700 civil servants and more than 1,000 public servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to cope with the increasing social management functions as the population and regional area continue to increase, Pingxiang Economic Development Zone began to set up its own institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that there are basically two situations when economic and technological development zones set up their own institutions: population growth creates social management needs, and they must set up their own institutions to provide public services; municipal functional departments have vertical management needs , requiring the Economic and Technological Development Zone to set up corresponding institutions for work docking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Economic and Technological Development Zone has set up five social work bureaus, each of which manages several administrative villages. In fact, it performs the functions of the township government or city sub-district office; the Urban Management Bureau of the Economic and Technological Development Zone, The establishment of the Garden Management Bureau was because the Pingxiang City Urban Management Bureau and the Garden Management Bureau required the Economic Development Zone to also set up a management agency to facilitate the unified planning and implementation of urban management and gardening work in Pingxiang city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some self-established institutions set up by the Economic Development Zone to coordinate line work. The Public Security Bureau of the Economic Development Zone is the Development Zone branch established by the Pingxiang Municipal Public Security Bureau. The prosecutorial functions are performed by the Procuratorate in the Development Zone established by the Pingxiang Municipal Procuratorate. The judicial institution is hosted by the Anyuan District Court and the Development Zone Tribunal is established. In order to coordinate the work of public prosecutors, prosecutors and law enforcement as well as petitions, inspections and comprehensive management, the Economic Development Zone has set up its own political and legal committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 31 years of development and construction, the Economic Development Zone has become a functional area with a high degree of industry-city integration. The functions of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee have shifted from single to comprehensive, and in fact are performing functions similar to those of district and county governments. . During an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, a major leader of the Economic Development Zone analyzed that with the current establishment and number of personnel, the Economic and Technological Development Zone&#39;s ability to perform all management functions is a bit like a &quot;small horse and a big cart&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Lock the entrance and keep the exit smooth”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although there are too many self-established institutions and self-employed cadres, it is necessary for actual work, but it is also a matter of organizational personnel management. Caused by insufficient standards, too many agencies and cadres have also produced many adverse consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In terms of cadre team building, the superior organizational departments do not recognize the self-employed cadres of the Economic Development Zone, which has a negative impact on the growth of cadres. This is objectively not conducive to the training of cadres.” Yu Zhifeng explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Min served in the Organization Department of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee before being transferred to the Economic Development Zone as the director of the Party and Mass Work Department. In 2019, Zhu Min went to work in the first cadre section of the Organization Department of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and was responsible for contacting the Economic Development Zone. “At that time, I raised the issue of irregular organizational work in the Economic Development Zone and too many self-established institutions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and the Municipal Government vigorously promoted the reform of the personnel system of the Pingxiang Economic Development Zone. The Municipal Party Committee Organization Department, the Municipal Party Committee Editorial Office, the Municipal Development and Reform Commission and other departments took the lead in organizing outings to learn from the experience of personnel reforms in economic development zones in other regions. . By 2022, the advancement of personnel reform will be significantly intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 11th issue of &quot;China Institutional Reform and Management&quot; magazine in 2021 published a signed article &quot;Pingxiang promotes standardized management of non-staff personnel&quot; written and edited by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee. The article summarizes Pingxiang City’s work experience in cleaning up non-staff personnel. The overall principle is to integrate non-staff personnel and on-staff personnel into total management. The institutional establishment department shall approve the number of non-staff personnel based on the department’s functions and staffing situation. We must resolutely clean up the non-staff personnel employed in the post, and standardize the management of the non-staff personnel employed within the post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The article also summarizes the direction of the use of non-staff personnel. It is prohibited to use non-staff personnel for administrative examination and approval, administrative law enforcement, archives management, political personnel, letters and visits, and confidentiality-related positions; insisting on &quot;doing things without hiring people&quot; In principle, employers are not allowed to use non-staff personnel for property management, security, greening maintenance, canteen services, information network services, public building facilities and equipment maintenance, etc., except for primary and secondary schools and kindergarten canteens, and all use market service outsourcing, The government purchases services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the cleanup of non-staff employees in the Economic Development Zone is also carried out within the framework of the above principles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the personnel system reform in April 2023, the Economic and Technological Development Zone implemented overall control of posts based on the personnel system reform plan approved by the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government. On this basis, the Economic Development Zone further stipulated that in accordance with the requirements of the general staff control, no new non-staff personnel will be added in the future, and only personnel within the establishment quota will be recruited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Lock the entrance of non-staff personnel into the Economic Development Zone, strengthen the assessment and management of existing personnel, implement the last elimination system, and smooth the exit.” Zhu Min said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is by no means “sweeping out”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When dismissing self-employed cadres, the Economic Development Zone’s main concern is causing excessive reactions from the dismissal targets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Min reported on the reform plan to the main leaders of the Pingxiang Municipal Party Committee, &quot;The leader emphasized the general direction: the purpose of the reform is not to destroy your Economic Development Zone, the Economic Development Zone is still the engine of Pingxiang&#39;s economic development .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dismantling and merging 19 self-established agencies, the work was reorganized and the functions of the dismantled agencies were merged into 8 offices including the Party and Government Office of the Economic Development Zone, the Economic Development Bureau, and the Social Development Bureau. It has internal institutions and 8 public institutions including the park enterprise service center and social governance center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Economic Development Zone breaks down the identity boundaries and implements a unified &quot;sponsoring system management&quot; for both staff and non-staff personnel. It does not distinguish whether they are on staff or not, only based on the position. The sponsorship is divided into 12 levels. Each level is divided into 12 levels. Levels correspond to different salaries. The host has a promotion and downgrade mechanism, and has set an annual assessment failure rate of 5%. It is clear that those who fail the assessment for two consecutive years will be eliminated directly, so that the host level can be moved up or down, and the salary and performance can be improved or reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Min’s view, the economic development zone’s gradual digestion of non-staff personnel is by no means simply “sweeping them out”, but using a sponsorship system to allow the remaining staff and non-staff personnel to compete on the same track, “Whether it is Whether within the system or outside the system, opportunities must be given to these young people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Southern Weekend reporter’s interview, the Economic Development Zone was conducting a survey. The theme was to explore a new mechanism for motivating cadres, and to build a competitive system through competition, job transfer, waiting for job, demotion, dismissal, etc. selection mechanism. Southern Weekend reporters asked several organizers of the Economic Development Zone for confirmation. They said that after the organizational reform, the work pace is faster, the work intensity is higher, and the work pressure is greater. After the National Day holiday in 2023, many organizers have been working continuously and can basically only take half a day off on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another reason is that after the organization was dissolved and personnel were eliminated, the social management functions of the original organization were not completely divested, and various functions were divided into newly established public institutions. Therefore, the overall work The amount has not decreased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the arrival of the next round of reforms, economic and technological development zones across the country may usher in a functional &quot;downsizing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;High-Quality Development Plan for Development Zones in Anhui Province&#39;s &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot;&quot; released in March 2022 has a special chapter discussing the reform of the development zone system and mechanism, focusing on the rational division of development zone management agencies , territorial governments, and development and operation companies have real power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the &quot;Regulations on Promoting High-Quality Development of Development Zones in Henan Province (Draft)&quot; was submitted to the Standing Committee of the Henan Provincial People&#39;s Congress for its first review. The draft clarified that the Management Committee is mainly responsible for policy formulation, development planning, Administrative management functions such as administrative approval, investment promotion, and corporate services do not mention social management functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statements in both places send a signal: the functional positioning of development zones at the provincial level may still be economic development. So, how to deal with the social management functions that are gradually increasing in the development process of development zones in various places? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that in the national overall plan for the next round of institutional reform of development zones across the country, straightening out the relationship between development zones and administrative regions and gradually stripping away social affairs management functions is one of the trends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际足联：沙特是2034年足球世界杯唯一申办方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:55:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;FIFA announced on October 31 that the Saudi Arabian Football Association was the only one to submit a proposal to host the 2034 Football World Cup before the deadline. Apply to the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FIFA confirmed that it has received Saudi Arabia’s application to host the 2034 World Cup, and Saudi Arabia is currently the only country that has expressed interest in hosting the 2034 World Cup to FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256476&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, FIFA announced that the only application for hosting the 2030 World Cup was jointly submitted by the football federations of Morocco, Portugal and Spain. Currently, these three countries have confirmed their intention to bid.由于2030年将举行世界杯百年庆典，国际足联计划在乌拉圭、阿根廷和巴拉圭分别举行一场世界杯比赛，这三个国家也已向国际足联确认了举办意愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙特与摩洛哥、葡萄牙和西班牙三国一样，还需要通过国际足联的审核。如果这几个申办国家都能够满足国际足联提出的要求，走完全部申办流程并通过，那么国际足联将在2024年年底的国际足联大会上确定其举办权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总部人去楼空，国美无力回天？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT9aftX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT9aftX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月30日，空空荡荡的国美总部。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者梅岭/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;地处北京东三环霄云路26号的鹏润大厦，一度是亚洲单体面积最大的顶级写字楼，紧邻使馆区及朝阳公园。这里也是国美电器总部所在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2000年启用至今，这栋36层通体浅蓝、顶层设有停机坪的建筑，曾经见证了国美电器创始人黄光裕三次登顶中国首富，又在当下见证了国美电器因亏损、拖欠货款、欠薪后的尴尬状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月中旬，国美APP的抽奖页面中，出现了针对国美创始人黄光裕、现任国美电器董事长黄秀虹的弹窗，内容包括“拖欠工资、拖欠货款”。事实上，国美欠薪等问题早在2022年就已经出现，愤怒的员工曾在鹏润大厦与黄光裕发生冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“员工已经被逼到什么份上，才能干弹窗这事？现在的国美是无人管的状态，员工只能自己找窗口。”2023年3月离开国美的北京总部员工赵强对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;总部&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;空空荡荡&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据国美零售（0493.HK）财报数据，2021年国美集团共计约3.2万名员工，截至2023年上半年，国美集团员工人数为3609名。这意味着一年半时间里，国美流失了九成员工。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以前鹏润大厦都是满坑满谷的国美人，早上停车都没有地方，一到饭点食堂都是人。”赵强对南方周末记者说，但当他离开时，这栋大楼的大部分楼层都没有人了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日周一上午，南方周末记者来到鹏润大厦，这里分为A、B两座楼，B座3－36层是国美电器的办公地点，AB座唯一的不同是，只有B座有着严格的门禁管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;走进国美总部，廊道灯光依旧亮着，最大的感受是“空空荡荡”，大大小小的会议室、办公区、接待室都已上锁，只有零星的工作人员和保洁人员走动，见到陌生人来访，也无人上来询问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鹏润大厦18层，电梯两侧悬挂条幅写着“成为倍受信赖的世界级零售企业”“以&#39;信&#39;统领企业的生存和发展”，中间黑色背景墙印有“国美”两个大字。背景墙右侧是国美集团的宣传室，这里密密麻麻摆满了黄光裕、杜鹃以及国美集团昔日的各种证书、奖杯。但时间多集中在2018年以前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与这些昔日的荣誉相冲突的是，现在这里随处贴着“非本楼层工作人员严禁入内”的A4纸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“18层是整个国美负责接待商家、供应商的地方，有好几个很大的VIP会议室，以前每天都有很多人。”赵强说。南方周末记者在这一层观察了近半小时，除了一两位保洁人员，无人到来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责为商家、供应商提供支持的国美供应链公司集中在16层，曾经包括国美定制公司、宁波国美真选科技有限公司等，这些公司原本的办公区已经上锁，并从楼层指引牌上被摘除。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年2月，黄光裕正式刑满出狱，高调表示将力争在未来18个月时间里，使企业恢复到原有的市场地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他回归后最大的动作是推出代表国美零售战略的“真快乐”APP。财报显示，2021年，国美在这款APP上花的广告费用达到9.62亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“真快乐”的痕迹密集地出现在国美总部的17层，办公区中仍然挂着“美好事业一起拼&amp;nbsp;美好生活一起品”的红色横幅，贴着“12.24 9:00-12:00家电事业部、生活电器”预约会议的房间已经上锁。赵强感叹，“&#39;真快乐&#39;是多少国美员工努力工作、加班熬夜换来的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总部的第5层，包含国美集团在2012年构建的全国性第三方物流公司“安迅物流”的办公区域，这家物流公司此前曾传出拟IPO的消息。目前这里已漆黑一片。在2022年年底，有关安迅物流及其子公司拖欠河南多地承运商运费超300万的消息已经出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以说，2023年以后，整个国美就陷入了一种死寂的状态。”赵强对南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“真快乐”痕迹仍在。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者梅岭/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;钱去哪了&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鹏润大厦的顶层36层，在过往的报道中，是黄光裕的办公地点。但有曾“登顶”成功过的国美前员工对南方周末记者表示，“黄老板也住在这里，36层有一个他改造后的中西结合风格的别墅。”而想要登上36层，需乘专属电梯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“之前很多员工来要工资，就是一层层爬上去的，闹过两回。后来为了防止大家再去，那层就进不去了。”赵强记得，此前曾有供应商来讨要货款，在鹏润大厦门口蹲守到了黄光裕，并“跟着黄老板去了36楼，但怎么处理的我不知道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日，多家媒体报道了大庆国美突然关门停业、近20位家电经销商讨要货款但“不知道该找谁要”的消息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在裁判文书网上，2022年国美电器涉及诉讼268起，这个数字在2023年达到1219起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年的诉讼，包括广东省佛山市某电器设备公司要求佛山国美电器支付货款126万元、浙江某公司要求浙江国美电器返还租金及违约金共220万元、宁波一建筑装饰公司要求国美电器、国美零售支付工程款240万元等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有离职员工开始发现企业出现问题，是在2022年三四月份。“最大的问题就是资金问题，结不了账了。”赵强对南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位直接涉及国美销卖、进货的前员工还记得，过去自己的工作不需要考虑结账问题，但从2022年开始，就处于一种“给这边付了，那边就付不了”的情况。“很直观的感受到现金流很紧张。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，他去查询了国美每天的销售额。“我记得当时每天的销售额依然可以达到几千万到一个亿甚至更高，因此我个人觉得不至于周转不过来，但钱回来、又去了哪，我就不知道了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而2022年年初“员工的基本工资还是有的，只是绩效部分很少发”，逐渐情况越来越严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月，在鹏润大厦召开的全员大会上，国美电器董事长黄秀虹公开表示，“公司到12月底之前，只会给员工上社保，不会再发工资了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国美还要求员工签署承诺函，上面提及“自2022年10月起，理解公司在未来半年到一年时间里，员工工资有可能延迟发放……承诺调整积极心态，相信公司……作为员工，承诺躬身力行，按时保质保量交付经营结果，达成业绩目标”等信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这份承诺函我当时也看过，我不签，欠薪还欠出道理来了吗？”赵强介绍，有的员工已经一年收入为零。讨薪无果后，赵强也提起仲裁，根据判决书，国美欠其薪水加上公积金超过20万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一位国美相关部门管理人员对南方周末记者表示，“我没有被欠薪，但我原先手下的小孩都被欠了，20万的很多”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更令赵强无法接受的是，从2022年5月开始，国美不再为员工缴纳社保公积金。“但我们个人缴纳部分是扣除了的，公司并没有交给公积金管理中心，所有员工都是这样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这相当于用了我们的钱，但不知道用到了哪里。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位国美电器连云港分公司的员工对南方周末记者表示，“从2022年10月开始，我们就意识到国美开始出现资金问题，因为一直没有按时发工资，一直拖到今年3月闭店”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;员工们都提起了仲裁，但他们没有太大信心，“国美账户没钱，怎么都是无疾而终的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国美电器在全国拥有3895家连锁店、2亿多名会员。但2023年开始，国美接连出现闭店消息，10月，有媒体报道国美广东门店全部关闭，随后公司回应并未全部关闭，但公布的数据显示，三季度国美在广东省减少了自营店12家，加盟店74家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京、上海、连云港等多地的国美员工、消费者也对南方周末记者表示，所在城市的国美门店也在逐渐关闭中。多位受访者说，“国美全国门店基本都关了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;门店关闭的过程中，令消费者无法接受的情况出现了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海地区一位消费者2022年12月在上海国美长宁总店购买了一台7200元的洗衣机，国美不发货不退款，消费者将国美起诉后调解，国美承诺会在2023年8月前退款，但至今没有任何音讯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我虽然知道黄光裕曾经入狱又出狱，但不影响我在国美购物，没想过付完钱不发货”，上述消费者对南方周末记者表示。在2023年国美涉及的上千起诉讼中，有大量类似的买卖纠纷、员工欠薪诉讼等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了资金问题外，在赵强的印象中，公司的第二个变化，就是直属领导的频繁变更，这意味着公司出现了问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者不完全统计，2021年至今，包括前国美在线CEO、国美电器CEO、国美零售总裁等数十位核心高管纷纷离职。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;缘&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;何走到今天&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;黄光裕出生于广东潮汕，现年54岁。根据国美集团的官方信息，黄光裕于1987年在北京前门珠市口大街成立了第一家以经营各类家用电器为主、面积不足一百平米的“国美电器店”，国美零售之路正式起步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年，国美尝试新的供销模式，脱离中间商，与厂家直接包销定制，开启了“直销式”家电模式。1993年，国美电器统一了门店名称、商品展示方式、门店售后服务、宣传，成为中国零售连锁模式的雏形。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2004年，国美电器以借壳方式在港交所上市成功，黄光裕借此以百亿身家登顶胡润百富榜中国大陆首富，并在2005年、2008年再度问鼎，个人财富一度高达450亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2008年11月，处于巅峰的黄光裕因涉嫌经济犯罪被警方拘查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年后，黄光裕因非法经营罪、内幕交易罪和单位行贿罪被判处有期徒刑14年。2020年6月，北京市第一中级人民法院依法裁定对黄光裕予以假释，2021年2月，黄光裕正式刑满出狱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;黄光裕昔日的荣誉仍展出在国美总部。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者梅岭/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵强是在黄光裕出狱后的第二个月加入国美的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“国美的辉煌年代我多少有一些了解，觉得它的底子蛮好，盘子也很大。当时认为，黄老板出来后肯定会有一些新的举措和方式，会把国美重新大力发展起来，结合自己的履历，我就加入了。”他对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，黄光裕归来后，首先将国美APP改名为“真快乐”，作为国美零售生态的“总平台”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据过往媒体报道，黄光裕在狱中时，仍然通过写信的方式与公司高管对接信息，国美高管甚至在书信中用画图的方式，试图让黄光裕明白智能手机和APP的原理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过赵强坦言，“直到离职那天，我也不知道这个APP的定位到底是什么”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“真快乐”平台上，有赛场、秀场、娱乐场三大场景，还包括内容分享社区、短视频直播、赛事榜单、电商购物平台等多个板块的集合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵强不知道如何定位这个APP，到底是社区电商、兴趣电商还是传统电商？在他看来，这个被老板倾注全力的APP，从设计、产品制作到体验上都没有核心和重点，这给传播带来不利影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是决策者的问题。”但赵强也提及，到2022年年初时，“真快乐”这一平台基础功能已经具备，消费者可以买东西，也可以正常退货。只要一个板块有爆点，整体倾斜后，这条路线依然可以走通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国美内部出现的严重内耗，让他开始对公司前景产生了怀疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他举例，一般电商平台的供应链会比较集中，但在国美内部，同时做供应链的公司有好几家。一个品牌的同一个产品，可能会与国美很多家供应链公司合作，&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些供应链公司，却只有一个输出端口，就是“真快乐”APP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这带来了人力的巨大浪费，每一个供应链公司都是几十人乃至上百人，但多个班子做的都是重复性工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“每一个班子都要活下来，大家都在不停地跟集团要钱，不停瓜分。老板也许希望竞争，但这种竞争并没有对外，分散又内耗。”赵强对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国美内部还搭建了一个并不对外的共享共建平台，小商家、供应商在缴纳了一定使用费后，可以接入这个系统。“这个平台最大的问题，在于没有人用，商家想要开店，直接去别的平台开店就可以了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了“真快乐”APP外，黄光裕归来后，还陆续推出了“打扮家”“折上折”等多款APP，这令市场不解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家电行业资深分析师刘步尘对南方周末记者说，“黄光裕回归后，激进的作风让国美迅速地烧钱，钱花出去了，却没有得到他预期的效果。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位国美集团的中层人士对南方周末记者表示，“除了公司领导的决策问题，对市场环境不了解以外，也受到疫情影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中国企业家》报道，2021年10月下旬，在鹏润大厦36层，国美连续召开了5天的高层会议，黄光裕坐在主位上，却盯着平放在桌上的iPad，玩着游戏《愤怒的小鸟》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵强说，“有时白天黄老板睡觉，开会都是在深夜，高管都疯了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;还能“起死回生”吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者就国美现状联系了一位已离职的副总裁级别高管，但对方拒绝谈论此事。此外，国美集团的公关部门已处于全员离职状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，国美集团国内官网已经无法打开，“打扮家”和“折上折”APP在苹果应用商店已经下架。在花费了巨额推广费后，2023年1月，“真快乐”又更名回“国美”APP。目前，国美APP部分品牌已撤出，电视、冰箱等部分品类全线下架，此外，直播销售榜单显示空白，原本可以提供的清洁、维修等服务已经停用，客服已无人回复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从财报来看，2023年上半年，国美零售营收4.15亿元，同比大降95.74%；实现归母净亏损35.39亿元。同期，国美零售的流动资产仅为53.26亿元，现金及现金等价物1.46亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但国美零售的总负债余额高达373.13亿元，资产负债率106.55%，公司已资不抵债。其中，流动负债为361.06亿元，占比高达96.78%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，从2021年下半年开始，黄光裕、杜鹃夫妇频繁减持国美零售股票，从2021年年底二人持股60.98%一路降至目前的10.79%，减持套现近20亿港元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年2月，黄光裕正式刑满出狱时，国美的股价迎来一波大涨，一度被市场戏称为“出狱概念股”，截至发稿，国美零售股价仅剩下0.037元／股，较其出狱时，下跌97%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“过去十几年，国美的发展战略主要体现在两个字——保守，能不花的钱尽量不花，这是杜鹃的观点。”而刘步尘认为，在电商主导的时代，传统家电连锁的没落是不可避免的，只是快和慢的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在昔日员工看来，没落和终结或许可以体面一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵强感慨，“回头看，我是惋惜的。我们加入国美，是希望帮助曾经的神话重塑另一个神话，你给我机会，我付出能力，但现在很难起死回生了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;国美总部办公室，停留在2022年的圣诞氛围中。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者梅岭/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中赵强为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海上危机专家谈：“我们需要的不是排外战略，而是包容的战略”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259713]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近年来，海洋成为各国关注的新兴发展空间，新的海洋秩序正在形成。与此同时，海上军事危机、海洋生态安全等新问题也随之出现。我们是否做好了迎接新秩序的准备？应该如何管控涉海争端？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在，我们正在步入新的海洋秩序，我们应该尽全力维持海洋安全，避免进入无序状态。”斯里兰卡原海军司令贾亚纳斯·科隆巴杰表示。他认为，很多国家依赖海洋，在海洋治理上人们需要互联互通的系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月30日，在北京香山论坛“海上军事危机预防与管控”分组会议上，多位中外学者围绕海上危机、海洋风险、海洋秩序与规则等问题进行了深入探讨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月30日，北京香山论坛上多名中外学者围绕“海上军事危机预防与管控”展开讨论。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（姚忆江/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“矛盾多发期”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当今世界面临巨大变局，海上安全问题受到多种因素影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国人民解放军海军原副司令员、退役中将丁一平判断：“各种风险因素叠加、联动、放大，海上形势受其影响，进入矛盾多发期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一方面是海上传统安全问题，主权争端、使用纠纷、资源开发、渔业等问题。”丁一平提到，“单是海洋使用纠纷，目前世界上至少有六十多个国家卷入了两百多个海洋领域的争端。”另一方面，“海盗抢劫、恐怖袭击等犯罪活动频发。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们生活在海洋危机之中。”贾亚纳斯·科隆巴杰是一名退役中将，曾担任斯里兰卡海军司令，他尤其关注印度洋及其沿岸国家的海洋安全问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印度洋是世界第三大洋，鱼类和海草资源丰富，海洋贸易非常发达，但科隆巴杰注意到，印度洋周边国家仍受到安全问题的困扰，“人口贩卖、海上非法移民等都发生在印度洋，对海洋秩序造成很大威胁。此外，印度洋有大量的军事行动。”科隆巴杰称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了日益加重的安全危机，海洋生态环境恶化也越来越成为海洋治理的难题。近年来，气候变化导致海洋灾害频发，冰川融化、海平面上升、海洋表面温度升高，对海洋和沿岸生态系统造成严重危害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丁一平谈到，“部分国家向海洋排放工业污水、倾倒垃圾，导致海水污染、海洋生态被严重破坏，而无序无度的开发使海洋资源快速衰退。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科隆巴杰关注的印度洋同样面临生态破坏，“南印度洋有一个6万平方公里的地方，有一大片垃圾。”科隆巴杰担心，如果不及时处理，印度洋的环境问题会越来越严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;频发的海洋安全问题背后，还存在更复杂的国家博弈，想要解决并非易事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丁一平表示，“由于海洋争端牵扯历史根源、民族感情、经济与安全利益，当事国都不愿妥协让步，一些域外大国为了自身利益插手他国争端，导致争议对抗下去，严重影响了一些地区的安全稳定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而科隆巴杰则表示，无论是海洋安全管理还是海洋环境治理，各国都面临合作困境。“海洋治理有几大阻碍，缺乏信任，缺少经济来源，领导者缺乏政治视野，公众认知不足，同时也缺乏广泛的政策。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“新的海洋秩序”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当前，关于印度洋有很多“战略”。科隆巴杰认为，这些战略导致大量印度洋周边国家的战略竞争、战略收紧、战略困境和战略分歧等，让印度洋变得不安全。和这些战略相似的是，印度洋地区有大量的联合倡议，而很多倡议都停留在纸面上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么我们一个小国需要这么多的战略？这些战略要达成什么目标？能为印度洋地区带来大发展吗？”科隆巴杰认为，这些战略中关于“秩序、规则”的定义是有争议的；印度洋需要的不是排外的战略，而应该是包容的战略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当事情朝着错误的方向，我们可以看向原点。比如说1982年通过的《联合国海洋法公约》，我们需要回到最初的共识。”科隆巴杰认为，很多国家依赖海洋，在海洋治理上人们需要互联互通的系统。比如“需要可持续的、一体化的海洋治理和强制执法”“一旦在海洋上出现争端，不能够使用军事手段”等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他呼吁政府和非政府组织、商业、私营部门都能团结在一起，因为“独行速，众行远”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们经常听到，我们生活在一个无法预测的世界。然而我们（研究者）的工作就是预见&#39;不可预见&#39;。现在，我们正在步入新的海洋秩序。为了防止无序，我们需要在无序中寻找秩序。”科隆巴杰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印度原联合国防参谋长、退役中将谢卡尔·辛哈认为，冷战结束后，越来越多的国家经济提升、军事力量增强，世界力量平衡重心从西方转移到东方，进而带来了更多的大国竞争。“海上军事冲突的强度还会增加，并且将会继续。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢卡尔担忧，军事领域的侵犯行为必然会引出军队，尤其是在海上，比如军舰碰撞。同时，军队或军事资产在海外运行涉及海上管辖权的争议，涉事方对历史、法规、公约等认知的不同也会加剧争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢卡尔提出，全球商业非常重要，冲突不应该影响到商业船只的航行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，全世界只有10%-15%的船只是军舰，剩下的都是商业船只。在任何时候，《联合国海洋法公约》被侵犯或违反，必须要有全球性的警告，并且要有执法的机制，以便制止这种违法行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“战舰在全球船只中所占的比例非常小，我们要遵守相关的规则，保护商业和贸易，大国的冲突更多地体现在海上而不是贸易冲突上。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;危机管控“中国方案”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;丁一平表示，中国倡导的海洋安全理念重点可以归纳为三个方面——分别是共同维护海洋和领域安全，共同应对海上安全威胁，尊重各国海洋权益、反对海洋霸权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“海洋绝大部分是公共领域，其安全需要世界各国共同维护。”丁一平提出，要维护以国际法为基础的海洋秩序，尊重各方和平的海洋利益诉求，反对利用海洋围堵、遏制、打压他国，运用别国海洋利益矛盾挑起事端。实践证明，唯有相互信任、加强沟通、积极合作、良性互动、共同维护，才能有效保障海洋安全，实现共同利益的最大化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，如何预防和管控海上军事危机？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丁一平提出，首要建议是达成防止涉海争端升级失控的战略公布，制止海上军事力量不当行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当前以美国为主的域外海上军事力量，在中国周边海域高频率的侦察、监视、测量活动，特别是针对中国南海、东海开展的主权挑衅行为，管控危机的强度增加，已经对海上局势危机的预防和管控构成了严重障碍。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，美军舰频繁穿越台湾海峡，刺激台海地区局势紧张，不断对中国挑衅。台湾孙文学校总校长张亚中在会上发言称，要建立两岸的军事互信机制，或者要预防跟管理两岸的海上军事危机，最根本也是最必要的方法，就是两岸必须有“政治共识”，“台湾方面应该重新再回到&#39;九二共识&#39;的立场”。他表示，期待两岸能够有智慧摆脱外国的影响，双方自行解决两岸的政治跟军事的难题，共同为两岸创造和平而努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生翟桓、包婧玥对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[保障“外嫁女”合法权益，最高检、全国妇联联合发布6件典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月1日，最高人民检察院、中华全国妇女联合会联合发布维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;该批典型案例共6件，包括支某兰诉山东省某市自然资源和规划局集体土地登记检察监督案，张某甲诉江苏省某镇人民政府土地权属不予受理决定检察监督案，湖南省某市某区人民检察院依法保障“外嫁女”土地征收权益检察监督案，钱某娟、季某熙诉浙江省某街道办事处不履行征收安置补偿职责检察监督案，俞某诉江苏省某镇人民政府违法拆除及行政赔偿检察监督案，周某诉海南省某市某村委会某村民小组集体经济组织成员资格确认检察监督案。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一直以来，检察机关、妇联组织深入学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想，主动加强联系，建立信息共享、案件移送、案情通报、联合督办等机制，强化对妇女权益的全方位司法保护。自2022年1月至2023年9月，检察机关共办理涉妇女权益保护行政检察案件4000余件。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;随着我国城镇化进程的加快，农村妇女因婚姻关系、户籍等发生变动，涉及农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、征地补偿或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面的争议更为复杂，已成为社会普遍关注的问题。该批典型案例聚焦集体经济组织中的“外嫁女”涉土地合法权益保护，坚持男女平等基本国策，加大对涉及农村妇女合法权益的行政诉讼、行政非诉执行案件的监督力度，强化调查核实，通过一体化办案、院领导包案、府检联动、检法联动等方式，妥善化解争议，以高质效法律监督推动解决妇女急难愁盼问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;党的二十大报告&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;指出，坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益。最高检第七检察厅负责人表示，今年是全面贯彻落实党的二十大精神的开局之年，也是新修订的妇女权益保障法施行第一年，各级检察机关行政检察部门将坚持以习近平法治思想为指引，深入贯彻落实党的二十大精神和习近平总书记对妇女儿童工作的重要指示精神，贯彻执行妇女权益保障法，持续深化与妇联组织等相关部门合作，带着真心真情，付出更大努力，高质效办好每一个案件，进一步加强对农村妇女财产权益的平等保护，推动源头治理，切实提升农村妇女的获得感、幸福感、安全感，为推动妇女儿童事业高质量发展作出新的贡献。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;关于印发维护农村妇女&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;的通知&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;各省、自治区、直辖市人民检察院、妇女联合会，新疆生产建设兵团人民检察院、妇女联合会：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近年来，随着我国城镇化进程的加快，涉土地征收征用纠纷呈现增长态势。农村妇女因婚姻关系、户籍等发生变动，涉及农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、土地征地补偿或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面的争议更为复杂。为全面贯彻党的二十大精神，深入学习贯彻习近平法治思想，贯彻执行新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》，加大对涉及农村妇女合法权益的行政诉讼、行政非诉执行案件的监督力度，更好维护妇女合法权益，最高人民检察院、中华全国妇女联合会共同选编了6件维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例，现印发你们，供参考借鉴。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;最高人民检察院&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;中华全国妇女联合会&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2023年9月7日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;行政检察典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例一&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;支某兰诉山东省某市自然资源和规划局集体土地登记检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女宅基地使用权登记抗诉&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;支某兰与支某瑞系姐弟关系，其父支某（2011年去世）在山东省某市某村有宅基地一处。2015年，支某瑞向某市国土资源局（现更名为某市自然资源和规划局）申请案涉宅基地使用权的变更登记，市国土资源局同意并向支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证。2018年10月12日，支某兰以某市国土资源局为被告、支某瑞为第三人向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求依法撤销该局为支某瑞颁发的集体土地使用证。某区人民法院于2019年4月25日作出行政裁定，认为支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，不能获得案涉土地使用权，该土地颁证行为不影响支某兰权益，裁定驳回支某兰的起诉。支某兰不服一审生效裁定，向某市中级人民法院申请再审。市中级人民法院于2020年6月4日裁定驳回支某兰的再审申请。支某兰向某区人民检察院申请监督。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法受理。经听取当事人意见、调取法院卷宗和案涉土地登记原始档案、听取原审法官意见，查明：某市国土资源局主要基于案涉宅基地上房屋的《房屋继承协议》，认定支某瑞因继承房屋获得土地使用权，从而为支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证，但该继承协议列明了宅基地上房屋的5名继承人，并未写明仅由支某瑞一人继承。另查明，支某兰原系该村集体经济组织成员，婚后因孩子上学原因将户口迁出，目前生活较为贫困。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院经审查认为，根据国土资源部、中央农村工作领导小组办公室、财政部、农业部《关于农村集体土地确权登记发证的若干意见》，非集体经济组织成员因继承房屋占用农村宅基地的，可按规定登记发证。本案中，虽然诉讼时支某兰并非该村集体经济组织成员，但其系支某的合法继承人，与案涉宅基地登记行为存在利害关系，法院以支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，以土地颁证行为不影响其权益为由，裁定驳回起诉，适用法律确有错误。某区人民检察院提请市人民检察院抗诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;市人民检察院经审查，依法提出抗诉。市中级人民法院采纳抗诉意见，于2021年11月17日裁定撤销原审裁定，指令某区人民法院继续审理本案。某区人民法院于2022年9月26日作出行政判决，撤销案涉集体土地使用证。某市自然资源和规划局、支某瑞不服一审判决，提出上诉。市中级人民法院于2023年3月6日判决驳回上诉，维持原判。同时，某市人民检察院审查认为支某兰符合司法救助条件，协助其申请司法救助。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;集体经济组织中的“外嫁女”权益保护问题成为社会普遍关注的问题。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，妇女享有与男子平等的继承权，妇女依法行使继承权，不受歧视。申请农村土地承包经营权、宅基地使用权等不动产登记，应当在不动产登记簿和权属证书上将享有权利的妇女等家庭成员全部列明。户口迁出的“外嫁女”虽然不再是原集体经济组织成员，但其通过取得宅基地上房屋的继承份额，可以登记为宅基地的使用权人。针对法院以“外嫁女”与被诉土地使用权登记行为无利害关系为由裁定驳回起诉的案件，检察机关围绕争议焦点，强化调查核实，厘清事实、准确适用法律，以高质效法律监督促进司法公正，维护妇女的合法权益。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例二&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;张某甲诉江苏省某镇人民政府土地权属不予受理决定检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女土地权属行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;张某甲原系江苏省某镇某社区居民，其父母曾建有瓦房四间，并育有四女，后四女因婚嫁户口均从某社区迁出。张某甲父母先后去世。2005年，某社区将张某甲父母的宅基地、承包地收回，重新发包给张某甲堂兄张某乙经营并签订土地承包经营合同，某市人民政府向张某乙户颁发了农村集体土地承包经营权证书。2007年3月，张某甲离异后，户口迁回某社区。2013年5月，张某乙夫妇将张某甲父母所建房屋拆除。张某甲等四姐妹将张某乙夫妇诉至法院，要求恢复房屋原状，未获法院支持。后张某甲的其他姐妹均出具书面申明，自愿放弃继承权。2015年12月，张某甲向某镇政府递交宅基地使用权确权申请书，请求确认其父母原宅基地、承包地的土地使用权归其享有，确认张某乙与某社区签订的土地承包经营合同无效。2017年3月，某镇政府对张某甲的确权申请作出不予受理决定。张某甲不服该决定，提起行政诉讼。一审法院认为，案涉土地已被某社区收回并发包给张某乙承包经营，根据《土地权属争议调查处理办法》第十四条规定，农村土地承包经营权争议案件不属于土地权属争议受案范围，某镇政府作出不予受理决定，符合法律规定，张某甲可依法另行寻求权利救济，遂判决驳回张某甲诉讼请求。张某甲提出上诉、申请再审，均未获支持。张某甲不服，向某市人民检察院申请监督。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员实地调查取证&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经审查原审卷宗，检索关联案件，实地走访调查，查明：自2013年以来，张某甲因案涉房屋及土地争议提起财产损害赔偿、不当得利返还、土地登记行为违法等13件民事、行政诉讼，其诉求均未获支持。相关生效判决虽已确认张某甲因继承取得案涉房屋所有权及宅基地使用权，亦指出某镇人民政府应当针对张某甲多年反映的宅基地被侵占问题妥善做好协调工作，但均未对该问题作出具体明确的裁决，导致案涉争议始终“诉而不决”。目前案涉社区已整体搬迁，张某甲回其父母原宅基地处重新申请建房不具有现实可能。张某甲常年在外务工，居无定所，多次诉讼实质是为求得其今后回原籍生活的“容身之所”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，本案为土地承包经营权争议，不属于人民政府土地权属争议受案范围，终审判决并无不当。但某社区未经张某甲等法定继承人同意，以自然闭户处理收回案涉土地，侵犯了张某甲等人的继承权，且张某甲户口迁回某社区后，作为村民亦应享有相应宅基地使用权。案涉争议持续近十年，历经多轮诉讼，张某甲的合法权益一直未能得到有效维护，且有引发新诉讼的可能，两级检察机关遂决定一体开展化解工作，彻底解决其多年“程序空转”难题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院致函某镇人民政府，指出张某甲权益受到侵害客观存在，镇政府应重视张某甲合理诉求，处理好当事人房屋土地问题，避免争议激化上行，保障妇女合法权益。同时，向当地妇联通报该案情况，共同至某镇政府开展化解工作。镇政府充分听取检察机关和妇联意见后，召集政法综治中心、某社区等部门商讨解决方案，最终确定张某甲可凭村民资格，以拆迁安置价格购买一套安置房用于解决居住问题。同时，检察机关向张某甲说明重新建房已不现实，应尽早从诉累中解脱，开始新生活。张某甲感受到人民政府的诚意，同意某镇政府方案。2022年10月11日，张某甲与某镇政府签订和解协议，张某甲向检察机关撤回监督申请。该案的行政争议与民事纠纷得到实质性化解。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在土地承包经营、宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。涉及村民利益事项的决定，不得以妇女未婚、结婚、离婚、丧偶、户无男性等为由，侵害妇女在农村集体经济组织中的各项权益。在办理争议历时长、关联诉讼多、民行交叉的涉损害“外嫁女”权益案件时，检察机关针对“案结事不了、程序空转”等问题，坚持人民至上、检察为民，聚焦群众急难愁盼问题，准确把握法律关系实质，统筹考虑法理情，综合运用实地走访、工作函告、协同属地妇联共同化解争议等方式“一揽子”化解行政争议与民事纠纷，切实维护农村妇女的合法权益，促进社会公平正义。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例三&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;湖南省某市某区人民检察院依法保障“外嫁女”土地征收权益检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政类案监督外嫁女征收补偿安置标准诉源治理&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2016年以来，湖南省某市自然资源和规划局某区分局（下称某自然资源和规划分局）在履行土地征收管理职能过程中，对在公安户籍管理系统单独登记立户的“外嫁女”张某及其子、王某及其女、易某及其子，分别纳入张某、王某、易某的近亲属户进行补偿安置。张某、王某、易某均不服，提起行政诉讼。2017年6月，在张某行政诉讼案中，某区人民法院判决某自然资源和规划分局应按单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，某自然资源和规划分局依法履行了判决确定的义务；2018年12月，在易某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局主动按单独一户标准计算了安置补偿费；2019年4月，在王某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局当庭发表“外嫁女”不按单独一户进行补偿安置的答辩意见。上述三起案件，某自然资源和规划分局对“外嫁女”是否按照单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，认定标准不统一。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院在开展“全面深化行政检察监督依法护航民生民利”专项活动中，以张某、王某、易某等三起具有典型性的案件为切口，通过数据检索，发现全区涉“外嫁女”土地征收补偿行政诉讼多达上百件。某区人民检察院经研判，决定开展类案监督。通过走访行政机关、人民法院及村民委员会，调取案卷、查看资料，发现行政机关对“外嫁女”征地补偿安置标准不统一的问题较为突出，还存在行政诉讼答辩“同案不同辩”应诉不规范等问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员就检察建议整改内容与行政机关进行沟通&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年3月29日，某区人民检察院向某自然资源和规划分局发出检察建议书，建议该局：1. 对“外嫁女”进行补偿安置时，要充分保障妇女合法权益，以是否依法登记所在地常住户口作为形式要件，以是否实际在本集体经济组织生产生活为实质要件，综合判断其是否具有集体经济组织成员资格。2. 对“外嫁女”是否按单独一户进行补偿安置，制定统一的补偿认定标准。3. 完善行政应诉机制，提升依法行政水平，维护政府公信力。检察建议发出后，某区人民检察院与某自然资源和规划分局、某区妇联多次召开联席会，交流意见，共商整改重点。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年4月27日，某自然资源和规划分局书面回复，表示进一步完善征地拆迁安置政策和补偿认定标准；严格落实“三轮会审”机制，及时梳理总结涉拆案件情况；提升自身应诉能力水平。2022年5月，某自然资源和规划分局制定新的《征拆安置政策和补偿认定标准》手册，对“外嫁女”制定了统一的身份认定、户型认定的补偿标准，按单独一户标准对符合规定的王某等“外嫁女”及其子女计算安置补偿费。聘请4名专职律师负责行政应诉工作，从源头堵塞行政应诉不规范问题。某区人民检察院与某区妇联会签《检察监督保障妇女权益协作配合机制意见》，在线索移送、支持起诉、行政争议化解、司法救助等多方面达成合作意见，建立长效机制。2022年6月以来，该区未再发生因“外嫁女”补偿安置标准不统一而引发的行政诉讼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;征地拆迁补偿，事关民生民利。“外嫁女”应否予以补偿安置，以及补偿安置标准是否一致，事关妇女群众切身利益。在土地征收补偿安置中，农村集体组织单独登记立户的“外嫁女”，应当平等享有安置补偿权利，以单独一户按照统一标准进行补偿安置。检察机关在履行法律监督职责中，对于侵害“外嫁女”补偿安置权益，已被人民法院判决纠正后仍得不到有效落实的多起同类不当行政行为，注重类案监督，找准深层次问题，推动完善制度构建，确保同类案件在同等条件下得到同等处理，促进诉源治理，充分彰显了检察机关敢于监督、善于监督的责任担当。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例四&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;钱某娟、季某熙诉浙江省某街道办事处不履行征收安置补偿职责检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格安置补偿社会治理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;钱某娟系浙江省某镇（现某街道办事处）某村村民，婚后仍落户在其父钱某户内，育有一女季某熙，亦落户在钱某户内。2015年9月，钱某娟与其夫季某离婚，季某熙随母共同生活。2017年，钱某娟、季某熙所在的某镇某村列入拆改范围，钱某的房屋在征收范围内。2017年9月11日，钱某与某镇人民政府签订《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，钱某娟、季某熙未被计入安置人口。钱某娟、季某熙提起行政诉讼，请求撤销《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，并重新签订；附带审查并确认某区政府安置补偿实施方案中“虽户口在册，但已嫁于外村且无独立合法产权房屋，不计入安置人口”的规定违法。某区人民法院判决驳回诉讼请求。钱某娟、季某熙不服，提出上诉、申请再审，未获支持。钱某娟、季某熙向某市人民检察院申请监督。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理，并根据一体化办案规定，成立两级院办案组，由某区人民检察院检察长包案办理。经调阅法院卷宗材料，调取钱某的户籍信息及某村集体经济组织成员情况，咨询区集体土地征收安置人口认定政策的制定背景及实践情况，查明：钱某娟、季某熙的户籍自始在某村，未变动，二人一直与钱某夫妇在该村生活。钱某娟系某村集体经济组织成员，享受股权6.21股，有股权证。钱某签订房屋征收安置补偿协议后，房屋被拆除，钱某娟、季某熙面临住房困难。安置补偿实施方案中的“已嫁于外村”，在实践中解释为“与外村人结婚”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;经过检察人员的努力调解，钱某娟撤回监督申请&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，钱某娟、季某熙自始系某村集体经济组织成员，二人也未在其他农村集体经济组织中享受宅基地分配使用、安置补偿。安置补偿实施方案损害妇女、儿童权益，不应作为否认“外嫁女”及其子女获得安置补偿待遇的依据。考虑到提抗、审判、执行周期长，且可能引发新一轮诉讼，增加当事人的诉累，为从根本上保障当事人的权益，某市人民检察院牵头召开府检、法检联席会议，研判“外嫁女”安置补偿案件的司法裁判规则，某区人民检察院与区房征办、信访局、街道办事处等共同研究解决方案。经多方协调联动，最终达成对钱某娟、季某熙补偿50万元的方案。2022年11月14日，钱某娟、季某熙领取补偿款后，向检察机关申请撤回监督申请。该案行政争议得到实质性化解。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关由该案进一步推动行政机关制定科学、合法、可行的土地征收安置补偿政策。目前，某区政府已修订土地征收安置补偿方案，涉“外嫁女”安置政策得以调整。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;男女平等是我国的基本国策。党的二十大报告强调“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”，充分彰显党中央对妇女儿童事业发展的高度重视。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》也要求检察机关在履职中加强对妇女权益的保护。检察机关在履职过程中，坚持问题导向，针对将“外嫁女”土地征收安置补偿权益排除在外，违反男女平等基本国策及相关法律规定的现象，通过一体化办案、成立联合办案组、院领导包案、府检联动、法检联动等方式，依法开展监督，妥善化解争议，有效维护妇女合法权益。同时，通过案件办理，推动地方政府在行政管理中重视妇女权益保障，完善土地征收安置补偿政策，有力提升社会治理法治化水平。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例五&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;俞某诉江苏省某镇人民政府违法拆除及行政赔偿检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女拆迁补偿独立基本户行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;俞某系某镇村民，婚前与其父、兄共同居住。2007年俞某结婚，户口未迁出，并一直居住在本村。因俞某属于与村集体经济组织以外人员结婚但户口未迁出的“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不符合单独分户条件，俞某同其丈夫（外地人）在俞某父亲宅基地翻建房屋240平方米，并多次申请宅基地及建房手续，但一直未能办理。2017年，当地政府作出房屋征收决定公告，对俞某所在“城中村”改造项目内的居民房屋实施征地拆迁。房屋被镇政府拆除后，俞某向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求判令按照拆迁安置补偿的标准，以房屋产权置换方式对房屋灭失损失进行赔偿。某区人民法院审理认为，俞某与其父亲并未分户，其翻建房屋使用的是其父亲宅基地，未办理房屋建房手续。根据有关规定，案涉房屋不能按照拆迁补偿的标准予以赔偿，鉴于房屋确系俞某所建，可按照房屋重置价予以赔偿（每平方米500元）。审理中，某镇政府表示可以赔偿90万元，法院予以准许。俞某不服一审判决，提出上诉、申请再审，均未获法院支持。俞某向某市人民检察院申请监督。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经调查核实查明：俞某房屋被拆除后，一直没有经济能力购买商品房，长期在外租房居住；俞某丈夫在原籍集体经济组织无住房、无宅基地；拆迁部门认为俞某是“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不同意按照“独立基本户”进行拆迁安置补偿；俞某认为其一直在该集体经济组织享有权利和承担义务，系当地村民，在父辈宅基地上分户建房并一直居住，应以“独立基本户”对其进行拆迁补偿安置。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，并进行释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，因俞某未分户且所建房屋未能办理审批手续，终审判决并无明显不当，但俞某的权益并未得到充分保障。本案系历史遗留问题，涉及村民自治规则的正当性、传统观念根深蒂固等问题，争议化解难度大。为此，检察机关联合当地妇联，多次组织当事人协商，赴政府商谈，引导当地政府切实增强男女平等意识，依法保障妇女在农村土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面享有与男子平等的权利。同时，多次赴俞某家实地开展联合走访慰问，为俞某提供心理疏导和关爱帮扶，减少其对立情绪。为进一步厘清外嫁女的相关法律、政策问题，2022年6月23日，检察机关就该案召开听证会，并邀请具有市区两级妇联代表身份的听证员参与。会上，双方围绕争议焦点充分表达意见、听证员现场提问，明晰案件事实，就和解方案进行全面评估与多次磋商。最终镇政府一次性补偿数十万元，合计先前赔偿的90万元，俞某得到的补偿与拆迁补偿的标准基本接近，双方达成和解协议，俞某撤回监督申请。长达五年的行政争议得以实质性化解。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，国家采取必要措施，促进男女平等，消除对妇女的一切形式的歧视，禁止排斥、限制妇女依法享有和行使各项权益。妇女在土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等权利。针对历史遗留问题，检察机关在办案过程中，坚持系统思维，统筹考虑拆迁安置争议形成的法律问题、社会成因和历史因素，为避免给当事人增加诉累，纾解其面临的现实困难，通过公开听证、联合商谈、入户走访等方式，推动当地政府研究制定合理的补偿方案，促成当事人达成和解协议，实质性化解行政争议，实现政治效果、社会效果、法律效果有机统一。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例六&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;周某诉海南省某市某村委会某村民小组集体经济组织成员资格确认检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格确认行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周某于1979年10月6日出生，户籍登记在某市某区某村其父亲周某驹为户主的家庭户口中。周某的父母以家庭承包的方式，承包该村土地11.31亩，承包期限至2027年12月31日。2018年6月13日，周某与外地的冯某登记结婚，但户口未迁出，未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款。2020年10月，某村决定给户口在本村的每个农业人员发放征地补偿款共计人民币80246元，村民小组以周某属于在本集体没有承包地的“外嫁女”，不具有集体经济组织成员资格为由，拒绝向其支付上述征地补偿款。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2021年1月6日，周某以村委会某村村民小组侵害其集体经济组织成员权益为由向某市某区人民法院起诉，法院判决确认周某未丧失村集体经济组织成员资格，仍系某村集体经济组织成员。某村村民小组应向周某支付土地补偿费80246元。该村村民小组不服，提出上诉、再审申请均未获支持。期间，周某两次请求某镇人民政府、某镇农业服务中心帮助解决确认集体经济组织成员资格问题，镇政府一直未处理，某村村民小组一直未支付土地补偿款。周某向某市某区人民检察院申请监督。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关监督情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，现场释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法审查认为，某区人民法院判决认定事实清楚、适用法律正确；某镇政府应当依法履行对某村委会某村村民小组不予确认周某集体经济成员资格、侵害其合法权益行为的监督管理职责。2022年8月22日，某区人民检察院向某镇政府发出《检察建议书》，要求及时协调、监督某村委会某村村民小组确认周某的集体经济组织成员资格，并加强对辖区农村集体成员身份确认工作的指导，避免出现类似侵害“外嫁女”合法权益的情形。同时，某区人民检察院组织公开听证，商请某市某区某镇政府代表、村民小组代表出席听证，邀请人大代表、人民监督员、律师担任听证员，摆事实讲道理，促进实质性化解本案争议。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年9月7日，某镇人民政府作出书面回复，已采纳检察建议，协调村小组人员确认周某集体经济组织成员资格，并已将周某录入集体经济组织成员身份系统，向其出具了集体经济组织成员股权证，并按程序分期向周某支付土地补偿款。2022年11月1日，周某签署了息诉承诺书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、集体经济组织收益分配、土地征收补偿安置或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。认定“外嫁女”是否具有集体经济组织成员资格，应当结合户籍、土地承包经营权、权利义务关系等综合认定，确保“外嫁女”应当享有的利益不落空。与他村村民结婚，但户口未迁出，在本村承包土地、履行村民义务，且未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款的“外嫁女”，依法具有集体经济组织成员资格，享有相关合法权益。检察机关履行法律监督职责中，对行政机关不依法履职导致“外嫁女”合法权益长期得不到解决的行政检察监督案件，综合运用检察建议、公开听证等方式，解决实质诉求，促进争议化解，有效维护妇女合法权益。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省教育厅要求：严禁“萝卜刀”等有害玩具进入校园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259751]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:09:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南都记者获悉，广东省教育厅发布《关于加强有害玩具教育管理的通知》。其中提到，各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园。同时，学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具；关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，近期一款名为“萝卜刀”的新型玩具在中小学生（幼儿）群体中走红。该玩具是一种外形酷似胡萝卜的彩色塑料玩具刀，由于该玩具本身具有攻击性，存在一定的安全隐患，又会形成心理暗示，激发孩子暴力倾向，对未成年人安全健康成长产生不良影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，广东省教育厅要求，加强对学生的安全教育。各地各校（园）要进一步加大安全教育力度，让学生（幼儿）认识到“萝卜刀”等玩具的危险性，自觉拒绝“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具，做到不购买、不携带、不玩耍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对家长的安全提醒。要采取多种形式提醒家长认真履行监护责任，务必选择正规厂商出产的、适合孩子年龄阶段、有益身心健康发展的儿童和学生用品，不要为孩子购买“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具。在玩具使用前，要仔细阅读包装上的警告和提醒内容，做好孩子使用时的安全防范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;严格对校园的安全管理。各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园，在进行安全教育的基础上，对仍带入校园的此类有害玩具，要清查封存。被封存的危险性有害玩具，要通知学生（幼儿）家长到学校接受教育，在作出承诺之后可由家长领回，并督促其销毁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对校园及周边的治理。学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具。要关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各地教育部门要会同相关部门深入开展儿童和学生用品安全治理，以“萝卜刀”等存在物理危害、化学危害、可燃性危害、心理暗示等危险性有害玩具产品为重点，加大校园周边商铺和流动摊贩管理力度，一旦发现存在售卖危险性玩具产品和学生用品的，要严肃查处。各地级以上市教育局于11月10日前，将排查治理工作情况反馈省教育厅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[间隔六年，茅台为何突然提价？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259745]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 17:18:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月1日凌晨，贵州茅台（600519.SH）发布重大事项公告：经研究决定，自2023年11月1日起上调本公司53%vol贵州茅台酒(飞天、五星)出厂价格，平均上调幅度约为20%。此次调整不涉及本公司产品的市场指导价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是贵州茅台自2018年元旦以来，时隔近六年再次提高出厂价。贵州茅台的核心单品飞天茅台出厂价将从此前969元/瓶，上调至约1169元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一重磅消息瞬间引爆了酒圈。多位行业人士在11月1日凌晨对南方周末记者表示，对于贵州茅台在这个时间点提价，感到有些震惊，并且超出预期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受提价消息刺激，11月1日，贵州茅台集合竞价高开9.82%，成交金额超12亿元。开盘后，贵州茅台股价从上一个交易日的1684.58元/股拉至1850元/股，改变了近期表现略显低迷的走势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height=&quot;843&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;自2023年11月1日起，贵州茅台的核心单品飞天茅台出厂价将从此前969元/瓶，上调至约1169元/瓶。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1499&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;元&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的市场指导价没有动&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“出厂价我不关心，但我关心1499元的价格是否会提高。”在茅台深夜发布公告后，有茅台消费者如此表示。2018年元旦，贵州茅台宣布将出厂价从819元/瓶调整到969元/瓶，同时市场指导价从1299元/瓶上调至1499元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵州茅台发布的公告中提及：此次调整不涉及本公司产品的市场指导价格。此次价格调整将会对本公司经营业绩产生一定影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月1日上午，南方周末记者以投资者身份致电贵州茅台董秘办，相关工作人员回复：“我们公告写得很清楚，此次调整的是出厂价，1499元的市场指导价是没有动的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于为何这个时间点进行提价，上述工作人员表示：“由于我们已经接近六年没有做出价格调整，充分考量了宏观经济环境、市场供需变化等因素，坚持以市场、顾客为中心，兼顾企业长远发展，市场长期稳健基础上，调整产品的出厂价格，这是一个正常的、合理的企业经营行为。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者不完全统计，贵州茅台从2001年上市以来，此次调价是第八次，此前调价的时间分别在2001年、2003年、2006年、2008年、2010年、2012年、2018年。而此次调整的间隔时间，是茅台上市以来最长的一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期研究茅台公司的鹤禧投资董事长霍东杰对南方周末记者表示：“此前茅台涨价一般是在白酒周期向上的时候，但近期飞天茅台价格比近几年同期都要弱，譬如历史上，中秋期间是涨价的，今年却是跌的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国最大白酒批发市场百荣市场酒商提供的数据显示，2023年10月31日，53%vol贵州茅台酒的散装飞天价格为2650元/瓶，而在2023年6月下旬，散装飞天价格为2820元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，多位受访者对南方周末记者表示，此次提价，部分经销商的利润将转给茅台，主要影响的是经销商以及经销商以下酒商的渠道利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑州玺韵实业总经理王占甫认为，目前白酒市场除茅台外的名酒品牌核心产品都倒挂严重，此次提价，一方面是行业老大的担当，还有对集团2023年度增长压力的有效释放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“经销商利润就普茅而言本就是暴利，所以此次调价，对经销商的影响并不大，何况经销商会推高流通价，这是贵州茅台强大的品牌张力决定的，其它品牌没有。”王占甫对南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为郑州资深酒商，11月1日上午，王占甫也在密切关注飞天茅台的流通价格，但截至南方周末记者发稿，他表示：“目前酒商大概率不出货，会观察一下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另有受访者表示，此次提价意味着贵州茅台效益的提高以及渠道利润的再分配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1-9月，贵州茅台实现营业收入1032.68亿元，归属于上市公司股东的净利润为528.76亿元。此时调价，意味着2023年最后两个月，将为茅台带来更多营收及净利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍东杰对南方周末记者表示：“我们初步评估，此次调价，将对贵州茅台明年盈利提升6%。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据方正证券估算，此次茅台出厂价由969元提升20%后，约增厚2023年收入62亿元，增厚幅度约4.2%，约增厚净利润41亿元，增厚幅度约5.6%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国酒业智库专家、知趣咨询总经理蔡学飞认为，此次提价有利于提振目前低迷的行业信心，合理的涨价预期也会刺激和拉动相关消费增长，同时呼应长期以来的资本市场需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;茅台提价&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的背后&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对于此次茅台提价，多位受访者表示既在意料之中又在意料之外。毕竟，距离上一次贵州茅台提价，已经过去了近六年，在此期间，茅台何时上调出厂价，一直是市场关注的焦点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期持有茅台股票的一位资深投资者对南方周末记者表示：“从茅台自身讲，前年就强烈希望提价了，但最后没批准，企业诉求很强。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，白酒行业掀起涨价潮，但茅台并没有跟进。在贵州茅台2022年度及第一季度业绩说明会以及2023年6月的股东大会上，茅台董事长丁雄军也多次回应提价问题，他曾表示，要按照价格法等相关法律法规来定茅台酒的价格，定价也会考虑供求关系等因素，“我们一定会充分遵循市场的规律，呼应市场的需求”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位不愿意透露姓名的白酒行业资深人士对南方周末记者表示：“茅台的特殊地位以及经济影响力，决定了茅台的价格调整是极其敏感的，往往涉及企业、政府等多方意见，并且有着严格的论证与保密流程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该人士指出，此次提价确实很突然，但明显有提振信心的意图。另一位长期投资茅台超过二十年的投资机构负责人则对南方周末记者表示：“此次提价，是呵护资本市场政策的一部分。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从企业自身来看，近年来，贵州茅台已经通过减少经销商数量，拓展直销渠道，增加直营店，推出i茅台平台等方法，不断提升直销收入的占比。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年至今，贵州茅台经销商总数从3083家减少到截至2023年三季度末的2082家。千家经销商的减少，带来了贵州茅台直销业务占比的持续增长。2022年，贵州茅台直销业务占比达到40%，2023前三季度，贵州茅台直销收入同比增长44.93%，达到462.07亿元，占总营收的比重约为44.92%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博士过剩愈演愈烈，读博值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;一方面，中国每年博士入学与毕业的人数迭创新高；另一方面，“博士过剩”凸显并愈演愈烈。“核物理博士当城管”“医学博士应聘校医”“博士生争当中小学教师”的新闻屡屡出现，展现出博士生在就业市场上“大材小用”的尴尬。 寒窗十数载，读博还是个好选择吗？</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当世界科幻大会来到中国：“许多超出以往经历的东西”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年建成的成都科幻馆成为10月18日-10月22日举办的世界科幻大会的主场馆。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（成都市郫都区科创新城管委会供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年第81届世界科幻大会的主会场——成都科幻馆，位于一条被称为“科幻大道”周围方圆两公里区域的中心。两年前成都申办成功的时候，这里还是一片旷野。这一本来被规划为“科技馆”的成都市郫都区地块，迅速升级为“科幻馆”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎哈事务所设计的这座科幻馆延续了其对曲线与未来感的追求，在郊区横平竖直的直线丛林里，植入了几瓣人工塑形的曲面。根据官方的说法，那是一片来自宇宙的星云，科幻作家刘慈欣则说，它也像一艘降落在湖畔的外星飞船。不管怎样，这是世界科幻大会，它需要一个视觉意象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是世界科幻大会首次来到中国。最初，世界科幻大会只是美国芝加哥几个不到20岁的年轻人产生的奇想——为全世界科幻迷创造一个集会的平台。1939年，他们在芝加哥举办了第一届大会。通过科幻迷的聚会与自治，全世界喜欢某一部科幻作品的人聚拢在一起，畅聊阅读经验、交换手工艺品、缅怀科幻逝者……八十年来，世界科幻大会传承着这样宽松而富有想象力的基因，生长出了一种独特又持久的科幻文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从巨大的穹顶式入口进入成都科幻馆，需要经过多道安检。开幕式展示了中国式晚会的一些常用元素——主持人高亢的朗诵、色彩饱和的舞台、撑满空间的群舞，但主办方在其中加入了尽可能多的科幻元素，来凸显这届大会的主题“共生纪元”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国的科幻迷文化与我成长时所接触的文化并没有长达几十年的广泛交流，我还有许多超出以往经历的东西需要学习。”本届大会联合主席本·亚洛表示，“当然，对于世界科幻大会的文化，中国科幻迷也有许多需要了解的地方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“会员文化”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月下旬的成都已经有了寒意，也早早过了学生的暑假时间。2021年成都在申办世界科幻大会的时候，很多学生科幻迷为了能在暑假一睹科幻盛会，纷纷花钱注册第79届华盛顿世界科幻大会会员（约合人民币六百多元），为成都投票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照《世界科幻协会章程》，各种名目不同的会员资格均可以购买，而购买当年的会员资格，就可以给两年后的申办城市投票，也可以为雨果奖的入围作品投票。这种做法类似于“众筹”，历届世界科幻大会的预算绝大多数来自会员的购买支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是世界科幻迷中特有的一种会员文化。1950年代，雨果奖设立不久，就增加了粉丝类的奖项，科幻迷自己写的作品、自己办的业余杂志，也可以站上雨果奖的领奖台，与那些“大牛”们的作品交相辉映。世界科幻大会的三大传统核心议题——雨果奖投票评选、事务会议和未来大会的选址投票，无不与普通科幻迷的参与息息相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“它的魅力就在于它是一种基于创造者社区的精神，每一个人既是参与者，又是创造者。这是文化传统赋予它的东西，不是能够随便取代或复制的。”本届大会联合主席陈石对南方周末记者说，让他感到遗憾的是，对于许多幻迷来说，这是一次无法抵达的大会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月20日，成都组委会在推特上宣布举办日期从2023年8月16日推迟到10月18日。“我身边至少有一百多个幻迷朋友来不了。”大学生千星说。他所在的学校离成都很远，他是少数能请得出假的人。千星穿着一套银蓝色的cosplay服装来到会场，非常显眼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果这些幻迷们能够来到成都科幻馆现场，他们在这座庞大、中空的建筑里，会首先看到大厅里一个高达9米的巨型“笨笨”塑像（电影《流浪地球》里的机器人），到了晚上，围绕它的射灯让它表面的颜色开始流动，制造出各种不同状态的“笨笨”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一楼的两个大型展厅分别为企业展厅与科幻迷展厅。企业展厅的几十个展位绝大多数为中国企业，有卖科幻文创的，也有做投影的，更多的是做科幻出版的。他们展位的声光电效果夺人耳目，与旁边的幻迷展区明显不同。企业展厅是此前的世界科幻大会不曾有过的单元。政府的支持、企业的参与、大量赞助商的品牌推广，都让大会有了更多的官方色彩与商业价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻馆附近没法满足这么多参展商的出行与餐饮需求。一位参展商告诉南方周末记者，“哪种票要怎么走、车怎么安排，议程怎么分布”，都是来了之后自己慢慢摸索出来的；这个崭新的会场周边商业还很稀少，如果不想吃会场内的餐饮如肯德基和赛百味，每天中午得去几公里外找吃的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和企业展区的酷炫相比，科幻迷展区显得朴素许多。一张桌子、一面旗帜、一张介绍卡片或者二维码，他们来自大学社团、国外的科幻组织，还有未成名的业余作者……有点像大学社团的招新现场。藏语科幻社团的桌子上，摆放着多年来出版的藏语科幻作品，一位藏族小伙耐心地给好奇的围观者介绍藏语科幻的历史。这样的氛围，更像此前的世界科幻大会，科幻文学研究学者严锋曾经参加过2019年都柏林世界科幻大会，回忆起那边的氛围，“自由散漫。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻馆二楼与三楼的会议室都被用来举办各种“沙龙”。所谓“沙龙”，就是科幻迷们自己组织的各种研讨会。科幻迷们自己邀请嘉宾，自己定选题，呈报给组委会之后，一般都会通过，然后组委会安排时间、场地，不再过问其他事务。历届世界科幻大会的沙龙场次稳定在三四百场之间。成都世界科幻大会报名的沙龙有四百多场，最终保留了230多场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次成都组委会一共邀请了六百多位嘉宾，其中海外嘉宾180多人（到场150多人），他们构成了沙龙的主力群体。过去的世界科幻大会，官方邀请的嘉宾只占很少一部分，其他参加沙龙的是科幻迷自己邀请的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈石在芝加哥世界科幻大会上也申请过一个沙龙。“我就带个表格，组委会直接跟我说地点、时间，你自己搞就OK了，他们就不怎么管你了。”陈石说，“在中国的文化背景下，可能这样并不合适。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“国外的世界科幻大会，对幻迷圈很有吸引力，但不出圈，他们的核心会员就两万多人，每年来的人变化不是很大，形成了自己的社群文化，要进入这个社群是有文化门槛的。如果我们完完全全照搬那个的话可能会非常惨，这个东西很难进入各个圈层。”当一开始陈石思考要办一届怎样的世界科幻大会的时候，他就已经决定要走一条不一样的路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨枫是科幻类出版企业八光分的CEO，她主编的《中国科幻口述史》也入围了2023年的雨果奖。她参加过多届世界科幻大会。她向南方周末记者回忆着此前的那些沙龙和展览，“那就像是科幻迷的party（聚会），没有多少&#39;高大上&#39;的设计，各种各样的coser（二次元形象模仿者）满场走，也有人围一个小圈子，整天弹吉他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让她流连忘返的还有曾经的跳蚤市场，每一年，科幻迷们都把自己的收藏、手工艺品、二手书拿到世界科幻大会的跳蚤市场拍卖，每个人在一个小牌子上写上自己心仪的价格，价高者得，“几乎每届我都拍到了我喜欢的东西”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“事务会议”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;质询、辩论&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;和&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;投票&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“您好，您的发言并不关涉到是与否的问题，而是另一个话题。”“您好，您的发言时间到了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星的发言不时地被主席台上的计时员打断。这是千星第一次来到世界科幻大会，也和绝大多数中国科幻迷一样，第一次体验事务会议。很多中国科幻迷流连于展区与沙龙，却往往忽视了这个重要会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但老科幻迷们都知道，“去参加事务会议，才能对世界科幻协会、世界科幻大会的组织方式和参与方式有一个深入的理解，而且你会感觉到一些好玩的地方。”陈石说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“事务会议”是每一届大会的重要议程，甚至是核心议程。在这个连续四五天的会议上，会员们经过质询、辩论、投票，对世界科幻大会的各种事务进行监督，也负责修改世界科幻大会的基石——《世界科幻协会章程》的某些条款。英语中，这个章程被称为“constitution”（宪法）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场会议的实践对于大多数中国科幻迷来说，都显得新鲜，甚至有点刺激。“什么是落日条款？”遇到不懂的法律名词，他们在现场也会坦诚地表达出来。他们的问题被来自全世界的人认真倾听。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果亲身感受过事务会议的流程与辩论，就不难理解幻迷圈为何将该会议称为“修宪会议”。成都世界科幻大会的事务会议放在了科幻馆的流星厅，这是一个独立于主馆的小厅，具有会员资格的人可以随时进入旁听、发表意见和投票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星是在场中国会员中发言最为积极的，几乎每个议题，他都要发表自己的看法，说到忘我处，往往超出发言时间，被要求终止发言——这是一场严格按照《罗伯特议事规则》进行发言辩论的会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今年人来得少，往年更热闹。”八光分影视总监西夏对南方周末记者说。每年事务会议之前会有一个预备会议，讨论事务会议的具体安排。往年的预备会议也热闹非凡，往往主持人开讲没几分钟，就有会员跳出来质疑各种安排，“有的人说要配几个翻译，有的人说屏幕要怎么显示，最后双方各辩论两分钟预备会议要不要开始。”陈石回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于来的人少，副审裁官凯文·斯坦利对陈石透露，2023年应该是预备会议上“扯皮”最少的一届。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流星厅里远远没有坐满，门口放着厚厚的两本书，《罗伯特议事规则》的中英文版本，会员若对辩论流程有意见，可以随时查阅质询。西夏这次带来了自己的“宪法修正案”，他想要增设一个雨果奖奖项，颁给独立电影人制作的科幻电影，他认为目前的“最佳戏剧表现（长片）”这一奖项过于重视商业大片而忽视独立电影了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年代的幻迷大多是科幻小说的拥趸，于是最先设立的雨果奖便是1953年的最佳长篇小说奖，此后慢慢地追加了粉丝杂志、戏剧表演和漫画类的奖项。如果翻看历年得奖的电影，会发现大多数是好莱坞的商业大制作，西夏认为有必要改变这种状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“打个比方，小说的奖项，我们已经有给商业上最成功、最有名的小说发奖，但还有一些粉丝创作的、没有得到商业关注但是圈里面觉得写得很好的小说，雨果奖会给他们颁最佳粉丝作者、最佳粉丝杂志、最佳粉丝播客。这样的奖项电影类也应该有一个。”西夏说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想要在“修宪会议”上通过新的修正案，至少需要两年时间。提案如果能在第一年的大会上辩论通过，就会变成正式的修正提案，第二年再次进行二审辩论，通过之后才算“修宪”成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年进行二审辩论的有两个提案，其中一个是“是否增设雨果奖最佳游戏或互动作品的奖项”。在场的中国会员们似乎对这一提案普遍持谨慎态度，他们质疑“游戏”的定义，尤其是科幻类游戏的边界似乎并不清晰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“辩论时间结束。请支持这一提案的人站起来……反对这一提案的人站起来……”审裁官唐纳德·伊斯特雷克说。最后的投票结果为10：3，修正案通过，这意味着今后雨果奖就要增设这一奖项了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星最激动的一次发言针对的是一个2023年的新提案。这一由凯文·斯坦利提出的新提案呼吁，此后的世界科幻大会在举办时间上最好在8月1日到9月30日之间，如果超出这一范围，应该和下一届的主办城市进行协商。千星的意见是，除了要和下一届主办方协商，还需要和会员们商量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“会员大会的参与者，有权利知道大会要更改日期。他们和组委会协商，组委会可以不采用这个会员的意见，但是这样协商的环节一定要有，一定要有表达意见的环节。”事务会议的休息空档，南方周末记者采访了千星。他看上去有些激动，大步走上主席台，发言语速慢却有力，希望把这个和会员协商的条款增补进凯文的提案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过投票，凯文的提案获得了通过，千星的增补条款没有获得通过。然而，整场会议都有视频摄录，千星的发言与意见已经被记录，成为了世界科幻大会的永久历史档案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西夏的提案也获得了初审通过。等到明年的格拉斯哥世界科幻大会，凯文与西夏的提案会被会员们再次审视、辩论、投票。《世界科幻协会章程》通过这种方式，让世界科幻大会回应着时代的变化与幻迷的诉求。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;创纪录、创历史&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日晚，第81届成都世界科幻大会颁出了这一届雨果奖。在此之前，本届奖项提名增加了不少有色面孔，中国入围者令人瞩目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国插画师赵恩哲获得了最佳职业艺术家奖，中国科幻迷河流与零始真编辑的《零重力报》获得了最佳粉丝杂志奖，科幻作家海漄的小说《时空画师》获得了“最佳短中篇小说奖”。按照雨果奖的传统，大会组委会要在颁奖之后公开投票的细节和数据，比如2022年芝加哥世界科幻大会的数据现在依然可以在官网上查到。这次大会之后，雨果奖官网上写道：“目前我们并没有此次投票数据的细节。我们将在获得数据的第一时间公布。”成都世界科幻大会中文官网上也暂时未能查到这个数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雨果奖评选委员会负责人戴夫·麦卡蒂在颁奖晚会后对记者说：“海漄的《时空画师》并没有英文译本，它创造了一个无英文译本、完全由中文作品获奖的历史。”这就意味着，给《时空画师》投票的会员可能大多是中国读者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;颁奖第二天，刊载《时空画师》的《银河边缘》（mook）在科幻馆内被销售一空，由于询问的人太多，科幻迷展区的售书摊上不得不挂出“售空”的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样卖得火热的当然还有刘慈欣作品，10月20日下午两点是刘慈欣的签售会，其他作家的签售一般只被安排了20分钟，主办方给刘慈欣预留了三个小时的签售时间。粉丝们早早挤满三楼签售大厅，队伍从三楼一直延伸到一楼，再蜿蜒绕了半圈的会场，很多站到腿酸的粉丝坐到了大刘的书上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来参展的各家出版机构想要在这个会场里签售自己的图书，并不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希希是一家出版机构的编辑，这次他带来了一位作者的科幻小说到成都，还组织了一个沙龙，希望科幻迷们可以和作家本人好好聊聊，再办一个签售会。一开始，希希把整个流程都申报给了组委会，但到了开幕前几天收到通知，沙龙不能和签售放在一起。“平时的书展活动，作者和读者交流完之后有签售，但这里两个场地一定要分开，时间段也会分开。”希希说。这也就意味着，对作者有兴趣的读者，得跑两趟才能获得签名本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界科幻大会会场里的沙龙、论坛、峰会林林总总，但是除了开闭幕式、雨果奖颁奖晚会之外，还有一场“产业发展峰会”，几乎所有主要嘉宾都被邀请出席了这场峰会，阵容堪比雨果奖颁奖之夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是第一次在世界科幻大会上举办产业发展的相关会议。会上，多项科幻产业发展相关的计划被公布，包括《科幻产业成都共识》、“天问”计划、《2023中国成都科幻产业报告》等，甚至还有科幻产业项目的集中签约仪式，据统计有21个签约项目，总投资达80亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个“产业发展峰会”上，刘慈欣也不再聊文学，而是对产业发展侃侃而谈，：“成都很早就谋划布局科幻产业，相关的产业规划、产业政策、人才政策等均已落地实施。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“科幻全产业链生态圈”“IP打造”“强化科幻之都形象”，面对这些五花八门的新鲜词汇，加拿大科幻作家罗伯特·索耶表示，“看到你们把科幻变成产业，感到非常震惊。”他说，在北美做这些事情的可能是出版商，科幻就是随意的、漫无目的的、没有长期规划的一个事业。这些产业界人士在以往的世界科幻大会上一般不被邀请，来的大多是作家、编辑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都科幻馆所在的这一片区域，也将被打造为成都的科幻高地。据一位接近当地政府的人士向南方周末记者介绍，这里以后可能要建一个科幻产业园，“那条街就是一个科幻主题的街区，一家家科幻企业后续可能会入驻，这一片说是要搞一个科幻露营基地，每年会做科幻作家的训练营和学生的夏令营，而科幻馆本身是一个大型的消费+公益结合的空间，这一圈会打造成一个科幻主题的旅游目的地。”他站在高台之上，手指从这一头划向那一头，划出一个大大的弧线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当地政府做了场馆、交通等保障工作，还发动了很多志愿者，”陈石说，“诉求核心就两点，一是提升成都的城市品牌形象，二是扶持科幻产业。”这届大会还创下了一个纪录——它拉到了有史以来最多的赞助商。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是什么让中国年轻人喜欢科幻？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;午后的幻迷展区，喧嚣异常，即便这一天已经是世界科幻大会的最后一天。一个机器人鼓手在角落里循环敲击着鼓点，家长带着孩子们坐了两个小时的公共交通，现在刚刚入馆，孩子们手上拿着敲章打卡的本子，尖叫着穿梭于各个展台之间。还有一位科幻迷拿着自己写的书在宣传：“我写的书和刘慈欣的世界观截然相反……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这片喧闹海洋之中，有一个人在椅子上打盹儿。他满头白发，牛仔帽放在桌上，双眼低垂，像是进入了另一个世界。他叫詹姆斯·约瑟夫，来自澳大利亚，七十多岁的他已经当了近五十年科幻迷。1975年，世界科幻大会第一次在大洋洲举办，他被科幻的氛围打动，至今已经去过15次世界科幻大会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;詹姆斯对南方周末记者说，这次大会是他去过的最特殊的一届，以前不管是在欧洲还是美国，从来没有见过这么多热情而年轻的科幻迷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年轻，是这届大会的一个关键词。“我今天签的名比过去56年加起来还多。”被找他签名的小学生们团团围住，尼古拉斯·怀特显得有点受宠若惊，学生们顺着摊位，一家一家地打卡、要签名。组委会和成都很多中小学达成合作，组织了很多学生去各种沙龙与论坛旁听，科幻馆里几乎没有冷场的时候。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2025年西雅图申幻组委会成员艾伦·布兰特对南方周末记者说，成都世界科幻大会的规模是他见过最大的。此前这项纪录的保持者是2014年的伦敦，参会人数在1万人左右。而据官方媒体公布的数字，成都的参会者超过了2万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，科幻文学的黄金年代是二战之后的几十年。当时正值美苏争霸，西方经济高速发展，科幻文学顺势而动，成为当时很多年轻人的精神家园。半个多世纪过去，当年的科幻迷们垂垂老矣，像詹姆斯·约瑟夫这样的西方老科幻迷，他们的银发是成都科幻馆里的亮点。“对于美国的科幻作品来说，很多读者都是灰头发，也就是中老年人才会读科幻作品，但是中国相反，年轻人更喜欢科幻作品。这是我的困惑，是什么让中国年轻人喜欢科幻？”罗伯特·索耶在成都提出了这个问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前的每次大会，都会专设一个缅怀区域，这是一个中老年科幻迷怀旧、叙旧的地方。2017年，英国科幻作家布莱恩·奥尔迪斯去世，当年的世界科幻大会就有一个小小的空间，里面展陈着他生前的作品、照片，和一些他收藏的宝贝，一台朴素的黑白电视机，播放他生前的采访视频。2023年，奥尔迪斯的女儿温蒂也来到了成都，她告诉南方周末记者，原本成都世界科幻大会要为这些照片举办一个展览，但后来“因为空间不够”，没能实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨枫原本也打算在大会上办一个缅怀的展览。缅怀的人物是美国科幻杂志《银河边缘》的前主编迈克尔·雷斯尼克。2020年，雷斯尼克去世之后，他的收藏和图书被挂到网上拍卖，八光分买到了大量他的藏品，“你看这个玻璃展柜里全是他的东西。”杨枫指着一个玻璃柜说。一开始，主办方答应给70平米的展陈面积。由于担心错过会期，藏品“花了上万元运费运回来”。后来展区被很多科技企业挤占，只给了杨枫一面玻璃展柜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们的黄金年代确实已经过去了。”严锋说，“而中国的科幻热又有很多网络的特征，我在这里看到很多人追星，听到很多尖叫，特别是对大刘和郭帆这样的人。中国科幻发展起来有它的幸运，网络文化的助推是非常有力的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都本土科幻作家何夕认为，目前的中国科幻处于第三次浪潮初期。“第一次是建国之初百业俱兴，第二次是1979年&#39;科学的春天&#39;，现在是第三次。”他说。另一位已经封笔的科幻作家王晋康也回忆了1990年代中国科幻的低潮期，“那时候中国科幻是野生野长，不太被社会关注，但是也有很多科幻迷，我们到大学里参加活动，都是用粉笔在黑板上写一个&#39;欢迎王晋康先生&#39;，就这样开始交流。那时的简陋也有它的情趣，现在还很怀念。现在确实不一样了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你能在大会的会场里隐隐感到一种科幻文化的冲突，”《零重力报》的编辑零始真对南方周末记者讲述了他的观察，“但我并不认为这种冲突是一种有害的，或者没有意义的东西，这是一个必经的过程。既然你要拥抱一个真正多元的世界，这一步是逃不开的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为大学老师，严锋已经很久没有在国内的学术会议上见过那么多国际友人了，这让他颇为感动，“目前这个分裂的世界，越来越相互隔绝，甚至对抗、敌视，但是科幻肯定是要超越国界来思考人类层面的问题，这也是科幻可贵的地方。”就像刘慈欣曾在不同场合所强调的，“科幻小说里，人类是作为一个整体出现的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦·布兰特说西雅图世界科幻大会已经搞定了场馆，但当地的科幻协会还在和酒店谈判，以期拿到更低的价格。尼古拉斯·怀特说自己有点“嫉妒”成都，明年的格拉斯哥世界科幻大会他估计拉不到这么多赞助：“很显然，成都世界科幻大会得到了当地政府的巨大支持，这在欧洲是很难实现的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（希希、千星为化名，南方周末实习生陈荃新对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[试管婴儿纳入医保：不孕不育是医学问题，也是社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259718]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，广西壮族自治区医保局等部门印发《关于将部分治疗性辅助生殖类医疗服务项目纳入基本医疗保险和工伤保险基金支付范围的通知》，将取卵术、胚胎培养、胚胎移植等辅助生殖项目纳入基本医保支付范围，职工医保与居民医保报销比例分别为70%与50%。新规于2023年11月1日起执行。据南宁市第二人民医院生殖医疗中心主任李荣估算，按上述通知，生育困难妇女做一代、二代试管婴儿，根据险种不同，可报销幅度在4000多元至1万多元不等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一举措，再次引发关注与讨论。此前，已有若干省份将辅助生殖项目纳入基本医保。自今年7月1日起，北京将包括“试管婴儿”、人工授精等在内的16项治疗性辅助生殖技术项目纳入基本医保报销范围；辽宁今年也将胚胎培养、胚胎移植术等18项辅助生殖项目纳入生育保险目录。可以想见，会有更多省份跟进，辅助生殖技术进基本医保或成标配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受惠于这一医保政策主要是两类家庭：一类家庭是高龄产妇有生育需求但难以自然怀孕，另一类家庭是（非年龄因素导致的）不孕不育，如先天因素、生育史、生活方式或环境因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家人类辅助生殖技术评审组专家张学红介绍：一般认为女性生理上的理想生育年龄是22-28岁，或至少不超过35岁，因为生育能力或卵巢功能在35岁之前达到峰值，之后便快速下降，超龄生育风险也会随之增高；而且，根据她的临床经验来看，近年来寻求辅助生殖的患者，平均年龄有年轻化的趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一类家庭的辅助生育需求源于：随着结婚与生育的不断推迟，年龄因素导致的不孕人数越来越高。据2017年生育状况抽样调查数据，2006至2016年，中国女性平均初育年龄从2006年的24.3岁上升到2016年的26.9岁。而在大城市，初育与生育年龄更迟，如2022年上海平均初育年龄为30.36岁，平均生育年龄为31.18岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二类不孕不育家庭，除了先天性因素外，生育史也是一个绕不过去的重大因素。2021年，北京大学第三医院院长乔杰发布《柳叶刀中国妇幼健康特邀重大报告》，报告称，2007-2020年间，我国不孕发病率从12%升至18%。在生育史方面，流产尤其是反复流产可能导致术后的输卵管炎、子宫内膜炎，甚至输卵管粘连堵塞、宫腔粘连，进而导致不孕。上述报告显示，2005-2017年，中国人工流产率从20.2‰升至27.3‰。在中国至少经历过一次流产的女性中，重复流产率为65.2%。居高不下的流产率及重复流产率同不孕率高度正相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因想要一个孩子的愿望强烈而求助于辅助生育技术，如试管婴儿，并不是“洒洒水”的轻松事儿，基本上做一次就成功是撞大运，从取卵到胚胎培养再到胚胎移植，每一个环节都可能出问题而功败垂成，身体遭受的痛苦、精神承受的压力，不足为外人道也。所付出的成本，不仅仅是金钱、时间与精力，更多的是精神上的负担与耗损。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个意义上，试管婴儿纳入基本医保，只能部分覆盖这些家庭所承受的财务成本，但无法从根本上解决不孕不育问题，因为不孕不育既是医学问题，也是社会问题。而一般来说，一个问题，在未出现或萌芽状态就予以重视，该预防就预防，该解决就解决，成本是最低的；等到酿成大规模社会问题再去应对，不仅成本会呈指数级上升，而且效果也难以让人满意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，可以解决的不孕不育问题是：让初育年龄往前推，落到最佳生育年龄区间内，这就要及早婚育；减少流产率尤其重复流产率，这就要降低乃至避免计划外的怀孕。这样比将来求助于辅助生殖技术好。对个人与家庭来说，显然可以这样考量与决策。不过，一个问题一旦上升为社会问题，就没有那么简单了，因为这一社会问题的本质是价值观问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多人把婚育年龄推迟、生育率下降、不婚不育族兴起，归结为生育成本太高。但就生育而言，显然收益端比成本端更重要。现在不少年轻男女追问“结婚组成家庭与生儿育女的意义何在”，本身就意味着生育本能与婚育价值观的骤变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我们生活在一个前所未有的和平与繁荣时代，物质丰裕是空前的，这第一会导致选择压的降低与消失，此时种群更倾向于自我享受而不是牺牲自我享受、含辛茹苦来抚育后代；第二会导致不婚不育观念的兴起，此种观念反过来又会进一步压制婚育意愿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于居高不下的流产率尤其重复流产率问题，从术的层面看，无非是加强避孕措施的问题；从道的层面看，还有一个如何加强性道德的问题。父母应该关心子女的价值观，言传身教子女对性有一个严肃与谨慎的态度：男性当然应该尊重女性的权利与意愿，并负起应有的责任；女性作为自己身心健康的第一责任人，应该保护自己的身体与生殖健康，在中国司法实践上，生育权或生育决定权是女性独有的，这权利的另一面意味着对自己的终极责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>