<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中国新金融竞争力榜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256721]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Benchmarking is the best state and core consideration for business competition. Finance is the blood of the economy, affecting the whole body. What should be special about its benchmark? In order to highlight the commonality of financial benchmarks, the research team of Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center spent more than four months to build a scientific and rigorous evaluation index system, and used the 2022 financial report as the benchmark value, following the principle of openness and fairness, to select &quot; China’s New Financial Competitiveness Ranking”. This list is divided into six sub-lists: &quot;Wealth Management List&quot;, &quot;Green Finance List&quot;, &quot;Digital Finance List&quot;, &quot;Data Security List&quot;, &quot;Life Insurance Efficiency Improvement List&quot; and &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency List&quot;.</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[教师的主业是教书育人，而不是攒论文]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, I had a dinner with several fellow villagers. A physical education teacher who works in a primary school in Guangzhou expressed his difficulties to me. He works diligently and conscientiously. More than 20 years have passed, but he still cannot be awarded a senior professional title because he has no grasp of thesis writing and has never published a scientific research paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of fellow students is not unique. Many primary and secondary school teachers, especially older teachers, were turned away during the professional title review process because they did not complete the basic requirements for writing scientific research papers, regardless of their teaching years. How long it has been, how rich the teaching experience is, and how many outstanding students it has trained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A journal editor friend of mine told me that her professional title evaluation was based on the editing sequence, but the evaluation indicators were basically the same as those of scientific researchers. In other words, the relevant parties&#39; performance evaluation is based on the same as that of a full-time scientific researcher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the experiences of teachers, there are doctors and people in other fields. For example, doctors also have basic requirements for scientific research papers or scientific research projects during the professional title evaluation process. They are busy treating diseases and saving people, and have no time to write papers, or are unable to complete papers. When the time comes for professional title evaluation, they are often at a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An agricultural expert may have rich practical experience in agriculture. After years of exploration and practice, he and his team have cultivated improved seeds, greatly increased grain output, and significantly increased grain productivity. He has trained many outstanding talents, but perhaps he still has an intermediate professional title simply because he is old and does not have or is not good at writing and publishing papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, writing papers and applying for projects have become prerequisites for the evaluation of professional titles for most professional and technical personnel. Without a paper of a certain weight and a project of a certain level, you cannot be promoted to a professional title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are several basic problems here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, papers and projects have become the most important factors in the assessment and evaluation mechanism of practitioners in many industries. Is this reasonable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Common sense tells us that a teacher’s primary duty is to teach and educate people so that students can grow and thrive healthily; a doctor’s primary duty is to treat illnesses and save people, and relieve patients from their illnesses. Compared with publishing papers or applying for projects, teaching or saving people are the most important things for teachers or doctors. It is really difficult and unnecessary to ask every teacher to be good at doing scientific research and writing papers, to ask every doctor to be good at doing scientific research and writing papers, and to ask every agricultural expert to write papers and submit projects. In other words, if you put the importance of writing papers and applying for projects above teaching, saving people, and taking root in the field, you are literally putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, since papers and topics should not be the most important indicators, why are they most frequently adopted in various personnel assessment and evaluation mechanisms? This is mainly due to the advantages of quantification. Generally speaking, for the assessment of a person, quantitative indicators are generally better than qualitative indicators. The former can eliminate subjective factors such as favors or relationships to a certain extent, that is, by counting the number of published papers and the level of journals, the level of applied topics and Funding is used to determine a person&#39;s professional level. As the main basis for professional title evaluation, it is relatively fair and fair, and it is relatively simple to operate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, are published papers or successfully applied topics necessarily very good? Can it truly reflect the scientific research ability or professional level of the person concerned? Not really. Many teachers are busy with daily teaching, or are not familiar with the routine of writing papers due to their old age. Many doctors are busy with heavy work and have no time to write papers. What should I do? Some people can only temporarily hire gunmen to write their papers and buy space to publish them. There are even “paper processing factories” and “paper gunmen” emerging one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result is that fake and shoddy papers are flying all over the place. Even if many papers are published, the authors themselves are too lazy to pay attention to them, and either shelve them or abandon them. Many papers are completed behind closed doors in the office, that is, mainly by purchasing data, constructing models, copying and pasting, and revising and revising. As for the relationship between the theoretical contribution of the paper and its practical value, and the relationship between the paper and one&#39;s own field of expertise, it is not important. What is important is that the article has been put into print. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same way, the funds applied for for many projects are not small, ranging from several million to tens of millions, but they are of little help in solving major issues in China&#39;s comprehensive modernization process, and they are not very helpful in promoting this discipline. There are very few major theoretical innovation contributions in the field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, what is a good paper or a good topic? Yu believes that a good topic or paper must originate from real production and life practices, must be combined with real production and life practices, and must undergo careful and rigorous exploration, investigation and research, or fill a certain research field. The blanks will either play a positive role in promoting human understanding and revealing the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course qualified teachers are encouraged to write papers, but the direct or main purpose of writing papers is to improve the quality of teaching, not to complete requirements, let alone write empty and irrelevant articles that have nothing to do with their own teaching. Boring garbage article. As a teacher, the topic or focus of the paper or topic should mainly focus on teaching, such as the discussion of teaching methods, the improvement of teaching forms, the summary of teaching experience, the design of teaching models, etc. As a doctor, the topic or focus of his paper or project should mainly originate from or be inspired by his own medical treatment process. The paper or project should be conducive to the fundamental alleviation or solution of a difficult and complicated disease and contribute to the practical improvement of medical treatment. It plays a practical role in improving patient treatment efficiency and fundamentally improving human health conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant parties need to re-examine and seriously reflect on the concrete meaning of the four words &quot;people-oriented&quot;: schools are places to cultivate talents, &quot;people-oriented&quot; should be student-oriented, and teachers&#39; primary responsibility is to make students healthy Growth and vigorous development; the hospital is a place where diseases are treated and patients are saved. &quot;Humanism&quot; is based on the patient, and the doctor&#39;s primary responsibility is to relieve the patient&#39;s pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the assessment and evaluation of relevant practitioners, the overall principle is to allow most people to return to their main business or first business, give full play to their strengths, and fundamentally change or optimize the current KPI assessment system in all walks of life. inappropriate or unreasonable elements, moderately or significantly reduce the proportion of papers or topics; implement different assessment methods and details for different types of practitioners, including paper or topic assessments and practical ability assessments, rather than the current relative The prevailing one-way street of only essays or only topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 19:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《横琴方案》发布两周年，数读成绩单丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72646&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69538&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Second Anniversary of the Hengqin Plan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;8301&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250814&quot; style=&quot; &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在“被强奸”漩涡中挣扎八天后，一位44岁农妇选择自杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house hidden under the trees, Yi Yonghong&#39;s self-report of being &quot;raped&quot; The place where the incident occurred. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height =&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house hidden under the trees is where the &quot;rape&quot; incident described by Yoshinaga Hong took place. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 23, 2023, Yi Yonghong decided to commit suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She placed the suicide note on the plastic stool at the head of the bed, and her purse and mobile phone, which she never left, were neatly placed beside the bed. The purse contained more than 3,000 yuan in cash. She locked the door and ignored the clothes in the washing machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m leaving. I don&#39;t know what I can do to make you less hurt... I don&#39;t ask you to forgive me. I just hope that you can live a happy life and forget that I am a bad wife and mother.&quot; .&quot; She said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To commit suicide, she chose a mile away. She had to pass through a large guava field. The unripe fruits wrapped in white plastic bags were hung all over the orchard. They were the fruits of her summer. The guava tree is not high, so you have to bend down when walking through it, and you have to cross a drainage ditch in three to five steps. The last section of the road is a slope about two meters high. Climb up and you will reach the embankment. A wide pond with a wide water surface slowly unfolds in front of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The embankment is covered with mimosa, lush and green. The pair of pink slippers were neatly placed on the steps by Yi Yonghong, with the toes facing the pond. A few hours later, her husband Cheng Shanzhi discovered her. She was wearing a red top and floating in a prone position in the middle of the pond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight days before committing suicide, at the age of 44, she reported that she was raped by fruit vendor Huang Mouguan. The police decided not to file the case because the existing evidence could not prove that a crime had occurred. After committing suicide, the police decided to open a case for investigation on September 7 because &quot;new evidence was discovered.&quot; In order to prove that she was raped, she was preserved in an ice coffin and underwent a craniotomy and a thoracotomy for an autopsy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Misfortune in the banana fields&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Typhoon Taili is approaching. Before the violent storm arrived, Yi Yonghong had to cut down more than 20 acres of plantains at home. Nine years ago, this couple from Yongzhou, Hunan, planted fruits on a contracted land in Wenchang, Hainan. Now the contracted land covers nearly 50 acres, half of which is planted with bananas and the other half with guava. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong’s WeChat chat records show that on the evening of July 14, she and Huang Mouguan finalized the time to harvest bananas the next day. Huang Mouguan opened a fruit wholesale stall near the busiest park in Wenchang, and would go to fruit farmers&#39; homes to buy fruit. In the Wenchang area, most of the fruit growers are outsiders who have crossed the Qiongzhou Strait to make a living, and most of the fruit vendors are Hainan locals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong rarely goes out in public to sell bananas, and spends most of his time working in the banana fields. In early 2023, Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband Cheng Shanzhi started doing business with Huang Mouguan after being introduced by a fellow villager. By the time the incident occurred, he had sold bananas to him five times in total, with a transaction volume of 1,480 yuan. The first two times, Cheng Shanzhi cut down plantains and traded them with Huang Mouguan. Because her husband&#39;s left ankle was severely cut due to an accident, Yi Yonghong took over the job of cutting plantains for the next three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was these three experiences of selling bananas alone that pushed Yi Yonghong&#39;s life to a point of no return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The banana land contracted by Yi Yonghong and his wife is not close to the village where she rents, and it takes half an hour by electric bicycle. In 2014, they built a shelter house using hollow bricks next to the plantain field. There was no other house within a radius of 200 meters. When we moved out in 2022, there was only a guard dog and a few free-range chickens left there. The unused old house began to fall into dust and became desolate. There was no longer a fire in the kitchen, and no one could sleep on the bed. Except for resting when working, Yi Yonghong rarely came here. The airtight trees almost swallowed up the small house. house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house at the crime scene. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house at the crime scene. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time Yi Yonghong took over for her husband who injured his foot and cut bananas alone with Huang Mouguan was on July 2. To cut bananas, vendors usually go to the fields to select the bananas, and the farmers carry them to the field, where they are finally weighed and loaded onto trucks. Yi Yonghong seems to particularly like pink. She has a short-sleeved shirt of this color, which she wears specially when working. Her right shoulder is covered with dark green glue marks from banana. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong later told her husband that that time, Huang Mouguan took the opportunity to help her carry the banana on his shoulders and touched her breasts. He also said to her: &quot;Don&#39;t do such hard work, I will give you money.&quot; Yi Yonghong refused him: &quot;Don&#39;t say this, we are doing hard work to earn hard money, I am not that Plant people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No more evidence can be obtained for what happened in the banana field. Other merchants next to Huang Mouguan&#39;s fruit shop said they had not seen him for more than a month after the incident. On the afternoon of September 2, Huang&#39;s wife was selling fruit at a stall next to the shop. She was emotional and refused to be interviewed: &quot;You don&#39;t know how much impact they have on our lives. I am under great pressure.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week later, the bananas had to be picked again. Yi Yonghong and Huang Mouguan met again in the deserted banana field with wild vegetation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of meeting seems inevitable: Yoshinaga chooses to endure it, and there are only three &quot;basho bosses&quot; working with them at the same time. One is a very old man who walks a little shaky, and the other boss does not The last one who came to purchase was Huang Mouguan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his wife’s account to Cheng Shanzhi, Huang Mouguan once again committed inappropriate behavior. After the attempt, Huang Mouguan gave Yi Yonghong an additional 100 yuan in addition to the 470 yuan in banana money, “My wife just Throw it back to him without asking for it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time was two days before the typhoon arrived. Cheng Shanzhi said that on July 15, Yi Yonghong arrived at the banana field at the agreed time and selected, cut off the backs, weighed and loaded the bananas. After paying the money, a heavy rainstorm suddenly fell from the sky in the afternoon. Yi Yonghong told Huang Mouguan, who had a canopy installed on the car, that he did not have a raincoat and would wait until the rain stopped before leaving, so he asked him to go first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Yi Yonghong entered the house and sat on the bed that she had not slept on for nearly a year to take shelter from the rain. In the subsequent report, Yi Yonghong said that she was raped at that time. Afterwards, Huang Mouguan left 150 yuan and ran away. Two days later, she told her husband that she felt a little uncomfortable after drinking the honey chrysanthemum tea handed to her by Huang Guan that day. She didn&#39;t know whether it was because of the heat stroke or the chrysanthemum tea, but she felt dizzy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Husband and daughter’s questioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If her husband hadn’t found out, Yi Yonghong originally planned to let these things rot in her stomach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision to &quot;hide it&quot; is not difficult to make. In the subsequent live recording of the two parties’ contact, Yoshinaga stated that she was worried that if she told her husband what had happened, he would definitely retaliate against him and eventually harm his two children. “I just want to protect this family.” Cheng Shanzhi added that his wife had other considerations, such as the fact that the other party was rich and powerful and she was a wandering migrant; another example was that she was &quot;raped&quot; at the age of 44, which was &quot;disgraceful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong has been covering up the traces of being &quot;raped&quot;. Huang Mouguan forced her to go to bed for the first time. When Yi Yonghong broke away and ran away, her inner thighs were red. When her husband asked, she lied that it was scratched on her back. After the incident, Yi Yonghong fell three times while riding her bike home. After returning home, Cheng Shanzhi saw that she was unhappy, but she didn&#39;t suffer any injuries, so he didn&#39;t take it to heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the night of the incident, Yi Yonghong asked her husband to sleep in her daughter&#39;s spare room, which made Cheng Shanzhi feel something was wrong. After 23 years of marriage, they rarely sleep in separate beds. Later, Yi Yonghong explained to her husband that the reason for dividing the room was that she didn&#39;t know whether Huang Guan was sick and was afraid of infecting him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how much his wife wanted to hide it, Cheng Shanzhi, who was full of doubts, discovered the clues the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As usual, Cheng Shanzhi rides to the banana patch every morning to feed the guard dog. When he opened the door, he found that the pillows on the bed had been touched, and only a small roll of paper towels was left in a large roll that had not been used for a long time. Cheng Shanzhi &quot;immediately suspected that this might happen.&quot; He didn&#39;t buy any groceries, so he hurried to his home in Sanpaipo Village and asked his wife what happened yesterday, but the answer he got was &quot;nothing happened.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that the roll of paper towels was strangely lacking. He thought that he and his wife would use paper towels to wipe after sex, so he continued to press. Until late at night, after questioning still yielded no results, he called his daughter who was working in Haikou during the summer vacation, hoping that her daughter could ask him something. At first, her 22-year-old daughter Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t believe what her father said, but she felt that he was very angry on the phone. She still called her mother and asked, &quot;Have you been bullied by others?&quot; and &quot;Have you done anything like that with others?&quot; Yi Yonghong was silent and crying on the phone for a long time. After asking the two questions several times in turn, Yi Yonghong finally relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yi Yonghong&#39;s daughter returns to her banana field. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/4e271c4134.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e271c4134. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yi Yonghong’s daughter returned to her family’s banana field. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After listening to his wife’s story, Cheng Shanzhi was very angry. He was angry about why his wife didn’t tell him. If he had told him the first or second time, there would have been no such thing. What happened next. He also couldn&#39;t understand why this kind of thing could happen to him. &quot;If you tell me, your body will not be obtained by others. This is the place that hurts my heart the most. I feel that my wife will be mine for life and cannot be shared with others.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;His wife kept it secret for many times, which made Cheng Shanzhi wonder whether she had been &quot;raped&quot; or cheated on her. That night, Cheng Shanzhi, who had never touched his wife before, slapped Yi Yonghong on the forearm. &quot;Am I still sorry to you in this life? I depend on you for everything, and you are in charge of the money. How do you want me to treat you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I know that no one would believe that something like this happened. If you don’t understand, I can’t even defend myself,” Yi Yonghong said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reconciliation and alarm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On July 17, Typhoon Taili was getting closer and stronger, and a storm was imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That morning, Cheng Shanzhi called Huang Mouguan and asked him to come to his home. He wanted to confront the other party face to face and also wanted to take revenge on the other party. At almost noon, Huang Mouguan came to the door carrying a box of Wong Lo Kat. Cheng Shanzhi opened a switchblade more than ten centimeters long and hid it in his pants pocket. When Yi Yonghong found out, he hugged him and told him not to do stupid things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that the three of them are present at the same time, and it is also the last time. Southern Weekend reporters heard from the live recording at the time that it was not so much a confrontation between two parties, but rather that the three people had their own concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi did not forgive his wife, and said to her angrily: &quot;As long as you get along with him, it&#39;s your own business.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong sometimes shouted hoarsely, He scolded Huang Mouguan: &quot;I can&#39;t protect myself now. I thought you were a very serious person. I&#39;m asking you, why do you want to mess with me? Why don&#39;t you mess with others.&quot; Sometimes he is powerless and self-pitying: &quot;Anyway It’s all my fault, and it doesn’t matter if I die. I have nothing now, and I don’t know where to go.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, Huang Mouguan was supposed to be the target of the crime, but he was like “ &quot;Peacemaker&quot;, while urging the two to live a good life, he agreed to the settlement plan and said to Cheng Shanzhi: &quot;I will give you 10,000 yuan, and we will be settled, and nothing will happen. We are all good brothers.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang Mouguan wrote a note on the spot: &quot;I had sexual relations with Yi Yonghong, and now I will compensate Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband for mental loss of 10,000 yuan.&quot; He signed Huang Mouguan&#39;s name. He took out 6,000 yuan in cash and transferred 4,000 yuan via WeChat. But Cheng Shanzhi did not accept the money. He followed his daughter&#39;s advice, called the police and handed the note to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan listened to the reconciliation via phone. She did not agree with this settlement plan. In addition to the risk of the other party suing for extortion, she also wanted Huang to apologize to his mother and even wanted him to go to jail. &lt;p>; .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 17, Huang The Wang Laoji that Guan brought with him during the reconciliation is still in Yi Yonghong&#39;s home. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in retrospect, Cheng Haiyan always felt that asking her father to call the police was a bit excessive. &quot;(The family) did not communicate well, so they called the police right away.&quot; In fact, the night before Huang Mouguan came to reconcile, Cheng Haiyan filed a complaint to the police, but Yi Yonghong kept crying and said that there was no evidence and the other party would not admit it. Cheng Haiyan believes that even if she fails to win in the end, she still wants Huang Mouguan to apologize to restore her mother&#39;s reputation. &quot;The other party has always wanted to use money to settle the matter. I think no matter how poor we are, we can&#39;t let you bully us like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan tried to call Huang Mouguan to &quot;collect evidence&quot;, but every time he said When it comes to key issues, the other party will say, &quot;Don&#39;t talk about this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to tell whether the public reporting to the police was more difficult for Yi Yonghong to accept than being &quot;raped&quot;. On the evening of July 17, Typhoon Taili landed in Wenchang, bringing heavy rain and strong winds to Bajiao. At this time, Yi Yonghong, Cheng Shanzhi, and Huang Mouguan were being questioned at the police station. Cheng Shanzhi heard that Yi Yonghong had been crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the surprise of the couple, on the afternoon of July 18, the day after the alarm was called, Huang&#39;s wife, son, daughter, sister, and brother-in-law came to their home with the intention of reconciling. The &quot;lawyer&quot; daughter in Huang&#39;s mouth told Yi Yonghong that words of discord would be unpleasant to hear in the future, and would also have a bad impact on her daughter who is currently in school. Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what else she said to her mother, which made Yi Yonghong feel that her daughter didn&#39;t understand the law. She called her daughter and asked, &quot;Do you understand the law or not?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi refused to reconcile. Later, the other party&#39;s attitude began to change. Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang&#39;s wife threatened them and humiliated Yi Yonghong, &quot;wanting to give her husband to her.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The crying collapse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the incident to the two failed reconciliations, to calling the police and being questioned, Yi Yonghong is being pushed to the edge of the cliff little by little. Cheng Haiyan said frankly that her family did not take much care of her emotions at that time, and also ignored the understanding and companionship she needed more. But to Cheng Haiyan at that time, her mother&#39;s behavior was &quot;everything was normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoshiyong Hong’s collapse may have started with a hysterical cry. At around 5 a.m. on July 19, Cheng Haiyan was woken up by her mother&#39;s cry. My mother had cried before, always while lying on the bed covered with quilts and crying silently. This was the first time Cheng Haiyan had seen her crying heartbrokenly like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi stood at the door, he didn&#39;t know what to do. Cheng Haiyan stood beside her mother&#39;s bed, equally at a loss. She was scared and didn&#39;t know how to express concern or comfort her. Even, she couldn&#39;t understand her mother&#39;s pain at this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to be an emotionally rough daughter, because in this family, they are taught that daughters can only rely on themselves, and sons rely on their parents. &quot;My grandmother&#39;s generation would regard their daughters as It&#39;s relatively light and I won&#39;t give too much emotion to my daughter.&quot; Yi Yonghong was taught that it was useless for girls to study, so she dropped out of school before finishing the second grade of junior high school. At that time, Yi Yonghong had good grades, ranked among the top three in her class, and was selected by a dance school, but her grandfather was unwilling to spend money to support her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A group photo of Yi Yonghong&#39;s family. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 825d62be57.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1175&quot; height=&quot;1383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/825d62be57.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A photo of Yi Yonghong’s family. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Haiyan&#39;s generation, she is still treated in this way. When she was a child, Yi Yonghong often told her that her sister must give way to her younger brother, and her younger brother&#39;s clothes must be washed by her sister. The couple&#39;s preference for their son reached its peak in 2015 after his son was diagnosed with acute leukemia. In order not to burden her parents, Cheng Haiyan earned living expenses by herself. She worked as a waiter, dishwasher, and cashier at the front desk. &quot;It was so hard that I felt numb.&quot; In recent years, Cheng Haiyan rarely spends the Chinese New Year with her parents and works outside to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong&#39;s crying did not subside. She repeatedly said &quot;Is this sentence correct?&quot; Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what &quot;this sentence&quot; was. She called her uncle, who was the most suitable person she could think of to comfort her mother. Grandma is old and can&#39;t stand the excitement; her sick brother is doing an internship in another place and is the key target of the family&#39;s concealment; and her aunt and uncle have a bad relationship with their mother and often quarrel. There are few people who can support Yoshiyong Hong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yi Yonghong has a strong self-esteem and is unwilling to let her family know about her. &quot;We rarely ask relatives for help or call them to complain. My mother feels that people will make fun of you and not want to help you,&quot; Cheng Haiyan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My uncle who was far away in Dongguan answered Cheng Haiyan&#39;s call. &quot;He called my mother&#39;s name twice, &#39;Honghong, Honghong&#39;, and she immediately calmed down.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan didn’t know why the backbone of the family suddenly collapsed. She survived even when her brother was sick and undergoing chemotherapy. Cheng Shanzhi also couldn&#39;t understand why his wife couldn&#39;t get over this hurdle: &quot;I didn&#39;t mention divorce, and I didn&#39;t drive you away. As a husband, I still love you, so why can&#39;t I just think about it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi is very satisfied with himself. His wife is beautiful, has fair skin, never puts on makeup, and speaks softly. When she took her home for the first time, people in the village praised him, &quot;Your ancestral grave is so nice.&quot; &quot;What else can I say about this kind of wife? There is nothing to dislike at all.&quot; Cheng Shanzhi often teaches his daughter that she should learn from her mother and be nice to her husband in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong is a traditional and conservative rural woman. Even when they fell in love, they only found out Cheng Shanzhi’s zodiac sign and birthday before they got together. After marriage, in addition to doing farm work, Yi Yonghong naturally took over the housework of washing and cooking. She massaged her husband&#39;s feet every day and trimmed his nails every other time. Jiu went to help him serve the rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the memory of her family, Yi Yonghong rarely interacted with the opposite sex or joked. She always hid when buying sanitary napkins and must put them in black plastic bags. Washed underwear is always hung among other clothes to dry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong doesn’t have many friends. Her pastimes are drinking tea, playing mahjong and scrolling through Douyin. Occasionally, she would take TikTok videos by herself, putting on a fancy template with the filter turned to the maximum, and staring at the camera with a serious expression. Sometimes she laments the hard life, and sometimes she sings the song &quot;Married girl, throw away the water, don&#39;t talk too much when you return to your parents&#39; home&quot; and &quot;Why is it so difficult in this life?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2000, I followed my husband to Hainan to work hard. They planted lemongrass and raised snakes, and finally saved money to build a house in their hometown. However, their son was diagnosed with acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Due to long-term labor, the joints of Yi Yonghong&#39;s hands were deformed and unable to be straightened. She often told her daughter that after following your father, there was no house in her hometown, no house in Hainan, and no home anywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her mother died, Cheng Haiyan always dreamed of her, but she could never see her face. Cheng Haiyan guessed that maybe her mother &quot;didn&#39;t want to see us, and we let her down.&quot; Cheng Haiyan did not dare to read the suicide note left by Yi Yonghong a second time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Questioned resistance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another important reason why Yi Yonghong is under tremendous pressure is that she always believes that the evidence is not enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the incident, in order to hide the incident, Yi Yonghong took a shower and washed the clothes she wore that day. She also threw the used tissues under the tree outside the house and had them removed. Heavy rain washed it away. &quot;I hate myself for not knowing how to use the law to protect myself... There is no evidence of guilt, and I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t win against him,&quot; she stated in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that made Yi Yonghong feel even more desperate was that during the incident, she was not sure whether her behavior was considered resistance. In her suicide note, she said: &quot;If resistance involves scratching as you said, tearing clothes to pieces, there is no such thing. Because I am afraid that he will beat me and harm my family. In my confession, I only said to push him and not to do it. , is this considered resistance?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi seemed to be comforting his dead wife. He said that Huang Guan was a head taller than him, his arms were as thick as his own, and he was tall and tall. &quot;If he holds you with both hands, do you have the strength to resist? No matter whether my wife resists or not, it is you, the man, who takes the initiative to violate my wife, not my wife who violates you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan doesn&#39;t know what resistance is. In her opinion, pushing the other person away is also resistance. She rarely pays attention to news about women&#39;s rights protection. After her mother committed suicide, a friend recommended Cheng Haiyan to watch the TV series &quot;Imperfect Victim&quot;: &quot;The heroine did not know how to resist under mental oppression. I felt that I My mother is mentally rebellious. If she had not resisted, she would not have cried.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Hangyuan, the 66-year-old village team leader, has his own views on resistance. He believes that to leave a mark on the other person&#39;s body, even if a knife is placed on the woman&#39;s neck, she must resist. After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, another version of the story circulated in the teahouse where Yi Yonghong used to frequent in this small village with only 13 households: The two had an affair and committed suicide after being discovered by her husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another factor that complicates the case is the 150 yuan Huang Mouguan left behind when he left. In a confrontation between the two parties after Yi Yonghong committed suicide, Huang&#39;s wife believed that by giving 150 yuan, the nature of the matter changed and became a &quot;business.&quot; After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, the two dirty, black banknotes were crumpled and stacked in Yi Yonghong&#39;s pocket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that his wife was insulted by their money, &quot;He (Huang Mouguan) lost the money and ran away. My wife will definitely pick it up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 21, the sixth day after the incident, Cheng Shanzhi and Yi Yonghong were called again to take statements. This was also the second time they took statements after the incident. It was after recording this confession that Yoshinaga wrote the suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan remembered that after her mother came home after taking the confession, she called her mother and asked: &quot;Are you willing to file a lawsuit? If you are willing to file a lawsuit, I can only try my best to help you. If If she doesn&#39;t want to sue, she won&#39;t sue.&quot; Cheng Haiyan realized later, &quot;(Before) we wanted her to sue, not that she wanted to sue herself. Taking the initiative and being pushed are not the same thing.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong chose to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Yi Yonghong’s experience was reported by the media, on August 26, the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau stated that it had deployed elite police forces to set up a joint investigation team to conduct a comprehensive review. According to Cheng Haiyan’s statistics, after Yi Yonghong’s suicide, the police re-collected the following evidence: 20 bottles of honey chrysanthemum tea (2 bottles unopened, 18 empty boxes), Yi Yonghong’s mobile phone, 150 yuan banknotes, Yi Yonghong’s gynecology department Check the medical records, the underwear worn by Yi Yonghong the next day after the incident, sheets, quilt covers, mats, pillows, bras, trousers, coats, tissues washed away by the rain, as well as the blood, liver and spleen obtained by Yi Yonghong&#39;s autopsy . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to whether Huang Mouguan has been detained and what new evidence is available for filing the case, a staff member of the Political Affairs Office of the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;The case is under investigation and it is not convenient to disclose it.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death, the suicide note was placed on the red stool. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death , the suicide note was placed on the red stool. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Shanzhi’s view, even on the day Yi Yonghong secretly wrote the suicide note, he did not notice anything unusual about his wife. On July 22, after working for a day, the couple decided to have dinner in a restaurant. Cheng Shanzhi bought four cans of Red Bull for his wife. Yi Yonghong loved to drink Red Bull and drank one can almost every day before the incident. Cheng Shanzhi lay on the recliner waiting for her. After taking a shower, Yi Yonghong hugged her husband and kissed him. For dinner, they ordered a piece of white-chopped chicken and a plate of sweet potato leaves. Yi Yonghong still had no appetite. She didn&#39;t even drink her favorite Red Bull and only ate some sweet potato leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 23 was the day when Cheng Haiyan returned to Wenchang from Haikou to record her confession. Early in the morning, Cheng Shanzhi called her: &quot;Hong, let&#39;s go with our daughter to record a statement. The two of us have a companion.&quot; After calling her three times in a row, Yi Yonghong refused. &quot;She said, go ahead, I&#39;ll wait for you to come back at home. I&#39;m very tired and want to take a rest at home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a normal day, Cheng Shanzhi would go pick her up and the couple would always be inseparable when traveling. But that day, &quot;I forgot to give her a hand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汕尾如何“握手”高铁经济时代：拥抱文旅融合发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway will be officially opened in late September. At that time, it will only travel from Xintang Station to Shanwei Station. It takes about 50 minutes. This is the first railway named after the city of Shanwei. It is an important channel to promote the deep integration of the old revolutionary areas of Hailufeng into the Bay. After its opening, it will greatly shorten the distance between Shanwei and eastern Guangdong and the core cities of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6ef41814ed4b3d857360965c9b9b0834.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6ef41814ed4b3d857360965c9b9b0834.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250734 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Aerial photo of Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanwei City seized the important opportunity of the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway and held a press conference on the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway in 2023 to boost the high-quality economic development of Shanwei and a cultural tourism real estate investment promotion on the afternoon of September 12 The meeting will announce a series of activities planned and organized by Shanwei City during the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway and relevant measures to regulate the order of the cultural tourism market, and promote Shanwei City’s high-quality cultural tourism resources, real estate resources and investment environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Visible achievements, creating a new highland for Shanwei’s cultural tourism&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Shantou City is the ‘National It is the &quot;emerging niche city with the fastest growth rate of travel intention&quot;, one of the top ten &quot;new local travel destinations&quot; in the country for National Day in 2022, and will be shortlisted for the Top 10 cities in the annual life travel intensity index in 2022...&quot; Shanwei City Culture, Radio, Television, Tourism and Sports&lt;span >;Bureau Director Xie Wei&lt;span>;Xuan&lt;/span>; said at the press conference that in recent years, Shanwei City has focused on high-quality development, strengthened the supply capacity of cultural tourism products, and unswervingly cultivated the cultural tourism industry It has become a strategic pillar industry for high-quality economic and social development, and the cultural tourism market has achieved considerable results and achieved fruitful results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/e4515ced78a221f8ab57f7f91ea61c06.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/e4515ced78a221f8ab57f7f91ea61c06.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250736&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Jinxiang Silver Beach Tourist Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of this year, the &lt;span>;tourism market was generally active and strong, and &lt;/span>; continued its rapid growth momentum. The total number of overnight tourists in Shanwei City was 9.7866 million, a year-on-year increase of 279.33%; tourists The total number of tourists was 15.1135 million, a year-on-year increase of 294.61%; the total tourism revenue was 7.581 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 130.78%. During the summer vacation from July to August this year, Shanwei seized the opportunity of the country&#39;s &quot;Twenty Measures&quot; to promote consumption, integrated performing arts, sports, culture, food and tourism, and extended more new tourism formats and models that attract young people. Further unleash the consumption potential of the cultural tourism market. From July to August 2023, the city&#39;s total number of overnight tourists was 3.65 million, a year-on-year increase of 204.17%&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;The total number of tourists was 6.2 million, a year-on-year increase of 228.42%&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;The total tourism revenue was 3.4 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 183.33%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/399894f6fc8ddf650b504a8407ceef2a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/399894f6fc8ddf650b504a8407ceef2a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250738&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Red Bay Tourist Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Come to Shanwei by high-speed rail+&quot; series of activities, nine special sessions are waiting for you&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot; This year&#39;s &#39;Super Golden Week&#39; is the first super golden week after the epidemic, and combined with the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway, it will bring unprecedented opportunities for the high-quality development of Shanwei tourism.&quot; Xie Siying, deputy director of the Shanwei Municipal Culture, Radio, Television, Tourism and Sports Bureau, said, The Guangzhou Tourism and Sports Bureau will lead the Municipal &lt;span>;Transportation Bureau&lt;/span>;, Municipal Investment Promotion Bureau, Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, Municipal Education Bureau, Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, Municipal Civil Affairs Bureau, Municipal Health Bureau, and Municipal Development and Reform Bureau Relevant units such as the Municipal Hong Kong and Macao Affairs Bureau and the Municipal Hong Kong and Macao Affairs Bureau have planned to launch a series of activities to promote the opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway from September to December, hoping to widely attract tourists and set off a cultural wave during the &quot;Super Golden Week&quot; with eight consecutive days of National Day and Mid-Autumn Festival. Travel boom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/12ced8b257cbdd4080127a76b8e9a708.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/12ced8b257cbdd4080127a76b8e9a708.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250737&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway Shanwei Station. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revolving around key tasks such as &quot;hundreds of millions of projects&quot;, strengthening the city by ocean, and strengthening the city by culture, Shanwei City has launched a series of activities &quot;Come to Shanwei+ by high-speed rail&quot;, starting from this week to the end of the year , mainly concentrated from September to October, in principle, held once a week. These include Shanwei’s high-quality hot tourist routes, locational transportation advantages, high-speed rail economic investment, high-speed rail economy and Shanwei real estate development, medical and health care, new energy and green energy promotion, Hong Kong and Macao compatriots’ visit to Shanwei, Shanwei Harvest Food Festival, and Shanwei Tourism Market There are nine special activities in the standardized promotion action, which promote and introduce Shanwei&#39;s cultural tourism resources and development opportunities from different dimensions, and promote the development of related economic industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Shanwei City also launched the &quot;Take the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway to Shanwei&quot; activity. On the day the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway was opened to traffic, 200 tourists were recruited to form a tour group and experience Shanwei&#39;s high-quality tourist routes for free. A sightseeing bus line will be opened directly from the high-speed rail station in the urban area. Tourists can reserve free rides through the WeChat applet and enjoy the scenery of Shanwei. &lt;h4>; Give full play to the resource advantages of &#39;red + blue&#39; and polish the business card of &#39;growing Shanwei in winter&#39;.&quot; After the press conference, Xie Weixuan promoted Shanwei&#39;s cultural tourism resources at the Shanwei Cultural Tourism Real Estate Investment Promotion Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;red&quot; is reflected in the fact that Shanwei is a place where red culture gathers. Shanwei is the birthplace of the first Soviet power in the country and one of the 13 revolutionary base areas in the country. The Red Palace and Red Square are the national patriotism education base and the national red tourism classic scenic spot. Zhou Enlai&#39;s Crossing of the Sea &lt;span>;Commemoration&lt;/span>; red tourist area, the former site of the Second Red Division &lt;span>;Division&lt;/span>;, the former site of the Fourth Red &lt;span>;Division&lt;/span>; Division, the former site of the Forty-ninth Regiment Headquarters, etc. The revolutionary relics tell the story of Hailufeng’s vigorous revolutionary history, and eight provincial-level red demonstration villages shine with the splendor of a happy countryside in the new era in Shanwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/87000187c3b7abbb586f751ccfd3da07.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;354&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/87000187c3b7abbb586f751ccfd3da07.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250739&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Red Palace and Red Square are the national patriotism education base and the national red tourism classic scenic spot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Blue&quot; is reflected in the resource advantages of &lt;span>;Shantou Binhai&lt;/span>; city. Shanwei belongs to the south subtropical monsoon climate zone with a pronounced maritime climate. It has a coastline of 455 kilometers, including 150 kilometers of high-quality beach coastline. It is rich in marine resources, and the &quot;Hundred Islands, Ten Beaches and Nine Bays&quot; are the highlight. Shanwei has no severe cold in winter and no scorching heat in summer. It is a coastal tourist resort to escape the summer heat, cold and haze. It has been awarded the title of &quot;Winter Nutrition for Shanwei·National Ecological Tourism Demonstration Experimental Area&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/251a00f8049ce079ca9a7fd9f7c81734.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;237&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/251a00f8049ce079ca9a7fd9f7c81734.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250741&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Aerial photo of Shanwei coastline. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of cultural tourism is inseparable from the planning of cultural and sports activities. Shanwei City held the &quot;Winter Shanwei&quot; cultural tourism brand promotion event and the first China Prose Poetry Festival, won the country&#39;s first prefecture-level city &quot;Hometown of Chinese Prose Poetry&quot; honorary plaque, and released the first blue book of Chinese prose poetry. This is &lt;span>;after&lt;/span>; winning the title of “Hometown of Chinese Folk Culture and Art”, &lt;span>; Shanwei has added another&lt;/span>; “national” cultural brand. Not only that, Shanwei also won three golden business cards: &quot;Hometown of Drama in Guangdong Province&quot;, &quot;Hometown of Fishermen&#39;s Songs in Guangdong Province&quot; and &quot;Hometown of Violin in Guangdong Province&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/d4dce25401ddb621bb2b4be9b8c58bc2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/d4dce25401ddb621bb2b4be9b8c58bc2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250740&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shantou has three rare operas and one world-class intangible cultural heritage, Lufeng Shadow Puppetry. Pictured is a shadow puppet show. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Shanwei City joined hands with the short video platform to hold the 2023 South China &quot;Guangdong Hometown Welcomes the New Year&quot; and &quot;Mountains, Seas and Lakes City Winter Care for Shanwei&quot; cultural benefit to the people to celebrate the New Year, with a total of online views The number of visitors reached 170 million. Not only that, Shanwei City also held the 2023 New Year Carnival of &quot;Shanhai Lake City Winter Care for Shanwei&quot;, which combined traditional intangible cultural heritage with modern humanities to fully demonstrate the image of &lt;span>;Shantou Coastal&lt;/span>; as a tourist city. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Revitalize real estate tourism resources and provide high-quality services&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Relevant persons in charge of the Municipal Natural Resources Bureau and the Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau respectively &lt;span>;Assist&lt;/span>; Promote hotel land preferential policies and real estate resources. In order to promote the series of activities for the opening of the Guangshan-Shantou High-speed Railway, Shanwei City is actively planning to hold the 2023 Shanwei Golden Autumn Home Buying Festival with the theme of &quot;Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway New Era, More Exciting Life in the City&quot;. During the event, relevant departments and enterprises will be coordinated and implemented on home purchases Special discounts and support measures will be launched during the festival to attract investment and construction from four aspects: increasing the provident fund loan limit, preferential interest rates on personal mortgage loans, issuing house purchase subsidies, and providing preferential treatment for corporate activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/223819745eecaaf78e082f2a9ec321f4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/223819745eecaaf78e082f2a9ec321f4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250742&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Poly Golden Bay Tourist Resort. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of real estate resources, Shanwei City has many real estate projects such as Shanwei Galaxy, Poly Group, Country Garden Star Diamond, Galaxy Lingyu, Wandelong Sunshine City, among which Shanwei Galaxy is the It&#39;s eye-catching. Shanwei Galaxy Bay is located on the shore of Pinqing Lake, the largest lagoon in the country, with mountains on its back and the sea. It enjoys the beautiful scenery of Pinqing Lake and enjoys high-quality ecological resources. In addition, Star River Bay is in an excellent location, adjacent to the high-speed rail station and has convenient transportation. It is also equipped with an international five-star standard hotel, a banquet hall for 1,000 people, an international standard gymnasium, a harbor-style leisure commercial street, an oriental garden, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/bd060dad242d35f40fdf2f3718d50246.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/bd060dad242d35f40fdf2f3718d50246.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250743&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; Shanwei is rich in marine resources and has the largest lagoon in the country - Pinqing Lake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of hotel construction, Shanwei City focuses on strengthening and improving hotel service and reception capabilities, promptly promotes the construction and renovation of star-rated hotels, actively promotes the commissioning and construction of high-end hotel projects, and strives to improve the city&#39;s reception level and grade , providing tourists with better hotel services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Shanwei City is also committed to innovating new models of tourism B&amp;B development. There are 40 newly registered B&amp;Bs in the city, and a large number of B&amp;Bs with rural characteristics have been born, such as Shangying Mishu Reed House, Jinxiang Hainajin &lt;span>;Tandin&lt;/span>; Bed and Breakfast Town, and Lijun Pavilion·Wooden House Theme B&amp;B. B&amp;B. The construction of new public cultural spaces has been carried out in tourism operating units such as tourist attractions, hotels, B&amp;Bs and tourist transportation distribution centers. 12 &quot;Cantonese Book Bars&quot;, 3 &quot;Cantonese Literature Forums&quot; and 11 other types of new public cultural spaces have been built in villages. There are 14 pilot projects for the &quot;integration of the two centers&quot; of comprehensive cultural service centers and tourism service centers and 195 tourist toilets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3facebb5057d5419bb41005b35a89f37.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3facebb5057d5419bb41005b35a89f37.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250746&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Jinxiang Haina Golden Beach B&amp;B Town. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening of the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway means that &lt;span>;Shantou is ushering in&lt;/span>; a new era of development. This transportation infrastructure will bring huge development opportunities to the local area. Shanwei City is fully prepared for this, actively promotes local cultural tourism resources, attracts investment in construction, and promotes the vigorous development of cultural tourism-related industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【Recommendation of high-quality tourist routes】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;◎Haifeng: The tourist route is based on the red color of Haifeng. It connects forest health care, leisure agriculture and coastal eco-tourism, allowing tourists to understand the red gene of Haifeng, appreciate the beautiful pastoral scenery of the local countryside and experience the &quot;romantic&quot; rhythm of coastal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/a036a19024be67560fb229b8e594280a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/a036a19024be67560fb229b8e594280a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250744&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Lianhua Mountain Resort in Haifeng County. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;◎Lufeng: Plan to create four high-quality tourist routes, namely &lt;span>;: &lt;/span>; &quot;Red Fortress·Gold Coast&quot;, &quot;Red Coast·Charm of the Ancient City&quot;, &quot;Landscape Gallery·Kang&quot; &quot;Nurturance land&quot;, &quot;local ancient charm, cradle of agricultural movement&quot;. Among them, &quot;Red Fortress·Gold Coast&quot; and &quot;Country Ancient Rhythm·Cradle of Agricultural Movement&quot; were selected as high-quality rural tourism routes in Guangdong Province. At the same time, in order to provide tourists with a better tourism experience, Lufeng City has integrated its superior resources and re-planned and optimized the &quot;1+1&quot; quality tourism routes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/47a606f4deb2deec1f7703800553d1f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/47a606f4deb2deec1f7703800553d1f0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250747&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Lufeng Xuanwu Mountain Tourist Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;◎Luhe: Based on the four seasons of &quot;Spring, Summer, Autumn and Winter&quot;, the &quot;North and South&quot; rural demonstration zones, and different themes, a total of 13 tourist routes have been formulated, including &quot;Beautiful Landscapes, Wonderland on Earth&quot; The three routes of &quot;Luhe Red Kesu Meiyun Tour&quot; and &quot;Healthy Hometown, Full of Love in Liyuan&quot; were rated as high-quality rural tourism routes in Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1f02a4a182c47ab5734d45632983b943.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;544&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1f02a4a182c47ab5734d45632983b943.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250748&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Baishuizhai Waterfall in Luhe County. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[茂名鳄鱼雨中出逃，已围捕追回58条]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256743]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 14:36:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[信用卡质效榜：两大梯队均分化严重  华夏仅优于城商行 ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256663]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After nearly 30 years of rapid development, along with the &quot;Further Promoting the Standardized and Healthy Development of Credit Card Business&quot; &quot;Notice&quot; (known as the &quot;New Credit Card Regulations&quot; in the industry) will be implemented in 2022, and China&#39;s credit card market has entered an era of intensive cultivation. Commercial banks&#39; reliance on card quantity has been replaced by quality and efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Overall Operation of the Payment System in the Fourth Quarter of 2022&quot; released by the People&#39;s Bank of China shows that as of the end of 2022, the number of credit cards and debit and credit cards in use totaled 798 million, a year-on-year decrease of 0.28%. This is the first negative growth in credit card issuance in China since records began. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as the core high-quality business segment of commercial banks, in the era of digital finance, the credit card business is facing a new competitive situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, which card issuing bank will still have outstanding scale and growth rate? Which card issuing bank has better risk management system and risk control effect? Which card issuer is better at retaining customers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center adopted a combination of quantitative and qualitative research and analysis methods to construct a comprehensive evaluation index system including 16 indicators in three major dimensions, and differentiated the indicators based on their importance. Empowerment. This enables commercial banks of different sizes and types to achieve &quot;horizontally comparable and vertical ranking&quot; in terms of their overall strength in credit card business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this indicator system, researchers from Southern Weekend New Financial Center objectively evaluated the performance of 19 major commercial banks in their credit card business based on their 2022 annual report data and third-party evaluation data, and The &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency List&quot; is released based on the evaluation score results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Indicator system&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Three dimensions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Sixteen&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;sub-indicators&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since the birth of China&#39;s first standard credit card in 1995, the &quot;imported product&quot; of credit card has become one of the basic tools of personal credit business of various financial institutions after nearly 30 years of hard work. At the end of 2022, the credit card loan balance of 18 major commercial banks was 7.89 trillion (Ningbo Bank&#39;s credit card loan balance data was not disclosed, so it was not included in the statistics), accounting for 14.4% of the personal loan balance, becoming the second largest personal loan after housing mortgage loans. credit markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the important value of credit card business to commercial banks? First of all, the credit card business is an important support for the bank’s retail business; secondly, the credit card business helps banks improve customer loyalty and stickiness; thirdly, the credit card business provides banks with consumer-related data, and banks can better complete portraits of their customers and consumers. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the development trend characteristics of the credit card business of various commercial banks and the credit card customer satisfaction survey, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center constructed the &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency Ranking&quot; evaluation index system &lt;em>;,&lt;/em>; which It includes three major dimensions: business scale and growth, risk management, customer service and product innovation, and is refined into fifteen quantitative indicators and one qualitative indicator. The evaluation index system is now described in detail as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/rB3LjY143PkCBOLBGAvB6nIqPDnWobGzOmO0ep0Z.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;498&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/rB3LjY143PkCBOLBGAvB6nIqPDnWobGzOmO0ep0Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250761 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(1) Business scale and growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Credit cards are an important tool for banks to establish long-term relationships with customers, and are also the focus of banks’ retail business. The scale and growth of the credit card business reflect the bank&#39;s customer acquisition capabilities and market position, while the number of credit card issuances and changes in the issuance volume reflect the bank&#39;s expansion effect, and the loan balance and proportion reflect the actual contribution of the bank&#39;s credit cards, the number of active accounts and transactions The amount reflects the marketing accuracy and stickiness of bank credit cards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Risk management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is very necessary to examine the risk management capabilities of bank credit cards. Credit cards are &quot;unsecured revolving loans&quot; issued by banks based on their trust in cardholders. The risk management capabilities of credit card business affect the bank&#39;s operating efficiency and competitiveness. Credit cards are an important source of income for banks, and their revenue comes from interest, fees and annual fees. If indicators such as the bad debt rate, fraud rate, and theft rate of credit cards cannot be effectively controlled, the bank&#39;s costs will increase and its profits will decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the epidemic, the non-performing loan ratio of commercial banks (including the non-performing ratio of credit card loans) will increase in 2022. At the same time, the measures to improve non-performing loan ratios disclosed in the annual reports of most listed banks are relatively general, and the measures taken by various banks lack comparability. In order to highlight the efforts and effects of banks in controlling the non-performing loan ratio, this evaluation system uses the credit card loan non-performing ratio indicator in 2022 and also sets a change rate indicator for the credit card loan non-performing ratio to directly reflect the achievements of the measures taken by each bank. Effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(3) Customer service and product innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competition in the credit card market is becoming increasingly fierce, and banks are constantly launching new products, services, functions and activities to meet the diverse needs of customers and improve customer stickiness. This evaluation system evaluates from both the bank side and the consumer side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We use the types of credit cards issued by banks and the number of complaints about credit card business as positive and negative indicators respectively. On the consumer side, evaluations from third-party organizations are used, because third-party organizations obtain consumers’ evaluations of credit card products through a large number of objective questionnaires, which are more objective than those disclosed in bank annual reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We select China Customer Satisfaction Index (C-CSI) and China Net Promoter Score (C-NPS) as consumers’ evaluation of credit card products. index. C-CSI and C-NPS survey targets permanent residents between the ages of 15 and 60, and are randomly sampled according to gender, age, income and region, and completed through household interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We consider the card issuer’s distinctive credit card services of the year as bonus points. Each unique credit card service that is publicly disclosed and can be collected will receive 10 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(4) Reward and punishment mechanism for information disclosure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our research, we found that most banks have disclosed data on each of the above indicators, but a few banks have not disclosed one or more indicators. In order to reduce the impact of information asymmetry and punish banks that do not disclose sufficient information, this evaluation system will give the lowest score to any indicator item that does not disclose relevant data. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China Merchants Bank takes the lead&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Hua Xia is only better than city commercial banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;We will 19 The credit card businesses of commercial banks are ranked according to their scores, and the &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency List&quot; is selected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency Ranking&quot; shows that national commercial banks that started their credit card business earlier and have a large customer base rank high. But it does not mean that the larger the card issuance volume, the higher the overall score. As a joint-stock bank, although China Merchants Bank is not as large as the state-owned banks, it ranks first in the overall score of credit card business. This is due to its strategic vision of taking the lead in developing retail business and its innovation power that has been sustained for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nrq2m73w7NwpA0YngHO0HozRPlvgzwOnrwyzdfu2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nrq2m73w7NwpA0YngHO0HozRPlvgzwOnrwyzdfu2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Building Bank of China and Industrial and Commercial Bank of China closely followed China Merchants Bank in second and third place respectively. Among them, the total score of China Construction Bank&#39;s credit cards is only 20 points less than that of China Merchants Bank, with a very small gap. Three banks form the leading phalanx in the credit card business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the six major state-owned banks, the total score of Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China is far outside the top five. Not only are they far behind China Merchants Bank, but they are also surpassed by joint-stock banks such as CITIC, Ping An and China Guangdong Development Bank. Postal Savings Bank ranked thirteenth. Among joint-stock banks, Hua Xia Bank is at the bottom, with a score difference of 248 points from China Merchants Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/XPGZaas4gffibT9dkNVoXQWhd7gVkP1r0UbYHUiZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/XPGZaas4gffibT9dkNVoXQWhd7gVkP1r0UbYHUiZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Business and Industry The main reason why banks lose points with credit cards is that they only publish the total complaints but not the complaints of the credit card business. Therefore, when we do not consider the indicator of credit card business complaints, China Merchants Bank still leads the list, and Industrial and Commercial Bank of China overtook China Construction Bank and rose to second place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, if the number of complaints is not taken into account, China Guangdong Development Bank and Bank of Communications leap to fourth and fifth place. This shows that the number of complaints from these two banks is relatively large. Of course, this does not rule out malicious complaints from gray products. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;State-owned banks and joint-stock banks are seriously divided&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;City commercial banks are catching up&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; Regardless of state-owned banks or joint-stock banks, the credit card scores of the two echelons are seriously divided in their respective camps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the six major state-owned banks, only two and three are among the top five in the two lists, namely China Construction Bank, ICBC, China Construction Bank, ICBC and Bank of Communications. Agricultural Bank of China and Bank of China ranked low in both lists. Especially in the list excluding the number of complaints, Bank of China’s score has reached fourteenth place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among joint-stock banks, China Merchants Bank has always been far ahead. The overall performance of CITIC, Ping An and GF is remarkable. Among them, China CITIC Bank’s total credit card score is second only to China Merchants Bank among joint-stock banks. This is mainly due to the fact that the bank has received more scores than its peers in terms of consumer services and credit card business complaints. Among them, the score for credit card complaints is higher than that of other companies on the list. Bank and credit card categories also scored over 80, indicating that they cover a wide range of consumer groups. Although Guangdong Development Bank is smaller among all joint-stock banks, the overall score of Guangfa Credit Card is high among all banks. This reflects the important position of China Guangdong Development Bank&#39;s credit card business in the bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The credit card scores of the four city commercial banks are at the bottom of the list, which shows that they still have a clear gap with large and medium-sized banks in terms of comprehensive credit card strength. Affected by factors such as their short time in the credit card market, small business scale and weak customer base, city commercial banks as a whole lag behind in indicators such as credit card issuance volume and credit card loan balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, among city commercial banks, Bank of Jiangsu and Bank of Ningbo both scored 100 points for the credit card change volume indicator, especially Bank of Ningbo, which scored as high as 90 points for the proportion of complaints in the credit card business. This reflects that leading city commercial banks are working hard to catch up in the credit card business and have made great progress in some indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Assistant researcher Liang Chenghao, Zou Huan and Yang Chaoqun also contributed)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[父亲殴打猥亵女儿者，检察机关不予起诉：义愤彰显人性，震慑奸宄之徒丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256739]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 14:09:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a case published by the &quot;Procuratorial Daily&quot; made many netizens shout &quot;Yangjian News&quot; and &quot;very mentioning&quot; gas&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 9, 2021, Li learned that his 15-year-old daughter had been molested by Xie Moumou, the deputy dean of a certain vocational and technical college, and came to the school to beat Xie Moumou. Xie&#39;s injury was assessed as minor injury level two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The procuratorial organ believed that although Li&#39;s act of injuring Xie was suspected of intentional injury, it was an act of injury carried out out of anger in the process of claiming his daughter&#39;s legitimate rights and interests from the school. Because Li was a first-time offender and an occasional offender, his behavior was justified and the circumstances were minor, and he had lenient and lenient punishment circumstances such as surrendering, so the decision was made not to prosecute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Xie Moumou, after the procuratorate initiated a public prosecution, the court sentenced him to two years and two months in prison for the crime of forced indecency, prohibiting him from engaging in sexual relations with minors from the date of completion of the sentence or the date of parole. Occupations with special responsibilities such as education, training, and nursing that are in close contact with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among netizens’ reactions, no one complained about his father Li’s beating of Xie to a minor injury, let alone treating it as “intentional injury.” Instead, there were various “beatings” &quot;Good&quot; and &quot;It&#39;s not an exaggeration to beat him to death&quot;. Does such a sound sound &quot;tyrannical&quot;? not at all. This is the manifestation of the &quot;simple sense of justice&quot; or &quot;emotion of law&quot; inherent in every normal person&#39;s heart. Indignation makes us human, and integrity must mean knowing what to love and what to hate. Confucius said: Only benevolent people can love others and hate others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens also had complimentary words for the local procuratorate, such as &quot;the light of justice&quot; and &quot;wanting to send a banner.&quot; If the law were applied mechanically, the father could be prosecuted and sentenced if he beat someone to a minor injury of the second degree. There are many cases like this in reality: one spouse cheats, the other catches the cheater in bed, and beats the lover wildly in anger. Then the lover goes to assess the injury. As long as the injury is minor, the other spouse will either pay for a settlement or be charged with intentional injury. Although it is legal to go to jail and let the attacker go to jail, it is against human ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, to some extent, the above cases reflect the conflict between natural law and statutory/statutory law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called natural law/natural rights simply means that laws are discovered, not invented or formulated, which is often referred to as &quot;natural law&quot;. From the perspective of evolutionary game theory, natural law is the embodiment of &quot;evolutionary stable strategy&quot; (ESS). Tit for retaliation, or what Confucius said, &quot;repay kindness with kindness, repay hatred with directness&quot; is ESS. Only in this way , can promote cooperation among members of society, suppress breach of trust and aggression, and enable society and civilization to survive. The final rule derived from &quot;reciprocity&quot; is that each other respects each other&#39;s life, freedom and property rights, as the Chinese say, &quot;Kill to pay for life, debt to pay for money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Statutory law is made by people and will refer to natural law or customary law, but it is not always consistent with natural law or customary law, and sometimes even runs counter to it. In the fields of marriage, family and property inheritance, there are many cases Reflects the conflict between statutory law and natural law or customary law. The only daughter, Ms. Yang, wanted to inherit her parents&#39; inheritance, but found that 22 relatives of both parents also had the right to inherit (based on statutory law). Fortunately, these relatives did not think they had the right to inherit the inheritance of Ms. Yang&#39;s parents (based on natural law and common law). This is Heaven governs people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to the case where his father Li beat Xie. Xie obviously knew how to use legal weapons to protect himself. After being beaten, he immediately identified the injury as &quot;minor injury level two&quot;, which showed that he He also suffered injuries, using this as a bargaining chip, or wanting to offset the disadvantages he faced in the molestation case, because minor injuries can be administratively detained, and minor injuries can be sentenced to prison. The show is &quot;I go to jail, you also go to jail, let&#39;s go together.&quot; posture. Judging from the local procuratorate&#39;s handling of both cases, it is obvious that the police also completed the investigation into the beating case of his father Li and handed it over to the prosecutor. It can be inferred that Xie reported the case to the police after being beaten. Reporting the crime + injury assessment, the direction of counterattacking Li is very obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the local procuratorate’s decision not to prosecute Li has resolved the conflict between natural law and statutory law in this incident. It is in accordance with the laws of nature and people’s hearts, and it is for the father Li to stand up for his daughter. The behavior and morality are very good, and it is also a good deterrent to those who try to extend their dirty hands to minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How do individuals deal with conflicts between natural law and statutory law? My father, Li, is a good example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different statutory provisions and different judgments based on them mean different behavioral incentives for people and will change people&#39;s behavior. For example, the case of Datong, Shanxi, where she was accused of rape after getting engaged, triggered strong concerns and debates. , one of the motives discussed by everyone is &quot;how to avoid legal risks&quot;, but generally speaking, when the rights of parents and children are violated, the emotions and temperament of blood thicker than water will prevail, at least they will be very angry, and often stand Come out, instead of blindly looking forward and backward, timid, and appearing particularly &quot;rational and calm&quot;. If a person does not show blood and courage at this time, then he probably does not have these things at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every father and mother who stands up for their children is worthy of respect. When their children are hurt and most vulnerable and helpless, they stand up to confront the aggressor and expose the aggressor&#39;s evil deeds to the broad daylight. This is the best help and the best value for their children. educate. They let their children know that when they are hurt, their parents are their strongest backing and support; they must be as brave as their parents, dare to say no to infringements and infringers, and dare to advocate and defend their rights. If there are more parents like this, not only will those who are ready to make a move think twice about it, but they will also convey a strong and profound value system to the next generation and the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：9月20日起将猴痘纳入乙类传染病进行管理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256733]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;National Health Commission Announcement&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to the relevant provisions of the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention and Control of Infectious Diseases&quot;, monkeypox will be included in the management of Class B infectious diseases from September 20, 2023. Prevention and control measures for infectious diseases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is an announcement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;National Health Commission&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt; span>;September 15, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Interpretation of the policy on incorporating monkeypox into the management of Class B infectious diseases&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Monkeypox is a zoonotic disease caused by monkeypox virus infection. In the past, it mainly occurred in Central and West Africa. Since May 2022, monkeypox epidemics have occurred in more than 100 countries and regions around the world. Epidemics in many countries have shown that monkeypox has been transmitted from person to person and has spread widely to countries and regions outside Africa, with a case fatality rate of approximately 0.1%. In September 2022, my country reported its first imported case of monkeypox, and local monkeypox epidemics began to appear in June 2023. Currently, more than 20 provinces across the country have reported monkeypox cases, triggering new local secondary outbreaks and hidden transmission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The National Health Commission and the State Administration for Disease Control and Prevention conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, treat monkeypox as a new emerging infectious disease, and give full play to their multiple capabilities. The important role of departmental coordination in prevention and control, continuous improvement of prevention and control policies and measures, strengthening information release, publicity and education, intervention of key groups and standardized treatment have achieved positive results in monkeypox epidemic prevention and control. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Considering that the monkeypox epidemic will continue to exist in my country for a certain period of time, in order to further carry out scientific and standardized prevention and control of the monkeypox epidemic and effectively protect the life safety and health of the people, The National Health Commission decided to include monkeypox as a Class B infectious disease for management under the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention and Control of Infectious Diseases&quot; from September 20, 2023, and adopt prevention and control measures for Class B infectious diseases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/dcdb718c013bccbff37e45063b6e2e3d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/dcdb718c013bccbff37e45063b6e2e3d.png&quot; data-key =&quot;250883&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/a7e16978f496a2d7dd21f9834e7c5ba3.png&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/a7e16978f496a2d7dd21f9834e7c5ba3.png&quot; data -key=&quot;250884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Website screenshot&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年暑期旅游超18亿人次，部分地区游客流入占比超2019年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国庆长假火车票正式开抢，你有多久没坐过绿皮火车了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256725]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 15, train tickets will officially go on sale on the first day of the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday. This year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday runs from September 29 to October 6. According to the 15-day pre-sale period for railway tickets, return train tickets for the last day of the holiday will go on sale on September 22. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While tickets to many popular destinations are hard to come by, there are also many trains and lines that are quietly withdrawing from the public eye. With the development of high-speed rail networks, the popularity of private cars and the expansion of air routes, regular-speed lines have ceased operations in recent years. For example, at Shantou Station in eastern Guangdong Province, all regular-speed trains have been suspended. The surrounding Jieyang South Station and Chaozhou Station have already closed their passenger transportation services, which have nothing to do with passenger travel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In neighboring Japan, this phenomenon is even more obvious. With the aging of the population and the outflow of people to big cities, a large number of local railway lines in Japan have been abandoned and stations removed. Not only is the travel of local residents in towns and villages affected, but many beautiful scenery along the railway are also difficult to see again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How long has it been since you took a green train? Are you interested in trying it out during your vacation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>