<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[母亲起诉儿子返还购房款：对家庭是一个警示丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261756]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;Today&#39;s Statement&quot; report, Yang&#39;s mother is a single mother, and her original condom was located in Dongcheng District, Beijing. The only house I have is my only son, Xiao Yang. She got 3.7 million from selling her house and transferred it to her son. She used it to buy a larger house in Tongzhou District, which she lived in and used as a wedding house for her son. Only her son&#39;s name was written on the property ownership certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2019, Xiao Yang got married, and Yang’s mother lived with Xiao Yang and his wife in the new house. Soon after the marriage, the daughter-in-law had conflicts with Yang&#39;s mother over daily trivial matters. The relationship between Xiao Yang, who firmly stands by his wife, and Yang&#39;s mother continues to deteriorate. After that, Xiao Yang and his wife moved out of their new house. Later, because his wife had another quarrel with Yang&#39;s mother, Xiao Yang became angry and blocked Yang&#39;s mother on WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, in order to solve the problem of her daughter’s schooling, Xiao Yang sent a WeChat message to her grandmother: “Sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house, and I will save money. Buy a house.&quot; &quot;If my mother can&#39;t agree, I will go to court to sue my mother in one month. If it really goes to court, there will be no turning back on our mother-son relationship.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Known After what her son said, Yang&#39;s mother said she was &quot;completely heartbroken&quot; and said she would be &quot;homeless&quot; if Xiao Yang sued her for obstruction. So Yang&#39;s mother sued Xiao Yang to return the purchase price of 3.7 million yuan for future pension purposes, and received the support of the court. This decision is in accordance with common law, or good customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a typical case of the conflict between the extended family orientation and the small family orientation. The current statutory legal framework talks about the individual standard and the small family standard: the division of property is based on the boundaries between individuals and small families, and small families implement the &quot;community property system&quot;; parents have raised their children to adulthood and have done their best to support them. Adult children have the obligation to support their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children who are minors must rely on their parents’ care, care and protection. Parents have custody and control over their children. When children become adults, they separate from their parents and form a nuclear family. If they get married and buy a house on their own, and do not receive support from their parents, nor do they expect to receive large amounts of property or inheritance from their parents, then the parents have not interfered with their children. A legitimate reason and effective starting point in life, children are &quot;independent&quot; from the extended family and gain the &quot;sovereignty&quot; of the small family. This is a normal intergenerational power transfer in a family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if on the one hand, the children get a large amount of support from their parents when they get married and buy a house, but on the other hand, they want to have a soft life and refuse their parents&#39; interference in their lives (whether it is &quot;suggestions&quot; or &quot;pointing fingers&quot;) Well, it’s actually the same thing), which essentially refuses parents to fulfill their “investor rights/powers”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as this case is concerned, the quarrel between the daughter-in-law and Yang&#39;s mother over &quot;daily trivial matters&quot; may have started because the daughter-in-law couldn&#39;t stand her mother-in-law&#39;s lifestyle, or she couldn&#39;t accept her mother-in-law&#39;s interference in the couple&#39;s lifestyle. The specific quarrel may have different rights and wrongs, but the underlying reason must be: the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law are fighting for the right to speak or dominate the house or the family, or one party believes that the other party has usurped his rights to the things in the house or the family. power or dominance. This is the essence of many conflicts between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a lot of poisonous chicken soups on the Internet nowadays, such as &quot;A husband must stand for his daughter-in-law, otherwise he will be a mama&#39;s boy.&quot; This is probably because the daughter-in-law or the person who acts as the daughter-in-law by herself is online more, while the mother-in-law is less online, and the former has a higher voice. bigger. After Yang&#39;s mother paid 3.7 million yuan to provide a wedding house for the young couple, after the conflict between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, the son did not reconcile the conflict, but blindly sided with the daughter-in-law, further intensifying the conflict, which shows that the son has nothing to do with his mother, who is an elder and investor. respect. There are many voices on the Internet who ridicule Xiao Yang for &quot;taking a wife and forgetting her mother.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, it was originally a tough and feasible plan to &quot;sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house while I save money to buy another house.&quot; But at the same time, Xiao Yang threatened his mother with &quot;prosecution&quot; and &quot;mother-child affection&quot;, which made her a little confused. During the court hearing, Yang&#39;s mother requested that the 3.7 million be recognized as a loan, while Xiao Yang requested that it be recognized as a gift from his mother, which seemed to contradict his promise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court ultimately determined that the money was a loan. But even if it is a gift, it is conditional and can be withdrawn. Mother Yang gave the money to her son to buy a house and only wrote his son&#39;s name on it. What she really meant was not &quot;I gave this money to you unconditionally. The house I bought will be written on your name.&quot; You can name it whatever you want.&quot; Instead, &quot;Mom, I have given all my belongings to prepare a wedding room for you. I will live with you. You have to take good care of me when I grow old. I only write your name because I hope you can compare my feelings with mine. Not only do they have the right to live, they should also be respected.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xiao Yangs not only failed to manage intergenerational conflicts and despised the rights/rights of investors, but instead took the initiative to escalate conflicts and regarded their widowed mother as an enemy. Such a move is morally wrong, and it is unfair to weigh the interests and benefits. Sensible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s okay to adhere to individual orientation + small family orientation, and at the same time insist on living independently and rejecting large-amount funding from parents; if you accept large-amount funding from parents, you must respect the rights/powers of the investor, and even You must have the awareness to be a low-key child. Of course, high-profile parents may not intervene, but in this case, not intervening is a sign of affection, not a duty. &quot;Having both&quot; doesn&#39;t work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, this case is also a warning to parents. By raising the children to adulthood, the parents&#39; duty has been completed and the legal responsibilities have been fulfilled. You cannot hand over your old capital to your children casually, and your main assets must be in your own hands. If a child needs a large amount of financial aid, it can be lent in a clear way, stipulating the principal, interest and repayment plan, or at least it should be clear that the parents have the right to claim it back. Don&#39;t let the children feel that their parents&#39; love for them is unconditional and they can take whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parent-child love must be two-way. It is sad that many parents become the tools of their children, providing money and effort, and then being picked on and stabbed by their young couples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[霞浦：摄影与旅游之间的距离]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml83fADU1S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml8 3fADU1S. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take pictures of the sunrise at the seaside of Huazhu Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Becoming a photography resort&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the sunset was about to dissipate, a group of foreign photographers returned At the B&amp;B on the mountain, we stood on the observation deck facing the coast and chatted. Looking down from the observation deck, there are still tourists taking pictures on the highway bridge at the foot of the mountain. Dongbi Village and Yugongting Village in Sansha Town, Xiapu County are famous for their sunset scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While waiting for the seafood banquet, a local member of the team introduced the owner of this B&amp;B to the photographers, Zheng Dexiong, the president of the Xiapu Photography Association, the person who famously photographed the Xiapu beach. His last introduction was: , &quot;The man who made Xiapu housing prices increase countless times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts are more powerful than words. An abandoned rural self-built house in Sansha Town can be sold for more than 100,000 yuan a year. Rented to B&amp;B owners, if the property rights can be traded, the price of a house can be as high as several million. And B&amp;B owners just for a piece of land, they knocked down their houses and rebuilt them, decorating them carefully. The price for a sea view room per night in the off-season is four figures. The skyrocketing housing prices have become a difficult problem for Sansha people who moved away due to lack of local industries in the early years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After greetings, Zheng Dexiong sat back on the outdoor seat on the other side of the observation deck and was busy planning the shooting schedule for another upcoming photography group. There were two more shoots arranged by the local government the next day. meeting. Everyone who comes to Xiapu for research and inspection wants to meet Zheng Dexiong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Zheng Dexiong, no one focused on tidal flat photography, and almost no one realized that the beautiful scenery of Xiapu was rare enough to be displayed. Zheng Dexiong, who has been engaged in commercial photography since the 1990s, was convinced of the uniqueness of Xiapu scenery after seeing many photos of seaside scenery. In 2002, Zheng Dexiong began photographing the tidal flats in his hometown in his spare time. Two years later, at the suggestion of a friend, he held the first photography exhibition in Xiapu on the street of Longshou Road. He also submitted articles to many photography magazines. His works were repeatedly published and won awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kasumigaura and its tidal flats are famous in the photography circle. Xiapu was rated as &quot;the first of China&#39;s top ten landscape photography holy places&quot;. Photography bases were built in small fishing villages along the coast. Fishermen who were engaged in seafood fishing returned to the shore, and young people who went out to work returned to their hometowns and started the tourism industry from scratch. . Zheng Dexiong remembers that 20 years ago, Xiapu County had only one short street and no foreign population. But now the city has expanded all the way to the seaside, and Taikang Road filled with food stalls is busy until late at night. In 2022, Xiapu, with a population of just over 500,000, received 7.2 million tourists. A few photos changed the fate of a county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s easy to say, but it’s not that simple. Over the past 20 years, we have actually invested a lot in transforming from private power to strong government support and from free services to a business model.” Zheng Dexiong objects to easy generalizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first started photographing the tidal flats, Zheng Dexiong walked along the more than 400 kilometers of Xiapu coastline. It turned out that there were no roads on the shore and it was a barren mountain. He had to bring a machete and a hoe to open a road while walking. When shooting at Shajiang Pier, in order to find a shooting point with a suitable height, he climbed up from the bottom of the mountain. When he reached the top of the mountain, he discovered that there was a stone road built by the village on the other side. Several of Xiapu&#39;s early famous photography spots were discovered by Zheng Dexiong in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong paid for the early foreign photographers who came to Xiapu with his own money, until he could no longer afford the money. On May 1, 2007, he opened the first paid photography group. A one-week trip for 20 people cost more than 1,000 yuan per person. The local government saw the power of photography in the tourism industry and began to hold national photography competitions and create logos for photography spots. More importantly, the government has taken the lead in gradually building and improving supporting infrastructure for photography spots, including roads, parking lots, and observation decks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, new photography spots are constantly being discovered. The 2017 edition of the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot; issued by the Xiapu Culture and Tourism Bureau lists 28 photography spots, and the number has increased to 33 in the 2021 edition. The infrastructure and tourism model around the photography spots have not yet been fully finalized, and both locals and tourists are adapting to the differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259979&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiapu tidal flat scenery through Zheng Dexiong&#39;s lens&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Perfect Photo&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first people to profit from photography are the characters closely related to the shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong believes that shooting in Xiapu is a test of skills and experience. &quot;The ebb and flow, changes in light and shadow, the alternation of four seasons, and different labor scenes in each season.&quot; This also means that shooting in Xiapu is uncertain. There are too many factors, including weather, tides, and seasons. The absence of any one element will lead to deviation from the default. Weather and tides can be grasped by experience, while labor scenes out of season can only be reproduced through performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of 2005, a Taiwanese photographer came to Xiapu to take pictures, but the whole series was missing a picture of Xiaohao Village catching fish fry in spring. Considering that it was not easy to travel from Taiwan to the mainland, Zheng Dexiong asked local fishermen to cooperate in posing for photos. This is how the new profession of fishing model was born in Xiapu. To this day, even if no one buys fish fry anymore, the fishing models in Xiaohao Village still hold up a triangular fishing net frame every time they perform - this kind of special-shaped net is specially used to catch fish fry, and because of the award-winning photo shoot There are three fishing models, so the trio is also fixed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Three people make a good photo.” Every time they perform, Bao Xuexian, who is in her fifties, her aunt in her seventies, and her aunt’s brother-in-law will put on knee-length rubber shoes, wearing Put on your straw hat, carry your fishing net and bamboo basket, and walk on the Xiaohao beach after low tide. The photographer would stand on the top of the mountain behind the village and shoot with a telephoto lens from a distance. Bao Xuexian&#39;s uncle Lin Jisong was responsible for reception on the mountain and conveyed the photographer&#39;s instructions to Bao Xuexian and others via radio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance fee for a performance is 300 yuan, and the fishing model costs 100 yuan per person. More than half of the days a month, people will be invited to perform, but Bao Xuexian does not think that fishing models are an enviable job. &quot;Only those who can&#39;t make money become fishing models, and those who can make money go to cultivate oysters and grow seaweed.&quot; &quot;When there are no performances, Bao Xuexian and her aunt weave fishing nets and sell them for money. A two-layered large fishing net sells for 31 yuan, and a three-layered one sells for 42 yuan. They can weave up to two per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Jisong receives guests at the top of the mountain, but does not participate in the distribution of performance fees. He has other income. Most of the people in Xiaohao Village were originally fishermen. Lin Jisong did not know how to fish. 24 years ago, he built a temple on the top of the mountain and made a living by collecting incense money. When fishermen go to sea, life and death are determined by fate, and they will worship gods before leaving. After the Xiaohao Tidal Flat became famous, the government built an observation deck on the top of the mountain, right next to the temple built by Lin Jisong. He felt that the angle of the path on the cliffside was better, so he paved a stone road and placed a few plastic stools. Anyone who goes to take pictures on the stone road must &quot;donate&quot; 10 yuan for the film fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Famous photography spots have regular fishing models, such as Jiang Lianshui in Beiqi Tidal Flat and Lao Cheng in Yangjiaxi. They have taken award-winning photos together and know better than novice photographers about how to take photos. &quot;They all know the angle, focal length, aperture, and speed.&quot; Zheng Dexiong found it very interesting. &quot;Initially, we went to the village to select models. There were no special criteria. They just had to be fishermen.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the government building In front of the roads and observation decks, outsiders who come to take pictures of Xiapu have to find local photographers who know their way around. Photography directors came into being, referred to as photography directors. With supporting facilities in place, photography guides are still needed because outsiders can’t figure out the tide schedule and the best time to take photos at photography spots. Nowadays, the threshold for photography guides is much lower. Not only members of the local photography association, but also taxi drivers, travel agencies and villagers have joined in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, Zheng Dexiong also proposed to the Culture and Tourism Bureau to provide centralized training for people engaged in photography and photography to improve their service awareness and photography skills. Later, there were too many people and it was difficult to coordinate. When he was out shooting, Zheng Dexiong heard the cameraman introducing him to the tourists. They stood face to face and neither could recognize the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259980&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists vacation at a B&amp;B in Dongbi Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Advantage Judgment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the minds of photographers, different photography spots have different ratings. Zheng Dexiong believes that although Xiaohao Village has the most award-winning films, the scenery does not change much and is the same regardless of the season; Huazhu Village only has sunrise, and the location is best only in winter, which is relatively monotonous; Beiqi Village can be photographed in any season. However, the pole frames for planting seaweed have been moved from the coast to the edge of the inland sea, and the beauty of the tidal flat patterns and pole shadows can no longer be photographed. The coast of his hometown, Dakyo Village, is more suitable for tourism than photography, because there are only beaches in that area and no tidal flats, and tidal flats are the core of Kasumigaura photography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Zheng Dexiong likes most is the east wall. The scenery changes endlessly throughout the year. In 2019, Sansha Town invested 20 million to build a light and shadow plank road to connect the photography spots along the east wall, making this area more popular. When the tide goes out a few days after the first and fifteenth day of the lunar month, more people come to the road. I can&#39;t even stand on either side. The highway bridge where the Dongbi Photography Spot is located is on one side of Dongbi Village and on the other side is Yugongting Village. The two villages have become a gathering place for boutique B&amp;Bs. Zheng Dexiong and his students all stay here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what the photographer thinks, the villagers have their own way of judging their own advantages. Uncle Zhang, the owner of Huazhu in the countryside of Huazhu Village, was originally doing business abroad. In 2020, he returned to the village to run a B&amp;B. He saw the potential of Huazhu. “Huazhu is a scenic spot for watching the sunrise. It is a must-go spot for anyone who comes to Xiapu. You must watch the sunrise. , you will most likely have to stay the night before.&quot; Uncle Zhang currently has 6 rooms, and the price per night is 400 to 600 yuan. According to his statistics, the occupancy rate is about 80%, and it is fully booked almost every day in the peak season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another characteristic of Huazhu is that it is the Hokkien-speaking area of ​​this small town in eastern Fujian. Uncle Zhang talked about the history of Huazhu, starting from three hundred years ago, &quot;Our ancestors were Those who moved from southern Fujian didn’t have big boats before. Fishermen fished along the coast and came all the way along the coast. Maybe they came here to escape the wind and rain. Later, they saw the abundant seafood here and settled down.” Huazhu Village speaks Hokkien and lives in stone houses. , pronounced &quot;厝&quot; in Hokkien. When building the B&amp;B, the village committee required that the exterior appearance must retain the appearance of a house. Uncle Zhang plans to do a crowdfunding project to raise 8 million yuan to build 8 more B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259978&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Xuexian’s aunt is in her seventies. When she is not performing, she makes money by weaving fishing nets&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the light and shadow plank road was built on the east wall, Niulangang Natural Village was gradually lost, but they were not willing to lag behind. Niulangang Village is the opening point of Xiapu’s first boutique B&amp;B CaoMuRen Teahouse. It has always regarded itself as the birthplace of Xiapu B&amp;B and is close to the county seat and the entrance to the highway. The introduction reads: “It is surrounded by mountains and sea, with beautiful scenery and convenient transportation. The location advantage is obvious and the tourism resources are unique.&quot; In the summer of 2023, Niulangang Village began construction to build an asphalt road and a viewing platform on the mountain where B&amp;Bs gather, hoping to regain the limelight as the first choice for tourists in the off-season. However, the construction team still started work during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day, which caused several negative reviews for surrounding B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sightseeing route from Gaoluo Beach, Dajing Beach to Hawei Island is named Donghai Route 1. Although there are few photographers, it is the route recommended by everyone in Xiapu. According to the observation of Xiaona, a stall owner on Xiawei Island, the sea caves on Xiawei Island are the internet celebrity photo spots that occupy the high traffic volume of social platforms. Since being photographed by an Internet celebrity at the end of 2021, it has attracted countless tourists. &quot;On May Day, one kilometer of road can be blocked for several hours.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Na and the young people in the stall area They originally worked in the county or around Ningde City. After their hometown became a tourist attraction in the past two years, they came back to set up stalls. &quot;No matter how much or how little you earn, at least you have more freedom.&quot; Xiaona&#39;s husband also came back to work as a photo guide, using his home An idle small off-road vehicle will charge 150 yuan to pick up passengers from Xiawei Island to another nearby scenic spot, the lighthouse; if it is a chartered vehicle, the price per day is 600 yuan, and you can choose Donghai Line 1 or Sansha Dongbi Line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It only takes two days to visit all the popular photography spots in Kasumigaura, and most tour groups’ itineraries are customized within two or three days. Xiaona has heard from many tourists that a three-day and two-night tour that includes transportation, food, and accommodation only costs more than a thousand yuan. “But the tour group doesn’t care about the weather and tides, and skips some spots if you can’t see them. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259977&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the planning of Huazhu Village, the appearance of the B&amp;B should retain the unique stone house style of southern Fujian&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Uneven&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The most common thing Ou Shao of Beiqi Village hears from tourists is, &quot;Why is it different here from the photos?&quot; &quot;So when he sees tourists now, he will explain in advance, &quot;Be sure to pay attention to the weather when visiting Xiapu. The weather is good or bad, and taking photos is completely different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zheng Dexiong&#39;s view, photography spots and tourist spots themselves It’s just different. “Some tourists come to the photography spot and feel that there is nothing to see, because photography has requirements on time and light.” The aesthetic perspectives of photographers and tourists are also different. The photographer was on the highway bridge on the east wall. There are three types of landscapes you can take pictures of - the grand landscape of the sunset, the seaweed net on the lake and the lines of the tidal flats under the bridge, but tourists generally only look at the sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ye Yu, who sells coffee under the observation deck of Huazhu Village, remembers that no one in the village cared about the sunrise before. When fishermen go out to catch fish, they go out at high tide and return at high tide. They look at the tide table, which has nothing to do with sunrise and sunset. On New Year&#39;s Day in 2013, CCTV broadcast the sunrise live in Huazhu, which earned Huazhu the title of &quot;China&#39;s Sun Viewing Landmark.&quot; The sunrise footage captured by CCTV was posted on the wall under the observation deck, and a stone tablet was erected next to it: &quot; How blessed to be in the same time and space as this sunrise.&quot; Ye Yu remembered that the CCTV sunrise was filmed by the staff who set up tents on the top of the mountain and lived there for a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqi Village was probably the first place to realize the different needs of tourism and photography. The Ou Shao family opened a B&amp;B in the village in 2013, and began taking tourists out to sea for sightseeing and fishing entertainment in 2020. So far, it has developed nearly ten projects, including tourist charters, fishing outings, parent-child trips to the sea, sales of dried seafood, and cage nets. &quot;The passenger flow here is unstable, so we can only develop more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao&#39;s family used to be fishermen, and their income from fishing was unstable. &quot;There are not so many fish now, and every May The fishing season is closed from the 1st to August 31st, and large boats can park on the shore.&quot; They considered daily fishing and tourism during the fishing season, and found that it was not cost-effective to only do it for three months. &quot;Do it all year round. If you do this, you will accumulate many old customers.&quot; So they concentrated on the tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao’s father now goes out to sea to fish, always accompanying guests on a chartered boat. The price of chartering a boat is 600 yuan, and the catch is uncertain. “It’s okay to catch more or less. Some tourists are Those who have come from the inland have never seen the sea and find it very fresh.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More tourists choose to spend 30 yuan to take a 20-minute boat ride to see the seaweed that has been planted on the edge of the inland sea. The Ou Shao family built a new boat in May 2023, costing 50,000 to 60,000 yuan. The cabin area was specially enlarged to accommodate up to 30 people. There are several families involved in the boat tour project in the village, including Ou Shao&#39;s relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ou Shao was soliciting tourists at the beach, an electric bicycle rode on the village road and he also talked to the tourists on the roadside. I asked Ou Shao, &quot;Is that your relative or a competitor?&quot; Ou Shao replied: &quot;It&#39;s my relative and a competitor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two of them stood guard in front of the entrance of the seaside parking lot, taking turns. Go up and ask the private car coming in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Uncle Zhang is making fire hoses for a B&amp;B by hand. He believes that returning to his hometown to build a B&amp;B is a feeling for his hometown&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under construction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all famous photography spots can catch up with the tourism boom. Xiaohao Beach is the earliest famous, but the surrounding areas The supporting facilities and B&amp;B design are lagging behind those of Dongbi and Huazhu on the same line. The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are concentrated in the new area on the edge of the old village. A large open space from the new area to the seaside is filled with sand, gravel, soil, fishing nets, construction waste and domestic garbage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are mainly self-built houses in rural areas. Villagers rent and sell spare rooms in their own houses. The decoration style of the rooms is basically the bedrooms of ordinary commercial houses. In order to reduce the difficulty of cleaning, a pile of public slippers are placed at the door of each B&amp;B for guests to change into. Such a room costs 300 yuan a night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Muhai B&amp;B is one of the few boutique B&amp;Bs currently in operation. It has floor-to-ceiling glass windows facing the sea and a small outdoor garden. The proprietress Wu Sister-in-law said that the design fee for the B&amp;B cost 60,000 yuan. . Sister-in-law Wu’s husband is a village cadre. When the houses in the new district first started to be decorated in 2018, he suggested that the villagers decorate them in the style of a B&amp;B, but the villagers were unwilling. Sister-in-law Wu said, “Someone asked at that time, and I bought it after all the hard work. If you decorate a house yourself and enjoy it, why should you let others live in it? By the time they want to think about a B&amp;B again, it will be too late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister-in-law Wu&#39;s B&amp;B will open in 2021, and only 5 of the two floors have been repaired. In the peak season, the price of a suite and bathtub room is as high as thousands of yuan per night, but in the off-season, there are almost no guests. She believes that the supporting facilities around Xiaohao Village have affected the development of B&amp;Bs. “There used to be a parking lot that could park 70 cars, and the roads were beautifully built, but it was demolished in 2021 and has not been built yet.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2021, Xiaohao Village has been caught in a storm of accountability for illegal land occupation and illegal construction in rural areas. After investigation and verification by relevant departments, Xiaohao Village actually built 121 homesteads, of which 61 were built by non-village personnel. It also introduced commercial health care projects and occupied 16 homesteads. In March 2022, information released by relevant higher-level departments stated that &quot;all illegally sold collective land has been taken back to the village collective, and the land will be restored to its original state after demolition.&quot; The villagers also don&#39;t know what will happen to this empty land filled with waste. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Natural conditions also restrict the development of some photography spots. Although the Xiawei Island Sea Cave is popular, it can only be revealed after low tide. Tourists who want to take pictures have to climb down the seaside rocks with bare hands. A warm reminder in the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot;, &quot;The reefs on the shore are easily slippery due to corrosion by sea water. It is recommended to wear non-slip shoes and walk slowly. Elderly people with limited mobility should not go there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sea caves are equipped with The rescue workers said, &quot;Every day, tourists slip off the rocks and fall into the sea.&quot; The scenic spot originally wanted to build a wooden boardwalk, but the rocks were severely corroded and broke when nails were hammered in, so they had to give up. &quot;Do you know why the scenic spot doesn&#39;t charge admission tickets? If it does, the compensation (if something happens) will be up to the sky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nearly 50 kilometers from the county seat to Xiamei Island, and there is a long stretch of road in the middle. It is a gentle mountain road. In recent years, a new road has been built close to the coastline. This road is open even before it is included in the map navigation. Just like the tourism industry here, it seems that it has not yet been completed, but the reception of tourists has already begun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我和物业博弈的这一年：解决问题有多难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261740]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The fate that every new owner cannot escape is to deal with and confront the property. This is his homework and his of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since I took over the house and became an owner in October last year, I have started to form a front with my neighbors and compete with the property management. Today, the team has collapsed, losing ground, and the rights protection has ended in failure. It&#39;s the same as the mental process of decorating, from being full of emotions to being discouraged, and finally giving up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the house was handed over for inspection, the quality of the house was worrying and many areas needed repairs. However, the developer did not do anything and delayed to solve most of the problems. Until now, the paint surface of the corner of my second bedroom is cracked. The seam is still there intact. This is indeed the developer&#39;s problem. The property management company can only help me communicate my needs, but they belong to the same company, and the property management company has collected property fees early. I have to discuss an explanation with the property management company. It is not unfair at all to take the blame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of fighting with the property owners, each other&#39;s tactics also changed according to the other&#39;s actions, and they continued to see each other&#39;s progress and retreat. If the housekeeper responds politely and politely, I will also communicate politely. If I am tougher, she will get angry at me. More often than not, the housekeeper will use low-grade deception, but I can&#39;t expose her directly. I have to leave a little kindness so that we can meet each other in the future and everything can be discussed. She told lies and fully accepted my needs, saying that she would urge and reflect them, but my problems would not be advanced or solved. She treats me as a fool. If she can evade something, she will do it first. Later problems will be dealt with later. The rhetoric will always be dealt with in a unified manner later. In the end, he couldn&#39;t do anything perfunctorily and ran out of patience. The housekeeper simply stopped making excuses and played the emotional card. She admitted that the developers were rogue and the property management companies were rogue. She only received a salary of a few dollars a month, so how could she have the final say? Without pretending, I was moved by her words that were completely embarrassing, and I began to accept in my heart that this was the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before I paid the property fee, I had to ask the housekeeper to get the key when I opened the door of my house. The owner of the owner group once privately suggested that I replace the lock cylinder and argue with the property management company about when to solve the problem and when to pay. . I didn&#39;t want to take an extreme approach, and I was eager to get a property certificate to install charging piles, so I had no choice but to surrender. Once the money is handed over, it becomes even more difficult to ask them to do something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this year’s negotiations and observations, I found that one of the main job responsibilities of the property management company is to collect fees. As early as September, before the previous year&#39;s property fees were due, the housekeeper started a show of fancy reminders to pay the next year&#39;s property fees. Taking advantage of the fact that the owners were at home at night, the housekeepers divided their forces and went door to door to collect property fees. Everyone among the owners condemned this behavior of only enjoying rights without assuming obligations. A few days later, the property management company sent out a notice with bait, offering free rice and cooking oil if the property management fee was paid during this period. So, I often see the housekeeper walking in the community carrying grain and oil, and watching her retreating back, I wonder, if the execution of solving problems is so touching, why are we here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a year of fighting, my interest in fighting for the rights of my neighbors has slowly cooled down. Recently, there have been voices in the group that want to replace the property, but I no longer have such high expectations for the final result. Confrontation between property owners and property owners has become the norm. I am afraid that my property and I, as well as the domestic property management industry, still have a long, long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an employee of a state-owned enterprise in Hangzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to you Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港仔：太平山B面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Take the green-painted Star Ferry from Tsim Sha Tsui. Rows of high-rise buildings slowly approach and zoom in. Behind them The Taiping Mountains are spread out like a belt, rising and falling gently in the porthole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original name of Taiping Mountain is Hard Head Mountain, also known as Xianglu Peak. It was renamed because after the surrender of the great thief Zhang Baozai during the Jiaqing period of the Qing Dynasty, the residents of Hong Kong Island thought that there would be peace from now on. In a broad sense, Taipingshan is composed of Mount Chechi, Lufeng Gorge, Gough Hill, Kwun Lung Kok and Mount Keli; in a narrow sense, it refers to Mount Chechi, the highest peak on Hong Kong Island with an altitude of 554 meters. There are two theories about what flag-pulling is: one is that Cheung Po Tsai raised the flag as a signal when he was a thief and commanded the people at the bottom of the mountain to rob merchant ships; the other is that in 1841, the British army occupied Hong Kong Island and raised the Union Jack flag here. Austin, who served as Colonial Secretary of Hong Kong from 1868 to 1878, named the mountain Mount Austin, and later renamed it Victoria Peak after the Queen of England (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Victoria Peak&lt;/span>;) and is still used today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After living in Shenzhen for more than 20 years, I have traveled to Hong Kong many times and visited Victoria Peak. To be precise, it is the crowded places on the north bank of Victoria Peak such as Central, Admiralty, Causeway Bay, and The Peak. Among Hong Kong people, the Peak refers specifically to Victoria Peak, and there is no ambiguity. However, most tourists today mistake the cable car terminal and Lingxiao Pavilion area for the top of the mountain. In fact, it is called Lufeng Gorge. Even for me, it was a few months ago that I walked through the slightly deserted Austin Mountain Road and climbed to the top of the real mountain for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the observation deck on the top of the mountain, leaning on the railing and overlooking the sky, you can see the vast red dust on the north bank, and the glitz and glamour. On the south bank, countless low hills seem to be eager to embrace the South China Sea... If the noise and commotion were the Taiping Mountains, The A side of Taiping Mountain, then, silence and tranquility are the B side of Taiping Mountain. A green mountain magically captures a completely different contrast. Unfortunately, due to other arrangements, I had no time to get close to Nan&#39;an Fangze that day. This time, Aberdeen, Hong Kong, where I made a special trip, is located in the center of Side B of Victoria Peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian looking at Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for Hong Kong Village&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;At Admiralty, transfer to the MTR South Island Line. One stop will bring you to the famous Ocean Park in Hong Kong, and then take a short shuttle bus to the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel you booked. Speaking of which, I am no stranger to Fullerton. Many years ago, I was in a business trip to Singapore&#39;s Fulun Hotel. It was a neoclassical building that made in 1928. The legend is comparable to the peace hotel in Shanghai Beach. So far I still remember that the negative layer of passage can go straight to Lion City&#39;s landmark lion tail. The Fulipun Ocean Park Hotel this time is located at the geometric center on the south bank of the Taiping Mountain. When the bus turns away from the noisy market, the transparent window suddenly crowded with green mountains and blue and white inlaid sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Hong Kong Tsai position map Pang Mc =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/cd1f944deb.jpg &quot;&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;734&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;260441 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; Hong Kong Zai location map &amp; nbsp; The first Asia&#39;s first all -weather sea water park -Marine Park Water Park, the amusement facilities are layered, and the terraces are permeated on the entire hillside; the right -hand side, the two random stacked warehouses are as gray as marks, collecting the rich people’s &quot;Toys&quot; -epon yacht and sailing; and in front of them, ducks, like ducks, buried half of their heads and body into the sea, vividly divided this series of Victoria Harbor and the South China Sea. Two widths and width channels: within the ducklings, it is narrow, known as the Hong Kong Strait, walking a boat; in addition, it is wider. For a moment, under the eyelids, the endless busy stream of ocean -ocean wheels and the slow leisure of various yacht sailing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Overlooking Duckzhou in the hotel in Fulipun Ocean Park. Photography Pang Mian&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/dc6241d429.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/dc6241d429.jpg &quot;Data-key =&quot; 260442 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; Overlooking Duckzhou in the hotel of Fulipun Ocean Park. &amp; nbsp; Photography Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Nanfeng Road near the Ocean Park has the entrance to the Hong Kong Zaoming Park. Like Hong Kong citizens, it is one of my wish lists in my journey. Unexpectedly, I took a few steps to the south wind duct and met a small black and white street sign. Soon, on the north side of the Jockey Club Science Building, behind the cement steps that are easily overlooked, a flowing flowing stream, I saw Huangzhukeng stone carvings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a relic of about 3500 years ago. Although the yellow cliff wall stands on the right bank of the stream, although it has been weathered, the six or seven square meters of rock surface, the three sets of slightly blurred rotation patterns, still like animals&#39; eyes, staring at me. This reminds me of the &lt;span>; 餮 pattern &lt;/span>; of the same Shang Zhou bronze ware.古, is the monster in ancient myths in China, fierce and greedy. &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; believes: &quot;Corruption is a lot of money, and greedy food.&quot; In recent times, its righteous flow has become a food that describes the food that describes Zhongyi Fengfeng. As for the patterns, the earliest pottery and jade of Liangzhu culture below the Yangtze River, because the patterns are mostly &quot;no body&quot;, also known as &quot;animal face pattern&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Reading the cultural relic cards on the spot, I learned that there are nine ancient stone carvings in Hong Kong. Hong Kong Island only existing Dalang Bay and Huangzhukeng in the south bank. Among them, the earliest stone carvings in Dalang Bay (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1978 &lt;/span>;) was listed as legal monuments, and Huangzhukeng stone carvings are the only position inland inland Stone carving away from the coast. So, why is the moment of stone? According to my judgment, if the creek under the feet is ancient, here is a high probability that the ancestors sacrifice water and draw fresh water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There must be villages with fresh water. When the original road was returning, I noticed that the stream drilled into the underground culvert in the south air duct while the stream was chaotic and disappeared. Fortunately, a blue card &quot;Old Wide Village&quot; was erected on the opposite intersection, pointing to the south wind diameter from the south wind channel. &quot;Siege&quot; is the general title of the past in Lingnan Village. It has both the meaning of &quot;gathering in Sri Lanka&quot;, as well as the &quot;image summary&quot; of the village to build a fence and a surround house. Old and old surroundings are equivalent to the old villages and villages in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The full name of Huangzhukeng in the old surrounding village, because of the &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The ravine with flowing water &lt;/ span>;) The yellow bamboo that raised a broom was named. However, according to Ye Lingfeng&#39;s book &quot;Hong Kong Palm&quot;, Old Wai Village was first known as Hong Kong Village or Hong Kong Wai, and the ancient books of the Ming Dynasty Wanli &quot;Cantonese Dacheng · Guangdong Coastal Map&quot; and Qing Kangxi&#39;s &quot;Xin&#39;an County Chronicle&quot; were recorded. At that time, Wanxiang (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Agarwood produced in Dongguan, Shenzhen, Hong Kong and other regions &lt;/span>;), this area It is the initial distribution center. Late to 1866, the &quot;Xin&#39;an County Full Map&quot; printed in Leipzig, Germany still marked the village name of &quot;Hong Kong Wide&quot;. The name of Hong Kong today &quot;is based on the name of this small village gradually becoming popular.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The southern wind is not long, and the old surround village curled up at the end of the steep slope. Under the slope, the vehicle is filled with the vehicle; on the slope, it is incredible to cover the house with iron. When I entered the village, I circled around. Except for a small Buddhist temple and a small mountain god&#39;s nib, the incense was smoked a little bit, I didn&#39;t find any ancient meaning. Inquiring about the grandmother of the servant garden, I learned that I built the Hong Kong Tunnel Toll Station and Huangzhukeng Hospital many years ago, and the old house was demolished. Talking, suddenly, four or five big yellow dogs approached, barking at me. When I was young, the empirical school of the country was used in handy. At this time, there was a bamboo pavilion and a nest of long and fine bamboo in the entrance of the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Fulipun Ocean Park Hotel&#39;s swimming pool is facing the Dongbojiao Strait. 23/12/02/d712e53ef0.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 719 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/ms/medias/23/12/02/ d712e53ef0.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260443 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; The swimming pool of the Fulun Ocean Park Hotel is facing the East Expo Strait. &amp; nbsp; Photo Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Hills Hong Kong Zai &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Return to the south air duct. embrace. Gradually go, gradually walking away, and the body and mind float with the mountains, like the fragrance soaked in the forest and the occasional bird singing. Hong Kong Zaoming Park is one of the first batch of country parks in Hong Kong. It was established in 1977 and covers an area of ​​about 423 hectares. From east to west, Nie Gaoxin, Jin Marun, Banner, and Tianwan Mountain. In the meantime, the traversal diameter and the vertical and horizontal areas can reach the entire Hong Kong Island. At the end of the 19th century, the old house in the old enclosure was still there. The surrounding fields and grass and grass were like the city. The official giant and gentleman ladies in the area &lt;/span>;) have come and spend time. There are more people walking, and there are more roads in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Climbing to the mountainside, a width of more than 1 meter deep (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Direction canal &lt;/span>;) Objectives, the bottom of the U -shaped toss. As we all know, Hong Kong freshwater is barren, especially Hong Kong Island. In order to relieve tension, in the 1960s, Guangdong Province successively constructed Shenzhen Reservoir and Dongjiang-Shenzhen Water Supply Project to support it. = &quot;FonT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Reservoir &lt;/span>;). Today, the diversion channel, together with the ponds, has almost become the &quot;standard&quot; of all country parks in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260444 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; p; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Mrs. Kim Joma has a bird&#39;s -eye view of Hong Kong Zai Center. &amp; nbsp; Photographer Pang Mian &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the water diversion rush down and rushed down the mountain pit, at the foot, the road of Mrs. Jin was replaced by stone scarc to loess. Mrs. Jin is also known as Mrs. Jin, named after the 17th Hong Kong Governor Jin Wentai, and has a total length of about 5 kilometers. Mrs. Kim&#39;s name was Mary &lt;span>; Aels &lt;/span>;, born in 1889, and later moved to Hong Kong with his father C. J. Alx. In 1912, she married her 14 -year -old Jin Wentai. The two are deeply affectionate, Yahao travels and Chinese culture, and Jin Wentai can even be promoted to Hong Kong Governor in 1925. During his tenure, Jin Wensai reluctantly disappeared the adverse impact of the strike of the provincial and Hong Kong University on Hong Kong, improved the relationship with the Mainland, and promoted Chinese education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under his advocacy, in 1927, the Chinese University of Hong Kong added a Chinese department, and a group of former Qinghanlin was invited to teach the old classics. Unexpectedly, this caused a word of words of new cultural sports characters such as Lu Xun and Hu Shi. Right or wrong, the time has changed. However, it is an indisputable fact that the Chinese Department of the University of Hong Kong attaches importance to Chinese education and later came out of Zhang Ailing, Huang Zhan, Lin Xi, and other literary coffees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to official duties, Jin Wensai often accompanied his wife to come here to go out to experience the mountains and sea of ​​Hong Kong. Writer Liu Kexiang pointed out in &quot;Three-quarters of Hong Kong&quot; that the area area of ​​Hong Kong Magazine Park in winter is six hundred or seven hundred. &lt;/span>;) Favorite city green wild &quot;. Maybe the season I came was earlier, and I just saw a few soaring. But the Jin Wentai couple should have seen the scenes that hover the sky to cover the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Figure Pang Mc =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/27c1665F22.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 719 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/27c1665f2222.jpg &quot;data-&quot; 260445 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; Hiravity in Nanlang Mountain &amp; nbsp; Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; 疍 疍 舫 舫 &lt;/strong>; &lt; /h4>; &lt;p>; At this moment, at 4 pm, I rushed to the Pier of the Plant Bay, and then fell into the surround of sea ships and shore shipyards. At this time, Sunshine jumped off the main peak of Yahuangzhou on the opposite side, caught the red, blue, green, and white reflection. Suddenly, I was in the background of a Hong Kong film, and some of them were yellow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dashu Bay, where Fulipun Hotel is located in the south of the Futanwan, is connected to Shenzhen Bay in the north. Many online posts explained that the cloth factory Bay was named after many clothing factories. In fact, according to my on -site observation, the &quot;cloth factory&quot; should be written by the &quot;port&quot;. The master of the Chinese painting master Guan Shanyue&#39;s hometown Yangjiangbu Farm is a dock with the sea from the sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;舢舨 Photography Pang Mian&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ 474c20fddd.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/23/12/474c20fddd.jpg &quot;data-- Key = &quot;260446&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>; 舢舨 &amp; nbsp; photography Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; You came with a red canopy boat with the side of the yellow flag on the side of the side, and welcomed the wind. On board and sitting, I found that the bundle was covered with jewelry: red lanterns, artificial flowers and plants, and small &quot;nation&#39;s flags&quot; in Hong Kong&#39;s place names. As soon as the boat opened, it followed slightly. Zhu Grando, who was driving the boat, said deliberately: &quot;This is the most beautiful in Hong Kong&#39;s water. The most beautiful &lt;/span>; in Hong Kong&#39;s water &lt;/span>;). &quot;The boat pocked a beautiful arc, the motor was low, and the direction of the coming was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Water people call &lt;span>; as &lt;/span>; in the Mainland, mainly distributed in the southeast coast. Historically, the name of the family is mixed, such as yachts, Baishuilang, eggs, 蜑, snakes, boat households, etc. Until the Tang and Song dynasties, it was collectively referred to as &quot;疍&quot;. The Tang Dynasty Liu Zongyuan&#39;s &quot;Lingnan John John Temple&quot; was the earliest &quot;疍&quot; literature. Regarding the origin of the origin of the family, scholar Chen Xujing has done statistics, as many as 30 species. Among them, the most romantic: one is from the people, the mermaid; the other is the descendants of Fan Ye and Xi Shi in the Spring and Autumn Period. The generally accepted opinion believes that the family is the descendants of Baiyue, who was killed in the southeast of the Qinhuang and Han Wu. The &quot;Answers of the Ridge&quot; that the Southern Song Dynasty went to the &quot;Mountains&quot; said: &quot;Take the boat as the room, the water as the land, and the floating life rivers and the sea, and the&quot; also &quot;; From an early age, he taught him to step on waves. Boil crabs as grains, and bananas do not need gauze for cloth. &quot;Since the 1950s, the Mainland’ s family members have been settled ashore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Grandma Zhu did not agree with the view of the book. She told me that in the past, the people on the water were small and could not raise pig cows, so they had to raise chickens, ducks and geese. For a long time when people on the shore came to buy eggs. After a long time, it was called the waterman &quot;&lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Tongyu &lt;/span>;). &quot;If my mother is alive, when I hear the egg family, I will be scolded, so taboo.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Zhu Grandma Zhu who has been driving for a lifetime, Pang Mian&quot; src = &quot;http: // images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1439 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/cms/cms/cms /-Medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260447 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; Zhu Awo &amp; nbsp; Monster &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1841, the British first came to let a family member Chen Qun bring the road. After passing the village of Hong Kong, when he asked the place name, Chen Qun, who asked the family, answered &quot;Kanggang&quot;, and the British army remembered it with &quot;hongkong&quot;. Of course, this is just a legend. As far as I know, in 1793, when the Macau Milk Mission in the United Kingdom left China, the relevant reports have mentioned &quot;hongkong&quot;: &quot;&lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Today belongs to Shenzhen &lt;/span>;) and Hong Kong is suitable for colonial.&quot; But in any case, this legend also reflects the relationship between Hong Kong and the family. As for the origin of Hong Kong, it is also a bit related to this legend: After Hong Kong became the name of the entire island, in order to avoid confusion, the people renamed it as &quot;Hong Kong Zai&quot;, that is, &quot;Little Hong Kong&quot;. Later, the Hong Kong British government changed Hong Kong&#39;s English name &quot;Littlehongkong&quot; to Aberdeen (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Yabutian &lt;/span>;) The four generations of Earl Yabudian and the British Foreign Minister George Hamilton-Gordon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The boat entered the deep bay, revealing a piece of empty water, and the huge neon light cards desertedly wrote &quot;Welcome&quot;. Far away, there is a bleak painting — Taibai seafood, like the old lady who is old to miss youth. &quot;The original position of the treasure seafood&quot;, Grandma Zhu said that the guests turned their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Around 1930, Guangzhou&#39;s family brought the &quot;singing hall&quot; into Hong Kong Zai. This kind of water restaurant that integrates and tourism is integrated, coupled with local famous seafood, quickly became popular. Cultural celebrities who went south to visit Hong Kong, such as Hu Shi and Cai Yuanpei, also smelled the fragrance and the friends, and came here. After entering the 1950s, there were more than ten upgraded seafood crickets in the &quot;Church&quot;. In 1971, the treasure seafood was fired during the decoration, which was severely damaged. The Macau Gambler He Hongzhang heard the news that the Xunjia genes in the bones wake up (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The great-grandmother is the family &lt;/span>;), partnership with others, throwing a person, throwing a person, throwing it More than 30 million Hong Kong dollars bought rebuilds. In 1976, the design of the palace style of the Ming Dynasty and the treasure seafood of more than 2,300 people opened. A few years later, He Hongzhang included the biggest competitors&#39; Taibai Seafood and Haijiao Palace. The world&#39;s largest sea food house, the treasure kingdom, was born in the air, and it was like the green landmark of Hong Kong. At that time, the dignitaries visited Hong Kong, and they couldn&#39;t come here to &quot;check in.&quot; The young man Zhu, Zhu, rely on the free boat (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; ferry &lt;/span>;), with a monthly income of more than 10,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is interesting that the golden age of &quot;treasure kingdom&quot; is also a period of prosperity and prosperity in Hong Kong films. From Bruce Lee to Jackie Chan, from &quot;Dragon Fighting Tiger&quot; to &quot;Infernal Affairs 2&quot;, it has become a resort for Hong Kong films to compete. Especially in &quot;God of Food&quot;, Zhou Xingchi has a floating clothes, walking around the waves, and flying to the bridge of the window, leaving deep memories for the star fans. Including a word, the real shooting point of &quot;God of Food&quot; is in Taibai Seafood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1998, the Asian financial turmoil created the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot;. The Haijiao Palace stopped business first, and then moved to Qingdao. In the future, the &quot;treasure kingdom&quot; is getting worse. In 2022, the treasure seafood dragged away from Hong Kong was devoured by the waves near the Xisha Islands in the South China Sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; The God of Food &quot;is Taibai Seafood 舫 Figure Pang Mian&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02 /fc2b691b61.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 719 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/23/12/fc2b691.jpg &quot;data -Key = &quot;260448&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>; The scene of &quot;God of Food&quot; Taibai Sea &amp; NBSP; Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;strong>; The sunset &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Through the duck 脷 落 bridge, the number of water birds is increasing, and the wings are welcoming us on the upper and lower wings. There are constantly taking selfies to the bow of the bow to capture the moment when they are in the same frame as the waterbird. The girl around me also excitedly raised her mobile phone, looking around, but I didn&#39;t know which one was shot. &quot;See, the boat beside the boat, there is a big fake bird,&quot; we looked along the girl&#39;s fingertips. Maybe the sea breeze took her, and the &quot;fake bird&quot; instantly &quot;resurrected&quot;, twisted his long neck, and &quot;stared&quot; at us. In the laugch of the coax, Hong Kong Zai Fengtang arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The righteousness of the wind pond refers to the water surface of the typhoon. When Hong Kong was also called Shiquan Bay, the family had been engaged in short -distance fishery and water transportation, and participated in the transfer of stone and Guanxiang. But what I saw in front of me was unexpected, and it was clearly a water floating city. The ships selling vegetables, boats driving shops, households, repaired boats, trafficking boats, ferry boats, water police boats, fish -collecting boats, boats to visit, catering boats, cleaner ships, seafood selling seafood, selling seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, sales of seafood, and seafood sold The boat, the luxurious ship, the humble ship, the dilapidated ship, the brand -new boat, the hurried boat, the slow boat ... I can&#39;t help but remind me of the Americans William C. Hunter&#39;s to the Pearl River Estuary in 198. Description: &quot;The river is covered with local ships ... In addition, there are 舢舨, as well as 舢舨, and the ferry of Henan (&lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; South Bank of Zhujiang &lt;/span>;) There are also some razor boats and the sale of daily necessities sold by all kinds of food, clothes, toys and shops on the shore shop. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A Po slows slowly and moves closer to a stove in a pot. Over there, put his hands early; here, Zhu Grando praised the sentence &quot;good business&quot; and restored the speed of the boat. It turned out that it was a &quot;powder boat&quot; specializing in fish and egg powder and roasting powder. In the 1960s and 1970s, Hong Kong&#39;s fishery production entered its peak, and the &quot;Fanzai Boat&quot; was also popular, and it was everywhere to avoid the wind ponds. In addition to fishermen and crew members frequently patronized, citizens and tourists also came here to show off the boat on the shore. Now, there are three or two boats doing it regularly. &quot;Eat and eat, you are lucky.&quot; Grandma Zhu went on to say. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; It also needs&quot; luck &quot;, as well as Zhu Daxian&#39;s party in the wind pond. According to Zhu Gauxian, Zhu Daxian, who will be sacrificed by Zhu Daxian, is the Eight Precepts of the Pig. He has been in charge of Tianhe, and is regarded as a sea god by the waterfront of Hong Kong. Family: Kaiti, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Godfather &lt;/span>;)&quot; &quot;&quot; &quot;is second only to the queen mother&#39;s ancestor. Among all the crickets in Hong Kong and Macau, only Zhu Daxian will be held at sea every year, so it is also called the water surface. Since the meeting period is not fixed, when the meeting is not fixed, when the meeting is not fixed, you have to ask for a question in advance. Whether you can bite in his prosperity, completely &quot;luck&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In countless ships, we found one, no, two Zhu Daxian Temple. It seems that it is transformed from a double -layer cruise ship. The top flagpole is towering, and the fluttering yellow triangle red flag reflects Yu Xia Xia at the setting sun. The reason why there are two, Zhu Grandma explained because &quot;Lao Zhu Daxian&quot; needs to lead the &quot;new Zhu Daxian&quot; to be familiar with the personnel of the Fengtang. After some days, he has completely handed over the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Sitting and watching the sunset is one of the&quot; compulsory courses &quot;to travel to Hong Kong. /Image/23/12/02/fae0742e11.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 719 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/mdias/image/23/12 /02/fae0742e11.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260449 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; &quot;>; Sitting to watch the sunset is one of the&quot; required courses &quot;for Hong Kong Zai. &amp; nbsp; Photo Pang Mian &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Return to the boat and go through the &quot;site&quot; of the treasure seafood. The night rose and drowned the neon light card in a dark shadow. In front, the lights are bright and the lights are brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雄心勃勃的印度海军扩张计划丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261746]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-03 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/8vkwkfngropwdxswgako2MKS5JHGHHKP18mAppx.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 640 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i MAGE/23/11/29/8VKWWKFNGROPWDXSWGAKO2MKS5JHGHHKP18MAPPX. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259964 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; August 17, 2023, Kolkata answered, the Indian Navy&#39;s new warship Ins Vindhyagiri sailed in. Hu Geli River &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the Indian Navy proposed the need to buy French SCALP long -range cruise missiles, hoping to use this missile As a standard anti-ship and ground attack weapon equipped with 26 &quot;gusts&quot; -M carrier-based aircraft equipped with the aircraft carrier &quot;Victor&quot;. One month ago, Ukraine used the SCALP cruise missile to destroy a Russian and Black Sea fleet submarine that is repairing in the Crimea dock. This is the only submarine sunk by the cruise missile so far. In addition, the SCALP missile also hit the headquarters of the Black Sea Fleet, which performed well in actual combat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, this is not the only naval equipment recently purchased from France. On October 28, 2023, the Indian Navy just submitted a purchase request for 26 array -based carrier -based aircraft to the French government. The carrier -based aircraft is fully replaced with the French gusts, not the Russian -made MiG fighter that has been upgraded for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The procurement plan is by no means simple, which is part of the Indian ambitious navy reorganization plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2022, the Indian Navy Ajendra Bahadur Singh (Ajndra Bahadur Singh) told the media: &quot;Some naval ships will retire in the next few years, while Increasing some ships, we hope that in 15 years (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 2037 &lt;/span>;) The number of naval ships can reach more than 200 ships. &quot;&lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; Since India&#39;s independence in 1948, the Indian Navy has always hoped to be a Blue Water Navy with 142 ships and operating two aircraft carriers at the same time. The target of the ship seems to be a bit difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The difficulty of expansion of the Indian Navy is far from the problem that is far from 200, but India not only needs to increase 68 ships in 15 years, but also needs to be mostly equipped with the main equipment equipment of the Navy in these 15 years. NATO. This also means that at least one -third of the main ships in India&#39;s active duty, which are more than 40, to complete the preliminary NATO goal. In this case, India must equip more than 100 ships within 15 years, while India now equips about about 4 ships every year. At this speed, the Indian Navy may only maintain the current scale, not to mention India&#39;s grand equipment expansion of equipment expansion The plan also includes a new aircraft carrier, which is undoubtedly difficult to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From a practical point of view, the Indian navy reorganization plan may not be as magnificent as it claims. The Indian Navy has long relied on Russia&#39;s supply equipment for a long time, while Russia has lost huge losses in the war. The supporting chain of large surface ships in the Soviet era is mostly in Ukraine. Since the Crimean crisis in 2014, Russia has not been able to obtain Ukrainian supporting products. As a result, its large surface ships have difficulty even maintenance and maintenance, and it may not be able to continue to supply India in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When India had previously cooperated with Russia to cooperate with the &quot;Super Kings&quot; aircraft carrier reconstruction project, the progress was procrastinating and seriously overdue. India had realized that it was difficult to rely on Russia at the time, so they had begun to build large surface ships by themselves. Industry Planning. Helplessly, India was sanctioned by the United States for nuclear weapons at the time, and could only continue military cooperation with Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In recent years, with the rapid heating up with the United States, India&#39;s navy equipment self -made plan is accelerating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2022, the first local aircraft carrier &quot;Vikrant&quot; manufactured by the Indian Kachin Shipyard Co., Ltd. (CSL) was officially served, marking that India has the ability to build an aircraft carrier -though this ship Difficulty aircraft carriers have been delayed from work to formal service, and the Indian Navy has been waiting for 17 years for this. However, compared with the aircraft carrier, the construction of the Indian domestic destroyer can be said to be quite smooth. The first ship has been serving from 2011 to 2021. It only takes ten years, and is continuously launching at a speed of one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, India has built three 7,000 tons of Vishacapartan destroyers on its own. The ship has an invisible appearance and shield air defense system. India claims that its localization rate has reached 75%. It is a model for Indian warship countries. It can be seen that the Indian shipbuilding industry is at least on the large main ship of the construction destroyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another favorable Indian shipbuilding industry is the signing agreement in India and the United States in 2021, announcing that India will become the U.S. Navy&#39;s future large -scale equipment maintenance center in the Indo -Pacific region. In 2022, the US -India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue announced that the United States intends to inspect the Indian shipyard. Immediately after, the US Navy Charles Druc (T-AKE-10) stopped at the Katapari Shipyard for maintenance and repair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This agreement means that the United States will help India improve the maintenance and construction capacity of large warships, and even directly provide technical cooperation to allow India to master the construction and maintenance technology of large American warships, as well as related technical standards and management process. From the experience of Japan and South Korea, the United States&#39; cooperation weapons and equipment maintenance bases established in the North Korea after the Korean War have played a key role in improving the local shipbuilding technology technology and the optimization of management processes. Especially for countries such as South Korea, independent after World War II, the lack of weak talents in its own industrial foundation, and the technical support provided by the United States is essential for its industrial system. Thanks to this, South Korea has established its own military industry, or even even Now it has begun to become a new type of weapon and equipment exporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although India ’s main war equipment has a long -term poor manufacturing capability, it has to admit that it already has its own manufacturing capabilities at least in terms of naval equipment. Part of the logistics system for military equipment in the United States. Considering that India&#39;s economic development momentum is strong, and the U.S. and Europe&#39;s technical restrictions on their technical restrictions are almost completely lifted. Therefore, it is possible to replace the original Soviet system in 15 years to make its navy equipment Westernization. In the case of scale, vomiting the new goal can be fully achieved. As for whether it can be expanded to the scale of 200 ships, it also depends on the execution capabilities of the Indian shipbuilding industry and economic development. However, it is foreseeable that with the help of Western technology, the combat effectiveness of the Indian naval ships will definitely improve significantly, which is also the goal of the hope of the United States and Indian military cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北极光：极夜中的极致绚烂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261722]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我匆匆地走入森林中丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzXZeGIW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzX ZeGIW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260804 &quot; title=&quot;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&quot;>;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer, a dazzling news: 94 Lu Delin, a 20-year-old Shanghainese man, told on social media that he was abused by his nanny and defrauded of his pension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to Shanghai&#39;s 2022 elderly population and aging undertaking monitoring statistics, the registered elderly population aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022 will be 5.5366 million, accounting for nearly 40% of the total registered population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone is 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connection between individual circumstances and the lifeline of the times is about to emerge. It is a topic of public value. After encountering countless stories, I still can’t help but feel the initial excitement and impulse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, standing in winter and thinking back to that summer, the first thing that comes to mind is the part about mosquitoes. The scene we first arrived at was the community where the incident occurred. The community is located in Huangpu District, Shanghai, in the city center. It was built in the early 1990s and has 4 high-rise buildings interspersed with lush tall trees and low grass. It was a summer evening in Shanghai, and there were two or three old people sitting on the benches downstairs enjoying the shade. I wanted to know some surrounding information, and I became the target of &quot;mosquitoes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culprit is probably the &quot;flower mosquito&quot; as the local elderly call it. In just three or two hours, it left more than a dozen red and swollen bumps on my legs that were already wearing trousers. It was obviously not appropriate to scratch and chat at the same time, so I had to scratch twice quickly in the gap from one bench to another. The physical feeling was real, and this unspeakable and unseemly detail became the first fragment that hit me in my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This feeling is like a coincidence, and it has been fulfilled in several recent questions, which are about the body. In the topic of Lu Delin, the accused nanny is no longer in the local area. Even during the exchange of evidence before the court session, she still did not appear. The subjects on the other side, the two elderly people, were taken to Hangzhou by their son and daughter-in-law, and their mental condition was not very good for a time. Well, considering that I was afraid that the visit of strangers would bring excitement to the two old people, I did not go to see them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the message left for me? It&#39;s an empty house, and there are surrounding clues that need to be found. Room number 2401, pushing open the closed door, the first thing that came out was a sour smell. This is supposed to be well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. There are several orchids on the balcony. The flower pots are quite old, and the branches and leaves are wilting. For a moment, people don&#39;t know whether they should be described as being well-groomed or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moldy cutting boards, dirty yellow clothes, expired food, all indicating the disorder of life, suddenly broke into my eyes in an instant. In the eyes of young people, in the undisordered time, what I discussed with my friends around me was more about the spiritual part, and the instinct of the body was automatically ignored in the surface respectability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last topic was in Xi&#39;an. The interview subjects were some disabled people. In the continuous rain, we could not wait for the scene of their &quot;reunion&quot; and had to go door to door to chat. During the process, everyone The disorder of the body was mentioned invariably; and after Lu Delin chose the topic, I continued my business trip in Shanghai. The new topic was about Alzheimer&#39;s disease. The wife who became a caregiver told the story of taking care of her sick husband for nine years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From these stories, we can see what everyone is trying their best to maintain, and this effort seems to be an inevitable disorder of life. As a bystander, I hurriedly walked into this forest and felt the &quot;disorder&quot; that I had never experienced in real life. Some disorders are accidental, such as a car accident or sudden illness. They are also unprepared and rush into the forest and never get out; some disorders are slow, such as aging. They are already on the road to aging. It has been too long, so long that I have to admit that aging has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the perspective of journalism, when we encounter these stories, how should we report this disorder? After the initial excitement and impulse, it’s time to write. I think that we should not visit this forest with a pair of curious eyes and notice something unsightly. It should not be regarded as the author&#39;s delicate observation and be presented freely. It’s better to enter this forest with a level gaze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this time we entered this forest because of work, such a forest may break into our real life at any time, and in addition to the accident that breaks in at any time, its final arrival is a kind of inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“巴基斯坦可以从中国学到很多”:专访巴参议院国防委员会主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261738]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73936&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70727&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Exclusive interview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At noon on December 1, Mshahi De accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporter. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260507&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December At noon on the 1st, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of December 1, Guangzhou Yuexiu International Conference Center. After the one-hour press conference, Pakistani guest Mushahid Hussain Saeed walked out of the venue quickly. Entering December, the weather in Guangzhou turns cooler. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I like Guangzhou. It has a pleasant climate and is a very dynamic place in China.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid is the chairman of the Defense Committee of the Senate of Pakistan and the chairman of the Pakistan-China Society. From December 1st to 3rd, he was invited to participate in the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference to discuss and communicate with domestic and foreign guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past fifty years, Mushahid came to China many times. In his words, he witnessed the poverty-stricken China in the 1970s and the reform and opening-up China in the 1980s. &quot;What we see today is a prosperous and powerful China that is leading the development of globalization.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;I am very happy to witness the rise of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Mushahid Shahid spent four years in Washington, the United States, and obtained a master&#39;s degree in international relations from Georgetown University&#39;s School of Foreign Service, &quot;with an understanding of the U.S. political system and how it operates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He proposed that there are two different &quot;roads&quot; in the world today. One proposed by the United States and Western countries is security-centered, military-led, and focused on conflicts and confrontations. On the contrary, China insists on connectivity and cooperation, respecting diversity and being more inclusive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years, the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor, an important pilot project of the “Belt and Road Initiative”, has brought development opportunities to Pakistan. &quot;26 billion U.S. dollars of investment, 250,000 job opportunities, and 28,000 Pakistanis came to China to study. Electricity, roads, hospitals, education, etc. are constantly improving.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;These have benefited Pakistan.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Global and regional security are also the focus of the conference. Regarding peace on the India-Pakistan border, Mushahid has optimistic expectations. &quot;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is will. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on December 1, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/h4>; strong>;&lt;span>;Is this your first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum? How do you feel? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is my first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum. This forum is very valuable. First of all, we use this platform to understand China, the region and the world, and how they change and develop. Secondly, it is important for Pakistan to understand China. Because China is our closest strategic partner and our neighbor. Third, personally, I have been dealing with China for nearly fifty years. When I first came to China, I was still a young man of 17 or 18 years old. As a friend of China and a student of Chairman Mao, I saw China at that time. It can be said that I have witnessed China&#39;s transformation. If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with the first time you came to China, now what is the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to China was in the 1970s. At that time, China was very poor and isolated from the world. Today, China has become rich and powerful, a global leader, and a leader in globalization. China has proposed the “One Belt, One Road” initiative to lead green development and technological innovation. So, this is a huge change. In addition to China, the world has also changed. Because the global center of gravity is shifting from the West to the East. This change in China also reflects global changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What are your impressions of Guangdong? For example, for the two big cities of Guangzhou and Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to Guangdong Province was in 1972, when Guangzhou A trade fair is being held. During that time, I went shopping at Guangzhou Friendship Store. I only had 200 yuan with me at that time, but I felt like a &quot;millionaire&quot;. Because no matter how I bought it, I never spent all the money. At that time, the price of Chinese goods was too cheap. There were no computers at that time, so people used calculators to calculate accounts or calculate money by hand. Then, I took a train from Guangzhou to Hong Kong, which was indeed a wonderful experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Shenzhen was in 1982, and then in 1984. At that time, Shenzhen was a remote fishing village. After seeing it in person, I also felt that it was too backward and underdeveloped. When I first came to China, the city of Shenzhen did not exist. But in the subsequent 1980s, I saw the rapid rise of Shenzhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many Pakistani businessmen do business in Guangzhou. Can they find business opportunities here? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid: Of course. Pakistani businessmen in Guangzhou have been working here for years, even decades. In fact, many trades began not just now, but decades or even centuries ago. Guangzhou has always been a hub of connectivity and a warm and welcoming city. Foreigners are welcome to come here to do business and stay here. It has a pleasant climate, is close to the sea, and is a beautiful city. So Pakistanis enjoy life here, we support them and they can make a lot of money. So I think it&#39;s very good and they play a very good role in promoting relations between the people of Pakistan and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Pakistan can learn a lot from China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span >;Over the past 40 years, China has undergone tremendous changes. What lessons do you think this has for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Pakistan can learn a lot from this. First, have a clear vision. Second, there must be the will to turn this vision into reality. Deng Xiaoping, the architect of China&#39;s reform and opening up, once said, &quot;Seek truth from facts&quot; and &quot;development is the last word.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insist on development and openness, simplify bureaucracy and cumbersome processes, give talents the attention they deserve, and put them first. Good leadership qualities, policy continuity, learning from mistakes, openness and inclusiveness, focus on people-centered development, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I said, we can learn a lot from Guangdong, China, and China&#39;s reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Are you confident about Pakistan’s future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very optimistic about the future of Pakistan. I studied in the United States for four years, but I didn’t want to live there. I said I would go back and serve my country. This is thanks to our relationship with China, which is our neighbor and our best friend. China invests extensively in Pakistan. We must unleash the energy and creativity of the people of Pakistan, move forward, reduce bureaucracy and allow them to develop. We need to build industries, innovate, get education, and let them focus on what they should do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73937&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70728&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;At the media meeting on December 1 , Mushahid said that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260508&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At a media conference on December 1, Mushahid said that the “One Belt, One Road” initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, development opportunities have come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot; >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Is the “One Belt, One Road” initiative a development opportunity for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan, and we must seize this opportunity. In the past ten years, China has invested US$26 billion in Pakistan, created 250,000 jobs and produced 8,000 megawatts of electricity. These results have given Pakistan and its people confidence in the future. For example, Gwadar Port has developed and become a hub between Pakistan and Central Asian countries. So this is a big opportunity. Because of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative, a whole new world is unfolding. This is a historical opportunity for Pakistan to develop rapidly, and it is also a historical opportunity to learn from China&#39;s poverty alleviation and green development model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have misunderstandings about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, but most Pakistanis fully support the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Maritime Silk Road. Many Pakistanis care about China. They believe that China is Pakistan&#39;s good friend and close ally. Therefore, the negative voices come from foreign propaganda. They come from misinformation, false stories and fake news. We have to fight back against this. This is the biggest challenge facing the Belt and Road Initiative in the next decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Terrorist attacks occur frequently in Pakistan. How should the government solve the problem of terrorism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, terrorist incidents do happen from time to time. Some of the terrorists come from neighboring areas, which are very unstable. Some are forces that do not want cooperation and development between Pakistan and China. In addition, we feel that there are foreign forces controlling terrorist activities in Pakistan, and they specifically target Chinese companies, individuals and projects. Therefore, we must develop an effective counter-terrorism strategy in Pakistan, carry out effective Pakistan-China security cooperation, and develop effective plans to protect Chinese projects and Chinese people living in Pakistan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We reject global hegemony and regional hegemony”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2023, Pakistan’s Foreign Minister will visit India for the first time in 12 years. Do you think India and Pakistan have the will and motivation to deal with border conflicts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is a will. India should be broader-minded and not become narrow-minded in dealing with small countries. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony. Whether it is Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, etc., they all reject hegemony. Look at Afghanistan, they reject American hegemony even though they are a small country. Therefore, the size of a country does not equal its strength. India should learn from the mistakes of other major powers and understand how they went in the wrong (direction). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The internal and external obstacles to solving the India-Pakistan issue are What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the internal obstacles mainly come from the negative attitude of the Indian government, and their mentality must change. The external problem is the &quot;new cold war&quot; launched by the United States against China in Asia. They are using India to counter China. This is where the problem lies. Therefore, India should be part of the Asian countries and should be part of the Belt and Road Initiative. We want India to be united with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India is a nation-state with a great civilization. Why say no to this? Why should India work and behave like Washington or London? India should cooperate with Beijing, Kathmandu, Dhaka and Colombo. This is a regional issue. The future belongs to this region, not Europe or the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If India continues to respond negatively to relations between the two countries, will there be a risk of escalation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think escalation can be avoided because India also knows that if they try to escalate, the other country will respond . Every country hopes to safeguard its territorial integrity, safeguard sovereignty, and maintain unity and dignity. They tried to launch an attack on Pakistan in February 2019, and they sent several aircraft over Pakistan. But we fought back and shot down two helicopters. So the country will respond, and this response will come quickly and strongly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融合规榜：万余条罚单中，哪家银保机构在坚守底线？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:24:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the financial industry with strict supervision and strong supervision, compliance Rules are the bottom line that must be adhered to. As the world&#39;s largest banking market and the second largest insurance market, China&#39;s banking and insurance industries have always been the focus of supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Today, financial institutions’ compliance will be elevated to a new level. The Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that &quot;financial chaos and corruption problems continue to occur, and financial supervision and governance capabilities are weak&quot; and emphasized that &quot;financial supervision must be comprehensively strengthened to effectively prevent and resolve financial risks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Compliance has thus become a core consideration for the soundness of financial institutions’ operations. Which financial institution often commits crimes? Which financial institution frequently charges sky-high fines? Which financial institution has the most business lines involved? This is not only the key regulatory orientation of regulatory agencies, but also a concern of every financial consumer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to monitor the compliance of various financial institutions in real time, the relevant departments of Southern Weekend worked together for nearly a year to build the &quot;Shepherd-China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud&quot; Platform” (hereinafter referred to as the “Sheepdog Platform”). After continuous iterative upgrades and improvements, the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; now collects in real time the administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and their national offices, and simultaneously performs manual correction. test. In order to ensure the accuracy of the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; data, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared the recorded data with the information released by the three institutions one by one. The comparison results show that the accuracy of the penalty information data collected by the Shepherd Platform is as high as 100%, with no omissions or errors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively present the compliance of 20 systemically important banks and nine major life insurance companies in 2023, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; &quot;More than 10,000 pieces of data collected were mined and analyzed to construct the 2023 China New Financial Compliance List. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Penalty information from three regulatory agencies, two dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; in real time Includes administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, and their national offices. Therefore, this data information basically covers all regulatory penalties for the banking and insurance industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also conducts statistical analysis on the number of fines and the amount of fines received by financial institutions, because the number of fines and the amount of fines respectively reflect the extent of violations. How many and whether the violation is serious or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to statistics, from January to October 2023, 20 Chinese systemically important banks and their branches received a total of 802 fines, with an average of 802 fines per bank. and its branches received 40 fines; the above-mentioned fines totaled nearly 1.127 billion yuan in fines, and each bank and its branches were fined nearly 56.3548 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Nine major life insurance companies and their branches received 287 fines, with an average of 31 fines per life insurance company and its branches; the total of the above fines The fine was nearly 52 million yuan, and each life insurance company and its branches were fined nearly 5.73 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From a mean perspective, banks have higher values ​​than life insurance companies in terms of both the number of fines and the amount of fines. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that this is related to the bank&#39;s large scale and business volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center collected 10,467 pieces of penalty information (including institutions) issued by the three major regulatory agencies from January to October 2023 on the Shepherd Platform Penalty information and personal penalty information) conduct data mining analysis and construct a new financial compliance list for 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Which bank was fined the largest amount? Which company has been punished the most? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank compliance list shows that China Construction Bank, Minsheng Bank and Shanghai Bank took the top three spots. Among them, China Construction Bank and China Minsheng Bank were fined more than 200 million yuan each, far exceeding the 98.544 million yuan imposed by Bank of Shanghai. The list of the number of penalties imposed on the bank compliance list shows that the five major state-owned banks of Industry, Agriculture, Postal Service, Construction, and China are among the top five in the list, and the number of institutional penalty information is more than 70, far exceeding the sixth place Minsheng Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness Ranking - Bank Compliance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banks in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, from January to October 2023, the number of institutional fines received by each bank is basically the same. They are arranged in order of state-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks. There is no obvious pattern in the amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For state-owned banks, during the time period included in this list, compared with the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, and Postal Service Bank, Bank of Communications The degree of compliance is relatively good. In terms of the amount of fines, Bank of Communications ranked twelfth, while the other five state-owned banks were all ranked in the top ten. At the same time, the number of fines received by Bank of Communications is also relatively small, and it is the only bank that is not in the echelon of state-owned banks in terms of the number of fines. The bank received 41 pieces of penalty information during the time period of this statistics. The number of penalty messages is only higher than that of China Minsheng Bank, a joint-stock bank in the echelon, with 42 messages. China Construction Bank became the bank with the largest amount of fines at this stage due to a fine of nearly 200 million yuan issued by the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission (now the State Administration of Financial Supervision) on February 16, 2023. In addition, the amount of each fine of ICBC, which ranked first in the number of fines, did not exceed 6 million yuan. Therefore, its total amount of fines ranks low among state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The compliance status of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks is relatively similar. During the statistical time period of this list, one bank in each of the above two categories ranked in the top three in the list of fines imposed, and the reason was that they received large fines of more than 60 million yuan. Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu are the two banks with the best compliance during the statistical period of this list. The fines imposed on the above two banks did not exceed 10 million yuan, which were 600,000 yuan and 8.601 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that because the four major banks have large business scale and many branches, a high number of penalties does not necessarily mean that their compliance is lower than that of other banks. bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Loans are still the hardest hit area for violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Analyzing the types of violations, the statistical time of this list During this period, the violations of the 20 systemically important banks were concentrated in three areas: loans, external guarantees and customer identification. Among them, the loan business is the hardest hit area for bank violations. The above-mentioned fine of nearly 200 million yuan from China Construction Bank involves a total of 38 violations of laws and regulations, 15 of which are related to violations of loan business. Among the top ten in terms of the amount of fines received, except for Shanghai Bank, which only had one fine for &quot;violating the handling of domestic guarantees and overseas loans&quot; and seven other fines involving illegal handling of foreign exchange business, the fines received by the remaining nine banks all related to loans. Business violations. In fact, according to penalty information over the years, loan business violations have always been an &quot;old disease&quot; in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Illegal handling of domestic guarantees for overseas loans and illegal external guarantees are the largest fines imposed on banks by the State Administration of Foreign Exchange during this statistical period. Bank of Shanghai and China CITIC Bank were fined 98.544 million yuan and 11.7544 million yuan respectively for the above-mentioned issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, customer identification issues were the third highest fine imposed on banks by regulatory agencies during this statistical period. Among them, the highest fines received by Ping An Bank and Postal Savings Bank during this statistical period both involved &quot;failure to perform customer identification obligations as required&quot;, and the fines for these two tickets were 53.4117 million yuan and 31.86 million yuan respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above analysis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that banks need to focus on the compliance of loan business, guarantee business and payment and settlement business. How to eradicate old diseases and ensure the compliance of loan business is an issue that major commercial banks need to think about urgently. Today, some banks have applied artificial intelligence technology to assist manual loan review and other processes. Therefore, improving the accuracy of artificial intelligence technology in assisting in reviewing loan information may be one of the feasible solutions to rectify the &quot;old disease&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance companies urgently need to strengthen the implementation of internal control systems&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance compliance list shows that regardless of Ping An Life ranks first in terms of both the amount of fines and the number of fines it has received. Taikang Life ranked third and second respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The second place in the list of the amount of fines and the third place in the list of the number of fines are Taiping Life and China Life respectively. It is worth noting that AIA Life Insurance Co., Ltd. performed better in this compliance list. During this statistical period, AIA Life was the only financial institution among all participants in the list that did not receive any fines from the three major financial regulatory agencies and their dispatched agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness List - Life Insurance Compliance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the perspective of the types of violations, life insurance companies’ violations are mainly fraud, deception and inducement of policyholders and system management issues . According to the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, from January to October 2023, there were 453 pieces of information about penalties for life insurance companies. Among them, 187 involve fraud, 105 involve deceiving or inducing policyholders, and 130 involve internal control systems and management issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, most of the fines involving &quot;inadequate implementation of internal control systems&quot; involve &quot;preparing false information&quot; and &quot;inciting and inducing insurance agents to engage in acts that violate integrity&quot; voluntary activities”. &quot;Instigating and inducing insurance agents to engage in activities that violate their fiduciary obligations&quot; is the root cause of &quot;deceiving or inducing policyholders&quot;. This may be related to the business value concept of the company and its branches. If the design of the company&#39;s assessment indicators is unreasonable or the implementation is deformed, or the managers of relevant departments behave inappropriately, it will be difficult for their subordinates, especially grassroots personnel, to ensure business compliance when conducting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, the compliance issues of life insurance companies this year can basically be attributed to the unscientific design of the indicator system and the inability to implement the internal control system. The Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recommends that leaders of life insurance companies should adhere to the strategic focus of high-quality development and should not ignore compliance for temporary performance impulses, let alone engage in fraud that affects the image of the company or even the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿险效能提升榜：谁现在领先？谁拥有未来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2023, China’s life insurance industry will continue to undergo difficult transformation. In a complex and ever-changing market: Life insurance was a hot seller in the first half of the year due to high interest rates, but the twists and turns in the equity market made life insurance investments suffer. &quot;Integrating newspaper and bank into one&quot; (see Southern Weekend App for details) Perennially deformed? &quot;>;&quot;Big accounts are high and small accounts are constantly rising. Why is the bancassurance business deformed all year round?&quot;&lt;/a>;) The new regulations have made the bancassurance channel under pressure even more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, life insurance companies are still determined to continue transformation, pursuing efficiency improvements, and are more committed to the blue ocean market of pension insurance and insurance +, and are competing for more considerate customer service upgrades . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Who is leading the race to transformation? Who sticks more to the &quot;customer-centric&quot; strategy? Which company is more transparent and open to the media and the public? Which company pays more attention to compliance? Which company pays more attention to innovation? Based on the principles of objectivity, fairness and science, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed an evaluation index system for life insurance performance improvement rankings and evaluated the performance of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight major dimensions&amp;nbsp;Fourteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Life Insurance Performance Improvement List&quot; Quantitative The qualitative evaluation index system consists of six first-level indicators and fourteen second-level indicators. Among them, the first-level indicators include three quantitative dimensional indicators of &quot;operational capabilities, customer service, and regulatory compliance&quot; and three qualitative dimensional indicators of &quot;business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecology, and product innovation.&quot; The secondary indicators are refined into fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of the quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on the special research on the above-mentioned life insurance companies, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the participating life insurance companies. The company conducts independent real-name scoring. Both scores have a weight of 15%. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the life insurance company under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2087&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a.png&quot; data-key= &quot;260503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now The specific description of quantitative and qualitative indicators is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(1) Business capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How to judge the management ability of a life insurance company? From the perspective of business model, the business logic of life insurance companies is to collect premiums to form insurance liabilities, use insurance liabilities to invest to form investment assets, and the investment assets generate investment income. Therefore, to evaluate the operating capabilities of a life insurance company, one is to look at its ability to obtain premiums; the other is to look at its investment asset management capabilities. Original premium income is commonly used in the industry to measure the liability capacity of life insurance companies, but the premium income of nine life insurance companies accounts for about 3/4 of the life insurance industry. The life insurance performance list aims to select the best among the best, so the new indicator insurance service income is included in the statistics&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is insurance service income? According to the explanation in China Ping An’s semi-annual report, insurance service income refers to recognition during the insurance period based on the provision of services, and excludes investment components. Insurance service income reflects the income obtained from engaging in insurance business. In accordance with the provisions of the &quot;Accounting Standards for Business Enterprises No. 25 - Insurance Contracts&quot; (Finance [2020] No. 20) revised and issued on December 24, 2020, listed insurance companies will implement it from January 1, 2023. This regulation is also called the &quot;Chinese version of IFRS 17&quot;. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found in its survey that, except for China Life and Taikang Life, seven other life insurance companies have applied the new insurance contract standard IFRS17. Under the new accounting standards, insurance business income is replaced by insurance service income, which also leads to a significant reduction in the recognition of premium income of life insurance companies. Life insurance companies with a large proportion of investment savings products and a high proportion of single premiums will be more obviously affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, new business value and embedded value measure the insurance company&#39;s value, profitability and sustainable development, and the total investment return rate measures investment performance. These three indicators are commonly used indicators in the industry. In summary, the total weight of the four secondary indicators in this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(2) Customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The insurance industry is a typical service-intensive industry. How to implement the &quot;customer-centered&quot; development concept, meet the diverse needs of customers, and improve the service quality of the insurance industry are key issues for my country&#39;s insurance industry to achieve high-quality development. From the demand side, the age composition and demand of insurance customer groups have changed significantly, and young customers have increasingly higher requirements for insurance services. From the supply side, my country&#39;s insurance products are highly homogeneous, with little difference in product pricing and basically similar scopes of liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the life insurance industry cannot sell insurance as a &quot;fast-moving consumer goods&quot;. Otherwise, large-scale surrenders may occur, and the service attributes of &quot;slow experience&quot; and &quot;slow decision-making&quot; of insurance should be returned. Risk protection is the core function of the insurance industry. To implement &quot;customer-centric&quot;, on the one hand, insurance must be renamed insurance and return to the protection function; on the other hand, insurance must be made &quot;value for money&quot; insurance. In other words, we need to make it affordable, worthwhile, convenient and reassuring for consumers. Based on this, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has set up three secondary indicators to measure claims settlement amount, average claim settlement timeliness and surrender rate in the customer service dimension. The total weight of the three indicators in this dimension is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(3) Compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, &quot;standardization&quot; has become the key word for the development of the insurance industry. At present, institutional supervision, behavioral supervision, functional supervision, penetrating supervision and continuous supervision have gradually formed. In 2021, the focus of supervision will be on the top-level design of the reform. In the fields of corporate governance, solvency, and insurance capital utilization, the &quot;Corporate Governance Guidelines for Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot;, &quot;Insurance Company Solvency Supervision Rules (II)&quot; and &quot;On Modifying the Parts in the Areas of Insurance Capital Utilization&quot; were released Notice of Normative Documents&quot;. In 2022, regulatory agencies will deepen supervision of consumer rights and interests and issue the &quot;Management Measures for the Protection of Consumer Rights and Interests of Banking and Insurance Institutions.&quot; This is a basic and programmatic document in the field of consumer rights protection in the banking and insurance industries. In 2023, supervision will shift to the regulation of bancassurance and individual insurance channels, and the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products in Bank Agency Channels&quot; and &quot;Measures for the Management of Insurance Sales Behavior&quot; will be issued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sets four sub-indicators in the compliance dimension, among which core solvency adequacy ratio and comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio are key regulatory indicators; insurance The service quality index refers to the 2022 insurance service quality index released by China Banking and Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Banking and Insurance&quot;); the data on the number of administrative penalties comes from &quot;Sheepdog&quot; - China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud Platform Regulatory data collected by the system from January to September. The total weight of the four sub-indicators of this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(4) Business cross-penetration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension reflects the synergy and cross-selling capabilities of life insurance companies between different business lines. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the growth logic of life insurance institutions has shifted from &quot;scale&quot; to &quot;quality.&quot; The “insurance + service” development strategy has become an industry consensus. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(5) Healthy ecological construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The development of pension finance is inseparable from the construction of a comprehensive health ecosystem, because &quot;the elderly are provided for and the sick are treated&quot; are inseparable. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the development of life insurance companies in the field of big health business based on the annual reports or other public information of each life insurance company. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(6) Product innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension mainly reflects the product development and innovation capabilities of life insurance companies. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life leads the way&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above dimensions and indicator system, and integrating the 2023 results of various life insurance companies Mid-year reports and announcements, as well as data from third-party rating agencies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated 9 insurance companies and obtained a total score of quantitative and qualitative indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on media factor weights and external expert review weights, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed a life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked the top three. Among them, China Life and Ping An Life have a clear lead and are the only two life insurance companies on the list with a total score of more than 60 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/1da3a7600f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1188&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1da3a7600f.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify ;&quot;>;Sub-indicator system observation shows that in the quantitative and qualitative indicator scores, China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked in the top three, and there was a wide gap between the scores of the other six life insurance institutions. There is a nearly ten-point difference in scores between AIA Life in third place and Taiping Life Insurance in fourth place. This shows that the first-tier life insurance companies have a larger lead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the scores of the expert jury, the expert judges favored Ping An Life Insurance. The company was the only life insurance company to receive a score of 9. In the media factor, AIA Life, PICC Life and China Pacific Insurance failed to respond within the limited time for some reason and did not score, which in turn affected the overall score to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed from different dimensions, China Life, Ping An Life and PICC Life ranked the top three. China Life&#39;s 2023 interim report did not apply the new insurance contract standards, but replaced insurance service income with insurance business income, so there is an overestimation to a certain extent. However, China Life’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that its insurance service revenue reached 136.439 billion yuan, only slightly lower than Ping An Life’s 168.945 billion yuan. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center calculated and found that the adjustment did not affect China Life&#39;s ranking in the life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Why does China Life top the list? China Life has obvious advantages on the liability side. China Life&#39;s third quarterly report shows that in the first three quarters of 2023, the scale and growth rate of premium income, new policy premiums, and first-year regular premiums all hit new highs for the same period in the past three years. First-year regular premiums with ten years or more were RMB 44.639 billion, a year-on-year increase of 15.4%, accounting for 42.12% of first-year regular premiums; new business value continued to grow in the first three quarters of 2023, with a year-on-year increase of 14.0%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From an asset perspective, declining investment returns are a common problem in the industry. Against the backdrop of downward shifts in interest rates and fluctuations in the equity market, investment returns in the insurance industry have generally declined. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the life insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. Therefore, the overall score for this indicator is low, with PICC Life scoring the highest because it uses group data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life performs well in the customer service dimension. In terms of sub-indicators, China Life’s three indicators are all at the leading level in the industry. Data from the company&#39;s 2023 interim report show that the average claim settlement timeframe is 0.39 days, a year-on-year increase of 17%; &quot;claims prepayment&quot; exceeded 74 million yuan; &quot;claims direct payment&quot; exceeded 3.41 million; &quot;one-day critical illness compensation&quot; compensation amount exceeded 5.4 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, China Life does not fall behind in terms of regulatory compliance. In terms of sub-indicators, the company&#39;s core solvency adequacy ratio reached 140%, and its comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio reached 204%, both well above regulatory requirements and at the average level among the nine life insurance companies. In the 2022 Insurance Service Quality Index released by China Banking and Information Technology, China Life received a high score of 94.61, which is higher than the average level of 85.28 in the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, according to data from &quot;Sheepdog&quot;, a compliance cloud platform for China&#39;s financial industry, China Life was fined 47 times (including branches) in the first three quarters, a high On average 29 times. Because China Life has a large business volume and many branches, this indicator does not mean that the company&#39;s compliance is lower than that of other peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Develop pension finance and cultivate new growth poles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the midst of high-quality transformation of life insurance companies Nowadays, as the core component of the third pension pillar, pension insurance is becoming a strategic insurance type. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that pension finance has huge potential. The three-dimensional indicators of business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecological construction and product innovation reflect the development of pension finance of life insurance companies to a certain extent. However, the disclosure standards of various life insurance companies are not uniform because they are in the exploratory period. Therefore, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducts evaluations based on the annual reports of each life insurance company and with reference to various information such as announcements and publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that although Ping An Life ranks second in the total score of the list, it scores first in the three qualitative indicators. China Life Second, AIA Life, Taiping Life and Sunshine Life tied for third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also found in its survey that nine life insurance companies are actively participating in the construction of pension finance. Among them, China People&#39;s Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., China Life Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., and Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd. are the first batch of pension insurance companies designated by the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau to participate in the commercial pension pilot. The pilot is about to be completed for one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Other life insurance companies are also actively exploring pension finance business. For example, Ping An Life relies on the resources of Ping An Group of China to continue to make efforts in the direction of &quot;insurance + services&quot;. In terms of &quot;insurance + health&quot;, Ping An Life launched the &quot;Ping An Zhenxiang RUN&quot; health service plan. In the first three quarters of 2023, Ping An Life has served more than 19 million customers, a year-on-year increase of more than 10%; in the &quot;insurance + high-quality health care community&quot; In terms of &quot;Ping An Life Insurance&quot;, Ping An Life has teamed up with other professional companies within the group to build a high-quality health care brand &quot;Zhen Yi Nian&quot;. In October 2023, Ping An Zhenyi Nian officially released Wellness Care 3.0, launching two new benefits: residence and CCaH (Continuing Care at Home). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of &quot;insurance + home care&quot;, Ping An Life continues to explore home care services. As of the end of September 2023, Ping An&#39;s home care services have covered 54 cities across the country, with a total of more than 70,000 people qualified for home care services, and more than 50% of policyholders in 54 cities have activated their home service rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Taikang Life has formed a collaboration with 20 &quot;Taikang Homes&quot; across the country and has become an industry benchmark. Sunshine Life will start with the Sunshine Family (Guangzhou) health care community and gradually deploy a chain of CCRC senior care communities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the integration of medical and nursing care is a general trend, and &quot;insurance + services&quot; is becoming a new blue ocean. All life insurance companies should continue to innovate in products and services. On the one hand, they should enrich product connotations and expand the coverage of insurance products; on the other hand, they should extend the value chain of insurance services and provide comprehensive services such as health management, medical services, and long-term care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欠发达县1个在编身后1.8个临聘：转移支付保“吃饭财政”难以为继]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot;, the reporter was in a county in Wumeng Mountain District During the investigation, it was found that the county’s total wage guarantee budget expenditure for the year was 2.63 billion, including 2 billion for in-service personnel, 170 million for retired personnel, and 460 million for temporary personnel. The number of temporary employees is 1.8 times that of in-service employees, but the total salary budget of the former is less than a quarter of the latter. In addition, the county&#39;s total salary expenditures for temporary employees have exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue. In several neighboring districts and counties of the county, the average number of temporary employees is 1.7 times that of in-service employees. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Specifically, the per capita annual income of temporary employees in the county is about 16,100 yuan, and the total number of employees is 28,806; the per capita annual income of current employees is about 12.83 million, and the total number of personnel is 15,580. The per capita annual income of current employees is eight times that of temporary employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How do you view this phenomenon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First of all, the county has been completely reduced to &quot;food finance&quot;. The total annual salary budget for temporary staff is 460 million, which has exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue, which means that the county&#39;s economic strength and endogenous fiscal capacity are very weak. Against the background that the sluggish housing market has stalled land finance, especially in small localities, the total annual budget expenditure of 2.63 billion on guaranteed wages will most likely come from transfer payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for the economically developed areas that currently provide sources of transfer payments, their finances are not sufficient or even very difficult. It is impossible to maintain the &quot;food finance&quot; for a long time by relying on transfer payments. , the county may have to slim down: reductions in personnel, staff, budgets, and expenditures are inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, the so-called on-the-job personnel are formal workers with a formal establishment; the so-called temporary personnel are temporary workers and contract workers without a permanent establishment. If we have to reduce headcount, which category of people will be eliminated first? From the perspective of effectiveness and efficiency, how should redundant staff be eliminated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The answer to the first question is obvious. In the case of financial difficulties, unemployed personnel will be laid off first. This is also a common practice everywhere. It&#39;s called &quot;retiring temporary workers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason is very simple: the principle of minimum action. In theory, there is no iron rice bowl anymore. The current &quot;Civil Service Assessment Regulations (Trial)&quot; has annual assessments, and the results are divided into four grades: excellent, competent, basically competent and incompetent. &quot;The annual assessment for two consecutive years is determined to be Those who are found to be incompetent will be dismissed.&quot; But in fact, unless a major principled error is made, it is very difficult to lay off an employee with a civil servant or a public institution, and few leaders are willing to be evil and &quot;smash people&#39;s jobs&quot; and are worried about being sacked. The job holder or his family may cause trouble, be unsightly, and have a &quot;bad influence.&quot; But it&#39;s different for temporary workers without official establishment. They are mentally prepared to be laid off due to the company running out of money or the superior&#39;s request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, should temporary workers be eliminated (first)? Before answering this question, you must understand why the company recruits temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Temporary workers are different from temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​is that there is a relationship, but the relationship is not strong enough and it is not enough to get the establishment in one step. First, recruit people to make a temporary transition and wait for the internal opportunity to become a regular employee. Banyuetan reporter&#39;s investigation found that the recruitment and management of most temporary personnel are not handled by a unified department and are basically carried out according to the principle of &quot;who employs people, who recruits them&quot; without approval or approval from the establishment department, finance department, organization department, human resources and social security department. The registration and recruitment procedures are relatively haphazard, with the phenomenon of disorderly growth in quantity and unguaranteed quality, and it is difficult to eliminate recruitment based on personal relationships and relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The other type is irrelevant or almost irrelevant. They are recruited to do the dirty and tiring work that regular workers are unwilling to do. , hard work and troublesome work, you may be pushed out to take the blame if something goes wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also many internal contradictions in such units: on the one hand, formal workers get more money, good benefits, but work less, and there are various ways to obtain honors and Opportunities for promotion; on the other hand, temporary workers who work receive less money, poor benefits, and more work. If something goes wrong, they will be pushed out to take the blame. With such a close contrast, the latter&#39;s psychology will be very unbalanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, if we look at the logic of the market, temporary workers are paid market prices; for the same position, regular workers are paid more than temporary workers. Part of it is the premium brought by the preparation. When multiple people compete for an organization, they compete for the premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public people think that when &quot;retiring temporary workers&quot;, the first type of eviction is to let those who do not work leave to improve efficiency, but in fact The second type is often eliminated, which is to let the temporary workers leave. It doesn&#39;t matter and they are hard-working, so there is the least resistance to the elimination. However, after they are dismissed, the regular workers often complain because someone has to do the work. After laying off these many people, work can still be done. In this sense, efficiency has been improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, government functions should be viewed from the perspectives of government and market/society. Government management should also live within its means: a county&#39;s tax revenue is less than 500 million a year, and the total budgeted expenditure on guaranteed wages is 2.63 billion. The county has been financially exhausted. Do we really need so many people, spend so much money, and take care of so many things? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We should sort out: which management and service functions are absolutely necessary and can only be performed by the government, and what budget and staff size are appropriate; which ones can be abolished to allow Society manages itself; what is considered excessive regulation or improper regulation stifles economic vitality? Even if a county has too many net outflows of people and its population and economic scale continue to shrink, then merging counties is also a good choice, and merging villages It has been practiced in many places such as , , towns and villages, reducing the scale of government and releasing market vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, it is because civil servants have become the de facto iron rice bowl and the premium brought by the establishment is very high, that’s why everyone has such a big interest in the public examination preparation. enthusiasm. If we can implement the annual assessment of civil servants and public institutions, and dare to fire veterans who only get paid but do not work like market-oriented enterprises, and reduce the premium brought by the establishment to zero, everyone will be more rational about the public examination preparation. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is another way to compress or even eliminate the premium brought by staffing: marketize job salaries and see how much the temporary workers recruited from the market are paid. Then the salary of regular workers is as close as possible to that of temporary workers, so as to squeeze out the premium of establishment. Cleaners in a certain place have a staff. Cleaners with staff hire people to do their work and then enjoy the price difference. This difference is the premium brought by the staff. The government or taxpayers were taken advantage of and spent more money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:25:19 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>