<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[四川“废弃神话公园”，藏着“七仙女”与“历代帝王”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260960]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the ancient exhibition with &quot;Chinese history and culture&quot; as the core theme The famous scenic spot has many statues of emperors and generals designed in the China Progress Garden.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258918&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot with &quot;Chinese History and Culture&quot; as the core theme was designed in the Huaxia Process Garden There are many statues of emperors and generals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is not uncommon for scenic spots to close down, but the &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; tourist attraction located in Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan Province has left a large amount of money full of tourism after being abandoned. A man-made &quot;cultural heritage&quot; with a sense of absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, in Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, the gate of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was closed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, The gates of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot are closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main body of this large-scale scenic spot is built in Fengdian Town, Zhongjiang County, with a planned land area of ​​more than 10,000 acres. In 2014, the developer of the scenic spot brought the project to this small county town, claiming that it would help local people get rich. Unexpectedly, there was insufficient funds in the first year of construction. Despite being in arrears with tens of millions of project funds, the scenic spot still barely opened for business at the end of 2019. At the opening, colorful balloons floated in the air, and hundreds of people watched the red-faced Guan Gong perform his machete on the red carpet. The scene was lively. However, the scenic area&#39;s business has been bleak since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, weeds grew on both sides of the road in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/f7a677405f.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/f7a677405f .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the roads in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area were overgrown with weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; standing in front of a chariot looked dilapidated due to long-term disrepair.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Yizun Station The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; in front of the chariot appear dilapidated due to disrepair over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; have solemn expressions, as if people have traveled from Deyang to Xi&#39;an in an instant.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses&quot; His expression was solemn, as if people were transported from Deyang to Xi&#39;an in an instant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; were arranged neatly in the scenic spot.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size statues The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are neatly arranged in the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to encountering the epidemic, there are traces of the failure of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot;. Scenic spots usually attract tourists with beautiful mountains and rivers or cultural history, but the gimmick of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; is the &quot;immersive experience of Chinese culture&quot; brought by nearly 2,000 artificial sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The themes of these sculptures are all-encompassing, interpreting mythical stories such as Chang&#39;e flying to the moon, the Eight Immortals crossing the sea, the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl, and the Seven Fairies, but the production is relatively rough. In order to let tourists experience the feeling of &quot;pointing the country&quot;, the scenic spot has also built thousands of replicas of terracotta warriors and horses. Accompanying the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are nearly 500 &quot;statues of emperors from past dynasties&quot;. However, the imperial appearance, which is far from the common perception, and the text introduction full of errors, made the visitors laugh and cry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot is already a pool of stagnant water.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258924&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was turned into a pool of stagnant water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a statue of an emperor surrounded by wild grass almost as tall as a person.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20 /b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, a statue was surrounded by weeds almost as tall as a person. statue of the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scenic tour line is 19 kilometers long, and sculptures are scattered in more than 20 scenic spots. Some tourists once complained on the review software, which is equivalent to forcing people to spend money to take a sightseeing bus. In early November 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter sat on a villager&#39;s motorcycle and visited less than 10 scenic spots, which took more than 3 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scenic spot was temporarily closed in June 2022, the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, &quot;seven fairies&quot; and &quot;emperors and generals&quot; were left in the barren mountains and ridges without anyone. Take care of it and live next to wind, rain, weeds, insects and ants. When Southern Weekend reporters visited the scenic spot, they only met two or three villagers in the scenic spot. The local villagers did not embark on the road to wealth. Instead, they were owed many years of land rent. Now the villagers have resumed farming in many places in the scenic area and planted the local cash crop rapeseed. They said that this year the rapeseed can be sold for 3 yuan per catty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, an aerial photo was taken of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, aerial photography was taken of the ancient famous scenic spot in the world. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The ticket office, offices, commercial street shops, etc. in the scenic area were all in a mess. Doors, windows, tables and cabinets were smashed, and the floor was littered with scattered documents and broken glass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to arrears in land rent and project payments, &quot;Gumingtianxia&quot; has more than 80 million yuan in outstanding financing. Under the promotion of the scenic area promoters, perhaps investors believe that the scenic area has a bright future. Southern Weekend reporters learned from multiple judgments and on-site construction personnel that the investors attracted by the scenic spot tend to be older. Some retired men were defrauded of 210,000 yuan to buy &quot;health products&quot; and then invested tens of thousands more yuan in scenic spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/cdcad5f48d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cdcad5f48d .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The abandoned scenic spots were spread through the Internet, attracting some explorers. It&#39;s just that all entrances to the scenic area are locked, and you have to overcome some difficulties to enter - climb over the wall at the main entrance, or get in through a patch of weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local villagers sometimes gather outside the main entrance of the scenic spot to chat. They are used to strange visitors with curiosity, and they will always kindly persuade: &quot;The above Nothing to see.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a local resident rode a motorcycle past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, one Local residents rode motorcycles past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都警方：陈某杰涉嫌开设赌场罪，已被依法执行逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261063]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 12:47:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;@ Chengdu Dujiangyan Public Security Bureau issued the &quot;Police Notice&quot; on November 22: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, our bureau found that Chen Moujie (male, 39 years old) was suspected of opening a casino. Currently, Chen Moujie has been arrested in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Related reports&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, Douyu issued an announcement stating that the company’s CEO, Mr. Chen Shaojie, was arrested by Chengdu police around November 16, 2023. . The company has not received any formal notification of the investigation into Mr. Chen or the reasons for Mr. Chen’s apparent arrest. Mr. Chen&#39;s continued detention and any subsequent related legal proceedings and enforcement actions against relevant parties could have a material adverse effect on the Company&#39;s reputation, business and results of operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川这个倒闭的景区总长19公里的游览路线埋藏了多少荒诞感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261045]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 12:18:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 12:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有见过需要那么多雕塑的”：四川达州古名天下景区烂尾调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261047]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 11:34:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; are famous all over the world in ancient times. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; The ancient world-famous &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot;. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County in Sichuan Province was once the county with the largest number of people who have not been lifted out of poverty, apart from the national and provincial poverty-stricken counties in Sichuan. There is a scenic spot in the mountains here, spanning three counties and three towns, with a planned area of ​​15.3 square kilometers, equivalent to the size of 15 Forbidden City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is known as &quot;the only imperial cultural area in the world&quot; and includes nearly 2,000 statues, including nearly 500 portraits of emperors and generals, thousands of imitation &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, and more than 3 meters high. Images such as &quot;Seven Fairies&quot; and &quot;Eight Immortals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was not completed. No one cared about it for many years. The statue gradually peeled off and faded, disappearing in the grass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2021, someone asked on the official website of &quot;Ask Politics in Sichuan&quot;: &quot;The ancient Fengdian Town in Zhongjiang, Sichuan is famous all over the world. What is the reason why it has not been completed for many years?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fengdian Town is famous all over the world. The town government responded in November that the capital chain of the scenic spot builder was broken, with about 28 million yuan in arrears in project payments and more than 80 million yuan in arrears in financing, involving more than 2,700 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more surprising is that the judgment document website states that the legal representative of the developer was sentenced at the end of 2019 for illegally occupying agricultural land for the construction of a scenic spot. While he was on probation, he was still actively soliciting investment. In June 2022, the scenic spot announced its temporary closure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How was such a behemoth built? Who is responsible for its failure? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses from Sichuan&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area is affiliated to Deyang City. According to promotional materials, the project was launched in 2014 with a total planned investment of approximately 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its location is relatively remote, more than an hour&#39;s drive from the center of Deyang and surrounding cities, such as Chengdu and Guanghan. Drive from the Fengdian section exit of Zhongjiang County on the Hurong Expressway and turn right. You will see 9 golden bull elephant sculptures, which is the main entrance of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The tour loop is 19 kilometers long. Welcome to take the sightseeing bus.&quot; A line of golden characters at the main entrance reminds tourists of the scale of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance is built in imitation of ancient city walls, with couplets in red letters on a gold background hanging on both sides: North, south, east, west, there is no other place in the world, but this place has existed in the world throughout the ages. After the scenic spot was temporarily closed, the gates were locked and items in the ticket room were smashed. Nearby villagers gathered under the &quot;golden elephant&quot; to chat, and occasionally gave directions to curious tourists from out of town. &quot;You can climb over the wall.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beside the Jade Dragon Gate at the entrance of the scenic spot, the Fengdian Town Government posted a notice in March 2023, warning tourists not to enter the scenic spot in any way, because the current infrastructure is incomplete and there are major safety risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone opened a trail from the left side of Jade Dragon Gate. If you walk forward for a few minutes against the weeds more than 1 meter high, you will see a statue of an emperor more than 2 meters high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The statue of the emperor in the grass. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;259128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A statue of an emperor in the grass. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three Sovereigns and Five Emperors are making CALL online. Qin Emperor and Han Wu invite you to point out the country together.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion, there are nearly 500 statues here, including Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty, Wu Zetian, Taizu of the Song Dynasty, etc. The emperors of modernization also include the leaders of the &quot;Five Hus and Sixteen Kingdoms&quot; and the &quot;Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hong Hai participated in the construction of about 100 emperor statues from the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty and stayed in the scenic spot for more than two months. He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters on the phone that the developer was inspired by &quot;Pictures of Emperors of the Past&quot; by Yan Liben, a painter from the Tang Dynasty, and wanted to present the emperors of the past dynasties in the form of sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statue is placed in a cement field called &quot;Chinese Historical Process Park&quot;. The scenic spot hopes to allow tourists to appreciate five thousand years of Chinese culture by displaying the emperor&#39;s style and introducing his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if tourists look carefully, they will laugh. For example, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty Yang You (605-619) only lived 15 years old, but the statue of Yang You in the scenic area has a thick long beard and wrinkles on his face, making him look like a mature uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The text introduction is not rigorous enough. For example, in the introduction to Song Taizu, &quot;Zhao Kuangyin practiced martial arts when he was young, and first joined Guo Wei, Taizu of the Northern Zhou Dynasty. Later, he followed Chai Rong, Emperor Shizong of the Zhou Dynasty, to fight in various places, and made many military exploits. There were commanders and envoys in front of the palace, and he mastered ice boxing.&quot; Not only is the sentence incomplete, it also contains typos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Hong Hai said that he and his team were not involved in the coloring and text introduction of the statue. The appearance of the emperor was also built based on the drawings provided by the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that the raw materials of these imperial statues are mainly steel bars and cement, which are cheaper than copper. He did not disclose the total price, citing commercial confidentiality. Due to lack of maintenance and management, hundreds of emperors are now living with dead grass. Under the sun and rain, the acrylic paint on many statues has faded, exposing gray cement, and steel bars are also exposed at the joints of the bases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far from the emperor&#39;s statue, nearly a thousand &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are quietly guarding in the mud. These &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; imitate armored warrior warriors, wearing battle uniforms, armor, and hair tied in high buns. However, compared with the various terracotta warriors and horses in the Qin Shihuang Mausoleum in Xi&#39;an, the &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses Sichuan&quot; are rough in workmanship, lack details in their expressions and costumes, and are weak in momentum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot once attracted tourists with the gimmick that &quot;you can see the Terracotta Warriors and Horses without leaving Sichuan&quot;. Now these replicas are surrounded by moss and wild grass on the edge of the mountain forest, and some have white thatch inserted into their hands. &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot;, who was wearing a dragon robe, had a red ribbon &quot;praying for peace&quot; wrapped around his bun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a sign under the feet of &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot; that reads: &quot;No destruction of property!&quot; However, due to no one taking care of them, these imitations have faded and have cracks in many places. Some &quot;Kneeling Shooting Figurines&quot; were cut off at the waist, and many &quot;Warrior Figurines&quot; lost their arms and even their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early November 2023, Southern Weekend reporters also saw giant sculptures placed in scenic spots such as Seven Fairies, Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea, Mother Earth, Chang&#39;e Flying to the Moon, Queens of the Four Seasons, and Zhuzi Square. They are three to four meters high, but the workmanship is rough when seen up close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity, there are more than 20 scenic spots in the scenic area, such as the Drunken Concubine, the Sifang Wealth Saint, the Yue Laotai, the Nine Fox Fairy Cave, and the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl. &quot;Their huge lineup and magnificent momentum are truly unparalleled throughout the ages. Unparalleled.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making emperor statues for Gu Ming Tian Xia, Hong Hai saw the terracotta warriors and horses and other statues being moved into the scenic spot. He has been engaged in the sculpture industry for nearly 20 years and lamented, &quot;I have never seen anything that requires so many sculptures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity of the scenic spot, the ancient name of the world is based on the five thousand years of Chinese civilization as the core theme, integrating the Chinese cultural story line into the natural ecology and cultural landscape, allowing the story to connect, empower and cast the soul of the landscape. Thus forming an internal logical connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Driving local people to get rich&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Developers came to this town in 2014. According to (2019) Sichuan 0623 Xingchu No. 409 Judgment, on March 7, 2014, Sichuan Gumingtianxia Investment Management Co., Ltd. signed an investment cooperation framework agreement with the Fengdian Town Government of Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County is a major agricultural county in the hilly areas of Sichuan. The food crops grown are mainly rice, rapeseed and wheat. Fengdian Town under its jurisdiction is also a typical remote agricultural town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia Investment Company will invest 370 million yuan to build a new wintersweet viewing base and agricultural tourism project in Fengdian Town. The Fengdian Town Government agrees to provide its company with the land for this project within the ownership and land scope of Huangping Village and Hejia Village Committees. The area shall be based on the lease area signed between the company and the village, but it shall not change the land without authorization. Nature of land use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the investment cooperation framework agreement obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, the two parties also agreed that Gumingtianxia Investment Company should register and establish a Zhongjiang branch within the jurisdiction of Zhongjiang County. After the project is completed and put into production, taxes will be paid in the territory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 21, 2014, Zhou Lizhu registered and established Sichuan Guming Tianxia Tourism Development Co., Ltd. in the name of her daughter Zhou Xiaxia (in 2016, the legal representative became Zhou Lizhu, hereinafter referred to as &quot; &quot;Anciently Famous&quot;), with a registered capital of 100 million yuan, and Zhou Lizhu holds 100% of the shares. The registered address of Gu Ming Tian Xia is No. 5, Huangping Village, Fengdian Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance of the scenic spot is built in Huangping Village. Southern Weekend reporters learned from many Huangping Village villagers that rents in scenic spots range from 400 yuan/mu/year to 1,000 yuan/mu/year. One villager said that the land on the mountain was basically unable to grow food and was originally abandoned with no income. The scenic spot also hired local people to do cleaning, maintenance and other work, providing some jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot also mentioned in its publicity that it will &quot;drive local people to become rich.&quot; The economy of Zhongjiang County is relatively backward. Information disclosed by the Sichuan Provincial Poverty Alleviation and Immigration Bureau shows that there were 92,500 poor people in Zhongjiang County in 2014. From 2011 to 2014, the province allocated 65.642 million yuan in special financial poverty alleviation funds for Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investment cooperation framework agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia plans to invest 370 million yuan, and the project construction period will be 4 years and will be completed at the end of December 2018. After completion, it can achieve annual sales revenue of 200 million yuan and tax revenue of 20 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Lizhu is from Dazhou, Sichuan Province. Local media in Dazhou reported his story twice. In 1980, Zhou Lizhu worked as a cashier in a mining company in Dazhou, earning more than 60 yuan a month. But he felt &quot;so tired&quot; that he resigned after five months and set up a leather factory. Zhou Lizhu was only 17 years old at the time and was called the &quot;Doll Factory Manager&quot; by her 10 workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mr. Zhou Lizhu, who has been in business for a long time, has a heroic spirit between his brows, and his beard makes his outline more subtle and elegant.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion article, Zhou Lizhu has since He has worked in communication equipment, steel manufacturing, real estate, tourism and other industries, and has also studied in the EMBA class of Xiamen University and Peking University Guanghua School of Management. However, according to the verdict, Zhou Lizhu only had a junior high school education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to &quot;well-known entrepreneur&quot;, another label attached to Zhou Lizhu is &quot;philanthropist&quot;. According to the &quot;Dazhou Evening News&quot; report, Zhou Lizhu once used part of Gumingtianxia&#39;s operating income to establish the &quot;Love Weekly Special Fund&quot;. In October 2015, he donated 200 cherry blossom saplings worth 100,000 yuan to his hometown of Dazhu County, Dazhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It took four years of construction before it was found to be illegal&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhongjiang County Government website, in August 2016, the first phase of the Gumingtianxia project was registered, and the scenic area is planned to cover an area of ​​about 3,000 acres. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an investor, Southern Weekend reporters obtained the registration notice for the scenic spot’s corporate investment project from Gumingtianxia’s investment recruiters. The project name is “Gumingtianxia Sightseeing and Tourism Project—Planting Base and Historical, Cultural and Leisure Plaza” Construction Project&quot;, with a total planned investment of 180 million yuan, and the source of funds will be self-raised funds. The planned land area is 2,400 acres, and the construction area of ​​the main buildings is 10,000 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction content includes a planting base, office building, visitor center, exhibition hall, cultural and leisure square and ancillary facilities. The scale of products and services is to plant 100,000 balengang crabapples and wintersweet plants each year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registration notice shall be stamped by the Zhongjiang County Development and Reform Bureau. According to the remarks, the project unit can handle environmental protection, urban planning, land use, construction permit and other procedures in accordance with the law based on the notice. Construction of projects with incomplete relevant procedures shall not begin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice is valid for one year. During the validity period, if there are important changes (including changes in the project investment entity, construction location, main construction content, product technical solutions, and the expected change in the total investment or construction scale of the project by more than 20%, etc.), the project unit should apply for re- Filing. In October 2016, Gumingtianxia applied for re-registration, and the original planned land use of 2,400 acres was changed to 3,590.5 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another document obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that in August 2016, the Zhongjiang County Tourism Bureau sent a letter to Gu Ming Tian Xia, &quot;In principle, we agree that your company will invest in the development of Gu Ming Tian Xia Tourism in Fengdian Town.&quot; Tourism &#39;Project&#39;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fourth year of signing the contract, the scenic spot was found to have illegally occupied agricultural land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned judgment stated that, “In addition to planting wintersweet, crabapple and other agricultural planting projects on the rented land, the company also carried out agricultural projects from 2014 to 2018 without obtaining any construction land approval documents and procedures. During the year, the use nature of the original leased land was changed and construction projects were started.&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, through the appraisal led by the former Deyang City Land and Resources Bureau and Zhongjiang County Forest Public Security Bureau, the scenic spot involved the occupation of damaged cultivated land. The area is 140.1595 acres, involving an occupied forest area of ​​18,360 square meters (approximately 27.54 acres). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two parts of the area actually account for a very small proportion in the scenic spot, accounting for approximately 4.67% of the registered planned land area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2019, the Zhongjiang County People’s Court sentenced Gu Mingtianxia to the crime of illegal occupation of agricultural land and was fined 50,000 yuan; Zhou Lizhu was sentenced to two years and six months in prison, suspended for three years, and fined Ten thousand yuan in gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past four years involving illegal construction, the scenic spot has still received support from the local government many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the public account of the scenic spot, in February 2016, the then Secretary of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee brought an inspection team to the scenic spot for guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Zhongjiang County Government, on August 9, 2016, the former deputy county magistrate presided over the Gumingtianxia project construction promotion meeting and listened to the project planning unit’s status report, the project investor’s construction plan report and related Opinions and suggestions from department heads. The meeting requested that relevant departments should work together to coordinate and solve problems existing in project construction to ensure the smooth progress of the construction project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing, one of the original managers of the scenic spot, told Southern Weekend reporters that the scenic spot did not clearly occupy basic farmland at the beginning of its construction. &quot;If he (the government) does not agree, does he dare to touch the land?&quot; Liao Xing said. Since 2014, she has followed Zhou Lizhu to work in Gumingtianxia, ​​mainly responsible for project management. After being owed wages, she resigned in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2017, the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Protection of Cultivated Land and Improving the Balance of Acquisition and Compensation&quot; to implement the strictest cultivated land protection system. According to the official website of the Sichuan Provincial Department of Land and Resources in September 2018, the Deyang Municipal Land and Resources Bureau paid close attention to the protection of cultivated land. In that year, the city carried out 685 dynamic inspections, discovered and stopped 10 land violations, and filed 4 cases for investigation and punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing and the above-mentioned investment personnel said that after Gu Mingtianxia and Zhou Lizhu were sentenced and paid fines, the local government had adjusted the basic farmland and forestland occupied by the scenic spot into general land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity materials of the scenic spot, on April 10, 2020, members of the Standing Committee of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, Director of the County Culture and Tourism Bureau, and Deputy Director of the County Natural Resources Bureau visited the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Spot to guide the work and provide opinions. Or suggest that Zhou Lizhu and others accompany him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Twenty million is owed to build the scenic spot&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2015, the construction team began to enter the site. However, the construction of the scenic spot was carried out illegally at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A judgment shows that in August 2015, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd. signed a contract with Gumingtianxia, ​​agreeing to undertake the construction of anti-corrosion cabin projects for office buildings, hotels, and commercial streets in scenic spots. However, because Gu Ming Tianxia did not obtain the approval procedures for the construction of the office building, the competent authorities prohibited the construction, and Chongqing Jingwu Industrial immediately stopped the construction of the office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, the two parties signed a contract, agreeing to outsource the road pavement projects in the scenic area to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial. After June 2019, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial completed the roadbed construction, but because Gumingtianxia did not provide construction drawings and did not connect electricity for construction, it was unable to continue to complete the road pavement construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong was once one of the management members of the scenic spot. He told Southern Weekend reporters that because the scenic spot is a tourism project for investment promotion by the local government, the policy may be more liberal and construction will start first. He wants to build it first and then build it later. formalities. At present, Wang Rong is still owed about 100,000 yuan in salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong admitted that the scenic spot violated the relevant regulations on temporary land use at the beginning of its construction. &quot;There is no planning or construction report.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Gumingtianxia is facing a shortage of funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned judgment, in October 2016, Guming Tianxia issued an IOU to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial and admitted that it owed 2.6158 million yuan in project payment and 100,000 yuan in deposit. After returning the deposit, Gu Mingtianxia has been in arrears with the project payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from many construction parties that they had agreed with Gumingtianxia to &quot;advance funds first and then settle the settlement.&quot; Li Chengwu, a native of Sichuan, is in his fifties and has been in this business for more than 30 years, mainly contracting earthwork construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He saw that Zhou Lizhu had two companies under his name and thought he was quite strong. By the end of 2016, Li Chengwu calculated the accounts and found that the advance amount had reached nearly 5 million yuan. At this time, Zhou Lizhu still couldn&#39;t get the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Chinese New Year approached, Jiang Tao, who was in charge of the infrastructure project, and Yang Tinghong, who was doing the green sandstone paving project, also went to Zhou Lizhu to settle the bill, but they couldn&#39;t get their money back either. Zhou Lizhu&#39;s arrears to them were 2.9 million and 270,000 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Li Chengwu and others began to report the situation to the government. On September 1, 2017, at the Zhongjiang County Labor and Social Security Bureau, Gu Mingtianxia promised that Li Chengwu would pay off the project payment before August 30, 2018. After Zhou Lizhu signed, she wrote the word &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Li Chengwu and others belong to the &quot;Ancient Debt Collection Group&quot; with 88 people, including construction teams for landscaping, door and window guardrails, hardened roads, and paving bluestone in scenic spots. In November 2023, a boss who made doors and windows for scenic spots compiled statistics in the group. At least 22 construction teams were owed a total of about 20 million yuan in project payments, wages and deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many construction team bosses told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why construction teams continued to enter the site in 2017 was because Gu Ming Tian Xia’s quotations were 5% to 10% higher than the market price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Judgment Documents Network, since the second half of 2017, construction parties have successively sued Zhou Lizhu and Gu Mingtianxia, ​​and won the lawsuit. Several plaintiffs applied for compulsory execution, but the court was unable to find any property or property clues in the name of the person subject to execution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the construction company, but also the villagers of Huangping Village, Fengdian Town, have been unable to get the rent from the scenic spot since about 2017. The investment promotion personnel of the above-mentioned scenic spots said that about 90% of the scenic spots are built in Fengdian Town, and so far the land rent arrears is about 9 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;This scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is the ancient world always short of money? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the verdict, Gu Ming Tianxia initially planned to invest 370 million yuan in Fengdian Town. However, according to the publicity of the scenic spot, the total planned investment is about 3.1 billion yuan, and the scenic spot will be constructed in four phases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He does many things, including running a leather factory, selling steel, selling communications, and also doing crowdfunding.” Qiu Song, a native of Dazhou and a fellow villager of Zhou Lizhu, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Zhou Lizhu Lizhu &quot;crowdfunded&quot; a sum of money to start a company in Dazhou, and then went to Fengdian to build a scenic spot. Qiu Song built the steel frame structure for the scenic spot and is now owed about 1 million yuan by Gumingtianxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Dazhou native took Zhou Lizhu to court in 2018. According to the judgment, since December 2013, Zhou Lizhu borrowed a total of 1.2 million yuan from the plaintiff&#39;s father and used three houses in Tongchuan District, Dazhou City to pay off the debt. However, the plaintiff discovered that the owner of the mortgaged property was not Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also heard from Zhou Lizhu that he had a real estate development project in Dazhou. In order to collect debts, Li Chengwu went to the prefecture several times to look for Zhou Lizhu&#39;s property. &quot;Later I found out that he was deceived. He had no projects in Dazhou to draw money from.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also went to Hainan because Zhou Lizhu claimed that there were 16 suites in a certain real estate in Sanya, which he could get. Several sets of money were paid to him. After he went there, he found that the person guarding the property was fellow Zhou Lizhu, and the property had nothing to do with Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong said that Zhou Lizhu once set up a financing company in Dazhou, financing money with 3 cents of interest and lending it to others at 5 cents or 8 cents. But later there were bad debts that could not be recovered, and he squandered some of them, resulting in arrears of hundreds of millions of yuan to investors. So Zhou Lizhu thought of setting up a scenic spot and claimed that all the financing funds had been invested in the construction of the scenic spot. &quot;Write a promise to those who owe money. The scenic spot will give you shares, and after the park opens, it will pay you dividends every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tear down the east wall to pay for the west wall, and the capital hole is getting bigger and bigger.&quot; Nanfang. Over the weekend, reporters learned from an official in Fengdian Town as an investor that Zhou Lizhu initially came to build the scenic spot with about 40 million yuan. After the money ran out, she went to Mianyang, Deyang, Suining, Chengdu, Nanchong and other places to raise funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that from 2017 to 2018, Zhou Lizhu registered companies related to Guming Tianxia in Deyang, Chengdu, Mianyang, and Suining. According to the Fengdian Town Government, Gu Ming Tianxia’s arrears in financing amounted to more than 80 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that he did not know the source of Zhou Lizhu’s funds. He mentioned that due to road construction, the scenic spot received a road subsidy of about 1 million yuan from the local government, but other than that, it did not enjoy other subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Tao, who is in charge of infrastructure projects, said that he saw two tourist buses parked in the scenic spot in 2017, and they were investors attracted by Gumingtianxia. &quot;Cheating the elderly out of their money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the judgment documents website, there are three judgments on private lending disputes related to Gu Ming Tianxia. The three judgments show that in March, May, and June 2019, Gu Mingtianxia borrowed 100,000, 10,000, and 100,000 from three people respectively, all promising an annual interest rate of 24%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the three plaintiffs are all older, and were 71, 60, and 63 years old respectively when they borrowed the money. Two of them are from Mianyang and one is from Deyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Blog China website, an investor who visited the scenic spot in October 2018 recorded the visit. At that time, the construction of the scenic spot was initially completed. The promoter said that the scenic spot was built solely by Zhou Lizhu. The original funds were sufficient. However, due to the continuous increase in raw material and labor prices in recent years, there was a gap in funds, so private funds were borrowed for the construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investor saw a retired man in his seventies investing 30,000 yuan at the scene. The old man had been defrauded of 210,000 yuan for buying &quot;health products.&quot; Seeing that the old man believed in Zhou Lizhu so much, the investor &quot;invested a little more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 13, 2019, Guming Tianxia also announced that it would be listed on the Tianfu (Sichuan) United Equity Trading Center with the code 610161. Tianfu Equity Exchange Center is a regional equity market operating institution that provides financing channels for small, medium and micro enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above three judgments, as of January 2020, Gumingtianxia failed to pay interest to the three plaintiffs as agreed, nor could it repay the principal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where did Zhou Lizhu spend her money? Liao Xing said that all the money was invested in the project. Not all of the project money was paid, but part of it was paid. For example, he said that excluding transportation and installation fees, the production cost of each emperor statue is about 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong said that before 2017, Gumingtianxia’s investment in the scenic spot did not exceed 5 million yuan. &quot;The government did not require capital verification at that time, and in the end he could not get out a penny.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu heard from Zhou Lizhu that the scenic spot was originally planned to open in May 2017. But it was not officially opened to the public until the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that the company’s capital chain was broken because the scenic spot was affected by the epidemic and stopped operating just after it opened, leaving no income. &quot;Roads were built, trees were planted, the projects were all placed there and they were not taken away.&quot; He felt that Zhou Lizhu was &quot;a person who wants to do things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Rong believes that Zhou Liyu is a guise to circle money outside the scenic area, and he is not serious about making scenic spots. &quot;Except for the statue, the tourists will not come for the second time.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Liao Xing also had doubts about the development of the scenic area. &quot;Indeed, the plan is too big.&quot; He had received other companies where the scenic area visited, and the other party told him that to complete the planning of the scenic spot, at least it would be 1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot;, the ancient names of the world originally planned to build a Zen Medical Kangyang Ecological Park, low -altitude sports base, Huaxia History and Culture Research Travel Base, Grand Theater, Ancient Shaolin Temple and other attractions. Liao Xing said that the large purpose of the scenic area was to retain tourists overnight, and tourists lived before they lived. However, until the scene of the scenic area was closed, the ancient names have not yet built a hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, the scenic spot is not much attractive to tourists. In the East Square, the reporter from the Southern Weekend saw several discarded tickets with a fare of 98 yuan. There are 20 evaluations of the scenic spot in the public comment. Most of them are talked about high charges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;The imitation&quot; Terracotta Warriors and Horses &quot;here are as many as thousands of lords. /23/11/22/67491062de.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/ms/medias/23/11/22 /67491062de.jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259130 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; There are thousands of imitation&quot; Terracotta Warriors &quot;. Southern Weekend reporter Weng Yan &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; During the suspension, he still ran around &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; During the three years of probation, Zhou Liyu was still investing. The Fengdian Town Government stated in November 2021 that it is actively urging the ancient world investors to raise funds and financing to resolve debt problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the promotion of the scenic area, in December 2020, Zhou Liyu signed a strategic cooperation agreement on behalf of the Scenic Area and the Chengdu Tourism Association Travel Agency Branch at the 2020 China (Sichuan) tourist scenic spot and the cultural and creative industry innovation development expo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I have to do everything possible to repay your funds as soon as possible.&quot; In early 2022, Zhou Lizheng wrote a letter to the investment member. The letter mentioned that, in response to the &quot;investment member contract expires&quot;, under the guidance of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, the County People&#39;s Government, and the relevant departments of the superior, the company is vigorously promoting the investment promotion work and adopting project implant cooperation + equity cooperation. Mode increases the hematopoietic function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June 2022, the scenic area announced the temporary closing of the park. In July, Li Chengwu went to the office to find Zhou Liyu and saw the other party talk to two three investors in the reception room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The office of the ancient world is located in the &quot;ancient famous courtyard&quot; in the courtyard style. When a reporter from the Southern Weekend visited the &quot;Ancient Famous Courtyard&quot; in early November 2023, the office was empty. The leaflets with yellowish and wrinkled scenic spots were blown into the corner by the wind and rain. There were sheep dung and insect corpses everywhere on the ground. It seemed that the yard had been deserted for a while. The reception room, financial room and other office areas borrowed a piece of wolf. The overthrow -pushed office cabinets, crushed glass everywhere, and scattered paper showed fierce conflict traces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The feet of &quot;Four Seasons Girls&quot; are another office place in the ancient world. Nowadays, the renderings of the scenic area and a calligraphy of the scenic area are hung in the room. It is likely that there are also conflicts here. The jewelry cabinet of sterling silver bracelets and the natural Gobi red agate was broken, and the empty jewelry box and price were signed to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Zhongjiang County Government Network, on the morning of July 23, 2022, the Standing Committee of the County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, and Chairman of the County Federation of Trade Unions went to Fengdian Town to hold a &quot;Ancient World&quot; petition stable work site coordination meeting. The Bureau, the County Cultural and Travel Bureau, the County Natural Resources Bureau, the county and other departments and other departments coordinated the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September of the same year, the news of Zhou Lizhen appeared last time in the public account of the scenic spot. In the Mid -Autumn Festival congratulations, he continued to convey to the outside world&#39;s determination to develop forward, saying that he would &quot;fight the tough battles of attracting investment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The public account of the scenic spot left an investment call, and the contact person told the southern weekend reporter that he was mainly responsible for updating the public account and marketing of the scenic spot. &quot;Big Investors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The investment scenic spot is large and the return cycle is very slow. If the natural endowment is average, it is difficult to find the investor. Other scenic spots also have bankruptcy. Things. &quot;The contact claims to have resigned at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter from the Southern Weekend learned from a number of debtors that at the end of 2022, Zhou Lizhen was admitted to the hospital. At that time, Zhou Lizhen was 56 years old. But Wang Rong believes that Zhou Lizhen is to hide the news of debt. On November 11, 2023, a reporter from the Southern Weekend dialed Zhou Lizhen&#39;s mobile phone number, and the other party denied that he was Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the above -mentioned scenic spot investment personnel and Fengdian town officials, the scenic spot has not been found. In early November 2023, the &amp; nbsp at the entrance of the scenic spot; &quot;Chang&#39;e Running Moon&quot; has been repeatedly cultivated like near and on both sides of the main entrance, and the villagers planted rapeseed rapeseed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (&quot;>; ( At the request of the interviewees, Honghai, Wang Rong, and Liao Xing in the Wenwen were a pseudonym.) &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从喝无糖茶到内卷茶叶，年轻人又爱杯泡茶了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261035]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 11:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/604305F84ECECBD8DA5F7176dc8f4C18.jpeg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 736 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/ CMS/Medias/Image/ 23/11/21/604305F84ECECBD8DA5F7176DC8F4C18.JPEG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 259011 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span>; (Visual China &amp; N BSP; / Picture ) &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, more and more young people have begun to drink tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that the tea here does not refer to milk tea or tea, but to make tea by yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In social media, young people began to show their tea or kung fu tea with cups, a cup of black tea or green tea, and became the standard of the case. Whether it is a postgraduate or a worker, or an overtime, drinking tea is gradually becoming a fashion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Sugar -free tea is once again favored &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;pan>; In fact, before cup of tea, Sanchali, oriental leaves, etc. Sugar -free tea has begun to be favored by young people. This kind of tea drink soaked in the original tea as the raw material is different from all kinds of milk tea. It focuses on sugar -free and tea flavor. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Whether it is the old -fashioned Sanchali or the Oriental leaves under the Nongfu Spring, when recommending its own products, they emphasize that they are based on natural tea as the raw material, fermentation technology used, and no added added Any sweetener and additives, etc., strive to become its characteristic with the purest original tea. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; For young people under the environment of work and family, paying attention Take intake, and the lifestyle of reducing sugar and abstaining sugar. The change of such a consumer mentality is the main mechanism to bring huge growth space for sugar -free tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related data shows that from 2017 to 2022, the average annual compound growth rate of the market size of sugar -free tea reached 28%. It is expected to maintain a growth of about 10.9%from 2022 to 2027. ——Bing obviously, this wave of &lt;Span>; young people are thinking of being difficult to drink, to starting to adapt to its taste, and start to buy repeatedly. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; However, for this kind of tea encapsulated by plastic bottle, of course, there are still not enough freshness, and the main drinking methods are cold drinks and other shortcomings. Especially cold drinks, for some girls who don&#39;t like frozen, are actually not friendly. Even if it is heated in a convenience store, it feels average when it is drinking, it will even affect the taste. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/F64539bdceb90d4EC2B592DC48CDD6B.jpeg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 764 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/Image/23/11/21/f64539bbd4EC2B592DC48CDD6B. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259009 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span>; (visual China &amp; nbsp;/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;strong>; SPAN>; Cup brewing tea fire &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Today, young people are with sugar tea and frozen sugar -free tea. In contact, more and more young people have begun to give birth to &quot;new demand&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Tea Research of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences &lt;/span>; The &quot;2022 New Tea High -quality Development Report&quot; released by institutions and other institutions shows that 46.90%of the &quot;post -90s&quot; Said that I met more traditional tea in the process of new tea consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Douyin data, in 2023, the proportion of interested users from 18 to 30 years old in the tea industry increased to 38.4 %. This shows that the age of tea is moving downward, young people have continued to improve tea awareness, and tea audiences are constantly showing a trend of younger. The latest report of CCTV Finance&#39;s &quot;Zhengxian Finance&quot; section has the latest market observation of &quot;young people love drinking tea and become a new driving force for tea consumption&quot;, which has also attracted attention and hot discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared to non -sugar tea, it is actually a lot of benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First of all, you can choose the fresh &lt;span>; tea. Regardless of whether it is bean -flavored Ming Longjing, a mellow and fragrant Wuyi rock tea, or the oily oolong or Pu&#39;er, different tea brings different taste. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Fresh tea can immediately force the fresh taste, which is actually more refreshing in taste. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; And, making tea is very friendly for the young ladies and sisters who like hot drinks. You don&#39;t have to be afraid that cold drinking tea will hurt your stomach. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; And buy several different tea leaves, change to drink according to the season or mood, and can also adapt to your taste needs at any time. In the production of tea, it takes a little time to cook water, throw tea, and wait for juice, etc., which can make people feel quiet and comfortable in simple hand work. It is also a buffer of learning or work pressure. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the choice of tea, compared with sugar -free tea, the choice of fresh raw materials tea is rich and colorful. Those who like black tea, there are Yunnan red in Yunnan, Jinjunmei, Yinjunmei in Fujian, Qimen black tea in Anhui. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Like green tea, West Lake Longjing, Dongting Biluochun, Huangshan Maofeng, Xinyang Maojian, and Liu&#39;an Melon in Anhui. Some fragrances are tangy, and some are mellow and moist, which can be described as their own characteristics. Others, there are all kinds of tea such as Shengpu, Mature Pu, Jasmine Tea, Oolong Tea, etc. to choose from. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Tea can be selected according to the region, production area, year &lt;/span>;, and the production area or craftsman. For young people who have just started, the basic knowledge of some tea is still very interesting. Make some choices in categories and regions, find a few of their favorite tea, and learn simple tea skills. It is actually very fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, there are some things to pay attention to when making tea, water quality, water temperature, what utensils are used for soaking, etc. Tea people still need to know. Such as purple sand pots are suitable for brewing black tea, Pu&#39;er tea, oolong tea, Wuyi rock tea, etc., which are not suitable for making green tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Green tea such as Longjing, which is more delicate, cannot be rushed immediately with too hot boiling water. It will destroy the chlorophyll in the tea, make it yellow, and lose the flavor and taste. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Tea is a forever track &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;sp>; &lt;span>; At the beginning of drinking, the cooking method of tea has not stopped updating. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; From cooking tea from the Tang Dynasty, to tea from the Song Dynasty, and then the tea made of tea in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, and the spread of matcha overseas such as overseas in Japan. In the age, the tea drinking method has undergone changes. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In modern times, with the changes in technology and technology, there are new Chinese tea drinks represented by various milk tea today. Various sugar -free tea, composite tea drinks containing tea ingredients, and all kinds of bags for making tea. Various tea varieties and tea drinking methods are still changing and iterative, and young people also repeatedly explore and try to consume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For young people who like to be popular and follow the trend, the traditional way of &quot;making tea&quot;, because of the driving between social platforms and video platforms and friends, it is very Easy to become a social symbol and communication method, making tea quickly become a lifestyle of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The preferences and tastes of young people will also be projected into tea -related &lt;span>; products, such as tea sets, etc., may become younger, simple, and fashionable. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the future, I believe that there will still be various ways to drink tea for young people. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Whether it is the Renaissance of Tea, or the new tea drinking new taste, more and more young people fall in love with tea -related products and consume it. It will further increase the overall market of the tea industry to make the tea ecosystem richer. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: Orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style:oraange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: //feedx.best &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为保住工作买公司产品？企业与员工间应建立合理边界丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261008]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Weilai layoffs are a recent hot topic. First of all, the industry was rumored. On November 3, 2023, Li Bin, the founder, chairman and CEO of Weilai Automobile, said in the internal letter of &quot;Organization Optimization and Two Years Priority&quot; that in order to further improve the efficiency of execution and ensure that the key businesses have sufficient resources, there are sufficient resources Investing, the company will reduce positions of about 10%, and the specific adjustment will be completed in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the 2022 ESG report released by Weilai on September 25, a total of 2,6763 employees were released. Based on this, it is estimated that there will be more than 2,600 or more layoffs. For Weilai layoffs, the mainstream narrative on the market is based on the situation of the electric vehicle industry or the company itself. This is of course a meaningful perspective. Here you can also cut into the perspective of employees. According to the &quot;China Business Daily&quot; report, from Weilai&#39;s internal employees, it is learned that the compensation plan is N+3, which should be good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, a user named &quot;Sugarbao&quot; posted in Xiaohongshu, saying that he has worked in Weilai for 5.5 years (also known as &quot;turning right a year ago&quot;, which seems to suggest that it was not officially before Work), nearly forty years old, there are old and young, especially cherish this job. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TA charges that the Weilai employees of &quot;almost 80%&quot; have been explicitly shown or implied that if you want to keep this job, you must buy Weilai Automobile. In order to avoid middle -aged unemployment, the Mercedes -Benz CLA, who had only bought it for two years by the end of last year, was replaced with Weilai ET5. This person wrote a post of &quot;ET5&#39;s January&quot; at the end of last year, saying that &quot;in terms of user first (car owner father), Weilai said that no one dares to say the first.&quot; This seems to confirm the authenticity of TA purchasing an ET5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Then TA wrote again: &quot;The leader talked to me and said that if he wanted to be promoted, you must mobilize the friends and relatives around you to buy a car together.&quot; Then TA recommended his cousin and cousin to let them buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately. Weilai ES7 and ES6; Earlier this year, in order to be promoted, I bought another ET5. There is a certificate of successful purchase-lending in the back, showing that the total price of ET5 it purchased is 345,200 yuan, of which nearly 300,000 are loans, and the monthly supply is 8150.56 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TA claims to be the first car ET5 car loan for 3,000 per month, then the monthly car loan is more than 10,000 yuan. Work and promotion? One family needs to buy two ET5? And the interval between the two purchases is very short. Therefore, some netizens have questioned, and some netizens believe that it is credible and believes that &quot;Weilai originally mobilized employees to buy cars (even linked to performance).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this regard, Weilai should clarify: Is this the staff of Weilai? Did you buy two ET5? This claims that &quot;in order to support the company and the stability of their positions, dozens of cars were pushed to relatives and friends around them, and they were almost sold part -time.&quot; Is it true or false? Does the enterprise ask employees to buy Weilai Automobile with performance or hidden rules for performance, retention and promotion linked? The media can also investigate these issues with face -to -law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The products from the enterprise are good, and the employees also need it and buy it voluntarily. There is no problem. However, if employees are required to buy a certain number or amount of the company&#39;s products, they can stay, and they can be promoted to increase their salary. The problem is very large: it is ugly to eat, break through the public and private border with employees, because the company is There is no right to interfere with employees&#39; personal consumption options; to the point, this is the &quot;pyramidization&quot; of the business-profit model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The true money routine of the MLM organization is to squeeze the money of each participant, and let the participants trust and cash with them, that is, the important interpersonal relationship of the participants to extract the participants The value of money, then sweep it out. A large number of systems destroy the personal social capital of participants, and the greatest social harm of MLM is this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Given that after the vast majority of people go out of school, they want to work in a business or organization, so there is a problem worth discussing: the employees are first, everyone is the first person, how to keep as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to keep your act as a person. The basic principles of people? Is it because you are not easy to find, or you are worried that you lose your job, or if you want to be promoted, you can take the initiative to do anything under the explicit or hint of the company and superior? &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As an employee, especially engaged in the free competition industry, the best strategy to keep your own work is always to enhance your strength. Replacement, creating irreplaceable value for enterprises or making the replacement cost of the enterprise very high. This strength may be your technical ability, you may be your ability to analyze and judge, or it may be your ability to dig and expand customers. In short, it is best to have the ability to be alone and who you have, and maintain and maintain your choice. In this way, you can have the unreasonable requirements of rejection of the enterprise or your boss, and keep the reasonable boundary with the enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In turn, if your ability, courage, or confidence is insufficient, the company or your boss must not use you, then you may eat some &quot;flies&quot; in order to keep your position, such as making you spend you giant Buy a company&#39;s products, let you borrow or loan to the company. If you do it, can you be able to pay it as expected? One company or boss may destroy the contract, uninstall it, and will cross the river to dismantle the bridge. As a result of holding your own salary to save the enterprise, you still have been cut. Isn&#39;t it a loss of money? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Those who know people, those who know themselves clearly. The beginning of a person&#39;s wisdom and courage is to dare to face his weakness. Facing the problem is always the first step to solve the problem; a person who has no courage cannot have a strong values ​​core, and often goes back and loses the evidence.就算为了生存，你也不需要在心灵上依附于任何人或任何外物，这是软弱与无能的体现；你需要激发出内在的勇气，培植基于实力的勇气，然后去开拓，去工作，去fighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列内阁投票同意与哈马斯达成临时停火协议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261041]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 09:23:28 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;pan>; According to the Israeli &quot;Land News&quot;, the Israeli cabinet vote in the early morning of the 22nd local time with Palestine Islamic Islamic Resistance movement (Hamas) reaches temporary ceasefire agreement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[三季度罚没金额145亿，近七成罚金来自第三方支付丨金融合规榜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261039]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; In the third quarter of 2023, the third-party payment industry became the area with the highest amount of administrative penalties in the financial industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Researcher researcher at the New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend of Southern weekend, based on the statistical analysis of the &quot;Shepherd -China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud Platform&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;) found that in the third quarter of 2023, 1105 institutions The total of 2881 individuals were fined 14.531 billion yuan, of which about 70 % of the third -party payment industry was fined. However, the number of punishment institutions is the head of the banking industry, of which the Rural Commercial Bank is the hardest hit area. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Guangdong sent institution &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; The amount of the penalty &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; 居 &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; each &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; province &lt;/strongRong >; &lt;strong>; City &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Shou &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot; is now publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Finance and Administration of Finance Administrative punishment information is included in real time, and artificial verification is performed simultaneously, with a completeness and accuracy of 100%. Researchers in the New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend Weekend found the data mining analysis of the &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; found that from July to September 2023, the above-mentioned institutions released a total of 3203 penalties, and 1105 institutions and 2881 individuals were fined; the fines were 14.531 billion yuan, and 53 people were banned for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ZIEVFHMKUT9WGCy2YMSKXBZ5DV3.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 658 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zun9IEVFHMKUT9WGCY2YMSKXBZ5DV3.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259083 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vrozcrgkz8portvg7g7h34qotmyotuiq.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;831&quot; height = &quot;1045&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vrozcrgkz8porjrm0b7G7HOTMYOTMYOTMYOTUIQ.PNG&quot; Data-KE y = &quot;259084&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Which regulatory agency has the largest amount of fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to statistics, the amount of fines issued by the General Office and the General Administration of HKMA is the largest, over 6.25 billion yuan. From the perspective of the dispatch agency, the amount of fines of the Guangdong sent institutions of the two institutions ranked first in 31 provinces and cities, reaching 3.717 billion yuan; It was 554 million yuan and 553 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/oiaaeko0fuznhyqadlxwideri8fwgddoeh6uq.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/oiaaeko0fuznhyqadlxwideri8fwgddoeh6uq.png.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259085 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Number of Shadow Penalty Institutions &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; The most &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Many &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Which region is the largest number of penalties? The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that from the perspective of the region, the number of penalties in Shandong sent institutions in the two institutions of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the General Administration of HKMA is top -ranked, and it is far exceeding the second Shanxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bldnlvoexmdojtlx20v5w4kwuv8HEQAD9O.PNG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bldnlvoExmdojtlx20v5W4kwuv8Heqad9o.pn g &quot;data-key =&quot; 259086 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; The top two of the financial institutions are consistent with the &quot;Total List of the Third quarter of the third quarter of 2023&quot;. Strong>;. &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wllzlx5v528kag46g6dnqwzpfxmim.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 669 &quot;Height =&quot; 1396 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wllzlx5v528Tyu0kag46A2T8M6DNQ wzpfxmim.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259087 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In terms of industries, the top three of the number of tickets for banking institutions are Shandong, Jiangxi Province, and Henan Province. However, Guizhou&#39;s banking institutions were fined to the first of the provinces and cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/AZOLPTUV5KAZU0CTOJQIFOF3G5ornkthati4x.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/AZOLPTUVCTOJQIFOF3G5ornkthati4x.png &quot; data-key = &quot;259088&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkagzahy5xato9effl19rlzzejf0s5wms.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;669&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkagzahy5XATO9EFFL19rlzzejfo0s5WMS.png&quot; Data- K ey = &quot;259089&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the insurance industry, &lt;SPAN>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; institutional ticket &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; institutional ticket amount &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Span>; all top the list. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgvsfgpsu2hrit8vnlapwidirbmezxxc.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;1396&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgvsfgpsu2hrtbr2LAPWIDIR bmezxzxc.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259090 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/cd7dkkap9dhnenikfmr2vn8kj6c159gbmqKyq &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;ST YLE = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/cd7dkkap9dhnenikfmr2vn8kj6c159gbmqkyq. png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259091 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; The highest penalty of third -party payments &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In all penalty financial institutions, which areas are the most institutions? &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Statistics found that among the 1105 institutions of the penalty, banks and insurance were 647 and 366, respectively, and were fined 585 million yuan and 78 million yuan, respectively. In terms of quantity composition, &lt;span>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; >; 1.4 billion, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 The list of financial convergence &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; announced 2 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 023 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; In the first half of the year &lt;/span>; The data is consistent, it is still the most bank and the insurance is second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the penalties in various fields in the third quarter were large compared with the first half of the year. In the third quarter, although the number of non -bank insurance financial institutions was fined only 15, the amount of penalties was as high as 9.82 billion yuan, far exceeding the banking and insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the 15 non -bank insurance financial institutions, 12 are third -party payment companies. Twelve third -party payment companies received a penalty of 9.77 billion yuan, accounting for 67.53%of all institutions&#39; fines. It is worth noting that in the top ten fines in the third quarter, the four fines are related to violating the management regulations of payment accounts. It can be seen that the field of payment is a concentrated area in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qomi7srkerjexw58fw1wutixdk6coac1ymjloc.png&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 1205 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qomi7srkerjexw58fw1wutixdk6coac1ymjloc.png &quot;d ata-key = &quot;259092&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; The sky -high price fines in the field of third -party payment are the two major platforms of &quot;Ant Department&quot; and &quot;Tencent&quot;. The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that of the top ten fines and ten personal tickets in the third quarter, the &quot;Ant Department&quot; and &quot;Tencent&quot; enterprises and the person in charge of the payment business or department manager were on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1sRguy5p3fwfsr9nav5ihdp9s4xmszyczxjl.png&quot; 0 &quot;STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 831 &quot;Height =&quot; 391 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1sRguy5p3fwfsr9NAV5IHDP9S4XMSZYCZXJL.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259094 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wg5hi1uoyhmbcx208jnrn3s8dehetav7e6mwjnes.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;831&quot; Height = &quot;294&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wg5hi1uoyhmbcx208jnrn3s8dehetav7e6mwjnes.png&quot; Data- K ey = &quot;259095&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; The largest number of agencies of the Rural Commercial Bank &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the banking industry with the largest number of fines, a total of 192 state -owned banks and joint -stock banks and branches have a fine of nearly 238 million yuan. , Accounting for 40.6%of the banking industry; Agricultural Commercial Bank, City Commercial Bank, Rural Credit Co., Ltd., village and township banks, private banks and rural cooperative banks, a total of 327 million yuan, accounting for 55.94%of the bank industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, the number of fined and fined by the Rural Commercial Bank exceeded the state -owned bank, becoming a prominent phenomenon in the third quarter. The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that there are up to 206 rural commercial banks received by the ticket, with a total of 140 million yuan, which is higher than 119 and 97.54 million yuan.而在&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;《半年罚没金额&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;14亿， The top three banks in the three banks &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; The number of agricultural and commercial banks&#39; penalty institutions and the amount of penalties are approaching state -owned banks. This shows that the degree of compliance of the Rural Commercial Bank has always been at a lower level, and there is a growth trend in violation of regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zdjeuxu1NPGKSMYLKJ9TeqrfjmdivixFgwyer.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 811 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zdjeuxu1NPGKSMYLX5RFJMDIXFGWYER.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259093 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bnuzxmpjx1sst1zlydhgmwiaupb4wq9iiegm.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;811&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bnuzx0x1zwlydhgmwiaupb4wq9iegm.png&quot; data-k &quot; ey = &quot;259096&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For a single bank&#39;s penalties, joint -stock banks and state -owned banks still have the top three. Ping An Bank, Minsheng Bank and Postal Savings Bank ranks in the top three. Among the three banks, except for the penalty of Minsheng Bank for loan violations, the penalties of the other two banks involved &quot;the obligation to not perform customer identity in accordance with regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the statistics of the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;, the number of bank penalties information involved in &quot;illegal use of identity information&quot; or &quot;trading with unknown customers&quot; in the third quarter, a total of 164 pieces of bank penalties, with a total penalty amount of 142 million Yuan, accounting for 24.3%of the bank&#39;s penalty for the number of bank institutions in the third quarter. The number of loans of violations reached 325, and the total penalty was 280 million yuan, accounting for 47.9%of the bank institutions&#39; penalties in the third quarter. This shows that these two major issues are more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/abp2zaqcf5tu1zvyqymgiailhpoli.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 831 &quot;Height =&quot; 1345 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/abp2zaqcf5tuzvyqymgiailhplfoli.pn g &quot;data-key =&quot; 259097 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Property Insurance &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Institution &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Quantity of being fined &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Still the most &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strongRongG>; >; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Compared with the banking industry, the insurance industry&#39;s fined amount and quantity are lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the third quarter of 2023, the punishment of the insurance industry and the &lt;span>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/Contents/254429?source=101&amp;MP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; &quot;There is no amount for half a year of penalty &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; 1.4 billion, the three banks&quot; take &quot;the top three 丨 finance rules list &lt;/u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; announced In the first half of 2023, the insurance industry was penalized. Regardless of whether it is a comprehensive insurance group or other insurance companies, the number of property insurance institutions has the largest number and the largest amount of fined. A total of 113 property insurance companies under the comprehensive insurance group of punishment groups, with a total fine of 32.463 million yuan; 65 other property insurance companies were punished with a fine of 18.04 million yuan. Life insurance business followed closely. The number of life insurance companies of comprehensive insurance groups was fined 88, with a fine of 10.968 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fotzzz5coifywxocubnavrhlk6pdfg.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 1167 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fotzzz5qqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqcoCSNAVRF6PDFG.PNG.PNG.PNG.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259098 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/lhus1FF1UBXCTDLZSFU6U4TWU5RRKZIIWYYF.PNG&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot; &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;811&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21FF1FF1UBXCTDLZSFU6U4TWU5RRKZIIWYYYYYYYYYYY ey = &quot;259099&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared to &lt;aver>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; &quot;There is no amount of fine fine &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; 1.4 billion, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 Financial Formation List &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; The insurance company&#39;s fined amount list in the first half of 2023, Chinese Insurance And China Life is still the top three of the list, while Ping An of China is the sixth place in the list. Although the business scale and the number of institutions in China, China Life, and Ping An of China are relatively large, the amount of Ping An of Ping An is much lower than the fined amount of the previous two. It can be seen that in the third quarter, the degree of Ping An compliance in China improved compared to the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/md7yrkeyfarkmezmvartib6mabzwo20ajws.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 791 &quot;Height =&quot; 1396 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/md7yrkeyfarkmezmvartib6MABZWO20AJWS.PNG &quot;&quot; data-key = &quot;259100&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; According to statistics from the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;, in the third quarter of 2023, there were 199 penalties involved in providing false information among 384 insurance companies, with a total fine of 52.137 million yuan, accounting for all insurance companies. 66.66%of the total fine. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Do not touch the red line &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Do not step on the bottom line &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In summary, it can be seen in the third quarter finance The violations of banks are mainly concentrated in the three areas of payment field, loan business and fictional documents. The latter two are both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/Contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; 100 million, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 The list of financial convergence &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; mentioned 2 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 023 &lt; /span>; &lt;span>; Focusing on the rules of the first half of the year &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; field &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, it is also the &quot;old problem&quot; of the banking and insurance industry. Each financial institution urgently needs to cure &quot;old faults&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; third party &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Payment &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; The industry&#39;s highlights &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; and online payment business &lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;span>; Fast &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Development &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; and &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Platform enterprise financial innovation. Online &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; third party &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Payment &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; brings great convenience for people &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; At the same time &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, also &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; illegal elements &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &quot;Drilling the money&quot; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;span>; channel &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Researchers at the New Financial Research Center of the Southern Weekend suggested that when financial institutions and platform enterprises are carried out, they must consider both innovation and inclusiveness, and always pay attention to regulatory policies. Touch the red line and don&#39;t step on the bottom line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (all drawing of this article: Feng Qingchao) &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[控诉菊花被偷采之后：公安出警、村干部下田维持秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261037]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum land, some tourists are picking flowers. &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/a2f4d2c512.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1197&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/a2f4d2c512.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;张亮家的菊花地，有游客在摘花。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月中旬，正值菊花怒放时节，河南省南阳市一菊花农场主张亮发布视频称，自家种植的四五百亩菊花每天遭多人采摘、偷窃。 In the video he posted, three people were picking chrysanthemums on the ground. Zhang Liang pretended to be a passerby to the person who picked the semi -plastic bag chrysanthemum and asked: &quot;This pick is also a lot of miles. ？”对方答：“少摘一点，溜着边摘。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月19日，26岁的张亮告诉南方周末记者，自己是南阳市方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;县清河镇廓封村张秀毓庄的村民，2017年开始在家附近承包土地种植菊花，用来加工成菊花茶。 It is currently the time of chrysanthemum opening and harvest. Zhang Liang said that there are dozens of stolen every day, &quot;hundreds of pounds of loss every day, like the drone shouted and scolded last year, and people couldn&#39;t get away, which caused a lot of losses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮拍摄的视频传到网上后，很快引起争议。两天后，张亮删除了视频。他解释：“有网友觉得我给河南人抹黑了，所以我就把视频删除了，与任何人无关。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“丢了河南人的脸”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮介绍，方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;县主要农作物是小麦和玉米。 2017年，“看到别人种菊花，当时的利润点也比较高，就跟着种了。”2021年7月，张亮成立了方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;县义诚家庭农场，主要种植金丝皇菊、婺源皇菊、小皇菊等品种的菊花，每年的收益要看行情，行情好了能多卖点，“但是近两年行情都不好”。菊花地一直是张亮父母在打理，农忙时在外打工的张亮也会回家帮忙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮回忆，从第一年开始种菊花时，就有人到地里看花，此后每年都有，尤其是在菊花刚开的时候，因为当地大面积种植菊花的较少，很多人图个新鲜。张亮称，来看菊花的多是周边人，几乎都是生面孔，周末时人比较多，但具体多少人他无法估算，“反正卖浆面条、&lt;span>;烙&lt;/span>;馍卷菜、甘蔗汁等小零食的都在这附近摆摊”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;看花的人多了，随意攀折、采摘菊花的情况也就出现了。在此前的视频中，张亮称每天都有几十起偷摘菊花事件发生，以前在主要路口还围过篱笆，但“挡君子不挡小人”。他告诉南方周末记者，2022年曾因偷摘菊花的事报过警，“警察也来了，教育了一下，罚了对方200块钱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮认为，自家的菊花地之所以有这么多人来，与当地一些自媒体博主的“宣传”分不开，“就是那些拍小视频的，他们一传十，十传百”。在网络世界，张亮的菊花地有了名字，它被叫做“方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;清河菊花园”，百亩的菊花园也被夸张为“千亩”“万亩”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位网名为“谢老二”的博主曾于11月12日推荐过张亮家的菊花地，“赏菊何必上开封，家门口就有成片的菊花，还不要钱。”“谢老二”账号的一位员工告诉南方周末记者，“谢老二”本职工作是一名导游，平常账号里会发各地的美景，“让别人知道上哪玩”。采摘菊花的视频引起争议后，“谢老二”的评论区也不太平，有网友指责他“把人家种花的害惨了”。 “谢老二”婉拒了南方周末记者的采访，“不想过多解释了，越闹越多，也不得劲”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上述员工告诉南方周末记者，她觉得“谢老二”并没有引导大家去摘花，“他只是觉得花怪好，景色怪好，叫别人去看。只是有极个别的人摘花，有素质的人还是多的”&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;在“谢老二”那条推荐视频最后，他向游客强调“一定不要乱采摘人家的菊花，珍惜人家的劳动成果，也不要到地里踩踏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为南阳人，上述员工认为随意采摘别人花的人哪儿都有，“不是说只有河南有这号人”。在得知该事上了新闻后，她更加生气，气那些不自觉的人“丢了河南人的脸”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;一位蹲在地头采菊花的游客。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/89e2fbf9bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/89e2fbf9bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一位蹲在地头采菊花的游客。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“摘花存在，但是极少数”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮觉得是自己给河南人丢的脸，给河南人抹了黑。 “身为一个河南人，我应该给河南人增光添彩的，结果我没想到（把视频传上网）会造成这么多不良影响。”张亮解释，来看花的人只有极个别摘了花，并没有造成严重的经济损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月18日，张亮发布一条澄清视频，“我拍摄视频的目的是劝导大家来这里打卡拍照的时候文明赏花，没想到会引起这么大的一个误会”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在接受南方周末记者采访时，张亮态度反复，他有时承认这一切都是他个人的错，自己承担后果&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;有时又怒意十足：“我说句实话，有时候我真不想昧良心说话，我没错。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于自家菊花被摘，张亮的态度同样模糊不定。他有时觉得“人家那么远跑来了，就图个新鲜，摘点没啥”&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;有时又觉得“有个别人确实不应该摘，这是我的私人财产”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月19日晚，方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;县委宣传部一名工作人员告诉南方周末记者，“当地政府也好，咱们宣传部门也好，是不可能去给人家施加压力的。但是当地政府第一时间看到视频后去了解情况了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;该工作人员称：“他们这块地，是一个集观光、采摘、加工销售为一体的基地。周末或是天气好的时候，会有游客到那打卡，只不过个别市民有一些不文明行为，比如想让孩子闻闻花香，或是出于好奇、留个念想，有个别的、极少数人会采摘人家的菊花，这个是确实存在，但肯定是极少数的，不可能说咱方&lt;span>;城&lt;/span>;县百十万人都是这么没素质，不可能的，哄抢或偷盗等根本就不存在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其称，事情发生后，当地公安已经介入，出动警力到菊花地里维持秩序。 “当地政府已经让村里的村干部、党员干部走进田间地头，告知去观光打卡的市民，这里可以打卡的，但是不能进人家地里去采摘或者踩踏。要确保农户承包的菊花不受损失，这个是最重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张亮则否认自家的菊花地可以观光，“我们只是自己种地，不需要任何人宣传”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“哄抢”还是“捡拾”？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;偷摘菊花事件并非个例，南方周末记者梳理发现，2023年秋收阶段，多地发生哄抢事件。 10月3日，南阳音乐节多名乐迷财物被盗；10月14日，周口市郸城县发生“百亩玉米田被百余人哄抢”；10月31日，周口市淮阳区发生“数百人哄抢药材”事件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月19日，“数百人哄抢药材”当事人邱军在接受南方周末记者采访时回忆，10月31日下午，机器正在进行第二遍药材收割，收到三分之二时，机器发生故障无法工作。当时田边已经围了一两百人，多是岁数大的老人。在机器无法收割后，一部分村民进地捡拾，后来人越来越多，邱军和他雇&lt;span>;用&lt;/span>;的二十多人劝阻无效后便作罢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱军是周口市淮阳区冯塘乡代楼村的中药材白术种植大户，今年是他种白术的第六年，按以往习惯，上百亩地里会剩余一两千斤机器无法收割到的白术供村民捡拾。事件发生后，邱军感到心里不舒服，但又无力劝阻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱军告诉南方周末记者，该事件被媒体报道后，当地民警共追回约八百斤白术，村干部也挨家挨户教育村民， “人家不让你进地，你进，说好听了你去捡，说不好听你这就是抢。”村里的喇叭也广播，教育大家“这种捡拾行为是不好的行为，违反了法律” . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;回过头再看这件事，邱军认为“也不能怪老百姓”，捡拾的村民都是年纪大的老人，好多都是文盲，也不懂法律，他们觉得这个东西掉在地里就能捡。对于该事件在网上引起的舆论，邱军认为对当地的名声影响很不好，采访中，他不断纠正记者的措辞，将“哄抢”改为“捡拾”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京德和衡（广州）律师事务所高级合伙人赵绍华担心，这种处理方式可能使大多数违法者认为他们的行为不会受到处罚，助长违法行为，使得更多的种植户遭受损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵绍华坦言，对于此类未经农户同意擅自攀折、采摘他人农作物的行为，定性为违法行为仍有难度。首先是证据的固定和收集难，因大面积的农作物种植场一般在郊区，场地面积大，难以直接固定和收集行为人攀折、采摘的直接行为，往往是事后发现农作物被毁损；主观认定上也难，因部分农村地区确有允许本地村民在种植场内捡拾收割后遗留的少量或残次农作物的习惯，对此在法律评价层面，&lt;span>;判断&lt;/span>;行为人是否具有非法占有的主观目的存在难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵绍华建议，在农村地区执法要突破“法不责众”的错误认识。 “像有的偷盗、哄抢农作物达到法定的程度，就应该严格依法采取执法行动，而不是继续依&#39;习惯&#39;来模糊处理解决。要让当地村民知道，偷盗、哄抢或破坏他人财物将依法被追究法律责任，法不责众不会成为任何人的保护伞”&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;同时，也需要加强农村社会的普法工作，包括产权意识、物权意识，特别是向村民普及《中华人民共和国民法典》物权编关于土地承包经营权的专项规定，向村民讲解刑法和治安管理处罚法的相关规定，告知村民其行为是违法的，是要受到处罚的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，张亮、邱军为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 08:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么晚清的改良派、维新派、革命派都推崇黄宗羲？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260980]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxRmek3qIAAc6Lhq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxRmek3qIAAc6Lhq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郑观应（前排中）为《原君·原臣》小册子写了introduction. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1895年秋第一次广州起义失败，孙中山流亡日本，在横滨发展兴中会组织，文经商店东主冯镜如出任横滨兴中会首任会长，其子冯自由年仅14岁，亦加入为会员。 Zheng Guanying&#39;s &quot;Yuan Jun · Yuanchen&quot; booklet, which was copied and prefaced, was printed by Hengbinwen through the store. Feng Free&#39;s &quot;Revolutionary History&quot; said: &quot;There are only two propaganda materials of the Shixing Middle School: one for&quot; Yangzhou Ten Diary &quot;, and at the end of the article, the Qing regent Wang Doru and the Ming Pavilion Department Shi Kefa resumed the second book; the second为黄梨洲《明夷待访录》选本之《原君·原臣》篇。均由余店代为印刷。”冯自由又言：“兴中会初期，文人墨士极感缺乏，所用宣传工具，仅有《扬州十日记》《嘉定屠城记》，及选录《明夷待访录》内《原君》《原臣》数种。”1896年，清廷驻旧金山总领事派人潜入孙中山住处偷窥，随后报告称“查阅该犯书册两本，一系摘录明黄梨洲《明夷待访录》中《原君》《原臣》二篇，卷端加一小引，自称杞忧公子”。 1897年6 月，孙中山在英国时，将《原君·原臣》小册子赠送给日本友人南方熊楠。 《原君·原臣》为黄宗羲《明夷待访录》中《原君》《原臣》两篇的节钞本，1895年冬在日本印刷，卷前有“杞忧公子”撰写的小引：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从来天生民而立之君长，所以为民役者也，君一人不能独治万几，于是建设臣工以分治之，凡佐君为民役者也。孟子曰:“民为贵，社稷次之，君为轻。”此千古之通义，先觉言之，后世讳之，皆未知君臣之义，悉为治民而生。苟大地孑孑无生民，又何从有君？又何从有臣工哉？惟不知立君之为民，故一人晏安，百姓失所；惟不知立臣之亦为民，故百僚阿顺，损下益上。呜乎! 此其弊，人人心非之而人人不能深知之、明言之，陵夷以至于今天，心之所深恫也。唯有明黄梨洲先生，家传忠孝，卓荦能文章，高瞻远识，超越千古。尝著《明夷待访录》一编，附托于箕子之蒙难艰贞。内有《原君》《原臣》二论，尤足握全书之要，垂万世之谟。爰摘录印行，希以启迪后生小子之蒙，而张中国自强之本。孔子云:“知我者其惟《春秋》乎，罪我者其惟《春秋》乎？”窃遵斯旨，以告夫当世之有心富强者。乙未立夏，杞忧公子小引。 &lt;/span>;（转引自孙卫华《〈原君原臣〉小引作者考》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“杞忧公子”是谁，学界有王韬、孙中山等不同说法，小野和子、李敖认为是郑观应。中南民族大学孙卫华作了深入考证，从郑观应《盛世危言》内容、早年著作《易言》使用“杞忧生”笔名等，认定作者即郑观应，论证有力。笔者检索《申报》发现，郑观应还用过“铁城杞忧生”笔名发表诗作，“铁城”为香山县城石岐别称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王韬曾为郑观应《易言》作跋：“杞忧生不知其何许人也，继乃知其居铁城，氏荥阳，足迹遍南北，而旅处沪渎最久。其地为冠盖之往来，商贾所辐辏，杞忧生居其间，不仕不隐，亦吏亦儒。日交其贤豪长者，而与之纵谈天下事，时或慷慨泣下，击碎唾壶。今湘乡郭筠仙侍郎、吴川陈荔秋司宪皆赏识之，屡欲加以拂拭，拟招佐星轺以备谘访，而杞忧生悉坚辞弗往，日惟寄情缃素，肆志林泉，慨慕黄、虞，读书自娱而已。”熟悉王韬、郑观应的学者不难发现，小引行文风格跟《盛世危言》十分相似，厚重而略显笨拙，与王韬跌宕有节奏的老练文风迥然不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1894年郑观应为孙中山上书李鸿章奔走出力，在孙中山“造反”之后，郑观应销毁了两人密切接触的资料。据易惠莉的研究，1895年秋孙中山发动广州起义之前，“郑观应5、6月间在广东”，光绪帝要求刷印《盛世危言》二千部的消息“促使郑观应中断在广东的活动返回上海&quot;.这个时间，跟小引落款时间“乙未立夏”（1895年5月6日）吻合。大胆一点猜测，郑观应将节抄本《原君·原臣》连同小引交给了孙中山。孙中山流亡日本后，将书稿交冯镜如出版。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《原君》《原臣》两名篇，出自黄宗羲《明夷待访录》。 《原君》批判君主“以我之大私为天下之大公”“为天下之大害”，《原臣》指出臣子的责任是“为天下，非为君也；为万民，非为一姓also&quot;.两名篇所阐述的民主思想，很适合孙中山用来批判清廷，也切合激进改良派、维新党人的需要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1895—1898年间，康有为与郑观应有过深度合作。 1895年12月1日，郑观应致函王韬：“康长素主政奉南皮命到沪，设立强学书局，约弟午后两点钟同谒先生……”郑观应曾陪康有为拜访王韬。郑观应也是强学书局主要负责人之一，他的作用被康梁有意淡化了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超后来在《中国近三百年学术史》中评论《明夷待访录》称：“光绪间，我们一班朋友曾私印许多送人，作为宣传民主主义的工具。”在《清代学术概论》一书中，梁启超又言：“梁启超、谭嗣同辈倡民权共和之说，则将其节抄，印数万本，秘密散布，于晚清思想之骤变，极有力焉。”俞国林为中华书局新版《清代学术概论》撰写长篇《校订说明》，即指出“节录《明夷待访录》之《原君》《原臣》两篇，印成小册宣传者，实为杞忧公子”“此节本实为革命派之宣传工具也”。梁氏只提《明夷待访录》而不点出《原君》《原臣》，或是有意为之。戊戌政变前，在与日本志士宫崎寅藏（宫崎滔天）的笔谈中，孙中山说他跟梁启超之间有一套“秘语”，相互通信不怕泄密：“弟近欲发信上海，请梁启超或其亲信一人到此一游。”这说明孙、梁之间早有联系，不是梁启超流亡日本之后才开始交往。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超、孙中山共用郑观应编篡的《原君·原臣》小册子作宣传工具，揭示有些历史人物的派系归属，并没有想象中那么固定。晚清投身革命的知识分子，或多或少都经历过“改良”阶段，孙中山上书李鸿章就是最好的证明；梁启超一度倾向革命排满；郑观应未必就没有“革命”的想法，只是不便公开。黄宗羲《原君》《原臣》名篇，可为各派进步势力所共用，也表明在甲午战争爆发后一段时间，进步势力还没有找到合适的舆论武器，黄宗羲的雄文是最“趁手”的宣传工具，革命派用来宣传革命排满，激进改良派、维新派以此宣传改革的迫切性。黄宗羲的历史地位在晚清突然提升，有利于宣传排满、虚君共和，但若说《明夷待访录》对郑观应、孙中山有思想启蒙作用，则又过于溢美，毕竟这两人能直接阅读英文著作，他们接触到的思想比黄宗羲更加有力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（原标题为“《原君·原臣》：郑观应、梁启超、孙中山的共享文本”，现标题为编者所拟）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女足的跌宕与辉煌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261025]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;11月20日下午，中国足协官宣：水庆霞不再担任中国女足主教练，原因是女足未能获得巴黎奥运会参赛资格。2021年11月，水庆霞临危受命，在两年时间里与中国女足共担风雨彩虹。她们带来胜利和希望，时隔16年后再夺亚洲杯冠军。她们也带来失利甚至绝望，亚运会无缘决赛、世界杯1：6惨败英格兰。走过风雨、见过风浪，期待铿锵玫瑰再绽放。</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>