<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“灵活就业”的毕业生，和一轮针对性核查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/sNHZwMvuADwj1CPQR3Pntdh9Q6ZY5K2couy1rWDi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1142&quot; height=&quot;1068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/sNHZwMvuADwj1CPQR3Pntdh9Q6ZY5K2couy1r WDi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Nongjian/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can a graduate prove that he is &quot;flexibly employed&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only proof Yang Yu, a 2023 graduate of a 211 university in Beijing, was asked to provide was a handwritten letter of guarantee, which read: I guarantee that my salary will be higher than 2,420 yuan per month after graduation. 2,420 yuan is the minimum wage in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn’t until one month after Yang Yu graduated that the school informed him that the certificate was not valid enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bank statements or transfer records of income, chat records about work situations, or photos of work scenes.&quot; At noon on August 5, 2023, the counselor sent a new request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an afterthought on the part of the school. One day ago, the Ministry of Education issued a notice and dispatched multiple working groups to various provinces to conduct special employment verification, check the employment data self-check list, verify the self-check report, spot-check relevant employment supporting materials, and opened a supervision and reporting hotline and email address to detect any false employment information. Relevant universities and personnel will be held accountable for violations signed and certified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flexible employment is the focus of this inspection. Yang Yu, who plans to become a food blogger, is one of them. In previous statistics on his graduation destination, he filled in an annual salary of 300,000-500,000 yuan. Yang Yu said that he really &quot;thought about making this amount. Being an Internet celebrity is very profitable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He not only wants to do &quot;eating broadcast&quot;, but also hopes to present the character of a blogger who loves life through long videos. However, the data for long videos is not ideal. Currently, the four videos he posted on a certain social media have the highest likes of 49. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2024 school recruitment season has begun. After delaying entering the job market for a long time, some people have decided to get out of their confusion and re-enter the social chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Flexible Employment”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today, the real life of food blogger Yang Yu is like this:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Monday to Friday , he and his girlfriend shared a two-bedroom apartment in a county near Zhengzhou. The apartment was located in a community with the best conditions in the county, but their lives depended on online loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early on Saturday morning, he first took the bus, then the subway, then the train, and returned to his hometown to teach children how to swim. This job was recommended by a friend at home who owns a swimming pool. Yang Yu likes this job because &quot;he works less and makes more money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first week after confirming the shared tenancy, Yang Yu and his girlfriend purchased a large bag of oil, salt, sauce, vinegar and pots and pans from the supermarket, moved them from the supermarket to an electric car, and then took them home and moved them upstairs together. . &quot;At that time, I thought that when I finally have my own home, I must cook a lot of my favorite dishes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now his concept has changed, &quot;I will measure my time according to the standard of making quick money. If you can earn 200 yuan an hour, then spending an hour cooking is a waste. It is better to spend 20 yuan to eat out.&quot; He started visiting the neighborhood pizza parlor and gained weight compared to when he was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the materials given to the counselor, Yang Yu wrote, &quot;As a perfectionist, I have been constantly testing and adjusting to make myself more confident.&quot; He has been three I haven’t updated the video in months, and my phone is full of test shots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He himself is aware of the contradiction, &quot;I plan to shoot a new video early the next morning, but the reality is that I usually turn off the alarm clock and go to sleep.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the self-certified flexible employment methods, the &quot;income guarantee letter&quot; provided by Yang Yu is only an extremely niche one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meng Lan, who graduated from a 211 college in Wuhan majoring in advertising, provided the transaction flow of selling idle items on Xianyu; Wu Xuan, a Chinese major from a normal college, provided screenshots of income and work chats Records to prove her identity as a freelance writer - she experienced failed postgraduate entrance examinations and failed autumn recruitment before graduation, and then decided to return to her hometown to become a freelancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter food bloggers or online store owners, they are not their first choice. Postgraduate entrance examinations and editing examinations are. But Yang Yu has no specific review plan. His daily study time ranges from one hour to five hours. “Sometimes he doesn’t do much in a day, but the study time is just gone.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Lan often doubted herself and even developed neurasthenia and depression. &quot;After graduation, I felt sluggish every day and felt that I was incapable of doing many things well.&quot; Now she decided to fight for the next national examination and signed up for the national examination to get off work offline, &quot;from 8 am to 10 pm every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since you have to take public and postgraduate entrance exams, why do you call yourself flexible employment? Meng Lan said that before graduation, the counselor and class teacher knew that she would continue to take the civil service exam. They interviewed Meng Lan on the grounds of college employment and suggested that she fill in &quot;self-employment&quot; and the job content was to open a store on Xianyu. &quot;Some of my classmates from World War II were also interviewed by teachers and asked to fill in the form of flexible employment.&quot; According to Meng Lan&#39;s estimate, there are nearly ten people in the class who are in a similar situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Yu’s situation is more complicated. In May 2023, on the school’s employment statistics questionnaire, Yang Yu truthfully filled out “unknown employment direction”. Soon, the counselor contacted him and said that &quot;the college leaders want to help.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two other students in the same major received assistance, and they both got interview opportunities from a unit in Beijing. When he arrived at the interview site, Yang Yu hesitated. &quot;I don&#39;t want to go, the salary is low, and I hate working the night shift. The fundamental reason is that I don&#39;t want to work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the three students decided to tell the college that they wanted to do self-media. However, unlike Yang Yu, who thought he could earn three to five million, the other two were conservative in terms of annual salary. They filled in &quot;50,000-100,000.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nPtS9sHGHvCtbsoSM2IBCSTIk58iOpmTPvNLQjfk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;933&quot; height= &quot;622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nPtS9sHGHvCtbsoSM2IBCSTIk58iOpmTPvNLQjfk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2018, a &quot;eating broadcaster&quot; appeared in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rising year by year&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; Than&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bloggers, online store owners, and freelance writers are all flexible employment. According to relevant documents from the General Office of the State Council, flexible employment refers to flexible and diverse employment methods such as self-employment, part-time employment, and new employment forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This formulation appeared in 2002. At that time, the Ministry of Education proposed in its employment work to &quot;actively open up various channels such as temporary employment and flexible employment.&quot; Two years later, it was included in graduate employment statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2021, the &quot;employment rate&quot; of college graduates will be changed to the &quot;graduation destination implementation rate&quot;, which includes the flexible employment rate, which coexists with the agreement and contract employment rate, entrepreneurship rate, and enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One concept that needs to be clarified is that the Ministry of Education’s employment rate statistics are different from those of the National Bureau of Statistics, and it is the latter that is more commonly discussed in the media. &quot;In the unemployment rate statistics of the Bureau of Statistics, only the unemployment rate of people who want to be employed is counted. In other words, people who have no intention of employment are not included in the denominator. However, the denominator of the employment rate statistics of colleges and universities is the total number of graduates, and there is no distinction between employment intention.&quot; Feng Xiliang, vice president of the China Labor Society and professor at the School of Labor Economics at Capital University of Economics and Business, pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In employment statistics, there are more and more graduates with &quot;flexible employment&quot;. According to Zhaopin recruitment data, the proportion of flexible employment among college graduates in 2022 has increased by 10.9% compared with 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Flexible employment is indeed a development trend.” Feng Xiliang said, “In the past, flexible employment was mostly skilled work. Due to the development of information technology, new employment forms have emerged in recent years, relying on There are more and more flexible jobs in information networks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another trend is the flexibility of standard employment. &quot;The boundaries of jobs are becoming increasingly blurred, such as labor dispatch personnel and contract employees. Mobile work blurs the boundaries of previous positions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang believes that the statistical standards of colleges and universities should also be adjusted with the development of the times. Three years ago, he suggested that relevant departments appropriately relax the statistical standards of flexible employment. Students who are suitable for the position and those who start their own businesses. For example, Yang Yu and Meng Lan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flexible employment is becoming a &quot;reservoir&quot; in graduate employment rate statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that taking universities in Hebei Province as an example, according to the employment quality reports released by each university, the flexible employment rate of undergraduates in Chengde Medical College, Baoding University, and Hebei Normal University for Nationalities in 2022 exceeded 50 %. Among them, the total number of graduates of Hebei Normal University for Nationalities in 2022 is 3,294, and the total number of flexible employment is 1,941, accounting for 58.93%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang is cautious about the flexible employment rate of nearly 60%. According to Feng Xiliang&#39;s 2021 survey, about 14% of graduates choose flexible employment, of which about 70% are active, and about 30% are &quot;passively&quot; employed flexibly because they cannot find a suitable job or during the transition period. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that survey, after completing 8,604 valid questionnaires in 30 universities, Feng Xiliang found that the flexible employment rates of different schools and majors vary. “Graduates of art and foreign language majors have flexible employment options. The proportion of employment is higher, and the flexible employment rate is higher in junior colleges than in undergraduate schools.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot; report, some colleges and universities are cheating on their employment rates. Counselors told students in the WeChat group, &quot;If you can&#39;t find a job, just write flexible employment when filling out the form&quot; and &quot;If you encounter a survey, just write &quot;flexible employment&quot; He said he was doing self-media.&quot; A counselor at a Beijing science and engineering 211 college also told a reporter from Beijing Youth Daily that some &quot;edge balls&quot; will be played in the employment rate, such as registering part-time jobs as flexible employment. This category does not require a tripartite agreement and can be counted. into the employment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the routine verification of the employment rate of graduates of the Ministry of Education in 2023, flexible employment has become the focus of the verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/IMonWDCtySveZYKhvmALzex4Z80tSKVUHLiLcnmY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/IMonWDCtySveZYKhvmALzex4Z80tSKVUHLiLcnmY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250777&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 20, 2023, an outdoor night market job fair was held in Guanyun County, Lianyungang City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Verification&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to check flexible employment? Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main methods for verifying employment data in each province are intra-provincial inspections, self-inspections within schools, mutual inspections between colleges, and supervision and reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take provincial inspections as an example. In early July 2023, the Hunan Provincial Department of Education issued a notice requiring schools with a flexible employment rate of more than 20% to submit a special inspection report. The report includes the reasons, inspection status, Correction results and other information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some universities in Hunan Province have made this ratio even stricter. Hunan Institute of Technology proposed that secondary colleges with a flexible employment rate of more than 15% &quot;need to strictly check the flexible employment categories and submit a written flexible employment verification report.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang analyzed that the Hunan Provincial Department of Education’s flexible employment rate red line may have been set with reference to the previous flexible employment situation of college students. According to statistics from the National College Student Information Consultation and Employment Guidance Center, flexible employment accounts for 16.9% of college graduates in the country in 2020, and 16.25% of college graduates in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“But 20% is not an absolutely correct red line, and relevant departments can control it more flexibly.” Feng Xiliang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the school level, there are also &quot;self-examinations&quot; and &quot;mutual examinations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 12, 2023, Jining Medical College issued an announcement stating that when secondary colleges conduct mutual inspections, flexible employment telephone interview verification must &quot;achieve 100% coverage.&quot; The announcement also stated that the Shandong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security will organize on-site cross-checks between colleges and universities five days before graduates leave school. The team will be led by the leader in charge of employment, carrying laptops and all employment certification materials, and will conduct cross-checks between schools. A list of inspection opinions and issues will be formed, and “if no problems are found during the inspection, but problems are discovered later in the inspection by the superior organization, the relevant inspection units shall bear joint and several liability.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surveillance calls are another method of verifying employment rates. Southern Weekend reporters contacted seven colleges and universities through the published supervision and reporting hotlines, and the responses they received were all &quot;no reports have been received from students so far.&quot; However, there is not much difference in the verification methods. A staff member of the Employment Office of Yunnan Special Education Vocational College told Southern Weekend reporters that if a student does not have a &quot;formal job&quot; but &quot;his department and major report that he has a job or flexible employment&quot;, then the Employment Office &quot;will step by step Downward, the responsible persons of departments, majors, classes, counselors and teachers are held accountable.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verification process of student reports is somewhat difficult. The Employment Office of Inner Mongolia Agricultural University told Southern Weekend reporters that students choosing to report with their real names will be more conducive to the school&#39;s investigation and verification one by one. A staff member of the Employment Office of Inner Mongolia Normal University said that the Education Department had reported that there were anonymous reports from students at the school, but because the school was unable to obtain student information, it could only conduct a large-scale investigation to see whether teachers had said or done these things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Back to the social chain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Neither really employed nor After preparing for the exam with all their strength, several flexible employment graduates interviewed revealed complex group characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They all have certain financial security provided by their families. The family hopes that Meng Lan will continue to take the civil service exam next year. &quot;We have not considered the option of working directly. Now I am preparing for the exam at home. I have no source of income, but I have sufficient support from my family.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xuan’s father likes his daughter to cook for him at home. “He thinks it would be good for me to be a full-time daughter.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang’s research found that family economic foundation, digital development and professional matching will all affect students’ tendency to choose flexible employment. &quot;If parents have a certain financial foundation and can give their children space to develop freely, graduates will get more understanding and support. In addition, digital background is the biggest technical factor, and mastering digital technology provides a foundation for college students to find flexible employment.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Compared with flexible employment, Yang Yu and Meng Lan&#39;s status is actually closer to &quot;slow employment&quot;, that is, they neither intend to find employment immediately nor continue their studies after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;2023 College Student Employability Survey Report&quot; released by Zhaopin Recruitment in May 2023, among the 2023 graduates, the proportion of &quot;slow employment&quot; increased from 15.9% in 2022 to 18.9%, which is close to the overall rate. one-fifth of . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are different from the older generation. We don’t have to worry about survival issues after graduation. I can go to graduate school, make money, start a business as a food blogger, or even take the civil service exam if I can’t. I have many options, so I won’t be anxious,” Yang Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trouble is that he still doesn’t know what he really wants to do. &quot;Although there are many choices in front of me, I need to work hard for any future, and I have nothing now.&quot; Walking on the road, he is often swept away by a sense of emptiness, and has not yet adapted to the fact that he is no longer part of the social chain. &quot;College students here&quot;. &quot;I used to think it was not good to go to school for too long. After I graduated, I found that I didn&#39;t want to grow up and wanted to go to school more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Yu’s latest food shop exploration material was shot on August 4. He made up his mind, “I will definitely post a new video within three days.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My parents said before that if you don&#39;t pass the public examination, you can do whatever you want. But I still haven&#39;t done what I originally wanted to do. Sometimes, I don&#39;t know Is it the constraints of the family or the constraints of myself?&quot; Meng Lan had been working as a contract photographer when she was in college. She once hoped that this love would turn into a long-term career, but now she is fully preparing for the public examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Changjun, deputy dean of the School of Education at Peking University, once wrote that in recent years, phenomena such as &quot;postgraduate entrance examination fever&quot;, &quot;graduate entrance examination fever&quot; and &quot;slow employment&quot; among college graduates can reflect that graduates have not yet prepared for future employment. Be fully prepared in terms of capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang believes that the mentality of this generation of college students is closely related to the impact of the three-year epidemic. &quot;Universities are spending their time during the epidemic. Classes and internships may be online. They are more inclined to use virtual networks to understand society and solve problems, and have little contact with the real society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True realization Wu Xuan, who wanted flexible employment, decided to go to work after two months of experience as a freelance writer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The income from freelance writing is neither stable nor considerable. Wu Xuan also noticed changes in her mental state. During the two months of free life, her willingness to work became less and less. &quot;Lack of contact with others&quot; People’s deep links are gradually closed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discovering that the flexible employment life was not in line with expectations, Wu Xuan finally chose to become a junior high school Chinese teacher in his hometown. Although the shift system restricted her freedom, she &quot;finally felt that she had entered the social chain and was no longer so anxious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Yang Yu, Meng Lan, and Wu Xuan are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 20:25:14 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[癌症老人乘机被拒，哪些情况不能飞？川航称艾滋患者需报备]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 12, a passenger with cancer was denied boarding when checking in at Chengdu Tianfu International Airport. . The passenger who was denied boarding was suspected to have been suffering from cancer for four months, according to live video captured by a bystander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The live video showed that at about 9:45 a.m. that day, at the boarding gate of flight EU2205, an elderly man was sitting in a wheelchair, and the man and the elderly woman, who were suspected to be family members, were sitting on the ground. The man shouted to the staff: &quot;The commitment book has been signed and the hospital certificate has been written. I also brought a nurse with me. You won&#39;t let me leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the man was suspected of working with another employee of the airline company. The staff called, &quot;I have cancer, four months ago. You said before that you have no heart disease, no respiratory disease, no trauma, and everything is fine.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, a reporter from Nandu called Chengdu Airlines Co., Ltd., and the customer service responded It is said that if the passenger has early-stage or mid-stage cancer, the flight can be carried, but if the passenger has late-stage cancer, the flight will not be carried due to restrictions on the aircraft&#39;s air transport environment, medical facilities and other conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to inquiries from Nandu reporters, in the EU05 version of the &quot;General Conditions for Domestic Transportation of Passengers and Baggage of Chengdu Airlines Co., Ltd.&quot;, &quot;late-stage cancer patients&quot; are indeed included. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6P1HD8tOa06hRhDtqm6q5sUkJha11836nXXwSPkt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1017&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6P1HD8tOa06hRhDtqm6q5sUkJha11836nXXwSPkt.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporter also I called the customer service of Chengdu Tianfu International Airport, but the other party said that they did not know about the matter and &quot;it is up to the airline to explain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Chengdu Airlines Co., Ltd. also stated that if the elderly person taking the flight is over 65 years old, , it is recommended to issue a health certificate at a hospital at or above the county level within 72 hours before boarding. Otherwise, if the ground handling staff thinks that the elderly person is &quot;apathetic&quot; when boarding, he may be refused boarding. After being refused boarding, &quot;responsibility&quot; Passengers need to bear the responsibility themselves.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when Nandu reporters further asked about the criteria for judging &quot;apathetic&quot;, customer service was unable to give a specific description. However, no relevant provisions were found in the &quot;General Conditions for Domestic Transportation of Passengers and Baggage of Chengdu Airlines Co., Ltd.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to inquiries from Nandu reporters, various airlines have different standards for not accepting flights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the relevant provisions of the &quot;Public Air Transport Passenger Service Management Regulations&quot; issued by the Ministry of Transport in 2021: The general conditions of transportation should at least include: &quot;Relevant regulations for passengers taking flights, including infants, pregnant women, and unaccompanied by adults&quot; Carriage standards for special passengers such as children and seriously ill patients.&quot; In other words, airlines can set operating standards in this regard, but there are no specific regulations on what the specific standards are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, China Southern Airlines clearly stipulates that chickenpox patients cannot fly until the damaged area has recovered; cerebrovascular patients. For patients with cerebral embolism, cerebral hemorrhage, and brain tumors, the roar, vibration, and lack of oxygen during takeoff and landing can aggravate their condition and are prohibited from flying. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sichuan Airlines Co., Ltd. stipulates that passengers who require special care due to physical reasons or who must meet certain conditions can only be transported in compliance with Sichuan Airlines’ transportation regulations, with Sichuan Airlines’ prior consent, and when necessary. Transportation will be accepted only after arrangements have been made. This includes seriously ill passengers, stretcher passengers, those who need premature infant incubators, and passengers with AIDS without any external injuries. They must present a medical certificate issued by a hospital recognized by Sichuan Airlines and signed by the passenger&#39;s doctor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/PIV3CwEUrih0SedAmv4EdhrI95es9bJz4AbW0ADX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/PIV3CwEUrih0SedAmv4EdhrI95es9bJz4AbW0ADX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250780&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiamen Airlines The conditions for refusing to carry passengers are listed in more detail, including various medical parameters, postoperative time, etc. When a reporter from Nandu called Xiamen Airlines customer service to ask under what circumstances they would not be allowed to board the plane, the other party said, &quot;Everyone can board the plane except those who drink alcohol. There are no clear regulations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[台风拔树树砸车，谁来赔，怎么赔？物业保险、车损险与巨灾险了解一下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256671]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When disasters such as typhoons occur, they often cause heavy personal and property losses to local residents. According to the Beijing News, on September 2, this year&#39;s No. 9 Typhoon &quot;Sura&quot; landed in Guangdong at the level of a strong typhoon. Affected by the typhoon weather, many trees on the roadside on Beihuan Avenue, Futian District, Shenzhen were blown down by strong winds. , a car was hit by a tree, killing one person and injuring two others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by &quot;City Zero Distance&quot; in July this year, affected by Typhoon Taili, a banyan tree in the community where Mr. Lu lived in Zhongshan City was blown down and hit his car. The damage was very serious. In this regard, the property management said, &quot;We hope that the owner will drive the vehicle to a maintenance point or 4S shop for repair as soon as possible. We have a &#39;public liability insurance&#39; ourselves. After the owner completes the repair, he will report the quotation and catalog to us simultaneously, and we will report it to the insurance Company.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the above two incidents were related to natural disasters, vehicles were smashed and even caused casualties. The parties involved and their families will definitely seek corresponding relief afterwards. Take the community as an example. There have been many disputes before about whether the property management company is responsible for being hit by a tree when a car is parked in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is such a case in Beijing Haidian Court. The party involved, Mr. Zhang, said that it rained heavily that night and the tree fell down, causing damage to his vehicle parked in the community, and the roots of the tree had bulged out of the ground before it fell. Therefore, he filed a lawsuit with the court and requested the property company to compensate for various losses. . The property company argued that, first, the community involved in the case is a non-operating asset, it does not charge property fees and parking fees, and only provides minimum basic guarantees. The property company is not the owner or manager of the trees; second, the gardening department stipulates that private property rights are not allowed. Dealing with trees, so even if the tree roots bulged out of the ground before, it could not deal with it; thirdly, the heavy rain that night was force majeure. In addition, Mr. Zhang’s car has been repaired by insurance and cannot be compensated again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, the court held that the property management company was the property service company of the disputed community. Although it did not collect the property service fees or parking fees paid by the owners, it was still responsible for the equipment, facilities and equipment in the community. The manager of this matter is the manager of the broken tree in this case. Although the property company claimed that it was not at fault for the broken trees, the evidence submitted was not enough to prove that it had fulfilled its reasonable management and maintenance obligations for the trees involved, and both parties acknowledged that the roots of the trees involved had bulged out of the ground before the incident. But the property company did not deal with it. In addition, although there was heavy rain on the night of the incident, it was still a natural force. The property company’s defense that it was force majeure could not be established. Therefore, the property management company should bear corresponding responsibilities. However, because the vehicle maintenance fees claimed by Mr. Zhang have been compensated by insurance, the court cannot support Mr. Zhang’s request for the property company to pay him this part of the expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the property management responsibility for the trees in the community, Article 1257 of the Civil Code stipulates that if the owner or manager of the forest causes damage to others due to breaking, toppling, or falling fruit, etc., and the owner or manager of the forest cannot prove that he is not at fault, Should bear infringement liability. This shows that as long as they are within the community, trees are within the jurisdiction of the property. If the property owner refuses compensation on the grounds that it is subject to force majeure factors such as typhoons or heavy rains rather than daily management, the reason is untenable. Due to advance forecasts such as typhoons, property management companies should inspect and reinforce trees planted in ground-level open-air parking lots in advance to avoid damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the best way for property companies to avoid similar situations is to learn from the community properties reported in &quot;Nanjing Zero Distance&quot; and purchase property insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Property insurance means that the property pays insurance premiums to the insurance company, and both parties sign an insurance contract. After the occurrence of causes, accidents, and disasters within the scope of the contract, the insurance company will bear the compensation within the scope of the contract. Property insurance covers a wide range of areas. Among them, public liability insurance refers to the financial compensation liability for the victim that the insured party shall bear in accordance with the law due to damage to other people&#39;s personal or property due to his or her fault in public places. By purchasing this type of insurance, the insurance company will pay compensation if there are problems such as damage to vehicles or even people caused by trees in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who will pay the premium? The &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Property Service Charges&quot; stipulates that property service costs or property service expenditures include shared parts of the property, shared facilities and equipment, and public liability insurance costs. That is, the property fees charged by the property to the owners include public liability insurance costs. Therefore, in the event of a &quot;car being hit by a tree in a community&quot; incident, the property owner should pay compensation first and then seek compensation from the insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the judgment of the Beijing Haidian Court provides another solution. If car owners purchase car damage insurance (vehicle loss insurance), they can make claims on their own to the insurance company. According to the car damage insurance of an insurance company, compensation will be provided for vehicle losses caused by fire, explosion, collapse of external objects, falling objects in the air, lightning strikes, windstorms, tornadoes, heavy rains, floods, etc. However, car damage insurance is a voluntary insurance policy for car owners, and currently this model is still niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Shenzhen case, because the accident occurred in a public area, according to the Civil Code, the owner and manager of the tree should also be held liable, unless they can fully prove that the cause of the accident was force majeure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, catastrophe insurance can also cover the cost sharing of compensation for accidents involving trees hitting cars and people in this municipal area. As one of the first catastrophe insurance pilot cities in my country, Ningbo City has launched a catastrophe insurance pilot project in 2014. The Ningbo Civil Affairs Bureau, on behalf of the Ningbo Municipal Government, signed a catastrophe insurance contract with the Ningbo Branch of PICC Property and Casualty Insurance Company as the policy holder. , the protection content not only covers household property losses caused by typhoons, heavy rains, etc., but also includes personal injury and death liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that through the coverage of property insurance and the promotion of various types of insurance such as car damage insurance and catastrophe insurance, when disasters such as typhoons occur, resulting in losses of people and property such as trees hitting cars, etc., whether it occurs in the community Both indoors and in urban public areas, we can achieve the maximum goal of &quot;no longer having to admit that we are unlucky in the event of a disaster.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[农业农村部：“村播”是乡村振兴的新型人才]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5CKBUu5vtw3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5 CKBUu5vtw3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 8, 2023, fruit farmers in Zhuxi Town, Cengong County, Guizhou Province broadcast live Selling golden autumn pears. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rural areas, like cities, have huge consumption potential. On September 12, 2023, Zhang Guoqing, deputy director of the Information Center of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that farmers’ income has grown faster than urban residents for 11 consecutive years, and the township and village consumer markets account for 38% of my country’s total consumer market, but to To build a connection between resources and markets and promote the further development of rural economy, &quot;village broadcasters&quot; who use short videos and live broadcast tools are also needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Zhang Guoqing said in his speech at the Kuaishou Light Chasing Conference that as a new type of talent for rural revitalization, &quot;village broadcasters&quot; have brought the &quot;source of living water&quot; of talents to rural revitalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emphasis on &quot;village broadcasting&quot; is to a large extent inseparable from the development trend of Internet e-commerce. At a special press conference on August 15, 2023, Li Gang, Director of the Circulation Development Department of the Ministry of Commerce, introduced that in 2022, the national rural online retail sales will reach 2.17 trillion yuan, and the online retail sales of agricultural products will reach 531.38 billion yuan, which is similar to that in 2014. Compared with the same period last year, it increased by 11 times and 4 times year-on-year. By the end of 2022, the number of rural online merchants (stores) nationwide has reached 17.303 million, and the number of rural Internet users nationwide has exceeded 300 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Suning County, Hebei Province alone, a small county located at the western end of the central city of Cangzhou, more than 6,500 online fishing rod and fishing gear shops have already solved the employment problem for nearly a quarter of the local population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chaohui, director of the Digital Economy Development Service Center in Suning County, Hebei Province, said that among the local 340,000 permanent residents, 30,000 are directly engaged in e-commerce, and 85,000 are indirectly engaged in packaging, video production and other related work. The products are online The sales rate is over 90%. According to a previous report by China News Network, a 3-hour live broadcast in early July 2023 attracted 150,000 viewers from a &quot;village broadcaster&quot; in Suning County, and the transaction volume in a single session exceeded 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the 26-year-old &quot;village broadcaster&quot; Gerong Zhuom, as a representative of new farmers, once again recalled the first attempt that took place in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a mountain more than 5,000 meters high, she posted her first video under the account &quot;Hide Dolma&quot;. It was a snowy May. In the camera, she was walking among exposed rocks, bending down to look for wild cordyceps. Behind her was a gray valley, and a snow-white stream was vaguely visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, this 14-second daily record received more than 500,000 views the next day. In private messages, hundreds of strangers from far away offered to buy Cordyceps. &quot;I sold it for more than 2,000 yuan at that time, and I was very happy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past six years, more and more new farmers like Gerong Zhuom have appeared on camera as &quot;village broadcasters&quot;. They sell agricultural products through short videos and live broadcasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Guoqing introduced that as early as 2022, the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs and the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League jointly launched the Kuaishou platform with the goal of increasing farmers’ income and strengthening the county economy in 160 national key counties for rural revitalization. Focus on supporting the cultivation of &quot;rural youth anchors&quot; in counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emphasis on rural talents has been written into the No. 1 Central Document of 2023. In the &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; work in 2023 and in the future period, it is necessary to &quot;strengthen the construction of rural talent teams&quot;, implement the rural revitalization talent support plan and the high-quality farmer cultivation plan, and carry out the cultivation of rural entrepreneurial leaders has been included in the plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“By the end of 2022, the number of people across the country who have returned to their hometowns to start businesses has reached 12.2 million, driving more than 34 million rural employment, and the coverage rate of innovation and entrepreneurship among rural returnees has reached 83.6%.” And. In Zhang Guoqing’s view, the power of digital technology and digital economy has not yet been fully exerted. By 2025, the number of people returning to their hometowns across the country is expected to reach more than 15 million. “I believe that in this digital age, every ordinary person, Every village, every cheer shines brightly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[这几种新型网络传销骗局，你要小心了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development and popularity of the Internet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Online MLMs continue to change their criminal methods&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various MLM scams emerge in endlessly&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leading victims into heavy debts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even families are ruined...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to prevent New type of online MLM? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come and learn the routines and precautions&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 14/1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc31 1. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc311.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb. png&quot; data-key=&quot;250772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; data- key=&quot;250767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; data-key= &quot;250773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250770 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250769&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中华儿慈会志愿者疑卷走近千万救助款，大病家庭再陷配捐骗局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1kePsVXTtsk1Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1kePsVXTtsk1Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250787&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会（简称中华儿慈会）被曝光其“河北项目负责人”卷走千万救助款，患者家属疑遭诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月13日，意识到被骗的家长们再次来到中华儿慈会门口。部分家属告诉南方周末记者，他们参与了中华儿慈会“河北项目负责人”柯某孝的配捐活动。按照前期宣传，以“48500配1500”为例，家长自筹48500元“捐”至指定账户，20天至一个月不等的时间后，能收到本金加上1500元配捐共5万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一项目曾有许多病友参与，家属未曾怀疑，直至2023年8月底许诺的资金迟迟没有回款，他们发现被骗。患者家属王军告诉南方周末记者，目前家长初步统计后，发现共有88个家庭受骗，涉及900万余元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日晚，中华儿慈会发布声明否认柯某孝为该会工作人员，也从未委托过柯某孝个人为9958儿童紧急救助项目（以下简称9958）筹集资金。而网传的1000万元资金，该声明表示该会账号从未收到过这些资金，“当事人将资金打给柯某孝个人账户，并曾从柯某孝个人账户获得返款”。中华儿慈会工作人员对媒体表示，柯某孝身份为志愿者，警方已对其冒名诈骗的行为立案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1242&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月13日，中华儿慈会发布声明。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（中华儿慈会官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;习以为常的“配捐”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月13日下午，南方周末记者来到位于北京的中华儿慈会门口时，部分家属代表进入儿慈会办公室沟通，更多患儿家属则在院外等待。他们大都是带着孩子异地求医，从湖北、湖南、四川等地到河北燕达陆道培医院及山东省肿瘤医院治疗，在医院附近租房居住。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李燕的孩子两岁时确诊为神经母细胞瘤，这是一种非常罕见的儿童癌症，为此她们一家从四川到山东省肿瘤医院求医。治疗两年来，家里已花费数百万元，“免疫治疗一个月得几十万，全自费”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孩子确诊以后，李燕加入了病友群，在病友群里，她发现经常有人在群里发大病救助的筹款配捐信息，一直有病友参加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据部分家长展示的页面，这些配捐通知描述简单，如“101500，配2500，一个月回款”“这个月名额只有一个，想做的报名”。李燕说，每次配捐的金额都不一样，参与的名额也不一样。以49000元配捐1000元为例，家长自筹49000元投入该项目中的同时，还要提供5万元的医疗发票，才能获得5万元的回款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位家长称，配捐回款有时打回家长个人账户，有时直接拨付至医院的指定账户，家长凭借报销单据逐笔核销，“不能取出来，只能用于医院治疗”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对家长而言，家里有大病患儿的负担很重。“普通人的感冒只是一件小事，对他们（白血病人）来说，可能要几万块钱治疗”，另一位在现场的家长陈晨说，12岁的女儿患髓系白血病，仅是一盒靶向药便要3万多。“能配捐1000、2000元，付房租，改善一下伙食，我们还是很愿意的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;患儿家属在照顾孩子的过程中，共享治疗经验，互相安慰理解，形成了不一样的信任感。李燕称更早确诊的病友为“前辈”，她知道有些病友已经做配捐好几年了，都是正常回款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有的病友则看重9958项目的“招牌”，它由中华儿慈会举办，几乎患儿家庭都知道。而在拉家长做配捐时，组织者都会问是否已入档。“入档”是指录入儿慈会9958项目的档案，家长们通过扫二维码填写“中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助中心申请表（廊坊）”，提供孩子姓名、年龄、病情等信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你知道之前有很多人做过，大家对这个事情持默认态度”，李燕说正是这种常态化的操作方式、病友之间彼此的信任，让她对项目的真实性没有产生怀疑。加上大病患儿需要小心翼翼护理，父母的身心都投入小孩身上，很难有心力核实项目的真伪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月25日，李燕和山东肿瘤医院的几位病友向张某账户转了48500元，由张某逐层转账，汇给柯某孝，约定在9月15日回款5万元。但是9月初，他们得知上一批病友的钱没有及时回款，柯某孝也失联，这才意识到款项无法追回。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家属在河北燕达陆道培医院治疗的王军告诉南方周末记者，8月30日柯某孝没有及时给病友回款后，十多位家属找到柯某孝要说法。在柯某孝多次推脱后，家长联合向河北燕郊警方报案，警方立案后对柯某孝采取刑事拘留措施。出事后，患儿家庭彼此问了一下，大部分家长参与了“48500配1500”“101500配2500”“126000配4000”的项目，“最少投了4万8，最多的投了30万多”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height=&quot;1079&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;患者家属参与该“配捐”项目的信息记录。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“最佳领导力”的志愿者&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;事实上，类似的公益配捐骗局曾多次出现。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;详见南方周末报道&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/pOTRdqBYVw-c9-xTie39dQ&quot;>;&lt;u>;《百万款项下落不明，白血病家庭疑遇“公益配捐”骗局》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;）此次事件引起广泛关注，或因涉及金额较大且牵涉中华儿慈会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会于2010年成立，为民政部主管的全国性公募基金会，主要从医疗、成长、教育、文体等方面，对困境儿童、事实无人抚养儿童、留守儿童、流浪儿童等开展帮扶活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9958儿童紧急救助项目则成立于2012年,为中华儿慈会的自主品牌项目，该项目服务于0-18岁的困境儿童群体，整合资讯信息服务、筹资渠道服务、救助执行服务三大功能。据中华儿慈会官网介绍，目前9958主要设立了50多个合作项目，搭建紧急救助通道网络和全国救助分中心25家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据中华儿慈会的声明，柯某孝仅在该会9958儿童紧急救助项目河北廊坊地区合作机构中当过短暂的志愿者，而家长的转账是打给柯某孝个人账户。南方周末记者在现场了解到，受访家长的筹款配捐确实没有转入9958项目的对公账户，而是转入多个不同的个人账户。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管如此，家长们都认为柯某孝行为与儿慈会有关。多位家长告诉南方周末记者，首次参与配捐项目必须扫码填写“中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助中心申请表（廊坊）”，60岁的潘昌荣称孙子因白血病在陆道培医院治疗，他们的信息已录入儿慈会的系统，“说明那个码是真的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，家属们说配捐回款的流水单显示拨款人为中华儿慈会，并据此认为这些配捐项目是由中华儿慈会操作执行的正规项目。但未有家长向南方周末记者出示相关的回款单据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军说，9月7日以前，家长们还能在中华儿慈会的官网上看到柯某孝的个人介绍，说明他是9958项目廊坊团队的主任，但是9月8日与中华儿慈会正式沟通时，家长们发现官网已删除相关信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，中华儿慈会负责人还向前来沟通的家属出具了一份解约文件。该解约文件称，“儿慈会9958救助项目廊坊救助站的签约机构为天津市北辰区天眷公益服务中心，因救助量未达到标准，不符合9958儿童紧急救助项目的发展需求，经过评估于2023年3月31日和廊坊救助站解约，解约后9958救助项目廊坊救助站进行的任何名义募捐、宣传等活动都与中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助项目无关”。南方周末记者从照片中看到，该文件上面盖有儿慈会公章，落款时间为2023年3月31日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军称，案件被警方立案受理后，警方曾就这一情况询问中华儿慈会项目负责人，对方承认该解约书是这两天补办的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军指出，目前在9958儿童紧急救助的公众号上，仍有一篇2月发布的全国网络平台培训活动的文章，配图显示柯某孝获颁“中华儿慈会2022年度最佳领导力奖”。签约仪式中，作为廊坊团队代表签约合影的正是柯某孝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日下午，中华儿慈会的工作人员称暂不能接受南方周末记者采访，上述信息未能得到证实。在随后发布的声明中，中华儿慈会也未对以上信息做出说明，仅提到柯某孝目前已被河北三河市公安局燕郊治安分局拘押，正在接受调查，他们也向公安机关进行了举报，并积极配合公安机关进行调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与中华儿慈会进行沟通的家属代表告诉南方周末记者，中华儿慈会对家长表示，目前该案已刑事立案，需等到警察调查结束后，能追回多少款项再赔付多少。“但好多家庭等不了那么长时间，孩子都在医院。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同一天，腾讯公益、新浪微公益分别发文回应，称9958涉嫌诈骗的行为未发生在该平台，但基于平台运营规则、行业自律公约及用户为本的原则，对9958所有项目暂停筹款，等待政府部门的调查结果，并根据结果做进一步处理。南方周末记者查阅后发现，腾讯公益平台共上线2939个9958项目，目前均已标注“筹款结束”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中患者家属均为化名，南方周末记者汪徐秋林亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI火爆之下，英属小岛安圭拉为啥躺赚了一笔横财？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256613]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;人工智能（AI）在全球的火爆，带来了一些有趣的意外。在OpenAI还亏损的时候，加勒比海的一个英属岛屿，却实实在在地赚到了钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个地方就是安圭拉。面积只有96平方千米，人口只有1.6万人，它赚到Al红利是因为安圭拉岛地区顶级域名后缀是.ai。AI爆火大量初创公司注册以.ai为后缀的产品网址，一个.ai的域名，售价大概是每年70美元。于是安圭拉就得到了从天而降的馅饼，今年的政府收入预计暴涨3000万美元，相当于10%的年度GDP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;全世界域名的最高管理机构，叫做ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers)，中文简称互联网名称与数字地址分配机构，是一个成立于1998年10月的非营利性国际组织。原是美国商务部下面的一个非营利机构，2016年美国政府宣布，ICANN 不再隶属于商务部，成为一个自我管理的独立机构。当然，美国肯定对它有着很大影响力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;ICANN负责管理全世界域名系统的运作。它的一项主要工作，就是制定顶级域名（top leveldomain），规定哪些字符串可以当作顶级域名。所谓顶级域名（TLD），就是最高层级的域名，就是网址最后那部分。比如，.com，.cn。如今的域名种类可以分为三大种类。一是.com、.net、.org、.info、.biz等，可以说是全球级的域名。二是国别或地区域名，比如.cn中国域名、.us美国域名、.uk英国域名、.de德国域名等，长度只有两个字母。三是新顶级域名，比如.top域名、.vip域名、.xyz域名、.app域名、.site域名等，后缀长度3字符起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;ICANN不可能自己去管理一千多个域名后缀，而且既做裁判又做球员也不合适收这个钱，所以ICANN为每一个顶级域名寻找一个靠谱的注册局（托管商），负责管理此域名的服务器、注册、使用、费用等事项。一个注册局也可以同时管理多个域名后缀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前管理.com域名后缀的是威瑞信(Verisign)，威瑞信还同时管理着.cc域名、.net域名、.tv域名。一般来说，国别或地区域名出于安全考虑，ICANN会给予该国或该地的政府组织机构管理，管理.cn域名后缀的是中国互联网络信息中心(CNNIC)，CNNIC还同时管理着中国域名。域名注册局只拥有管理权，并不能参与市场买卖。所以域名注册局下面还有很多域名注册商，在中国就有阿里云、誉名网、腾讯云、百度云等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国别或地区域名注册通常需要支付一定的费用，具体费用取决于域名的类型、顶级域名和注册商。注册费用通常是年费制，需要定期续费以保持域名的所有权。域名的价格由域名注册局决定。比如cn域名的价格，就由中国互联网络信息中心（CNNIC）决定。这个就是域名的成本价。域名注册局制定域名后缀的批量注册价格（批发价）后，域名注册商服务平台会根据这个标准，收取相应的注册费用以及一定比例的服务费。域名注册商要代替政府完成域名的实名认证，域名的解析服务等，赚的是辛苦钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，安圭拉挣的这个钱，一大部分应该是该国或该地托管商提高了价格，另一方面，是近水楼台先得月，该地民众注册了一些域名，然后卖给了先要的公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但是，对托管商而言，域名价格的制定也不是越高越好。首先，域名的供应量其实是无限的，一个顶级域名后缀前面，可以是无数个域名。所以托管商定得太高，销量就少了，可能总收入反而减少。其次，域名还是有一定替代性的，比如，用.com、.cn、.net都是可以的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一个好的域名对企业知名度和人气汇聚有重要作用，更重要的是，域名是网络时代的身份标识，具有“唯一性”，这就具有了资产性。一般来说，域名的注册采取的是先到先得原则，谁注册得早就是谁的，后来者需要的话，就得掏钱买。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对企业特别是大企业来说，域名是一个显示实力的信号。道理很简单，如果一个企业，都没有最合适自己的域名，那域名一定是被抢注了而企业没实力买回来。所以，互联网企业对于域名依赖性较高，京东、小米、苹果，都有花大钱买更契合自己域名的事。曾有报道显示苹果公司为了收购域http://icloud.net支付了大约150万美元；而更早之前为了http://icloud.com更是花费了接近520万美元的巨资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当然，这种抢注域名也不是无底线的先到先得。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据《中国互联网络信息中心域名争议解决办法》第八条，对于一些域名注册可以投诉。比如，被投诉的域名与投诉人享有民事权益的名称或者标志相同，或者具有足以导致混淆的近似性；被投诉的域名持有人对域名或者其主要部分不享有合法权益；被投诉的域名持有人对域名的注册或者使用具有恶意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;第九条还规定了恶意注册或者使用域名的情况。比如，注册或受让域名的目的是向作为民事权益所有人的投诉人或其竞争对手出售、出租或者以其他方式转让该域名，以获取不正当利益；多次将他人享有合法权益的名称或者标志注册为自己的域名，以阻止他人以域名的形式在互联网上使用其享有合法权益的名称或者标志；注册或者受让域名是为了损害投诉人的声誉，破坏投诉人正常的业务活动，或者混淆与投诉人之间的区别，误导公众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但是，需要指出的是，“抱有出售、出租目的注册域名”不再是判断恶意的标准。打个比方，抢先注册苹果域名是合法的，卖给苹果也是合法的，但不能卖给苹果的竞争对手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《过往人生》：所有分手，皆是前世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3xhFWCTzZEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3xhFWCTzZEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250685&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影《过往人生》（&lt;em>;Past Lives&lt;/em>;）的英文片名一语双关，既是过去的生活，又是复数的前世。这部2023年柏林电影节主竞赛单元的入围影片，近来受到了众多观众的好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当诺拉在分别24年后，与12岁时情窦初开的男孩海盛重逢，她早已改用了英文名。诺拉的左手边，坐着她的丈夫，美国犹太人，作家亚瑟，跟他讲英语；诺拉的右手边，坐着神迹般从孩子变成了成熟男人的海盛，跟他讲韩语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诺拉与海盛讨论，他们之所以能坐在这里，是因为在前世充满了羁绊。那些前世里，他们或者是一个公主与家仆地下恋，或者是两个不相爱的人，因家族联姻结合，各自背叛，或者只是碰巧的火车邻座，或者是一只鸟与承载着它的清晨的树枝。分别之时，他们说，此时此刻，或许也是前世。因为前世既是佛教中因缘的说辞，也是想象的、遗憾的、错失的种种可能性的平行时空。既然此世他们的关系仍充满缺憾，那就把它看成恍兮惚兮的前世吧，把它看成已发生的、被写就的，而不是正在创造的，把它看成梦幻泡影，而不是历历在目。他们的来世将会怎样？没有人知道答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;三段前世或平行时空&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在日本作家三岛由纪夫的遗作、系列长篇小说《丰饶之海》四部曲里，前世、今生、来世的轮回，以既离奇又合理的方式徐徐展开，那是与西方迥然有别的时间观，一切悲剧，总能被绵绵无绝期的或然的世界抚慰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片中，12岁，在首尔，诺拉还叫文娜英，父亲是导演，母亲是艺术家，是韩国的文化精英和中产阶级，决定举家移民加拿大。海盛是娜英的小学同班，因为娜英总是考第一，有次海盛考了第一，娜英就变成爱哭鬼。同学问她为什么要移民，她说因为韩国人拿不到诺贝尔文学奖。娜英在海盛的胳膊上，用彩笔画上一只鸟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;24岁，诺拉偶然在父亲的脸书主页上发现一个寻找她的帖子，海盛一直在网上寻找娜英，但她早已改名Nora Moon。两人发信息联系，拨通视频电话，重新相互crush，怦然心动。有段时间，他们的关系像异国网恋，诺拉为了适应海盛的时区，改变作息早起跟他通话，海盛在南山坐缆车时，也要给诺拉打视频，从空中给她看首尔的风景。但空中的信号不稳定，断线之后，诺拉的表情仿佛在担心海盛出现意外，网络的阿拉丁神灯收回了对她的许诺，海盛被囚禁在屏幕的黑暗中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海盛对诺拉说，你的韩语真烂，她说，我只对妈妈和你两个人讲韩语。网恋总有奔现的一天，诺拉希望海盛来纽约，这里有她戏剧和写作的梦想，但她现在想拿的不是诺贝尔文学奖，而是普利策。海盛要去中国交换，他一直想学中文，因为以后用处多。两人的距离只是茫茫太平洋吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36岁，海盛借口来纽约旅行，其实是专程看望诺拉。诺拉已经与亚瑟结婚七年。与海盛相比，亚瑟长相平平，习惯穿破旧的牛仔裤和棕色夹克，他是个作家，当然不会像游客一样，坐游艇去看自由女神像这样的明信片景观，但得知诺拉陪海盛去过这个旅行项目，又有些隐隐的失落。他跟诺拉在创意写作的驻地认识，为了诺拉的绿卡结婚。亚瑟问诺拉，我们的故事是不是太平淡了点？你在梦里只说韩语，那是一个我无法了解的世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诺拉最终送海盛来到等车的街边，两人隔着一米，沉默了两分钟，好像这一米才是太平洋。两分钟里，他们没有接吻，没有依依不舍的缱绻，没有告白，他们从未成为真正的恋人，直到车来了，才有了一个犹豫再三的礼节性拥抱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两分钟的沉默为什么是感人的，可能没人比美国作家塞林格说得更好：“有人认为爱是性，是婚姻，是清晨六点的吻，是一堆孩子，也许真是这样的，莱斯特小姐。但你知道我怎么想吗？我觉得爱是想触碰又收回手。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;没有乐土，没有人间天堂&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《过往人生》的导演席琳·宋（Celine Song）对塞林格一定并不陌生。她是一个作家，加拿大籍韩裔，二十多岁来到纽约做戏剧，根据相似的经历写出了这个故事。几年前，在纽约东村的酒吧，一边坐着美国丈夫，一边坐着童年玩伴，她不停为两人进行翻译。宋感到周围的眼睛打量着这个奇怪的三人组合，于是有了影片开头画外音的议论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋喜欢浪漫剧，她觉得，驱动罗曼蒂克戏剧的，往往是表现得像小孩一样的成年人，她希望角色在每个人袒露对彼此的感受时，展示出爱情是什么样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诺拉的饰演者、韩裔美国女演员格雷塔·李读到这个电影剧本时，忍不住抽泣，不得不边哭边艰难地继续读下去。虽然格雷塔·李是个在美国出生的移民二代，但她显然能体会到亚裔在北美的双重困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诺拉对亚瑟说，在纽约，她认识很多韩裔美国人，但海盛跟他们不像，他是个地地道道的韩国人。然而跟海盛聊天时，她也变得更像韩国人了，诺拉问海盛为什么还不结婚，似乎完全丧失了纽约艺术家对多元文化和婚恋状态的包容，以保守的思维方式来询问同胞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，海盛和诺拉人生选择的分歧，就是对韩国社会的一个隐喻：海盛学实用的工程学，来到与韩国有深厚历史渊源、经济前景广阔的中国交换；诺拉学文学和戏剧，想在全球性的文化中心纽约施展抱负。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当诺拉说移民的原因是“韩国人拿不到诺贝尔文学奖”时，这句颇有喜剧效果的台词，却道出了第三世界居民的一种普遍焦虑：一方面对诺贝尔文学奖代表的文学成就充满认同和钦羡，另一方面无意识地掉进了诺贝尔文学奖评选机制无可避免的西方中心主义陷阱。 “韩国人拿不到……”这一否定句式包含的自恨，背后是对落后地区的社会结构、文化制度、整体创造力的不信任。但当她脱离韩国、使用英语写作时，当她被识别为一个北美的亚裔，她便永远卡在了既非韩国作家也非美国作家的中间状态。因为合租省钱才跟亚瑟搬到一起住，因为移民政策才早早结婚，诺拉问，这真的是父母移民时，期待女儿过上的生活吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;豆瓣网友toska在短评中说：《过往人生》“让我感到最不适的是暗流的优越感”，纽约优于多伦多，多伦多优于首尔，她自己优于或等于美国韩裔，美国韩裔优于韩国人（电影里用的一个词是Korean Koreans，前一个词是文化意义上的韩国人，后一个词是族群意义上的韩国人），“可怕的是我觉得创作者本身是不自知的，却觉得自己委屈。在缺乏自我反思的前提下高歌自身贫瘠的体验和感受”。这或许提供了思考这部影片的另一个角度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年釜山国际电影节的开幕影片《我讨厌韩国》根据小说《走出韩国》改编，主人公桂娜是一个学历、工作、容貌都平平的人，未来的一切都已注定，没有奇迹发生，她说：“韩国爱的人是它自己，而不是我。它只爱让它发光的那些人……而对于那些让它蒙羞的人，它都是避之不及的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样的离散主题，《走出韩国》的主人公是为了逃离内卷和阶层固化，《过往人生》的诺拉是期待登上世界的舞台，留在韩国的海盛则想成为“更优秀”的人，即便身体辛苦，精神也不肯认输。真正的问题是，不论在哪片土地，都不能期待一个人间天堂，没有一劳永逸的乐土，只有永恒的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海盛问诺拉，假如你12岁时没有出国，假如我24岁时来到了纽约，会有什么不同？也许，正因为他们24年来只有两度惊鸿一瞥，没有陷入生活的琐屑、放大彼此的缺点，这缺憾才完美而迷人，值得诺拉失声痛哭，一边是不完美的祖国的完美的初恋，一边是完美的乌托邦的不完美的日常，她徘徊在曼哈顿的街区，也徘徊于无地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海一初中现投毒事件？警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:23:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 15:37 on September 12, 2023, the Pudong Public Security Bureau received an alarm saying that there was a police officer in a middle school on Xianan Road. Many students are feeling unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After preliminary investigation, the school’s student Yang Moumou (&lt;span>;female, 13 years old&lt;/span>;) and his classmate Zheng Moumou (female, 13 years old) took advantage of the physical education class that morning. Returning to the classroom, he poured the cleaning and bleaching mixture into the water cups of his classmates, causing many students to become uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant students were sent to the hospital for treatment and were discharged that night and have now resumed normal classes. Currently, the police are working with the education department to conduct further investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;295&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当买不起LV包的年轻人入手了百元高奢包装袋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo/图）&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wearing the latest Chanel jacket, putting on a collector’s edition Cartier watch, picking up the Hermès “Dream Love Bag”, and feeling the refreshing fragrance of Guerlain perfume, it was officially Stepping out of the house - this is the &quot;luxury&lt;/span>;urban dream&quot; in the hearts of countless boys and girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, a post &quot;Zhejiang people spend 1.8 billion a year on Chanel&quot; sparked heated discussion. Sales of the Chanel store in Hangzhou Tower reached 1.8 billion yuan last year. Many luxury goods, including Chanel, are advertised as &quot;rich&quot;. Netizens joked: &quot;Poverty limits my imagination. There are so many rich people, why can&#39;t there be one more for me?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“There are not many people in ordinary shopping malls, but there are long queues in luxury stores.” Many netizens have this feeling about luxury stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking across the country, whether in Beijing, Shanghai, or other cities, the stores of luxury brands such as Hermès, Chanel, and Gucci are often overcrowded. When new products are released, they are comparable to large-scale &quot;ticket check-in&quot; scenes, which are different from ordinary stores. Compared with the twos and threes of customers in the brand store, it can be described as a world of ice and fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China’s luxury craze: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Thousand-layer tricks to attract attention and attract money&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Luxury goods are recognized internationally It is defined as &quot;a kind of consumer goods that are unique, scarce, rare and beyond the scope of people&#39;s survival and development needs&quot;, also known as non-living necessities. However, the sluggish consumption environment does not seem to affect the enthusiasm of &quot;die-hard fans&quot; for this &quot;non-necessities of life&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, a Louis Vuitton handbag&lt;/span>; sells for 17,000 yuan in France and 24,000 yuan in mainland China. Yuan. In addition to the long queues outside the store, a group of people silently opened the page of the overseas purchasing platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an important force in the world’s luxury consumption, the Chinese market is indispensable for brand expansion. The &quot;2022 China Luxury Goods Report&quot; shows that Chinese luxury goods market sales will reach 956 billion yuan in 2022, a slight decrease of 4% year-on-year, accounting for 38% of the global luxury goods market. Its importance can be imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only are they expensive, the prices of luxury goods are also soaring. In November last year, Chanel raised the prices of all products by 3% to 11%. According to statistics from the fashion website Purse&lt;span>;Bop, the average annual increase for low-end luxury goods is about 4%, and that for high-end luxury goods is between 15% and 18%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although prices are &quot;rising and rising&quot;, they cannot resist the enthusiasm of buyers, and snapping up luxury goods has become a highly sought-after fashion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250401 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Behind the &quot;pursuit of luxury&quot; is the multi-pronged strategy of &quot;attracting attention&quot; and &quot;attracting money&quot; created by luxury brands&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the popularity of the &quot;Metaverse&quot; concept, many brands have turned their attention to this new way of playing. Gucci once cooperated with the gaming platform Roblox to open a Gucci pop-up store and launched a digital version of the Gucci Bacchus bag, which was sold for US$4,100, US$700 higher than the physical bag. Balenciaga also makes virtual costumes for multiple characters in the game &quot;Fortnite&quot;, and players can wear &quot;genuine skins&quot; for $8. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“It’s not money that is wasted. If you can’t afford it in real life, just enjoy it in the game.” Ronaldinho, a senior gamer, talked about his views on buying “skins” mentioned at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Not only that, brands such as Prada, Louis Vuitton, and Burberry have all tested the &quot;Metaverse&quot;. This wave of operations inevitably led to ridicule from netizens: &quot;The leeks in reality&lt;/span>; are endless, and we have to cut the leeks in the &#39;metaverse&#39; again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Breaking the consumption dimension wall is not enough, &quot;it is economical&quot; Luxury goods are also indispensable for the hot trend. As the saying goes, &quot;pampering comes with the owner,&quot; many cats and dogs enjoy a luxurious cat/dog life under the &quot;absolute love&quot; of their owners. A traction rope worth 5,000 yuan, a pet carrying case worth 20,000 yuan, a pet bed worth 17,000 yuan... The pet products launched by Hermès focus on &quot;gold and preciousness&quot;, &quot;These days, dogs are richer than me.&quot; Pet. Zhu Xiaofang commented on social media, &quot;Why are even pets involved? I cried.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course, luxury brands will not let go of any potential consumers. In addition to traditional items such as bags, clothing, and jewelry, small items such as mobile phone cases, earphone cases, and keychains are also quietly emerging. A certain grassroots blogger wrote on Xiaohongshu: &quot;Can&#39;t afford a five-figure Louis Vuitton bag, and also can&#39;t afford peripherals? Go, go, go!&quot; I don&#39;t know how many buyers were attracted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking through the catalogs of luxury brands, you can also see many novel products: coffins, body bags... rich in styles and expensive. Netizens&#39; imaginations ran wild: &quot;Is this the &lt;span>;legendary &#39;die gracefully&#39;?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC pho&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to / picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people play high-end luxury: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Second-hand buying and selling , Big-name samples&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The level of luxury goods consumption is inseparable from the city&#39;s economic strength. The &quot;2019 Luxury Goods Industry Insight Report&quot; shows that Beijing and Shanghai ranked first and second respectively in the ranking of cities with luxury goods consumption levels in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 53 Hermès stores across the country, excluding a total of 20 stores in Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan, Beijing and Shanghai have 5 stores each, accounting for nearly 1/3 of the number of stores in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these buyers, high-net-worth groups (mainland Chinese with assets of tens of millions of yuan) are the &quot;top-tier&quot; consumers. They and &quot;luxury goods&quot; are like the best partners going both ways. However, nowadays, luxury consumers are not just traditional &quot;high-end buyers&quot;, but also a huge number of young people who can become buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that the post-90s generation in China’s luxury goods market has become the main force in luxury goods consumption, accounting for 50% of the overall market consumer population. At the same time, Bain Luxury Research Report has predicted that by 2025, Millennials and consumers under the age of 25 will become the main force in the luxury consumer market, accounting for 65% to 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As young people with potential, luxury brands have made a lot of efforts in digital marketing to reach them - 68% of young people will be &quot;planted&quot; by content posted by celebrities or bloggers , and then generate purchasing behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250409&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, not all young people have amazing financial resources. Young buyers can also enjoy luxury goods by buying second-hand goods with &quot;exquisite poverty&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;China&#39;s Second-hand Luxury Goods Industry Overview 2021&quot; shows that more than half of second-hand luxury goods consumers are under 30 years old, and the reasons for more than half of consumers&lt;/span>;&#39;s purchases The price is lower than new products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buy and sell, sell and buy, &quot;out-of-print&quot; goods on the market can be found second-hand, and both parties enjoy the joy of luxury goods circulation in the transaction. According to statistics, more than half of the users in the market choose to &quot;buy and sell at the same time&quot;, and there is a significant trend of &quot;integration of buying and selling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 Circular Fashion Industry Trend Report&quot; shows that the domestic second-hand luxury goods market reached 17.3 billion yuan in 2020, and is expected to reach 38.4 billion yuan in 2025. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Buyers hunt for goods in a variety of categories, mainly in the fields of luggage and leather goods, clothing, shoes and hats, high-end watches and jewelry accessories. Due to the wide audience and high value retention, luggage Leather goods have become the first choice for second-hand luxury goods consumers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Facing high-end luxury cosmetics that are easy to wear, there is a more affordable &quot;big brand sample&quot; method. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“You can enjoy big-name brands at a two- or three-digit price, why not?” Xiaotian, a junior student, is a makeup novice and works with many beauty experts. Similarly, she has collected all kinds of big-name foundations, lipsticks, perfumes, and skin care products. The only difference is that hers are all &quot;samples&quot;: &quot;I don&#39;t wear makeup more than ten times a month. It&#39;s a waste to buy formal clothes. Worry about being cheap, big brands will feel more at ease.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by the huge consumer market, businesses have sensed business opportunities. Not only are &quot;samples&quot; sold individually, but repackaged versions of big-name cosmetics are also highly sought after. On the e-commerce platform, the official price of 100ml of Chanel Gabrielle Natural Perfume is about 1,690 yuan, and its 10ml &quot;sample&quot; only costs about 130 yuan. However, most of these products are sold by stores named &quot;XX Purchasing Agency&quot; or other stores whose legitimacy is difficult to judge. The products are mixed and it is difficult to distinguish between genuine and fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1074&quot; height=&quot;3659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250408&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, there is also the method of &quot;making the most of everything&lt;/span>;&quot; that was once popular. Platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu have launched a trend of packaging reform. Some bloggers have transformed packaging bags or packaging boxes with brand logos into tissue boxes, jewelry boxes, and take-out bags, which has quickly accelerated the purchasing trend of luxury packaging. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, there are still many people selling luxury goods packaging on Xianyu, ranging from tens of yuan to hundreds of yuan, and there is an endless stream of people coming to inquire. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250406 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC photo / picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;Luxury goods controversy:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The quality of genuine products is worrying, and the fake rate reaches 80%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;No&lt;/span>; However, luxury goods remain The public&#39;s impression is not only that it is expensive, but also a product that is deeply involved in controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, almost every year, the Internet takes turns to ridicule the &quot;legendary&quot; items launched by certain luxury goods. For example, the &quot;woven bag for moving&quot; that appeared in the fashion week, the sneakers covered with green grass, the same fake bangs of the &quot;Buried Love Family&quot;, and the hole-in-the-wall umbrella that &quot;shelters from rain and loneliness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the designer did it intentionally or not, the marketing effect is so good that even if the whole network complains, it cannot stop a group of people from secretly placing orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, luxury shopping has been described by various bloggers as a &quot;magical&quot; experience. &quot;Wearing cheap clothes and being looked down upon after entering the store&quot; &quot;The shopkeeper looks down on ordinary people&quot;...Such shopping reviews are flooded with short video platforms, and the amplification of the Internet has made many people fear luxury stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the quality of luxury goods has been criticized. In February this year, Ms. Zhang from Fujian spent 20,000 yuan to buy a Chanel handbag while traveling in Chengdu. However, the chain broke after just 15 minutes of carrying it. Such problems are common, and there are endless complaints about luxury goods on the Black Cat complaint platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is a widely circulated joke on the Internet: If&lt;/span>; the luxury bag you buy has problems such as fading, there is no doubt that it must be genuine. It is particularly strong and wear-resistant, so be careful as it may be a fake. &quot;Key customer data&quot; shows that in channels other than the brand&#39;s official channels, the rate of fake products is as high as over 80%. In the current Chinese market, the number of fake luxury goods is six times that of genuine goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4178&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250410&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is even more nerve-wracking&lt;/span>; is the frequent plagiarism of luxury goods in recent years. Last year, Dior launched a mid-length skirt that collided with the traditional Chinese dress &quot;horse face skirt&quot;, but the brand called it &quot;Dior&#39;s signature silhouette.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, with the aftermath of the &quot;Horse Face Skirt&quot; incident still lingering, Dior has launched a 2022 autumn and winter series of clothing, with the original Dior winter garden pattern once again colliding with the Chinese traditional painting &quot;Flowers and Birds&quot;. In the face of successive acts of plagiarism, the voice of resisting &quot;cultural appropriation&quot; has become increasingly louder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the world-class luxury goods that are currently highly sought after still mainly come from overseas. On the other hand, my country&#39;s local brands still have huge room for growth on the road to becoming the world&#39;s business card. We also look forward to the international success of local brands&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部启动首届全国大学生职业规划大赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the Ministry of Education issued a notice to launch the first National College Student Career Planning Competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first National College Student Career Planning Competition, with the theme of &quot;Building Dreams and Aiming for Youth in All Places, Planning to Start Careers and Lead the Future&quot;, was co-sponsored by the Ministry of Education and the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Government. By holding competitions, we strive to create a large classroom that strengthens career education, a large platform that promotes the connection between talent supply and demand, and a large market that serves graduates&#39; employment. We strengthen career education and employment guidance in colleges and universities, enhance college students&#39; awareness of career planning, and guide college students to prepare for employment as early as possible. Better promote high-quality and full employment of college graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition will be held from September 2023 to May 2024. It will adopt a three-level competition system of school competition, provincial competition, and national finals. It will set up a growth track, an employment track, and career development and employment guidance courses for college students. The teaching track is for teachers of career development and employment guidance courses for junior and middle school students, senior students and college students in colleges and universities. The school competition is organized by each university, and the provincial competition is organized by each locality. The national finals are hosted by the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission, Fudan University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai Normal University, and Shanghai Vocational College of Arts and Crafts. There are gold, silver, and bronze awards, as well as individual awards, local and university outstanding organizations. Award, Outstanding Instructor Award and other awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Registration for the competition will begin on September 20, 2023. At that time, participating students can register through the National College Student Career Planning Competition platform (website: zgs.chsi.com.cn) or designated channels. Registration deadline The time is determined by each place according to the provincial competition arrangements. During the competition, universities across the country will also hold a series of activities such as employment guidance, campus recruitment, school-enterprise supply and demand matching, and career experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>