<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“加沙没有安全的地方”，巴以厮杀循环何时休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCLMiDOB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCL MiDOB. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the Israeli bombing of the Gaza Strip taken on the Israeli side of the Gaza border on October 15 Thick smoke rose behind. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo by Xinhua News Agency Ilan Asayag/Kini Photo Agency/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is an emergency now, I&#39;m sorry The original interview plan will be postponed again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 14, 2023, staff from the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (hereinafter referred to as &quot;UNRWA&quot;) sent a message to Southern Weekend reporters News comes, postponing an interview with Communications Director Julia Tuma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just the day before, the agency announced that &quot;due to increased Israeli attacks on the Gaza Strip&quot; it had moved its operations center and staff to the southern Gaza Strip to continue supporting Palestinian refugees in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a statement issued by the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) on October 17, the number of humanitarian workers killed in Gaza has increased to 31. Gaza has experienced a &quot;total power outage&quot; for the sixth consecutive day, the statement said. Gaza hospitals are on the verge of collapse, with fuel reserves used to run backup generators almost completely depleted, putting the lives of thousands of patients at risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the 15th, two days ago, IDF spokesman Jonathan Conricus posted a video on social media, once again issuing a warning to residents of northern Gaza, causing Palestinians in the area to flee to South. The Israeli military had previously issued a similar evacuation order to Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This violent fight continues to expand in a cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s counterattacks in recent days, today&#39;s Gaza neighborhoods have become beyond recognition, with ruins and ruins visible everywhere. In fear, many Gaza residents embarked on a journey to escape. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We witness death every day.” local Said Shoaib wrote on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Israel has implemented a comprehensive blockade on the Gaza Strip, including cutting off water supply, electricity and gas, closing all ports of entry, and bombing the Rafah port leading to Egypt, causing its infrastructure to not work properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the local humanitarian crisis rapidly deepens, many United Nations agencies have issued stern warnings. Philippe Lazzari, head of UNRWA, said Gaza was &quot;rapidly turning into hell&quot; and on the verge of collapse. He urged all parties to &quot;put an end to this tragedy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, Xu Wei, spokesperson of the China International Development Cooperation Agency, said that China is providing emergency humanitarian assistance to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East and the Palestinian Authority respectively. To solve the urgent needs of food, medical care, housing and other needs in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a new round of conflict between Palestine and Israel continues, the number of casualties on both sides is also rising. As of October 15, local time, the conflict had killed more than 4,100 people on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian, a researcher at the Foreign Policy Institute of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, told Southern Weekend reporters that Israel&#39;s &quot;retaliatory actions&quot; will continue for a period of time. &quot;Hamas&#39; actions are humiliating to Israel, so Israel needs to get a psychological balance.&quot; He believes that Israel will use this power to eliminate Hamas on a regular basis. &quot;In fact, he is already doing this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Urban Street Fighting&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;UNRWA&quot; intern Wu Chenyu on October 12 She received an email stating that &quot;11 staff members of the agency (Gaza office) were killed.&quot; Although she already knew the news, she still felt very sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Chenyu is an intern at the agency’s Jordan office. She told Southern Weekend reporters that the agency’s headquarters manages five field offices, namely Lebanon, Gaza, the West Bank, Syria and Jordan. The Jordanian relief office where she works has not been affected by the war yet, &quot;but other field offices such as Gaza, staff have been informed to evacuate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later on October 14, Hamas sent a message to Israel Rocket attacks were launched in Tel Aviv and surrounding areas, the central city of Bat Yam, the southern city of Ashkelon and other places. According to outside analysis, no one on either side of Palestine or Israel can predict exactly what will happen in the ground war. Hamas has proven that it can survive in previous Israeli-Palestinian conflicts and has &quot;powerful weapons suitable for street fighting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qassan Brigades, an armed faction affiliated with Hamas, released information to the Israeli military on the 14th that the organization was &quot;fully prepared&quot; for &quot;any ground military operations&quot; by the Israeli army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gaza Strip covers an area of ​​approximately 360 square kilometers, with dense population and numerous houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Hamas claimed to have built 500 kilometers of tunnels. Many experts and scholars believe that the tunnel network will make street fighting more difficult. Once the Israeli army and Hamas start &quot;urban street fighting&quot; there, both sides will suffer higher casualties than in the first few days of this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and will have a negative impact on the Israeli army. pose a fatal threat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are two levels in the Gaza Strip, one for civilians and the other for Hamas.&quot; An IDF spokesman said on October 12 that these tunnels are just &quot;bunkers for Hamas&quot; ” so that they can continue to plot cross-border operations and fire rockets into Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media reports revealed that this &quot;maze-like huge underground tunnel network&quot; was built 30 meters underground in Gaza, with the entrance hidden on the ground floor of houses, schools and other public buildings. It is used for Hama Sri Lanka transports personnel, supplies, stores ammunition, etc., while avoiding Israeli artillery shells and reconnaissance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few days, Israel has continued to launch air strikes on Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a week after the conflict broke out, Hamas was still able to fire rockets into Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outside world believes that this is because the rockets hidden in the tunnels can be moved at any time. Saleh al-Arouri, one of the military leaders of Hamas, said before the outbreak of this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, &quot;Hamas&#39;s defensive plan is more powerful than its offensive plan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I don&#39;t think Israeli soldiers have the ability to attack these tunnels.&quot; Shaul, a Palestinian historian at Tel Aviv University&#39;s Middle East and African Studies Center, said, but Israel &quot;will find a way to smoke out Hamas.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin, director of the Mediterranean Research Institute at Zhejiang University of International Studies, believes that Israel cannot and will not completely eliminate Hamas. He said that Hamas has grown from small to large, and there is no lack of &quot;contribution&quot; to Israel for allowing it to grow to fight against the mainstream faction of the PLO. Retaining the Gaza Strip as the so-called &quot;Hamastan&quot; can continue to divide, weaken, and internally divide the Palestinian camp and benefit Israeli strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Revenge and scruples&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I never imagined that this journey would be like this.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Have successfully returned from Israel Rao Pingman from China recalls her escape from Israel as if it was yesterday. After waiting for 15 hours at Tel Aviv Airport, Ms. Rao boarded a plane from Tel Aviv to Ethiopia on the morning of October 8, and then returned to China via the Ethiopia-Bangkok-Hong Kong route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in retaliation for Hamas, the Israeli army has launched multiple rounds of air strikes in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces publicly stated on the afternoon of October 16 that the head of Hamas’s intelligence agency was killed in an assassination operation by the Israeli army. Currently, Hamas has no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces also stated in a statement that the Israeli army has completed the mobilization of hundreds of thousands of reservists, and the logistics department is working hard to ensure the supply of weapons and equipment for ground troops. He also stated that the equipment needed for the battle has been moved to the assembly area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a &quot;counterattack&quot; operation, Israel&#39;s actions can be called &quot;all-round&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, the Israel Defense Forces announced that it would implement a more extensive ground military action plan in the Gaza Strip and expand its offensive in the Gaza Strip, including launching &quot;joint and coordinated attacks by air, sea and land.&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu previously threatened that the Israeli army would &quot;destroy Hamas&quot; through a ground offensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces stated that Israeli soldiers are preparing for &quot;major ground operations&quot; and that the Israeli army will implement an &quot;extensive ground offensive plan&quot; in the Gaza Strip to expand the offensive, including the implementation of &quot;air, sea and joint coordinated attack on land.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian believes that Israel&#39;s mentality at this time is not determined to fight a &quot;win or lose&quot; battle, but that Israel believes that the losses suffered this time are too great, so Hamas must pay the price and double the price. revenge. &quot;Under this mentality, Israel will definitely do more in retaliation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the night of October 12 to the early morning of October 13, the Israeli army attacked about 750 Hamas and other organizations in the Gaza Strip. Air strikes were carried out against targets. These include tunnels, military compounds, residences used as military command centers for senior members, weapons warehouses, communications rooms and 12 buildings housing Hamas assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 11th, the day before that, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu gave a televised speech that night. He vowed to &quot;crush and destroy&quot; Hamas militants, saying that the Every member of the organization is a &quot;dead person.&quot; The Israeli army also attacked two Hamas military bases in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In one of the compounds, the headquarters of the commander of Hamas&#39;s northern division was destroyed, and a military infrastructure building belonging to the Hamas naval unit was also attacked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces stated that since the Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out on October 7, the Israeli army has arrested more than 330 Palestinians in the West Bank, including more than 100 people related to Hamas. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Israel&#39;s &quot;counterattack&quot; actions will not expand indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin judged that once the Gaza Strip, known as the &quot;hornet&#39;s nest&quot; and the &quot;damned strip&quot; by the Israelis, is included in the territory, Israel will once again bear a heavy burden of international law, morality, public opinion, economy, demographic structure and security. It will also put an end to the reconciliation process with Arab countries that has made significant progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Israel also has many concerns.&quot; Li Weijian analyzed that if Israel excessively causes a humanitarian crisis or kills many civilians, it will eventually arouse the anger of the Arab world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Hurt each other&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Israel&#39;s &quot;evacuation order&quot; was issued, residents of northern Gaza began to flee to the south, looking for shelter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In videos circulating on social media, residents of Wuyangyang stuffed their belongings into pickup trucks and cars. Some residents had to squeeze onto flatbed trucks pulled by livestock and move with difficulty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some residents refused to leave and stayed in the collapsed and dilapidated houses. Speaking to the cameras, they said that while their homeland might be fraught with dangers, leaving would be &quot;turning back the land and history.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a new round of conflict broke out, Said Shoaib&#39;s family had to go from the Brei refugee camp near the Israeli border to the Deir al-Balah refugee camp. He continues to document it on social media. He said, &quot;There is no safe place in Gaza. Israel tells people to go to the south, but they are still bombing in the south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s &quot;blockade&quot;, World Health Organization spokesperson Jassa Revi Qi said Gaza&#39;s hospitals were running out of medical supplies and beds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs released news on October 13, stating that since the outbreak of the new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the number of displaced people in the Gaza Strip has exceeded 420,000. United Nations agencies have called for funds to provide aid to Palestinians in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Israeli government released &quot;horrific photos of babies being killed and burned by Hamas monsters.&quot; The three photos were posted on the social media accounts of Netanyahu&#39;s office. But Hamas denies the accusations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ran, who has now fled to Turkey, moved into the shelter of his school in Israel with his luggage when a new round of conflicts broke out. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the place has complete water, electricity and internet connections and is safer than other shelters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The battlefield is mainly concentrated in the south. In the central part where I am, except for a few thousand rockets on the first day, the number of rockets decreased thereafter, and even buses and trains were restored the next day.&quot; Yang Ran revealed , because Israelis may have one or two rocket attacks every year, they are &quot;relatively accustomed to it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The size of the economic damage to Israel will depend on how long these reservists are away from work.” Eyal Winter, an economics professor at Israel’s Hebrew University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the outbreak of the conflict, the Israel Defense Forces has called up many reservists to perform tasks. These reservists come from all walks of life. They are separated from daily economic production activities and go into battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;The quagmire of &quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Multi-front operations&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, Israel has fully &quot;blocked&quot; Hamas-controlled areas In the Gaza Strip, water and electricity supplies were cut off. The move has the United Nations concerned about an exacerbation of the humanitarian crisis in Gaza. United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres urged all parties to allow the United Nations to provide humanitarian assistance to the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a United States that is &quot;busy on both sides&quot;, it has made frequent &quot;big moves&quot; since the Palestinian-Israeli conflict escalated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. White House announced on October 16 that after visiting Israel on October 18, U.S. President Biden will go to the Jordanian capital Amman to meet with Jordanian King Abdullah II and Egyptian President Sisi. Met with Palestinian President and Palestinian National Liberation Movement (Fatah) Chairman Mahmoud Abbas to discuss conflict-related matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, US Secretary of Defense Austin ordered the &quot;Eisenhower&quot; aircraft carrier strike group to head to the Eastern Mediterranean. He said this was &quot;part of efforts to contain the expansion of the war.&quot; Biden publicly stated that the White House is quickly &quot;providing additional security assistance such as ammunition and missile interception systems&quot; to Israel. He urged the U.S. Congress to take urgent action to approve funds to meet the security needs of the United States&#39; &quot;key partners&quot; including Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The United States sends an aircraft carrier fleet to support Israel and deter Iran and Hezbollah, but it will not actively intervene in the Gaza war and create enemies on all sides in the Middle East, and it does not want to get stuck in the quagmire of the Middle East again.” Zhejiang International Studies University’s Mediterranean Research Ma Xiaolin, the dean of the hospital, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this conflict, Iran, which was speculated to be a &quot;supporter&quot; of Hamas, held its first meeting with senior Hamas officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 14th local time, Iranian Foreign Minister Abdullahiyan met with Hamas leader Haniyeh in Doha, the capital of Qatar. He called on Israel not to launch a ground attack on the Gaza Strip. He also warned that if the Lebanese Hezbollah joins the conflict, this round of conflicts may further expand to other regions in the Middle East, which will cause Israel to suffer huge losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When will this cycle of violent fighting stop? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Marzouk, a member of the Hamas Political Bureau, said on October 10 that Hamas &quot;has achieved its goals&quot; and is open to discussing &quot;similar things&quot; and &quot;all political dialogue&quot; about a ceasefire. The Qatar Al Jazeera website reported that Hamas has captured a sufficient number of Israeli soldiers, but Hamas will only be willing to discuss the issue of prisoner exchange after the war is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is noteworthy that conflicts also broke out in the border areas between Israel and Lebanon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Lebanese National News Agency reported that on October 15, local time, Israel launched an artillery bombardment on the southern Lebanese border town of Al-Dhahira, causing complete disruption of public road traffic. It is generally believed that if the situation on the Lebanese-Israeli border escalates further, Israel may face a &quot;second front&quot; in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin said that the main battlefield of this conflict has been moved to the Gaza Strip. No matter how large the casualties are, the war will not spill over to the four countries of Palestine, Israel, Lebanon, and Syria. &quot;Coupled with the first phone call between the heads of state of Saudi Arabia and Iran to discuss the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, this shows that the regional identity politics game once led by both parties will not be repeated, and the Palestinian issue may continue to be marginalized.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Next, Israel will still take future development into consideration.&quot; Li Weijian analyzed that Israel has to deal with Middle Eastern countries and Arab countries, and it also hopes to maintain the situation it has finally opened and improve the development of relations with other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Ning, spokesperson of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, called on the top priority to cool down the situation, cease fire and violence, protect civilians, and avoid humanitarian disasters. When dealing with international and regional hot-spot issues, major countries should adhere to objectivity and fairness, maintain calmness and restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Rao Pingman and Yang Ran are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt; br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt; /a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年前三季度中国GDP同比增长5.2%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Data released by the National Bureau of Statistics on the 18th showed that preliminary calculations showed that China’s gross domestic product (GDP) in the first three quarters ) 91.3027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.2% at constant prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at quarters, GDP grew by 4.5% year-on-year in the first quarter, 6.3% in the second quarter, and 4.9% in the third quarter. From a quarter-on-quarter perspective, GDP grew by 1.3% in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sheng Laiyun, deputy director of the National Bureau of Statistics, said at a press conference of the State Council Information Office that day that in the first three quarters, faced with the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, various regions and departments Resolutely implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, focus on expanding domestic demand, boost confidence, and prevent risks, and the national economy continues to recover and improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall agricultural production situation is good, the recovery of industrial production is accelerating, and the service industry continues to recover rapidly. In the first three quarters, the added value of agriculture (planting industry) increased by 3.6% year-on-year; the added value of the national industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 4% year-on-year, 0.2 percentage points faster than the first half of the year; the added value of the service industry increased by 6% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market sales tend to be active, the scale of fixed asset investment continues to expand, and the import and export of goods are generally stable. In the first three quarters, the total retail sales of consumer goods reached 34,210.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.8%. National fixed asset investment (excluding rural households) increased by 3.1% year-on-year; excluding the impact of price factors, it increased by 6% year-on-year. The total import and export of goods was 30.8021 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumer prices rose moderately, the employment situation was generally stable, and residents&#39; income grew steadily. In the first three quarters, the national consumer price index (CPI) rose by 0.4% year-on-year, and the national average urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.3%. The per capita disposable income of residents across the country was 29,398 yuan, a nominal increase of 6.3% year-on-year; after deducting price factors, the real growth was 5.9%, 0.1 percentage point faster than the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Overall, the national economy has continued to recover in the first three quarters, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced, laying a solid foundation for achieving the full-year development goals. However, it must also be noted that the external environment has become more The situation is complex and severe, domestic demand is still insufficient, and the foundation for economic recovery still needs to be consolidated.&quot; Sheng Laiyun said that in the next stage, we must do a good job in implementing the policies that have been introduced to achieve effective results, and continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous improvement of endogenous power, and the continuous improvement of social It is expected to continue to improve, risks and hidden dangers will continue to be resolved, and efforts will be made to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“江浙沪独生女”人设走红，这届年轻人在羡慕什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjB k6gukrSbaP. png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021999449192&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data -filename=&quot;The character of &quot;The Only Child in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, what are the young people of this generation envious of.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot; width= &quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot;>;The character of &quot;The Only Girl in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, and young people in this generation are envious What to admire.mp3 &lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;In the imagination of netizens, the only daughter of a wealthy middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys family resources and pampering, and her parents are open-minded enough. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture generated by &quot;AI Huitu&quot;/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, and meeting social people who come from south to north, Hello Southern Weekend listeners, welcome to Southern Weekly’s podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; became popular on the Internet, becoming the most enviable female character template after &quot;Single Aunt&quot; and &quot;Runaway Wanyu&quot;. In the imagination of netizens, an only daughter born in a well-off middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys the resources and love of her family. Her parents are open-minded enough, so she has the confidence to pursue career development and the capital to go home and settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, is this really the only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai? What will be the other side of returning under the wings of your parents and enjoying the protection of your family? What expectations do the two labels &quot;rich&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; carry for contemporary young people? Behind the changes in the female template, how are our attitudes towards life and work changing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this podcast, we invite two guests who are both &quot;only children from Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; to discuss the above issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;This issue’s guests&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Sun Lin (left), lecturer at the Chinese Studies Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong and PhD in Anthropology, and Ge Shurun ​​(right), a doctoral candidate at the School of Journalism, Renmin University of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>; Listening tips: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►03:34 &amp;nbsp;“Someone will tell me the truth” is the very attractive part of this label&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►06:22 &amp;nbsp;In the process of growing up, the only daughter born in the 1980s in Shanghai believed in trying things out&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►08:48 &amp;nbsp;The &quot;Pyramid of Filial Piety&quot; emphasizes cost-effectiveness&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►11:51 &amp;nbsp;Interview with the elderly in Shanghai, almost no one expects their children to support them in old age&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►15:09 &amp;nbsp;Returning to the family character and independent character co-exist&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 20:25 &amp;nbsp;Changes in the external environment have made young people more in need of family to resist risks&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►25:46 &amp;nbsp;The labels of &quot;Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; hide some social prejudices&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;►29:06 &amp;nbsp;In addition to money, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; also emphasizes the emotional support of the family&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►31:02 &amp;nbsp;Different female templates are pursued by different people. Or is it a conflict between ideals and reality&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►35:22 &amp;nbsp;The label also ignores the obligations and responsibilities that an only child will face&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►39:29 &amp;nbsp;Enlightened parents will also Giving hints on &quot;should you come back and take the civil service exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editors: Wang Yixuan, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operators: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会开幕，新能源汽车备受外商关注]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院副秘书长近期密集调整：4人履新，其中两名“69后”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security announced that the State Council appoints and removes national staff. Among them, Sun Guangyu was appointed as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council; Wang Zhiqing was removed from the post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu previously served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management. Wang Zhiqing, who has resigned, has served as Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July this year, the deputy secretary-general of the State Council has been reshuffled frequently, with &quot;four in and four out&quot; - Sun Guangyu, Xu Shouben, Wang Zhijun, and Wang Yonghong have taken over, while Wang Zhiqing, Ding Xuedong, Peng Shujie, and Li Wenwen have stepped down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, during the two sessions of the National People’s Congress, the leadership team of the central government changed, and State Councilor Wu Zhenglong also served as Secretary-General of the State Council. According to public reports, there are currently at least 7 deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, namely Meng Yang, Liu Jianbo, Guo Wei, Wang Zhijun, Wang Yonghong, Xu Shouben, and Sun Guangyu (in order of appointment). Among them, Wang Zhijun is clearly at the ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council come from different fields&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who took up their posts this year come from different fields. He is an expert in the field. Sun Guangyu has worked in the chemical industry for a long time and is an expert in the field of hazardous chemical safety supervision. Before taking up his new post, he served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management; Xu Shouben is a &quot;veteran&quot; in the financial industry and before taking up his new post, he served as the vice president of the China Development Bank. ; Wang Zhijun has been engaged in economic management work in central ministries and commissions for a long time, and served as deputy secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee before taking office; Wang Yonghong has long worked in the State Administration Bureau (referred to as the State Administration Bureau), serving for 32 years, and took office in June this year. Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four new people are all born after 1965, among whom Wang Yonghong and Xu Shouben were both born in 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254335&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Guangyu. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu, who took office as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council today, was born in December 1966. He has a university degree, a master&#39;s degree in engineering, a professor-level senior engineer, and a member of the chemical industry group of the National Safety Production Expert Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu graduated from Dalian University of Technology, majoring in fine chemical engineering. According to the official website of Dalian University of Technology, he worked at Sinopec in his early years. In 2009, he was transferred from the manager of the Aromatic Hydrocarbons Department of the Tianjin Branch of Sinopec Co., Ltd. to the deputy director and director of the Safety Supervision and Management Department of the State Administration of Work Safety, and later served as the Hazardous Chemicals Department of the Emergency Management Department. Director of the Supervision Department and Director of the First Department of Hazardous Chemical Supervision. In June 2022, Sun Guangyu served as a member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and later served as deputy director of the Office of the State Council Safety Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a week ago, Sun Guangyu interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government on behalf of the Security Affairs Office of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Emergency Management, on September 7, a major high-pressure gas leak occurred at Yiding Ecological Agriculture Development Co., Ltd. in Ordos, Inner Mongolia, resulting in 10 deaths and 3 injuries in a major production safety accident. On September 14, the State Council Safety Committee decided to supervise the investigation and handling of this major accident. On September 11, the Ministry of Emergency Management organized a national emergency video conference on hazardous chemicals safety risk prevention, at which the situation of the Ordos &quot;9.7&quot; accident was reported. Sun Guangyu, member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. The meeting pointed out that lessons from the accident must be carefully learned, and the lessons learned in blood must not be verified with blood again! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, in response to the &quot;9.7&quot; major high-pressure gas leakage accident in Ordos, the Office of the State Council Safety Committee interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government. Sun Guangyu, deputy director of the Office of the State Council Security Committee and deputy minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, presided over the interview, and heads of relevant departments and bureaus of the Ministry of Emergency Management attended the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Guangyu has left the chemical industry and emergency management leadership position he held for many years and joined the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254337&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Shouben. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben took office as deputy secretary-general of the State Council on August 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Xu Shouben was born in April 1969 in Yantai, Shandong Province. He graduated from the School of Management of Harbin Institute of Technology and received a doctorate in Western Economics from Lingnan College of Sun Yat-sen University and is a senior economist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben has worked in the financial industry for many years. He joined the Guangdong Branch of ICBC in April 1995. He has worked in various branches of ICBC in Guangdong Province for a long time. He once served as the Office Director of ICBC Guangdong Branch, President of Guangdong Jiangmen Branch, and Party committee secretary and other positions. In March 2011, he was appointed as the vice president of the Guangdong Branch and in July 2015, he was appointed as the president of the Shenzhen Branch. In August 2020, Xu Shouben was promoted to Vice President of ICBC. In October 2022, Xu Shouben was appointed as Vice President of the China Development Bank and will take office as the State Council in August this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254338&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhijun. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong took up their posts on the same day and were appointed deputy secretary-general of the State Council on July 4. Among them, Wang Zhijun is in charge of the daily work of the General Office of the State Council and is clearly at the ministerial level. He is a member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhijun was born in September 1965 in Hohhot, Inner Mongolia, and has a graduate degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun has been responsible for economic management for many years. He has served as the director of the National Economic Comprehensive Department of the National Development and Reform Commission, deputy inspector of the Comprehensive Group of the Office of the National Energy Leading Group, and deputy director of the Economic Bureau No. 1 of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group. , inspector, director of the fifth economic bureau, director of the first economic bureau of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Commission, etc. In January 2019, Wang Zhijun was appointed as a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. In April 2022, he was transferred to the position of Deputy Secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee, and he will assume the new position of the State Council in July this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Yonghong. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has worked in the State Administration of Institutional Affairs for a long time. The National Administration Bureau is an agency directly under the State Council that manages the affairs of state agencies. It is responsible for the management of funds, finances, official vehicles, state-owned assets and real estate of central state agencies, and is responsible for the management of life services for party and state leaders and relevant service objects within a designated range. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Administration of Management, Wang Yonghong was born in June 1969, with a bachelor&#39;s degree and a master&#39;s degree in management. He joined the National Bureau of Management in August 1991 and served successively as deputy director of the Financial Management Department, deputy director of the Logistics Reform and Comprehensive Management Department, director of the training center, director of the Financial Management Department, and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs; 2017 In April 2017, he was appointed as deputy director, member of the Party Leadership Group and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Management. In November 2017, he was appointed as deputy director and member of the leading party group of the State Administration of Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 20 this year, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs and announced the central government’s decision: Comrade Wang Yonghong was appointed as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has assumed the new post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council and concurrently serves as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. Previous directors of the State Administration of Management were also concurrently held by the deputy secretary-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned, three have assumed new duties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned this year, three have assumed their new posts. new. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhiqing, who resigned as deputy secretary-general of the State Council today, has been appointed chairman and party secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. a week ago. Among the three deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who resigned on July 4, Ding Xuedong has served as Party Secretary of the National Council for Social Security Fund, and Li Wenwen has served as Deputy Minister of the Central Ministry of Social Work and Director of the Office of the Central Joint Conference on Petitions, and continues to serve concurrently as the National Petitions Bureau. Director of the Bureau and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254336&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhiqing. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhiqing was born in March 1966 and is from Tianjin.王志清长期在民航系统工作，1992年入职民航总局，在多个处室担任领导职务，2014年3月任中国民用航空局副局长。 2019年3月，他调任交通运输部党组成员兼总规划师、综合规划司司长，2021年2月升任交通运输部副部长。 2021年11月，王志清获任国务院副秘书长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“中国东航”微信公众号消息，10月9日上午，中国东方航空集团有限公司召开中层以上管理人员大会。中央组织部有关负责同志宣布了中央关于中国东方航空集团有限公司董事长、党组书记任职的决定：王志清同志任中国东方航空集团有限公司董事长、党组书记。东航总部位于上海，是中国三大国有骨干航空运输集团之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月4日，国务院任免国家工作人员，王志军和王永红履新国务院副秘书长的当日，丁学东、彭树杰、李文章被免去国务院副秘书长职务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;丁学东。资料图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丁学东是二十届中央委员，曾两度出任国务院副秘书长，此番卸任前任职国务院常务副秘书长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据公开履历，丁学东，1960年2月出生，江苏常州人，湖北财经学院（现中南财经政法大学）工业经济系硕士研究生，财政部财政科学研究所研究生部财政学专业经济学博士，财政部财政科学研究所博士生导师。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他曾长期任职财政部，历任财政部国有资本金基础管理司司长、农业司司长、教科文司司长，2006年11月任财政部部长助理、党组成员，2008年3月，任财政部副部长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年5月，丁学东任国务院副秘书长，2013年7月任中国投资有限责任公司董事长兼首席执行官，2014年10月兼任中金公司董事长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年3月，国务院任命丁学东为国务院副秘书长（正部长级）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年7月1日，全国社会保障基金理事会召开领导干部会议。中央组织部有关负责同志宣布了中央决定：丁学东同志任全国社会保障基金理事会党组书记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;彭树杰。资料图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彭树杰是名新闻“老兵”，1963年5月生，安徽蚌埠人，高级记者，硕士研究生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据公开履历，彭树杰早年先后在安徽大学外语系和中国社会科学院研究生院新闻系学习，20世纪90年代还曾公派美国夏威夷大学留学。他于1989年进入新华社工作，历任新华社对外部中央新闻采编室记者、副主任，对外部中央外事新闻采编室副主任、主任，新华社总编辑室总编辑助理（副局级），新华社总编辑室副总编辑兼新华社国际部主任等职，并于2014年7月升任新华社副总编辑、党组成员。 2015年11月获任国务院副秘书长，任职近8年卸任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254340&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李文章。资料图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据公开履历，李文章1963年1月出生，宁夏大学政法系毕业，中央党校研究生学历。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他早年长期在宁夏工作，曾任银川市委副书记（正厅级）、宁夏回族自治区司法厅厅长、党委书记；宁夏回族自治区石嘴山市委书记、固原市委书记等职。 2012年6月，李文章晋升宁夏回族自治区党委常委、兼任固原市委书记。 2015年6月任宁夏回族自治区党委常委、政法委书记。 2016年6月任辽宁省委常委、政法委书记。 2018年12月任国家安全部政治部主任、党委委员、机关党委书记，副总警监。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年4月，李文章履新国务院副秘书长、机关党组成员，国家信访局党组书记、局长。值得注意的是，过去几任国家信访局局长也都由国务院副秘书长兼任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年7月4日，李文章被免去国务院副秘书长职务。 10天后，国家信访局“领导介绍”一栏信息显示， 李文章现任中央社会工作部副部长，中央信访工作联席会议办公室主任，国家信访局局长、党组书记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年3月16日，中共中央、国务院印发《党和国家机构改革方案》，在党中央机构改革方面，新组建中央社会工作部等5个“中字头”机构。其中，中央社会工作部负责统筹指导人民信访工作，指导人民建议征集工作，统筹推进党建引领基层治理和基层政权建设，统一领导全国性行业协会商会党的工作，协调推动行业协会商会深化改革和转型发展，指导混合所有制企业、非公有制企业和新经济组织、新社会组织、新就业群体党建工作，指导社会工作人才队伍建设等，作为党中央职能部门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《方案》还明确，中央社会工作部统一领导国家信访局。国家信访局由国务院办公厅管理的国家局调整为国务院直属机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;国务院副秘书长的职责是什么？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据公开报道，目前国务院副秘书长至少有7人，分别是孟扬、刘建波、郭玮、王志军、王永红、徐守本、孙广宇(按任职顺序)。除了今年履新的4人，其余3人，孟扬2015年5月获任国务院副秘书长，刘建波2021年5月获任国务院副秘书长，郭玮2021年7月获任国务院副秘书长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国务院副秘书长一般配置多少人？据中国政府网，国办2008年7月曾印发了一份《国务院办公厅主要职责内设机构和人员编制规定》，其中提到，国务院办公厅机关行政编制为519名。其中：国务院秘书长1名、国务院副秘书长9名（含兼职），司局级领导职数43名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国务院副秘书长的职责是什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年3月修订的《国务院工作规则》明确提到，国务院实行总理负责制。秘书长在总理领导下，负责处理国务院的日常工作，副秘书长协助秘书长工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中提到“对各地区、各部门报送国务院审批的公文，国务院办公厅要认真审核把关，提出办理意见。涉及以国务院或者国务院办公厅名义印发行政规范性文件、报请国务院批准后以部门名义印发行政规范性文件的，由国务院司法行政部门进行合法性审核。对部门之间有分歧的事项，分管主办部门的国务院领导同志应牵头加强协调。国务院副秘书长协助国务院分管领导同志做好协调工作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了相关的规则和文件的把关审核，从国务院副秘书长兼任的一些职务中可以得到更具体的信息。如孟扬，兼任国务院残疾人工作委员会副主任，担任过国务院第一次全国自然灾害综合风险普查领导小组副组长、国务院优化生育政策工作部际联席会议制度副召集人等。刘建波兼任国家禁毒委副主任。王永红兼任国家机关事务管理局党组书记、局长。此外，郭玮还是第十四届全国政协委员、农业和农村委员会委员，刘建波是第十四届全国政协委员、民族和宗教委员会委员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话许知远：梁启超和他诞生150年后的世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;梁启超是我们“熟悉的陌生人”。在中国，几乎无人不知他的名字，但他模糊的形象，被限定在维新派政治家、《少年中国说》的作者、培养了众多杰出子女的父亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1873年，梁启超生于广州府新会县茶坑村。在《三十自述》里，梁启超用中国和世界历史的重大事件为自己出生的年份寻找坐标：那是太平天国覆灭后第十年，曾国藩逝世后一年，普法战争结束的第三年。当然，在他出生时，纪年方式是同治十二年，癸酉。公元纪年直到新中国成立才广泛采用。而十九、二十世纪的说法，正是经由梁启超，在中文世界流布。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超是最早意识到世纪交替的中国人之一，1900年伊始，他写下了《二十世纪太平洋歌》，预言新世纪将迎来太平洋时代。十九世纪的中国人并不会意识到自己在十九世纪，只有到了二十世纪，我们才会借助新的历史坐标向前回溯，来描述这个沉沦、屈辱与奋发、救亡并存的时代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1898年，百日维新失败后，梁启超流亡日本，环游世界。中华民国建立后，梁启超回国，主要的活动舞台在首都北京和天津的饮冰室。对他而言，广东的家乡，变得像少年时代一样遥远。但这并不意味着他告别了故乡，事实上，梁启超在日本横滨、北美和澳洲的许多活动，正有赖于广东华侨网络的巨大支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height=&quot;1055&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在日本期间的梁启超。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“假如我们把眼光放在大历史中没有名字的那些人身上，会发现从十九世纪中叶开始，已经有大量的广东人去了北美和日本，蒸汽轮船的使用，使广东侨民不再只是下南洋，而是横跨太平洋来到世界各地。”《地域文化与国家认同：晚清以来广东文化观的形成》的作者程美宝教授告诉南方周末记者，“太平洋沿岸各个埠头，都有广东人的踪影，他们在异国建立起会馆、庙宇、同乡会，或是用公司的方式组织自己，所以当康梁、孙中山等人在海外活动的时候，就会有人给他接头，安排住宿和行程。这些历史名人的活动，背后是无名的群体数十年的铺垫。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多人曾尝试为梁启超作传，民国历史学家吴其昌写过半本，到戊戌变法为止；解玺璋的《梁启超传》，以梁氏与不同历史人物的交往与关系进行分章；作家魏微在出版长篇小说《烟霞里》之前，曾花了数年时间写梁启超传记，写到十几万字时，她觉得头绪太繁杂，便放了下来，先去从事小说创作了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年是梁启超150周年诞辰，许知远的《梁启超》第二部也出版面世。第一部的标题是《青年变革者》，写1873年到1898年的梁启超，于2019年出版。许知远原本计划分三部写完，现在写作计划已扩充到了五部，第二部《亡命》从1898年写到1903年，庞杂的历史线索、众多与梁氏交汇的人物，都让许知远觉得，有必要把他的版本的梁启超传扩容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所有人都是同时代人。”许知远这样提示他的写作以及每一位读者进入梁启超的世界的方式。梁启超并不仅仅属于昨天，也许他还属于未来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《梁启超》第二部的编辑罗丹妮告诉南方周末记者：“许知远的写作脉络跟史家学者有不同，并非是为回应特定学术史脉络中的一个问题，而是出于一种很纯粹的，一个人对另外一个人的好奇心。就是对另外一个也同样身处新旧交替、未可知的巨变时期的读书人，他怎么面对变局，参与其中，产生好奇。所以他的写作是一种将心比心的、有代入感的写作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，南方周末记者在杭州大运河边的单向空间专访许知远。许知远十分繁忙，除了《十三邀》的节目录制，他正辗转于各个城市进行新书的推广。当记者问到，如何去平衡书中梁启超的思想轨迹与社会图景时，许知远说：“有时候会觉得时代写太多了，时代压倒了个体，有时候又觉得个体写多了，缺少时代的映照，这是一个不断去寻找的过程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254310&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，许知远在杭州谈梁启超。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南瓜视业供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我特别希望跟传主梁启超一起进行思想的冒险，你也不知道下一步会发生什么事情。我目前只写到第二卷，他的思想仍然在继续演变，我不愿意用后见之明来评价他的思想是不是已经成熟了，那段时间他就产生了这样一种思想状况。我想尽量回到历史现场，去创造某种可能性。这套书的写作过程，并不是说我已经经过20年研究，深思熟虑了，对他有很多的理解，才开始动笔来书写它，不是的。我的理解会随着写作的进行不断加深，比如我写到第二卷，就比第一卷更理解他一些，写到第三卷可能比第二卷更理解他一些。但也有可能，写完最后一卷的时候，会意识到最初对他的思想理解得不太准确，因为这是更大的一个框架。”许知远对南方周末记者说。某种意义上，梁启超的世界已经是许知远的平行宇宙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;像做拼图一样，构建梁启超的世界&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;之前有一些从思想史角度来讨论梁启超的著作，比如美国学者列文森的《梁启超与中国近代思想》、张灏的《梁启超与中国思想的过渡（1890—1907）》等，而你写梁启超传，主要的兴趣是要描述梁启超那一代人经历的社会转型，你觉得这两种写作的主要区别是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;列文森和张灏先生的书是最初影响我对梁启超的兴趣的著作，对我有思想启蒙的意义。列文森把梁启超放在一个更大的范畴里，来看待他在中国传统中扮演的角色，用短短的篇幅涵盖他的一生。张灏先生的书主要是讨论1907年以前梁启超的思想历程。大约十年前，我还在美国华盛顿见过张灏先生，去他家做客，一起吃了个夫妻肺片。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它们是思想式的传记，而我想写的，是一个更多以人为中心展开，兼具文学性、历史性，某种意义上具有百科全书色彩的书。我花了很多笔墨不仅写梁启超，也写他的同代人，写他背后整个时代的精神，写整个中国的变化，日本的变化，世界的变化，所以它更像“梁启超和他的时代”。我希望把梁启超看作全球现代性转变过程中的一个代表人物，他不仅属于中国的传统，也属于亚洲乃至世界的传统，因此我要去描绘他背后的生活空间和场景。我大量地写了他作为一个行动者的部分，他不仅是一个思想者，更重要的还是一个行动者。我想用现代意义上的传记写作的方式，给他更多的立体性的展示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如果要更多分析他的思想轨迹，就会增加论述的部分，你的写作方式是尽量用史料说话，很少论述，这是出于什么考虑？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我尽量不去破坏叙事节奏，叙事有一个乐感也好，一个逻辑也好，我尽量遵循叙事本身的结构，人物慢慢随着每一卷的进行，在每一页纸上变得丰满鲜活起来，他有自己的性格，我并不能完全操纵和规定，而他的性格又是由那些现实的材料，可能加上我的某种重组材料的想象力共同构成的。我的主观性是在序言里完成的，一旦进入正文写作，我希望把主观情绪藏在文字后面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在阅读刚刚出版的梁启超传第二部《亡命》以及前几年出版的《青年变革者》时，读者的很大一部分乐趣，在于通过你的书写，可以建立起对一百多年前的一部分中国人生活经验的感知。比如清末广东的读书人进京赶考，不是走陆路，而是走海路，一般要在上海停留中转，所以上海自然地成了他们的一个活动舞台；比如到了北京，会住在同乡会馆。搜集这些材料时，遇到了哪些困难？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;收集材料，一个是要去想象他的生活空间，比如说梁启超经常会被抽象成一个简单的思想人物，当然这也很重要，但是他不仅生活在一个思想的语境中，也生活在现实的语境中，他不仅是个思想者，还是那个时代重要的见证者和参与者，所以对我来说，创造那个时代背景变得非常重要。只有更理解那个时代的背景，才更容易理解他的行动的杰出和困难之处在哪里。所以我花很多精力去构建时代空间，去理解当年一个秀才或举人怎么进京赶考，一个读书人他们日常生活是什么样子的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有你更理解一个读书人的日常生活，比如说他在学海堂读什么样的作品，才会理解他突然要到日本，进入西方语境的思想脉络是多么非比寻常。所以我就要描绘读书人的日常，在广州、在北京是什么状况，在会馆里怎么跟人交往，要靠当年的日记、笔记，一些看起来跟梁启超毫不相关的记录，来创造一个世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这方面我很受史景迁的影响，你看他写《王氏之死》，王氏没有什么记载，但他通过蒲松龄的小说来想象当年山东是什么样的，当年清王朝的生活气氛。我也大量凭借这种笔记，甚至当时的小说，去构造这样的气氛，包括其他考生对日常的记载，第二卷更是要创造19世纪末到20世纪初一个东京的、横滨的、墨尔本的时空，还要在这个世界里穿梭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我年轻时喜欢看各种杂书，杂书的作用就在这里。比如我看过很多澳大利亚历史的书，然后写作的时候，去描述1900年的悉尼，要大量搜集当时的报纸文献，可能用上的就寥寥几笔。当时澳大利亚的侨领梅光达是什么样子？温哥华的叶家又是什么状况？都需要通过各种奇怪的资料，像做拼图一样，可能并不完整，尽量多拼一点是一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;比如你写梁启超跟他妻子的关系，还有他在夏威夷一段没有结果的爱情，这方面材料就很少，一方面他是一个早熟的文化明星，有着与年龄不相称的社会声望，另一方面他好像是一个不需要儿女私情的人，妻子很少随他出行或陪在他身边。今天的读者就很难理解这一点。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那是一个男性为中心的时代，对于这些以天下为己任的读书人，家庭尽管很重要，但往往被他们的叙述忽略，留下的记载很少。包括海外的唐人街，基本也是一个男性的世界，除了侨领有可能把太太带在身边，大部分人的家眷都留在广东、福建的家乡。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超一直在世界各地颠沛流离，有很大的情感空缺，他会把自己的焦灼、孤独和挫败，在诗里流露，他写了24首情诗，描绘对何小姐强烈的情感，放在这样一个时空里，他的情感才会容易理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;康有为的情感就更丰富了，他一路流亡，娶了不同的太太，有各种艳遇。而梁启超妻子的哥哥是他的考官，这是一个对他有恩的家庭，然后因为他的行动，使妻子和全家卷入到危险和慌乱之中，他有很多负疚在里面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;可不可以说，梁启超是一个比较禁欲的人？张灏那本书谈到“克己”，克己也包含了禁欲的一面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;梁启超的情感非常丰沛，同时又很自律，他的热情、欲望在行动和写作中已经得到了非常大幅度的展现。你想，他写了那么多作品，在短时间内做了那么多事，从政治组织到创办杂志，涉及的领域从政治经济学到如何写小说，什么都有。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;众多人的心理动机，构成了历史的动力&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说梁启超可能是中国最早的环球旅行者，但中国文人没有关注旅途中的衣食住行、风土、景观这些细节的习惯。你是通过哪些手段来补充这些细节的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他自己写过一部分，横跨太平洋的晕船，在纽约、美国的见闻。我还需要去翻阅当年的报纸，要看美国史、澳洲史怎么描述当时的国家和社会的面貌，跟梁启超的个人见闻、感受混在一起，共同形成他眼中的世界的样子。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超之前，黄遵宪也随着他的外交活动，在日本、美国、新加坡长期生活。广东华侨的网络在他们的游历中发挥了什么作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;太平洋两岸的城市聚集了很多广东人，形成了资金和观念的网络，这个网络支撑了近代中国的变革者。如果没有广东人的海外网络，许多事情都不会发生，康梁也无法扮演这么重要的角色。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那为什么这些变革者没有诞生在福建？福建人海外移民也很多。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;一方面跟杰出人物的诞生有关，另一方面香港发挥了重要的作用，香港是一个新思想的辐射地，同时广州也是一个文化中心，香港与广州之间形成了有趣的文化张力和文化动力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超在澳洲和美国的旅行最吸引你的地方是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是他与当地社会的互动，如何去激发当地人对他的政治理念的兴趣和热情，所以我花了很多时间去寻找当地华人对梁启超的反应是什么。我非常开心找到了一个材料，梁启超在西雅图演讲时，正好一个日本留学生记录下了华人剧院里大家欣赏梁启超演讲的盛况，这种描述对我来说非常重要。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个我感兴趣的地方是不同的华人世界之间的区别。比如新金山墨尔本、旧金山圣弗朗西斯科、温哥华，每个城市的华人社区都有各自的特性，这些特性也会反映在他们对流亡者的态度里。包括华人社会内部的分歧和紧张，富有的商人想从保皇会当中获得什么，普通人想得到什么，每个人都有复杂的心理动机，这些心理动机就构成了历史的动力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对今天的海外华人有什么新的观察？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;能看到叠加的移民浪潮，他们会留下不同的遗产，一方面还有广东人构成的老式的唐人街；另一方面，从饮食上可以看出变化，现在海外的中餐不仅有粤菜，还有越来越多的川菜。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那个时代的旅行最主要的交通方式是轮船，海运的风险、漫长的时间、晕船的痛苦，是今天的旅行者很难体会的了。你有过长距离乘坐轮船的经历或计划吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没有，也很难有了。那个时候的时间感跟我们现在不一样，他们可能认为一个月坐船穿越大洋是很正常的一件事情。因为他们没有飞机。时间感都是相对的，对他们来说坐船比如10天能够从横滨到夏威夷已经是非常快的。梁启超经历了地球突然缩小、速度加快的时代，他可以这么短的时间里，去很多不同的州，不同的国家，这是一个崭新的体验。时间感的变化、现代性的变化，对梁启超思想的形成是非常重要的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天的读者要理解梁启超那个时代，最大的隔膜和困难在什么地方？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得对日常生活的理解可能还没有那么难，毕竟日常生活的节奏虽然有差异，但也没有那么难把握。他的思想变化是非常难理解的，他要突然从一个四书五经的，或者仅仅从《万国公报》上看到外部世界的只言片语的一个年轻人，进入明治晚期的日本，面对那么多不同的思想的冲击，从社会达尔文主义到自由主义、君主立宪，还有小说、科学、经济学，所有这些东西涌来，他怎么去理解这样一个世界的新，那种思想的爆炸。当然我们现在也处在一个技术巨变的时代，有很多陌生的名词不知道，但是我们毕竟受过一些现代教育的训练，至少这些新的变化是沿着现代教育的基础和脉络进行的，梁启超他们受的是传统教育，这种巨大冲击的思想感受，是很难去描述的一个过程。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像你受的是牛顿力学的训练，突然把你扔进量子力学的世界，那是怎样一种感觉？我们在描绘这样的思想变化的时候，不能都是后见之明，认为那些名词已经是固定的常识了，那些名词本身是梁启超他们创造出来的，通过对日语的翻译，琢磨这个新词是不是可用的，甚至是来不及想太多就要赶紧开始使用了，要给别人讲述，我觉得那是非常慌乱的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;写梁启超传，一个很大的悖论或挑战是，今天我们中国人运用的很多观念、词汇，本来是经由梁启超创造的，却要用他创造的词像“咬尾蛇”一样去复述他。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;所以怎么回到当时的陌生感是一个问题，我希望描绘思想变化的过程，不是已经固化的思想本身。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;换句话说，除了“同时代性”，我们与一百多年前，也存在文明范式的巨大差异，这个差异首先就体现在我们的教育、我们与传统的关系上。或许呈现这种细微又无处不在的差异，是一个巨大的挑战？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;必须要运用一些想象力和同理心。当然，想象力有它的局限，在写作过程中，误读是一定会发生的。可能误读本身也是历史给我们的很重要的一个动力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在2023年写梁启超传，它一定是2023年的人写的。到了2053年，可以有另外的人去写。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;一定是带着这一代人的问题意识，包括选择什么资料，一定是触发了你此刻的心情的材料，才会选择它。所以它带着强烈的当下性，有点像翻译。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一种翻译的观念就是说，文学经典应当每隔五十年重译一次，每次重译，一定是使用这个时代的文学语汇、日常语言。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对梁启超这样的人物，他确实应该不断地被重新书写。不光是梁启超，严复、蔡元培这些现代中国之父，都值得每一代人重新书写。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;回到梁启超是我们的同时代人这种说法，我们今天援引梁启超也好，回到鲁迅也好，都是在回应当下我们对许多问题没有答案的一种困境？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;思想需要历史的维度，如果没有历史的维度，你的思想会非常轻飘或者说无根。所以写作它的时候，当然是对当下的某种回应，同时也是为当下的问题寻找某种历史的脉络和框架。在这个历史的框架之中，你就更容易理解当下的感受。对我来说，所有的时空都是交错的，其实梁启超的影响并没有消失，它仍然弥漫在我们的生活里。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国应该有一种综合思想性和文学性的历史写作&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超面对巨变和各种棘手的思想难题的抉择，给了你哪些启发？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没有机会深思熟虑，每个人都要在一个信息不充分的情况下展开行动。我喜欢他身上那种行动的精神。行动也是一种思想方式，行动会不断确认思想的局限性和可能性。梁启超对我最强的触动，就是让行动来验证或者拓展思想。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超会比较推崇王阳明，而不是朱熹。梁启超觉得王阳明的知行合一的精神，对日本江户末期到明治维新的变革者产生了巨大的影响。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为王阳明是对个人主体性的一种释放。然后个人能够进行自我塑造，这种能力是非常大的，可以直接影响环境与时代，鼓舞很多胸怀大志的人。梁启超肯定深受此影响，因为他在一个流亡的状态，一切都充满不确定，个人的能动性就变得至关重要。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超是一个学者、媒体工作者，也是一个教育家、作者，他的哪一种身份最吸引你？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，还有个身份是政治家。我觉得他首先是一个书写者，他的其他行动都在不断地展开，那些角色对他也非常重要，但写作者是能最充分地展现他的一切、施展他的才能的一个角色。梁启超是百科全书派的写作者，一个转型时代的启蒙思想家，他的写作就像日本的福泽谕吉，或者法国启蒙运动时期的伏尔泰、卢梭、狄德罗，触及方方面面，可以用文字发挥很直接的政治和社会的影响力。他的时代也在经历中国各种现代学科形成的过程，梁启超卷入其中，然后他又有中国文人士大夫的那种风采，在这样一个过渡时代，他的写作是非常混杂的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你有很多媒体工作经历，会对梁启超编报刊杂志特别感兴趣吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;写一本传记，传主当然会潜移默化影响你。梁启超和我隔了一百年，他是1873出生，我是1976年，可能会有一种潜意识的呼应。但我更感兴趣的，是从19世纪到20世纪，中国剧烈转型、进入现代世界的过程中，梁启超是一个精神世界的代表，他广泛的社会参与也提供了样本的丰富性。接下来我还想写李鸿章的传记，他的性格和经历跟我就完全不一样了，我希望描述那个历史舞台，19世纪中国进入世界舞台过程中的困境，以及个人的失败。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超是19世纪到20世纪的桥梁，李鸿章是中国19世纪的挽歌。你主编过《东方历史评论》，《东方历史评论》很关注中国与周边的历史、中国海外移民，写近代历史人物的传记，也是这种兴趣的延伸吧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;写完梁启超传、李鸿章传，我还想写林语堂传，他们三个人分别代表了中国人的power（权力）、idea（观念）、identity（身份），估计可以写到八十岁了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我一直很喜欢这样一个杂志的样式，介于学院和大众媒体之间的载体，非常有可读性，但背后有很强的学术背景，题材也非常广泛。我对历史一直有强烈的热情，受史景迁的影响，我觉得应该有一种综合思想性和文学性的历史写作。历史和传记写作应该是我们的一种非常重要的知识成果。有的时代是诗歌的时代，有的时代是小说的时代，有的时代可能是散文或旅行写作的时代，我希望还有一些时代是属于历史和传记写作的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说在日本开单向空间，也是写梁启超传的副产品，在外国开书店有哪些困难？尤其日本是一个书店和出版业很发达、自成体系的国家。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;说副产品其实是开玩笑，我是2020年因为疫情困在日本，就想做点事情，结果我在东京的房东成了书店的合伙人。日本书店虽然很多，但是没有很好的当代的中文书店，东京的单向空间百分之七十是中文书，然后也有日文、英文、韩文书，所以它也是一个亚洲书店的概念。就像中国的单向一样，它会提供沙龙活动，是个交流的场所。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;困难当然也不少，在银座找个地方是很不容易的，成本也相对高，它的商业逻辑我也还没想清楚。中国的单向空间，我们是品牌的输出和管理方，不是靠零售来盈利，更像一个综合意义上的文化公司。在东京不是这种商业逻辑，还要看能不能持续支撑下去，所以它是一个很鲁莽的产物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;清末民国的书店往往兼有出版的功能，也是一个新信息的集散中心，你有通过单向空间呼应这一传统的考虑吗？在当下的移动互联网时代，书店扮演了什么特殊的角色？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;书店不仅是知识储存的物理空间，也是人员聚合、知识流动、观念生产的地方，它其实是一个精神的公共体，社区的支持很重要。我们东京店就在推一个会员计划，希望会员能找到共同体的感觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;某种意义上说，图书和纸媒已经被称为夕阳行业，你在流媒体上做的《十三邀》，更有对应于梁启超时代的新媒体的属性，你怎么看待这两者对你不同的意义？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实它们本质上并没有那么大的区别，都是思想的表达。当然不同的媒介有不同媒介的特性，比如书写是更古老的一个媒介，它跟我个人内心，跟我的思想有更密切的关系。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍视频是团队的产物，它能够表现我的某一部分，但经常是集体的表达。公司也是，在公司我就是其中的一个创始人或者是灵魂人物，但它的整个运转经常超出我的控制范围，甚至是个逐渐失控的过程。写书是能够自己控制的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对中国的士大夫来说，可能就自己印一些诗文集，所以到了梁启超那代人，杂志、报纸就是他们的超级新媒体，每十天就能出一期新的，有上万人可以看到，这种冲击是非常直接的，很快形成一个共振效应。梁启超大部分文章是在报纸、杂志上发表，真的就像现在做直播和视频一样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;而且梁启超也面临了失控的情况，比如跟汪康年产生矛盾等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，然后他又被会计骗了，集资也不顺利。他也要考虑经营的问题、营收的压力，给股东派息，要面对印刷厂起火了怎么办。大家往往忽略了一点，梁启超是个连续创业者，办完《清议报》办《新民丛报》，然后又办《新小说》、广智书局，而且他都找到了投资，以编辑和主笔的身份，占二到四成股份。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超主要是一个写作者和编辑，你除了内容产出，还有许多商业活动，你会对这些活动对精力的占用感到困扰吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有时候当然会分散精力，但有时候也是相互促进，因为当你拍节目或者去参与公司的很多事情的时候，经常会挫败，涣散，当然也很兴奋，但是当你写作的时候，就回到更专注的自我，我觉得那是对其他生活的躲避和回避，而你在日常生活面对的一些混乱和失控，也可以把它带到书里，帮你更好地理解梁启超的世界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一些历史材料受到了怀疑，我尽量把这种怀疑也呈现出来&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超通过他大量的写作，创造了一种新的语体，我们现在的文法和语言风格则受到了大量外国译作的影响。有人说你的写作是“翻译体”，你怎么看待这个问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们这代人都受翻译很大的影响，读的很多书是翻译过来的，而且会感到翻译的文体的新颖性。其实梁启超也是翻译体，受到很多日本的影响。更别说五四时期，鲁迅等人的语言。我们白话文的语感就是在翻译的影响下产生的，而且我觉得已经找不到一个纯粹的不受外来语影响的文体。其实最重要的是，你能不能从中找到阅读的快感。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是一个经验丰富的媒体写作者，非常注重公共写作的可读性，但是写作梁启超传需要参考大量的学术著作和史料。你会不会担心，对于普通读者来说，你的梁启超传太艰涩，对于学界来说，信息密度又不够？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对学者来说，信息密度也是非常大的。你看我们出版的各种论文，很多也没多大的信息密度。我写梁启超传，用了非常多的新材料，但是我希望它同时有很强的可读性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一些史料，比如冯自由的《革命逸史》，它的可靠性受到了学界的很多质疑，但冯自由的演绎又是很有戏剧性的。对待这一类史料，你是怎么处理的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有一些历史材料受到了怀疑，我尽量把它受到的怀疑也呈现出来。尽管冯自由的很多东西有道听途说的成分，但当时很多史料都是道听途说的，甚至说不那么确切的材料，也是构成那个时代场域的重要部分。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于梁启超的传说，或者他的同代人的很多传说，也是当时的史料，并没有一个完全纯然的hard fact，就像今天我们俩在这谈话，这中间很多信息在产生，但它并不一定是准确的信息。所以我觉得，要理解历史的这种多样性，对材料本身的引用和怀疑，你给它一个展开的空间，读者自己会感受到的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超认为，20世纪是民族帝国主义的时代，他后来的思想有浓重的社会达尔文主义的色彩，如何看待他的这种思想倾向对后世产生的影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得每一代人要解决每一代人的问题，我们不能要求一代人解决100年之后的问题，有的先知者会看到他的困境是什么，但是对于梁启超那代人来讲，他面临的现实是国家受到羞辱，进入历史的谷底，富强是他们最重要的目标，而他们认为现代民族国家是参与全球竞争的最重要的一种角色，所以他们要去塑造一个现代的民族国家。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于它的内在矛盾性，它可能产生的一种压迫性，是逐渐发展出来的，章太炎对这个问题更敏锐。梁启超可能也感受到这部分，但他有他的迫切性，每个思想家的特质是不一样的，所以我们无法去要求每一个思想者既做出迫切的选择，又有长远的观照。韦伯看到了更长远的东西，看到现代性作为铁笼子的一面，他就是更伟大的一个思想家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然我觉得思想者只能负思想者的责任。历史上一个思想观念的形成，它对我们的影响，不仅来自思想家本身，还来自后来的社会和教育体制的塑造。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁启超徘徊于中国的传统文化与西方的知识之间，他的后代也多是考古、航天等领域的专家，而在今天，我们的困境却是学科太过专门化、辖域化，梁启超式的综合性的人文知识分子越来越缺乏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;随着学科的细分，那种纵横式的思想者，不仅中国，全世界都稀缺。可能当时代发生新的巨大变化，大家就渴望综合性的思想者出现。比如说为什么全球这么多人要读赫拉利的作品，它谈不上多么伟大或深刻，但他具有某种综合性，他对眼前迫切性的问题提出了自己的某种回应，这种回应就会引起大量的注意。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在大众认知中，梁启超是一个被高度窄化的人，今年是他150周年诞辰，梁启超传当然也是改变公众对他的认识的一个重要努力。你觉得在他卷帙浩繁的著述中，有哪些是最值得被今天的读者阅读的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;梁启超写了1400万字，非常庞杂，他的经历和作品一样重要。他的思想史著作，关于清代学术三百年，还有《少年中国说》《新民说》这些散文，都值得被不断重读。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;与梁启超相比，大众对鲁迅作品的阅读就要全面得多。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许知远：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;20世纪是一个革命的世纪，鲁迅是作为一个革命作家被铭记的。梁启超长期以来被认为是维新力量的代表，而维新是被革命叙事所压抑的。其实，在梁启超的时代，他是一位国民作家，从比他年长的人，到他的同代人，再到下一代的陈独秀、毛泽东、胡适，所有人都在读他。此外，梁启超的写作还处在文体转化的过程中，而鲁迅他们已经探索出一种新的白话文的写作方式了。其实，被窄化的不光是梁启超，我们对蔡元培、林语堂的认识也还远远不够，所以我觉得应该有更多写作者加入到重估和重新发现他们的工作中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叶刘淑仪：“丝绸之路也是全球的品牌”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258784]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;539&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9 EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yip Liu Shuyi, who wears many hats, is still making waves in the political arena. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before accepting the exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, Ip Liu Shuyi handed over four business cards with the titles of &quot;Member of the Legislative Council&quot; &quot;Chairman of the New Democratic Party&quot;, &quot;Convener of the Unofficial Members of the Hong Kong Executive Council&quot; and &quot;Co-Chairman of the Maritime Silk Road Association&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These identities occupy most of her time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a member of the Legislative Council, when Ip Lau Suk-yee questioned officials in parliament, the officials said they had to &quot;keep their spirits up.&quot; Because the officials were facing a former senior official who had worked in the government system for decades and knew the situation in Hong Kong well. As the chairperson of the New Democratic Party of Hong Kong, Sandra Yip once said that she would promote the development of high-quality democracy in Hong Kong and do her best to serve the people of Hong Kong. With busy affairs and frequent exposure, Ip Liu Shuyi, who wears many hats, is still making waves in the political arena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, people have mixed reviews about the first woman to head the disciplinary department in Hong Kong SAR. Those who support her believe that during her tenure as the Secretary for Security of Hong Kong, she was decisive, tough and accomplished in many incidents such as the Public Order Ordinance controversy, the issue of right of abode in Hong Kong, and the Immigration Building arson case. The &quot;Iron Lady of Hong Kong&quot;. But it is this tough style that has attracted many voices of opposition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also announced her candidacy for the chief executive of Hong Kong twice in 2012 and 2016. Although they all ended in defeat, the campaign slogan &quot;Win Back Hong Kong&quot; still inspired many Hong Kong people. During the election process, Ip Lau Suk-yee repeatedly emphasized that &quot;if elected, she will take the lead in dealing with Hong Kong&#39;s core governance issues.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does she view Hong Kong’s unique role on the Maritime Silk Road, and what are her expectations for Hong Kong’s development? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Connecting&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Global&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Friends Circle&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/ strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As one of the Maritime Silk Road Alliance cities, Hong Kong has geographical advantages. How should Hong Kong use the Maritime Silk Road to promote Hong Kong&#39;s economic development and connect the &quot;circle of friends&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ye Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Maritime Silk Road Association I founded was established in 2015. It is the earliest initiative after the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. Hong Kong organizations responding to the initiative. The Silk Road is a very important brand in China and a global brand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, China was the first to promote globalization and open up to the outside world. Zhang Qian&#39;s expedition to the Western Regions was a great expedition and built a bridge connecting the world. Hong Kong is geographically located in the south and is also a very important node on the Maritime Silk Road. Historically, Chinese merchant ships sailing from China or returning to the sea would usually wait for the northeasterly winds in winter to go out to sea via Tuen Mun, Hong Kong, then sail southward to the Indochina Peninsula and Nanyang Islands, and then to India and the Persian Gulf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Silk Road is a very important cultural symbol and more soft power should be used to promote it to young people. For example, we arrange free movies such as &quot;Xuan Zang of the Tang Dynasty&quot; for the audience to enjoy, telling the history of exchanges between businessmen who brought Chinese sericulture to the Western Regions and also brought some grape products from the Western Regions to China. Use this soft power to help Hong Kong young people understand China&#39;s great development history and profound cultural heritage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another characteristic of Hong Kong society is that many overseas Chinese, including many large Southeast Asian families, have branches in Hong Kong. The relationship between Hong Kong and Southeast Asia is very good. For example, most of the people in the Philippines are Fujian people, there are Fujian and Teochew Hakka people in Singapore, and there are also many Teochew people in Thailand, and business exchanges are very frequent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think we should establish an association and alliance to connect the provinces and cities along the Maritime Silk Road and Southeast Asian countries. When we founded it, we hoped to work more on connecting people and educate young people in Hong Kong to understand China&#39;s great history and culture. Therefore, some important activities of the association will arrange for some young college students to travel to countries in the Maritime Silk Road region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this the &quot;Zhang Qian Plan&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yip Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, learn from Zhang Qian’s brave pioneering spirit. When we were founded, the president of the Dutch Chamber of Commerce was very interested. The end point of the “Belt and Road Initiative” is Rotterdam in Europe, so he was also interested in joining. We have also arranged for college students to go to Guangxi and Guangdong in the Mainland, as well as Southeast Asian countries, such as Thailand, Malaysia, and Singapore. We also went to Djibouti in East Africa and London in Europe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the invitation of a small island in Greece, we arranged for teachers in charge of Chinese culture to go to Greece during the summer to promote Chinese culture and teach Chinese, which was also very popular. However, due to the epidemic, it stalled for three years. This year we restarted and received support from many companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At its peak, this plan sent a hundred students out. Approximately how many people are there this year? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ye Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are at least a hundred people this year. Because many Chinese and foreign companies have successively participated in and supported this program, college students have the opportunity to study, practice, and broaden their horizons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to the &quot;Zhang Qian Plan&quot;, the Maritime Silk Road What other thoughts does the association have on its work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ye Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We have conducted many forums, including forums in different countries and Southeast Asian countries. Our goal is to expand our circle of friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Soft power” promotes Chinese culture&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nowadays, the Bay Area is becoming more and more integrated and interactive. As the chairman of the Maritime Silk Road Association, what are your relevant plans and assumptions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sandra Yip: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Chief Executive Lee has held the first Guangdong-Hong Kong study conference since taking office, which will strengthen the exchange of technology, finance and talents. Cultural enhancement and exchange are also very important. Macao is part of the Maritime Silk Road, and we also want to strengthen cooperation with Macao. At the same time, we hope to arrange more students to study and inspect in the Greater Bay Area in the future to deepen their understanding of Lingnan culture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now Hong Kong students’ understanding of the culture of the Maritime Silk Road , including the familiarity and understanding of Chinese traditional culture, to what extent?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sandra Yip:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it is a pity that it is from Hong Kong Educational reform. I think the education reform launched in 2009 went the wrong way. Just like Taiwan, it greatly reduced the elements of Chinese culture. Because Chinese history is not a compulsory course, only 5,000 of the more than 50,000 college entrance examination candidates study Chinese history, fewer than 5,000 study world history, and only 2,000 examinees study Chinese cultural classics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to a British school, but I also read many classics when I was a child, including a little bit of &quot;The Classics and History&quot;, but most of today&#39;s students have never been exposed to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We arranged for young people to watch the popular movie &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; during the Spring Festival in Mainland China for free, but they did not know the historical background in which the story took place, and the response was average. So I think there is a problem with education, but now we have strengthened the education and teaching of Chinese historical classics, strengthened the teaching of Chinese history and national conditions education, these are of very important significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The future of Hong Kong is inseparable from China&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the head of the Huixian Think Tank, he is also the head of the Maritime Silk Road Association. He is also a legislator and former director of the Security Bureau. How do you see the future of Hong Kong through integrated identity? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sandra Yip: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many Hong Kong people don’t understand, but more and more people are understanding and awakening. In fact, more than 20 years ago, before Hong Kong returned to the motherland, Singapore Prime Minister Lee Kuan Yew visited Hong Kong and said, &quot;The future of Hong Kong is inseparable from China.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, Hong Kong and the country We go together through thick and thin. Therefore, we are also very grateful to the country for its continuous support for Hong Kong. Hong Kong’s stable and safe situation today is hard-won. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, although the National Security Law quelled the riots in 2019, there are still some hostile forces ready to move in Hong Kong, so we still need to be vigilant. Hong Kong has yet to legislate Article 23 of the Basic Law, while Macau completed this work in 2009. Therefore, Chief Executive Lee has stated that this is a very important and priority task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the crises and opportunities in Hong Kong?&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yip Liu Shuyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China has a history of more than 5,000 years. The country has a very ancient side and a very modern and advanced side. For example, the movie &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot; fully reflects China&#39;s development in science and technology, including its extraordinary achievements in aerospace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We need to introduce more to the young people in Hong Kong China’s achievements in all aspects. Now there is the Palace Museum in Hong Kong, which is a very important communication carrier. In addition, Hong Kong has also held exhibitions such as the &quot;Sanxingdui&quot;. I hope that more of China&#39;s modernization achievements will be displayed in Hong Kong in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the mainland’s cultural soft power is very powerful. Nowadays, many young people, including some studying abroad, also like to watch mainland TV series. Top mainland idols also have a market in Hong Kong, and their standards are very high. Relatively modern street dance and other performances are very popular among young people in Hong Kong. I also hope that Hong Kong&#39;s cultural performance groups will have the opportunity to perform in the mainland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I heard that during the Spring Festival this year, there was a very popular movie &quot;The Vengeful Lawyer&quot;, which is a legal film and very popular in the Mainland, so I look forward to more cultural exchanges between Hong Kong and the Mainland in the future. Hong Kong is a center for cultural exchanges between China and the West. I hope that both the New Democratic Party and the Maritime Silk Road Association can make more contributions in this regard in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Super Contact&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;The main members of the New Democratic Party are basically elites and upper middle class. As the chairman of the New Democratic Party, how do you view the role of the New Democratic Party? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sandra Yip:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The New Democratic Party officially held its founding ceremony in Hong Kong on January 9, 2011. At that time, I was the only member of parliament. But in the 2021 general election, we won three seats, and we won one more seat in the 2022 by-election. So the New Democratic Party now has 6 Legislative Council members and 1 district councilor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different political parties have different representations. I founded the party because I felt that there were a large number of citizens in Hong Kong, such as middle-class citizens, citizens who had received education abroad, and citizens who were more Western-minded. They all loved the country and Hong Kong, but there was no political party to speak out for them. Therefore, when the New Democratic Party recruits these people, their educational level is also relatively high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lai Tung-kwok (former Secretary for Security) and I are former officials, so we have the support of many civil servants, including the disciplinary forces; Senator Yung Hoi-yan is a barrister; Li Zijing received higher education in the United States; Chen Jiapei Directly elected by region. Ho King Hong, who won a seat in the 2022 by-election, is the nephew of Mr. Ho Hau Wah, the former chief executive of Macau. He can help us strengthen our ties with Macau. Moreover, he also studied in the United Kingdom and the United States. He understands Western cultural values ​​​​very well and can help Hong Kong develop. The role of &quot;intermediary&quot; and &quot;super contact&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the establishment of the Hong Kong SAR government, you are the first female Secretary for Security. The current chief executive, Li Ka-chiu, was also the former director of the Security Bureau. Is there any kind of communication and cooperation between you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yip Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My relationship with the chief executive of the Li family is very interesting. When I was the Secretary for Security in Hong Kong, Li Ka-chao was the head of the Organized and Serious Crime Bureau. At that time, his nickname was &quot;The Detective&quot; because he was very thoughtful. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether he is the Secretary for Security or the Chief Executive, I have worked well with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before speaking in the Legislative Council, I will ask Li Jiachao some information to form a tacit working understanding and lay the foundation for current work cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chief Executive Li has a very good ability and is willing to praise his subordinates. When they perform well at work, I am willing to praise them and recognize their contributions. And he can unite civil servants, parliamentarians, and members of the Executive Council. So after Chief Executive Lee took office, we had a very good atmosphere. I think 2023 is really a year worth fighting for as the country&#39;s economy recovers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国内首部放生法规将生效：科学放生才是行善丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258752]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The first domestic local regulation specifically regulating the release of wild animals, the &quot;Guangzhou Wildlife Release Management Regulations&quot;, Will be implemented from November 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Releasing animals is a &quot;good deed&quot; in both Buddhism and Taoism. The Buddhist &quot;Brahma Net Sutra&quot; says, &quot;Buddhas should practice the act of releasing lives with compassion... If you see people killing animals in the world, you should rescue them and relieve their suffering.&quot; Taoist classics also include &quot;The Essay on Release of Life&quot; and &quot;The Seven Precepts on Killing.&quot; ” and other scriptures advising people not to kill but to release lives. There are many believers in Buddhism and Taoism in China, so there have been more and more releases of animals in recent years. However, unscientific and blind release will not only fail to bring benefits to the animals being released, but may also cause ecological disasters. It is necessary to regulate release activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The release management regulations formulated by the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Congress first stipulate that the release of all exotic species is prohibited, and lists the alligator gar, leopard catfish (commonly known as &quot;scavenger fish&quot;), Qi&#39;s Key species include tilapia, freshwater white pomfret, mosquito fish, Egyptian frogfish, Thai dace, giant snapping turtle, red-eared turtle (commonly known as Brazilian turtle), and American bullfrog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The release of these exotic wild animals may pose serious threats to native organisms. For example, the alligator gar is a ferocious carnivorous fish with a huge adult size, up to 3 meters. It is said that one can eat all the fish in a lake, and can even bite people. The alligator gar is native to southern North America, but in recent years it has appeared in many places across the country. This kind of fish has almost no natural enemies in domestic waters. Once it overflows in the wild, the consequences will be disastrous. Ruzhou Central Park in Henan once drained 200,000 cubic meters of lake water just to catch an alligator gar. Exotic species such as tilapia and scavengers will also seriously squeeze the living space of native organisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is probably not &quot;good&quot; to release one kind of animal, but bring disaster to other animals or even the entire ecology. In fact, the unauthorized release of alien species has been clearly defined as illegal or even criminal. The &quot;Biosecurity Law&quot; that took effect on April 15, 2021 stipulates that anyone who releases or discards alien species without approval shall be ordered to capture or retrieve the released or discarded alien species within a time limit, and shall be fined not less than RMB 10,000 but not more than RMB 50,000. fine. The Criminal Law Amendment (11), which took effect on March 1, 2021, stipulates that those who illegally introduce, release or discard invasive alien species, if the circumstances are serious, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years or criminal detention, and shall also or solely be fined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although some species are not from outside the country, releasing them into inappropriate locations may be counterproductive. China has a vast territory and many places have their own unique ecosystems. Species native to one place may not be able to adapt to the environment and die in other places. For example, fish that are suitable for living in warm waters will freeze to death in northern winter. Blindly releasing animals into an environment that is not suitable for their survival will not only make these animals unable to &quot;live&quot;, but will accelerate their death. Some people even take freshwater fish to the sea and release them. This is not releasing them, but killing them. The death of a large number of released animals will also cause environmental pollution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a possibility that native species in one place may become &quot;invasive species&quot; in another place, destroying the local native ecology. Such species from other ecosystems within the territory are essentially invasive alien species to the native ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Guangzhou’s release management regulations require that wild animals suitable for survival in the wild at the release site should be selected, and the number of releases should be strictly controlled without causing harm to the ecosystem. Regulations also require management departments to develop and publish a list of native wildlife suitable for release, from which the public can select species for release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the choice of species, the release site is also important. Inappropriate release locations, in addition to the possibility that the released animals cannot survive, may also bring danger to humans, such as releasing ferocious and poisonous animals in areas close to human activities. Some people once released venomous snakes and crocodiles in the park, and electric rays and moray eels on the beach, which seriously threatened the personal safety of tourists. To this end, Guangzhou’s release management regulations require the management department to delineate and announce areas suitable for release, and prohibit release outside the release area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The regulations also stipulate the consequences of illegal release. Those who release wild animal exotic species shall be punished in accordance with the provisions of the Wildlife Protection Law; those who release wild animals in places other than the release area shall be fined not less than 2,000 yuan but not more than 10,000 yuan; those who may cause damage to the ecological environment shall be ordered to capture them within a time limit. If damage has been caused, a fine of not less than RMB 10,000 but not more than RMB 100,000 shall be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Releasing animals is &quot;good&quot; in religious concepts. However, blind release may not be a good thing, and may even cause serious harm to the released animals themselves, other creatures, the ecological environment, and people. In that case, it is not doing good, but doing evil. It is necessary to regulate the release of animals. Publicity should be strengthened to popularize the knowledge of scientific release, and law enforcement should be strengthened to punish illegal release behaviors to avoid serious damage caused by blind release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一位34岁的也门人，在三亚开了两家“万亿级”公司]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258780]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/Wm2jjWukGfmx50lErAsIuDMgTiDL8oeQrW33PL1X.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/Wm2jjWukGfmx50lErAsIuDMgTiDL8oeQr W33PL1X. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254328&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sanya city scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four &quot;Big Mac&quot; companies have emerged in Sanya, with registered capitals of up to 950 billion euros (approximately 7 trillion yuan), far exceeding Hainan Province’s GDP in 2022 (681.822 billion yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System, these four companies are: Brand New Concept (Sanya) Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Brand New Concept), Wansheng Zhaoye (Sanya) Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Brand New Concept) (referred to as Wansheng Zhaoye), Lianou Honghan (Hainan) Industrial Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lianou Honghan), and Minhong (Sanya) Technology Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Minhong Technology). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were incorporated between September 25, 2023 and October 8, 2023, and their registered addresses are on the same floor of the same building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These four companies have other similarities. For example, their shareholders are all overseas companies, but their registered capital is small. After the equity penetration, the controlling shareholder of the two companies is the same, a Yemeni living in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Main investment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the national enterprise credit information disclosure system, New Concept, Wansheng Zhaoye, Lianou Honghan, and Minhong Technology were established respectively On September 25, 2023, October 7, 2023, October 8, 2023, October 8, 2023. 4家公司的经营范围都包括“以自有资金从事投资活动；自有资金投资的资产管理服务；创业投资（限投资未上市企业）”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yuchen, director of Beijing Jinliu Law Firm, told Southern Weekend reporters that a company&#39;s high registered capital can improve the company&#39;s credibility to a certain extent and show that the company has relatively strong economic strength, which is conducive to attracting investment. investors and customers. Secondly, companies with high registered capital will have certain advantages when participating in some large-scale projects, bidding and other activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Yuchen also pointed out that if the registered capital is too high, there will be certain legal risks. First of all, if the registered capital is falsely high but the actual operating capabilities are not strong, it may cause the company&#39;s financial situation to be strained and affect the company&#39;s normal operations. Secondly, it will increase the risks for shareholders. For example, if the actual capital contribution is not made in accordance with the commitment of subscribed capital, the relevant shareholders may bear corresponding liabilities within the scope of subscribed capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that when a company sets its registered capital, it should take into account not only the need to improve the company&#39;s credibility, but also its own financial capacity according to its actual situation, and avoid falsely reporting registered capital. legal risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to having similar registration times, the four companies have the same registered addresses, all located on the 10th floor of the Glory Century Building, Yingbin Road, Jiyang District, Sanya City, Hainan Province. According to the Hainan Free Trade Port Investment and Talent Promotion Network, the Glory Century Building is a commercial office building with a total area of ​​20,000 square meters. Tianyancha shows that there are 95 companies with registered addresses in the Glory Century Building, including travel agencies, law firms, educational institutions, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, according to industrial and commercial information, the names of managers of Wansheng Zhaoye and Minhong Technology overlap. The general manager and financial person in charge of Wansheng Zhaoye is &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;, and the legal representative and executive director of Minhong Technology are also named &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, 2023, Dejizhong (Hainan) Digital Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Dejizhong), a wholly-owned subsidiary of Lianou Honghan, was established. Dejizhong&#39;s registered address is also located in the Glory Century Building, and its registered capital is as high as 100 billion yuan. The general manager and financial person in charge of Dejizhong is also &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;. The supervisor of Dejizhong is named &quot;Li Ping&quot;, which is the same name as the general manager and financial director of Minhong Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legal representative and executive director of the new concept is Li Yuyu. On October 16, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter called Li Yuyu&#39;s phone number shown on Tianyancha. The other party hung up the phone after learning that the reporter wanted to know why the registered capital was so high. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A shareholder is from the Middle East&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the national enterprise credit information disclosure system, Brand New Concept, Wansheng Zhaoye, Lianou Honghan, and Minhong Technology The shareholders are all registered overseas and are NGC Global Holdings Limited, Wansheng Zhaoye Co., Ltd., PINWHEEL INTERNATIONAL INVESTMENT LTD and TALIYA HOLDINGS GROUP PTE.LTD. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wansheng Zhaoye’s shareholders are registered in Hong Kong. Information from the Hong Kong Companies Registry shows that the English name of MILLIONS MEGA TRADE LIMITED is MILLIONS MEGA TRADE LIMITED. It was established on December 7, 2017, and its registered place is Des Voeux Road, Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paid-in share capital of Wansheng Zhaoye Co., Ltd. is only HK$1, and the shareholder and director is Taiwanese Cai Qinglong. Cai Qinglong also serves as the executive director of Wansheng Zhaoye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registration date of NGC Global Holdings Limited is September 6, 2023, which was established in the same month as the new concept of the subsidiary. The registered address of this company is in Kwai Chung, Hong Kong, with a paid-in capital of HK$10,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shareholder and director of NGC Global Holdings Limited is BASSAM TAHER ALI AL-SALAFI. His nationality is the Republic of Yemen and he currently lives in China. His mailing address is School of International Education, China University of Geosciences, Wuhan City, Hubei Province. International Education, China University of Geosciences) faculty apartment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, according to the company registration documents of PINWHEEL INTERNATIONAL INVESTMENT LTD, the shareholders and directors of PINWHEEL are also Yemeni BASSAM TAHER ALI AL-SALAFI, and the mailing address he left is consistent with the above. Registration documents also revealed that the Yemeni was born in 1989. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, after the equity penetration, the controlling shareholders of Brand New Concept and Lianou Honghan are both Yemenis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yemen is located at the southwest end of the Arabian Peninsula, adjacent to Saudi Arabia and Oman. It is a typical resource-based country, with oil and natural gas being its most important natural resources. Since 2023, a lot of Middle Eastern funds have poured into China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PINWHEEL&#39;s registered address is in the UK, with a registered share capital of 1,000 pounds. It was established on September 10, 2023, only one month earlier than its subsidiary Lianou Honghan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shareholder company of Minhong Technology will also be established in September 2023. According to the Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority of Singapore (ACRA), the registration date of TALIYA HOLDINGS GROUP PTE.LTD. is September 20, 2023, which was established half a month before Minhong Technology. The registration place is at Paya Lebar Plaza in Singapore. As of October 16, 2023, TALIYA&#39;s registered capital is SGD 1,000/USD and its paid-in capital is 0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TALIYA’s shareholders are Taiwanese CHEN and CHIH-SHENG. In addition to CHEN and CHIH-SHENG, the company&#39;s management also includes a Malaysian LIEW SHAN YEE and a Chinese GUAN XU. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[上热搜的“支原体肺炎”，究竟是啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258756]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, more patients with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection have appeared in hospitals across the country, mostly children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is mycoplasma? At what age is it easy for a child to get it? Can adults get it too? Let me reveal the secrets of Mycoplasma pneumoniae one by one! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bddf3c3d344dfbd96d0d82199ddeb4b5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bddf3c3d344dfbd96d0d82199ddeb4b5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254305&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;What is Mycoplasma pneumoniae? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is the smallest microorganism known in the world that can survive independently, between bacteria and viruses. Mycoplasma pneumoniae has no cell wall structure, like bacteria without a &quot;coat&quot;. Both 75% alcohol and chlorine-containing disinfectant (such as 84 disinfectant) can kill Mycoplasma pneumoniae. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/477dce0e66baefc1fe83bdbeb2bd445b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/477dce0e66baefc1fe83bdbeb2bd445b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254303&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is an important pathogen of acute respiratory infections in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae is divided into two subtypes, type I and type II. Currently, type I is the main prevalent subtype in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The population is generally susceptible to Mycoplasma pneumoniae, but it is more common in children and adolescents over 5 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year. The high incidence period of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in Beijing is from August to December every year, and usually reaches its peak around November every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How is Mycoplasma pneumoniae spread? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Patients with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and asymptomatic infections are the main sources of infection. The incubation period is 1 to 3 weeks, and they are infectious during the incubation period until symptoms subside for several weeks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly transmitted through droplets, and the pathogen can be carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing, and runny noses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;What are the symptoms of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The main symptoms of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection are fever and cough. Generally, the cough is severe, and the cough may continue for 1-2 weeks after the fever subsides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can cause upper respiratory tract infections, lower respiratory tract infections such as pneumonia, and extrapulmonary complications, such as autoimmune hemolytic anemia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is one of the main pathogens causing the high incidence of pneumonia in autumn and winter in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia is generally an interstitial pneumonia, so the clinical signs are often lighter than the imaging examination results, and after the clinical symptoms disappear, lung imaging examinations may still show inflammation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Mycoplasma pneumoniae does not have a cell wall, the familiar penicillins and cephalosporins, which are antibiotics that target the cell wall, are completely ineffective against Mycoplasma pneumoniae. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macrolide antibiotics, such as roxithromycin and azithromycin, are currently the first-choice treatments for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if citizens have fever accompanied by severe cough, they should seek medical treatment in time, identify the cause as soon as possible, standardize treatment, and avoid blindly taking medication on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;04&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There is currently no vaccine to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. The most important thing to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection is to develop good personal hygiene habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Try to avoid going to public places with dense crowds and poor ventilation, and wear a mask to protect yourself when necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Cover your mouth and nose with a tissue when coughing or sneezing, or cover it with your elbow or upper sleeve, and throw the used tissue into a covered trash can. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Pay attention to hand hygiene, use soap and hand sanitizer to wash hands under running water. If there is no running water, you can use alcohol-based hand sanitizer to wipe and disinfect your hands&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/5fdc5214073f81a1b9a66cf32966e8bd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/5fdc5214073f81a1b9a66cf32966e8bd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254304 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;4. During the high epidemic season&lt;/span>;, pay attention to indoor ventilation and ventilate for no less than 30 minutes each time to keep the air fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. Develop healthy living habits, exercise moderately, increase body resistance, and keep warm to avoid catching cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Schools, kindergartens and other key places should pay attention to ventilation and disinfection, do daily cleaning work, and strengthen health monitoring to avoid clusters of infectious &lt;span>; infections. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 08:25:57 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[纠正百年历史错误，美国宾大将追授林徽因建筑学学位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/47b57ec8864febb24d3be047bded52e0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;754&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/17/47b57ec8864febb24d3be047bded52e0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 15, local time, the official website of the University of Pennsylvania announced that the school will open on May 18 next year At the graduation ceremony of the Weizman School of Design, Lin Huiyin, a graduate of the school and a pioneer in Chinese architecture, was awarded a belated Bachelor of Architecture degree to express her commemoration and recognition. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the exhibition &quot;Building in China: A Century of Dialogues on Modern Architecture&quot; currently on display at the Penn Wharton China Center in Beijing, a long The 15-foot display board is eye-catching. It shows 23 Chinese graduates who studied architecture at the University of Pennsylvania between 1918 and 1941. After returning to China, these students became pioneers in opening up China&#39;s construction industry and architectural education, and devoted themselves to building China&#39;s rapidly developing cities and towns. , so he is known as the &quot;first generation of Chinese modern architects&quot;. At the center of the panel is Lin Huiyin, the only female among these students, and the only one who was not awarded a degree in architecture from Penn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the chief curator of the exhibition, Professor Lin Zhongjie from the Department of Urban and Regional Planning at the Weitzman School of Design at the University of Pennsylvania, Lin Huiyin and Liang Sicheng entered the University of Pennsylvania in the fall of 1924. At that time, they both wanted to pursue a degree in architecture. However, at that time, due to the fact that the required art courses including male model sketching and construction courses teaching construction techniques were not suitable for girls, the Department of Architecture at the University of Pennsylvania did not recruit girls, so Lin Huiyin had to register in the Art Department. However, she not only took all the architectural design courses, studied design theory, painting and architectural history, but also served as a teaching assistant in architectural design. Her academic performance was better than that of most of her male classmates. On her transcript, many classes received &quot;Excellence&quot; ( Distinguished) rating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China, Lin Huiyin and Liang Sicheng worked together and made great contributions to reshaping China&#39;s architectural history, education and practice. “当你来到美国时，每个人都知道弗兰克·劳埃德·赖特（Frank Lloyd Wright）。而当你去中国时，每个人都知道林徽因和梁思成。”韦茨曼设计学院城市与区域规划系城市研究与教育教授基尼·伯奇（Genie Birch）说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1934年，宾大建筑专业才开始招收女生。自此，美术学院（韦茨曼设计学院在20世纪的原名）为之前在宾大学习建筑学的女性补颁建筑学学位，其中包括费城城市建设部第一任女主任乔治亚娜·波普·伊特曼（Georgiana Pope Yeatman）。但是，林徽因的情况一直被忽视，即使她完成了比同时期其他女学生更多的建筑学课程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“从当时的记录来看，很明显林徽因想要学习建筑并成为一名建筑师，并且她后来也在这一领域取得了巨大成功。”韦茨曼设计学院院长兼佩利讲席教授弗里茨·斯坦纳(Fritz Steiner)从2022年对林徽因的学位发起了调研和审阅程序，“随着我们研究的不断深入，她没有被授予学位的原因很清楚，就是她的女性身份。这是一个历史遗留错误，是时候来纠正它了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6297d1bb86516148ed8689a960d73cfd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6297d1bb86516148ed8689a960d73cfd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得知宾大决定追授林徽因学位的消息后，她的家人都表达了骄傲、感激和喜悦的心情。 “母亲百年之后能够得到学校这种承认，让我想起她当年选择这个专业的勇敢与坚定。她少年伊始就认定了建筑学，立志成为新一代女建筑师，她满腔热情地引导&#39;鼓动&#39;父亲梁思成和她一起爱上并选择了建筑学专业，从此她一生忠于自己的选择，并且为了她的选择不惜牺牲一切。”林徽因的女儿梁再冰感慨道，今天，在林徽因的墓碑上，丈夫梁思成铭刻的“建筑师林徽因”，可以说是对她一生的高度概括和总结。 “作为她的后代，我们钦佩并欣赏她在追求艺术梦想时的无畏精神。”林徽因的外孙女于葵表示，宾大选择在林徽因诞辰120周年之际，也是她入学100周年之时，为她追授建筑学位，将为后来人，特别是女性追求梦想注入更多的希望和力量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>