<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[胡服骑射：五百里国运浮沉丨古国多少事④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257358]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The distance from Handan to Gaoping is about five hundred miles. A country, just within these five hundred miles, has staged the ups and downs of its national destiny from rise to decline, from glory to annihilation. Sometimes, history can not only be examined with time, but also measured with space...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Congtai&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Climb high and have a bird&#39;s eye view, the lake lingers. In early autumn, the leaves of the wood are slightly yellow, and under the morning sun, their slender shadows wade across the lake and fall towards the square tower. The tower and the corridors at both ends are shaped like a giant bow. ——This reminds people of the several-meter-high statue in the square a few hundred meters away, also holding a bow. What&#39;s even more interesting is that when I walked into the blue-brick paved terrace, I saw that there was also a statue in the corner of the terrace, depicting the same person, also holding a bow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This man was once the master of this square tower, this city, and this vast land. He is the founder of the glorious history of Zhao State: King Zhao Wuling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/SUG0kgzgaydIkLLurgUzAZf3TVhKEoQy8BrWm0hb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1370&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/SUG0kgzgaydIkLLurgUzAZf3TVhKEoQy8BrWm0hb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of King Zhao Wuling in Congtai Square, Handan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During my visit to the Zhao ruins, I was reminded several times of British scholar John Keegan&#39;s conclusion in &quot;History of War&quot;: Kings are created by great war horses. Although he is talking about the king of the West, King Zhao Wuling, the Eastern monarch, was also created by war horses. Of course, in addition to the war horse, there is another thing that must be added, and that is the bow in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three families were divided into Jin, and Zhao State had the largest territory and was also the most remote. Its main territory is in central and northern Shanxi, northern Henan, and southern Hebei. When talking with Fei Yi, King Wuling of Zhao said, &quot;Today, our country has the river and Boluo River in the east, which is shared with Qi and Zhongshan... From Changshan to Dai and Shangdang, there are the borders of Yan and Donghu in the east, and the borders of Donghu in the west. Bordering Loufan, Qin and Han.&quot; - A section of the ancient Zhangshui River in the eastern part of Zhao State bounded by the Yellow River and Boluoshui (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; in present-day Hebei Julu&lt;/span>;) serves as the border with Qi State and Zhongshan State; from Changshan to Daijun and Shangdang, it borders Yan State and Donghu State to the east, and Loufan, Qin State and South Korea to the west. From this point of view, Zhao was surrounded by the Qi, Zhongshan, Yan, Han, Qin and other princes, as well as the Donghu, Loufan and other tribes. If Daliang, the capital of Wei, is a city with four wars, then Zhao State is even more unfortunate. The entire country is a country with four wars - enemies are eyeing on all sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to achieve long-term peace and stability with strong enemies around. Especially under the law of the jungle where the strong bullies the weak and the masses bully the mob. King Wuling of Zhao sighed sadly all night long. He said, &quot;Today Zhongshan is in my heart. There are Yan in the north, Hu in the east, Linhu and Loufan in the west. If there are no strong soldiers on the border of Qin and Han, the country will be destroyed. What can I do?&quot; ?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you are poor, you want to change. This is the driving force for the princes in the Spring and Autumn and Warring States periods to compete for reform and self-improvement. King Zhao Wuling was no exception. So, there was Hufu riding and shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boundary between the monsoon area and the non-monsoon area is also the 400 mm equal precipitation line, which runs through the northern border of Zhao State. Zhao State is at the end of agricultural civilization and adjacent to nomadic civilization, especially Dai County of Zhao State. , and even closer to the nomads. The advantage of this proximity is that Zhao can obtain horses more easily than other princes. Before the industrial revolution, horses were mankind&#39;s most powerful and reliable source of power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The disadvantages are also obvious. Once the climate becomes dry and the pastures wither, it will be difficult for the nomads in non-monsoon areas to survive, and they will have no choice but to go south to plunder. At the beginning of the founding of Zhao State, it often faced intrusions from Donghu and other tribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reforms of King Wuling of Zhao surprised the people at the time - he ordered to learn from these barbarians who often invaded Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speed and maneuverability of horses are not only incomparable to humans, but also to chariots. Moreover, in the era of King Zhao Wuling, the early aristocratic competitive chariot battles had evolved into a bloody and cruel life-and-death fight. The bulky chariots and the war ethics of not drumming and not rowing had long been unable to meet the needs of the times. Therefore, the heavy infantry represented by Wei Wuzu of Wei State came to prominence. However, the hoplites marched too slowly and had insufficient impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What King Wuling of Zhao thought was that if the soldiers were allowed to ride on flying horses like the Hu people, and shoot and charge on the horses, the mobility and flexibility of the army would be greatly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest problem is that the Chinese clothes are not suitable for riding horses. During the Warring States Period, the clothes of the various vassal states of the Huaxia tribe were generally the same. Today we generally refer to clothes as clothes. At that time, clothes meant upper garments and Shang meant lower garments. There are types of jackets, such as jacket, brown, coat, fur, robe and so on. Shang is a bottom garment, similar to a skirt, and is the same for both men and women. There is another type called Shenyi, which means the clothes and clothes are connected together, which is equivalent to the dress in later generations. ——As you can imagine, whether you are wearing a skirt and robe or a dress, it is really difficult to ride a horse, or even gallop on a horse, and perform various complex and difficult movements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how did the nomads do it? It turns out that their clothes are different from those of the Chinese people. The main features of the Hufu of the nomadic people are a short jacket with narrow sleeves and crotch trousers. The former is convenient for archery and the latter is convenient for horseback riding. In addition, the shoes of the Chinese people are made of cloth, while the shoes of the Hu people are made of leather. Leather boots are naturally more suitable for outdoor sports than cloth shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When King Wuling of Zhao disregarded many objections, including from his own uncle, and vigorously promoted Hufu riding and archery, he was like a magical magician who in the blink of an eye transformed the remote and weak Zhao country. Rising powerfully at a speed that dazzled the princes. The first real cavalry in Chinese history was born. The flying cavalry caused a dimensionality-reducing blow to the cumbersome chariots - from a historical perspective, King Zhao Wuling&#39;s Hufu cavalry not only marked China&#39;s transition from the era of chariot warfare to the era of cavalry warfare, but also meant that Hufu&#39;s It has become the common clothing of Chinese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on the cavalry, Zhao conquered the three Hus. &quot;King Lin Hu offered his horse&quot; and &quot;Xiang Zhao Gu took control of Hu and sent his troops.&quot; Zhao State&#39;s control of Sanhu means that it can continuously obtain war horses, further increasing the strength of the cavalry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is particularly important is that after conquering Sanhu, Zhao State annexed Zhongshan, which lay across the middle of Zhao State and blocked Zhao State from the north to the south. In order to destroy Zhongshan, King Wuling of Zhao used troops several times. Zhongshan was weak and Zhao Guo was strong, so Zhongshan had to constantly cede territory to seek peace. After each time of ceding territory and seeking peace, Zhao became stronger and Zhongshan became weaker. Entrusting one&#39;s own safety to bribing the enemy would only make the enemy more greedy. A few years later, the Zhao army captured the capital of Zhongshan. The last king of Zhongshan was exiled and Zhongshan died. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With Zhongshan destroyed, Zhao State has solved its inner problems, and there are no more obstacles in the north and south territories. Moreover, although Zhongshan is weaker than the Seven Kingdoms, it is also a country of thousands of chariots, and Zhao&#39;s national power has greatly increased due to this. &quot;Warring States Policy&quot; said: &quot;Zhongshan is five hundred miles away, and Zhao is good at it alone. After his success and fame, he has become a vassal, and no one in the world can harm him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After rapid expansion, Zhao&#39;s territory reached its peak: &quot; It reaches Yan and Dai in the north, and Yunzhong and Jiuyuan in the west.&quot; Every inch of territory captured from the enemy echoed with the crisp sound of horse hooves and the long cry of powerful bows. With the cavalry pouring into the enemy formation like a tide as the background, Zhao State ushered in its unprecedented glorious years...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Handan in early autumn, the wind was a bit cold. In the afternoon, people came and went in Congtai Square, and the tall statue of King Zhao Wuling cast a heavy shadow. Congtai was completed more than two thousand years ago. The Congtai at that time was far larger and more spectacular than the Qing Dynasty building I see now. The main function of Congtai was for King Zhao Wuling to review troops and enjoy singing and dancing. In the pre-Qin Dynasty, when buildings were generally low, tall towers stood on the vast plains, which were symbols of the king&#39;s authority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With millions of people looking up to him, King Zhao Wuling ascended the Congtai step by step. This aloof king becomes even more mysterious and majestic because he is far away from all living beings. When the rapidly expanding territory and invincible cavalry made Zhao the only country among the princes that had the strength to compete with Qin, King Wuling of Zhao, who was looking forward to his glory, looked at the people in the audience who would give him orders at any time. And when the soldiers are stained with blood, their ambition to conquer the world seems to be surging like a spring tide...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 02/23/QEreryEQMOEb9mCKtYQkcNHIeg5xtuTanyqIesQd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1428&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/QEreryEQMOEb9mCKtYQkcNHIeg5xtuTanyqIesQd. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Handan Ancient Congtai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sand Dunes&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 298 BC, in Xianyang, the capital of Qin, King Zhao of Qin, who had reigned for ten years, received an envoy from Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The envoy’s temperament and speech surprised King Qin Zhao. After the messenger said goodbye, the more he thought about it, the more he felt something was wrong: this was definitely not an ordinary messenger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Qin Zhao sent people to investigate and found out that the envoy had returned to Zhao. However, some of the envoy&#39;s entourage had not yet had time to leave. After questioning the entourage, their answers surprised King Zhao of Qin and his ministers: the envoy &quot;whose appearance was very majestic and unworthy of a human minister&quot; turned out to be the father-in-law of the State of Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called father-in-law is Zhao Yong, the former king of Zhao State - later given the posthumous title of Wu Ling and known as King Zhao Wuling in history. The year before, King Zhao Wuling passed the throne to his son Zhao He, calling himself the master father, equivalent to the supreme emperor in later generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the father-in-law of Zhao go to Qin in disguise to see the King of Qin? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that before the annexation of Sanhu and the destruction of Zhongshan, between Zhao and Qin, only a small part of the southwest of Zhao State and the northeastern part of Qin State bordered. If the princes want to attack Qin, they must go west through Hangu Pass in the east of Qin. However, Hangu Pass is easy to defend and difficult to attack. The princes rushed thousands of miles, but they were unable to do anything to Qin who had one man to guard the pass and ten thousand men to open it. As Zhao State occupied Yunzhong and Jiuyuan, the situation quietly changed dramatically: Yunzhong and Jiuyuan were in the north of Qin State, which meant that Zhao army could move from north to south and from the north of Qin State to the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is what King Zhao Wuling envisioned. In order to investigate the national conditions of Qin, he took the risk to go to Qin by pretending to be an envoy from Zhao. Two thousand years later, another emperor who was thousands of miles away also disguised himself like King Wuling of Zhao and went deep into neighboring countries to investigate. This man was Peter of Russia. Emperor. In order to make the backward Russia strong, Peter the Great disguised himself as a sailor and visited various countries in Western Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before going to Qin, King Wuling of Zhao met with the ministers in the palace and announced that he would pass the throne to his youngest son Zhao He, who was less than ten years old, and Fei Yi would be appointed prime minister. He called himself the father-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of King Zhao Wuling&#39;s inner Zen is to get rid of the specific domestic government affairs and devote all his energy to the war against Qin. Of course, he had another consideration in doing so: Zhao Zhang, the eldest son of King Zhao Wuling, was now an adult. According to etiquette, Zhao Zhang should be appointed instead of Zhao He. However, because King Wuling of Zhao once doted on Zhao He&#39;s biological mother Wu Wa, and Wu Wa had just passed away, the memory of Wu Wa and the love for his youngest son were intertwined in the heart of this passionate king. So, he decided to make Zhao He king. Zhao He was too young, so he hoped to let him enter the role as soon as possible by accommodating him, and teach him how to govern the world while he was still alive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, abolishing the elders and establishing young ones caused terrible consequences, and also made the rise of Zhao State like a flash in the pan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zhao Zhang was deposed, King Zhao Wuling named him Lord Anyang, but Zhao Zhang was still resentful of his father&#39;s arrangement. Moreover, the courtiers were also divided into two groups, some sympathized with Zhao Zhang and some supported Zhao He. At the critical moment, King Wuling of Zhao made another big mistake: when he saw his eldest son kneeling at the feet of his younger son as a minister, he felt pity for the eldest son&#39;s situation, and actually planned to divide the Zhao country in two and let the two The sons each became king. This idea was firmly opposed by Fei Yi and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Zhao Wuling&#39;s plan has not been implemented in time, and the conflict between the two parties has reached an irreconcilable point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tragedy finally happened in a place called Sand Dune. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sima Qian wrote about sand dunes three times in &quot;Historical Records&quot;. In other words, there have been at least three major historical events in the small place of Sand Dune: first, King Zhou of Shang built the meat forest wine pool; second, Qin Shihuang died of illness during his last tour; third, King Wuling of Zhao and his son committed suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzong is a county under the jurisdiction of Xingtai City, Hebei Province, about 70 kilometers away from Handan City. In Dadai Township, northwest of Guangzong County, there is a pair of towers near the highway. Behind the towers, there are two steles with the words: Sand Dune Platform Ruins. Behind the monument, a fence seals a mound, which is the ruins of the Sand Dune Palace passed down through the ages. From the Shang Dynasty to the Qin Dynasty, although the fate of heaven changed and the emperor changed like a lantern, a palace has always been built here. Nowadays, in the wilderness and wilderness, the grass grows and crows fly, and there is no sign of the palace. Only in the small woods on the side, a group of dirty goats were chewing on the withered grass like wires. The shepherd was sitting on the stone, with the same expressionless face as the goats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Zhao Wuling wavered between his two sons, which was an unprecedented disaster for him and his country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 295 BC, King Wuling of Zhao held a court meeting in the Sand Dune Palace. Zhao Zhang and his followers launched a mutiny. Fei Yi was killed. Zhao He escaped under the protection of General Gao Xin, and the people who supported Zhao He were well prepared. Gongzi Cheng—Gongzi Cheng was the uncle of King Wuling of Zhao and had firmly opposed Hu Fu’s riding and shooting—rushed troops from Handan and surrounded the Sand Dune Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the situation was over, Zhao Zhang fled into the palace, hoping to be protected by his father. However, Gong Zicheng and Li Dui killed Zhao Zhang. At this time, King Wuling of Zhao had lost control of the political situation. Prince Cheng and Li Dui neither dared to kill the king nor withdraw from the siege. Therefore, everyone in the palace was ordered to withdraw, except King Zhao Wuling, who was not allowed to leave the palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lack of food and drink, King Zhao Wuling had to eat young birds raw, and eventually &quot;starved to death in the Sand Dune Palace in more than three months.&quot; This heroic hero died in such a useless way in an empty palace in grief and anger. What decayed along with his body was Zhao&#39;s domination of the world and its glory like a meteor streaking across. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the solid foundation laid by King Zhao Wuling&#39;s reforms will continue to support Zhao for a long time. Since Qi and Chu were crippled, Zhao has become the most powerful prince outside Qin. Therefore, the descendants of King Wuling of Zhao can still rely on the legacy of his reforms to continue to deal with Qin: in Xianyang Palace, Lin Xiangru returned the intact jade to Zhao; at the Mianchi meeting, Lin Xiangru broke into Zunzu; outside the city, Zhao She defeated the Qin army—— All of this relies on the strength accumulated by King Zhao Wuling and Hufu since riding and shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this strength will gradually decline with the unfaithfulness of future generations and the ebb and flow of the national destiny, until a war breaks out five hundred miles away from Congtai...&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;h4>;Changping&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before going to Gaoping, I watched a video: On a cliff more than 20 meters long and half a meter high, the soil is inlaid with stones, like inlaid with stones. Densely packed human bones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of horrifying scene is not unfamiliar to Gaoping people at all. Over the years, a heavy rain or an infrastructure construction project may reveal a large number of white human bones. No one knew whose son, whose father, or whose husband they were. People only know that since ancient times, as a battleground for military strategists, Gaoping has buried countless corpses under the loess. Among them, just in the decisive battle between Qin and Zhao, the death toll on both sides may be more than 600,000. Today, the entire permanent population of Gaoping City is only 450,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaoping, also known as Changping in ancient times. During the Warring States Period, it belonged to South Korea. Among the seven countries, South Korea is the weakest, and it is adjacent to Qin. The sad fate of being beaten is almost destined. Shangdang, to which Gaoping belonged, is now located in Changzhi, Shanxi Province, southwest of Taihang Mountain, east of Taiyue Mountain, and north of Wangwu Mountain. &quot;It is the highest, so it is called Shangdang.&quot; The terrain here is high, and it looks condescending to the surroundings. There are four roads in the Taihang Eighth Routes that pass through the lofty mountains. Through it, it leads to the North China Plain in the east, Linfen Basin in the west, Luoyang in the south, and Taiyuan in the north. It has been a battleground for military strategists since ancient times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 262 BC, the Qin army captured Yewang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Qinyang, Henan&lt;/span>;), Shangdang and South Korea The main body was divided and became a lonely enclave. For this reason, South Korea had to agree to cede Shangdang to Qin in exchange for peace. However, the people of Shangdang did not want to be ruled by the tiger and wolf Qin, which was known for its cruelty. Feng Ting, the governor of Shangdang County, sent an envoy to the State of Zhao to request that 17 cities belonging to Shangdang be dedicated to the State of Zhao. The State of Zhao sent troops to defend Shangdang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The kings and ministers of Zhao had a debate over whether to accept the seventeen cities that fell from the sky. In the end, Zhao He&#39;s son Zhao Xiaocheng and King Zhao Dan couldn&#39;t refuse such a big temptation. Instigated by Pingyuan Lord Zhao Sheng, he accepted the Shangdang and sent heavy troops to defend it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the Shangdang was already in the bag, he did not expect that the State of Zhao would show up halfway, and the State of Qin would naturally not give up. Moreover, Fan Ju, the prime minister of Qin, believed that the main reason why Qin had captured a large area of ​​Chu&#39;s land before and forced troops to attack Daliang and Xinzheng was that Wei and Han were unable to fight back, but still failed to become the king of the world. yield. Therefore, we must occupy Shangdang and then attack the area west of Handan, the capital of Zhao State, to threaten the heart of Zhao State and force Zhao State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, one of the most famous battles in Chinese history - the Battle of Changping, broke out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Gaoping urban area, the Dan River flows through. Going up the Dan River, north of Gaoping City, there is a small village called Changping. Changping Village is the ancient Changping City. On both sides of the Dan River, the valley is flat, and further away, there are winding peaks on the east and west. In and around this valley, there are many place names that are reminiscent of the tragic battle that determined the fate of the country: Siege, Arrowhead, Baiqitai, Skull Mountain, Lianpotun, Jiangjunling... Find peace and quiet in such places When you visit ancient times, you can feel that history is not just written on the page, but also imprinted on the mountains and rivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The armies of Qin and Zhao each built camps along the mountains fifty miles to the left and right of Changping City. The Qin army was led by Wang Lu, and the Zhao army was led by Lian Po. Lian Po believed that the Qin army had high morale and intended to fight quickly. The Zhao army is weak and at a disadvantage, so it is best to build fortifications and hold on. Starting from July 260 BC, after several small confrontations between the two sides, Lian Po made Zhao Jun unable to move out by virtue of the favorable terrain. The Qin army was unable to fight and gradually lost its vigor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two armies have been in confrontation for more than two years. The Qin State began to implement counterintuitive tactics. Counterintuitive tactics are a common trick of the Qin State, and they often achieve miraculous results. Qin spies sneaked into the Zhao State and spread rumors. Claiming that the Qin army was really afraid of Zhao Kuo, not Lian Po. King Zhao Xiaocheng was originally dissatisfied with Lian Po&#39;s defensive stance and suspected that he was timid. When he heard the rumors, he believed them to be true. As the Qin people hoped, he removed Lian Po, who had experienced hundreds of battles, and replaced him with a paper warrior. Zhao Kuo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Qin Zhao was overjoyed to learn that Zhao Guo had changed his general. He immediately sent Bai Qi, known as the God of War, to Changping secretly to replace Wang Lu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tragedy is already unstoppable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zhao Kuo took office, he changed the rules of integrity and changed from defensive to offensive. Bai Qi pretended to be defeated and retreated, but then attacked Zhao Jun&#39;s supply line from behind and cut Zhao Jun into two unrelated parts - one part was the main force led by Zhao Kuo himself, and the other part was the left behind guarding the camp. Zhao Kuo&#39;s return route to the camp was cut off and he was surrounded by the Qin army, so he had to hold on to the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to kill the Zhao army, King Qin Zhao ordered a nationwide mobilization - all men over the age of fifteen were recruited into the army. It can be said that for the Battle of Changping, the Qin State almost devoted its entire country&#39;s strength to a desperate effort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Kuo was besieged and had no supplies. After a month and a half without food, there was even a tragedy in the army where soldiers killed each other and fed on corpses. Zhao Kuo organized elite breakouts several times, but they were all repelled by the Qin army. During the last breakout, Zhao Kuo went into battle in person, but was shot to death by a burst of arrows. The commander-in-chief was killed in battle and the army had been without food for a long time. The Zhao army had no fighting spirit and had to surrender to the Qin army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of Zhao troops who surrendered was as many as 400,000. Bai Qi believed that the Qin State could neither reorganize these Zhao soldiers into the Qin Army nor release them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tragic massacre happened like this. Of the more than 400,000 Zhao soldiers, all were killed except for more than 20 young men who were released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The figure of 400,000 was so huge that later generations doubted whether &quot;Historical Records&quot; had exaggerated. However, the numerous bones discovered continuously in the Gaoping area prove that the massacre actually happened. However, how many people died is an eternal mystery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Changping Battle Memorial Hall, there is a pit of corpses protected by glass. Through the glass, the layers of corpses glowed white. That day, there was no one else in the memorial hall except me. Gazing at the remains of those who died abnormally more than two thousand years ago, I seemed to hear the muffled sound of weapons hitting the flesh, as well as the desperate screams one after another...&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/EXiG7MlCUKRdWHYtFlxAnpwVCdVbfxsm64C088yE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1439&quot; height=&quot;960 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/EXiG7MlCUKRdWHYtFlxAnpwVCdVbfxsm64C088yE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhao State Coins from the Warring States Period collected by the Shanghai Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In the valley more than ten kilometers south of Changping Village, there is a small village named Gukou, which is said to be the place where Bai Qi killed prisoners. It is also known as Killing Valley, Weeping Head, and Province of Injustice Valley. In the village, there is a skull temple, and the Dan River flows slowly in front of the temple. This courtyard-shaped temple was built in the Tang Dynasty. According to historical records, during the reign of Emperor Zhongzong of the Tang Dynasty, Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, who was still driving away from Luzhou, passed by Changping. The mountains of skeletons left behind by the Battle of Changping made him very sad, so he ordered them to be collected and buried, and a temple was built to offer sacrifices. However, the Skull Temple I saw was rebuilt by the Qing Dynasty. In the main hall, Zhao Kuo and his wife are enshrined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surprisingly, there is also a small house in the temple, with a red and white sign hanging in front of the door: Roast Tofu House. Roast tofu is a special delicacy in Gaoping, also known as white meat. ——Because they hated Bai Qi for killing hundreds of thousands of Zhao soldiers, the people of Gaoping invented this kind of food: they used tofu as meat, and then mixed the tofu residue with minced garlic and ginger to make a juice, which was used as Bai Qi&#39;s brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a statue outside the Changping Battle Site Memorial Hall, which is still made of Zhao Kuo. Under the statue, there are eight words: empty talk will harm the country, but hard work will prosper the country. History silently warns future generations with cries, blood, tears and numerous bones. As for whether future generations will really learn the lesson, history has never been able to do anything about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/S6c4GwGZPNSL6jutwDgjJT6u8QGIhYQvavuMleQT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1458&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/S6c4GwGZPNSL6jutwDgjJT6u8QGIhYQvavuMleQT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old Handan Railway Station was demolished after it was decommissioned in 2018, including the statue of Hu Fu riding a horse and shooting in the square. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The disastrous defeat in the Battle of Changping was forty-seven years after King Wuling of Zhao was riding and shooting in Hufu ; Thirty-two years after the Battle of Changping, the Qin army captured Handan and Zhao died. At that time, no matter the high spirits of the military parade in Congtai, the desperate sigh of being trapped in the sand dunes, or the national mourning of the tragic defeat in Changping, they had all turned into smoke and smoke. The State of Zhao has also gone through its more than 170 years of ups and downs, and has been lost in the turbulent river of time...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;[Main reference books: &quot; &quot;Historical Records&quot;, &quot;Warring States Policy&quot;, &quot;Zi Zhi Tong Jian&quot;, &quot;Chinese Historical Atlas&quot;, &quot;Chinese War History&quot;, &quot;General History of Chinese Customs·Two Volumes&quot;, &quot;Handan City Chronicles&quot;, &quot;Guangzong County Chronicles&quot;, &quot;Gaoping County Chronicles&quot;]&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年诺贝尔生理学或医学奖揭晓！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258036]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 18:01:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 2, Beijing time, the Swedish Karolinska Institute announced that the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine would be awarded Katalin Karikó and Drew Weissman for their discoveries in nucleoside base modifications that enabled the development of effective mRNA vaccines against COVID-19. They will share the prize money of SEK 11 million equally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/e2fd64108e043ee3fdfa87b0032be35b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/e2fd64108e043ee3fdfa87b0032be35b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252943&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[夜游磁器口古镇丨指尖华夏④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257585]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At night, the scenic area of ​​Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, Chongqing has focused on &quot;night food&quot;, &quot;night nourishment&quot;, &quot;night appreciation&quot;, &quot;night fun&quot; and &quot;night shopping&quot; and other business formats, deeply exploring Chongqing&#39;s characteristics, striving to build a night-time economy and attracting many tourists. play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/57OkanvMQMYOKYvOkADBTgnNi0s4QSmHv3aA8cFi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/57OkanvMQMYOKYvOkADBTgnNi0s4QSmHv3aA8cFi.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town in Shapingba District, Chongqing City is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous, attracting many tourists. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/VY2GMvoB4MASoXdnYXT7dqBKwMxJmllQc0MaHquE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/VY2GMvoB4MASoXdnYXT7dqBKwMxJmllQc0MaHquE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Night view of Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/phbsrWVOJhSFbd9uvf9R0kaiOO2BpYXENT9wM57A.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/phbsrWVOJhSFbd9uvf9R0kaiOO2BpYXENT9wM57A.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Night view of Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/DCeJmye9kvL6DrmI7B46VIi3yVPjtnV2AydS7Cma.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/DCeJmye9kvL6DrmI7B46VIi3yVPjtnV2AydS7Cma.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous , attracting many tourists to come and play. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Rs0Juw5S6ZBlDbE0CKroYDN0NBHjaTFdx5xAgdGd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;728&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Rs0Juw5S6ZBlDbE0CKroYDN0NBHjaTFdx5xAgdGd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists dressed in Sichuan opera costumes in Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing Take photos in costumes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/0PQSnc5ef6CyDM1lf1tyYpzt81gzzokwiONrJtRT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/0PQSnc5ef6CyDM1lf1tyYpzt81gzzokwiONrJtRT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous , attracting many tourists to come and play. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王嘉男跳远摘金，“惊人一跃”后的卫冕之战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258034]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/02/Cb6yv52uGM0jve15u01uI2vlWW65BkgNwmgUqO9w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/Cb6yv52uGM0jve15u01uI2vlWW 65BkgNwmgUqO9w. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 1, 2023, champion Chinese player Wang Jianan (middle), runner-up India Contestant Sri Shankar (left) and third runner-up Chinese player Shi Yuhao at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 1 In the evening, at the men&#39;s long jump final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Wang Jianan was the last to appear. Everything was ready. He clapped his hands as if to cheer himself up, and there were cheers on the field. After a moment, he took a few steps back, started running, accelerated, got on the board, jumped, and landed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first jump was 8.22 meters, which was very close to his own Asian Games record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second jump was 8.15 meters; the third jump was 8.06 meters. The first three jumps all exceeded 8 meters, showing stable performance. Wang Jianan voluntarily gave up on the fourth jump to accumulate energy for the next two jumps, but the fifth and sixth jumps were not scored due to fouls. With his excellent performance in the first jump, he won the Asian Games championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this Asian Games competition, Wang Jianan continued his distinctive personal style: good results often appear in the first few jumps. In the qualifying round the day before, Wang Jianan was still recovering due to an injury to his front foot. He only jumped 1 jump in the qualifying round and advanced with a score of 7.76 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview after winning the gold medal, he said frankly: &quot;Coming here as the defending champion is quite stressful. I have never defended my title before. Last time in Budapest, as the defending champion, my performance was average. So this time I really hope to win the Asian Games gold medal, but I am also afraid that this gold medal will put too much pressure on myself, so I have been adjusting myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, more than a month ago, At the 2023 World Championships in Budapest, Wang Jianan jumped 8.05 meters in the first jump in the final, but he failed to exceed this score in five subsequent attempts. He failed to defend his title and unfortunately missed the podium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long jump tests explosive power, and the victory is decided in seconds. Behind it is the athletes’ years of training and hard work. Ups and downs are normal. What is difficult is to have the confidence to face success, and even more to have the courage to face failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3UocneDe9x73yhQsmADXWFxF5t4RW68db8QMFUBG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3UocneDe9x73yhQsmADXWFxF5t4RW68db8QMFUBG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2023, Chinese player Wang Jianan competed &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Genius boy, a blockbuster&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan is a typical &quot;genius boy&quot;. He was discovered to have talent in track and field sports when he was very young. He was born in Shenyang, Liaoning Province in August 1996. He participated in the Shenhe District Games in 2005. Although his performance in the 100-meter dash was average, he was spotted by Yang Keqiang, the coach of the Shenyang Sports School. Coach Yang saw Wang Jianan walking on the playground and found that although he was not very tall, he had long legs and a &quot;bumpy&quot; walk. &quot;He has the energy of an athlete, and I feel like he is a good prospect.&quot; At that time. Wang Jianan is still in primary school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, he lived up to the expectations of his enlightenment coach. Yang Keqiang commented that he &quot;trains very hard, is very smart, and has strong comprehension ability. Many technical moves can be adjusted after a few times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;At first, Wang Jianan was not a long jumper, but a decathlete, and his best event was the pole vault. At the age of 14, Wang Jianan entered the Xuzhou track and field team; at the age of 16, he was selected by the Jiangsu Provincial Sports Team to represent Jiangsu Province in the national indoor men&#39;s decathlon competition, scoring 7063 points. This is the second best result among world youth athletes in 2012: long jump 7.80 meters, 100 meters run 10 seconds 88, pole vault breakthrough 5 meters, high jump 1.94 meters - this was called a &quot;decathlon genius&quot; at the time &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan jumped 8 meters for the first time at the age of 16. He won the national long jump championship with a score of 8.04 meters. You know, this is a result that can only be achieved by a veteran who has been training for many years. Chinese men&#39;s long jump has been seeking breakthroughs since it broke the 8-meter mark in the early 1980s. However, most athletes have not made a splash on the international stage. Their best results were achieved in domestic or Asian competitions until Players such as Li Jinzhe began to appear on the international stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also allowed Wang Jianan to focus on long jump in early 2013 and was selected for the national team. &quot;I switched to long jump because of my love for track and field. I am a decathlete athlete, and I still love all track and field events. I always have a kind of self-confidence: I feel that no matter what I practice, it will not be a problem. I am not an ordinary person. , I can do it.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a &quot;genius long jump boy&quot; Wang Jianan, his journey has indeed been relatively smooth. Some people call him &quot;lucky,&quot; and he doesn&#39;t shy away from it. He felt, &quot;From winning the bronze medal at home in 2015 to creating the best ranking in history at the 2016 Rio Olympics, strength is the foundation, but my luck is better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2013, in Pudong, India At the Asian Championships held there, in the absence of China&#39;s &quot;first brother&quot; Li Jinzhe in the long jump, 17-year-old Wang Jianan won the long jump championship with a time of 7.95 meters. He had never even participated in the World Youth Championships. Qualification for the World Championships in Moscow. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 24, 2014, Wang Jianan, who was under 18 years old, became a blockbuster in Eugene, USA. He won the men&#39;s long jump championship at the World Youth Athletics Championships with a time of 8.08 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2015 Beijing World Athletics Championships, at the Bird&#39;s Nest competition, three players of the Chinese men&#39;s long jump team, Li Jinzhe, Gao Xinglong, and Wang Jianan, appeared in the final at the same time. At that time, someone exclaimed, &quot;The best era for China&#39;s long jump It&#39;s already here.&quot; 19-year-old Wang Jianan won the long jump bronze medal, becoming the first Chinese and Asian athlete to reach the men&#39;s long jump podium at the World Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this also puts pressure on Wang Jianan. &quot;To be honest, after winning that medal, my confidence did not increase significantly, but it put more pressure on me. This medal is the only Asian medal in 32 years, and I won it, and It was a score of 8.18 meters, neither high nor low. Did I think this score was convincing at the time? This led to my results in 2016 being not particularly good throughout the whole year. I felt that I was suppressed by the bronze medal. .&quot; In an interview with CCTV, he admitted that he was carrying a burden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 National Track and Field Championships and Asian Games Trials, Wang Jianan jumped 8.47 meters, which not only tied the men&#39;s long jump national record held by Li Jinzhe, but was also Wang Jianan&#39;s personal best. In the men&#39;s long jump track and field finals of the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games, Wang Jianan won the gold medal with an Asian Games record-breaking performance of 8.24 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/hlG2dACpPpI9xL1HZ1aEZYGboeSy1vRF9XUXdI3D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/hlG2dACpPpI9xL1HZ1aEZYGboeSy1vRF9XUXdI3D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2023, in the men&#39;s long jump final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Wang Jianan won the gold medal with a time of 8.22 meters&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hibernating after failure, reaching the top again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the smooth journey, there are injuries , there are also upcoming surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the 2016 Rio Olympics and the 2017 National Games, Wang Jianan underwent two knee surgeries on his left and right knees. When he learned that he had torn his meniscus, he even &quot;didn&#39;t want to practice anymore and wanted to retire.&quot; He took anti-inflammatory drugs for more than a month before he began to gradually improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next major blow to his career was his failure to compete in the Tokyo Olympics. At that time, Wang Jianan had high hopes and was the only athlete in the jumping department of the national track and field team with a medal mission. Although he got a spot to go to the Tokyo Olympics, he did not perform well due to running-in problems with his coach and great pressure. He only jumped 7.81 meters and missed the finals. &quot;It was also a big blow to me. I feel that all the problems arise from my own problems.&quot; He took all the responsibility on himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This blow did not defeat him. He summed up his experience, regained his confidence and prepared to fight again. &quot;How much worse could it be?&quot; he recalled that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next step was his &quot;amazing jump&quot; at the World Championships in Eugene, which made more people remember this Chinese face. Before heading to the World Championships in Eugene, Wang Jianan shared a calendar on his mobile app on social media: &quot;It has been 3,078 days since I joined the national team, 2,058 days have passed since the 2016 Olympics long jump final, and my first meniscus surgery has passed. 1928 days, 1565 days have passed since the second meniscus surgery...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Wang Jianan did not continue his past style. Until the last jump, his score of 8.03 meters was only ranked second. fifth place. On the big screen showing the results, the third place score was 8.15 meters. &quot;It&#39;s not very high. I think I should be able to sprint. Even if I jump with my head up, I can win a medal.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On July 17, 2022, after the last jump, he glided perfectly in the air and landed. He looked back at the sand pit and felt confident. When he saw the score of 8.36 meters displayed on the big screen in the arena, Wang Jianan squatted on the ground, covered his face and cried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/VBqSOdlm1LeWgX4cPeNrTmafyIaYCCjMlzec8A6L.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/VBqSOdlm1LeWgX4cPeNrTmafyIaYCCjMlzec8A6L.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 16, 2022, Wang Jianan won China&#39;s first ever World Championships men&#39;s long jump gold medal at the World Athletics Championships in Oregon, and became the first man in history to win a World Championships. The Asian athlete who won the long jump championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, 25-year-old Wang Jianan won the men&#39;s long jump final at the World Athletics Championships in Oregon With his final &quot;shattering leap&quot;, he broke the Asian record and won the championship. He became the first Chinese male athlete to win the field championship at the World Athletics Championships. He was also the fourth Chinese male athlete to win the field event after Liu Xiang, Wang Hao and Chen Ding. The Chinese male athlete who won the gold medal at the World Athletics Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan, who became famous in one battle, will have to face how to surpass himself and break the world record, but this is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lewis, a world-famous athlete and American track and field athlete, once forwarded an article on a social platform called &quot;Why is the world record for the long jump so difficult to break?&quot; The article mentioned: In 1968, Beamon set a long jump of 8.90 meters. World record, if Powell had not broken the world record with a score of 8.95 meters in 1991, then no one could come close to Beamon&#39;s score of 8.90 meters in 1968. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/6ybnrDlU8AxDOYAn5Ra5skfpKlbffXKimTaCIMxV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/6ybnrDlU8AxDOYAn5Ra5skfpKlbffXKimTaCIMxV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 24, 2023, in the men&#39;s long jump final of the 2023 World Athletics Championships in Budapest, Hungary, Chinese player Wang Jianan won fifth place&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 84 years, the world record for long jump has only been held by three people. Jesse Owens held it for 25 years, and Bob Bee Mon lasted 23 years and Mike Powell lasted 31 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recent World Championships in Budapest, Wang Jianan ranked fifth, and at the Hangzhou Asian Games, he finally successfully defended his title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the game, he mentioned, &quot;The result of 8.22 meters may be a little bit lower than my competition goal. Originally, I wanted to break my own competition record, but I was still 2 centimeters short. Next, I will still To find problems in the competition, the results of the World Championships in Budapest were not very satisfactory, and it also taught me a lesson. I hope to apply the experience of the World Championships in Budapest and the Asian Games to the Paris Olympics, so that I can achieve a relatively good result. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hardships will make you successful.&quot; He once said that he has always believed in this sentence, from the failure of the Tokyo Olympics to the leap to create an Asian record, and then to the successful defense of the Hangzhou Asian Games. , along the way, Wang Jianan himself is the best confirmation of this sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不受理“知假买假”，可能会有怎样的结果？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258016]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Market Supervision and Administration Bureau in a place in Sichuan issued a warning, strictly prohibiting profit-making activities such as buying fakes based on known fakes. Consumers make complaints and reports. The announcement stated that once a complaint is determined to be malicious, the Municipal Supervision Bureau will not accept it. At the same time, if the complaint is used for extortion, threats and intimidation, the complaint will be transferred to the police to investigate the criminal responsibility of the malicious complaint reporter. Not surprisingly, this &quot;letter of caution&quot; caused great controversy. The bureau later deleted the document from its social media accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time such an announcement has appeared. In recent years, many places across the country have issued similar announcements. The municipal supervision department stated that its purpose is to &quot;create safe and comfortable consumption and a good business environment&quot; and &quot;equally protect the legitimate rights and interests of consumers and business entities.&quot; However, it is the legal duty of the municipal supervisory department to supervise illegal goods such as counterfeit and shoddy goods. If &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot; is considered a malicious complaint and refused to be accepted, it is suspected of neglecting the performance of duties and administrative inaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Profit-making anti-counterfeiting&quot; is also commonly known as &quot;professional anti-counterfeiting&quot;. Its legal basis is mainly the relevant provisions of the Consumer Rights Protection Law, Food Safety Law, and Drug Administration Law. The Consumer Protection Law stipulates that if an operator commits fraud in providing goods or services, in addition to compensating the losses suffered by consumers, the amount of compensation should also be increased by three times the price of the goods or service fees. If the amount is less than 500 yuan, the compensation shall be 500 yuan, that is, &quot; If you give a false one, you will lose three.&quot; The Food Safety Law and the Drug Administration Law stipulate that if you produce food, counterfeit drugs, or inferior drugs that do not meet food safety standards, or you sell and use food that you know are not in compliance with food safety standards, or you know that they are counterfeit or inferior drugs, you are &quot;counterfeit.&quot; &quot;Ten for one&quot;, the minimum is 1,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these legal provisions, a group of &quot;professional anti-counterfeiters&quot; were born. They look for substandard goods, food and medicines in the market, and after purchasing them, they complain or sue in order to obtain three or ten times the price. Additional compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cracking down on counterfeit and shoddy goods and maintaining food and drug safety are the legal responsibilities of market supervision departments. However, the market is very huge, and it is difficult to detect all illegal activities solely relying on the power of market supervision departments. The purpose of punitive damages stipulated in the law is not only to protect the interests of consumers, but more importantly, to make the criminals who make and sell counterfeit goods pay a greater price through punitive damages, so as to curb the behavior of counterfeiting and counterfeiting. With the incentive of punitive damages, professional anti-counterfeiters also have greater incentives to discover counterfeit and shoddy goods and report them to regulatory authorities. In this sense, professional anti-counterfeiters are actually helpers to regulatory authorities. It is much more efficient to discover illegal activities through the clues they provide than it is for the regulatory authorities to find the needle in the haystack on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are indeed some people who actually engage in extortion in the name of fighting counterfeiting. For example, some people frame the situation first and then &quot;crack down on counterfeiting&quot;, placing expired food taken away in supermarkets and framing merchants for selling expired food. Some people deliberately hide the food that is about to expire in the supermarket. The supermarket fails to find out that it has not been collected in time. They wait until it has expired and then buy it, claiming for selling expired food. Some even failed to find problematic products and threatened merchants with reports to pay &quot;consultancy fees.&quot; These actions are no longer a crackdown on counterfeiting, but a &quot;black crackdown&quot;, which is illegal and criminal. It is necessary to crack down on these &quot;black crackdowns&quot;. However, for the majority of professional anti-counterfeiters who legitimately exercise their rights conferred by the law and demand compensation in accordance with the law, the regulatory authorities simply refuse to accept their reports and complaints because their anti-counterfeiting behavior is &quot;profit-making&quot;. There is no legal basis and they are suspected of neglecting to fulfill statutory obligations. Responsibilities may encourage the trend of counterfeiting and selling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The criteria for regulatory authorities to identify &quot;malicious complaints&quot; include purchasing the same product again after receiving punitive damages and then complaining. But if substandard goods are completely removed from the market after being discovered for the first time, how can professional counterfeiters buy the same substandard goods again? If you continue to sell substandard goods after being punished for the first time, but the regulatory authorities no longer accept subsequent complaints, will the counterfeit merchants be able to continue selling fake goods unscrupulously? Do such regulations protect consumers or counterfeiters? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that, at least in the field of food and drugs, the judicial system supports &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes.&quot; The Judicial Interpretation &quot;Provisions on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Law in the Trial of Food and Drug Dispute Cases&quot; issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2013 clearly states that for food and drug quality disputes, producers and sellers of food and drugs with quality problems shall use the consumer&#39;s knowledge to purchase fake products. If the defense is false, the court will not support it. That is to say, we support consumers to “know fakes and buy fakes.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a government department, the Market Supervision Bureau prohibits &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot; and considers it &quot;malicious&quot;, which is contrary to the regulations of the judicial organs. Once the counterfeiters are sued for administrative inaction, they will be sued in court. I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s inevitable that I&#39;ll lose. According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, a professional anti-counterfeiter once reported that many units in Guizhou, Yunnan and other provinces were selling counterfeit medicines. After the market supervision department verified it, they found that he was not buying for consumption purposes and was seeking improper benefits. He was refused a reward and he filed a lawsuit. The court ruled that the municipal supervisory department lost the lawsuit and he should be rewarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unscrupulous merchants selling counterfeit goods not only harm the interests of consumers, but also harm the interests of legitimate merchants. To &quot;optimize the business environment&quot; and &quot;protect the interests of business entities&quot;, we should crack down on extortion of enterprises and protect the interests of legitimate business entities. If there is a blanket ban on &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot;, it will only condone &quot;knowing about fakes and selling fakes&quot; and objectively protect the interests of unscrupulous businessmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[摇滚之城惹热议：中国哪儿人最把摇滚刻进DNA里？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fc790a5708bf0500e071a8465b07a524.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/25/fc790a5708bf0500e071a8465b07a524.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252071&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, cities such as Shijiazhuang and Xinxiang in Henan have also successively played the &quot;rock card&quot; and announced that they will compete for the city and hometown of rock. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Speaking of Shijiazhuang, the public may feel unfamiliar, but when it comes to some rock bands in Shijiazhuang, music fans are familiar with them. Many rock bands such as Universal Youth Hotel and Dawn&#39;s Leader have a certain connection with Shijiazhuang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How glorious was Chinese rock music?&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back at history, there have been several rock music in China. After ten years of development, rock music also has fertile soil. As early as the 1980s, with the reform and opening up and social changes, local rock music secretly sprouted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 1986, 24-year-old Cui Jian sang &quot;Nothing&quot; in a high-pitched and roaring voice at the Beijing Workers&#39; Gymnasium. When the passionate lyrics came out &lt;span>;, thousands of spectators in the audience sang and shouted loudly, and Chinese rock music began an unprecedented process. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Subsequently, a number of outstanding bands and musicians emerged one after another. The Black Panther Band, the Tang Dynasty Band, and the Stinger Band, which originated in Beijing and Xi&#39;an, came out of nowhere and successively released albums such as &quot;Black Panther&quot;, &quot;Dream Back to the Tang Dynasty&quot;, and &quot;Chinese Fire I&quot; with lightning speed. Set off a wave of Chinese rock music. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In that era when materials were still scarce, the albums of rock bands sold like crazy. The Black Panther Band&#39;s self-titled album &quot;Black Panther&quot; sold 1.5 million copies, and the Tang Dynasty Band&#39;s &quot;Dream Back to the Tang Dynasty&quot; sold 2 million copies, becoming a hit that is still difficult to match. Young people wear big waves, bell-bottom pants, and play these albums repeatedly with tape recorders, making it fashionable to listen to these rock music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994 is known as the peak year of Chinese rock music at that time. Dou Wei, He Yong, Zhang Chu, Tang Dynasty Band, etc. gathered in Hong Kong and performed a &quot;China&#39;s New Rock Forces&quot; concert that had nothing to do with the Hong Kong Philharmonic at the Hung Hom Arena, which represents the trend vane of pop music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage, with the sounds of &quot;Advanced Animals&quot;, &quot;Bell and Drum Tower&quot;, &quot;Flying Birds&quot; and other songs, in the audience, the audience from Hong Kong and all over the world watched again and again for more than three hours. He jumped up and down and roared until his throat became hoarse. After the concert, major media in Hong Kong used headlines to record this classic moment with &quot;rock soul, shocking Hong Kong&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/d5332f9dd68b222b6707f7425e603845.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/d5332f9dd68b222b6707f7425e603845.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252068 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Who is the hidden rock city in China&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Now, decades have passed since the 1990s, and the development of Chinese rock music has undergone tremendous changes. , the position of rock music is also changing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Beijing and Xi&#39;an, once the most important rock and roll venues, are showing a current situation of replacement of old and new. Rock seniors such as Cui Jian, Xu Wei, and Zheng Jun have become more epoch-making memories flowing in people&#39;s minds, while new bands such as Pain Yang Band, Black Sa Band, Xuan Band, and Island Mood have become the mainstream of current performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leaping cities of Shijiazhuang and Xinxiang, Henan Province represent the extension of rock DNA. In Shijiazhuang, local bands such as Universal Youth Hotel, Relativity Band, Small Town Spring, and Plasticine Band have emerged one after another. In particular, the birth of the Universal Youth Hostel, which combines rock, punk, folk and other elements, was born like a sharp blade. Songs such as &quot;Kill That Shijiazhuang Man&lt;span>;&quot; and &quot;Qinhuangdao&quot; can be called the secret codes of many music fans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In Xinxiang, Henan, the rock genes that once attracted Tang Dynasty, Samsara, Zero Point, Overload, etc. to perform are continued. Bands such as Little Pumpkin were also born in a small area. , Mad Doctor Band, Cyclops Band and many other bands that represent the power of rock music for the younger generation. In the local area, even the owner of a milk tea shop or noodle shop can put down his kitchen utensils and play a musical instrument at any time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the rock flavor of Shandong is permeated in various music festivals. Jinan Erli Music Festival, Rizhao Ocean Music Festival, Qingdao Phoenix Music Festival, Weifang Guochao Music Festival, Dongying Strawberry Music Festival, Binzhou Midi Music Festival and many other music festivals have also turned the release of rock elements into cultural life. daily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thousands of miles away in Chengdu, the land of abundance, is another important narrative venue about rock and roll. Whether it is Tang Lei’s tavern band or the founder of bands such as Sound Toy, Mr. Turtle, and Asura, they all have incomprehensible connections with Shu. Chengdu rock music has also continued to spread across the country starting from the live house on Yulin Road. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The possibility of the development of Chinese rock &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be found that today’s Chinese rock is no longer It is limited to a certain place, but has become popular among young people in more regions and cities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, influential and highly sung songs have quickly captured the hearts of young people, allowing young people in different cities to whisper and resonate with each other through music. On the other hand, with the popularity of music variety shows such as &quot;Summer of the Band&quot; and the holding of various music festivals starting in 2019, young people have become more aware of the connection between rock and music by watching competitions and attending events in person. charm, and also hatched more music fans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of music festivals, although there are old brands abroad such as Woodstock Music Festival, Glastonbury Music Festival and other very influential music festivals, Festival, but with the creation of rock cities in Shijiazhuang, Xinxiang and other places, as well as the urbanization and large-scale promotion of various music festivals, music festivals in China are gradually rising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strawberry Music Festival, Midi Music Festival, Simple Life Music Festival, etc. have gradually become well-known music festival brands. They have strong appeal and influence in the country and can attract audiences everywhere. Many music fans went to watch. In the future, it is not impossible to go abroad and cooperate with some foreign music festivals, or to host them in other cities in Asia, Europe and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, as the professionalization of rock and pop music increases, professional learning and training in modern pop music, including rock, has also taken shape. Midi Music School in Beijing &lt;span>; now offers a variety of majors. By teaching modern music courses covering pop, punk, rock, etc., students who like rock music can study systematically. The school has also produced Rock musicians such as Zhao Meng, bassist of New Pants Band, and Mao Chuan, lead singer of Escape Plan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, as a form of music and art&lt;/span>; expression, rock music has recorded the confusion, thinking and emotions of reality and contemporary young people in different social periods. . In the music atmosphere of the new Generation Z, the presence of rock and roll is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future of Chinese rock music, the collision and integration of cultures and creators from different regions will bring more possibilities to music and will also give birth to new &lt;span>; dazzling stars in the team of tomorrow. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花西子眉笔引发的行业审视：直播电商，成也主播，毁也主播？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258032]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor was live broadcasting products on the booth. Pictures and texts Unrelated. Interface News Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor broadcast live on the booth. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Interface News Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After briefly entering the live broadcast room, a domestic beauty brand established for more than two years decided not to enter the show again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is both a fame and fortune fair and a place at the forefront of the limelight. The most recent farce was on September 10, 2023, when super anchor Li Jiaqi criticized netizens while selling Huaxizi eyebrow pencil. The turmoil has been postponed to this day, and the Huaxizi brand has become the target of public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people in the industry are re-examining the sales ecology of anchors bringing goods. A brand manager Chu Shi (pseudonym) is also a melon-eater. For her, the high commissions and pit fees required by big anchors are difficult for small brands to resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;last straw&quot; that caused Chu Shi to give up the live broadcast was exactly a live broadcast. The brand invited a top anchor with tens of millions of fans, and the position fee was about 70,000 yuan, with an agreed sales guarantee of 210,000 yuan. They have high expectations and regard it as the &quot;most important event&quot; since its inception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end, the leading anchor only sold a few thousand yuan, and did not refund the corresponding amount according to the contract. Chu Shi called this incident a &quot;trigger&quot;. Although she felt that the business was unhealthy before, she was willing to abide by the rules of the industry. This time she was in the whirlpool and felt chilled: &quot;Given such a high commission, there are still pitfalls. For a bit fee, a brand like ours cannot play like that.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The brand went to the police station to report the crime, and then won the lawsuit through litigation. However, the refunded fees have not yet been received, and the anchor is still active in the live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“So much profit goes to the host”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For this new brand, the first “obstacle” to live broadcast admission sounds humble: identifying the reasons for rejection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu Shi and the others contacted thousands of anchors and bloggers. Chu Shi recalled: “In the first year, we really hoped to increase the brand’s exposure through some experts. I put a lot of effort into promoting it and its popularity. But the result is really not very good.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sending products to popular live broadcast rooms is the preferred way for small brands to gain popularity. Data from the live broadcast e-commerce industry blue book released by the China Institute of Metrology and other units show that in the first half of 2023, the sales of live broadcasts on key monitored e-commerce platforms reached 1.27 trillion yuan, with more than 110 million live broadcasts and more than 70 million live products. , the number of active anchors exceeds 2.7 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following the anchor&#39;s product selection process, they will communicate with the other party&#39;s business personnel and wait for feedback. If there is no feedback, it means it is inappropriate by default. It’s like rushing through the sand, “maybe less than 10% of anchors or business people will reply to us in this link.” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first Chu Shi would feel confused, not knowing where he was stuck. Later, the picture gradually became clearer, &quot;In fact, it is not the product at all, but the dissatisfaction with the price or commission.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that anchors would focus on promoting the same product in various categories, making it particularly difficult for new products to emerge. The products that were strongly promoted by the anchors were actually the ones for which the brand offered high commissions. “For example, there are several products we know that offer commissions of 60 to 70 points, and they have already sold to the top in that category. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;70% commission means that if a product sells for 100 yuan, 70 yuan will be given to the anchor. The remaining costs should cover product development, raw materials, packaging materials and other costs, as well as warehousing logistics, site and labor costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We think this business is very unhealthy.” Chu Shi believes that high commissions force costs to be reduced. “So much profit is given to the anchors. They charge such high commissions, but they do not Without creating corresponding social value and providing more jobs, the profits of upstream brands and the supply chain have been reduced. Brands can only continue to reduce costs, and their products will become worse and worse, and the treatment of employees will also be worse. It’s getting worse.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four or five years ago, she worked with anchors for beauty brands at the time, with commissions ranging from 20% to 30%. However, the live broadcast ecosystem gradually evolved. “From the year before last to last year, the commissions continued to increase. It’s rising. I don’t think it’s because the anchors are raising the price, it’s because the industry is too complicated, whether it’s beauty or live streaming, it’s all too complicated.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beauty is recognized as one of the most popular fields. Nanshan, co-founder of the beauty MCN organization May Beauty, also feels the same way. Although there is a lot of beauty traffic on the platform, there are also a lot of people entering the platform. &quot;I think it started to roll out in 2019 and 2020, and every year it is better than before. I kept curling more and more without stopping.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of the volume, the mechanism of the volume, the content of the volume, the capital of the volume... the prices of things of the same quality are constantly falling in the competition, but the commissions for the anchors are gradually increasing. &quot;I think this volume is good in all aspects.&quot; , product homogeneity is also very serious, and every price range is full of competitors.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang, director of Hangzhou Xijiang New Retail Research Institute and former deputy director of Alibaba Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that taking eyebrow pencils as an example, from the perspective of raw material processing fees, including factory delivery The cost plus tax may be less than 10 yuan. The biggest cost of cosmetics is sales expenses. Previously, this part included marketing and channel expenses, that is, advertising, celebrity endorsements, channel deduction fees, and profits from offline wholesalers and agents. Now, if you sell through live e-commerce, it is a direct retail. The most important ones are traffic fees, advertising fees, anchor commissions for bringing goods, and pit fees. &quot;These fees account for a very high proportion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out that the biggest problem with the current live broadcast sales system is the trend of low prices. “After the emergence of live broadcast e-commerce, China’s retail market has been turned upside down. Everyone is fighting for low prices. , If a company has no profits, it will have no money to do product research and development and innovation, and bad money may drive out good money.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Only care about three points: price, commission, and pit fee&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Price and gifts are the key points when attracting consumers to place orders in the live broadcast room. At this point, super The head anchor does have a higher say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Lei (pseudonym), the person in charge of a domestic brand who once sent products to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, told Southern Weekend reporters that Li Jiaqi’s pit fee one or two years ago was “not expensive,” “about 8. &quot;More than 10,000 yuan&quot;, the commission is 30 to 40%, which is almost the same as other anchors. But Li Jiaqi&#39;s prices are very low, even at prices the merchant himself has &quot;never sold before.&quot; &quot;He doesn&#39;t care how much you originally sold them for, he will only tell you &#39;how much I want to sell them for.&#39;&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;He will demand &#39;I am the lowest&#39;, but he will not tell you openly. He will only tell you a price to see if you can give it.&quot; Qiao Lei said that both parties It is also necessary to sign a price guarantee agreement to ensure that there will be no lower prices, including the brand&#39;s own live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This condition is almost harsh, but a large number of businesses are still willing to accept it. Even now, there are still small brands that are eager to get into the super live broadcast room and are waiting hard. Lillian (pseudonym) is the person in charge of branding and e-commerce at a start-up company that makes functional skin care products. For her, the road to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room has not yet been opened. “I have been following them for half a year, and I still have During the data review stage.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Super anchors such as Li Jiaqi (first from left) will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Like Li Jiaqi (first from left) Super anchors will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Chu Shi has come into contact with &quot;very few anchors who are truly professional.&quot; Brands provide product selling points, and anchors follow the script. &quot;They rarely ask us professional questions about products.&quot; , because today’s anchors have too many choices, and merchants of all sizes are waiting for them to deliver products. They don’t know the raw materials, ingredients and functions of the products. What they care about most are three points: How much is the price, how much is the commission, and is there any pit fee?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo (pseudonym), an anchor who has been doing live broadcasts for five years, told Southern Weekend reporters that she would learn about the product information before the live broadcast. Go to the live broadcast room every hour and communicate with the operation about the overall situation. During the live broadcast, consumers are mainly told three pieces of information: how favorable the price of this product is, how easy it is to use, and when and in what scenario it will be needed. If consumers are tempted but are still hesitant, they will emphasize the accompanying gifts and the decreasing inventory, &quot;to force another order.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chu Shi’s observation, this is because the time to explain each product in the live broadcast room is very limited. Within a few minutes, the strength of the discount is reflected in order to impress users and make them purchase. &quot;Use &#39;Quantity&#39; is the fastest way for them to reflect the value of the product.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo has been a brand external anchor for a long time, and has worked with 30 or 40 brands. She is charged by the hour. &quot;Selling more or less all depends on my own professional ethics and KPIs.&quot; There is not a lot of pressure on sales.” Recently, she decided to go it alone and collect commissions for selling goods. The more she sold, the more she earned, which gave her a greater sense of urgency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the platform will analyze the live broadcast data in real time, display the product placement expenses, sales volume and total sales of the day, and also conduct vertical comparisons. Increasingly intuitive data also tests the ability of anchors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The game mechanism between brands and anchors&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to create a super anchor. May Beauty, where Nanshan is located, once failed to become a super anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This MCN organization has incubated more than 60 beauty experts. Nanshan recalled that the company originally “wanted to go towards the top.” At the end of 2021, they tried to support a beauty blogger with more than 10 million fans. At his peak, the blogger could bring in 5 to 6 million yuan in goods per sale. But they soon discovered that the top anchors were &quot;not that easy to do&quot; and it was difficult to obtain &quot;a particularly good mechanism&quot;. The frequency of live broadcasts could not be increased, and the commission rate was relatively low. It was very likely that &quot;the work was in vain and no money was made.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the keys to being stuck in the top spot is the mechanism, that is, the brand merchants give the anchors product prices, gift configurations, commission sharing or other incentive resources. The differences in the mechanisms obtained by different anchors are obvious. Nanshan compared its own anchors with the leading anchors in the industry. The same shampoo was sold in both live broadcast rooms for 119 yuan for two bottles of 1,000 ml. At the head anchor, those who place orders can get an extra 400 to 500 ml of shampoo, but they may only get 100 to 200 ml. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sales that exceed brand expectations, make products a hit, have good daily video and live broadcast data, and excellent business negotiation skills can all help anchors get better mechanisms, &quot;If Without a good mechanism, it will be difficult for users to continue paying for it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Nanshan also observed that compared with the previous two years, brands have made less and less &quot;sacrifice&quot; in terms of mechanism. &quot;In 2021, brands are more willing to sacrifice some mechanisms for anchors. For example, if he sells it for 119 yuan in his flagship store, he may give 99 yuan to our live broadcast room.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out,品牌方与主播方本质上是博弈关系。品牌此前低价让利，是希望凭借主播带货，将粉丝吸引到自家官网账号，直接关注品牌本身。主播则需要直播间产品保持低价，维护好原有粉丝，抬高身价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产品在直播间的标价、主播方能拿到的佣金比例、消费者的赠品等，都是博弈重点。在2023年8月，南山他们以18万元的价格谈下一名百万粉丝主播的合作，包含两三条短视频、两条直播预热及一场专场直播，带货五项产品。品牌方的主要诉求是降低佣金、减少赠品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方手里拿着机制表，经历两三轮开会探讨，最终选择各退一步。平均佣金从31%左右降到28%，产品从两瓶600毫升119元及150毫升赠品，变成了两瓶128元加300毫升赠品，相当于“128元一下子到手三瓶”。两方对结果都算满意，算下来，两三场直播后，品牌初期投入“就会回来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南山提到，部分品牌与主播也产生了新的合作关系，即在产品面世之前，品牌就会让主播参与到产品开发中，品牌方会和主播沟通：“我这个产品你觉得定多少钱合适”“哪些地方还不合适，我要改一改”，双方会拉长合作线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“因为主播有个特点，他们比较了解消费者，会使整个产业链更好地贴近消费者。”中国社科院财经战略院研究室主任李勇坚指出，品牌与主播之间的深度合作是相对有益的，能够提高供应链的效率，有利于国产品牌快速形成。但需要警惕的是，有的主播可能会利用消费者的信任，进一步压榨消费者，“（要记得）你是代表消费者的利益，帮消费者去找到物美价廉的商品”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直播依旧是这家MCN机构2023年发力的方向。南山的依据是，消费者的心智已经形成，有日常在直播间买东西的习惯，同时，直播消费行为变得更加理性，除了价格外，也会考虑产品的适用度，“这时候我们通过直播这种形式去&#39;种草&#39;用户，让他进而下单”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年5月，杭州一个美妆电商在直播。图文无关。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年5月，杭州一个美妆电商在直播。 Pictures and texts are irrelevant.视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;直播电商“天花板”在哪？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不同品牌进直播间的目的各异。乔磊称，对于某些大品牌来说，直播只是渠道，他们更看重“种草”效果，而非主播带货量。新品牌、小品牌则有所不同，需要“种草”，亦需“割草”，希望有足够的卖货量，合作费用回本，货品周转率提高。至于他自己，更重要的目的是推广。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;效果是显而易见的，李佳琦一场直播，为他们的店铺带来了十几万的访客，“原来的日销是五六万块钱，可能他帮我们直播带货之后，日销到了八九万，影响力在扩大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但李勇坚指出，“依赖大厨”是直播电商生态最大的毛病。对于一个新生品牌，讲好品牌故事、做好产品、形成品牌力是最基本的，依赖头部主播去做品牌难度很大，“有个别的（成功）案例，但是这个案例能不能持续，如果没有品牌力、产品力的话，我觉得值得怀疑”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，现在直播电商的“天花板”已经出现。他称，电商的基本逻辑是舒展供应链，缩短营销链，“现在突然之间多了一个主播，砍走25%，砍走30%，这个商业逻辑本身就有问题的”。利益分配机制不健全、价格体系混乱、主播之间发展不均衡均是直播生态乱象，由此引发了新的问题，数据流量造假、虚假下单刷单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对乔磊来说，直播领域的发展已趋于成熟。不论粉丝量是多是少，受众年龄是大是小，所处领域是热是冷，都有相应的竞争者，“其实现在每一个卡位上都有占位的，任何一个垂类赛道基本上都已被覆盖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乔磊发现，往日里，每个平台、每位主播都有各自的受众，彼此影响不大，但到了“618”“双十一”这样的大促时期，几个平台的消费者重合率会明显变高，所有带货主播便会被拉至同一竞技场，竞争力的强弱格外明显。 “一到大型促销节点，其实尾部主播的生存空间是很小的，还是以头部主播为主。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样，竞争力不强的小品牌也会选择在大促时“躺平”自保，退出激烈战场。莉莉安称，大促期间流量费用都会变高，自家不具备抢流量分市场的能力，会主动避开战火，“一般（大促节）其实我们都不焦虑的，我们就直接摆烂”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浙江工商大学经济学院教授、浙江省消费促进工作专家委员会委员赵浩兴告诉南方周末记者，目前直播领域生态是不健全的，“一方面拼命压低供应链上游的价格，另一方面又抬高销售价格，取得巨额利润。红利全都聚集在网红头上去了，生态圈的利润分配严重不合理，以后肯定是要打破这种现象”。他建议市场监管部门加强监管力度，希望供应链更加成熟完善，上下游利润分配合理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他称，目前直播行业已到了转型期，多种类型的垂直产业链直播、工厂直播、专家直播都在发挥更大作用，出现“小而美、小而专精”的特性，这也是“未来2.0版直播”的发展方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访许鞍华：因为不服气，所以继续拍电影丨影视大咖谈④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FAMbdwT9pAbp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FAMbdwT9pAbp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年10月29日，许鞍华在上海参加《第一炉香》映后交流活动。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年立冬这天，许鞍华的心情很好，她从北京飞往厦门，打算把这里作为她此次内地之行的最后一站。 2019年5月22日，许鞍华执导的新片《第一炉香》在厦门鼓浪屿开机，两年半之后，她带着电影返回这里。在放映活动现场，有观众悄声对话：“听说这部电影是不是拍得不太好？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有讨论是好事。”谈及《第一炉香》的口碑争议，许鞍华的态度很坦然，尽管她的职业生涯曾多次遭遇失败和质疑，但在豆瓣网上，《第一炉香》的评分只有5.6，成为许鞍华从影43年来的最低分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;制片人刘韧告诉南方周末记者：“因为种种原因，《第一炉香》没有首映式，这次导演来厦门，是为了答谢之前拍摄帮助过我们的人，完全是我们自费的。《第一炉香》的口碑争议有着很复杂的原因，这和当下电影行业的宣发规则不无关系。Ann(许鞍华英文名)对此不是不在意，但她还经常为我打气，说没关系，她虽然生气，但不会难过，一定要反击回去，吸取经验继续拍——你看她是对抗型的人，有一颗革命的心。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“拍《第一炉香》大概率会失败”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“这个项目我做了七年，说起来真是一个漫长的故事。”《第一炉香》制片人刘韧说，“《第一炉香》是我制片的第一个项目，青鸟这家公司是我的老师夏梦（注：香港影星，知名爱国人士）临终前交付我的，她嘱咐我一定要拍好电影，所以我就找了许鞍华导演来拍《第一炉香》。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张爱玲《第一炉香》的电影改编辗转了几十年。张爱玲生前曾中意影星林黛演绎女主角葛薇龙，后来林黛自杀，此事不了了之。 1980年代，夏梦创办的青鸟电影公司开启了香港和内地合拍片的风潮，投资了《投奔怒海》《自古英雄出少年》《似水流年》三部电影。夏梦也曾考虑购买《第一炉香》的版权，但因为香港电影的制作环境发生了一些变化，夏梦离开了电影圈，这件事又耽搁了下来。 1990年代，《霸王别姬》的出品人徐枫购买了小说的版权，曾经与杨德昌接洽过，因为各种原因也没有拍。直到2014年，当时在上海出版行业工作的刘韧与朋友闲聊，萌生了电影改编张爱玲小说的想法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张爱玲众多小说里，刘韧选择了《第一炉香》。经过一番波折，2015年，他从张爱玲版权拥有者宋以朗那里买到了这篇小说五年的改编权，着手寻找自己心仪的导演。 2016年，他得到许鞍华首肯愿意担任该片的监制。 “Ann当时就告诉我改编这部电影的难度，改编《第一炉香》大概率是失败，她建议我找一位年轻导演来拍。因为拍这部电影即使拍不好有争议，但年轻人有年轻人的视角，有争议也是好事。”刘韧告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2016年到2019年，刘韧一直在为电影开拍做着各项工作，遭遇过各种意外和不顺利，眼看着改编版权快要到期了，资方提出请许鞍华担任导演。当时，许鞍华刚刚完成电影《明月几时有》，她对比了手头的几个工作邀约，最终决定承担这部影片的导演工作，她找来了曾和自己在舞台剧《金锁记》有过合作的作家王安忆担任编剧，电影《第一炉香》的雏形渐渐形成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许鞍华出生于1947年，2021年10月《第一炉香》上映的时候，她已经74岁了。新冠疫情暴发的2020年，许鞍华做完了这部电影的后期，得知威尼斯电影节要将终身成就奖颁发给自己的消息。她是全球首位获得这个荣誉的女性导演，这被看做全球女性电影工作者的胜利。许鞍华在领奖时用英文发表了演说，表示自己回去要帮助更多的年轻人，让他们将来也有机会获得终身成就奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年10月，一部记录许鞍华从影40年的纪录片《好好拍电影》在香港国际电影节首映，这部作品的导演文念中曾担任过许鞍华几部电影的美术指导，以朋友和合作者的视角为观众展现了晚年许鞍华生活的一些片段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许鞍华一生未婚，情感经验几乎是空白，她曾说“电影是自己的老公或老婆，文学是自己的情妇”。她眼里只有电影，工作时因为太投入常常会摔倒，最焦虑的事情是没有电影可以拍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘韧告诉南方周末记者：“我们在鼓浪屿拍摄的时候，有一天Ann在浴室摔倒了，因为是后脑勺着地，很吓人。她恢复意识后第一时间给我发消息说，&#39;小刘，我摔倒了，我不敢动，你能不能来看看我？&#39;我赶去一看，她后脑勺到脖子那里全是青紫的淤血，赶紧带她去做核磁共振，她和我说，脑子里第一时间考虑的是如果真的出了事，赶紧叫阿关（导演关锦鹏）来（代替她）。Ann真的是一个为了电影拼命的人，以至于很多时候我都忘记她是一位七十多岁的老人了，接下来我们会继续合作，我希望她在80岁之前还能再拍两部电影。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年11月6日，电影《第一炉香》在一片差评中票房还是超过6000万元人民币，有望成为许鞍华内地票房第二名的作品。第二天上午，南方周末记者在厦门对许鞍华进行了专访。谈到最后，她突然说：“我也问你一个问题吧，说实话，你觉得《第一炉香》到底怎么样？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;许鞍华根据张爱玲同名小说改编的电影《半生缘》(1997)，梅艳芳(右)和王志文(左)参演。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“张爱玲已经变成一个不可侵犯的作家”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《第一炉香》这次在网络上遭到这么多批评，说实话我是有些意外的，从豆瓣网的评分来看，这是你职业生涯里口碑最差的一部。我很想知道，你是怎么看待《第一炉香》这次的口碑争议的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我也没想到会有这么大的声量，但是我觉得这个戏如果得不到好评，能有争议也是好的。大家可以公开谈论自己对电影的观念、一起讨论这个戏，就很好。另外一些社会性的议题，多谈谈也是好的，可能因为疫情的原因，大家都有点无所适从，正好也可以借此机会厘清一些基本概念。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我看过一些访谈，你说在拍了《倾城之恋》《半生缘》之后，不想再拍张爱玲作品改编的电影了，可为何还会接拍《第一炉香》？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不是不想拍张爱玲，其实我很想拍，但确实我没有想到怎么拍张爱玲的作品才能让观众接受，或者说怎么拍才能让人感觉电影的艺术性更上一层楼。经过前两部电影积累的拍摄经验，我意识到改编张爱玲作品是很难讨好的，既无法讨好西方（的观众），也不容易讨好中国（的观众）。实话实说，《半生缘》就被威尼斯电影节拒绝了，他们本来满怀热情请我把这部电影带到威尼斯，看过之后却觉得这是一部很普通的爱情电影。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来有一次《半生缘》在美国放映，一个很有名的影评人说我们可以把这部电影当成威廉·惠勒（William Wyler，《罗马假日》导演）这类技术型导演拍摄的一个感人的、中规中矩的爱情片。他们以这种眼光看《半生缘》，所以我拍《第一炉香》的时候并非不知道后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实他们分不清，我们克服巨大的困难拍摄的实景和假的有什么区别，也不理解人物的背景，认为这是一部普通的“肥皂剧”。因为他们没有看过张爱玲，我们在原著文本的基础上进行了高难度的改编，做足了工夫，他们也不觉得，认为这样的电影和好莱坞1940年代的电影没有区别。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《第一炉香》和《倾城之恋》都有很长的台词，这些台词在电影里特别不讨好，但是如果没有使用原著里的句子，读者又不会放过我。张爱玲的读者会要求你的作品和原著一样或者更好，可我知道张爱玲笔下的故事很多都不算有创意，因为她的创意在于她的写法，而不是故事本身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我一直都没有想到该怎么拍才是好的，我没办法将它做成一个小众的艺术片，因为那样是拿不到钱的。这中间我听到过各种反馈，越发意识到市场改变了。何况这些年来，张爱玲已经变成了一个不可侵犯的作家，有很多狂热的书迷，他们对张爱玲比我还熟悉，一点差错都会很麻烦，我是深深知道这些问题的，只是还没想到如何克服。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我拍这样一个故事给现在的“90后”“00后”看，其中的人物关系他们可能是不懂的，他们不知道谁是Uncle，什么是二房，姑妈的身世又是怎么回事，不是他们无知，是他们的经验里面没有这些东西。比如一个女孩，在1940年代的农村，一旦“失身”就是要浸猪笼的。现在不是那回事，女孩贪图舒适的生活也是无可厚非的。那个年代其实特别虚伪，大家不谈钱的，一个女人想要钱也不肯认的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这样的情况下，我要把这个故事弄得让年轻观众看得明白、觉得合情合理，同时还要忠于原著，平衡这些是很难的。我不是为了自己拍不好而自辩，我只是想分享我经历过的一些问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你好像说过《第一炉香》和《倾城之恋》比，你认为是好过后者的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，肯定。以前是整个错了，现在也许是和原著有一些偏离，可我是故意的。我拍《倾城之恋》是希望把它拍成很感人的故事，但其实它应该是最不感人的故事，只是有一个看上去好的结局罢了，这才是张爱玲的创意。但因为我是看很多浪漫小说长大的，就希望男女主人公有种成为“战乱鸳鸯”的感觉，其实都错了，完全违背了原著的精神。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《第一炉香》从筹备到拍摄的过程里，你觉得难度最大的地方是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;光是找资金已经很困难了，不过不是我找的，是制片人找的，他找了三年。买了版权以后，人家都说《第一炉香》怎么（好），张爱玲怎么（好），但真的要掏钱出来的时候却没人。我不怪他们，因为只要一算，票房很容易算出来的，这是一个文艺片，可能需要庞大的资金，要重现那个时代的景和服装，恐怕很难回本。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我反而觉得选择演员和组拍摄班子不是太大问题，因为张爱玲的号召力，大家都愿意来试试。其次的难度是选择拍摄的地方，这中间也蛮波折的，后来才选择了鼓浪屿，到真正拍摄的时候，因为已经有了这样一个成熟的班子，反而是没有什么问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你讲到这个片子找钱很难，找演员是相对容易的，但这部电影争议最大的地方反而是演员的选择上，在你找演员的过程里是否受到过资本的干预和介入？比如他们会从票房的角度告诉你应该选谁不应该选谁?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;会有，但都是一些正常的讨论，他们没有给我很大的难处。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;许鞍华(左)与服装指导和田惠美(中)、制片人刘韧(右)在电影《第一炉香》片场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“我已经不再为票房焦虑了”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在关于你的纪录片《好好拍电影》里，你很直接地表达了自己每次拍完一部电影都会担心票房，这对你来说是个挺焦虑的事情。综观你的职业生涯，你几乎没有停止过工作，这在香港的电影环境里并不容易。你能不能谈谈自己在不同时期和不同电影公司合作和博弈的过程？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我没有必要很详细地谈以前的困难，而且从《第一炉香》开始，你刚才说的这种焦虑已经不存在了，因为对我来说，判断一部电影成功与否已经不完全是（通过）票房了。上世纪七八十年代，当时的香港（电影）不卖钱可不行，那就找不到下一部的钱。我感觉现在只要能得个奖，有少部分观众觉得特别好，导演名声在外的话还是可以找到投资的。当然，也不是说就一定可以拍到理想中的东西，因为投资方还是要评估这部电影是不是有收益。但我意识到我也不用焦虑了，我焦虑的是怕没戏拍，不是焦虑别人骂或者是不成功，所以这个问题已经不存在了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回想起来，每一部戏都有不同的困难，如果我说得很细，好像是诉苦，也没有必要。这就是我工作的一部分，不接受就不要做了，老是抱怨没有什么好处的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一般提到你，大家都会想到你拍的那些文艺片，会说你很有社会关怀。其实你也尝试过不少类型电影，比如武侠片、恐怖片，你拍这些是否受到市场的左右？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;《幽灵人间》这样的“鬼片”其实从来都没流行过的，很少人拍的；武打片是曾经流行过，我想拍是因为我是“武侠迷”。我只有很少数的几部电影完全是为了工作，比如拍摄《上海假期》，是因为当时在等下一部电影开拍，有人和我说《上海假期》的导演退出了，问我要不要拍，我看了剧本觉得还不错。我认可一个剧本才会拍，不会不认可就拍的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;大家总有一个感觉就是香港电影整体的环境都特别商业，类似你拍的《投奔怒海》《千言万语》这样的电影是不够主流的，几乎没有人拍的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那倒不是，香港其实也有不少导演拍这些的，可是产量不多，我感觉至少也有十几位吧，比如关锦鹏、张婉婷、罗启锐，跟我们同时期的谭家明……其实上世纪七八十年代还是蛮多人拍这种电影的，不是我一个人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;显然你和他们也有一些差异，比如1982年的《投奔怒海》，你就关注到了越南难民这个题材，当时很少有香港导演去拍香港之外的人和事，这和你的个人经历有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有关系，1978年的时候，我在无线电视台工作，要拍一部写实的剧集《狮子山下》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我选了拍摄这个题材，就做了好多功课，还跑去难民营。我开始对他们以前在越南的生活产生兴趣，发现很多难民根本就是华人，他们的唐人街和我小时候生活的澳门蛮像的，我对这种地方特别有情感，就想把这些画面拍进电影里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以你一直都特别关注社会现实？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我很少概念为先的，都是先看到人和事，觉得不错，再慢慢琢磨，最后才会理出一个逻辑，用来回答各种问题。比如要告诉编剧为什么要选择这样的故事，很多都是事后才会考虑的，最初往往就是凭借一时冲动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我知道你之所以接拍《第一炉香》，其实和《投奔怒海》也有一些渊源，是因为青鸟这家公司。为什么在当时香港的大环境里，夏梦会投资《投奔怒海》呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这类电影一直是不好找钱的，但夏梦有自己的理想和她强硬的后台，他们拍这部片子完全不想赚钱的，主要是为了拍摄一部有文化感的电影。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的电影处女作《疯劫》就获得了成功，拿了金马奖；《投奔怒海》获得了金像奖，当时你都不到35岁，可后来的十年间，你的几部电影又都不是很理想，直到《女人四十》事业才有了起色，这中间你是怎么熬过来的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我想知道为什么会这样，到底是拍的电影出了问题，还是我自己出了问题，不了解社会跟观众了吗？我其实蛮好奇的，也很想知道到底为什么有些片子不好，所以我就继续拍，能拍就拍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天回过头来看，你有找到这个原因吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有的，其实每一部都不一样。总体来说，1985年到1995年是香港动作片的全盛时代。整个行业里的工作人员习惯那种工作方式了，完全不配合我们这种类似学生作业、半工业化的方式，他们都是同时做好几组的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我的心情一直不太好，觉得自己和他们格格不入，工作也没有做好。因为工作人员拍商业片，同时做好几组，他们很累的，我也会觉得整个大环境不支持我拍的这类电影。 1994年以后，这波高潮就结束了，香港的电影工业开始慢下来了，大家差不多就回归到一次一部戏的状态里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这个过程当中，你没想过转型的问题吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我1986年就拍了《书剑恩仇录》，但不成功。 1991年左右拍了《极道追踪》，是一个黑帮片，也不成功。主要是我真的不喜欢拍动作，我跟动作指导合作，交给他就不管了，等到他来给我看，我也不习惯要反复地沟通。其实动作指导在现场指挥，我应该在后面待着，不停地跟他研究怎么拍，但我不是很喜欢这种形式的合作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以到了《女人四十》之后，你才找到什么样的电影是更适合自己的——也许投资不是特别大，但可以保持自己风格的电影？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，是这样的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;许鞍华根据张爱玲同名小说改编的电影《倾城之恋》(1984)，周润发(右二)和缪骞人(右一)饰演男女主角。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“我其实比较像内地导演”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是最早来内地拍戏的香港导演之一，1985年拍《书剑恩仇录》的时候，曾经在内地生活了整整一年。后来你的《半生缘》被看做当时合拍片的一部典范。等到了《玉观音》《黄金时代》等电影，可以说几乎就是内地资本占主要部分了。可你也不像陈可辛等导演那样把重心完全放在内地。或者像徐克，他和你一样都算是“香港新浪潮”的导演，但拍摄《长津湖》这种主旋律电影也得心应手。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。我觉得1980年代我拍《投奔怒海》和《书剑恩仇录》的时候，内地的电影工业是很落后的。现在相对于香港来说，内地的电影工业变得很发达。比如你走进一家后期公司，它什么都安排好了，非常成熟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港商业片的导演和内地导演的思路也不太一样，他们有自己的创意，但完全以市场为焦点的，追求的是好看就行。但内地，就算是商业片导演都还是有一套伦理，想要文以载道，一定要有核心的主题才拍。我其实比较像内地的导演，要有一个主题贯穿在电影里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在香港大学读的是文学专业，我觉得你是很看重电影里的文学性的，而且你很喜欢在电影里使用一些文学元素，比如《男人四十》里的诗词。我觉得这些元素是你电影里的人物的来处，你的电影和王家卫等导演不同，人物总是有一个来处的，可能是物理意义的来处，也可能是精神意义的，这个来处往往是中国内地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，这些可能和我的经历有关，但也不是刻意的，有时候不是我加进去的，比如说《男人四十》里面念古诗的场面都是编剧岸西原创的。 《客途秋恨》里面那是真实的东西，我爷爷教我念诗，也不是我刻意地加的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你来内地拍的几部电影努力做着各种探索和尝试，《姨妈的后现代生活》《玉观音》《黄金时代》等等，几乎每一部都有争议。尤其是前两部，因为是现代戏，大家会觉得你不是很懂内地的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有争议是挺好的，的确也存在一些隔膜，比如观众有时候不喜欢配音，有时候不喜欢语言上带着口音，都不一样的。他们很在意台词讲得好不好，但我们广东话其实不太在意这个，讲的自然随便就好，没有所谓抑扬顿挫台词的训练，这是很大的分别。我想未来我可能还会拍内地生活，但要看题材是怎么样的，能拍的当然拍了，只是恐怕比较难，因为完全不知道好多生活细节。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你从《黄金时代》开始就一直在拍年代戏，是不是这样会更容易规避掉这些文化隔膜的东西？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，因为有些时候我不懂网络。尤其是现在这个网络时代，我连衣食住行都不懂，完全不一样了，比如说如何跟人家交往啊，怎么通电话啊，我都不知道了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“导演是一个年轻人的职业”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020年，你获得了威尼斯电影节的终身成就奖，当时你说未来想把精力放在培养年青一代的电影人身上，未来你在这方面可能会做哪些工作？你们这代导演被叫做“香港新浪潮”，你觉得未来华语地区的年轻导演是否还能形成一股新的浪潮？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有机会就做吧，我不会刻意去开一个公司，我不善于做这些事。如果有问题大家一起商量就很好啊，但不是真的大展宏图地做。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我讲“新浪潮”讲得太多了，开始有些受不了，其实正好那时候有一些从外国念电影的人回香港，一开始都在电视台工作，刚好差不多时间拍了电影，那时候传统的电影大厂制度有点不知道何去何从了，我们这群人在电视上拍了一些写实的东西，后来也就继续拍下来了。其实不是法国新浪潮这种革新电影历史和语言的想法了，当时也蛮繁荣的，大家都有戏可以拍，都很开心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实这些年一直都有不错的年轻人出来，只是可能不叫“新浪潮”，因为没有那么集中。香港还是很小的，从各种影展来看内地导演，一些年轻人拍得很好，坚持几年多拍几部，就会变成中坚分子了，这个跟“香港新浪潮”一样，只不过没有大锣大鼓地这么命名而已，其实你们媒体真的可以多给他们一些曝光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;给年轻人机会是好的，但没必要把帮助青年人挂在嘴里，变成一个没有预设的口号，我感觉年轻人需要的是精神上支持，而不是跑去做一个监制，要是出了问题，是换了对方，还是支持他做一些自己不认同的事情呢？我不想把这件事作为一个全职的事情，因为我不喜欢管人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;是不是可以理解为，你在工作里既不想管别人，也不想被人管？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不是的，拍电影是一个高度合作的工作，怎么能不跟人合作呢？可是我自己有一些标准，有什么是人家不能管的，要不然你白拍了；有些什么是人家能管的，自己知道就行了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也要看具体的情况，比如说真是很想拍某部电影，底线可能会变低，或者反而会高要求。我是保持这个灵活性的，不能一早说了自己一定如何，到时候可能会自打嘴巴的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你已经74岁了，我真的很好奇你是如何保持一直拍电影的状态，你的同辈人甚至一些晚辈，很多都退休了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我自己都在问这个问题，我在工作的时候没有想过克服什么困难，因为困难是一定的，导演这个行业和自己的灵感以及多想拍有关系。有些人拍得差不多了，就觉得要去赚钱了，或者要改职业了，这恐怕不是因为遭遇了什么挫折。一个人其实很难一生都在拍电影，导演是一个年轻人的职业。超过五十岁，体力就跟不上了，也跟不上时代了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍《女人四十》以前，我才四十多岁，就有朋友叫我退休了，但我就是不服气，我也没有什么事情是可以超越拍电影这件事的。当然，我的例子只是个别情况，拿来给人家做一个鼓励，但也许没有什么用，做导演又不能发财，喜欢才可以一直拍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前几年内地电影市场特别繁荣，一些人会产生做了导演就可以获得某些名利的错觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没关系，你什么时候停，为了什么去拍，只要自己搞清楚就可以了。我觉得做每件事都需要想清楚为何去做，不是人家如何也跟着去做。做导演最好是能够不断地挑战自己，如果每次都一样，来来去去都是同样的东西，我可能就不会继续拍了。另外，在这个激烈变迁的世界和社会，导演的位置变得很快。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我一直在考虑拍什么人家才会想看，也可能去拍剧集。老实讲，最重要的就是要保持身体健康，没有这个什么都做不了，至于想拍什么，会不会有成就，这些都是不能保证的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;说到年龄限制，欧洲和美国年纪很大还在拍的导演并不少，比如克林特·伊斯特伍德(Clint Eastwood)，九十多岁了还在拍电影，但亚洲几乎没有这样的导演，你觉得和文化有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当然了。他们团队比较适合年纪大的导演吧，因为分工分得比较细，拍摄制度也比较完善，可能每天就拍6个小时，他们都是有度的，比较容易，不像我们这边这么拼命，但你说的这种现象其实都是非常少数的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[代长胖、代健身、代赶高铁……这些赚钱的路子你能看懂吗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“互换住房”有没有风险？理解年轻人对人性的乐观、对陌生人的善意丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;长假漫漫，正宜出行。据文旅部，今年长假期间全国国内旅游出游预计达8.96亿人次，同比增长86%。而2019年长假七天全国共接待国内游客7.82亿人次。今年多一天，也就是说，今年长假日均国内出游人数已经回到2019年的水平。看来，旅游业的复苏是实打实的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据显示，长假假期，长三角、珠三角地区像上海、苏州等热门旅游城市的文旅市场异常火爆，酒店、机票等订单量已比去年同期增加了至少5倍，价格也普遍大幅上涨。在长假前夕，有不少网友在社交平台上发布“旅游互换住房”帖子，寻找与自己旅游目的地相反的网友，以互换住房，节约开销。这倒是契合了旅游的本意：旅游，无非是从自己玩厌的地方去别人玩厌的地方，逃离日常生活，寻找有别于日常生活的疏离感与新鲜感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;互换住房，同时段每一方都去对方的城市，住上对方的房子，风险应是可控的，因为每一方至少都知道对方的住址与联系方式等真实信息。 “对等”本来就是一种建立“均势”、控制背信等风险的有效手段。不过，如果双方达成的互换住房约定是：一方先在这个假期去另一方的城市，住另一方的房子，另一方在一段时间后去声索自己的对价，那难免有些风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是安全风险。哪怕有约定，来入住的一方对你来说是陌生人，你没法核实Ta的身份，Ta可能用假名假身份证，你哪怕不以真实身份示人，你的住址与联系方式等信息总是真的，这就带来了不对称与不对等。对方有恶疾，会损害家人健康；对方有不良卫生习惯，把居住环境搞得很差，不免让人头大。如果对方有意无意搞坏了屋内设施，也是麻烦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次有背信风险。只要不是一手交钱一手交货的交易或约定，都有这样的风险，在你履行了约定，好心好意招待了TA，但等到你要去TA所在的城市，TA直接毁约背信，你难有办法维护自己的权益，或者，对方提供的居住条件与其所宣称的相差甚远，大大占了你的便宜，你大概率也只能捏着鼻子忍了。实物互换，又不是同时交付的，货不对板也是常有的事儿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平台随处可见对“互换特产”的控诉：被对方占便宜了、欺骗了，说到底还是对人性估计不足。古人有“慎独”之说，以此作为一个人是否真讲道德的判断标准，很有道理。不少人的道德是有弹性的：在熟人面前讲道德，因为不讲有后果，会影响声誉；在陌生人面前就不讲了，甚至还会临时起意作恶，因为觉得在谁也不认识自己的地方率性一把也很难被追究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，为了规避上述两种风险，你坚持要核验对方的身份，譬如找可信的第三方来担保，或者预收对方住宿费？这样的话，和做民宿又有什么差别呢？如果想做民宿，把可用的房间挂到OTA平台出售，经过平台这一道筛选，安全风险可控，背信风险全无，岂不更省事？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你坚持亲力亲为，其实是在重走Airbnb进化的老路：最早大家只是想要比住酒店省钱，建个平台搭个桥吧，但在经过一段时间的野蛮生长与混沌之后，发现草台班子不行，还是需要专业化与标准化，让专业的人来做专业的事儿，不定型的“非标”服务很难玩得长久，最后Airbnb还不是回到了酒店的模式。聚合的所谓民宿，不过是众多私人开的小规模酒店而已。大规模选秀节目，最终胜出的往往也是专业学音乐或舞蹈的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;话说回来，互换住房，其实就是“沙发客”换了个名称，也自有其生态位。有家有室的人想到上述风险就忍不住皱眉，出门在外宁愿花钱住酒店也不想因为省钱而摊上麻烦，这诚然是不错的。但对刚刚走上工作岗位的年轻人来说，租着一个刚刚可以容身的房子，里面没有贵重物品与设施，身无长物，总之没有钱，因初涉社会还比较小清新，有对人性的乐观与对陌生人的善意，上述风险也不是个事儿，乐意让外地网友来住上一宿几宿，自己去外地也是如此这般，不亦宜乎？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;都是年轻人，都穷，都理解要省钱，有共同话题，一个陌生人也许能带给自己一个从前接触不到甚至想象不到的世界，把自己充分暴露于随机性之中，与更多的人接触互动，发现更大更广阔的世界。自己走出去可“行万里路”，别人走进来则是“万里路向你行来”，运动是相对的，变换参考系两者是一回事，自己的经历与别人的经历都一样可增加知见。虽说可能会遇到一些烂人、怪人，但有些能成一辈子的好朋友也是这样认识的，风险可控，有何不可？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年轻人的这种开放心态与分享精神还是难能可贵的。某种程度上，如果遇事想到的全是风险，然后瞻前顾后、畏葸不前，什么也不敢做了，其实是心在变老的体现。所以，大家可以善意提示风险，但也无需用各种风险恫吓年轻人，应该乐见年轻人用好用足这青春时光，这美好恣意的时光是短暂的。我们的身体会衰老，但心态应该尽量保持年轻、锐气勇气不失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[布克奖得主弗兰纳根：活下去，比时代活得更久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3sGId82ZeAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3sGId82ZeAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Joel Saget/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“世界变得越来越不确定、毫无秩序可言，既然所有人都不知道明天会发生什么，这个故事或许会让他们想起，在一个不确定的世界中，我们还拥有彼此的爱，这大概是我们此生唯一能确定的事了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，澳大利亚作家理查德·弗兰纳根（Richard Flanagan）凭借长篇小说《深入北方的小路》折桂布克奖。小说基于他父亲二战中遭到日军俘虏、在泰缅修建“死亡铁路”的经历，双线讲述澳大利亚军医多里戈·埃文斯的一生两世：他在战俘营竭力挽救挣扎在死亡线上的同伴，孤独无望时，他会不断追忆生命中唯一一次刻骨铭心的爱情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在弗兰纳根笔下，“多里戈·埃文斯会活得很久，见证所有的变化”——他觉得有些东西正在凋零，但他会活下去，要比自己的时代活得更久……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一部关于爱与战争的巨著，”布克奖颁奖词指出，“弗兰纳根以优雅文字叙述了一个罪恶和英雄共存的故事，连接起东方与西方、过去与现实。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;弗兰纳根1961年生于澳大利亚东南部塔斯马尼亚，世世代代，人们都在这座“世界之尽”的荒岛上伐木生活。他的祖父母都不识字，全家唯独他父亲受过基础教育。 “父亲对文字的美感和魔力有着强烈感受，他至死都在感叹，人可以用这26个字母来窥测宇宙。阅读能享受到自由和超然的力量，文学这张魔毯，把我从这座小岛带到远方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994年，弗兰纳根发表处女作《河流引路人之死》，他以写意、梦幻、充满原始张力的语言，讲述了河流向导阿利亚什在塔斯马尼亚富兰克林河中船只倾覆、溺水而亡的经历，透过亡魂激流般的自白，弗兰纳根将个体经历与塔斯马尼亚祖辈的神话历史紧密绑缚。 “我可以写出泥土、气味、炎热和血液，却是读者带来了情感、同情、悲伤和怜悯。这本书当年没得到太多评论，但它收获了读者，这足以赋予一本书生命。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年夏末秋初，弗拉纳根《深入北方的小路》新译本和新作《幻梦中涌动的海》中译本相继在中国出版，他在塔斯马尼亚首府霍巴特接受了《南方人物周刊》的连线采访。 “文学让我见识到每个人的深邃广阔，以及蕴含在我们每个人身上的可能性，这其中既有邪恶，也有良善。当你意识到人能成为一切，既可以是杀人犯，也可以是圣人时，你就能学会谦卑地看待这个世界，并且明白：任何发生的事并非与你无关，而是我们作为人类的一种存在方式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;底层世界更真实，文学的宇宙直指人性&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;听说成为职业作家前你做过建筑工人、园丁，还考虑过前往澳大利亚北部挖矿。过往那些工作经历对你有何启发？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;的确，我做过不少工作，这些经历让我意识到，大多数人的生活如此艰难，为了能有饭吃、有房住，人们挣扎着生存下来，他们不喜欢自己的老板，工作非常卑微、又极其辛苦，这其实是世上多数人每天的生活境况。我一直告诫自己，如果有幸成为一名全职作家，我永远不会忘记那些艰难岁月，也永远不会抱怨写作中遇到的困难，因为有机会从事自己喜欢的事，你已获得了非凡特权。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去种种经历也让我发现，当你接近那些权贵、名人时，他们的世界并不真实，但当你身处底层时，人们往往很诚实，他们对彼此都说真话，所以你会发现大量真相。我的祖父母都是文盲，我很幸运成了作家，我和他们及他们的朋友在一起时，能看到一个真实的世界，但当我和那些取得巨大成就的人在一起时，我发现了解真相要困难得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的处女作《河流引路人之死》中，主人公阿利亚什与一位有中国血统的姑娘蔻塔·何相爱，你还写到何氏家族的历史，其中有何原始素材？ 2018年你也来过中国，可否分享下你的印象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实我有些中国表亲，19世纪许多中国人来到澳大利亚，他们与当地人通婚，所以很多澳大利亚人都有中国亲戚，我在小说中写到中国，是因为我就在这样的环境中成长，我对中国人并不陌生。澳大利亚历史上曾有段时期种族主义高涨，当时很多中国人被迫离开，但谢天谢地，现在这种情况又改变了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上次到访中国时，我和中国作家余华对谈，他的经历和我的很不一样，但我们分享了对阅读和写作的思考，他的文学英雄和我一样，也是威廉·福克纳，我发现我们的创作理念也非常相似。当你成为一名作家，你可能会踏入禁区，但你也属于文学的宇宙，而这片天地直指人性。你遇到来自远方的友人，他写的书来自另一个遥远国度，但你们有着相似的灵感来源，这让我深受感动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你刚提到自己的英雄福克纳。福克纳认为，对一个作家而言，经验、观察和想象是三样必要条件，你的写作中哪样最重要？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得福克纳这里并没完全说真话，因为他的经验并不丰富，我的也不多。 &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（笑）&lt;/span>;我造访过福克纳在密西西比州牛津市的故居，他以想象创造了那个世界，某种程度上，这也是他对那个世界的观察。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写作是门手艺，需要长期打磨，就像制作家具，许多时候它只是普通劳作的不断精进，就是莫泊桑说的将黑字写上白纸。但写作还有神秘的部分，伟大的爵士音乐家艾灵顿公爵曾谈到他的作曲，人们说那段钢琴曲作得太棒了，他说，不是，那是一场梦。我完全认同，所有杰出的创作都如入梦境。当你做梦时，你会发现，好比此刻你在上海，我在塔斯马尼亚，但我们有了连接，谈论不在场的余华，也谈故去的福克纳，你发现你不只是一人一地，你和所有人产生连接，甚至超越时空和生死，所有这一切，既是你，也不是你，在想象中发现这点很重要，这指向创作的最高境界，抵达那里时，我们知道自己不再孤独。写作提醒我与人分享，正如人们欣赏艺术作品时能有共鸣，我认为创作者必须勇敢闯入那个地方，仅靠观察和描述还不够，我们需要依赖想象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我们在前进中不断腐化，在情绪的剧场里迷失&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“为什么万物之始总有光？”《深入北方的小路》以这一颇具哲思的疑问开启，这句开头是如何诞生的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这本小说部分内容触及世界的阴暗面。我认为，如果你的创作涉及黑暗，就必须用光明来平衡，如果读者看到的全是阴暗面，他们不会相信，也有理由选择不信，因为这不符合我们对自己作为人类的认知和理解。如果到最后只有黑暗，那就没有真正地道出人性的全部，人类精神的核心在于怀抱希望，若没希望，我们只是行尸走肉。所以，我选择以光明和希望来平衡整个故事，因此，这部作品讲述战争，但也刻画爱情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，我对光的最初记忆实际上就是在那座教堂里，祖母和母亲抱着我，我看到一束光线投射过来，它在爱我的女人们的怀抱中奔跑。当我们愈发老迈，会逐渐丧失视力、掉光头发……但我认为，最遗憾的是，我们失去了那种惊奇感。还是孩子时，你保有这种非凡奇妙的感觉：只要能看到光，就心满意足。我想通过将它放在小说卷首以纪念这段闪光的记忆，因为它讲述了我们早已淡忘的真理，长大成人后，我们失去了这种惊奇感，也失去了敬畏和喜乐，但这曾是我们孩提时就已明白的伟大真理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;697&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;小说开篇写了小男孩手指受伤后的恐惧、玩球时被同龄人欺负，这些关于男孩成长的细节在你的生命中也发生过？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实这些更多源自父亲告诉我的故事。塔斯马尼亚不像其他地方，它是澳大利亚最穷的地区，这里的人不只生活在贫困地区，也生活在更久远的年代，我试着在故事中写出那种感觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于足球的故事，再一次，他奔向光中，感受到光。这个瞬间体现了我们少时的深刻感受，此后却永远回不去了。在西方有种错误观念——我们不断前进、摆脱纯真，对此我并不认可。我们在前进中不断腐化，其实纯真是我们曾拥有的珍宝，但我们太健忘了，丢弃了许多最基本的东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“后来，哭成了对情感的简单确认……情感变得时尚，情绪成了剧场，人们作为演员，无从知晓下了舞台之后，自己究竟是谁。”可否对书中这段话做些解读？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;全球正发生翻天覆地的变化，人们现在更多地抒发情感，但有些时候，他们表达的情感并不真诚。压抑情感不好，但我认为，有时公共空间的表达已汹涌过度。不管人们是否认同，这都是过去100年来最大的变化之一。我认为一部小说可以反映我们较少谈论的这类变化。我希望有个角色，他理解这些奇怪的变化，并将之记录下来。对于主角多里戈来说，这变化令人震惊，因为他一生都在扮演某个角色，他不是英雄，但不得不扮成英雄，因为这是其他战俘对他的要求。战争结束后，他还得继续扮演这个角色，不得不戴着这个面具，他知道这是谎言，但这对其他人而言已成了必要的生活，所以他同意了，部分原因也是他回避了自己的情绪。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我感兴趣的是，当一个人成了领导或名人，我们常认为他们自己创造了这个身份，但其实是我们“创造”了他们，我们决定让他们成为名人或英雄，有时这些角色对人是种禁锢，名人和名声，是误解和困扰的某种表象，这背后甚是寂寞，事实是，你越出名，就越孤独，这不是什么悖论，而是真相。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“人生在世，行走于地狱的屋顶，凝望花朵”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《深入北方的小路》标题和第一部分引语都引自松尾芭蕉的俳句，小说后面四部分则以小林一茶的俳句开启，说说你选择这几首俳句的考量？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这本书对我来说很难写，起初我觉得自己做不到。我不想冒犯父亲，写些他觉得与他经历不相称的东西，好像背叛了他。我花了12年写成这部作品，也花了这么长时间才找到最合适的表达方式。最终，我用爱完成了这次书写。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不想论断任何人，只想展示人类对彼此做的事。我想用自己从日本文学中学到的形式来组织这本书，我可以用日本文化中最美的东西去呈现同一社会中最糟糕的暴行，这样写下它可能是我解放自己的一种方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这本书结构有点像《罗生门》，从多个角度看待罪行，呈现关于同个罪行的不同观点，其中穿插了日本诗歌。我渴望撕去所有外在饰物，事实上，你剥除得越多，越能让读者发掘真意。当我写作时，我会试着不断拿掉些东西，删减又删减，剩下的就是读者能找到意义和目的的东西，而不是由我来告诉他是什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你引用的小林一茶的俳句有两首都涉及“露水之世”，你如何理解“露水之世”？又如何看待东方的禅宗思想？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本军国主义深受禅宗思想影响&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（注：禅的理论是日本军国主义战争动员的思想武器之一，相关论述参见《日本禅与军国主义》《近现代日本禅的误区及其超越》等论文）&lt;/span>;，后者有一种奇异的狂喜，但同样的想法，当他们鼓吹日本军国主义时，也可以表现为恶。书中最后，我引用了一首：“人生在世／行走于地狱的屋顶／凝望花朵”，对我来说，这就是总结这本书的俳句。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014年，澳大利亚作家理查德·弗兰纳根（右）凭借长篇小说《深入北方的小路》折桂布克奖&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;小说中你将毛笔一笔挥就的那个“圆”插入文本，说说你对这个图案的理解和构思？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是18世纪俳句诗人之水著名的辞世诗，辞世诗是日本文学的传统之一，临终前，之水抓起毛笔，“画”下这首诗，人们发现，他只是用毛笔在纸上画了一个圆。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对我而言，这个圆包含的虚空、谜团、轮回，契合故事主题，也符合小说回环往复、首尾呼应的结构，“宏伟的转轮，永恒的回返：圆一线的对立面”，书的结尾，我们并不清楚多里戈是死是活，他其实从未离开战俘营，一些幽灵让他永远困在某个特别的地方：那里是爱，也是地狱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在塔斯马尼亚，我们有种不同的时间观念：常常觉得时间循环往复、不再前进。我认为这是一种更宽阔的时间概念，我们常常是今年到明年、再到后年这样走，10年前发生的事已成过往，但这里的原住民认为：一千年前发生的事今天正在发生，明天还会发生，我认为这更真实地反映了我们的自我认知，那种认为过去发生的事已成过往的想法其实是种错觉，一切从未过去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当人们患上痴呆症，我们说他失去了意识，但他们只是丢失了记忆，一旦失忆，你就无法驾驭当下生活，因为人们凭借记忆来理解一切。所以，澳洲原住民对时间的这种概念在我的作品中发挥了作用，我的小说常以一种循环往复的结构呈现，而非像大多数英语小说，在一个单维度的空间中进行线性叙述。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“对于往事，可以原谅，但不能忘记”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从《河流引路人之死》到《深入北方的小路》，你的写作都在探索关于记忆的秘密，你曾提到，“我见证过丧失记忆的族群是如何陷入慌乱的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我着迷于人们追忆过去的方式。我们通常认为记忆是一种见证，我告诉你50年前到底发生了什么，就像我有台相机似的。但事实上，记忆更可能是一种创造行为，它能编成谎言，也能构出真相。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我父亲后来渐渐失去了他遭受的暴力和痛苦的记忆，但到最后，他却留下关于爱的意念，尽管他经历的不是爱，但最终拥有的记忆是他自己发现的有价值的东西。对此，我想了很多，试图捕捉人们通过记忆进行的思考。人们认为记忆代表某种正义陈述，它可能是，也可能不是。这里存在着悖论：当人经历重大创伤，你和你的同胞遭受巨大苦痛时，人们想做的第一件事是遗忘，我认为人类之所以幸存下来，靠的就是遗忘的能力；但与此同时，为了解放你自己，你必须退到记忆中，直面那些阴影，以便理解到底发生了什么，释放自己的灵魂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于战争，我们被灌输过许多关于恶人和英雄的谎言，当一些可怕的事发生，它不只影响个人，一场可怕的战争或社会动乱，创伤还会影响我的家人和朋友，最终会慢慢毒害周边社群，甚至整个社会。因为战争是个恐怖黑洞，那些巨大的创伤难以言说和传播，亲历者有时会擦除一部分记忆，责任就落到小说家身上，他们试图拼补过往，以更好地理解究竟发生了什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你父亲曾说过：“对于往事，你可以原谅，但你不可以忘记。”你刚才也提到释放自己的灵魂。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我刚才说，人们通过遗忘活下去，但他们又不得不记住一些事，人会因恨意活下去，因为恨是一种强烈的情感，但最终，你在恨意中无法前进，必须将它搁置一边，寻找其他出路。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我父亲生前经历过一件非常动人的事。约二十几年前，三位日本中年女性出现在我家。她们非常勇敢，毕生致力于记录日本的战争罪行。其中一位写了本关于731部队的书，那是日本人在你们国家犯下的可怕罪行，她曾因写了这本书在日本吃了许多苦头。她本人其实是东京大轰炸的幸存者，那是盟军对日本犯下的可怕罪行，超过10万无辜平民死亡。但她带着另外两位女士来我家，她们想向我父亲道歉，她们不代表政府、也不代表日本人民，我当时非常惊讶，我从未想过另一个国家的人会来到我家向我们道歉，这对我们全家人来说意义重大，对我们所有人而言也是种释放。这三位女性的壮举告诉我，有一条出路，它不是将人划分成对立双方，我们可以超越这一切，活出更好的结局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;向开放自由的世界致敬&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你常提到父亲，可否说说你的母亲还有兄弟姐妹？我知道你在六个孩子中排行第五，他们都读过你的作品吗？有何反馈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;你做了功课！我们兄弟姐妹都很亲密，每个人都对我成了作家感到惊讶，没人想到塔斯马尼亚会出个作家。他们读了我的书，喜欢我的小说。成为作家、获布克奖，是种荣誉，但在任何一个家庭，你最终是个儿子或女儿、兄弟或姐妹，家人对彼此的意义才是最重要的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我母亲是个可爱的女人，她满肚子故事。塔斯马尼亚曾是大英帝国的金袋，也是一座巨大的监狱，几个世纪以来，英国人将那些重犯流放至此，政治犯、奴隶主和奴隶……各种各样的人都来到这里。我祖上是爱尔兰人，爱尔兰有许多天主教徒，他们聚集、通婚，定居在此，形成独特的文化，爱尔兰盛产故事，也出了很多作家。我谈论父亲是因为《深入北方的小路》，但我和母亲非常亲近，从小听她讲述那些世代流传的故事，我许多写作都源自母亲，像她那个年代的女性，生活受限，不像当代女性有各种机会，但她是个了不起的女人，我非常爱她。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;爱尔兰文学对你有何影响？有没有你特别欣赏的爱尔兰作家？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我欣赏许多爱尔兰作家，但真正影响我的是博尔赫斯、聂鲁达、马尔克斯、科塔萨尔等南美作家，因为他们的世界更像塔斯马尼亚的世界。我们这里有些人演喜剧，试图找到自己的经验、自己的现实并逃离英国人的殖民影响，而他们在南美则要挣脱西班牙殖民的影响。福克纳的魅力在于，他既是美国作家又不是，他来自南方，但从未真正被美国接纳，但他对法国和南美的文学产生了重要影响，在我看来，他真的是20世纪小说创作取得突破的核心人物。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《河流引路人之死》中的阿利亚什不是生在塔斯马尼亚，而是生在的里雅斯特，为何选择这座欧洲小城作为他的出生地？乔伊斯曾在的里雅斯特生活，这和他在那里写下《尤利西斯》有关？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没错！正如你所想的，《河流引路人之死》是我的处女作，我希望自己第一个“孩子”生在的里雅斯特。的里雅斯特和世上许多地方不同，它是个混合体，那里更自由、也更开放，它不是真正的意大利，不是真正的斯洛文尼亚，也不是真正的德国，但它又都是，各种思想和文化在那里交会。让我感兴趣的是，乔伊斯创作了那部伟大的小说，不是在巴黎，也不是在都柏林，而是当时这个破败的、分崩离析中的老港口。他的写作受到所有这些民族的影响，他深受《泽诺的意识》启发，但作者伊塔洛·斯韦沃只用了个笔名，他是意大利犹太人，真名叫埃托雷·施米茨。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让阿利亚什生在的里雅斯特，还有个原因，我太太来自斯洛文尼亚，我写《河流引路人之死》时，南斯拉夫刚解体，斯洛文尼亚才诞生。我对多民族混居的国家很感兴趣，不同族群生活在一起，常发生摩擦冲突，但有时充满创造力。你刚才问我受哪些作家影响，我说到南美作家，但我也受到中欧作家的影响。二战前，尤其是1940年代之前，那些伟大的&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（中欧）&lt;/span>;作家，他们并不代表自己的国家，他们代表当时更伟大的思想，但在种族清洗后，许多地方成了一小块飞地。澳大利亚20世纪大部分时间都是非常种族主义的国家，现在它打开大门，欢迎所有人进来，因为文化精神的宽容，这里也成了更富有的地方。 20世纪初的中欧让我看到一个充满希望的世界，我让笔下主人公生在的里雅斯特，也是向那个开放自由的世界致敬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“乡痛”：从未离家，但隐隐觉得与故土剥离，深感失落&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;关于2020年出版的新作《幻梦中涌动的海》，你曾提到，这部作品和“乡痛”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（solastalgia）&lt;/span>;这个新词的意境相关。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是一位澳大利亚哲学家提出的新词：当人所处环境遭到破坏，心底失落，隐隐觉得自己与故土剥离，从未离家、却有种异乡人思乡心切的痛感。澳大利亚经历了可怕的丛林大火后，这个词开始被大量使用。家乡经历一些重创后，意识到昔日美好一去不返，人就会有这种感觉。我认为，许多宝贵的东西以发展和进步的名义被夺走了，这种发展只让少数人受益，却剥夺了其他所有人的利益，这种创痛会以非常真实的方式影响我们，对我们的身心造成毁灭性打击。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018年3月17日，北京单向空间，中国作家余华（右）对话澳大利亚作家理查德·弗兰纳根&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《幻梦中涌动的海》中，面临灾难，女主人公安娜不停查看手机上的新闻更新，但恐惧和焦虑只增无减。从丢失一根无名指开始，她身体各个部分逐渐消失，但她对此并无痛感也无知觉，这种构想是如何产生的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们生活在一个奇怪的时代，身上发生许多事，但我们选择不去察看。小说开头，我引用了英国浪漫主义诗人约翰·克莱尔的《纪念》：“破坏者和私欲的利斧砍倒了猎物；／我再也见不到这里的水莲木路和圆橡树窄街／还有像教堂讲坛般的中空大树：／圈地运动像拿破仑一样，把一切都铲除……”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19世纪的圈地运动是欧洲历史上非常悲惨可怕的事情，但我认为，现在世界上出现了一种新的圈地运动，正从我们手中夺走那些精神上锚定我们的东西。人们开始失去四肢、眼睛、膝盖……没人注意到，与此同时，我们每天越来越多查看手机，而不是关注真实世界发生的一切。随着社交软件的兴起，许多人的灵魂被占领了。每个人都有公共生活和私人生活，还有自己的秘密生活，伟大的文学塑造冲突中的人物，他们做的是一件事，想的却相反，此外还有第三面，他们也不明白自己为何如此矛盾，这就是我们人类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，这些高科技让我们公开展示自己的私生活，还能解读我们的生活，并将其转化为利益取悦他人。无论在哪国，这对我们都构成威胁，对大多数人来说，我认为，最终，它们的存在不是帮助我们，而是在剥削我们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得自己是个悲观主义者还是个乐观主义者？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;两者都不是。在《幻梦中涌动的海》里，安娜的母亲临终前说，世界如此美丽，但很少有人看见。我认为当我发现那些可爱的人时，世界是美的，但我们常常选择视而不见。我们让自己看得越多，希望就越大。所以我并不悲观，我试着每天去发现人身上朴素的美好，我相信这种点滴的喜乐会滋养你，让你活下去。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>