<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[孩子边输液边写作业：卷成这样，责任在谁？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;During autumn and winter, various epidemic viruses are rampant and pediatric hospitals are overcrowded. Pediatric experts have advised parents not to go to the hospital as soon as their children have a fever, but to rest and observe them at home first. Pediatrics has become a petri dish for various viruses, and the risk of cross-infection is not small; in pediatrics, because there are not enough beds, extra beds are added to the elevator room. Some have turned the observation room into a ward, and some have children sitting in rows receiving intravenous drips. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, several pictures of hospitals have attracted attention and heated discussions. In one photo, several rows of long tables are set up, and it looks like children in upper elementary school or junior high school are sitting and receiving intravenous drips. Most of them are doing homework against the clock, and a few are killing time looking at their mobile phones. In the other two video screenshots, there are also words such as &quot;The hospital thoughtfully prepares desks for children with infusions to do homework&quot; and &quot;Parents: I didn&#39;t want (to let the children) write, but the learning atmosphere is too strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first impression this gives people is that the children are so curled up and miserable. A high fever is an alarm for the body, and the immune system is mobilizing to fight the invading enemy. At this time, physical recovery is the first priority, so don&#39;t worry too much. You should rest and relax, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is too inhumane to allow children to study while sick and do their homework. It has reached the point of going against human nature. Let alone humans, let alone human cubs, even mules, cows and horses are not used in this way. Mules, cows and horses are the property of their owners. If they get sick, the owners will take good care of them, take good care of them, treat them in time, and provide them with nutrition. They will not let them work while they are recovering from illness. Otherwise, the gains will outweigh the losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A parent said in the comments: As a parent, I don’t want him to write at all. The teacher won’t let us go. When asking for sick leave, he has to write the same homework as the students in school. If he can’t finish it, he will get sick. Okay, I’ll make it up together. What if I don’t write it down? The implication is that it is the teacher&#39;s problem, and there is nothing parents and children can do about it. This idea is very typical and deserves to be distinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These children who are studying while sick are still minors and have no or limited capacity for civil conduct. They cannot take their own responsibility. As their guardians, parents have the first responsibility. of. Every parent should act in the best interests of their children, be their strongest backing, and protect their children with sharp claws, beaks, and warm wings like an eagle. This is a responsibility that cannot be shied away from, and is engraved in the Instinct in genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, parents must be responsible and don’t forget their responsibilities; they must have courage and don’t lose their instincts. Children&#39;s homework is not the highest rule that cannot be violated. The education department has introduced homework circuit breaker mechanisms. For example, Zhejiang Province’s burden reduction plan for primary and secondary school students stipulates that primary school students can refuse to do homework after 9 p.m. and junior high school students after 10 p.m. There are laws to follow, it just depends on parents if they dare to use them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What if I don’t make up for the homework I missed during my illness? Homework is just a means to consolidate knowledge. In fact, children with different qualifications need different time and means to consolidate knowledge. Schools and teachers will set the same amount of homework for all children across the board, just to standardize and save trouble, rather than teaching students in accordance with their aptitude. What if parents exempt their children from some homework when they think it is necessary? As a parent of a fifth-grade child, I have exempted my children from a large amount of homework in the past. Sometimes it was because the child was sick at home, sometimes because the homework was too heavy, sometimes because it was meaningless homework, but the child did not fall behind due to this. The teacher did not have a significantly negative view of the child as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many parents are afraid of offending teachers and fear that their children will be treated differently in school. In the homeschool group, there are many parents who give teachers all kinds of rainbow farts. Although many parents feel tired of the unreasonable demands imposed by schools and teachers, they dare not express their rejection clearly. No, even when my own child was sick and had an intravenous drip, I didn’t dare to ask the teacher to exempt my child from homework. Instead, I let my child study while sick, creating a strange scene in the corner of the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools and teachers certainly hope that parents will invest more time and energy. At the lowest level, they will urge their children to study and check their homework, and at the highest level, they will allow their children to learn in advance and learn more deeply. This can reduce the burden on teachers. With this burden, teachers and schools can more easily achieve education KPIs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But parents must understand: the family is not the dispatching agency of the school, parents are not the executors of the teacher&#39;s instructions, family education is not a vassal of school education, and knowledge education is only a small part of the total education. If parents value school knowledge and education above all else, they will feel that high marks are the key to everything. How can they tolerate their children not doing their homework? If parents feel that the teacher is in charge of their children and therefore also in charge of themselves, they will treat the teacher as their direct superior, and they will have to perform well in front of the teacher as if they are afraid of losing their job, and push their children to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, family education is more important than school education to some extent, and it cannot be limited to knowledge education. The more important education is character education and values ​​education. It is meaningless to just preach. Teaching by example is better than words. Much more important. Parents play cards and games every day, but they want their children to study hard and read books. The two cannot add up. If parents want their children to be cheerful and optimistic, interact more with peers, and go outdoors more often, they must lead by example and let their children see the necessity and correctness of doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among all character education and value education, courage education is the most important. Only when children have courage can they dare to refuse unreasonable demands, and only then can they be cheerful and full of righteousness to explore, explore and try. . If children devote all their time to knowledge education and neglect character education, values ​​education, and courage education, how can children release their free nature and grow into a mentally strong person? Parents are submissive and timid to their teachers, which makes them appear humble and set a very bad example. How can children relax their nature and cultivate courage and determination? Nowadays, children&#39;s mental health problems are prominent, and there is a problem that schools cannot control them properly, but the responsibility of parents cannot be denied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents are the starting line for their children. Before forcing their children to die, parents should look at themselves in the mirror. It is okay to hope that their children will become dragons and that their daughters will become phoenixes, but they should not put their own unfulfilled ambitions on their children, which will crush them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[告别“三元时代”，饮料集体提价：“都有经营数据压力”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261176]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:55:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The price adjustment effect is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverages are bidding farewell to the &quot;Three Yuan Era&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Starting from November 2023, Master Kong&#39;s beverage prices will increase across the board - the retail price of packaging of Master Kong&#39;s tea and juice series products will be adjusted from 3 yuan/bottle to 3.5 yuan/bottle bottle, the retail price of 1L bottle is adjusted from 4 yuan/bottle to 5 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Kong iced black tea is favored by users because of its low price and high cost performance. Master Kong’s customer service stated that the price increase was due to rising raw material and labor costs, and that retail prices across the country will be adjusted uniformly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the prices of two sizes of iced black tea in many Wumart supermarkets in Beijing have been consistent with the price adjustment notice. The prices in convenience stores such as Lawson are slightly higher. The 500ml package sells for 4 yuan. The price in online channels is slightly lower, but it is also higher than before. The price of 12 bottles of 1L iced black tea sold in Tingyi Tmall flagship store is 54.9 yuan, which is about 4.6 yuan per bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Master Kong is already a latecomer to price adjustments, and this wave of beverage price increases has already begun in the second half of 2022. In February 2023, Nongfu Spring announced that it would adjust the price of 19L bottled water in Hangzhou by 2 yuan, and Yakult also announced that the unit price of original products would increase from 11.7 yuan to 12.8 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historically, this is the fifth wave of price increases in the beverage industry. Since 2006, the domestic food and beverage industry has experienced four price increases, namely in 2010, 2012, 2017, and 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The effect of price adjustment is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. It is against this background that Coca-Cola President and Chief Financial Officer John Murphy said that Coca-Cola will continue to increase prices in the second half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beverage companies are all under pressure from operating data.&quot; Zhang Yi, chief analyst of iiMedia Consulting, pointed out to Southern Weekend reporters that there will naturally be comparisons when beverages are sold at low prices. Good sales data, but profits are relatively disproportionate, so companies need to raise prices to increase profits in financial reports. This is the &quot;most direct way.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar prices continue to rise&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao, a partner of Analysys Analysis and Consulting, told Southern Weekend reporters that the rise in sugar prices and packaging bottle raw material prices is the reason for this increase. The reason for the price increase of beverages “is the result of transmission throughout the industry chain.” A Haitong Securities research report shows that among the costs of the soft drink industry, manufacturing and labor on the raw material side account for 20%, white sugar accounts for 15%, and fruit juice accounts for 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Food and beverage marketing expert Yu Runjie told Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, white sugar accounted for 20%-30% of the total cost of beverages, but now many companies choose sweetened sugar. Flavoring agents are used to replace or partially replace white sugar, resulting in a reduction in the proportion of white sugar in costs and a reduction in the correlation between beverage prices and sugar prices. &quot;Of course, the prices of beverage brands and products that still insist on using white sugar will still be greatly affected by rising sugar prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the food and beverage industry , The price increase chain is generally transmitted from global commodity price increases to domestic bulk raw materials, then to the manufacturing industry, and then to midstream consumer goods companies, and finally downstream consumers feel the price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data released by the China Sugar Association in October 2023 show that in the 2022/23 sugar production period, the country will produce a total of 8.97 million tons of sugar, a year-on-year decrease of 590,000 tons. . The cumulative average sales price of finished white sugar by sugar industry enterprises across the country is 6,270 yuan/ton, a year-on-year increase of 516 yuan/ton. The average sales price of finished white sugar in August was as high as 7,035 yuan/ton, while in August 2022 the price was only 5,747 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main sources of sugar production are sugar cane and beets, of which sugar cane sugar accounts for 80%. Due to climate problems such as drought, sugarcane production will drop significantly worldwide in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the case with India, the largest sugar producer. Zhang Yi pointed out that under the influence of geopolitics, energy prices have risen, and more sugar has been used as biofuel. India plans to use 4.5 million to 5 million tons of sugar cane required for sugar production to produce ethanol, which will also occupy part of the sugar cane supply and affect India&#39;s sugar production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is against this background that, according to CCTV news reports, India announced a ban on sugar exports starting in October in response to domestic sugarcane production reductions due to climate change. Sugar supply is tight and prices are soaring. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar substitute products are also rising in price&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s not just sugary drinks. Southern Weekend reporters found that in this round of price increases, The prices of some sugar-free drinks have also increased.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, starting from January 2023, Yakult not only increased the price of the regular version, but also the low-sugar version with sucralose. It was adjusted from 12.7 yuan to 13.8 yuan, an increase of about 8.6%, which is equivalent to the regular version. In addition, Suntory&#39;s sugar-free oolong tea and sugar-free version of Vitasoy have also raised prices one after another, by about 1 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, sugar substitute products used in beverages include aspartame, sucralose, erythritol, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The September price adjustment letter from the sugar substitute manufacturer Kangbao Biochemical shows that the price of sucralose products has been adjusted to 180 yuan/kg for large packages and 182 yuan/kg for small packages. Kilogram, it was previously 140 yuan/kg; another company, Jinhe Industrial, adjusted its price twice in a row in September. After the price of sucralose increased from 138,000/ton to 150,000/ton, it was adjusted to 180,000/ton. According to data from Haitong International, the market price of acesulfame potassium also rose from 38,000 yuan/ton to 48,000 yuan/ton in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The increase in the price of sugar substitute products is related to the increase in their raw materials. Herbalife Biochemical pointed out in the price adjustment letter that the price of DMF, the main raw material for glycerol production, has increased by nearly 7,000 yuan/ton, acetic acid has increased by nearly 2,000 yuan/ton, white sugar has increased by nearly 1,000 yuan/ton, sulfoxide chloride and other The price of raw materials generally increased by 300-800 yuan per ton, and all raw materials continued to rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the impact of rising raw material prices, sugar substitute product manufacturers also attribute the increase in sucralose production costs to the approaching heating season, raw material transportation costs, steam energy Consumption costs continue to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At present, not only upstart beverage companies like Yuanqi Forest, but also traditional beverage manufacturers such as Master Kong and Nongfu Spring have launched sugar-free products to seize the market. Coca-Cola&#39;s annual report shows that the sales growth rate of sugar-free Coca-Cola in 2022 will reach 11%, which is much higher than the regular version of Coca-Cola. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on this, Yu Runjie believes that after the price of sugar rises, many companies will choose to replace sugar with lower-cost sugar substitute products, especially in the &quot; In the &quot;zero sugar&quot; trend, more companies are choosing sugar substitute products, which will also lead to a rapid increase in demand for sugar substitute products and an increase in the price of sugar substitute products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;COFCO Sugar stated in the minutes of the investor exchange meeting disclosed on November 1, 2023 that the current domestic and foreign sugar prices are at historically high levels, and are generally expected to remain high next year. There is a gap between supply and demand, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The leader takes the lead in raising prices, and competing products follow up in 3-6 months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally speaking, based on market competition Considering that in the face of high-priced raw materials, downstream beverage manufacturers maintain a wait-and-see attitude and choose to postpone the replenishment of sugar stocks or maintain costs through other means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, Guangzhou Langqi stated in its reply to investors that Huatang Food, a subsidiary that operates refined sugar and beverage businesses, carries out arbitrage in white sugar futures and white sugar options. The long-term hedging business effectively avoids and reduces operating risks caused by fluctuations in raw material prices and ensures the relative stability of product costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the continued rise in sugar prices has not stopped. COFCO Sugar stated in the investor exchange meeting minutes disclosed on November 1 that the current domestic and international sugar prices are at historically high levels. It is generally expected that there will still be a supply and demand gap next year, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Suntory said in the price increase notice that the company has hedged against the increased costs through internal operating cost optimization and other measures. However, the current cost increase &quot;has reached the limit that our company can bear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Manufacturers will also observe the choices of competitors. &quot;If the leading company does not raise prices, it will basically be more difficult for other companies to raise prices, or they will simply not dare to raise prices.&quot; Li Yingtao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take Master Kong as an example. This round of price increases starting in the second half of 2022 has given it enough confidence. Tingyi&#39;s previous financial report was not good-looking. Goldman Sachs also lowered Tingyi&#39;s sales forecast for the second half of the year in October 2023. Tingyi urgently needs to break the current situation of &quot;increasing revenue without increasing profits&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, the timing of price increases is also a consideration. Beverage price increases are usually carried out in the fourth quarter, the off-season sales season. A beverage distributor told Southern Weekend reporters that it would take 1-2 months for price increases to be transmitted to the sales terminal market, and requested that promotion activities be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie said that during the peak beverage sales season from May to September, dealers and channels have more goods. If the price is adjusted at this time, firstly, it will easily lead to The second reason is that the market mixes goods and the channels have random prices, which have a greater impact on sales. Adjusting prices after the peak sales season is over can minimize the impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A research report from Ping An Securities also shows that price increases usually occur after 1-2 quarters of rising raw material costs, with leading companies taking the lead in raising prices. Other competing products will follow in about 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Use price increases to increase channel profits? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The exact same drink is more expensive to buy in convenience stores than in large supermarkets, and large supermarkets are often more expensive than online channels. This is because of the price increases in different channels. different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverage price increases generally include increases at two levels - an increase in factory ex-factory prices and an increase in terminal sales prices, both of which usually occur at the same time. In addition to rising production costs, channel profits are also an important factor affecting price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao said that channel distribution fees are also the main cost of beverages, accounting for about 20%. In addition, dealers and agents at all levels in provinces, cities and counties play a major role. Cost also accounts for about 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In supermarket containers, the price of a wide range of beverages is generally above 5 yuan, and the price that dealers are willing to pay for these high-priced beverages is generally higher. Currently, channel push is still an important force in the sales growth of FMCG, especially new beverage brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie believes that the increase in beverage prices not only increases costs, but also increases channel profits through price increases, so as to improve the channel and The competitiveness of terminal stores. Vitasoy directly pointed out in the price adjustment notice that while the price adjustment is being made, it will &quot;reasonably increase channel gross profit and bring better sales profits to customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Personally, I don’t think that the new beverage brands with higher prices on the market are more high-end in terms of product content, but they just bring more profits to the channel than traditional beverage brands. It&#39;s just higher, which leads to higher selling prices.&quot; Yu Runjie believes that after the price increase of traditional beverages such as Master Kong, the profits at the channel end will increase, the push of the channel will also be enhanced, and the competitiveness of new beverage brands will also be enhanced. From this perspective, price increases will not have a negative impact on sales, and may even increase sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 18, 2023, consumers were buying juice drinks in a Wumart supermarket in Beijing. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“There is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On one side, beverage manufacturers are increasing prices; Consumers are looking to downgrade their spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Chinese Consumer Monthly Tracking Data&quot; released by the consulting company Mintel shows that for non-alcoholic beverages, the proportion of consumers with consumption upgrade plans has increased since 2021. It has been on a downward trend since April 2023 and reached a low of 21% in July 2023, ranking at the bottom among all food and beverage categories. At the same time, the proportion of consumers with downgrade plans increased from 11% in April 2021 to 18% in October 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lu Ruixun, deputy director of food and beverage research at Mintel, told Southern Weekend reporters that this shows that even if the unit price is relatively low, consumers&#39; spending on non-alcoholic beverages has changed. Consumers need to be more cautious as price increases may further influence consumers&#39; purchasing decisions for non-alcoholic beverages. The more positive news is that overall consumer demand for upgrades in non-alcoholic beverages still outweighs downgrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Aside from all the rhetoric about rising raw material prices, Zhang Yi particularly noticed that beverages such as Master Kong, Coca-Cola, and Pepsi-Cola are significantly priced compared to trendy domestic beverages. Low. &quot;Young people can actually buy these products whose unit prices are one or two yuan higher, or even two or three yuan higher. Theoretically, there is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;iiMedia data shows that soft drink consumers are mainly young people under the age of 30, and this group is generally not sensitive to price. According to its survey data, taking carbonated drinks as an example, young people’s monthly consumption expenditure on carbonated drinks between 50 yuan and 100 yuan accounts for the highest proportion, reaching 46.4%. Those priced below 50 yuan accounted for 36.5%, and those priced between 100 yuan and 300 yuan accounted for 14.5%. This shows that this group’s demand for beverages in daily consumption tends to be rigid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The data of e-commerce platforms also reflects this. Data from the consumption data platform Star Map shows that during the &quot;Double Eleven&quot; that just passed, online sales of food and beverages were 55.8 billion, accounting for 5.7%, an increase of 3.9 billion compared with 2022, an increase of 0.5 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhang Yi also found that consumers&#39; brand loyalty to beverages &quot;is generally not too fixed.&quot; The survey shows that consumers usually switch between two to three brands, accounting for 57.8%, and the proportion of consumers who are fixed on one brand is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From this perspective, affordable price tags may not be a good thing for brands. &quot;Our survey found that consumers pay more attention to the brand and the taste of drinks than health. For example, Yuanqi Forest and some other new tea products are more expensive than Master Kong, which does not hinder consumer consumption. Brand influence and Trendiness will play a very important role,&quot; Zhang Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被告人吴亦凡强奸、聚众淫乱案二审维持原判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 11:09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 24, 2023, the Beijing No. 3 Intermediate People’s Court appealed against Wu Yifan for rape and gathering for lewdness in accordance with the law. The verdict of the case was announced publicly, and the appeal was dismissed and the original verdict was upheld. ​​​&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690 &quot; height=&quot;1739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259486&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0 &quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孟庆旸：记住那一抹青绿就好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM5s1DwfYW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM 5s1DwfYW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is probably the busiest year for young dancer Meng Qingyang. On the stage of the 2023 Year of the Rabbit Spring Festival Gala, the dance poetry drama &quot;Only Green&quot; starring Meng Qingyang became popular all over the country and was well known to the public. On multiple social platforms, netizens rushed to imitate her classic dance move &quot;green waist&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Qingyang is a dancer of China Oriental Performing Arts Group and has been dancing for 11 years. She has been the leading dancer in many large-scale national events and foreign affairs events. Dancers are harder to remember than film and television actors. Large-scale dances have a large number of people, a variety of formations, and are covered by makeup and costumes, so most of the dancers&#39; faces are blurred. Now that his work has become popular, Meng Qingyang still maintains his sobriety: &quot;I think labels are not a bad thing. They can help everyone remember the role you played and the image you created. In a few years, people may forget that Meng Qingyang played Qinglu, but they can remember It&#39;s enough to have a touch of green.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, Meng Qingyang performed in Huanggang, Hubei. She is tall and straight, and her dancer&#39;s temperament is fully displayed. Many people rate her as &quot;stable&quot;, which is not only reflected in her stable dancing skills, but also her outstanding personal characteristics. Although during the interview she had to re-answer the questions she had already answered due to equipment problems, she did not show any impatience or displeasure and always kept smiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2021, in the rehearsal hall of China Oriental Performing Arts Group, the main creators talked about the fact that the entire dance drama was based on the Northern Song Dynasty&#39;s masterpiece &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; and used this as the background to create the dance drama. Prior to this, the actors all knew that directors Zhou Liya and Han Zhen were going to produce a dance drama with our company, and everyone had made full preparations. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s view, working with two directors can improve an actor&#39;s artistic career and enhance his artistic aesthetic, so no matter what drama they collaborate on, everyone is fully committed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Green&quot; is a freehand character. In the dance drama, it is the scroll-roller that connects modern times, leading the audience into the landscape of the Song Dynasty. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s eyes, she is like a connector of time and space. Meng Qingyang also experienced many physical and mental twists and turns in playing such a character that has no reference to reality and is even a bit nihilistic. When she first put on the practice skirt, because it was a very long fishtail skirt, the director said that she looked like a mermaid in a wedding dress, without the simple and quiet feeling of a painting. &quot;You have to feel like you are in this painting that lasts for nearly a thousand years, just like the scene where people in our century see the picture of mountains and rivers thousands of miles away.&quot; Through the guidance of the two directors, Meng Qingyang found the direction little by little. and grippers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To create a character, a dancer must first understand the cultural value and connotation behind it. In addition to directing, Meng Qingyang also learned a lot about the art of the Northern Song Dynasty, and went to the Palace Museum to see the working scenes of cultural workers, such as how to restore a painting bit by bit. A painting may need to be restored for several months or even longer. This spirit of devoting himself wholeheartedly to cultural and cultural undertakings made Meng Qingyang feel a certain kind of &quot;immersion and tranquility&quot;. The creative team also invited a number of intangible cultural heritage experts to explain the selection of silk and pigments in &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. Every detail contains rich cultural significance. Only by comprehensively grasping the various aspects of that era can we shape the characters for the actors. Add a little &quot;realness&quot; to the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, Meng Qingyang felt that standing there did not look like the person in the scroll that had been sealed in the museum for thousands of years. However, after a long period of immersion and learning, it was a &quot;sudden enlightenment&quot; when she really knew how to play this role. &quot;All of a sudden, it lights up your nerves and makes you catch Qinglu.&quot; When playing the role of Qinglu seriously, Meng Qingyang found that Qinglu also had a special persistence to work hard. That persistence seemed to guide her to the studio and pick up the strokes. Like &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, she had pictures and infinite reveries in her mind. At that moment, she was green, and green was her. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Immersive encounter with characters&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Qinglu is a freehand character. What qualities did you capture to express this character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The character Qinglu is almost always looking down. When a dancer stands on the stage, the body is the first way to output emotions, and the second is the eyes. But this character lowers his eyes, and there is a sense of alienation as the audience said, and that sense of alienation is very quiet and mysterious. It&#39;s an oriental aesthetic, so it&#39;s quite difficult to grasp this role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember which node you thought you found Qinglu Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the play, the stage design had a large scroll, and I was standing in the scroll. When the music started, the scroll slowly opened, and a very cold light shone on Qinglu. At that moment, she stood there like a scroll that had been sealed for thousands of years. When she moves, the entire space-time scroll moves with it, and then our modern scroll unfolder comes out. At that moment, it is like a human emotion that has been sealed for thousands of years and can only be generated when it moves. I would imagine that my body went from pale to filled with red blood, and gradually gained warmth and human emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think Green will be the most satisfying to you? Works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So far, I can say that it is my most satisfying work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you choose three keywords to describe yourself, Which three would you choose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing I would choose is freedom, because I think I am a person full of freedom in my heart. The second one I think is determination. I started learning dance when I was 5 years old and am now 31 years old. I have been on stage for 11 years. This persistence stems from my determination for dancers and my dance career. The third one can be said to be faith, because I don’t treat dance as a job, but as a faith. In this way, when you face your dance, face the stage, and face the audience every day, you will feel very happy. status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a dancer, he is well known to the public through Qinglu , you have now become a new face in the public eye. How do you understand this kind of accumulation and the word &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I am really lucky, because in fact, we dancers and actors are the same. It is very difficult to find a good role. And dancers are always waiting for good roles. After joining China Oriental Performing Arts Group as a dancer at the age of 20, you will absorb a lot of knowledge. At that time, you want to grow up quickly, gain good experience and mature appearance quickly. When you meet Qinglu at the age of 30, you suddenly slow down because of this character, and slowness is also very determined and powerful. I felt very cherished at that moment, and every day of rehearsal was an immersive encounter with her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The perfect score is not afraid of setbacks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How has dance shaped you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think my personality comes from learning dance since I was a child. Since I was 5 years old, I have had to endure physical pain, such as tearing my hips and lowering my waist, so I feel that dance has given me a character that is soft on the outside and strong on the inside. So until now, I don’t think there’s anything that would particularly break me down. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current status? Can it be called a perfect life? How do you define a perfect life or a perfect state? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am quite satisfied with every situation. Except for the year when I took the college entrance examination, which was quite stressful, I am quite satisfied with the rest. . It’s not like living a perfect life, because I feel that I am only 31 years old, and I have not returned home with a full score, and I still have to keep running. I think it is a psychological state that cannot be satisfied by any material life conditions. I think it is through an experience. I have experienced many setbacks. When I can face these things calmly, it is a very perfect state. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Dance is also a way of expression. Expression is especially important now. Do you think you have been able to express yourself through dance over the years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Dancers do not express themselves through themselves, they must be separated from themselves. For example, when I go on stage at 7:00, I will definitely forget the Meng Qingyang in my life. I will definitely put down my phone and forget what takeaway I ate today, which hotel I stayed in today, where I will go to play tomorrow, everything must be forgotten. The moment you actually get on stage, you&#39;re rendering this character on a blank sheet of paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you take photos of the performance now? Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, sometimes the audience will take some photos. I don’t like taking photos. I don’t like taking selfies or checking in and taking photos at places. But I will take photos to record through my perspective, not to photograph me. I think this is like this (taking pictures) This thing is like this. All the scenes and status I saw at the moment came out through your eyes, just like painting. Maybe everyone looks different from the mood. I will pass my eyes through my eyes. Go to shoot, and there are no particularly professional needs to compose composition and the like, and record it at will. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Week A good photo? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Meng Qingzheng: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I think it is a photo of memory. For example, when you turn your mobile phone album, you accidentally turn this photo and suddenly feel the mood and happiness at the time through this perspective. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Week Can I start at any time? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Meng Qingzhang: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Not afraid, not afraid of the setbacks and difficulties you face. Many people say that setbacks and difficulties are a good thing. I think they are not good, but I think we must first start from their own mentality, and don&#39;t be afraid of these things. When you really do one thing, when you are not successful, you will accept its unsuccessful. I believe my next thing will be better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[臭虫重启“全球旅行”，人类如何甩掉“吸血鬼”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261156]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 08:55:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 690 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/23/11/ 23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259416 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Local time November 14, 2023, Seoul, South Korea to prevent it to prevent The bug spreads, and the staff of the capital railway vehicle is being disinfected with epidemic prevention of subway facilities. Visual China | Picture &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Standing from the perspective of the bug, this is a story of a three-year dullness and restarting the journey in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Since France in August 2023, the bug has panicked in Europe and Asian countries. According to the Yonhap News Agency reported on November 8, South Korea reported 30 suspected or diagnosis infection incidents. The government announced the establishment of a bug joint response to the headquarters and declared war to the bug. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Burmese is also known as Bedbug (Bedbug), mung bean size, stinky smell, day and night, specializing in human blood. In the 1960s, it was one of the &quot;four harms&quot; with flies, mosquitoes, and mice. The advent of chemical pesticides such as DDT (DDT) once disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As a class of wingless insects that rely on human blood, long-distance travel for bugs is usually completed with the luggage carrier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It recognizes the owner through carbon dioxide, thermal signal and human smell, drill into the gap in the liquid box in &quot;Human Taste&quot;, hiding in the dirty clothes with sweat . When the suitcase is opened again, the bug may have crossed the intercontinental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;&quot; &quot;never been bitten before, and thought it was allergy. Now he is very afraid, and he completely eliminated at home.&quot; On November 11th, Zhang Minru came from South Korea Seoul returned to Beijing and found the traces of the bite of the bug on his body. Combined with the recent media reports, he discovered that he was recruited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 8th, the Food and Environmental Health Department of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Government issued an announcement saying that in order to reduce the opportunity to introduce the insects from overseas as much as possible, it has been related to the relevant related to the relevant related. Departments and institutions will strengthen publicity and education at different levels, and will closely monitor the situation and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed 11 patients who had suspected or diagnosed with bug bites. Domestic high incidence in the Pearl River Delta region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Jianguo, a professor at Jiangxi Agricultural University, and technical director of Nanchang Jiangnong Harm Prevention and Treatment Co., Ltd. told the south weekend that the bug is not suddenly outbreak, but has always existed in society. In the short term, the possibility of large -scale popularity in the Mainland in my country is not high. Whether it constitutes a &quot;crisis&quot; is yet to be questioned. On November 21, Chongqing&#39;s illness and control released the tweet &quot;&quot; Burmese &quot;again and not panic, and properly handling is the key&quot;. It is pointed out that in recent years, there have been cases in Chongqing&#39;s violent violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Overall, the bug does not pose a threat to human security, but it is a big event for individuals. Allergic reactions affect work and life, &quot;Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Tourism recovers, bugs are rampant &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The bug does not fly, but can follow humans globally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Changlu, a professor of insect prevention and control of urban pest control, and the Professor of Insect Department of the University of Rogers told the southern weekend reporter that in the late 1990s, the international flow of personnel increased and controlled the prevention and control of the prevention and control. Investment is not enough to resist the antibody of insecticides, and the bug appears worldwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Deson, deputy professor of the Department of Insect Protection of the School of Plant Protection of South China Agricultural University, has long been committed to research and comprehensive prevention and control of insect biology. Type types of pesticides have a significant resistance to drug resistance. The enhancement of resistance to drug resistance is directly related to the behavior resistance of the worm, the mutation of the drug resistance, and the thickening of the body wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Natalie Banggai of the British Insect Prevention Association has been a public health issue for Britain for many years. It can be seen everywhere in the United Kingdom that due to the lack of global travel in the new crown period, as people recover freely, any bug growth may now be returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The British &quot;Guardian&quot; reported that ANSES, a French national health and health institution, found that 11%of French families had suffered from fossils from 2017 to 2022. The Paris Olympic Games was held in 2024. The Paris subway, train, movie theaters, and airports attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Many insect scholars told the southern weekend reporter that the bugs most often appear in places with dense personnel, large population liquidity, and unpredictable environment, such as collective dormitories, such as collective dormitories , Train compartment, high -speed rail station massage chair, cinema. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Truth and darkness make the bugs must be in a dark environment that is wrapped around all over the body, so the bug is usually dormant in a small dark place. After having the opportunity to suck the blood of the host, the flat body swells into a ball. There is a pair of stinky glands on them, which will release unpleasant stinky fluids when they are frightened -this is the origin of the title of the bug. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9F67146102.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 819 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9F67146102.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259417 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Symptoms of the human body are bitten by a bug. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; A few allergic people will have an allergic shock when they are serious &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The other name of the bug is the bed lice, after entering the family environment They will climb up the mattresses such as mattresses and sofas along the furniture legs. If the furniture is against the wall, they will also climb from the gap between the wall to the furniture. Although the active diffusion distance is very short -a study published in PLOS One (&quot;Public Science Library: Comprehensive&quot;) found that the distance between the active diffusion of the bug was only a few meters to tens of meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Wei, who is in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that when the bugs in the family were the most fierce, she once held a flashlight in the middle of the night to find &quot;It will appear anywhere, including clothes, beds, plush toys, walls, toilets ... Its larvae are particularly small, small enough to be like a needle, and occasionally climb your mobile phone screen. Sometimes you find it on the bed to find on the bed. A thing like fat particles is it. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Wang Deson told the southern weekend reporter that after being bitten and blood-sucking by a bug, the human body will have a lot of discomfort. For example, erythema pimples or blisters will appear in the biting parts, and skin damage and secondary infection caused by scratching will also occur. In severe cases, allergic shocks and life -threatening will occur. Because the bug hiding is hidden, it is only difficult to capture than mosquitoes at night. Long -term troubles in the troubles of the odor will cause people to have symptoms such as insomnia, anxiety, neurasthenia, and mental depression. Although there is no report on the diseased disease, a large number of studies have shown that a variety of pathogens related to human diseases can be detected in the body, so the worm is still an important media for human disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A citizen who lived in Hong Kong encountered a bug two years ago. It will explode my mentality on the week. It will be itchy and painful when the wound encounters hot water. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; It should be noted that the traces of the bite can not be judged whether the traces of the bite cannot be judged whether From the bug. In an interview with BBC, Natalie Bang also stated that the concentration of media or the public about the concentration of the odor of the bug often leads to misunderstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Deson found in the survey that many residents are prone to confuse the bugs, fleas, lice, tadpoles, and mites. Flies are like flying ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Factory dormitory and group rental houses are high incidence areas &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Burmese belongs to the department of semi-winged foam, which is highly popular temperate insects and tropical tropics and tropical tropical The bug is closely related to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At present, the largest bug in China was hosted by Deng Guofan of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Feng Lanzhou, the Chinese Academy of Medical College. Deng and Feng collected China 81 between 1950-1951 Bewamed specimens in the region, research results &quot;CIMEX Lectularius L., CIMEX HEMIPTERA F. Geographical Distribution in China&quot; was published in 1953. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The above studies have shown that both green bugs and tropical bugs have been discovered in China. Tropical bugs are mainly distributed in Guangdong and Guizhou provinces. , Northeast and northwest provinces generally occur, and Xiamen, Fujian, Qujiang (Shaoguan City), Guilin, Guangxi, Montzi, Yunnan, Guiyang, Guizhou, and other places are also distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Jianguo introduced that the popular bed lice in the world usually refer to green strap. In China, temperate odor bugs are distributed in the Yangtze River and the Yellow River Basin, but South China is also distributed and is worldwide. Tropical bugs are distributed in South China, Taiwan and tropical regions. Wang Deson believes that with the changes in the indoor environment brought about by the warming of climate and the use of northern heating, tropical bugs may also appear in temperate regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/543Ded6239.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 682 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543Ded6239.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259418 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Ginseng bug adult and tropical bug adult. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters looking for domestic patients on social platforms to be bitten by the abnormal bugs in China. The triangle region is consistent with the existing research conclusions in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Researchers and other researchers in 2013 have published a investigation survey against insects in Shenzhen, and found that the workers in the Dongguan and Shenzhen Industrial Zone were found. The collective dormitory is the heaviest, with an average positive rate of 52.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Deson surveyed the hazards and prevention of insects in some areas of Guangdong between 2017-2019 and found that Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Dongguan, Foshan, Guangzhou, etc. There are bugs in the ground, and factory dormitories and rental houses with dense personnel, strong liquidity, and poor sanitary conditions are high incidence areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;We visited the factory dormitory and found that many factories had insect harm, and the back and forth scheduling of employees in different factories could easily cause the diffusion of the bug.&quot; Wang Deson said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Avoid prevention and control, recommend non-chemical means &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although it is difficult for the bug to form a &quot;crisis&quot; that threatens human health at this stage, the patient &quot; The experience of being bitten by hundreds of red bumps &quot;proves that it still has the power of&quot; suffering &quot;, and it is necessary to take scientific control measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The prevention and treatment of insects include physical control, chemical prevention, and comprehensive prevention and control. For ordinary residents&#39; families, it is recommended to use comprehensive prevention and control methods for physical control and chemical prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; physical control, refers to the use of heat treatment, inorganic powder, and insect interception device to prevent and treat bugs. Based on the characteristics of high temperatures that are very sensitive to high temperature, residents can clean up and dry bed supplies and clothing, and use hot steam machines (such as hanging perm) to deal with the harmfulness of furniture and items. After the heat treatment, the air humidity is reduced, and the inorganic powder represented by diatomic soil can also effectively kill the bugs in the corner of the stench, the bed frame, and the mattress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 498 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259419 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The hiding location of the bug. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is necessary to point out that the common misunderstanding of the insects is to place the furniture that discovered the bug in the sun. Because the temperature of the sun exposure cannot instantly reaches the death temperature (50 ° C), it may cause bugs to spread to other unbroken places, especially in apartments or residential buildings with many rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;In general, chemicals are not recommended, because commonly used in the market to be poisonous It is not recommended. If you need to use it, you should strictly follow the recommended dosage of the agent. Do not use it in a place where the sofa, bed, etc. are directly exposed to the human body. &quot;Wang Changlu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For people who often travel and travel, Wang Deson recommends that mosquito repellent water spray luggage in time, check and clean the suitcases and box underwear in time to avoid Bring the bugs into home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In a densely personnel community, once the bug burst out, all houses in the entire community are risked by infringement. Therefore, during the prevention and control of insects, governance should be considered in the entire community. Wang Deson pointed out that after removing the bug, he must also establish a long -term awareness of prevention. You can regularly check the corners of the bed, the gaps of the wall, etc. to determine whether there are traces, molting or feces of mosaic activity, molting or feces; in addition, long -term monitoring of placing the traps under the bed can also be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For dense places such as hotels, schools, unit collective dormitories, etc., Wang Jianguo suggested that PCO (harmful biological prevention) enterprises for professional monitoring and thorough disinfecting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;It is difficult to do a kind of pests to destroy &#39;completely. Caused a great harm. In addition to the &quot;Four Hurgers&quot; for so long, humans have been fighting them, but as long as people enhance their awareness of prevention and treatment of insects, it can avoid its large -scale outbreak. It may become a big harm like cockroaches, flies, and mosquitoes. &quot;Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (in the text Zhang Minru, Zhang Wei is a pseudonym) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.nett &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陆仙人：从乡村地头走到巴黎时装周]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261166]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/22/PUIN7FE8PUSQH3OOMDLXFM6S07kkkw4jyjgjrc6H.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 719 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/medias/ima/ima GE/23/11/22/Puin7fe8pusqh3oomdlxFM6S07kkkw4jyjgjrc6H. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259207 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Picture by Honor 100 Series Shooting/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 2023, Lu Xianren first appeared on the show in Paris Fashion Week for the first time. He was invited to walk the show, wearing black silhouette suits, white trousers, and capable hairstyle. He is one of the few non -scientific class models present, belonging to his running starting point, on a rural trail in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2019, Lu Xianren, who worked in Guangdong, resigned from work and returned to his full -time video to shoot short videos. He has always wanted to be a model, so most of the filming is the content of his own show. The clothing is self -made. The materials are weaving bags, blankets, waterproof plastic cloths, old lampsses, branches, leaves, etc. with the upper body and walking in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has worked hard for more than a month, and his account is not as popular as he imagined. It was summer at that time, and the hot weather also affected his emotions: Is it impossible to achieve results anyway? That&#39;s not as casual to show yourself. So at high temperature, he put on the red blanket at home for clothes, and walked with a barefoot. This free movement immediately brought a heat stroke and high fever, but also brought a lot of praise. Lu Xianren, who woke up from the sleeping, saw the videos of praise continued to rise, even suspecting the authenticity of this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, this video was pushed to the platform and liked more than 2 million. He was on fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the short video era, everyone has the opportunity to experience the &quot;fame 15 minutes&quot;. It is easy for ordinary people to produce an explosive video. Fighting a group of people. It is not easy to make this traffic sustainable. But Lu Xianren did not hesitate for this. When he decided to shoot short videos full -time, he had conceived a lot of ideas. So if it wasn&#39;t for red blankets, would it become popular because of other creativity? Lu Xianren laughed: &quot;Not necessarily.&quot; He still showed a prudent attitude towards his fame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lu Xianren&#39;s real name Lu Kaigang, born in Hengxian, Guangxi in 1999. His parents worked abroad all year round. He was brought by his grandparents. In the fifth grade, he saw the model played on the TV. He was attracted by the model&#39;s aura and wearing, and went to the catwalk to become his dream. Since then, he will take time to practice when he goes home from school. He had some humpback. After practicing, he opened his shoulders, and his head was holding his head. During the exercise, the top book was on the head, &quot;The book can&#39;t go away, and the steps are formed.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Three months later, the book was prison on the head. &quot;But what I have learned more about their confidence on the stage, the kind of appearance on the stage,&quot; said Lu Xianren today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After dropping out of school in middle school, Lu Kaigang went to work in Guangdong. He successively worked as an apprentice in a barber shop and restaurant, and then entered a factory to work. He uses a fragmented time to continue his model learning. He records videos and compares the pace of professional models. What time is the number of seconds when the head is left and the number of pauses is paused during positioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2018, he started shooting his own video. When he started his account nickname, he thought of the home in the mountains and woke up every day to see the mist outside the window. &quot;Very immortal&quot;, he named himself &quot;Lu Xianren&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One year later, he decided to quit his job and go back to his hometown to shoot short videos. &quot;Give himself half a year and go back to work honestly.&quot; So there was a later story. After that, his creativity was endless, and his model career was on track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lu Xianren is 180 cm tall, and is a women&#39;s watches in most videos. This is not understood. Some relatives saw the video and ran to ask Lu Xianren&#39;s family: &quot;How do you like this?&quot; Grandma said: Young people have their own ideas. What they must do must have their principles, so don&#39;t care about them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwnswixzetpbrezumplzbayimnpde0.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;719&quot; Height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwnswixzlyxo9umplzbayimnpde0.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259208&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (picture by the picture by Honor 100 series/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; My life is not now life. Counting the full score, but try to go in the direction of the full score &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 2023 3 3 On the month, you first participated in the catwalk of Paris Fashion Week. In the international fashion industry, you are a new face. What new features do you think you do? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The fashion industry has always been lacking in new faces. On the international stage, I have been recognized by more people. Global fashion media discovered again A brand new face is found to be a new force. Mainly myself (this type) will be relatively small in the fashion industry, and I personally feel more special. There is also &quot;new&quot; that represents a new force, which means that you can advance and represent an opportunity. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Walk on the international stage and walk on the countryside. What&#39;s the difference? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I personally think it is a mental change. At first, I was on the rural trails and rural roads. I just enjoyed the landscape. I felt very beautiful. After walking to Paris Fashion Week, for the first time, I was a little nervous, slowly adapt, enjoyed it slowly, and slowly began to interact with the audience to resonate with the designer. Perceive, there is a heart that is connected with the soul. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; That show stays in your mind What is the first picture? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When the last curtain was tested, the audience beckoned with the designer and applauded. I walked so many shows, some audiences applauded, and some of them left after the show, and the show was basically standing up and applauding. They must have discovered their likes and found resonance. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The state you presented in the camera is very professional For this, what kind of training do you go through? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When the scene, observe some photography teachers, in what state do they take pictures? I think taking pictures is related to the state. I don&#39;t like to put a look in order to take pictures, or to set up a big scene in order to take pictures. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I personally take pictures when I take pictures. When I encounter good scenery or beautiful things, I will shoot and record it. I bought a smartphone in 2016. At that time, I was still shooting the scenery, I didn&#39;t dare to shoot myself, and I was not very confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What do you think of a good photo like? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The first is definitely to attract the attention, and then have a sense of story and impact. I may not pay attention to a certain detail in the whole photo, and I will notice a general look. A photo cannot be 100%perfect, 98%or 95%perfection, and this photo may be remembered for a long time. I do n’t like to make a perfect photo. When I p pictures, I will retain my flaws and leave it. I am still satisfied with myself and pay more attention to the texture of the photo. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Do you have any suggestions for everyone? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; If you are not particularly confident, you don&#39;t have to look at the camera all the time, the lens is not so important. Take pictures is a record of the current thing. When you don&#39;t look at the camera, the relaxed state can be displayed. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; My confidence comes from my love for the camera, plus I like taking pictures -the feeling of the camera out. The moment the camera presses the shutter is the moment of recording the moment, I think it is a magical thing. Now everyone can take a camera to take a picture at any time. I don&#39;t necessarily say what kind of photos will be taken. I took a picture. I recorded what I was going to do at the moment. I watched it myself in the future and knew that I was quite happy at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are you playing for your current life? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The ideal full score life I think life is half, and then half of work is OK. But I don&#39;t think it is necessary to be full of points to be a perfect life, it depends on the pace of life. For example, I might be particularly busy a while ago. After I was busy, I went home to rest again, accompanied my grandma, and found new inspiration. Life needs to cooperate with work. My current life is not full, but try to go in the direction of the full score. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从入园难到关停潮，高速增长15年的幼儿园数量迎来拐点丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261170]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 23:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会顺利闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261168]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 21:24:16 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 23, the closing event of the second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was in Shenzhen International, Guangdong Province The exhibition center was held. Yu Jiadong, deputy director of the organizing committee of the conference, deputy minister of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, and Lin Tao, deputy director of the organizing committee and deputy governor of Guangdong Province, attended the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e725648413bbda6fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 392 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484413bbda6f7503.jpeg &quot;data-key = &quot;259427&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; At the closing activity, the conference announced the winning project of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest and the list of winners of the Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area Skills Contest, Human Resources Services Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest Finals Road Show Show, 12 Personal Resource Services Signing contracts for supply and demand projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a6859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 426 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/A6859A8B26AA76461c.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;259429&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98C995C1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; Opages y: 1; &quot;width = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406ABFA2C1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259 428 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23F95DF01880753535354580DCCD1FD.JPEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; Opages : 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;Height =&quot; 427 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23F95DF01880753535354580DCCD1FD.JPEG &quot;Data- key =&quot; 259433 0 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; The 2nd National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference has achieved fruitful results. 144 leading enterprises of human resources services and key employers of the Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area participated in the exhibition. Yuan, Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area Youth Talent Recruitment Activity provides more than 50,000 high -quality jobs online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/96AF7E89AF02AE54FAAD37F37208.jpeg&quot; BORder = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 427 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/96AF7E89AF02AE54FAAD37208.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;259432&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252FDFBFF713B5A2184ECE0263755C8.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPACI Ty: 1; &quot;width = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713ba21840263755C8.JPEG&quot; data- key = &quot;25 9431 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c6c1500f88.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;opigny: opign: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;Height =&quot; 427 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6C6C688.jpeg &quot;Data- key &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f8377778518904eadd&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opages: 1 ; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot; Height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837F66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259433&quot;>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt; img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770b777c9167369fc81.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; sayle = &quot;Opages: 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770b777c9167369FC81.JPEG&quot; data- key = &quot;259434&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Resource society Responsible comrades of the Ministry of Security, Guangdong Province and Shenzhen City, the responsible comrades of the Human Resources and Social Security Department (Bureau) of various provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities, and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, experts and scholars, human resources service agencies, key employers and other representatives, and media reporters Participate in the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636E4ADBD5A23072100E910FBBEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 480 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/A4349636E4ADBD5A23072100FBBE.JPEG &quot;Data- key = &quot;259435&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[瓦依那乐队：哪段水域都不能代表这条河流]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261164]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 21:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/RCWQUTHWT9BWFOGH9MNH9XVHSSFLUG0F7YPVWT8S.JPG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 664 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i MAGE/23/11/22/RCWQUTHWT9BWFOGH9MNH9XVHSSFLUG0F7YPVWT8S. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259201 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (picture by Honor 100 series Shooting/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the third season of &quot;The Summer of the Band&quot;, a &quot;Dream&quot; made the Wayana band popular, and the performance invitations have come. The band has become a new face that is very popular this summer. The life of the three members was filled with various itinerary, and the intensity was far better than farming. Before standing on the stage, they all lived in the ground. The farmers are busy in spring. Lu Min served as a tile at the construction site all year round, and occasionally went to sell it on the street. Eighteen, he planted land in his hometown, while being a stray singer in Guilin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The current Wayina, in order to maintain the order of life as much as possible in the busyness, the three members agreed: half a month drift outside and live at home for half a month. At present, they are still looking for a new rhythm. Lu Min and 18 have not adapted to the sudden and more cameras and flash. In the face of the camera, they are not free, their eyes are flickering, and they don&#39;t talk much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not long ago, he went to the streets to sing on the street, sang half of time, and took a photo with the audience in half. He promised himself: at least once a month. &quot;After all, I have been singing for the first time for 18 years.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In September 2023, &quot;Dream&quot; -using age as a node, from birth to death, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age. Dilemma of Duan -Before the stage broadcast, we had a interview with the Wayanan band. They detailed the beginning and end of the Wayana band and their respective life. But at that time, there was a short period of time before they really became popular, belonging to &quot;former Wayana&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Will they change? &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Real creation is a portrayal of people in this era. Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; You have performed well in&quot; The Summer of the Band &quot;. Although it has been debuted for 10 years, it is a new face for the public. What do you think of this &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The reason why we go to participate is for a stage. I love to write songs for a long time, and I have no chance to communicate with you. This stage allows us to freely express our original attitude. Original singing the song we want to sing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of Lumin and 18, they are indeed young and new. And I (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Editor&#39;s Note: 岜 岜 而 &lt;/span>;) has sang for many years, but I just heard that everyone heard this stage for the first time. Some of our songs have different angles as everyone often hear, and (audience) has a new feeling. But for us, we have been doing ourselves. The new thing (in the eyes of the audience) is our very old things, and it has always been some of our emotions and state of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjpenhzo9yk8kzsq2bkfybgpc3kk3kk3kk.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjpenhz0aexo9yk8kzsq2bkfybgpc3kk.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259205&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The farmers look at the old rice varieties in their own place &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (provided by the interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After this stage, the invitation and performance will be invited. Destroy your rhythm and affect your original attitude? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果我们没有清楚的方向就会被破坏，但是有很好的方向，它就不是破坏，而是Help us build the state we want, mainly to see how we grasp it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们依然比较注重自己生活的部分，现在就约定要有半个月在家生活，半个月在外边做更多的交流。当然这半个月是个常规计划，如果农忙或者家里有事，可以微微调整。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们的创作会受到影响吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;还是土地，是土地和人的关系，是真实的跟生活有关的一些（事物），发自体验的东西更多一点。我们比较偏向于从当代真实生活中表达一些情感，而不是纯创造、臆想一些东西。这种来源于真实的东西也有艺术修饰手法。但是人就是土地上的一个东西，跟土地有紧密的关系。现在人的很多哀愁可能就是人跟土地某种脱离后产生的一种后遗症，人一定离不开跟土地和整体的生活的一种关系，包括乡村，包括到城里。如果你真实（创作），就一定是这个时代的一个人在土地上的一个距离感的写照。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们没有限定要创作什么，但是可能有一个起跑点。瓦依那乐队想保留瓦依那的风格，但我们私下都有另外的创作，各种出于个人爱好的一些很不一样的创作。但是在瓦依那这一块还是相对不要跑题，像我们现在唱歌都有一点互动，但实际上我（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;编者注：岜農&lt;/span>;）做一些纯音乐，跟瓦依那的歌不太像，电子我也尝试过很多。所以瓦依那我们限定以乡村为视野，描写当代乡村的人跟自然，人跟人、社会的一些变化，这个为主要风格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;像《大梦》这首歌，不算是传统的瓦依那风格，但现在吸引了很多人，你们之后的创作会有偏向吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;还是接近真实生活写照的东西，像路民写的《阿妈归来》也是，那首歌是客家话，但瓦依那是壮族，那一样可以，它还是很乡土、很真实的一个（创作）。所谓的真实，指它像是从土地里长出来的东西，不是说我们瞎造一个花，当然那种也是一种美，也是一种意识，但是瓦依那偏向（真实）这一块。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（大家喜欢《大梦》）没事啊，大家喜欢，我们就先唱三遍《大梦》，再唱乡村就行了。 Good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们对现在的生活满意吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;主要是看怎么去设计，所有当下都得重新设计，没有一个固定的生活、满意的生活给你，随时都要根据舒服度和真实度来（调整），不要飘。我们还蛮自由，可以尽量调配时间。十八今晚想出去卖唱就出去，不想出去就不出去。主动去做事不累。被调控出来去做就有点辛苦。我被调控去吃饭也辛苦，因为我可能当时想睡觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;瓦依那乐队一开始不是岜農、路民和十八3位成员，之后你们会以现在这个阵容固定吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个有时候就有点像问结婚了以后还会离婚吗？我觉得在流动，不要刻意去绑架一个乐队。我希望每个人在什么地方做一件事情都用心去做，而不是为了赚钱去做、去应付。不管走不走在一起，大家都能够如实地继续去歌唱生活，这个才是最重要。如果我们三个感情玩腻了，想散了，那就散了。但是这个没关系，以后十八可以继续写出好歌，我也可以继续做音乐，路民可以继续唱想唱的歌。这个跟散不散没关系，重要的还是永远保持对生活的表达和体验。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们享受在镜头前面被拍摄的感觉? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;摇头&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;平时喜欢拍照吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;岜農&lt;/span>;）平时自己想拍我会拍，摘个野果扎个什么，我还是挺爱拍的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得好照片的标准是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有时我重新翻我的硬盘，发现有些照片当时觉得有意思，摆拍得很美，但其实都没use.真正有用的是什么？是我做那件事，我拍了。它让我想起当时做那件事情的真实的体验和感受。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们怎么定义满分的生活？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;每个人应该都不一样，找到他最舒服的状态，活得又自由，又能发挥生命意义，每个人都在找他的那个点，我很早就找到了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;满分这个词就把生活给割裂了，要从整个生命来看，每一个阶段都是组成你的生命的一部分，就像一条河流，你最喜欢哪一段水域？实际上哪一段水域都不代表这条河流。我觉得每个个体都是满分，如果能这样爱自己，这样去释怀，就是满分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨曾志平：坚守正确就是意义所在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping, the first doctor of military law in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1966 in Yudu County, Ganzhou, Jiangxi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1984-July 1988, studied at the Nanchang Army Academy of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army , received a bachelor&#39;s degree in military science. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1988-1995, successively&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as an officer of the People&#39;s Liberation Army stationed in Zhangzhou, Fujian and an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1995-July 1998, studied at Xi&#39;an Political College and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2004, he served as an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy and a military lawyer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 2004-January 2007, studied at China University of Political Science and Law, receiving a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Ph.D. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From January 2007 to August 2018, he served as professor and senior professor of Nanchang Institute of Technology Professor, Dean and Vice President of the School of Political Science and Law. From July to August 2010, he served as a visiting scholar at the China Research Service Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;April 2012-April 2013, at the University of California, Hastings He served as a visiting scholar at the School of Law (now the University of California, San Francisco School of Law) and the U.S. Institute of Military Justice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 2018-January 2019, served as the Faculty of Law, Xiamen University Kah Kee College professor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2019 to January 2022, he served as the Wenzheng College of Soochow University/Suzhou City Professor of the Department of Law and Political Science of the college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2023 to present, he serves as a professor at the Law School of Guangzhou Business School. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zeng Zhiping is China&#39;s first doctor of military law. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping is China’s first doctor of military law. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the PhDs interviewed, Zeng Zhiping may be the last to obtain a PhD. In January 2007, he graduated early from China University of Political Science and Law and became China&#39;s first doctor of military law - 24 years had passed since the first batch of doctors trained after the reform and opening up were awarded degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as a secondary discipline under the category of law, the process of military law becoming a discipline is relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1984, legal scholars Zhang Youyu and Pan Nianzhi first proposed that military law is a branch of the legal system in the &quot;Encyclopedia of China·Law Volume&quot;; three years later, in May 1987, the former State Education Commission Military law was officially listed as a branch discipline of law; in 1993, the Military Law Department of Xi&#39;an Political College (now the Xi&#39;an Campus of the Political College of the National Defense University of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army), the country&#39;s first teaching institution specializing in military legal education, was established, marking the establishment of the Department of Military Law. Military law professional education is officially on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, Xi&#39;an Political College became the first school with the right to award a doctorate in military law; in the same year, China University of Political Science and Law opened a military law research center. In 2004, China University of Political Science and Law began to recruit doctoral students in military law. Also in this year, Zeng Zhiping, who had the rank of lieutenant colonel, transferred from Nanchang Army College and was admitted to China University of Political Science and Law in September of the same year, becoming the only doctoral student in military law enrolled that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Zhiping studied under Professor Zhou Jian, a well-known expert in the field of military law and the first director of the Military Law Teaching and Research Office in China. Zhou Jian once pointed out in an article: &quot;Among the top ten legal disciplines identified by the Ministry of Education, military law (030110) can be said to be the one with the least talents and the most difficult to research.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with law Among other majors, military law is a relatively mysterious and niche subject. Before changing careers, Zeng Zhiping worked in the army for 21 years. In a sense, it was his status as a soldier that gave him the opportunity to specialize in military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zeng Zhiping’s view, today’s “openness” of military law is related to the atmosphere of the rule of law and the society’s demand for military legal talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Military academy, army, and then to military academy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1984, you were admitted to Nanchang Army College (now the Army Infantry College of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army) as an undergraduate student. Why did you choose a military school at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our time, especially in rural areas, everyone’s life was not guaranteed. The ones with relatively better treatment were the military. . When I graduated from high school, I participated in the military draft. At that time, I was recruited to be a pilot, and the requirements were relatively high. I was rejected during the physical examination. When Nanchang Army Academy came to recruit students, the head teacher recommended me. I didn’t have any particularly strong ideas at the time, but my father thought it would be good to be an officer, so he went for it. If you want to say that I have any strong (ideas) towards the military or officers, I don’t think I have any. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is special about undergraduate education in military academies? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Before I went to the military academy, I didn’t know much about the military or the military academy, but physical training was the most beneficial thing for me in the military academy. When I first went to school, I couldn&#39;t do any pull-ups. The school organized physical training, and during the training process, I made the fastest progress. Later, I became an all-around athlete in school and also participated in military sports competitions. Some of the teachers are from the army and will teach tactics, shooting, military fitness, formation and the like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating from Nanchang Army Academy, what did you do Which jobs? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduation, I was sent to the front-line army in Zhangzhou, Fujian. At that time, I was a platoon leader in a regiment. After a few months, I was transferred to the agency. During the training of all division cadres, the instructor of one training subject did not demonstrate accurately, so the regiment leader &quot;picked&quot; me out. Later, I became an instructor for many projects. This (experience) made me stand out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been in the front-line army for four and a half years. I have served as an officer in the Organizational Section of the Political Department and as an instructor. After the Lantern Festival in 1993, I was transferred to Nanchang Army Academy to teach, which I applied for on my own initiative. At that time, I went to the Marxist-Leninist Teaching and Research Office, and the director of the Military Teaching and Research Office asked me: &quot;Why don&#39;t you come to me?&quot; He was my instructor when I was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In school, I taught Introduction to International Politics when I first arrived because there were relatively few teachers taking this course at that time. I was also interested in the introduction to law class, and after one semester, I was teaching introduction to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Discipline Positioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why will you continue? Study law on your own? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s a bit of a coincidence that something happened in the spring of 1993 that had a great impact on college students across the country: the International College Debate Competition , the one Jiang Changjian and the others participated in. It was really interesting for us to watch this competition at that time. Jiang Changjian majored in National Politics, so I wanted to go to Fudan to study for a graduate degree in International Politics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But later at school, I learned that several young men we hung out with were preparing to take the bar exam. I felt that this matter was definitely the right thing to do. After weighing it, I said that I would study law instead of international politics. International politics is a &quot;dragon-slaying art&quot; and law is more practical. In 1994, I began to study law on my own in accordance with the requirements of the bar qualification examination syllabus. In October of that year, I ranked first in the military and qualified as a lawyer. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Note: The national judicial examination system had not yet been established at that time, and you could obtain lawyer qualifications by passing the bar qualification examination.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When I took the postgraduate entrance examination, I was not afraid of majors related to law. Because I had already passed the bar exam and my brain was good at that time, I thought I could pass the exam for any major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You already teach in a military academy, why do you want to study for a master&#39;s degree? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I had not thought about leaving the army at that time, but I did want to leave Nanchang Army Academy. Many professors in the school are older. I feel that if I don’t leave the school, I may not be as good as them when I get older. However, it is still relatively difficult to transfer to the army. The postgraduate entrance examination is a means of leaving school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to take the international law major at Wuhan University, but someone told me that if you study as a graduate student at a local university, you have to go back to your original school after graduation, because it is impossible for local universities to You stay. So I chose Xi&#39;an Political College, which is also a military school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think about it, if I had gone to Wuhan University from the beginning, my academic foundation might have been more reliable. If I received systematic academic training when I was young and read a lot of books, then my most source knowledge would be complete and my academic research would have a beginning and an end. My current knowledge cannot reach this level, which is a lifelong regret of mine. Now I mainly feel that my years have been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you were studying for a master&#39;s degree, what did you know about military law? Do you have any idea about what kind of disciplines and what kind of problems are to be solved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is true because I have a background in law. I have read a lot of materials before and also studied military law. In my master&#39;s degree, my direction is military justice, mainly studying the military prosecutorial system. What impressed me most was that I read a lot of English materials at that time and discussed with some famous professors the structure of criminal theory of the three levels of German and Japanese criminal law. This also had a great influence on me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You developed a love for military law during your Ph.D. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I can’t say it’s love. I just accumulated knowledge to a certain extent and have an understanding of this subject. On the other hand, I see a lot of work that is poorly written. I feel that my participation in this subject may make it better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Let’s go back to discuss the positioning of the discipline of military law Question, do you think it belongs to the branch of military science or the branch of law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It depends on how you treat belonging. This issue can be discussed from the subject management of the Ministry of Education, from the professional fields involved in the subject, and from the classification of knowledge. I only recognize the classification of knowledge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In June 2022, Wenzheng College of Suzhou University, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) is with students. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022 In June of this year, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) was with students at Wenzheng College of Soochow University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I am also a product of the times”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you graduated with a master&#39;s degree, your original plan was to continue on the academic path? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, before graduation, I want to go to the Shanghai Military Procuratorate or leave the original school. At that time, I returned to Nanchang and took an introduction to law class at school. Because there were several teachers taking the same course, I could only attend a few classes in one semester. In addition to taking classes at the military academy, I was also teaching part-time at several private universities. It can be said that teaching has nourished my psychology. In private universities, many students look at you with hungry and passionate eyes, which is different from what I encountered at my original school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then why did you go to China University of Political Science and Law? Where&#39;s Beau? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a bit of a coincidence. I had always wanted to change my job before the Spring Festival in 2004, but at that time the unit leader had not announced our job. There is news that I can change my job, I am just applying. At that time, I saw the information about various schools recruiting Ph.D.s, and I was thinking, &quot;Will it be approved (for career change) this year?&quot; Around January 10, 2004, after my application for job change was approved, I quickly checked the admissions information of various schools. I had always wanted to go to Wuhan University, but the registration had closed at that time. However, that year, because the Chinese Political Science and Law added a new doctoral program in military law, its registration period was extended, so I signed up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When looking at school admissions information, I will also consult some teachers. I met Teacher Zhou Jian when I was studying at Xi&#39;an Political College, and I called him. I originally wanted to major in criminal law, and I have been teaching criminal law. Then teacher Zhou Jian said, you don’t want to major in criminal law. I teach military law in China’s political and legal field, so you can study military law with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also told Teacher Zhou, &quot;I have changed careers, why should I study military law? I am still more interested in criminal law.&quot; Therefore, military law is really a product of the times, and I am also a product of the times. It is a coincidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Was the competition fierce to apply for a doctorate in military law at China University of Political Science and Law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, China University of Political Science and Law had three professors who could teach PhD students in military law, but that year only Professor Zhou Jian enrolled students, and the quota only one person. I was particularly impressed. There were 10 people who signed up at that time. I also checked the scores of other candidates using the score checking rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rule for checking scores at that time was to just enter your admission ticket number. According to the numbering method of the admission ticket number, the first digits are the same, and the difference is in the last single digits and tens digits. Based on where we were in the exam room at that time, I could probably guess how many people were in front of me and behind me. After I checked my scores, I guessed their numbers, and I actually found out my scores. Seeing that the second place was 20 points lower than me, I felt more relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How will it be for you to get a doctorate from China University of Political Science and Law? Something more important? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this is a very important turning point in life. At that time, I changed my career and had a doctorate in military law. Teacher Zhou said, China’s political and legal affairs will definitely keep you, so my life plan at that time had a general direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for my master&#39;s degree, I once went to Beijing. While reading in the Beijing Library, I met an old gentleman. He went to an event at Peking University and we had a brief chat. He said something to the effect of &quot;If I can go to Peking University to be a professor in this life, I can do whatever I want.&quot; I had a very imaginary idea at that time: It would be great if I could become a professor of political science and law in China, so sometimes life is very strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there were some changes later, and I did not stay at China University of Political Science and Law after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cognition is the core of personality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You Studying for a master&#39;s degree is to leave the original school; studying for a doctorate is to stay in a new school. So these choices you made were not based on professional choices? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have always wanted to teach in a better university, but people are like duckweeds of the times. My current thoughts may be more mature thoughts, because my career is nearing the &quot;end&quot;. I think it is like this: you need to go to school, your school, the teachers and classmates you meet should work together to help you find your interests in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think an ideal society should be one where everyone is encouraged to do what you want to do and find your interests and passions. If every young person&#39;s growth is to learn based on his own love, then this will enhance his love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The first doctor of military law after the founding of New China&quot; label, for Has it had a big impact on your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t realize this when I graduated. In 2007, my son was going to take the college entrance examination. My simple thought was, can I graduate early? If I stay in China Political Science and Law, it will be very convenient for my son to go to school in Beijing. But my son didn&#39;t think it was necessary. He got good grades and was admitted to Wuhan University. But I finished my thesis and graduated half a year ahead of schedule. I didn’t mean to be the first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I passed the graduation thesis defense in the morning, and the &quot;Legal Daily&quot; reported it in the afternoon. Later, some foreign media also followed up and reported the matter. It still seems very interesting now. I don’t know if the foreign media paid attention to the first doctorate in other disciplines, but at that time many foreign media reported on me and even mentioned the title of my thesis &quot;On Military Power&quot; and said that I was interested in Such a major theoretical issue is well researched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t told anyone about this label myself. Now that I have to say it has brought me any special benefits, I don’t think it has. After all, I haven’t used it to apply for a job. Or do some publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., you applied for Nanchang Institute of Technology and were ordered to establish Nanchang Institute of Technology Department of Political Science and Law, College. Compared with the “five colleges and four departments” in the legal world, what do you think the law department of a private university should look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I came to Nanchang Institute of Technology in 2007 and received the National Social Science Fund in 2008. At that time, there were only a dozen colleges and universities with law departments and law majors in Jiangxi, so it had a great impact. For a long time, the school regarded me as a signature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of undergraduate education, I am very conscious. I have not included military law in the professional courses of law undergraduates. I have only made it a public elective course for the whole school. It would be very shameless if you become the head of the department or the dean of the law school and then turn your own courses into professional courses, compile textbooks, and ask people to buy your books. Until now, I have not compiled a textbook on military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I started the courses based on the most basic law undergraduate major. If there is anything special about it, it can be said that I taught several very important general courses: general logic, grammar and rhetoric, introduction to political science, introduction to sociology, etc. At that time, these courses were not available in law schools. universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, we became the construction unit for the master&#39;s degree awarding project in Jiangxi Province, which was issued by the relevant units. I want students to receive a good education, which can also be regarded as a relatively direct achievement at work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the sense of accomplishment I get from teaching also gives me the motivation to continue. Why do I keep teaching? It&#39;s because I think there are many mistakes now, and teaching is also wrong teaching. Sometimes I say it very negatively, even though I am definitely not popular, I can at least eliminate those false popular ones, because I occupy a position, so that there is one less false popular person. Location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I stick to what is right, that’s what it means to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any experiences or ideas that you would like to share with current college students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is true that people cannot escape the fate of duckweed, but whether they care about knowledge or not is always different. After all, cognition is at the core of personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起底缅北电诈头目祝寿视频背后产业链：有明星报价一条14万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261143]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Which celebrities can be invited to record blessing videos for less than 2,000 yuan/5,000 yuan/10,000 yuan?&quot; &quot;Backstage private message recording of celebrity blessing video&quot; &quot;can be released in 3 days!&quot; Many celebrities were exposed to have filmed birthday videos for the leader of telecom fraud in northern Myanmar, causing an uproar. Recently, reporters from Nandu and N Video found on some e-commerce and social platforms that there are still an endless stream of merchants hyping and selling &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;birthday boy&quot; who caused the controversy is Bai Yingcang, the son of Bai Suocheng, one of the four major families in northern Myanmar. Bai Jiaci is recognized as the head of the &quot;four major Kokang families&quot; in northern Myanmar. Zi, who is also the deputy director of the Kokang Finance Bureau and the captain of the Kokang Autonomous Region Militia Brigade, controls Cangsheng Science and Technology Park, an electronic fraud park. Even though some celebrities said that filming a birthday video for them was &quot;out of favor&quot; and they did not know them, it still failed to dispel netizens&#39; doubts. The &quot;Celebrity Blessing Video&quot; industry chain has once again entered the public eye. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is it illegal to make a birthday video for a scammer? &quot;Celebrity blessing videos&quot; have been around for a long time. How is the trend now? Why are consumers so keen on buying, and how do celebrities view this phenomenon? Reporters from Nandu and N Video interviewed entertainment company agents, buyers and sellers of blessing videos, lawyers and experts, etc. to get to the bottom of the industry chain behind &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259403 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Someone promotes celebrity blessing videos on social platforms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Controversy: Celebrities send video of birthday wishes to Dian Toutou&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Here, I I wish Bai Yingcang a happy birthday and a bright future...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After several leaders of telecom fraud groups in northern Myanmar were arrested, a message &quot;Many celebrities paid tribute to the four major families in northern Myanmar. The news that Cheng&#39;s son Bai Yingcang recorded a video to celebrate his birthday caused an uproar in public opinion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this birthday party, the large screen in the center of the stage played congratulatory videos from many stars, including Hong Kong artists Eric Tsang, Wong Yifei, and Charlie Chao, as well as actor Du Xudong and crosstalk actor Hou Yaohua. wait. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eric Tsang, known as the eldest brother of the Hong Kong film industry, explained to the outside world, &quot;It may be that friends help each other by saying, &#39;This is my good friend&#39;, and then record it. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;After this, some unfamiliar people will try to avoid it.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Actor Charlie Cao released an apology video He said that he came back from Canada in August last year. &quot;When the manager sent this thing over, I asked why it seemed to be a dialogue from Jiang Hu, and I didn&#39;t want to shoot it. He said it&#39;s okay, many celebrities have filmed it, so I filmed it.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He said that he didn’t know where the manager put the video. Many celebrities did it for money. “I made this video just for money, because I want to live and live. I have no choice but to eat, but I have never interacted with people who scam people in northern Myanmar.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Nandu reporters found that before this incident, there had been similar &quot;overturning&quot; of celebrity blessing videos. Artist Yang Di once fell into a whirlpool of public opinion for filming a promotional video for a P2P platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July 2020, a large number of investors reported on social networks that the loans on the &quot;Lili.com&quot; platform had not been paid after they expired, and posted on Yang Di&#39;s Weibo account , calling on him to speak out about the &quot;Yiwang Fraud&quot; incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Subsequently, Yang Di issued a statement on Weibo, stating that he recorded the video for the promoter during the movie promotion period and was not the spokesperson of &quot;Yiliwang&quot;, nor did he record the video. Charge any fees. &quot;I will help the users who were deceived in this incident to pursue the case to the end, and I deeply apologize to the viewers who suffered losses due to the video recommendation.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is the reason why celebrities record blessing videos? For favor or for money? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July this year, Hong Kong media reported that Luo Jiaying and other actors shot exclusive blessing videos to endorse online club groups. Some people were deceived and transferred tens of thousands of yuan to stock trading platforms. Afterwards, the money cannot be withdrawn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Afterwards, Luo Jiaying admitted, &quot;I read the script according to the arrangement of the manager. I don&#39;t know this person.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Quotes: Someone has to collect an intention fee of more than four figures before making an inquiry&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 22, a Nandu reporter used keywords such as &quot;celebrity blessing video&quot; A search on some e-commerce and social media platforms found that many users with the words &quot;celebrity agent&quot; and &quot;media culture&quot; in their names have posted multiple celebrity blessing videos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Click on the user&#39;s homepage, and the introduction will have a prompt of &quot;backstage private message celebrity blessing video recording&quot;. Several sellers showed the Nandu reporter a quotation list, which included the celebrity&#39;s name, avatar, masterpieces, and the price of recording blessing videos for personal and commercial purposes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Most of them are singers, &lt;/span>; actors, hosts, and Chinese and foreign athletes from the Mainland, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. In the same quotation, the price difference is huge, as low as 100 yuan, and as high as 140,000 yuan. There are also celebrities who appear in the alternatives without price tags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259401&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The price of a celebrity shooting blessing video shown on a quotation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A seller introduced&lt;/span>; that the price quoted by such celebrities is more than 100,000 yuan. If you want to name them to record a video, the seller will need to charge more than four figures. Only if you need an intention fee, you are willing to contact the star company to inquire about the quotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen &lt;span>;Jian (pseudonym), who claims to work in the media circle, admitted to Nandu reporters that the prices of celebrities are naturally different depending on their status. Faced with doubts about the higher prices compared with peers, he said, &quot;The difference lies in the service.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He recommended a Taiwanese actor’s blessing video service with a quotation of 30,000 yuan. On the quotation sheet of Zhang Yong (pseudonym), the actor’s quotation was 23,000 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I offer low prices without any additional fees.” Zhang Yong claimed to be an artist manager and a first-hand general agent. “I can not only connect with media companies, but also You can connect with artist managers, or even directly contact the celebrities themselves.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Chen Jian said that the duration of celebrities&#39; blessing videos is generally controlled within 30 seconds, and in addition, the specific details need to be The content is reported to the star, and an accurate quote can only be given after confirming that it can be recorded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another seller, whose name is from a media company, made it clear to Nandu reporters that the video length is generally about 10 to 15 seconds, &quot;the normal speaking speed is 20 to 25 seconds.&quot; Between the words.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for the production time, it is generally determined according to the star&#39;s own time. &quot;It usually takes about 7 days, if faster, 3 to 5 days.&quot; Some sellers also write that &quot;it can be released in 3 days.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Yong revealed that his quotation list marked a group of celebrities who often record blessing videos because they are &quot;highly cost-effective, fast, and highly cooperative.&quot; Be recommended to buyers first. Some lesser-known celebrities will take the initiative to ask him to help recommend and record them first. The blessing videos of such celebrities will be &quot;packaged&quot; and sold at a uniform price. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some sellers told Nandu reporters that although some &quot;top&quot; names appeared in the quotations, in fact they did not accept orders specifically for A-list celebrities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for which celebrities are “top-tier”? &quot;Let&#39;s put it this way, you feel that celebrities or athletes who have endorsed many brands will basically not record blessing videos.&quot; Chen Jian said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Regulations: Some companies have clear regulations&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Why are celebrities recording blessing videos so popular? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai (pseudonym) once spent more than 200 Australian dollars (over 900 yuan) to purchase and customize two clips of English football legend Michael Owen on Cameo, an overseas video customization website. blessing video as an encouragement to myself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;603&quot; height=&quot;933&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259400 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Maimai received a blessing video recorded by Irving. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She fell in love with Owen when she was young and started to play football. It has been 17 years now. She recalled to Nandu reporters that when she decided to buy the video, she was going through a divorce and ended a seven-year relationship. She needed encouragement. &quot;When words of encouragement come from the mouth of an idol, it feels different.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai got the video&lt;/span>; within about a week after paying. And the moment she saw the video, she felt it was all worth it. &quot;This video gave me strong strength and belief at the lowest and saddest time in my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Guiping, associate professor of the Department of Audiovisual Communication, School of Journalism and Communication, South China University of Technology, analyzed to Nandu reporters, like The recording of videos by celebrities is a satisfying and public presentation of their mimetic intimacy, but there is another situation as well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individuals have profit-seeking appeals to the appeal of celebrities. &lt;span>; In layman&#39;s terms, it can be understood as &#39;traffic&#39;, that is, using the celebrity&#39;s popularity to increase one&#39;s visibility and discussion. Some even It can be directly converted into fans and platform revenue on social media platforms,” she said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters saw from Zhang Yong’s “Buyer Show” that there were many enthusiastic orders from various companies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;The psychological demands of companies for celebrities to record videos are more pure. There is no relationship demand, but mainly interest demands.&quot; Huang Guiping explained that in fact, it is to take advantage of the celebrity&#39;s popularity and Public trust endorses one&#39;s products, brands, and company image, reducing the public&#39;s doubts and uncertainty when purchasing its products. &quot;This kind of &#39;bringing goods&#39; is relatively risky for celebrities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Peng (pseudonym) is the manager of a well-known domestic female talent show team. He told Nandu reporters that he usually tells the artists directly that the company has clear regulations that do not allow recording of these blessing videos. &quot;In my opinion, these incomes are not scientific.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At work, he will strictly distinguish the nature of video recording. &quot;For example, for holiday blessings or cultural promotion, we will charge &#39;travel fees&#39; for recording as appropriate. &lt;span>;But if you record a video for a company, it is a proper business behavior. Our requirements will be higher and we will not just record it easily.&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters found that sellers who sell celebrity blessing videos often do not only engage in this business. Celebrity business endorsements, rummage videos, commercial performances, group photos... In the profiles they showed, various celebrity-related businesses emerged one after another. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 800 &quot;Height =&quot; 1068 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0A33324B87F08Edae13.je13.je13.je13.je13.je13.je peg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259402 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span>; seller shows the star recording blessing video business case. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;They often have commissions.&quot; Sun Peng revealed to Nantu reporter, &quot;In fact, the fixed salary of artist agents is not high, and sometimes it depends on others to make commissions for others to make commissions. Or return. But everyone has their own life, it is not easy to evaluate the quality of this phenomenon. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Risk: Stars may need to bear legal responsibility &lt;/&lt;/ Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Star recording blessing video, seemingly commercial transactions that can be achieved by moving the mouth, in fact, there is a hidden risk that cannot be ignored. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; If the birthday occasion, the star hinders the videos of blessings or charges, generally does not violate public order and customs, but if it involves the nature of the platform, &quot;endorsement&quot;, it cannot be understood simply For &quot;one party is willing to give money, one party can shoot &lt;/span>;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer Wang Jiaxin, a lawyer of Guangdong Guangxin Junda Law Firm, analyzed to Nandu reporters that providing blessings for individuals can be regarded as a fan economic behavior. This form is not a civil legal act, and it does not actually cause legal interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But if the stars shoot blessings for enterprises or products, because the star has celebrity effects, such videos are actually implying or explicitly showing the behavior of the advertising language &lt;span>; Enterprises and products should be widely promoted. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;Therefore, such videos are advertising endorsement behaviors. If the company involved in the videos is suspected of illegal business and the star knows the business Responsibility. Wang Jiaxin said. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; When a number of stars were exposed to recording a life video for the northern Burma electrical scammer, many netizens questioned, &quot;How many innocent people have the electronic scam head, why do you want to be for the people? He celebrates his birthday? &quot;&lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;&quot; But if these blessings were exposed to the leader of electrical fraud, netizens&#39; reports were not established because it was a personal blessing video, and Do not target the company. &quot;Wang Jiaxin further explained that if the star wishes the video emphasizes the electrical fraud company, it is necessary to prove that the star knows the company&#39;s suspected electrical fraud, such as whether the star participates in the company&#39;s operation or holds the company&#39;s shares, but It is generally more difficult to proof. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun Peng, the agent of a well -known domestic draft female group agent, also felt that recording blessing videos such as &quot;irregular cooperation forms&quot; will increase the hidden dangers of the artist&#39;s own risk. . At the same time, he also admits that sometimes companies spend millions of yuan to invite artists to participate in the promotion and endorsement of the brand. During the promotion, it is actually difficult for artists to refuse the company&#39;s request for taking photos and recording videos. Once agreed, follow -up photos and videos will be used by the other party, and the results are uncontrollable. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;&quot; Before the relevant laws and regulations and policy provisions are issued, the star shooting congratulations video will indeed be in a gray area, so it will bring what we say &#39;&#39; &#39;&#39; Conflying money or not. &quot;The communication expert Huang Guiping told Nantu reporter that when lacking norms and regulation, celebrities, enterprises, and consumers are in a state of lack of guarantee, which may cause a lot of losses. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;Therefore, when the relevant departments are rectified, the star is aware of the consumption of its own image, or the company realizes that Any kind of situation may make the &quot;star blessing video chaos&quot; relieved. &quot;Huang Guiping said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>