<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[20岁的她会是中国女子网球的希望吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257924]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 15:00:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuYzsro5qS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuY zsro5qS. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, in the women’s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen won 2 Defeated Zhu Lin 0-0 and won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s tennis at the Asian Games that ended on September 29, 2023 In the singles final, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated teammate Zhu Lin in straight sets 6:2, 6:4 and won the gold medal in the women&#39;s singles tennis event at the Hangzhou Asian Games. This is the first time that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in the Asian Games. With Zheng Qinwen and Zhu Lin winning both the championship and runner-up, the Chinese women&#39;s tennis team achieved its fifth consecutive Asian Games title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, Zheng Qinwen reached the top 16 at the French Open, setting a new age for a Chinese female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam event, and attracted the attention of the world&#39;s tennis community. In the first half of 2023, her state had some ups and downs, but she recovered at the US Open and reached the top 8, once again setting a personal best. Zheng Qinwen, who only turned 21 in October this year, has just begun his career. The excellent results have given fans high expectations for this Hubei girl: After Li Na, the representative Chinese female tennis player, retires, will she, who is also from Hubei, be the next hope for Chinese women&#39;s tennis? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, Zheng Qinwen returned the ball in the women&#39;s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Rocket Girl&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, tennis player Li Na officially retired. In her 15-year career, she reached the WTA women&#39;s singles finals 21 times and won a total of 9 WTA and 19 ITF singles championships, including the 2011 French Open and the 2014 Australian Open women&#39;s singles championships. She is Asia&#39;s first Grand Slam women&#39;s singles champion. She was once ranked second in the world&#39;s women&#39;s tennis singles rankings, with a total career record of 503 wins and 188 losses. When she retired, she was ranked sixth in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Na&#39;s retirement has left an insurmountable peak and a huge vacuum for Chinese women&#39;s tennis. She has retired for more than nine years. At least so far, there has not been a player in Chinese women&#39;s tennis who can surpass her or even be on par with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, when Li Na lifted her first Suzanne Langland Cup at Roland Garros in Paris, 9-year-old Zheng Qinwen was receiving tennis training in Wuhan under Li Na’s former coach Teacher Yu Liqiao. In her memory, it seemed that people all over the country were paying attention to Li Na&#39;s game that day. &quot;Li Na&#39;s victory planted a dream in me. One day I will also win a Grand Slam.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was the third year that Zheng Qinwen officially started tennis training. In 2008, Zheng Qinwen&#39;s father took her to Beijing to watch the tennis match at the Olympic Games. Zheng Qinwen thought quietly. After the game, she and her father repeatedly discussed the details on the court and told her father that she was very interested in tennis. His father was once an athlete. He took Zheng Qinwen to play table tennis, badminton, basketball, and volleyball... His daughter was able to get started, but she was not outstanding. This time, he decided to let Zheng Qin play tennis. The coaches at Zheng Qinwen&#39;s hometown Shiyan Sports Center recognized her talent very much and believed that the power bursting out of her body was much higher than that of her peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, Zheng Qinwen participated in the 12-year-old category of the National Youth Tennis Ranking Tournament and won the singles and doubles championships in one fell swoop. In the same year, the Shiyan Tennis Team she led participated in the 14th Hubei Provincial Games and won 2 gold medals. Her serving speed reached 169 kilometers per hour, which was outstanding in the country and the world at that time. Therefore, she was hailed as a &quot;genius girl&quot; by many domestic sports commentators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen successfully entered the Beijing Wheel of Ingenuity Tennis School and received the guidance of Li Na’s mentor Carlos. Zheng Qinwen gradually grew from a talented player to a mature player with no shortcomings and comprehensive skills. In 2015, Zheng Qinwen won the championship in the 14-year-old group (12 to 14 years old) of the European Youth Tennis Tour. She has participated in many national and world tennis events and achieved outstanding results. When she was 16 years old, she participated in the French Open, Wimbledon, and US Open youth competitions, reaching the top 16 in each of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, my father contacted Spanish male tennis player Pere Riba, who had just retired as a coach, and the two parties decided to cooperate. Zheng Qinwen started training in Spain under the care of his mother. From Monday to Saturday, he had 2 hours of tennis training in the morning, 1 hour of physical training, and 2 hours of tennis training in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, tennis competitions that were temporarily suspended due to the new crown epidemic resumed, and Zheng Qinwen began to participate frequently. In an interview with the media, Zheng Qinwen recalled that in order to more conveniently compete in Europe, the team would drive around Europe, driving from Barcelona to Germany, Italy and the Czech Republic. The furthest trip took 22 hours on the road. She didn&#39;t want to be eliminated in the first round and have to take a 22-hour drive home, so she worked very hard after playing. In order to maintain the best competitive condition, she hardly used the Internet during the competition, and even turned off her mobile phone when she arrived at the competition venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, 19-year-old Zheng Qinwen participated in the French Open for the first time. She defeated Zanievska, Halep, and Koné successively, reaching the top 16 of the tournament, refreshing China The youngest age for a female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam tournament. In the fourth round, she faced Swiatek, ranked No. 1 in the world and the last French Open champion. The first set took more than 80 minutes. Zheng Qinwen broke Swiatek&#39;s 37-day record of no opponent winning a single set. He won the &quot;tiebreak&quot; 7-5 and won the first set with difficulty. In the second set, Zheng Qinwen suffered from a right thigh injury that affected his performance. In the end, he lost 1:2 and missed the top 8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Zheng Qinwen unfortunately stopped in the top 16 of the French Open, but the comprehensive skills and playing temperament she displayed made fans all over the world remember &#39;Chinese Zheng&#39;. The potential shown by Zheng Qinwen makes us believe that this season She will also bring more surprises!&quot; People&#39;s Daily reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, when Zheng Qinwen first entered the professional arena, he was ranked 630th in the world. In the following more than two years, Zheng Qinwen won 8 ITF championships. He made history in his first Grand Slam tournament, reaching the second round of the Australian Open, the top 16 of the French Open, the top 32 of Wimbledon, and the top 32 of the US Open. WTA named him the &quot;Best Rookie of the 2022 Season&quot;. Because of her extremely fast rise in rankings, Zheng Qinwen was called the &quot;Rocket Girl&quot;. At the beginning of 2022, she promised to enter the top 30 in the world rankings, and at the end of the season, her ranking rose to 27th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 23, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles final of the Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) 250 Palermo Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Italian player Paolini 2-1 and won The first tour championship in her career &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) official social account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Queen Wen&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the new season starts in 2023, Zheng Qinwen vows to enter the top ten in the world rankings. In the first half of the year, she went through a difficult downturn. In the 2023 Australian Open and French Open, Zheng Qinwen failed in the second round one after another. Before the start of Wimbledon, Zheng Qinwen changed coaches, replacing Spanish coach Riba with famous Belgian coach Wim Fiset, who has coached Naomi Osaka, Azarenka and other famous players. However, the grass court season was still hard for her to win, and Wimbledon ended with a first-round trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;Although I didn&#39;t play well in the grass-court season, I don&#39;t think my (strength) will decline. I will still work hard and prepare for the next stop. Change. The team must have had an impact, but I don’t think the loss was due to the coach.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in the US Open, Zheng Qinwen went to Italy to participate in the WTA250 Palermo Station. She went all the way and won her first WTA tour-level championship in her career, and began to get out of the slump. &quot;This championship is hard-won. After experiencing failures, tears, regrets and disappointments, I finally tasted the taste of victory. I believe this is just the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a series of games before the US Open, Zheng Qinwen defeated Venus Williams and other famous players. After the start of the US Open, she quickly entered the state. Compared with before, she appeared calmer and more patient, with more swings and more frequent changes in long and short balls. She successfully broke into the top 16 of the US Open and expressed emotion in the interview: &quot;At the beginning of the year, I thought that reaching the second week of a Grand Slam was a basic operation, but I didn&#39;t expect that I would not have such a result until the last Grand Slam of the year. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, she defeated the 2022 tournament runner-up and No. 5 seed Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, creating the best Grand Slam record in her career and becoming the sixth woman in the Open era to enter the Grand Slam singles. /China Tennis Association players in the 4 finals. And this is only the second year that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in a Grand Slam event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles tennis semifinals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen signed autographs for fans&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen’s experience is a sample of the new generation of tennis players - he started playing tennis out of interest, received professional and international training since childhood, made independent choices, and did not take any detours. A relatively smooth growth process shaped her confident attitude and unruly temperament. During interviews, she often makes some sharp remarks. On August 12, 2022, in the third round of women&#39;s singles at the WTA1000 Toronto Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Andreescu 7-5, 5-7, 6-2 and entered the quarterfinals of the WTA1000 competition for the first time. When asked if he would celebrate after reaching the top 8, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;I will only celebrate after winning. I will be sad if I don&#39;t win.&quot; After the game, he talked about the match with former US Open champion Andreescu. , Zheng Qinwen responded domineeringly: &quot;I am stronger than her.&quot; When asked if he would work hard to win the US Open seed, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;It really doesn&#39;t matter. My philosophy has always been that no matter who my opponent is, I Just do your best and strive to win.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her speech became an indicator of the player&#39;s personality, and she was called &quot;Queen Wen&quot; by fans. At the US Open, fans called her &quot;Queen Wen&quot; from the sidelines. Zheng Qinwen enjoys this title very much, &quot;Of course I know, I like the name Queen Wen very much. After all, this is the Queen!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than half of the 2023 season has passed, and Zheng Qinwen is far from the top 10 in the world. There is still some distance. In an interview, she was asked why she always sets her goals very high, and why she always likes to speak out and take the initiative to withstand scrutiny from the outside world? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, in the fourth round of the women&#39;s singles match at the 2023 US Open, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated Tunisian player Jabeul 2-0 and advanced to the eighth round. Qiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen replied: &quot;Sometimes pressure is actually necessary and can motivate me to do better. . If there is no pressure and you always stay at the same level, you will not be able to keep moving forward. I play tennis because of my love. I hope that I am always in a state of progress. Top players are also constantly improving, which I admire very much. A little bit of them. I can’t imagine the pain it would cause me to stand still.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[菜鸟“单飞”：一半收入在海外，离不开阿里]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257910]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/EDsF1CaArx . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252755&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cainiao launches self-operated local express delivery business in Spain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Cainiao official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, Cainiao submitted IPO application documents to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. This is Alibaba The first spin-off and listed business after launching the &quot;1+6+n&quot; organizational reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus disclosed that Cainiao achieved 20% revenue in the fiscal years 2021, 2022 and 2023, as well as in the three months from March 30 to June 30, 2023 (hereinafter referred to as the most recent quarter). Revenue was 52.733 billion yuan, 66.867 billion yuan, 77.8 billion yuan and 23.164 billion yuan, and net profits were -1.688 billion yuan, -2.004 billion yuan, -2.325 billion yuan and 391 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, its cumulative losses in the three full fiscal years before listing exceeded 6 billion yuan, and it only turned a profit in the most recent quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s current business mainly includes three major sectors: international logistics, domestic logistics, technology and other services. From fiscal year 2021 to 2023 (ending March 30) and the most recent quarter, its international logistics revenue accounted for 55.1%, 52.3%, 47.4%, and 48.1% respectively, which are all higher than domestic logistics revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Alibaba Group, Yintai Group, Fosun Group, Fuchun Group and other Zhejiang capital circle tycoons, together with domestic express logistics companies SF Express and &quot;Three Communications and One Express&quot; jointly established Cainiao . At that time, Shen Guojun, the founder of Yintai Group, was the CEO of Cainiao Network. However, just one year later, Shen stepped down as CEO and became vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Current CEO Wan Lin joined Cainiao in 2014. Previously, he served as a senior manager of Amazon’s global logistics department. In 2017, Wan Lin officially took charge of Cainiao and made Cainiao one of Alibaba&#39;s fastest-growing business segments. Thanks to this, Wan Lin appears on Alibaba’s latest list of partners disclosed in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Betting on the international market&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Also in 2017, Cainiao’s overseas logistics ambitions began to emerge. This year, Cainiao launched its first e-Hub plan (comprehensive e-commerce logistics hub) in Kuala Lumpur, which became the gateway to the Southeast Asian e-commerce market. It mainly provides express delivery services for cross-border merchants on AliExpress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of June 30, 2023, Cainiao has established two logistics hubs with an area of ​​over 15,000 square meters around the world, located in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia and Liège, Belgium. It is expected to build a third logistics hub in Hong Kong hub. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s performance in cross-border logistics services is inseparable from Alibaba’s cross-border e-commerce AliExpress. AliExpress was established in 2010 and is known as the international version of &quot;Taobao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cross-border e-commerce practitioner in the women&#39;s clothing industry told Southern Weekend reporters that the platforms available on the market include Amazon, AliExpress, Shopee, Dunhuang, and E-bay. Due to their low cost, , early cross-border e-commerce entrepreneurs tend to choose AliExpress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amazon has the fastest transportation speed due to its large number of overseas warehouses. The goods can arrive in major European and American countries in about a week, while in remote areas it takes half a month to a month. &quot;After the express arrives at the local area, it still chooses to cooperate with the local post office, and the delivery time is determined by the local post office.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides express services to AliExpress merchants in the form of third-party services. &quot;For example, Di Sifang is owned by Cainiao express delivery company,&quot; she said. Tianyancha shows that Cainiao Network holds 45% of the shares in Shenzhen Di Sifang Information Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the prospectus, in 2022, Cainiao’s international logistics service revenue will increase by 20% compared with the previous year, and the most recent quarter increased by 41% compared with the same period last year. The main reason is AliExpress’s cross-border express service Significant growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to serving the e-commerce platform within the Alibaba ecosystem, Cainiao has also established local logistics services in Hong Kong and some overseas markets such as Spain, France, Poland and other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chishi Consulting data cited in the prospectus mentioned that the compound annual growth rate of cross-border e-commerce logistics from 2018 to 2022 will exceed that of China. In particular, China’s cross-border e-commerce far exceeds cross-border e-commerce in other regions. business. Europe and the United States are expected to become the main destinations for cross-border e-commerce products from China. In addition, Southeast Asia and Latin America are also expected to grow rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhuoshi Consulting, in 2022, Cainiao will become the world&#39;s largest cross-border e-commerce logistics company by package volume. Among the top five, there are two Chinese companies, Cainiao and EMS (China Postal Express Logistics), and the remaining three companies are from Germany, France and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the international market, Cainiao will also face challenges from SF Express and Jitu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jitu, which was just listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on September 15, has also set its sights on the global market. Jitu is a logistics company born in Indonesia. As of 2022, its express delivery services cover 13 countries, with the highest market share in Southeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, SF Express announced that it would go public in Hong Kong for a secondary listing. Before the news was released, SF Express made a large-scale acquisition of 10 subsidiaries of Kerry Logistics that engage in express delivery services in the Asia-Pacific region and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to previous media reports, since 2019, SF Express has been making continuous progress in overseas expansion, and has successively invested in Flexport, a US freight logistics service provider, and 100% equity interests in two companies, DHL Hong Kong and DHL Beijing, owned by the German DHL company. Myanmar logistics company KOSPA Limited has also established a joint venture with Indonesian Triputra Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Build the world&#39;s largest logistics network&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; According to the Cainiao prospectus, the gross profit margin in the latest quarter has increased compared with the same period in 2022, rising from 10.6%. to 13.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Its operating costs mainly include contract fulfillment costs (transportation routes, distribution, warehousing processing and other procurement and management services, that is, third-party services) and labor costs. Labor costs include employee welfare expenses and outsourced labor services, which basically account for about 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In its prospectus, Cainiao used &quot;the price of a cup of coffee to be sent around the world&quot; to evaluate the solutions it provides in cross-border logistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cross-border e-commerce practitioner told Southern Weekend reporters that the price of sending a T-shirt is 20 to 30 yuan, which is almost the same as China Post, but compared with foreign logistics companies Lower cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being cheap, the logistics solution provided by Cainiao for AliExpress merchants has also shortened the delivery time from one or two months to ten days, and some international express products only take five days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day that Cainiao submitted its IPO report, AliExpress and Cainiao launched the &quot;Global Five-Day Delivery&quot; international express product, with the first batch landing in the United Kingdom, Spain, the Netherlands, Belgium and South Korea. In other words, consumers in these five countries can receive packages from China in just five days as long as they order products with the &quot;five-day delivery&quot; logo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned practitioners said that five-day delivery of goods requires merchants to provide package online information within 48 hours of the customer placing an order. If your Internet access rate reaches the standard, you can apply to join Five-Day Delivery, and the platform will automatically allow merchants to join. It is not difficult for merchants to achieve Internet access rates. Usually after a link is created, they will stock up on some goods. Buyers can send out orders as soon as they place an order, and rookies will come to collect goods every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to reduce costs and increase transportation speed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus quoted information from Chishi Consulting. Cainiao has established the largest logistics network in the world, including two logistics hub centers of over 15,000 square meters, more than 1,100 warehouses and more than 380 warehouses. Sorting center. In June 2023, there will be an average of about 170 charter flights and board flights per week, more than 2,700 transportation routes, more than 4,400 outlets and more than 17,000 stations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology also plays a role. For example, artificial intelligence AI algorithms can improve sorting accuracy, improve inventory management, optimize route planning and vehicle scheduling, etc. In terms of smart hardware, there are RFID, smart IoT devices, automation and self-driving technologies, including AVG (automated warehousing technology) and the electric unmanned delivery vehicle &quot;Little Man Donkey&quot;. At the same time, it also provides a digital supply chain to facilitate monitoring, identifying problems, and improving efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, the autonomous driving business of Alibaba Damo Academy was merged into Cainiao Group, and some personnel were transferred to Cainiao. That is to say, both &quot;Damanlu&quot; (self-driving truck) and &quot;Xiaomanlu&quot; Return to rookie. According to the prospectus, as of March 30, 2023, more than 800 Xiaoman Donkeys have been put into use, delivering more than 10 million packages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/NzgzSpXJJwKMnxPPEpFsrvXwbWv21GI7T4uovkjt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/NzgzSpXJJwKMnxPPEpFsrvXwbWv21GI7T4uovkjt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252756&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cainiao Global Headquarters. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cannot live without Alibaba&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before IPO , Cainiao has gone through three rounds of equity financing. Alibaba Group holds a total of 69.54% of Cainiao&#39;s shares through three wholly-owned subsidiaries: Ali CN Investment, Ali KB&amp;nbsp;Investment, and Alibaba International. Currently, Cainiao is still a subsidiary of Alibaba Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao disclosed in detail its inextricable ties with Alibaba in its prospectus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba is Cainiao’s largest customer. From fiscal year 2021 to 2023 and the most recent quarter, revenue from Alibaba accounted for 29.2%, 30.8%, 28.2%, and 29.7% of total revenue respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides logistics services for multiple e-commerce platforms such as Tmall, Taobao, and AliExpress under the Alibaba ecosystem. After 2021, Cainiao will also serve merchants on well-known international e-commerce platforms and online channels (such as Kuaishou, etc.) outside the Alibaba system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus also states that due to the strategic synergy between Cainiao and Alibaba, Cainiao’s ability to maintain its ecosystem with Alibaba, or the development of Alibaba’s ecosystem itself, will have an impact on Cainiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The existing resource cooperation between Cainiao and Alibaba Group was fixed in the form of signing a business cooperation framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Includes certain intellectual property rights related to certain software and technologies used by Alibaba and Cainiao in their respective business operations. Alibaba Group provides certain backend, administrative support and shared services to Cainiao. Alibaba Cloud provides basic cloud computing services to Cainiao, and Best Logistics provides freight services to Cainiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides hardware and technical support services, warehousing and management services, comprehensive supply chain solutions and logistics services to Alibaba related parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in terms of management, rookies can still maintain a certain degree of independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Cainiao’s eight board members, Cai Chongxin, Dai Shan and Jiang Fan are respectively the chairman of the board of directors of Alibaba, the CEO and board member of Taotian Group, and the CEO and board member of Alibaba International Digital Business Group. . These three people are all non-executive directors of Cainiao Group. They do not participate in daily business management and operations and only provide professional opinions and judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the CEO of Cainiao Group, Wan Lin is also a member of the senior management of Alibaba Group, but does not hold other management positions in Alibaba Group. The remaining four members of Cainiao&#39;s board of directors also do not hold any positions in Alibaba Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[星际迷航般的传奇：“冥王号”采得小行星“贝努”样品归来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257904]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 10:53 on September 24, 2023, Eastern Time, samples from the &quot;Pluto&quot; detector returned The capsule, carrying samples collected from the surface of the asteroid &quot;Bennu&quot;, successfully landed in the desert near Salt Lake City, Utah. NASA has kept a low profile on this extremely complex and high-tech deep space exploration project and has not made any big publicity. But its mission originated nearly a quarter of a century ago, and the entire project is as weird, brain-burning, fantastic, and romantic as the science fiction film &quot;Star Trek.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1999, the NASA-funded Lincoln Near-Earth Asteroid Research Group discovered the asteroid Bennu (Bennu, the sun god in ancient Egyptian mythology). Its equatorial diameter is about 500 meters, its orbit is between Venus and Mars, intersecting with the Earth&#39;s orbit, and its perigee is about 7.5 million kilometers. This quickly attracted the attention of the U.S. Planetary Defense Coordination Office, which classified it as a &quot;potentially hazardous object.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After continuous observation and research, scientists believe that &quot;Bennu&quot; is composed of carbon and other minerals. It existed at the beginning of the birth of the solar system and is likely to contain the original molecules that existed when life on earth first formed. Matter is indeed the precious “first-hand material” of the solar system. More importantly, after repeated and precise calculations, &quot;Bennu&quot; has a 1/2700 probability of hitting the earth between 2175 and 2199, making it a high-risk space target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, NASA has formulated an exploration mission for this high-risk, high-value asteroid, which is called &quot;Origins, Spectral Interpretation (Solar System), Spectral Analysis, Resource Identification, Safety, and Regolith Exploration&quot; , Resource Identification, Security, Regolith Explorer)&quot;, meaning:. This lengthy professional name is abbreviated as &quot;OSIRIS-Rex&quot;, borrowing from &quot;Osiris&quot;, the god of the underworld in ancient Egyptian mythology, and is abbreviated as &quot;Pluto&quot; in Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, 2016, the rocket carrying the &quot;Pluto&quot; probe took off. On December 31, 2018, the probe entered the orbit around Bennu, which is only 1.6-2.1 kilometers away. This is the first time that a human probe has successfully orbited a small celestial body with such a small size, mass, and gravity for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following more than a year, the &quot;Pluto&quot; made many fine orbit changes and conducted very detailed detection of asteroids at various altitudes. In key areas of investigation, the detector flyby height Even lowering it to only 250 meters from the surface of the asteroid requires extremely high flight control technology. The detector&#39;s PolyCam camera used 2155 photos to piece together its ultra-high-definition global image with a resolution of up to 5 cm/pixel. It is the highest-definition global image of an extraterrestrial object ever obtained by humans. Therefore, &quot;Bennu&quot; It has become one of the most well-understood asteroids in the solar system so far. In late 2018, detectors found traces of water on its surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the orbiting survey is very detailed and precise, landing on the asteroid surface to sample is more difficult. NASA scientists found that the originally expected flat landing area with a diameter of about 50 meters turned out to be rocky. The possible landing area was only about 6 meters in diameter at most. Unexpected difficulty would damage the Pluto lander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists responded urgently: they changed the original plan and developed an alternative navigation and positioning solution based on optical images - natural feature tracking technology, which can fly away with the gentle gesture of &quot;a dragonfly touching the water&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2020, the &quot;Pluto&quot; probe landed in the &quot;Nightingale&quot; sampling area. The sampling head with a diameter of 0.3 meters was in contact with the surface of the star for about 6 seconds, collecting the gravel and dust particles on the surface of the asteroid, and then ignited and left. The revised contingency plan was unusually successful: the detector collected about 250 grams of samples, far exceeding the originally planned 60-gram sample mission requirement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 28, 2020, the &quot;Pluto&quot; packaged the collected samples into the return capsule. On May 10, 2021, the probe set off to return to Earth orbit with precious asteroid samples, and on September 24, 2023, it accurately and successfully landed the return capsule at the Utah Desert Experiment Base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan announced by NASA: In the next two years, 25% of the samples will be sent to about 200 scientists from many countries for research. The remaining 75% of the samples will be sealed for decades, waiting for future scientific and technological progress and the emergence of more advanced new technologies and equipment, before the samples can be taken out in batches for research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wonderful thing is that the &quot;Pluto&quot; detection mission is not over. After ejecting the sample return capsule back to the earth, it will use the earth&#39;s &quot;gravitational slingshot effect&quot; to fly to another asteroid Apophis ( Apophis, the Egyptian god of destruction and chaos). Thereafter, the mission code name of &quot;Pluto&quot; will be changed to &quot;Apophis Explorer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Apophis&quot; is a smaller but more dangerous asteroid than &quot;Bennu&quot;, with a diameter of about 370 meters. In 2029, it will pass by the earth at a high speed about 32,000 kilometers away, which is closer than the geostationary satellite at a distance of 36,000 kilometers from the ground. There is a 2.7% probability of hitting the earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asteroids with a diameter greater than 140 meters are called &quot;nation destroyers&quot;. If they hit a medium-sized country, they will be directly destroyed; even the largest countries in terms of territory will be destroyed if they are hit. Thus it declined. Asteroids with a diameter of more than 10 kilometers are &quot;planet destroyers&quot; and can smash the earth into pieces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists from the &quot;Pluto/Apophis Explorer&quot; mission team will control the probe into its orbit when the asteroid passes by the Earth on April 13, 2029, for a period of 18 months. The moon&#39;s &quot;Apophis&quot; close-up exploration will conduct a comprehensive survey in order to study the motion characteristics of near-Earth asteroids. Finally, the probe will turn on its propulsion system and stir up the asteroid&#39;s surface to study the materials and structures beneath its surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the scientist team of the &quot;OSIRIS-Rex&quot; project does not care much about the 2.7% asteroid impact rate, and planetary defense is not a research task within its project. The next step depends on whether NASA will take advantage of the opportunity of &quot;Apophis&quot; being delivered to our doorstep in 2029 to try the &quot;planetary defense&quot; project experiment again, using rocket thrust to change the orbit of the asteroid and push it farther away from the earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complexity and fantasy of the &quot;Pluto/Apophis Explorer&quot; mission are somewhat similar to a &quot;Star Trek&quot;-like journey of exploration: a vision of the future, curiosity about unknown areas, and a desire for science. Perseverance in exploration, persistence in dreams, unbridled imagination, and technical excellence...are all intertwined into a legend that is far from over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“消失”的婴儿牵出代孕贩婴暗网：涉多名儿童与东南亚代孕妈妈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257764]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/e9bfb77e42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023, in Huzhou, Zhejiang, Qiu Jiahong came again Chen Meifeng&#39;s residence. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The gestational age is more than 8 months, premature birth, black hair, a baby boy. This is all 37-year-old Qiu Jiahong knows about the children she has never met. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 23:35 on September 16, 2022, Qiu Jiahong, who had just undergone caesarean section and induced labor, woke up from general anesthesia. The child’s father, Zheng Xiaobing, told her that after The baby came out dead and was taken away by the doctor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Qiu Jiahong&#39;s account, when her originally healthy fetus was in labor, she was told by the hospital that &quot;the baby was hypoxic and had abnormal brain nerves, so it would be aborted.&quot; Half a year later, she suddenly realized something was wrong. On the afternoon of the first day of the caesarean section to induce labor, she received a phone call from a number in Huzhou, Zhejiang Province. She called twice in a row. The old lady on the other end of the phone asked her if she wanted to give her child away? &quot;It was inexplicable. I said how could I give it away, and then I died.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As many doubts emerged little by little, Qiu Jiahong suspected that she had fallen into a trap of human traffickers. It was not for nothing that she became &quot;prey&quot;. It was a reason that made it difficult for her to talk about it - the child she gave birth to out of wedlock was Zheng Xiaobing&#39;s illegitimate son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong believes that the child is still alive. She decided to follow the strange number to find her son. Unexpectedly, a combination of circumstances led to a major underground surrogacy and child trafficking case. As of September 13, 2023, the police investigating the case found that multiple children were involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hiring a private detective to find a son&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It has been raining all morning. There are few people in the gray grain and oil wholesale market and it is quiet. Most of the rows of rolling shutter doors have been pulled down. Occasionally, there are a few takeaways. Members shuttle back and forth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slim Qiu Jiahong led Southern Weekend reporters through the market, skillfully entered a nearby residential building, and followed the corridor covered with psoriasis advertisements to the door of Room 203. . This resident is the old lady who called her originally, and is now in a detention center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The old lady’s name is Chen Meifeng, 58 years old, from Putian, Fujian. Qiu Jiahong remembered that face clearly, with two arched eyebrows, deep bags under the eyes, a round face, high cheekbones, and a head of gray hair that exploded at the shoulders and was held up with a hairband. She is on the plump side, and in winter she often wears a black mink coat and wears black boots with strong soles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Six months ago, in February 2023, Qiu Jiahong hired two private detectives. The three drove from Shanghai to Huzhou, Zhejiang to find Chen Meifeng’s residence, trying to find her son who disappeared from the hospital here. She recalled that she had been squatting downstairs for a week in the cold weather, but she had never seen Chen Meifeng carrying her five or six-month-old baby boy out and about once. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confrontation with Chen Meifeng occurred on the 8th day of their stay. On February 23, Qiu Jiahong blocked Chen Meifeng at the door of Room 203 early in the morning, who was returning from a walk: &quot;Aunt Chen, do you recognize me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No,&quot; Chen Meifeng&#39;s Mandarin was mixed with a strong Putian accent. Accent, she politely invited the visitor to sit in the house. The old man was cooking for his granddaughter, and the house was a little messy. Qiu Jiahong glanced around the room, but there was no baby boy. She asked again, &quot;Then where did you get my number?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Meifeng finally understood Qiu Jiahong&#39;s purpose. &quot;I haven&#39;t called her before,&quot; she said, and then muttered, &quot;I don&#39;t remember.&quot; At Qiu Jiahong&#39;s insistent request, Chen Meifeng was accompanied to a nearby mobile business hall to retrieve communication records within six months. Qiu Jiahong&#39;s phone number indeed appeared in it, and the call time was 16:29 on September 15, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ed9bdd81dc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;One ​​early morning in February 2023, Chen Meifeng took her granddaughter back to the house. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong did not pay attention at the time. Before and after Chen Meifeng called her, she made three phone calls to the same person. , and later found to be the number of Chen Yongjin, director of Zhejiang Meifubao Women&#39;s and Children&#39;s Hospital (hereinafter referred to as Meifubao Hospital). On September 16, 2022, Qiu Jiahong gave birth at Meifubao Hospital in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, Qiu Jiahong learned from the police that the two were fellow Putian residents. Chen Yongjin’s response to this matter was, “Maybe I told Chen Meifeng (Qiu Jiahong’s contact information), but I’m not sure.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong remembered that after the caesarean section, Three days later, Yu Yanfen, the surgeon who performed the surgery, walked into her ward to do some daily routine. &quot;I was in a bit of a daze because of the pain. She chatted with me for two hours, asking me what my brothers and sisters did and what my husband did. How did we meet? We talked like one of our own people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;After a series of reflections, I felt something was wrong. She must have come to my ward to inquire about information. &quot;Qiu Jiahong determined that the child was alive, but was sold by Chen Meifeng and Mei Fubao Hospital; her boyfriend Zheng Xiaobing was also suspected of &quot;giving away&quot; the child, so the two had a dispute and parted ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Faced with Qiu Jiahong and the private detective questioning her child&#39;s whereabouts, Chen Meifeng cried, &quot;I really don&#39;t remember (calling Qiu Jiahong), I never did it ( Abduction and trafficking of Qiu Jiahong’s son).” In a live video on February 23, Chen Meifeng offered, “How about we go to the police station.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That night, Qiu Jiahong Reported the crime and Chen Meifeng was arrested. The next day, the Huzhou South Taihu New District Branch of the Huzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau, Zhejiang Province issued a decision on filing the case: According to the provisions of Article 109 of the Criminal Procedure Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, it was decided to file the case of abduction and trafficking of women and children in the South Taihu New District. reconnaissance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Six months later, the police investigating the case told Qiu Jiahong that Chen Meifeng mainly made money from selling babies and surrogacy business. As for the sale of children, investigation has revealed that many children were sold, and the case has been taken seriously by the Ministry of Public Security. Although the surrogacy business is illegal, it is not a criminal act and is therefore not within the scope of this police investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Southeast Asian surrogate girl behind the door&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was an accident to expose Chen Meifeng’s surrogacy nest . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong and his party did not get much information during the time they were stationed at the grain and oil wholesale market: they were probably Chen Meifeng and his wife, his son and daughter-in-law, and his two granddaughters. A family of six lives here. They rarely go out and don&#39;t like to greet their neighbors. Occasionally, the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law would take turns driving a black BMW to go out. The most frequent place they went to was the nearby Huzhou Maria Maternity Hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong discovered that every evening, Chen Meifeng would carry her little granddaughter around to the back row and disappear into Room 407 of another residential building. At one o&#39;clock, we returned to room 203. During the day, Chen Meifeng’s daughter-in-law would ride an electric bike to and from the front and back houses twice, carrying her lunch box. When the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law leave room 407, they will insert the key into the door hole and twist it several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first few days, Qiu Jiahong heard the cry of a baby in Room 203, where Chen Meifeng was humming to comfort the child. The small milk box hanging at the door will receive a box of fresh goat milk for babies every morning. After a few days, the crying completely disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiu Jiahong guessed that the crying sound belonged to her son. It was probably because of the commotion that Chen Meifeng placed the child in Room 407 in the back row. &quot;One night, I followed and listened secretly. There were many people&#39;s voices inside, and I felt something was wrong.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If she hadn&#39;t seen it with her own eyes, she wouldn&#39;t have thought anything of it. You would believe that behind the door of Room 407, there are actually three surrogate girls from Southeast Asian countries, all about 20 years old, and two of them have big bellies. When Qiu Jiahong saw them, they were lying on the bed, using their smartphones without phone cards installed. The furnishings in the house are messy. When you open the refrigerator, you will find a lot of miscarriage and blood-replenishing medicines. There are discarded medical materials in the trash can. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a video recorded by Qiu Jiahong and a fellow private detective after entering the house on February 23, a woman who calls herself Lili is silent at first, and then Expressing in unskilled Chinese, I am from Vietnam and am 6 months pregnant, while the girl on the bed next to me is 3 months pregnant. On the bedside table between the two of them was a box of capsules for the prevention and treatment of iron deficiency anemia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked how much money she could earn by giving birth to a child, Lili replied, &quot;I don&#39;t know. I haven&#39;t given birth yet. I won&#39;t know how much money I will pay until I give birth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She She said that she found Chen Meifeng through her sister&#39;s introduction, &quot;My sister gave birth here and she has gone back after giving birth. She gave birth to a girl and she said she had more than 20,000 (RMB).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another woman living in the attic of 407 said she was introduced to her by netizens on short video software. In a video, the woman said she had just arrived and was not pregnant yet. &quot;Someone introduced me here and asked Aunt Chen to help me find a job, so I came here.&quot; The contact information of the person who introduced her here has been lost because &quot;the phone has no card and the phone number has been deleted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, Huzhou police found out that two of the surrogate women were from Cambodia. &quot;Both girls came here with visas and got married here. For surrogacy, both parents (buyers) provide sperm and eggs, and they just borrow the mother&#39;s body.&quot; On September 13, a Southern Weekend reporter accompanied Qiu Jiahong there When the Huzhou Kangshan Police Station inquired about the case, a police officer from the police station said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/8bab885593.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/8bab885593.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huzhou, Zhejiang, Room 407, where a Southeast Asian surrogate woman once lived. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Surrogacy in some Southeast Asian countries such as Thailand is cheaper than in China, and the price of domestic pregnant mothers has been skyrocketed. It’s very high.” Lao Cheng (pseudonym), the person in charge of an underground surrogacy agency, told Southern Weekend reporters that domestic pregnant mothers generally come from relatively poor areas. “We are looking for those between the ages of 25 and 32 who have given birth to one child. Lord”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the process, every time Lao Cheng receives pregnant mothers, he will arrange for them to undergo a full physical examination first. &quot;Those who are qualified will stay with us, and as soon as they get their period, we will let them take fertility drugs at an early stage, establish an artificial cycle, monitor the endometrium, and find a suitable opportunity to arrange embryo transfer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a complete surrogacy industry chain, it includes buyers, pregnant mothers, surrogacy agencies, private laboratories used for test tubes, and maternity hospitals that can issue false birth certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Human Assisted Reproductive Technology Specifications&quot; revised by the former Ministry of Health in 2003 clearly stipulates that any form of buying and selling of gametes, zygotes, embryos, medical institutions and medical personnel is prohibited No form of surrogacy technology is allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, this regulation is only binding on medical institutions and medical personnel, and cannot prevent organizations and individuals outside medical institutions from implementing surrogacy. The Civil Code does not explicitly regulate surrogacy, and surrogacy has become an underground business that wanders in a gray area all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;To put it bluntly, when we do this, you (the buyer) and I (the seller) have no risk, because we are in a blank area of ​​​​the law. All risks are concentrated Among doctors and medical institutions, firstly, during the in vitro fertilization process, the sperm and egg must be transplanted to the pregnant mother, which is very risky; secondly, during the subsequent production process, the hospital needs to write down the child’s birth certificate as written by both of you and your husband (buyer). ) name is also risky.&quot; Lao Cheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For customers who want to find a surrogate mother in Shanghai, Lao Cheng offers a surrogate price of 680,000 yuan, and the customer can specify the gender of the child for an additional 80,000 yuan. &quot;Public hospitals are more strictly monitored and it is not easy to operate test tubes. Basically, they are done in smart laboratories outside. If you require that the test tubes must be done in a public tertiary hospital, we can also arrange it and add 80,000.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Chen Meifeng&#39;s husband Wu Yuzhang, Chen Meifeng once wanted to open a surrogacy store in Putian. In November 2020, she registered Putian Tianding Health Management Co., Ltd. in her hometown. “There is no (surrogacy) here in Putian, let’s see how to open one. After registering, if it doesn’t work, it won’t be open.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter visited It was discovered that this was a small and micro enterprise located in a residential area with no signboard or facade. Because it failed to publish its annual report in compliance with regulations twice, the company has been included in the list of operating abnormalities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A midwifery hospital&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 10, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter met in Putian on the pretext of looking for a surrogate mother. We arrived at Wu Yuzhang, who is currently on bail awaiting trial. The 60-year-old man lives in his hometown with his son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We haven&#39;t done it (surrogacy) for a long time. We only did it for a year and stopped doing it.&quot; When he learned that the visitor was looking for Chen Meifeng, Wu Yuzhang He became more vigilant and said, &quot;I haven&#39;t been out at home in the past few years. She works in Shanghai. I can&#39;t figure out where she is.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The living room in front of him It was empty, with a handbag from Huzhou Maria Maternity Hospital hanging on the toy pony on the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Wu Yuzhang’s account, Chen Meifeng and him made shoe molds at home more than ten years ago. “We set up a factory ourselves and hired more than 30 workers. She is in charge of all the money.&quot; After her son went to study, Chen Meifeng proposed to earn money outside, saying that a friend in Putian introduced her to the hospital business. It was a job of driving patients from place to place to see a doctor. Sometimes I would also introduce patients from one hospital to another, earning a small referral fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huzhou Maria Obstetrics and Gynecology Hospital is Chen Meifeng’s relatively regular place of work. The staff of the hospital also confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters, “Chen Meifeng used to bring people here for medical treatment. , I haven’t seen her in the past six months.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She knows how to see a doctor. She went to the hospital for training for several years. The doctors there gave her training, especially what kind of diseases girls have. She knows what kind of medicine to take and how much it costs.&quot; Wu Yuzhang said that Chen Meifeng went to high school and knew a lot, and even applied for a passport. &quot;She specializes in dealing with obstetrics and gynecology hospitals. She is familiar with many hospitals in Zhejiang and Shanghai, as well as tertiary hospitals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The other side of this job , is to find suitable babies for sale in the hospital. According to police insiders, in the baby trafficking chain, Chen Meifeng plays the role of &quot;sales introduction&quot;. She runs around several hospitals all year round, and the doctors involved in the case privately provide her with information about parents who induce labor or plan to abandon their babies after delivery. She then persuaded and coaxed these parents to give birth to children and leave them to her disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Chen Meifeng was arrested and implicated me. I was arrested on the spot by the police for investigation. The police thought I was colluding with Chen Meifeng to sell babies, but in fact I only accepted surrogates.&quot; On September 22, Chen Yongjin told Southern Weekend reporters that after Chen Meifeng was arrested, many doctors in Mei Fubao Hospital were taken away by the police to take notes. The doctor who performed Qiu Jiahong&#39;s caesarean section was Yanfen has resigned. &quot;She was also punished at that time. Anyway, this matter was quite big.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/488eb09656.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/27/488eb09656.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhejiang Meifubao Women&#39;s and Children&#39;s Hospital located in Hangzhou . (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Industrial and commercial information shows that Meifubao Hospital was established in January 2016 with a registered capital of 30 million yuan. Private maternity hospital. Chen Yongjin joined as the legal representative in August 2016, and the original legal representative Chen Chunlai withdrew. Also changing the legal representative to Chen Yongjin was Chen Chunlai’s Zhejiang Meifubao Health Management Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Chunlai is one of the 10 largest shareholders of Shanghai Medicilon Biopharmaceutical Co., Ltd., a well-known listed pharmaceutical company. Public information shows that Chen Chunlai is also the younger brother of Chen Chunlin, the general manager of the listed company. Like several other core executives surnamed Chen in Shanghai Medici Biotech, they all come from the Chen family, one of the &quot;Four Great Families in Putian.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Before the accident, we accepted many surrogates, but now we no longer do them.&quot; Chen Yongjin said that in the past, Chen Meifeng often brought some pregnant women to Meifubao Hospital delivery. Every time a surrogacy business is accepted, it means that the hospital has to forge a birth certificate and fill in the name of the buyer in the column of the baby&#39;s parents. &quot;Of the dozen or so children she sold, about four or five were born here. She told me that these children were all surrogates, and after they were born, they sold them privately.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Surrogacy and child abduction are two different things. As far as our hospital is concerned, I dare to do (play) borderline things. If I am found out, I will be fined at most, but I absolutely dare not We have done something completely illegal. Our daily turnover is 300,000 yuan, and our annual turnover is 10 billion. Such a large hospital cannot take this risk.&quot; Chen Yongjin emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that Mei Fubao Hospital has never participated in Chen Meifeng&#39;s trafficking Children&#39;s illegal behavior was not previously known to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 15, 2023, the Hangzhou Gongshu District Health Bureau fined Mei Fubao Hospital for failing to fill in and keep medical records as required. 140,000 yuan. The penalty decision also mentioned that from January 28, 2021 to March 27, 2022, Mei Fubao Hospital issued 6 false birth medical certificates, which constituted a violation of the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;That&#39;s 6 (children delivered under the name of surrogacy). Chen Meifeng brought more than 6 children, and there were many others. It might be true There may be test tubes, but there may be others, but we don’t know yet,” Chen Yongjin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As to whether Meifubao Hospital is involved in child trafficking, neither the Gongshu District Health Bureau nor the police disclosed relevant information, nor was it mentioned in the above-mentioned penalty decision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/d3a9ed3cb5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;747&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/d3a9ed3cb5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Floor of the Obstetrics and Gynecology Department of Mei Fubao Hospital. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She thinks it is not trafficking, but doing good deeds&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Today, few people in Chen Meifeng’s hometown village in Licheng District, Putian City, know her name. There are few pedestrians in the deep part of the alley. On both sides of the bluestone brick road are small cement buildings of certain age. Some living rooms with open doors worship Mazu or the God of Wealth, and the air is filled with the smell of incense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“The original village was demolished and everyone moved out.” An elderly villager told Southern Weekend reporter, “She hasn’t been back for many years. I heard that they are doing medicine outside.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Chen Meifeng left, Wu Yuzhang said that because of the bulk sales of shoe molds, customers had too much credit and could not get back hundreds of thousands. , and I won’t do it anymore. He rented out his three-story building and two warehouses, collecting rent of more than 100,000 yuan a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, Wu Yuzhang went to Huzhou, Zhejiang, to work as a logistics supporter for Chen Meifeng. He was responsible for buying vegetables, cooking and cleaning the house every day. &quot;I asked her once or twice (about business), and she said why are you asking so many questions? You can just spend it if you have money, and you still care about so much.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yuzhang doesn’t know everything. “(Surrogacy) women are too hard to find. We also found them from Kunming, Yunnan. It’s not easy. They (Chen Meifeng, etc.) also went to Thailand to do (surrogacy business) before. , Thailand may be more expensive.&quot; Wu Yuzhang said vaguely that buyers can choose the gender of the baby in advance, and the price is between 550,000 and 600,000 yuan; the surrogate buyer watches the surrogate girl from pregnancy to delivery, with a total quotation of 650,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, this is a price slightly lower than the market price. Southern Weekend reporters asked a number of underground surrogacy agencies. The starting prices are all around 700,000 yuan, but these agencies all said that all pregnant mothers come from China and there are no channels for foreign pregnant mothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How much money can Chen Meifeng get from a surrogacy business? Will she buy and sell ready-made babies through hospital channels? Wu Yuzhang expressed that he “can’t figure it out”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The aforementioned police insider said that in the child trafficking transaction, Chen Meifeng would price a child from hundreds of thousands to 20 to 30 yuan based on the child&#39;s health. It ranges from 10,000 yuan to 20,000 yuan, and she gets a commission from a few thousand to 20,000 to 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of September 13, the police found multiple children who were bought and sold by Chen Meifeng and had traceable traces. All of them had obtained the biological parents of the children before selling them. agree. &quot;She believes that doing this is not kidnapping, but doing good deeds. Because while she doesn&#39;t want children, she also needs children. She gives the unwanted children to those who need them, and she connects people along the way and collects hard work.&quot; Therefore, Chen Meifeng transferred all her children to those who needed them. Transaction records and chat records are preserved. To her, these are proof of &quot;good deeds&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ten years ago, after being arrested, Tan Yongzhi, the main criminal in the huge case of abduction and trafficking of women and children supervised by the Ministry of Public Security, also claimed that he was doing good deeds. &quot;I help people. When people want children, I help them. I don&#39;t directly find people to sell children.&quot; According to CCTV News, from 2008 to 2013, Tan Yongzhi organized or participated in the sale of 22 children, each of whom The selling price of the children ranges from 15,000 to 50,000 yuan, and Tan Yongzhi earns referral fees ranging from 1,000 to 6,000 yuan per order, making a total profit of more than 100,000 yuan. In the end, the Henan Higher People&#39;s Court sentenced Tan Yongzhi to death, and the Supreme People&#39;s Court approved it in 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The aforementioned people familiar with the matter said that unlike abduction in the traditional sense, Chen Meifeng’s child abduction and trafficking case was of an adoption nature. In Chen Meifeng&#39;s past transactions, a pair of parents sold their children for 170,000 yuan, and Chen received several thousand yuan in &quot;milk powder money.&quot; Later, the parents thought that 170,000 yuan was too little, so they went to Chen Meifeng to beg for more money. If they didn&#39;t pay more, they called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter called Huzhou Kangshan Police Station to inquire about the progress of the case. The police said that the case was investigated by the Huzhou South Taihu New District Branch of the Huzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau, and other information could not be disclosed for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Another version&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some of the children trafficked by Chen Meifeng suffered from congenital diseases or disabilities, and some were born out of wedlock.&quot; Not easy to deal with.” But there is no son of Qiu Jiahong among them. The police found no relevant clues in Chen Meifeng&#39;s transaction records and chat records in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Chen Meifeng&#39;s statement disclosed by the police, when Qiu Jiahong disagreed with the sale on the phone, Chen claimed to have given up the idea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The child just died. According to her wishes, the child was aborted and sent to the crematorium.&quot; Regarding Qiu Jiahong&#39;s son, Chen Yongjin told Southern Weekend The reporter&#39;s version is another version: Qiu Jiahong initially asked customer service whether she could abort the child, saying that the child had &quot;some problems&quot;; on August 22, 2022, she hesitated when she came to the hospital for an examination, and about a month later said she was sure to abort. Drop the child. &quot;There was a man (Zheng Xiaobing) who came with him, and his attitude was to abort the child.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We only have one problem, the law stipulates 28 Fetuses over 10 weeks old cannot be induced, so we changed Qiu Jiahong&#39;s gestational age in the medical records to be smaller, and everything else is true.&quot; When Southern Weekend reporters asked about the whereabouts of Qiu Jiahong&#39;s son, Chen Yongjin asked: &quot;If the child is alive, we She needs a birth certificate. The criminal police have already investigated and found out the buyers and sellers of more than a dozen children. Is she missing a child?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/19be07c4b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/19be07c4b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 15, 2019, the regulatory authorities decided to impose penalties on Mei Fubao Hospital. (Information map/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to a survey by the Hangzhou Gongshu District Health Bureau, since April 2022, Meifubao Hospital has not issued B-ultrasounds. Inspection report sheets, falsification of second-trimester gestational age and other methods are used to induce labor in pregnant women with a gestational age of more than 28 weeks. The specific induced labor data is not registered and it is difficult to collect statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The penalty decision made public by the Gongshu District Health Bureau also mentioned that from September 15 to 16, 2022, Mei Fubao Hospital was the actual gestational age. At 37 weeks and 2 days, Qiu Jiahong underwent amniocentesis to induce labor with mifepristone combined with ethacridine injection and cesarean section to remove the fetus. In this regard, Qiu Jiahong said, &quot;I only took two mifepristone tablets, which did not work at all, and I did not take an induction injection (ethacridine injection).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;After Qiu Jiahong repeatedly asked about the case, the police told Qiu Jiahong that the investigation of Chen Meifeng&#39;s case was now nearing completion, but in the existing evidence, there was no clue that her baby was a live fetus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We have all asked Zheng Xiaobing, Chen Meifeng and Xiao Mazai, who helped Chen Meifeng, and there is no clue about the child.&quot; September 13, 2023, When mentioning the child&#39;s father, Zheng Xiaobing, the policeman at the police station said: &quot;The person who knows (the child&#39;s condition) best is that person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After that, a Southern Weekend reporter called Zheng Xiaobing asked if he knew the whereabouts of the child. The other party said, &quot;I don&#39;t know about this matter&quot; and hung up the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;September 16 was the day when the child turned one year old. Qiu Jiahong drove alone to a village on the outskirts of Shanghai to find a fortune teller. After the fortune teller saw the trend of a few incense and smoke, he told her that the child was still there, and Qiu Jiahong felt a little more at ease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[藏在温州的中国皮鞋大王，卖不动国产平价男鞋了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257655]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Wenzhou, Zhejiang, Jiangnan Leather Factory has closed down&quot;, an advertisement once circulated in the streets The words express the sadness of Wenzhou leather shoes today. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wenzhou leather shoes were once a symbol of the quality of domestic men&#39;s leather shoes in the last century. Aokang, a listed company bred in this small town, once became the leading company in Chinese men&#39;s leather shoes. It has been on the market for 11 years and is 35 years old. Recently, it has encountered a &quot;mid-life crisis&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of August 30, Zhejiang Aokang Shoes Co., Ltd. (abbreviation: ST Aokang, 603001.SH) released its 2023 semi-annual report. In the first half of the year, ST Aokang’s revenue was 1,644.4523 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 12.22 %, and the net profit attributable to the parent company was 8.9976 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 177.59%. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, behind the overall red financial report is the &quot;great damage to vitality&quot; caused by the sharp decline in revenue that has lasted for many years and negative growth in 2022. In 2018, Aokang&#39;s total revenue was 3.043 billion. In 2022, the total revenue will be only 2.754 billion, and the net profit margin is even negative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to stabilize its market share, Aokang launched sports leather shoes in the first half of this year, inviting top celebrities to endorse and Dior designers to perfect the design. However, sports leather shoes that combine traditional leather shoes with sports shoes are difficult to sell. Make Aokang &quot;change his destiny against heaven&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taobao data shows that the price of Aokang sports leather shoes is on the high side, and the number of payers is relatively small. The best-selling celebrity sports leather shoes have more than a hundred people paying for them, while the other products have only a few people paying. ten people. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Aokang, the domestic men’s leather shoe market is facing a collective winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2016, China&#39;s leather shoe production has declined and overall development has been weak. The market share of men&#39;s leather shoe brands has continued to decrease. The market share of the top ten companies in terms of business scale has decreased from 10.1% in 2011. to 6.9% in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the market for sports and leisure shoes continues to expand, almost doubling from 269.1 billion in 2018 to 425.1 billion in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the impact of sports and leisure shoes, domestic men&#39;s leather shoes also lack the competitiveness to compete with international brands. Among the top ten best-selling men&#39;s leather shoe brands in 2020, only two are from mainland China, while the other brands come from Hong Kong, the United States, Italy and other countries or regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Domestic brands are mostly sold for less than 500 yuan, and national brands such as Aokang and Red Dragonfly are priced at 300 to 400 yuan. They cannot get a share of the cake of the sinking economy, and it is difficult to attract high-end markets. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should domestic men’s leather shoes break the situation? Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk to you about the direction of domestic men&#39;s leather shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3d9e82ef980e7678295ac22ad6b76b93.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;714&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3d9e82ef980e7678295ac22ad6b76b93.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252087&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/23abd593b2401fc57833a7c9e203bc32.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/23abd593b2401fc57833a7c9e203bc32.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252088&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/466b2ad01f88ffcfc590e84bb112e2f1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/466b2ad01f88ffcfc590e84bb112e2f1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252089&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c2196879c0165b00f135042ae2c094d3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c2196879c0165b00f135042ae2c094d3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252090&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/44ef440319b8979b6ff10d7d39a653fd.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/44ef440319b8979b6ff10d7d39a653fd.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252091&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c53fe59139d68e72ca1a7f6d364baa72.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c53fe59139d68e72ca1a7f6d364baa72.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252092&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/e27f3596b415c5b1870b43e90b0cf1d1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/e27f3596b415c5b1870b43e90b0cf1d1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252093&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[月神是帅哥还是美女？我们每个人都是半个月球人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257900]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The moon, as the closest celestial body to us and the only satellite of the earth, always seems to give us a sense of distance and distance. An unusual sense of closeness. Astronomers believe that the moon and the earth had a super close contact in the beginning of time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was an ancient dwarf planet in the early solar system, located at the Lagrange point of the earth-solar system, which was almost the same as As big as Mars. According to the giant collision hypothesis, about 4.533 billion years ago, the dwarf planet was perturbed by the gravity of Jupiter or Venus and deviated from its original position and collided with the early Earth. The debris produced by the collision eventually formed the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This ancient dwarf planet is often nicknamed &quot;Theia&quot; by Western astronomers. This is the name of a Titan goddess in Greek mythology who was the mother of Selene, the moon goddess. If we compare it to Chinese mythology, we may call this dwarf planet &quot;Chang Xi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the birth of the moon in Chinese mythology, many people will think of &quot;Pangu opened the sky and used his eye as the moon.&quot; However, this setting actually appeared quite late. It was first seen in the Wei, Jin, Southern and Northern Dynasties: &quot;In the past, when Pangu died, his head was the four mountains, his eyes were the sun and the moon, his fat was the rivers and seas, and his hair was the vegetation.&quot; In older myths, , Chang Xi is the goddess who gave birth to the moon. She combined with the god Di Jun and gave birth to twelve moons. The earth&#39;s revolution period around the sun is exactly twelve times the moon&#39;s revolution period around the earth. Therefore, most peoples in the world divide the year into twelve months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the coincidence of the revolution period, the changes of lunar eclipses and lunar phases provide more inspiration for earth mythology: the legend of &quot;Tengu Eclipses the Moon&quot; has long been familiar to the Chinese people; coincidentally, in In Nordic mythology, there is a similar story of &quot;Sirius swallowing the moon&quot;: The wolves hated the light created by God, so a wolf named Skull chased the sun. When a solar eclipse occurred, Skull swallowed it. sun. Another wolf named Hati was responsible for chasing the moon, and when he caught up, a lunar eclipse occurred. At this time, people on the ground will beat gongs and drums to scare away the wolf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Australian Aboriginal mythology, the moon god is often described as a beautiful man who gradually becomes fat due to laziness (full moon). At this time, his wife, the Sun Goddess, would chop him with an ax. Although the Moon God will hide in a big tree, he will eventually die and will be resurrected 3 days after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the moon god Chandra in Indian mythology is also a suave and beautiful man. Legend has it that he had twenty-seven wives and promised to love each of them equally. However, after marriage, Luna broke her promise and only loved one of her wives, and refused to listen to her repeated advice. This resulted in complaints from the other twenty-six wives. The life of the Moon God disappeared due to the curse. When he was about to disappear, the Moon God sadly prayed to Lord Shiva. Lord Shiva restored the life energy of the Moon God through blessing; however, since the power of the curse cannot be taken back, the Moon God must go through the process of gain, fullness, food and loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from a global perspective, handsome men on the moon are considered non-mainstream. Most of the moon gods in various countries are beauties. For example, in ancient Chinese mythology, the moon goddess is named &quot;Wangshu&quot;, and she drives a moon carriage across the sky every night. &quot;Huainanzi&quot; also adds, &quot;Yueyu is called Wangshu, and it is also called Xian&#39;a&quot;. Literally explained, &quot;Wangshu&quot; means &quot;good-looking&quot; and &quot;Xian&#39;a&quot; means &quot;beautiful and good-looking&quot;. It can be seen from these two names that the ancients obviously believed that the Moon God was a beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This setting is not surprising. Compared with the sun, the moonlight appears white and cold. In addition, the moon&#39;s revolution cycle is similar to the female menstrual cycle, so it is reasonable for people to imagine the moon goddess as a beautiful woman. Selene in ancient Greek mythology was not only a beauty, but also drove a moon carriage. Among the Romans, the name of this moon god was Luna - the word &quot;luna&quot; representing the moon and the lunar calendar originated from this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the beauty of the moon goddess, most Chinese people will immediately think of Chang&#39;e. But Chang&#39;e is not actually called this name, and she is not the Moon God at all: Chang&#39;e is just a general name for the Fairy of the Moon Palace. She is the maid of the Moon God rather than the Moon God herself. Chang&#39;e&#39;s name was originally written as Chang&#39;e. Later, in order to avoid the taboo of Emperor Liu Heng of Han Dynasty, it was temporarily changed to &quot;Chang&#39;e&quot; simply because the two words &quot;hengchang&quot; have similar meanings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taboo avoidance in the Han Dynasty was not strict, and taboo avoidance was only a temporary expediency and should be changed back later. But I don’t know whether it was because Emperor Wen of the Han Dynasty was too beloved by the people, or because of the strong cultural influence of the Han Dynasty, a series of &quot;constant changes to the ordinary&quot; are still used today:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first sentence of the &quot;Tao Te Ching&quot; &quot;The Tao can be Tao&quot; , non-constant Tao&quot; is still written as &quot;Very Tao&quot;; the &quot;Snake of Hengshan&quot; in &quot;The Art of War&quot; has always been written as &quot;Snake of Changshan&quot;, and Changshan Zhao Zilong has become an allusion; and Chang&#39;e&#39;s name is also called Today, Chang&#39;e has become a rare word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also the Han Dynasty when Chang&#39;e was forced to change her name, and Queen Mother Xi replaced Wangshu and became the new Moon Goddess. Then Taoism rose, and Taiyin Xingjun became the new moon god. This Taiyin Star King is said to be the Moon Mother Chang Xi. But whether it is the Queen Mother of the West or the Lord of Taiyin, they are all images of old women. The public obviously doesn&#39;t buy this, and still retains the impression that Luna is a beautiful woman. Therefore, it is not surprising that the &quot;Fairy Chang&#39;e&quot;, as a young maid, has replaced her boss and is regarded by everyone as the real moon goddess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In folk classics, Chang&#39;e always holds the Jade Rabbit in her arms. However, when it comes to seniority, it may be more reasonable to have the Jade Rabbit holding Chang&#39;e - the legend of the rabbit inside the moon is widely spread in East and Southeast Asia. The ancient Chinese books are among the earliest to record the legend of the Moon Rabbit. &quot;Chu Ci·Tian Wen&quot; says: &quot;What virtue is there in the moonlight, when death brings fertility? What is the benefit of the moon, but the tutu is in the belly?&quot; Therefore, the legends of various countries in East Asia and Southeast Asia The legend of the Moon Rabbit probably originated from China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Native Americans on the other side of the Pacific also spread the legend of the Moon Rabbit, which is even more magical: In Aztec mythology, Quetzalcoatl once descended to earth for training and almost died of hunger and thirst. At this time, a rabbit offered himself as food to save his life. Quetzalcoatl was moved by the rabbit&#39;s noble dedication, and after restoring his divine power, he promoted the rabbit to the moon god. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many versions of the Moon God in Mayan mythology, but almost all the images of the Moon God are holding a rabbit. After the arrival of Western colonists, the Mayans were unwilling to change their beliefs, and even stitched together Christianity and Mayan mythology: the sun god became Jehovah, the moon god became the Virgin Mary, and the corn god became Jesus Christ—I don’t know. How should they explain why Maria always held the rabbit? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many scholars believe that the legend of rabbits in the moon comes from the imagination of the shadow on the moon. However, so many ethnic groups around the world have various imaginations about shadows. For example, Europeans think that shadows look like a human face. Only the groups on the east and west sides of the Pacific believe that shadows resemble rabbits, which is too much of a coincidence. Therefore, some people also suspect that the legend of the Moon Rabbit may have been widely circulated among the ancestors as early as when the Native Americans left East Asia. Native Americans arrived in North America about 12,000 to 23,000 years ago. Based on this calculation, the legend of the Moon Rabbit may have been circulated for tens of thousands of years, and even now it has actually landed on the moon:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1969 Before Apollo 11 landed on the moon, the astronauts in the cabin mentioned Chang&#39;e and the Moon Rabbit in their conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lynton Johnson Space Center: There is a lot of important news about the Apollo this morning, and one of them calls your attention to a cute girl with a big rabbit. According to an ancient legend, a beautiful Chinese girl named Chang&#39;e has lived there for 4,000 years. It is said that she was exiled to the moon for stealing her husband&#39;s elixir of life. Perhaps her companion could be found - a huge Chinese rabbit, which always stood in the shade of the laurel tree and was easily spotted. The rabbit&#39;s name was not reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Astronaut Buzz Aldrin: OK, we&#39;ll keep an eye on that bunny girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country&#39;s lunar rover was also named &quot;Jade Rabbit&quot; to pay tribute to this beautiful and ancient myth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, our fate with the moon goes beyond that. According to the latest large collision theory, the ancient dwarf planet did not collide with the ancient Earth, but a head-on collision. The two planets were completely destroyed, forming the asteroid belt between the orbits of Mars and Venus, and then combined to form the Earth and the Moon. This also explains why the core accounts for such a large proportion of the Earth, because the core of the dwarf planet and the core of the Earth later merged into one, and the Earth&#39;s water may also come from the dwarf planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, each of us is actually half a lunar person - or half Theian/half Changxi person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[济南城投公司一次性售1341套现房，房从哪来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257906]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/RCBkXjPTUSHgAgP7TQ7gS7NWtD7htfWp74i5jRj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/RCBkXjPTUSHgAgP7TQ7gS7NWtD 7htfWp74i5jRj6. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252757&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jinan is full of high-rise buildings. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 22, 2023, at Qilu International Building, Jinan City, Shandong Province, Jinan Urban Development Group Assets Operation Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jinan Chengfa) has opened bids for a project - recruiting housing marketing agents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The project is selling 1,341 units of commercial housing, with a total area of ​​about 166,000 square meters, involving 4 properties, and developers include Greenland, Longfor, Poly, etc. Based on the average listing price in September, the total value of these properties exceeds 2.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that these houses are all existing houses and are first-hand residences. The project tenderer, Jinan Chengfa, is not a developer, but an urban investment company engaged in real estate development and operation, and is 100% owned by the Jinan Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only in Jinan, on September 21, 2023, the Beijing Equity Exchange auctioned and transferred 154 properties. The transferor was the Beijing Chaoyang District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee, and the source of the assets was &quot;physical assets of administrative institutions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where do local urban investment companies and government departments get their housing from? Why are they for sale? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The product of &quot;competitive construction&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Lin Gang has worked in the Shandong branch of a national real estate company for seven or eight years. This time Jinan City Among the four properties for sale are projects of his company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters that the hundreds of units for sale in the project were resettlement houses built by real estate companies during land auctions, and were transferred to Jinan City Development after completion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the real estate market was booming in the past few years, real estate companies were vying for land across the country. In order to control land prices, local governments often limited the maximum price for land auctions. After the local auction reaches the maximum price, if the winner has not yet been determined, there will be a &quot;competition for self-sustaining&quot; and a &quot;competition for construction&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;competition for construction&quot; means that after the developer&#39;s land quotation triggers the maximum price, it turns to competition for the construction area of ​​affordable housing. The one with the largest construction area is the winner. The housing provided is owned by the local government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Gang recalled that the above-mentioned land was purchased around 2018. In order to successfully bid, the company built two buildings as resettlement houses in a community of two to three thousand households, which increased the cost by more than 60 million yuan. But after the house was put on the market, the market price dropped and the entire project lost money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Jinan had just begun to implement &quot;competitive construction&quot;, which was still a minority in the country. Many cities usually use a lottery method to determine the winner after the land price triggers the maximum price limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Gang said that Jinan’s “competition for construction” has continued until now. In addition to the projects developed by his company, other properties sold in Jinan City Development this time are also the product of &quot;competition for construction&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;competition-to-build&quot; housing was originally used as local affordable housing. Especially since the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Accelerating the Development of Affordable Rental Housing&quot; in 2021, various places have accelerated the financing of affordable rental housing. Listings. In August 2022, Jinan Chengfa publicly purchased 3,000 units of commercial housing as rental reserves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Lin Gang admitted that the rental effect of the resettlement houses built by his company in the community was not good. The above-mentioned project, which was put up for sale by Jinan Chengfa, was completed in 2020. In 2022, I heard that two buildings would be used for lease by the government. The owners who had already moved in expressed their opposition and were worried that the mix of tenants would affect the community environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Some owners have come up with a plan and want to build a wall in the community to separate the two supporting buildings.” Lin Gang said that the owners’ opinions were fed back to Jinan Chengfa. The other party did not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are no companies near the community, it is not convenient for office workers to rent here and commute. The rental rate of the two resettlement houses has not been high. For Jinan Chengfa, this means limited rental income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the downturn in the real estate market, Jinan’s government fund income, which mainly comes from land sales, has been almost halved. Data from the Jinan Municipal Finance Bureau show that the city’s government fund revenue fell to 54.7 billion yuan in 2022 from 101.6 billion yuan in the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There have been very few land auctions in Jinan in the past four or five years.” Lin Gang said that under the influence of real estate regulation and the new crown epidemic, major real estate companies are shrinking, and Jinan’s land auction market continues to be cold. In order to maintain the team, his company has only acquired two pieces of land in Jinan in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In its prediction of the fiscal revenue and expenditure situation in 2023, the Jinan Municipal Government pointed out that fiscal operations are still in a state of tight balance, and the pressure to increase revenue, reduce expenditure and prevent risks is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to alleviate the contradiction between fiscal revenue and expenditure, the Jinan Municipal Government proposed in the 2023 budget report to increase the profit handover ratio of municipal state-owned enterprises to 20%, and transfer the municipal-level state-owned capital operating budget to the general public budget proportion increased to 35%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Jinan Chengfa, who has a house in hand, the income from selling houses is obviously more substantial than renting. Taking the housing listings in Huatongyuan Community in Greenland as an example, Anjuke showed that the monthly rent for a three-bedroom apartment of about 140 square meters is 5,000 yuan, and the rent per square meter is about 38 yuan/month. If sold, the new house price is 22,000 yuan/square meter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters called Jinan Chengfa many times, but the staff declined the interview because the person in charge was not available. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Revitalizing idle properties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Actually, this is not the first time Jinan State-owned Assets has sold commercial housing. In July 2023, the Dongcheng Yijia Community developed by Jinan Urban Construction Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jinan Urban Construction) was put on sale. Another property owned by the company, Xijiang Huafu, also announced that it will be launched for sale in the second half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the equity penetration, Jinan Urban Construction is 90% owned by the Jinan State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission and 10% by the Shandong Finance Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two communities are called &quot;civil servant communities&quot; in Jinan. Southern Weekend reporters consulted in the name of home buyers. The sales staff of Jinan Urban Construction Yi said that the two communities combined have a total of about 12,000 units, which were completed and delivered in 2016 and 2019. Half of the building was previously sold to civil servants, and the remaining half has been vacant until 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Dongcheng Yijia Community has more than 4,000 units for sale this time, and Xijiang Huafu has more than 1,000 units, which are expected to be officially launched after the National Day holiday. &quot;The two properties were originally off-plan properties and were sold internally by civil servants around 2013. The selling price was equivalent to the market price at that time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Lin Gang was still working as a real estate reporter for a newspaper in Jinan. &quot;When I got to know this community, people had already chosen a house.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Jinan hosted the 11th National Games and built a new Olympic Sports Center in the east of the city as the main venue. After the National Games, the Jinan Municipal Government also began to move eastward, moving into the Long&#39;ao Building, which is more than 100 meters away from the Olympic Sports Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Civil servants from Jinan Municipal Government units subsequently moved to Longao Building to work. Many civil servants did not have houses or lived far away. In order to meet the housing needs, two residential communities, Dongcheng Yijia and Xijiang Huafu, were built. Judging from the distance displayed on the map software, the two communities are both within 3 kilometers of Longao Building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, the Ministry of Finance issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Revitalizing State-owned Assets of Administrative Institutions&quot;, requiring the implementation of the government&#39;s tight living requirements and accelerating the revitalization and utilization of various state-owned assets such as houses, land, and vehicles. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, more than 5,000 units of existing houses have been put on the market in two communities, Dongcheng Yijia and Xijiang Huafu, and Jinan&#39;s property market has been shocked. &quot;This is amazing. The total number of online new houses signed in Jinan a year is only 40,000 to 50,000 units.&quot; Lin Gang sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned Jinan urban construction staff said that the current price of a small apartment of 95 square meters in Dongcheng Yijia is about 25,000 yuan/square meter, and the price of a large apartment of 175 square meters is about 29,000 yuan/square meter. Data from Lianjia.com shows that this price is lower than second-hand houses in the same area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Because these two communities are all rough housing.” She said that in the two months since Dongcheng Yijia went on sale, more than 400 units have been sold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Gang said that these two communities were built earlier, and the unit designs are not outstanding, which has also lowered the price to a certain extent. However, it has a superior location and is equipped with a high-quality school district. It is still popular after being listed and has a certain impact on surrounding second-hand houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 154 properties transferred by the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee of Chaoyang District, Beijing are similar to those in Jinan. This batch of properties is located in the China Railway Construction International City Community, and the listing price is also lower than the price of second-hand houses in the same community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Economic Observer&quot; report, after the completion of China Railway Construction International City, some houses were repurchased by Chaoyang District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee and other units, with plans to use them to solve the housing problem of employees. Later, it was not fully implemented as planned, and some of the houses remain vacant to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Staff from the Chaoyang District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee provided Southern Weekend reporters with the phone number of the person in charge, but no one answered the call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Lin Gang is a pseudonym at the request of the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[掰掰告别狮子林桥后，天津还有哪些快乐？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257898]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[东亚家庭的悲剧与温情，全程哭着看完]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257890]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The son who has been away from home for many years suddenly received a call from his old man. How will he face the call from his mother who wants to take a posthumous photo and explain what happened after her death? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary &quot;House of God&quot; from Taiwan starts with this phone call and reveals the painful past of a family. The son in the film is the documentary director Lu Yingliang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/5e40d477465b42d4a99706cdccee27b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1542&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/5e40d477465b42d4a99706cdccee27b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252723&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film is in Last year, it won four awards including the million-dollar first prize, the Best Documentary Award, the Best Editing Award and the Audience Choice Award at the Taipei Film Festival. It was also enthusiastically received during the film festival in Switzerland, and it also has a good score of 8.3 on Douban. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the film cuts into the native family from the director&#39;s perspective and shows every detail of rural life, many people compared it to the 2017 &quot;Four Spring&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to similar themes, similar perspectives, and both being filmed over a longer period of time, the emotional undertones of the two films are actually very different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/551c0fa59ff4e2e0b15fb68fce76c31b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/551c0fa59ff4e2e0b15fb68fce76c31b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252724&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Four &quot;Spring&quot; is like a simple literary utopia. We long to grow up in such a family, enjoy the influence of music, and have a warm life like the director; and &quot;House of Gods&quot; reproduces another situation of East Asian families - There was no dialogue, they tortured each other, and after &quot;living&quot; based on instinctive consciousness, they escaped from this cursed place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother who is thin and works all day long; the father who has nothing to do and is addicted to lottery tickets; and the brother who is just muddling along and accomplishing nothing. Director Lu Yingliang does not directly show the desperate state of these family members, but through a &quot;god&quot;. A rare perspective that reflects everyone&#39;s inner world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the director&#39;s hometown, there has always been a strong belief in gods, and the Lu family attaches particular importance to it. They have a separate room upstairs for worshiping a shrine and an incense altar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/355fc9f42b250a57564de8f63af746e6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;613&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/355fc9f42b250a57564de8f63af746e6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252725&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this source When Yu Lu Yingliang&#39;s brother was 12 years old, he suddenly became &quot;psychic&quot; and was chosen by the gods. He became a celebrity who traveled far and wide to seek guidance from gods. For many years after that, in addition to farm work, my brother also worked part-time as a fortune teller for others, and the Lu family became connected with the gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But through the director’s lens, we will find that family members have different attitudes towards gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my mother is in poor health, she still climbs up and down every day to worship the gods. When asked repeatedly by her son why she persisted, she said lonelyly: &quot;In the past, when your brother left home, you and your father were not at home. Your sister went to work, and I was the only one left at home. They were all there to accompany me.&quot; Me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/a599f88aa86a6400037aa147b2a4c52d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/a599f88aa86a6400037aa147b2a4c52d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252726&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Unlike his mother&#39;s simple emotional sustenance, his father is utilitarian towards gods. He always wanted to guess the numbers from the smoke coming out of the incense and use it to buy lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My brother, who has been dealing with gods for half his life, gradually fell into an embarrassing situation on camera. The film specifically uses the &quot;little tomato incident&quot; to expose the conceptual gap between the two generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before planting tomatoes, my brother specifically asked the gods for instructions on the farming date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/224bc1a4bc313d1d17b872c64c05f5a5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/224bc1a4bc313d1d17b872c64c05f5a5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252728&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But right here Not long after the fruit seedlings were planted, heavy rains for days flooded the farmland, but the gods did not play any role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young nephew was unwilling. He first said angrily that he had stopped believing in gods for a long time, but soon after, he burst into tears, hoping that his brother could ask the gods to find a solution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elder brother did not want to deceive his son, but in order to soothe the next generation&#39;s uneasiness and confusion, he could only pretend to have a breath with the gods, saying that Hua Tuo would greet his friends and solve the dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, God becomes the comforter of this ordinary family. When the family finds no hope in reality, the more they place their hope on the gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/9b655e87cb3cd81be4aa2e6434d3b5a0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/9b655e87cb3cd81be4aa2e6434d3b5a0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252727&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a director When my brother was doing farm work, he asked in despair and confusion: &quot;Do you really think God has helped our family? Or should I say, is there really a God?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are few Chinese speakers. The film explores such metaphysical themes, not to mention situating this discussion among members of a rural family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we don’t need to compare &quot;House of God&quot; with religious films such as &quot;First Reformed&quot; and &quot;The Last Temptation of Christ&quot;. Director Lu Yingliang does not have this ambition. The reason why he Raising this question is based on his despair for his original family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/efcf3ab445698828ae8311d7db21a9fb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/efcf3ab445698828ae8311d7db21a9fb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252729&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang&#39;s father He almost never fulfilled his responsibilities and only knew how to idle around. Even because of gambling debts in his early years, the whole family had to move. Although his elder brother was good-hearted, he lacked ability and failed to start his own business several times. He had to borrow money to pay off the debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang had no choice but to work hard in a big city at the age of 18 and almost never came back because he knew that once he fell into this house of gods and men, he would become the same as those god tablets and become the entrustment of the whole family. &quot;hope&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the beginning of the film until the middle and later stages, Lu Yingliang rarely appears in the picture. He basically communicates sparsely with his family in voice-over, and is full of confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation did not change until my father was suddenly diagnosed with cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/e1175bd37c5b0692749d2ef4e85ea3f8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/e1175bd37c5b0692749d2ef4e85ea3f8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang finally decided I helped my parents take photos of their deaths, and when choosing photos, I had a rare conversation with my father, and the family sat together, a rare moment of warmth and harmony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe this scene will make many people cry secretly, because its tenderness uses the photo of the deceased (death) as a bridge to connect. The resentment that had been built up for many years gradually dissipated, not because the Lu family was on the right track, but because his father would eventually pass away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a sad ending for an East Asian family. Just like the recent &quot;That Time a Ghost and I Became Family&quot;, the father played by Tuo Zonghua finally opened his heart because Mao Bangyu had passed away. Regret makes people put aside their prejudices and their attitudes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/13e3dceb1b845daa801316bac97ef234.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;605&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/13e3dceb1b845daa801316bac97ef234.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《神人Near the end of &quot;Home&quot;, Lu Yingliang finally returned to the home that had made him frustrated. He tasted the sweetness from the tomatoes grown by his brother, and took his mother on a train to see the sea, fulfilling her long-cherished wish. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The place where this old woman lives is actually only a few dozen kilometers away from the coastline. Apart from her wedding photos, she only had one young and beautiful photo when she was young. All her life since then has been dedicated to it. Three children and a useless husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there is a god in &quot;House of Gods&quot;, then it is Lu Yingliang&#39;s mother. She is the real glue of this family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/c659b1d78540742f7908265a93145cec.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/c659b1d78540742f7908265a93145cec.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252730&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Watch &quot;God When reading &quot;Human Home&quot;, it always reminds me of Huang Zi&#39;s &quot;Xiaowei&quot; and Dapeng&#39;s &quot;Auspicious Ruyi&quot;. One of these two films is an art film, and the other is a documentary in the form of a meta-film, but to some extent, they both belong to the category of private family films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creators of these films have honestly presented the disease, death and discord among members of the native family, whether it is long-term silent hostility or uncontrollable tension. It all reminds us of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;House of Gods&quot; may not be called a blockbuster of the year, let alone a high achievement in terms of images, but the sincerity of emotional expression is indeed something that has not been seen for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Lu Yingliang went from watching his family worshiping gods with a cold eye, to shifting his perspective away from the gods and towards his parents and brothers. This change in perspective is clearly visible. This tells us invisibly that he no longer carefully observes himself and his family in a binary opposition, but chooses to recognize his former identity and accompany his mother on the endless coastline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当幼儿园的儿子变得“社会”时，父亲在想什么丨养儿育女]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257882]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My son, who is in the third grade of kindergarten, came back from school one night and told me in a low mood: Dad, I can’t do it tomorrow. Because I was talking to my classmates today, the primary teacher who was supposed to be on duty tomorrow was assigned to another classmate by the teacher. I said it didn&#39;t matter, there would be another chance in the future, and then I pulled him with a smile to get ready to play. Unexpectedly, my son scolded me for my passive and careless attitude. He said no, so he would do it one less time. He would not be able to talk nonsense to his classmates next time. I was stunned for a moment. It was really I wonder why he is so interested in being a little teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under my gentle questioning, my son told the truth that he wanted to be a primary school teacher: because this way he could control other children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answer surprised me. It was clearly a sign of a desire for power. I heard that this is a kind of power given by teachers to children who perform well in order to facilitate daily management. Children who serve as primary school teachers can help the teacher supervise other children, mainly in that they can criticize children with irregular behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to indoctrinate my son and tell him that this idea was wrong. As soon as I said one sentence, I was already lacking in confidence and knew that my dogmatic words would be contradicted by him. I changed my way of saying this: When you are a primary school teacher, you should serve the children. When you find a child making a mistake, don’t scold him loudly, otherwise the other person will be sad. You should speak in a gentle tone. The son said very maturely, I understand. It seems that he has become accustomed to the rules of this little teacher&#39;s game, which I did not expect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that being a primary school teacher is sometimes difficult. Once, he and a classmate were both primary school teachers. His good friend was called out by the classmate when he was speaking. He wanted to be accommodating, but was rejected by the classmate. This made him very distressed and didn&#39;t know what to do. Another time, he criticized a classmate when he was a primary school teacher. A few days later, the classmate deliberately called his name when he was a primary school teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was stunned when I heard these stories. I was at a loss and felt very familiar at the same time. Isn’t this the epitome of the workplace for us adults, and it is too “social”. My son didn’t understand what I meant by “society”. I told him that what the other person did was wrong and you can’t do that. I asked a few friends who have children and they reported similar situations. The only comfort I can find is that such a mechanism can restrain children from some irregular behaviors in class, but it may not be effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe children don’t want to become too “social”. Sometimes they have no choice like us adults, or they are trapped in it without knowing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother of her son’s classmate told me something: Once, my son told her that one day her child was punished by the teacher at school to stand in the back of the classroom and talk to other children. She asked my son, how did you know, and he said without hesitation that the teacher made us stand while we were talking together. After listening to it, we burst out laughing. We were thinking about saying goodbye to others, but we suddenly exposed ourselves. Perhaps this is a contrast between &quot;society&quot; and innocence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, children’s world is becoming adult, and children experience the rules and confusion of adult society prematurely. When we face our own problems, we usually appear powerless or messed up. When our children encounter the same situation, how can we expect them to be perfect? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I went to pick up my son from school one day, he happily said that today he was on duty as a student. I thought to myself, what&#39;s so good about being a duty student? Isn&#39;t it just voluntary labor? But he told me that being a student on duty was to help the teacher sweep the floor and arrange chairs. It was a task assigned to him by the teacher, and it was a supreme honor. Thinking about children&#39;s &quot;society&quot;, there may be a gratifying point, that is, the threshold for happiness is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently I watched a movie online called &quot;Goodbye, Our Kindergarten&quot;. In the movie, the kindergarten children sang a song at the graduation ceremony, &quot;We have spent countless days here. Every night, we laughed many times, cried many times, caught cold many times, we played here with so many dear friends, we ran here, fell here, fought here, goodbye to our Kindergarten, this is our playground.” The singing and lyrics moved me very much. Kindergarten should be a pure and happy playground, with less social fetters and worries. I recommended this movie to my son. He refused at first, but when I told him that it was about a few children going on an adventure to visit a good friend who was seriously ill, he expressed great interest. That weekend afternoon, because there was no Mandarin dubbing, I read all the lines to him with great emotion. After the movie ended, he said he was going to cry. I knew that he must have the same empathy for other people&#39;s sadness and happiness as the children in the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a worker in the cultural industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(&quot;Raising Children&quot; in the &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of the Southern Weekend App, welcome Write a letter to share the scenery and principles you have learned as a parent and teacher on the way your children grow up. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 22:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打工人为什么越来越反感团建？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257819]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464su8Xku.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;920&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464 su8Xku. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Absurd Show&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;18 faces are on the ground, 18 hands are stretched out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18 employees in black team uniforms lay flat on the stage of a hotel conference hall, pointing in a worshiping posture to the judges&#39; seat where the team&#39;s appearance is scored - the seat of the training instructor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high scores given by the judges were like a black hole, sucking eight teams composed of employees into endless rehearsals and competitions. It seems that after being assigned the team names of &quot;War Wolf&quot;, &quot;Electric Wolf&quot; and &quot;Wild Wolf&quot;, people&#39;s wolf nature can be stimulated. The salesperson who doesn&#39;t like to exercise stacked up four layers of arhats without safety protection; the girl who usually speaks slowly and quietly yells &quot;Hello everyone&quot; while kicking in goose steps to compete for the glory of the team; to express her love for the company Out of gratitude, a team simply knelt down collectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The door to the conference hall was pushed open by the diligently practicing team members before 8 o&#39;clock in the morning, and was reluctantly closed until 1 o&#39;clock in the morning. Rehearsing exhaustingly, just so that one of the teams can show the most unique posture, the neatest steps, and the loudest slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The team building organized by the company made Li Yang a performer of spectacle. Before, he couldn&#39;t believe that he would show his style as &quot;falling headfirst&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang is a salesperson at a private lighting company. When he sees videos displayed by other teams on Douyin, he always sneers at those exaggerated actions. Unexpectedly, the person in the video now is himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an ordinary weekend in August 2023, in Changzhou, Jiangsu, under the threat of salary deduction from the personnel department, Li Yang and more than 200 other colleagues boarded the team-building bus angrily. In the hotel where the team was built, they devoted themselves to all activities day and night, without any fear of leaving behind hoarse voices, bruised limbs, and colds, as if everything was done willingly from the beginning. The anger of being forced to &quot;work overtime&quot; and the 100 yuan of self-funded team building fees seem to be just small hurdles that need to be overcome in the process of &quot;soul sublimation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sublimation of training activities is to let employees learn to be &quot;thankful&quot;, which is the appeal of the company boss. Li Yang recalled that this team building did sometimes touch the soft hearts of some employees. Listening to the training instructor&#39;s exaggeration, an employee who had left his hometown had an epiphany with tears in his eyes: he should regard the company as his &quot;home&quot;; the boss carried two employees on his back and ran panting around the venue to simulate the &quot;hardship of starting a business.&quot; Li Yang will also feel compassion when he sees it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, reason reminded him that these sensational points are more like the fog lingering on the abnormal logic: &quot;The mentor said that the boss runs on the back of his employees, just like when he started a business, he carried the burden for his employees. Why do I think it&#39;s the other way around? It&#39;s obviously the employees who are carrying the boss&#39;s weight forward. The instructor just wants us to feel guilty and work hard.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang does feel guilty, but This has nothing to do with the company&#39;s favor, but more to do with one&#39;s own actions against one&#39;s will. He confessed that he did not understand the value of these games, but he became the component that maintained their operation; he knew the mentor&#39;s &quot;lies&quot;, but accepted his every instruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving his previous company, this is Li Yang’s first year at this company and he has not yet established himself. He didn&#39;t dare to stand up and refute anything, &quot;I can&#39;t be the kind of person who dares to be the first in the world.&quot; Seeing a group of &quot;post-00&quot; colleagues sneak away in the night after experiencing the first day of training, Li Yang&#39;s feet were still nailed In place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who stayed behind, like Li Yang, carried out their &quot;behave&quot; to the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Life and Death Grid&quot; with &quot;team collaboration&quot; as the training purpose: nearly 300 people pass through the same net hole one after another. If someone touches the net, everything will be cleared and restarted. The whole process lasted for more than 4 hours, with the supervisor interrupting again and again and the team members numbly repeating the devastating actions. Meditation designed to teach people self-reflection: While everyone was meditating in soothing music, a dozen training assistants suddenly rushed out of the darkness and cursed at the employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang doesn’t have many complaints about his boss, the initiator of team building. What he dislikes the most is &quot;Brother Guo Shi&quot;, the training instructor who issues orders and designs courses - a man in his forties with unknown educational background and qualifications, who calls himself &quot;the master&quot;. &quot;He likes to ask us closed-ended questions, and his catchphrase is &#39;understand the applause&#39;, just like a pyramid scheme.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Employees of Li Yang’s company conducted a team presentation&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brother Guo Shi appeared with his head held high among a group of &quot;teaching assistants&quot; kneeling. On the podium, he emphasized that as long as Obey, don&#39;t argue, he has the power to eliminate anyone. A female employee in her fifties fell to the ground from exhaustion while being punished in a game (doing hundreds of push-ups). Instructor Guo yelled at those who came to help and urged the punished to complete it alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Instructor Guo is just one of the symbols of this closed venue. Along with him, suppressing the free movement of participants, there are banners hanging on the four walls: &quot;To love him is to strictly demand him&quot;, &quot;There is no you and me, only us&quot; &quot;If you don&#39;t provide results, the boss will bear the consequences&quot;; There is a game mechanism with bonuses for the top three, more than 200 uniform black T-shirts, and a queue shouting louder than the other. Li Yang explained, &quot;Although it seems absurd, in that environment, everyone did it, and you had no choice but to follow it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Today&#39;s team building is not training&quot;, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “bad money drives out good money”, this is the evaluation of the current team building market by Xia Hui, general manager of the experiential training institution Renzhongren in South China&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The loneliness of experiential training&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;No matter whether the experience is good or bad, &quot;team building&quot; is something that most migrant workers avoid today. I am afraid of the shackles of the workplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nothing new to rely on rationality to undergo certain magic operations in team building like Li Yang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A steady stream of companies send their employees on team-building tours that are infuriating and humiliating. On the Internet, every once in a while, there will be hot searches such as &quot;slapping each other&#39;s face team building&quot;, &quot;kowtow to the leader team building&quot; and &quot;cruel survival team building&quot;. What was once shocking news is now commonplace. They seem to form a part of our country&#39;s workplace culture, to an extreme degree and in a stable state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Today’s team building is not training”, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “Bad money drives out good money”, this is Xia Xia, General Manager of South China Region of Renzhongren, an experiential training institution. Wei’s evaluation of today’s team building market. Rather than “team building”, people in the industry prefer to use “experiential training” to refer to these corporate team trainings designed to challenge oneself, build a team, and improve performance. Xia Hui said that &quot;team building&quot; was originally just the name of a course in experiential training. Because it is designed with low difficulty, broad goals, and high demand, it has gradually become the most popular type among peers. Among them, games and activities are the easiest to imitate, so &quot;team building&quot; has become synonymous with various activities of corporate teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market is filled with all kinds of experiential trainers. Some, like &quot;Instructor Guo&quot;, specialize in corporate courses and are good at using chicken soup stories and game commands to establish themselves as authorities; some have switched careers from military training instructors and continue to enjoy the unique field control of this job in outdoor projects. more often, they act as &quot;tour guides&quot; in relaxed team-building trips. They rarely make guidance summaries, and their faces are vague in the minds of employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, there is currently no unified and official professional qualification certificate for experiential trainers to enter the industry. Training institutions set entry thresholds for trainers, and they all do so in their own way. Xia Hui said that perhaps we will see many &quot;team building alliances&quot; that have introduced some trainer assessment standards, but those are all &quot;private certifications.&quot; Renzhongren&#39;s trainers will undergo half a year of training courses and half a year of internal assessment before officially taking up their posts. Mr. Hu from Shaanxi relied on his previous experience as a military training instructor and self-study online to expand his training knowledge. He was able to work directly in a company he knew well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei, general manager of Shanghai Zhongji Development, feels dismayed by the uneven qualifications of trainers. &quot;Some colleagues distort experiential training into military training and devil training. It is not like this. It should be relatively mild.&quot; What he deplores even more is the loneliness of the golden age of experiential training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When experiential training was introduced from Europe and the United States to mainland China via Hong Kong 28 years ago, it was not as notorious as it is today. At that time, it was a niche, professional, high-level industry that was easily recognized by customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To find a true etymology for experiential training, it is Outward Bound. “Outdoor Development” and “Outward Bound” were both its translation names. Overseas, its identity is not a business-oriented service, but an education model. Its predecessor was the Seamen’s School of the same name founded by German-Jewish educator Kurt Hahn in Wales during World War II. Hann believes that the one-month wilderness survival training can allow trainees to break through themselves, hone their will and form a close team bond through &quot;personal experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first company in China to try something new is Renzhongren. In 1995, Renzhongren introduced Outward Bound to China, turned it into a corporate training business, promoted it in China, and registered the trademark &quot;Outward Bound&quot; for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders call the most prosperous decade of the experiential training industry at the beginning of the 21st century the &quot;Expansion Training Era.&quot; In 2004, when Lin Wei first entered the industry, experiential trainer was a profession with a halo. Most of those who came to participate in the first round of interviews with Lin Wei had a master&#39;s degree or above, including many with Ph.D.s and even university teachers who worked part-time during the winter and summer vacations. Undergraduate students with a background in education or psychology may also be selected, but it is best to have more than three years of work experience. After the first round of careful selection, the remaining 12 candidates will go to the base to receive a one-month training course. While attending class, he was eliminated. In the end, only five people were left in formal positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What attracted Lin Wei to join the industry was the high salary and dignity that this career brought. In 2004, the average monthly salary of a white-collar worker was around 5,000 yuan, but a Shanghai trainer who gave 15 classes a month could earn a salary of more than 20,000 yuan. A course lasts for 1-2 days, and one trainer is responsible for leading more than ten students. Whether they are ordinary employees or wealthy entrepreneurs, they all respect trainers as &quot;teachers&quot; - not through preaching, but through guidance and encouragement, allowing students to transcend previously unreachable limits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the classic project of high-altitude broken bridge, students need to climb an 8-meter-high shelf, walk on a broken narrow board, and jump from one end to the other. Of course, this is while wearing a fall arrester. Whenever students tremble at the take-off point due to fear of heights, Lin Wei would say soothing words on the edge of the bridge, teach them to take a deep breath, lower their posture, and tell them &quot;it can be done.&quot; During the review session, Lin Wei will summarize the students&#39; performance and explain the psychological mechanism behind the game, &quot;By breaking through situational pressure and expected pressure, people can get out of their comfort zone and grow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Students and training The trainers were reluctant to leave when they left. They even cheered and threw the trainer high into the air. Lin Wei believes that &quot;obtaining such great recognition from people in such a short period of time is unmatched by other professions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Lin Wei can no longer see the reverence he once had in the eyes of his students. and admiration, &quot;They no longer call trainers teachers, but &#39;coaches&#39; instead. However, this is not a position for training people&#39;s skills.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Kanzhun.com, currently, experiential training in Shanghai The average salary of a teacher is around 13,000 yuan. Lin Wei told Southern People Weekly that most of the original batch of high-quality trainers have now switched to in-house training (a type of corporate consulting that focuses on the right medicine and focuses on theoretical explanations). What left with them was Lin Wei&#39;s enthusiasm, a passion that &quot;sees that the peers around me are all excellent and I can learn a lot from them.&quot; He doesn’t understand why fitness coaches can also be trainers. “Physical fitness is not the focus. Improving mental understanding through experience is the purpose.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experiential training has low investment threshold, high income, and market demand. Large, various activity courses are also easy to copy. The sinking of &quot;high-end industries&quot; has led to the industry attracting many profit-seekers, but there is a lack of internal regulatory constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Customers favor fun activities and do not care about the &quot;training value&quot; behind them. To adapt to this, the proportion of business expansion training courses that require carefully designed outlines and emphasis on educational content is decreasing; the proportion of simple entertainment team building (such as simple games, fun sports, themed activities) is increasing. Entertainment team building accounts for 50% of Renzhongren’s business and as high as 70% for Zhongji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei pointed out that current team building is like letting participants simply watch a movie. While watching, their emotions fluctuated greatly; after leaving the theater, what happened in the dark had no impact on their future lives. &quot;Actually, the sharing session after the movie is the most valuable. The previous training was to guide the students to talk about these &#39;movie-viewing experiences&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On a personal level, Kang Ying The team building she participated in was regarded as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring the relationship between employees and the company closer &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team building is not that Important&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying, who returned from the United States six years ago, was full of child-like desire to explore when she first came into contact with team building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from college in 1999, Kang Ying has been working in the United States. He returned to China in 2017 and worked as a director in two domestic pharmaceutical companies. In recent years, she has unlocked team building, a unique domestic employee collective activity. &quot;I think it is very fresh and fun, so I am more involved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, Kang Ying is still grateful for the desert hike two years ago. The spiritual wealth that team building brought to her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, 15 kilometers, Dunhuang Gobi. For Kang Ying, who doesn&#39;t usually exercise much, this is an astronomical figure. After learning about the team building content, she almost had the idea of ​​resigning. At that time, she was pulled into a WeChat group by the service provider, which was designed to prepare for the subsequent hike. The trainer requires employees in the group to clock in and start running one kilometer every day. Mileage gradually increases until 8 kilometers per day. Colleagues check in together and encourage each other. Kang Ying gritted her teeth and persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This activity even helped her develop an exercise habit. &quot;It&#39;s hard to imagine that without this group, I would be able to run 8 kilometers alone. After that, I successfully lost 20 pounds and my whole body has reversed growth. It seems that I have really developed some perseverance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The long journey in the desert exhausted Kang Ying’s physical strength gained through running, and also allowed her to experience friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hiking activity starts at 7 a.m. and plans to cover 15 kilometers along the &quot;Xuan Zang Westbound&quot; route in 8 hours. After only 3 hours, Kang Ying could no longer move her legs. In her 46 years of life, she felt the despair of being physically exhausted for the first time. Looking up at the huge sandy slope, she paused in a daze. Suddenly a colleague&#39;s voice came from beside him: &quot;Don&#39;t think too much, step on this sand nest with your left foot, step on that one with your right foot, and climb up step by step.&quot; The other colleagues were not in a hurry and stopped to tell them Her knack for climbing. The trainer encouraged her while handing her water. The slope was finally over. The mutual-help friendship forged under difficult circumstances continues to this day. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I thought about it afterwards, and it&#39;s the same at work. As a superior, when I need my team&#39;s subordinates to overcome difficulties, I shouldn&#39;t threaten them: If they can&#39;t do it, come see me with your head raised. . You should stand in their shoes and give more specific guidance. Even if it is as simple as &#39;step your left foot first and then your right foot&#39;.&quot; Kang Ying concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kang Ying regards the team building she participates in as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring employees and the company closer. Effects such as &quot;strengthening employees&#39; sense of belonging to the company&quot; and &quot;deepening their recognition of corporate culture&quot;, in Kang Ying&#39;s view, are all illusions created by team-building advertisements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the desert team building helped the company accumulate some goodwill in Kang Ying&#39;s heart, then this goodwill has been completely lost in the lazy working environment and workplace factional struggles. Kang Ying believes that the CEO&#39;s behavior is the factor that actually affects a company&#39;s corporate culture the most. If the CEO notices that his subordinates are blaming others, but fails to stop them, blaming behavior will continue to occur in the company. Kang Ying&#39;s direct boss in the company is the general manager, but she once received a message from the human resources department: the group CEO wanted her to be his eyes and ears - to report all the general manager&#39;s activities at any time, including his private life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she thought that the leaders might be burying spies and scheming, but the company was always happy to organize team building and create a scene of concerted efforts, Kang Ying began to question the meaning of team building itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also two years ago, the company failed in financing and carried out large-scale layoffs. Kang Ying lost her job. The mountains I climbed, the speeches I heard, the games I fought, and the philosophies I learned were like a dream, leaving nothing behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying said that it is too reluctant to expect to gain a &quot;sense of belonging&quot; in the company through team building. If she can work in a company for more than ten years, she will naturally feel &quot;home&quot; about it. But in the past two years, she didn&#39;t know if the company would one day abandon her. A team building session cannot resolve this sense of crisis. Kang Ying believes that if employees show emotional dependence on the company, it is most likely a performance to &quot;show compliance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, team building is not only a performance by employees to their superiors, but also a performance by the company to the outside world. A staff member of Renzhongren revealed that when many customers book experiential training services, it is more for promotional purposes. With an excellent video team, multi-camera shooting, high-end equipment, and skilled editing, team-building activities are recorded as blockbusters and become advertisements for recruiting new members. The actual feelings of the actors are not important, and it is not important whether the training purpose is achieved. What is important is to show to the outside world that &quot;this is an exciting and accomplished collective activity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wearing a mask may be a survival rule for some people. Some people are also trying to take off their masks. In August 2023, a company in Hunan was worried that group travel would cause discomfort to some employees, so it changed the payment to 3,500 yuan per person, which can be freely disposed of; the personnel of a company in Chengdu discovered that when the boss arranged a weekend team building, no one After signing up, a full vote was initiated and the event was scheduled for Friday afternoon. They don&#39;t know yet what they will lose, but they seem to have regained a little bit of the fun they had been deprived of before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Li Yang, Teacher Hu, Kang Ying, and Bobo are all pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>