<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“基辛格不会有第二个，但基辛格的担忧却会不断重复”丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 15:11:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency and other media reports, on November 29, 2023 local time, former US Secretary of State Henry Kissing Gerard died at his home in Connecticut at the age of 100. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just two months ago, Kissinger was still mediating the conflict between Russia and Ukraine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 24, local time, according to the &quot;Ukrainian Pravda&quot; report, Ukrainian President Zelensky met with former US Secretary of State Kissinger during his visit to the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Andrei Yermak, director of the Ukrainian Presidential Office, posted the above news on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger visited China in July and attended the Bund Financial Summit online on September 23. Southern Weekend once published &quot;Mediating the Russia-Ukraine Conflict, Centenarian Kissinger&#39;s Achievements and Controversies | Think Tank Perspectives&quot;, and the old version is now reposted as a mark of commemoration. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is Kissinger still active?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The world today is facing huge risks, unlike any risks since the Cold War. Previous risks, whether the United States sent troops to Afghanistan or Iraq, occurred between world powers and small and medium-sized countries, and the risk of escalation is unlikely. But this time, it has become a confrontation between world powers and a strategic confrontation between nuclear powers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the Russia-Ukraine conflict and the Great Game between Russia and the West behind it have had a strong impact on the post-Cold War world order. The conflict between Russia and Ukraine marks a serious challenge to the post-Cold War world order. On the other hand, this is also the first indirect confrontation between Russia and the US and Western camps after the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Yermak&#39;s account, Kissinger told Zelensky during the meeting, &quot;Before this war, I opposed Ukraine joining NATO because I was worried that it would set in motion the war we are seeing now. process (the outbreak of the conflict). Now this process has reached such an extent that the idea of ​​​​keeping Ukraine neutral in this situation no longer makes sense.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time Kissinger has mentioned Ukraine joining NATO. On May 17, The Economist published an exclusive interview with Kissinger. During the interview, Kissinger stated that he supports Ukraine&#39;s membership of NATO. He also said: &quot;Ukraine should continue to be protected by Europe, rather than becoming an isolated country that protects itself on its own.&quot; Regarding Russia, Kissinger said, &quot;If I talk to (Russian President) Putin, I will tell him , Ukraine will be safer if it stays in NATO.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Kissinger called on all parties to sit down and carry out diplomatic negotiations. He warned that there is now a risk that the great powers&#39; military relationships dominate their geopolitical calculations. The Russia-Ukraine conflict may therefore develop into a global conflict, and diplomatic negotiations will become &quot;increasingly important.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Sino-US relations have undergone qualitative changes since the Trump era. Conflict has begun to replace cooperation and become the key word in Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the relationship between the world&#39;s major powers, represented by the relationship between China, the United States and Russia, has become very dangerous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, Kissinger became increasingly worried about Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by Xinhua News Agency on June 16, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that Sino-US relations are on &quot;a cliff&quot; and &quot;the current trajectory of the relationship must change.&quot; Later, Kissinger also said that the Cold War between China and the United States is now &quot;walking on a mountain road.&quot; Kissinger believes that China and the United States &quot;both believe that the other side poses a strategic threat. We are moving towards a confrontation between major powers.&quot; This is a process that &quot;should not continue&quot;. Once a conflict breaks out between China and the United States, it will be comparable to World War I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Kissinger actively mediates the conflict between Russia and Ukraine and drags his old body to visit China, which is an attempt to stabilize Sino-US relations and exert his residual energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why Kissinger? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are many influential strategists. There are also many people who are worried about the international situation and are trying to improve Russia-Ukraine relations and Sino-U.S. relations. But why Kissinger and not someone else? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Kissinger has a superstitious admiration and sense of mission for the United States. As a German Jew who escaped the Nazi regime, to hold a high position in the United States is an example of an American success story. This also makes him always grateful to the United States. He once wrote: &quot;The same generosity of spirit and lack of malice can be found anywhere else.&quot; This almost sentimental gratitude and admiration for the United States made him serve the United States at all costs in diplomacy and devote himself to Maximize the national interests of the United States. For this reason, he did not hesitate to sacrifice his personal beliefs and did not care about his personal success or failure, reaching the height of &quot;living and dying for the benefit of the country, how can he avoid it for the sake of misfortunes and blessings&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, more than half of Kissinger’s diplomatic achievements are in Sino-US relations. Kissinger is an eyewitness and operator of America&#39;s transformation from decline to prosperity. If President Nixon had not accepted his suggestion, destroyed the Sino-Soviet alliance, and shifted the strategic focus of the United States from Asia to Europe, it would have been difficult for the United States to win the Cold War in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he entered American politics, the United States was experiencing its lowest point after World War II, and was experiencing triple crises of foreign strategy, economy, and society. The United States was trapped in the Vietnam War and was unable to extricate itself; it was in economic difficulties, and the U.S. dollar lost its ability and credibility to redeem gold; domestic society was in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger left American politics, the United States had successfully transformed China from an enemy of the United States into a &quot;friendly non-ally&quot; of the United States against the Soviet Union. Although the U.S. dollar can no longer be redeemed freely with gold, it has been tied back to the oil trade, achieving an upgrade from the U.S. dollar to an international standard currency. The U.S. dollar has transformed from an intermediary in world economic and trade to a truly hegemonic currency and an international standard currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These all make Kissinger unique and a myth and legend in the diplomatic community. His status and influence in international politics, especially in Sino-US relations, are irreplaceable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Symbol of the Times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On June 16, 2023, according to Xinhua News Agency, Kissinger said in an interview with the media that the United States is politically polarized and is currently &quot;too focused&quot; on itself. If its foreign policy fails to balance U.S. and global interests, the United States &quot;will become isolated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Sino-US relations turned from hostility to cooperation was that both countries had to deal with the threat from the Soviet Union. However, without Kissinger&#39;s insight and courage, it would be difficult for China-US relations to quickly restart in such a bad bilateral relationship. The symbolic effect produced by this overlapping interaction between individuals and times is something that no one else can possess. Kissinger has become a symbol, a symbol of an era, and is unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, it was a product of the times when China and the United States united to fight against the Soviet Union during difficult times. When Kissinger secretly visited China, it was the Soviet Union&#39;s rise and hardening period, and it was a difficult period for China and the United States. The handshake between China and the United States across the Pacific and across the ideological divide not only created a diplomatic legend, but also stabilized the world situation at the time and destined the outcome of the Cold War in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Kissinger came to China, he saw the strategic contradictions and ideological differences between China and the Soviet Union, and wanted to contact China to jointly fight the Soviet Union. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, China and the United States have become the biggest beneficiaries of the end of the Cold War. After the end of the Cold War, both China and the United States were able to get rid of security concerns, reduce security burdens, and focus on economic development. The rise of China in the world and the rise of the United States within the Western camp complement each other. It can be said that Kissinger&#39;s personal luck lies in standing at a turning point in Sino-US relations and the world structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kissinger is often called a realist, mainly because he puts strategic thinking ahead of ideology. This distinguishes Kissinger from the current strategic researchers in the United States who are guided by ideology. However, he did not take ideological factors into consideration. In fact, he calls his foreign policy principles &quot;liberal internationalism,&quot; which is equivalent to the neoconservatism of the George W. Bush era. It is the product of combining the emphasis on values, internationalist principles, and diplomacy based on national strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of this kind of liberal internationalism that he offended the two US presidents, Trump and Biden. On November 25, 2020, Trump fired Kissinger from his position as an advisor to the U.S. Defense Policy Council. However, he is also dissatisfied with Biden&#39;s withdrawal from Afghanistan, believing it to be an irresponsible act that betrays the tradition of U.S. foreign policy dating back to President Wilson. One result of expressing this rhetoric is that Biden inherits Trump&#39;s approach to Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are many talents in the U.S. strategic field, and many of the younger generation of strategic people than Kissinger have also withdrawn from the stage. The young and middle-aged strategic talents in the United States are now leading the charge in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, age is a major advantage for Kissinger. Kissinger is 100 years old and has outlived all his friends and opponents. Kissinger is the only international politician in the world who is still active and influential at the age of 100. This makes Kissinger&#39;s role largely unrepeatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Can Kissinger be copied? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kissinger is a product of his times. Times cannot be repeated, and Kissinger cannot be copied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the shape of Sino-US relations has changed. During the Cold War, the biggest external threat to China and the United States was the Soviet Union. For the sake of their own security, China and the United States have established a quasi-alliance system across the ideological divide, which is in line with their own interests. Now, as China has unprecedentedly entered the center of the world&#39;s power stage, Sino-US relations have become the most important bilateral relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the characteristics of diplomacy have changed. The realists represented by Kissinger advocate personal factors and are superstitious about secret diplomacy. This was already outdated by the end of the Cold War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was obsessed with those passionate years throughout his life, and was intoxicated by the thrill and excitement of secretly boarding a plane from Pakistan to Beijing. In the post-Cold War era, especially in the era of highly transparent and open self-media, these individual heroic diplomatic behaviors are difficult to reproduce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Kissinger’s influence in the United States has declined much faster than in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of the new era, many Americans are also reflecting on and challenging Kissinger&#39;s past contributions and achievements. The famous international relations scholar Hans Morgenthau has long said that Kissinger, like Odysseus in Homer&#39;s epic poem, &quot;has many facades.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the United States, there are two descriptions of Kissinger: one is a liar. This person never tells the truth, always speaks ambiguous words, and almost never makes clear public comments on major events. This may be one of the secrets of his longevity in the world of international relations. Second, Kissinger is an amazing person with an excellent memory. He was an eyewitness and living dictionary of many major events. Christopher Hitchens&#39;s description of Kissinger is perhaps more accurate, calling him &quot;a stunning liar with an incredible memory.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, there is something very dangerous. Compared with Kissinger, whose main achievement was during the Cold War, current American strategists basically grew up in a peaceful atmosphere. For them, peace is no longer the primary goal of international politics, but the premise or background of international politics, which does not need to be fought for or paid for. Therefore, we can see that compared with Kissinger&#39;s concerns about the prospect of conflict, many American strategists seem not to be concerned about the possibility of conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, there will be no second Kissinger, but the crisis that Kissinger is worried about will continue to repeat itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Center for American Studies, Fudan University)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西藏阿里全体公务人员为一女子献血？应以令人信服的证据消除特权嫌疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261624]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 14:57:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A woman in Shanghai suffered severe bleeding in a car accident in Tibet. Her relatives contacted the Ngari region through the Shanghai Health Commission and mobilized all civil servants Donate blood for it? Recently, this news has attracted great attention on the Internet, and netizens have questioned whether there is a privilege issue behind it. Although the person concerned continues to deny that any relatives are public officials, many netizens do not buy it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Beijing News and other media, a woman who calls herself Xiaoyu recently posted a short video on social media, saying that she had a serious car accident while traveling by car to the Ali area of ​​Tibet during her honeymoon. Her liver ruptured, she lost serious blood, and she was injured. Danger to life. Her husband’s aunt contacted the Ngari area of ​​Tibet through the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission and coordinated with medical experts from Shanghai to assist Tibet to treat her. She also mobilized “all public servants” in the Ngari area, including police officers, fire fighters, and army officers and soldiers, to donate blood for her. In the end, more than 7,000 ml of blood was used to bring her back from the brink of death. Subsequently, she was transferred to West China Hospital in Sichuan via a medical charter flight for further treatment. After her injury stabilized, she returned to Shanghai from Sichuan to continue treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video quickly attracted a lot of attention. Many netizens question who the &quot;little aunt&quot; is. She can actually allow the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission to mobilize medical experts to assist Tibet, and can also mobilize all civil servants in the Ngari region to donate blood for her. Is she suspected of taking advantage of her privileges? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arousing great public opinion, all parties involved accepted media interviews and responded, denying the existence of privileged interference. However, these responses failed to dispel public doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, who is the &quot;little aunt&quot;. Ms. Yu&#39;s husband, Mr. Tao, later told the media that his aunt was not a public official in Shanghai. It was after his wife&#39;s car accident that the local authorities suggested asking the Shanghai Health Commission for help. The aunt, who was usually close to him, &quot;find a way&quot; to contact the Shanghai Health Commission. Committee. The Shanghai Health Commission stated that they received a letter from &quot;relevant departments&quot; at that time, requesting Tibet-aid doctors who were in Shigatse City, Tibet, to go to the hospital involved to participate in the treatment. There was no action caused by improper factors such as personal relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that this little aunt is indeed able to contact the Shanghai Health Commission and can also get the &quot;relevant departments&quot; to send letters to the Health Commission. In the eyes of ordinary people, an ordinary citizen may only be able to call the National Health Commission&#39;s hotline at most, so &quot;little aunt&quot; will inevitably raise questions. The Shanghai Health Commission needs to provide more explanations. Which department has received the letter? The department also needs to explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Ms. Yu was later sent to West China Hospital in Chengdu, Sichuan for treatment on a medical charter flight. The medical charter flight was expensive. Her father said that they were an ordinary family and the charter flight cost more than 1.2 million yuan, which they borrowed from relatives, friends and leaders. But this statement is also questionable. Although the purpose of spending one million yuan to charter a flight from Tibet to a better hospital in the mainland was to save her daughter&#39;s life, it was not easy to raise such a huge sum of money in a short period of time. According to Mr. Yu, he &quot;driving at work.&quot; Such a unit and such a good leader have aroused the envy of many netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, what netizens are most concerned about is whether &quot;all public servants&quot; were mobilized to donate blood for her. Mr. Tao later said that his wife had just undergone surgery and was still seriously injured. He said this to encourage his wife to have the will to survive. In fact, it was the hospital staff who posted messages in Moments and groups, hoping that well-wishers would donate blood. , I also contacted the local police station, fire department and other departments, hoping to get their help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba government staff said that cadres and employees did donate blood to the injured woman, but it was not officially organized, but voluntarily donated blood after seeing relevant news. Ali Hospital staff also said that after the blood bank inventory ran low, the hospital asked employees and social workers for help, and family members also asked multiple local departments for help. Later, many people came to donate blood, including dozens of public officials. The aforementioned government staff also said that the medical conditions in the Ngari area are relatively backward and the blood inventory is already very tight. If someone asks for help, many cadres and employees will voluntarily donate blood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Shanghai tourist had a car accident in Tibet. The relevant departments in Shanghai and Ngari worked together to coordinate the treatment of Tibet experts while voluntarily donating blood to save lives. Finally, the seriously injured tourist was rescued. This should have been a touching moment. s story. However, a short video caused an uproar on the Internet questioning privileges. The reason is that the public has seen too many unfair phenomena of using power for personal gain, and has also seen too many incidents where people show off their wealth and power online and inadvertently expose corruption issues. The short video posted by Ms. Yu may also give people the feeling of showing off her &quot;little aunt&#39;s&quot; abilities (that is, showing off her family&#39;s abilities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, no wonder the public suspects that there is privilege here. If you want everyone to believe that this is a purely touching incident, the parties involved, especially the official agencies involved, should come up with more Compelling evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[查理·芒格逝世 “我没有什么要补充的了”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/30/65rPbMhQMAk6Wb5LlOGb5rwNujlbtMcUqyWfR7Dm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/65rPbMhQMAk6Wb5LlOGb5rwNuj lbtMcUqyWfR7Dm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;May 3, 2019, Burke, Omaha, Nebraska, USA Hill Hathaway CEO Buffett (left) and Vice Chairman Munger &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;&quot;Less crazy and stupid than most people&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A month before his 100th birthday, Charlie Munger died in a hospital in California. Warren Buffett has lost his best friend forever, and the world has lost another humorous and unruly wise man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger, 99, is a partner of Warren Buffett. He has served as Vice Chairman of Berkshire Hathaway since 1978. Over the past 40 to 50 years, the two have worked together to build Berkshire from a shaky textile manufacturing company into one of the most successful multinational conglomerates in history. The group&#39;s subsidiaries have covered many fields such as insurance, rail transportation, energy, manufacturing, retail and services, and hold shares worth more than US$318 billion, about half of which are Apple shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two weeks ago, Munger was interviewed by CNBC reporter Becky Quick. Compared with the shareholders&#39; meeting half a year ago, his thinking is still sharp and he likes to use long sentences when stating his views, but his voice has become increasingly hoarse and difficult to understand. The limitations of the body cannot be overcome by the intellect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quick asked him what he wanted to do in particular, and got a negative answer. His hands can no longer feel the tension of the fishing line when different fish bite the hook like they did when he was young. He no longer insists on crossing &quot;catching a 200-pound tuna&quot; off his bucket list. &quot;It requires too much physical strength. Even if I have the chance now, I won&#39;t go there, I won&#39;t even chase them. Time will always make you give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with when he was 96 years old, he We are increasingly aware of aging and weakness in our bodies. When asked about it by Quick, he said he no longer had a plan. He &quot;happily accepts&quot; all kinds of changes. During the interview, he was sitting in a sunny courtyard, with a row of anthuriums, also known as flower candles, placed on the lawn beside him. This kind of flower has bright color and long-lasting flowering period. From blooming to withering, it will show beige, milky white, green and yellow, each with its own characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/QlY37KH7E81EYH1sOkTaiqbGA2Cmb0CkWmOADdgm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/QlY37KH7E81EYH1sOkTaiqbGA2Cmb0CkWmOADdgm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260223&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From &quot;The Way of Munger&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by CITIC Publishing Group)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Buffett often jokes that in front of Munger, he is still a young man. Just a week before Munger&#39;s death, 93-year-old Buffett had just announced a donation of approximately $866 million worth of Berkshire stock to four family charities. This is the latest step in his commitment to donate more than 99% of his net wealth to charity. Since 2006, every year on the eve of Thanksgiving, the &quot;Stock God&quot; has donated to the above four family charities. In a letter to shareholders, Buffett said that he is 93 years old and feels very good about himself, but he is also fully aware that he has entered &quot;overtime.&quot; A week later, in the &quot;overtime&quot; game, his most tacit teammate bid farewell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger has always believed that the important reason why he and Buffett have had outstanding careers is to stay on the scene long enough, but the prerequisite for the magic of &quot;compound interest&quot; to be cast is still &quot;more than most&quot; People are less crazy and stupid”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger was born on January 1, 1924 in Omaha, Nebraska. He has loved reading since he was a child, is especially fascinated by biographies, and has a strong logical thinking ability. After graduating from Harvard Law School as a magna cum laude graduate, Munger followed in the footsteps of his grandfather and father and started his career as a lawyer in Los Angeles. Subsequently, in order to earn more income than a senior lawyer, Munger began to rely on existing client resources to carry out investments outside of his legal business and created his own investment partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/mp7jsMBqiHAWf10KmMJXxXhIPShRxI9hoGZ1sDuV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;959&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/mp7jsMBqiHAWf10KmMJXxXhIPShRxI9hoGZ1sDuV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260228&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 9, 1988, Munger was in California, USA&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1959, Munger&#39;s father passed away. When he returned to his hometown to take care of his funeral, he met 29-year-old Warren Buffett at a dinner arranged by a friend. The two, who were 6 years apart, hit it off immediately. At Buffett&#39;s suggestion, Munger began to focus on business in 1965. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two were each other&#39;s confidants and contributed to an important turning point in each other&#39;s lives. Buffett once said that it was Munger&#39;s ideological power that expanded his horizons and allowed him to &quot;evolve from apes to humans at an extraordinary speed.&quot; Otherwise, he would be much poorer than he is now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of his career, Buffett was a loyal follower of Benjamin Graham, known as the &quot;Father of Value Investing.&quot; Graham advocated finding company stocks that were selling for less than working capital, buying them cheap, and then selling them when the stock price rose, leaving a sufficient margin of safety. These &quot;cheap and unloved stocks&quot; he compared to &quot;cigarette butts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DgBzqofMqcGvRNWJU3WDvArA4pJap8FglGpU91EU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1592&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DgBzqofMqcGvRNWJU3WDvArA4pJap8FglGpU91EU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Munger&#39;s Way&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key force driving the evolution of Buffett&#39;s investment philosophy is Munger. Munger believes that Graham&#39;s investment strategy is based on the assumption that the future will be &quot;more dangerous than full of opportunities.&quot; But in fact, investing in great companies with fair stock prices is far better than investing in ordinary companies with ultra-low stock prices. Influenced by Munger&#39;s ideas, Buffett gradually moved away from the limitations of Graham&#39;s theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They found that some stocks are still very cheap even though the price is two or three times their book value, because the company may be on a growth path, have very good managers, or The whole management system is excellent and so on. Through detailed analysis of balance sheets, social and economic trends, etc., Buffett and Munger detected high-quality stocks from the vast stock market that they regarded as &quot;compound interest machines.&quot; Holding these stocks over the long term will result in excess profit returns, and these funds will be reinvested. Buffett compared this process to &quot;snowballing&quot;. &quot;You can only roll a snowball if you find the right snow.&quot; &quot;Choose a snowy place while moving forward to let the snowball get bigger and bigger.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since From 1965 to the end of 2022, Berkshire&#39;s annual compound return was 19.8%, and its total return in 57 years reached nearly 37,900 times, far outperforming the performance of the S&amp;P 500 Index during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Without Charlie Munger’s inspiration, wisdom and involvement, Berkshire Hathaway would not be able to develop to its current position.” After Munger’s death, Buffett wrote in a statement road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/O7v0oHkL2z4eLmMxBbVRqU7G2xtdZwWNS8lw4ThR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/O7v0oHkL2z4eLmMxBbVRqU7G2xtdZwWNS8lw4ThR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 6, 2023, Nebraska, USA, shareholders listened to Munger (right) and Buffett via video at the Berkshire Hathaway annual meeting Deliver a speech &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Acquiring wisdom is a moral responsibility&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;According to Forbes, as of November 28, 2023, Munger&#39;s net worth was approximately US$2.6 billion. However, compared to his difficult-to-replicate wealth and life, what benefits ordinary people more is Munger&#39;s thinking mode. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett calls Munger &quot;the best fast thinker in the world.&quot; As a stock picker, Buffett would test his ideas through Munger&#39;s questioning. &quot;He can think from A to Z in one go, and he can see the essence of everything even before you finish speaking.&quot; Behind this insight is Munger&#39;s long-trained thinking method, which he calls &quot;multiple Thinking Model”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger has spoken many times in public about the value and importance of using &quot;multiple thinking models&quot; in the business world and real life. For example, before making an investment decision, he will conduct a comprehensive analysis of the internal operating conditions of the intended company and the larger overall &quot;ecosystem&quot; in which it operates, so he can always &quot;find convincing weaknesses within 60 seconds.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Munger&#39;s estimate, he has as many as a hundred multiple thinking models stored in his mind. These models will help him collect and process information and provide decision-making guidance on this basis. These models need to borrow and combine analytical tools, methods and formulas from various traditional disciplines, including the redundant backup system model of engineering, the compound interest model of mathematics, the breakpoint of engineering, the overturning moment of physics and chemistry, and the autocatalytic model. Modern Darwinian integrated models in biology, and cognitive misjudgment models in psychology, to name a few. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/CmTkpEB3YqZ184Ju7dBlvWVXmJpC6Sg8ZqUNmcab.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/CmTkpEB3YqZ184Ju7dBlvWVXmJpC6Sg8ZqUNmcab.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Poor Charlie&#39;s Almanac&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the so-called &quot;intuition&quot; is actually the end point of a long thinking journey, which is Munger&#39;s understanding of human behavior and business systems. and other products of long-term interdisciplinary research. He advocated &quot;quick annihilation of what shouldn&#39;t be done, followed by a skilled, interdisciplinary attack on what should be done, and then, when the right opportunity comes - and only when the right opportunity comes - decisive action.&quot; He likes to regard his life as an educational experiment. &quot;A person who has mastered his major well will test the feasibility and effectiveness of this basic academic spirit and method in a very broad academic field.&quot;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Munger&#39;s view, gaining wisdom is not just to make an individual&#39;s life better, but also a moral responsibility. He made this point in his 2007 commencement address at the USC Gould School of Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his speech, he also reminded the young graduates to &quot;avoid extremely strong ideologies&quot;, &quot;especially those expressed in a very violent way&quot; because &quot;it only &quot;Instilling some concepts in people instead of convincing people to accept some truths&quot;, &quot;This is tantamount to locking the brain in a very unfortunate mode&quot;, &quot;In this way, your mind will be broken, and sometimes it will be bad.&quot; It breaks at an alarming rate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to help himself stay clear when he is inclined to support a strong ideology, Munger set an &quot;iron rule&quot; - &quot;Only if you can be better than your opponent I am qualified to have an opinion only when it refutes my own position.&quot; Of course, this &quot;iron rule&quot; is not limited to avoiding the whirlpool of strong ideologies. Munger believes that this way of thinking deserves continuous training. Only by constantly falsifying and questioning yourself can you reduce your ignorance. In his opinion, perhaps more suitable as an ideology is the spirit of &quot;accuracy, diligence and objectivity&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, catastrophic thought states include &quot;jealousy, resentment, hatred, and self-pity.&quot; Munger has experienced the greatest pain in the world. In 1953, shortly after divorcing his wife, his eldest son Teddy suffered from fatal leukemia. Bone marrow transplant surgery had not yet been available at that time, and Teddy soon died of the terminal illness. In the memories of friends, after visiting his son in the hospital at that time, the 29-year-old Munger would often walk on the street crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, Munger warned young people, &quot;Excessive self-pity can make people almost paranoid. Paranoia is one of the hardest things to reverse. Whenever you find yourself feeling self-pity, whether it is No matter what the reason, even if your child is about to die from cancer, you have to think that self-pity will not help.&quot; However, different life stages will always encounter very difficult problems. His advice is: Don’t have high expectations; have a sense of humor; surround yourself with the love of friends and family. &quot;The most important thing is to adapt to changes in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a wealthy and long-lived wise man, Munger is most often asked &quot;How to become happy and wealthy?&quot; In his opinion Come on, there&#39;s more to life than just being smart about accumulating wealth. Most success in life and business comes from things that should be avoided, like premature death and bad marriages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/qxt9znRMzJc1X9gzp3gXf67kE7UzJkseFJjzmsKJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/qxt9znRMzJc1X9gzp3gXf67kE7UzJkseFJjzmsKJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260225&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2010, Munger (left), Buffett (middle) and Bill Gates attended an event in Beijing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has another answer - &quot;When you get up every day, strive to become a little smarter than you were before. Complete your tasks seriously and well. Slowly, you will make progress, but not necessarily quickly. But it will lay the foundation for rapid progress...slowly moving forward a little bit every day. In the end - if you live long enough - you will get better. Most people will get what they deserve.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 82, Munger&#39;s friends gave him a copy of &quot;Cicero on the Good Life&quot; published by Benjamin Franklin, which included a A translation of Cicero&#39;s &quot;On Old Age&quot;. Inspired by this article, Munger wrote the article &quot;In Praise of the Elders: Munger on His Old Age.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the article, Munger excerpted a summary of this wise man who was born in 106 BC: &quot;The best protective armor in old age is a life that has been carefully spent before it, and a life that has been used for... A life of useful knowledge, honorable deeds, and noble conduct; the man who leads it devotes himself from youth to his own improvement, and will reap in old age the happiest fruits that they produce; and not only because Beneficial knowledge, glorious achievements and noble deeds will accompany him throughout his life, even to the last moment of his life, and will bring supreme blessings to the soul because of the conscience that has witnessed an upright life and the memory of the good achievements in the past. Comfort.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger&#39;s life is one of the best illustrations of this. Like Benjamin Franklin, whom he loved to emulate, he always had a strong thirst for knowledge and a wide range of interests. He was always creating, giving, and then being remembered. He has spent a full 99 years carefully, just as his mantra at Berkshire&#39;s annual meeting: &quot;I have nothing to add.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;( Reference materials: &quot;Poor Charlie&#39;s Almanac&quot; and &quot;Munger&#39;s Way&quot;.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[糖分摄入过多有危害，上海试水含糖饮料健康提示]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261576]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“3元羽绒服”上热搜：不是买不起还是感冒药更有性价比]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, discussions about down jackets have become heated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When will down jackets sell for five figures?&quot; &quot;Domestic down jackets sell for 7,000 yuan&quot;... Thousands of thousands of down jackets are frequently on the hot search list, slowly becoming a &quot;luxury product&quot; in winter &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;3 yuan down jacket&quot; attracted the attention and discussion of netizens, showing that low-priced down jackets costing 3 yuan but actually selling for only 35 yuan were given to ordinary people in the cold winter. The warmest gift, for them, is more than enough for them compared to big-name luxury goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the light snow season has arrived and major cities have entered winter, many people have dug out the down jacket that has been at the bottom of their boxes for a year. Statistics show that more than half of netizens buy down jackets when needed. , during Double 11, down jackets became a hot-selling product on major e-commerce platforms. Many domestic down jackets were on Tmall’s best-selling list and received a lot of praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the rise of domestic down jackets is inseparable from the improvement of the comprehensive production strength of the manufacturers behind them, and the Yangtze River Delta is the main force in down production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiangsu, Zhejiang, and Shandong, the number of down-related companies exceeds 10,000, and many domestic down jacket brands are gradually starting to transform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the wide variety of down jacket brands and types, many netizens said that they are in urgent need of a scientific selection guide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it depends on the filling of the down jacket: goose down is more expensive than duck down due to factors such as large and full velvet, good fluffiness, strong warmth retention, and long use time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, it is the down that really plays a role in keeping warm, and the down content more intuitively reflects the quality of the down jacket. It is worth noting that thicker and warmer is not the case. The higher the fill power of a down jacket, the more air it insulates and the better its thermal insulation effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the data point of view, there are still a small number of netizens who choose thousand-yuan down jackets, and most netizens pursue cost-effectiveness. As a saying often seen on the Internet: It’s not that down jackets are unaffordable, but that cold medicine is more cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What price range of down jacket would you choose? Today, &quot;Know&quot; will show you how to choose a cost-effective down jacket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/586c1b2150.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/586c1b2150.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259897&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/135e6eaeff.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/135e6eaeff.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259898&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tytIIT1Ze3ZYW31QaU8DrhSJeQ8Tm4SvtKxe7GWc.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tytIIT1Ze3ZYW31QaU8DrhSJeQ8Tm4SvtKxe7GWc.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a2e0996720.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/28/a2e0996720.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259899&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/28/f6fba97f3a.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/28/f6fba97f3a.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259900&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/28/9a1cf85f82.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9a1cf85f82. PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259901&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dc54f1e8f9. PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dc54f1e8f9.PNG&quot; data-key= &quot;259902&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与南方周末读者交换一本书，请查收]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261587]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;From Xinjiang Sayibak, Inner Mongolia Hohhot, Heilongjiang Qiqihar, Sichuan Aba Tibetan and Qiang Autonomous Prefecture, from Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen, Hangzhou, Wuhan, Chongqing, Xi&#39;an... A book met in Yangcheng across time, space and geography, and was sent to another person&#39;s hands through exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who in the clouds sent a brocade book? The answer is hidden in the package. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/5A8ODADrJeJEAcfRuyYc7NbiN6vdtzKWG9svp2Bq.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;2182&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/5A8ODADrJeJEAcfRuyYc7NbiN6vdtzKWG9svp2Bq.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Good reviews from readers. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an era of cluttered information, we firmly believe that reading is a kind of concentration, so we have this book exchange event. It lasted for a week, and the conference room was filled with books. The courier boy became a mature person, and the name &quot;Xiao Nan&quot; became a high-frequency word in Cainiao Station&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ZSuV1QftTAdicJDCDmy7KX0wGMQzySclizpmZteN.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height= &quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ZSuV1QftTAdicJDCDmy7KX0wGMQzySclizpmZteN.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Packages are waiting to be opened. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/UvzQU6uLvkEZqtFtqb8FF4Ihn3CTp3SKihJNRbEk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/UvzQU6uLvkEZqtFtqb8FF4Ihn3CTp3SKihJNRbEk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Categorize books. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was surprised and moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opening the package, each book attempts to convey a series of experiences. The words and pictures, whether virtual or real, converge into the tastes and interests of each Southern Weekend reader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We received &quot;Letter from a Strange Woman&quot;, we took a &quot;Submarine at Night&quot;, we explored &quot;The Right Bank of the Ergun River&quot;, we met &quot;The Kite Runner&quot;, and we also followed Lao She, Mo Yan, Liang Shiqiu, Peter Heisler, Woolf, Camus, and Ryunosuke Akutagawa feel the personal emotional memories and the pulse of the times in which they live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/L8IUlatz6O6KMCwD6iBkAMfFfENlLy132bXjUkp1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;8000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/L8IUlatz6O6KMCwD6iBkAMfFfENlLy132bXjUkp1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;The books were passed around in the hands, and the battle continued until 2 o&#39;clock in the morning. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What touched us even more were the letters that came with the books. Some are as long as a page, and some are just a few sentences. Different words have the same heart-warming power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/WGgAC6icKNJBPsXemUizqGLavoSpezBZZPzkriRx.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/WGgAC6icKNJBPsXemUizqGLavoSpezBZZPzkriRx.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tCeYIaIVqz74XQhMn04FkERO0WtsBHZzvEri3ObE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tCeYIaIVqz74XQhMn04FkERO0WtsBHZzvEri3ObE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DinWciWR8LWNRVulrj7D9pxeHwfE5hBCgbpAU5sn.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4000&quot; height=&quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/30/DinWciWR8LWNRVulrj7D9pxeHwfE5hBCgbpAU5sn.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/30/svVVFShmqHbDtRxoLC2eYO5UqwYjuExRSr1AZUFn.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/svVVFShmqHbDtRxoLC2eYO5UqwYjuEx RSr1AZUFn. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/67Y1856tkQlaZxaGqnqXvEIXj648hdnXCPV1PW8X.jpeg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/67Y1856tkQlaZxaGqnqXvEIXj648hdnXCPV1PW8X.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260210&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/lG2eB62YslIBISUWqEKrA5SvmDmytU08KlwJhz4s.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height= &quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/lG2eB62YslIBISUWqEKrA5SvmDmytU08KlwJhz4s.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The text is fireworks , gives people the courage to ponder and question, which is hard to express in words. It also allows us to resonate with the world and find answers to the ever-changing world. &lt;strong>;The books participating in this event have been exchanged and shipped on November 28th&lt;/strong>;. We look forward to your excitement in opening the &quot;blind box&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But please don’t stop reading. After receiving the book, &lt;strong>;you are welcome to share your reading experience&lt;/strong>; in the comment area of ​​this article and communicate with the original owner of the book. &lt;strong>;During November 30th to December 10th&lt;/strong>;, we will draw one person every day to leave a heartfelt message and &lt;strong>;give away a signed book by Southern Weekend columnist and poet Chen Nianxi&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/RjwQmdKcZOdOZc5a47a6CKddLHNu4fWPHh7cOugQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;8000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/RjwQmdKcZOdOZc5a47a6CKddLHNu4fWPHh7cOugQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiao Nan is always careful when matching books, hoping to satisfy you. If the book you finally receive is different from what you imagined, please forgive me. After all, the meaning of exchange is more about encountering the unknown. &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Welcome to add Xiaonan Enterprise WeChat to share your event experience and suggestions. &lt;strong>;If you participated in the event and have not received the express delivery from us after December 4th&lt;/strong>;, please give us feedback. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/OdX0yHMcXD1ggRXcqxgTLlYMGq4661lHibwuT3Q2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 273&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/OdX0yHMcXD1ggRXcqxgTLlYMGq4661lHibwuT3Q2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 09:55:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 29, local time, former US Secretary of State Henry Kissinger was at his home in Connecticut Died at the age of 100. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨童兵：理论的价值是推动实务的进步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261562]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tong Bing, the first doctor of journalism in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;A native of Shaoxing, Zhejiang, born in November 1942 in Shaoxing, Zhejiang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1958-1963, studied at Shanghai Middle School in Shanghai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963-1968, studied in the Journalism Department of Fudan University, and was assigned to participate in After hard work and training, one year later he was transferred to &quot;Jintie News&quot; as a reporter and editor of the newspaper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1981, he was admitted to the Chinese Department of Peking University and became a graduate student after the resumption of the college entrance examination. The first graduate student soon moved back to Renmin University of China with the journalism major, and stayed at the school to teach after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984-1988, studied for a doctorate at Renmin University of China, becoming a Chinese-trained The first Ph.D. in journalism, he taught at Renmin University of China after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In December 1990, he was promoted to professor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;He has been a doctoral supervisor since 1993 and enjoys special allowances from the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2001, he was transferred to the School of Journalism, Fudan University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2012, he was awarded the title of Contributor to Chinese Journalism Education by the Journalism Professional Committee of the China Higher Education Commission and China Journalism Education Award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a senior professor of liberal arts at Fudan University, a doctoral supervisor, and a researcher on the Marxist view of journalism at Fudan University Director of the Center and Dean of Zhide College of Fudan University. He once served as the convener of the Journalism and Communication Discipline Evaluation Group of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council and a member of the fifth, sixth and seventh expert groups of the Postdoctoral Management Committee of the Ministry of Human Resources. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tong Bing, born in 1942, is the first doctor of journalism in New China. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ce49eaf0b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/29/ce49eaf0b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260107&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tong who was born in 1942 Bing is the first doctor of journalism in New China. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Become a reporter,&amp;nbsp; It was a child soldier&#39;s wish in middle school. But in more than ten years of study experience, he found that his ideal is still to &quot;engage in academics and do research.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating from the Journalism Department of Fudan University in 1968, the child soldiers were assigned to participate in labor training in Horqin, Inner Mongolia. In 1970, the &quot;Jintie News&quot; accidentally discovered their writing skills to become a journalist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The tide of the times is carrying budding journalism students drifting in unknown directions. In 1977, news came that the country had resumed the college entrance examination. The child soldiers who were far away from the border regained their fighting spirit to study, and the following year they were admitted to the postgraduate degree in the Chinese Department of Peking University. This year, a full ten years have passed since the child soldier graduated from college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;His mentor during his master&#39;s and doctoral studies was journalism educator Gan Xifen. Following in the footsteps of his mentor, Tong Bing devoted himself to the research of Marxist journalism concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Opening up a new research direction requires a lot of basic reading support. Within one year, Tong Bing read through more than 4,000 papers with the word &quot;horse&quot; in them, and also read through all 50 volumes of the complete works of Marx and Engels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The complete works of Marx and Engels were published in batches. After the first 39 volumes were read, the last 11 volumes were not published until 1985.&quot; Tong Bing said that at that time, the most complete new books could only be seen at the former Central Compilation and Translation Bureau. The child soldier who was still a &quot;poor student&quot; often brought two steamed buns and a cup of boiling water to read in the Translation and Compilation Bureau, sitting there all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating with his doctorate in 1988, Tong Bing stayed at Renmin University of China to take up a teaching position. In more than 40 years of research and teaching career, he has published more than 700 academic papers, published and edited more than 50 books, textbooks, dictionaries, etc., and successively published the &quot;History of Marxist Journalism Thought&quot; and &quot;The History of Marxist Journalism Thought&quot;. Academic monographs such as &quot;Classic Course of Marxist Journalism&quot;, &quot;Introduction to Theoretical Journalism and Communication&quot;, &quot;Journalism Theory&quot;, &quot;Comparative Journalism and Communication&quot;, &quot;Subject and Mouthpiece - An Examination of the Trajectory of News Communication in the Republic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is how I have been through these years. It can be said that there is no time to breathe and no chance to sleep peacefully. I am constantly breaking through new tasks. Although it was tiring at the time, looking back now, I think it was worth it,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the first PhD in journalism independently trained in China, Tong Bing has experienced the process of postgraduate journalism education from scratch, and witnessed the development of Renmin University of China, The development of journalism at Fudan University, one of the two famous universities in the north and the other in the south. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Do knowledge simply and plainly, but don&#39;t do simple learning&quot; and &quot;Don&#39;t dare to waste a day in life&quot; are the creeds he mentioned many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Already octogenarian, Tong Bing is currently a senior professor of liberal arts at Fudan University, still standing on the three-foot podium teaching journalism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Truth&quot; is a key word for Tong Bing&#39;s academic studies. He once used the four &quot;truths&quot; of &quot;true learning, true understanding, true belief, and true application&quot; The words summarized his lifelong academic insights. His pursuit of truth in learning also allowed him to repeatedly speak out about the shortcomings of the journalism community and the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Journalism research has entered a new era. He directly stated the shortcomings of the development of the discipline, &quot;Among various disciplines, the discipline construction of journalism has developed slowly.&quot; In his It seems that in order to solve the development problems of journalism, &quot;it is necessary to calmly spread out the problems and conduct in-depth analysis. This may be good.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;My ideal is not here. Place&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; When taking the college entrance examination in 1963 , why did you apply for the Journalism Department of Fudan University? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; I wanted to be a reporter when I was in middle school. At that time, I was a student cadre and the president of the student union. I was no stranger to news. . Student cadres who want to take the liberal arts major usually choose the Department of Politics, the Department of International Politics, and the Department of Journalism. At that time, the universities with the best journalism departments in my country were Renmin University in the north and Fudan University in the south. My parents didn’t want me to leave Shanghai, so I took the Fudan exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;It took ten years between graduating from undergraduate degree and applying for graduate school. Can you talk about this experience? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; When I graduated from my undergraduate degree, it was at the end of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and I was assigned to participate in labor training in the Northeast. I started out as a road maintenance worker building railroads. At that time, all major railway bureaus in our country had enterprise newspapers, and Jinzhou Railway had an enterprise newspaper called &quot;Jintie News&quot;. More than half a year later, they found out about me and transferred me to the newspaper as an editor and reporter. The newspaper office often holds correspondent training classes. Since I major in journalism, I often give lectures and have a relatively harmonious relationship with everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After staying there for a while, our country resumed the college entrance examination. At first, the railway didn’t want to let me go because I had already graduated from my undergraduate degree. But later, the Jinzhou Railway Bureau heard that both Renmin University and Fudan University were recruiting master&#39;s degree students (there were no graduate students in the journalism major before) and agreed that I would try to take the exam. I passed the exam right away and was the first batch of master&#39;s students recruited in our country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Reform and opening up on your personal destiny What is the impact? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; The changes in my personal destiny are closely linked to reform and opening up. Sometimes I often say in meetings or classes that I am very grateful to Deng Xiaoping. If the college entrance examination and university admissions are not resumed, I may still be a reporter at the Jinzhou Railway Bureau tabloid for the rest of my life. If I do well, I may be promoted to deputy editor-in-chief or editor-in-chief. However, my ideal is not in this place. I still want to engage in academics and theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; During graduate school, Professor Gan was How did that guide you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; Mr. Gan Xifen is also recruiting graduate students for the first time, and his requirements for me are relatively strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There were pilot projects before the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, but they could not be carried out after a while, so there was no master&#39;s degree in journalism before 1978. The lifelong wish of these old gentlemen is to push forward journalism research. The National People&#39;s Congress and Fudan University were the first to do relevant work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mr. Gan Xifen emphasized two points when guiding me. The first point is to read the original works. He believes that graduate students in journalism should learn more classic works; the second point is to practice. I always insisted on these two points while studying at Renmin University, and I persisted relatively well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;How do you insist on these two points? required? What are the specific methods? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; I had classes during the day, read in the afternoon, and went to the journalism department office around 4 o&#39;clock to read the day&#39;s newspapers. , we poor students could not afford to subscribe to newspapers at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I come back from the classroom and library at 9pm, I review the day&#39;s newspapers in the dormitory, including the day&#39;s &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; and &quot;China Youth Daily&quot;. The review is conducted 5 nights a week, each person is responsible for one week, and several people take turns. The students responsible for reviewing the newspaper should take notes and write a report every week, which should be sent to the newspaper. The newspaper also attaches great importance to our opinions and will reply to us every once in a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This arrangement is very helpful to our study. After a 3-year master&#39;s degree, I stuck to this method for almost 3 years. We also have many contacts with news organizations and have a relatively close relationship. I did the same thing until I stayed in school to become a teacher after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Continuously opening new courses and recruiting new students&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;In 1983, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council agreed to establish a doctorate in journalism. Under the background of that time, if you graduate with a master&#39;s degree and work as a university teacher, your academic qualifications are enough. Why do you continue to study for a doctorate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Child Soldier:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;One is because of the need for theoretical study , studying for a doctoral degree will give you the opportunity to audit courses in many other majors at Renmin University. For example, I have listened to history, scientific socialism, and international politics. When I went to attend classes, none of the teachers refused. They saw that I was not too young and still eager to learn, so they generally allowed me to enter their classrooms. I often asked questions in class, and they really treated me in this regard. Very considerate: When I go to ask questions after class, other teachers or classmates will stop and let me (ask questions first). In the process of my study, it can be said that many teachers from relevant majors at Renmin University have helped me a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, my supervisor and other teachers in the journalism department hope that I can take the lead in helping the school establish a doctoral program in journalism. Later, the State Education Commission agreed that journalism would have a doctoral degree. At that time, China began to have doctoral programs (in journalism), and two schools were approved, one was the Journalism Department of Fudan University, and the other was the Journalism Department of Renmin University of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;After graduating from the Ph.D., you stayed He taught at the National People&#39;s Congress and returned to his alma mater, Fudan University, in 2001. What did you think at that time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>;After completing my master&#39;s degree at Renmin University, I stayed in school because of the needs of school work. At that time, our journalism industry was in great need of talents, and young people wanted to join it and go out into the society. But the instructor said something to me, which moved me very much. The Cultural Revolution delayed it for ten years, and they really wanted to restore our major as soon as possible, so they hoped that I could stay and teach in this school with peace of mind. Only by staying in this profession and being a good teacher can this profession continue to have new talents and new developments. I quickly accepted the arrangements in the school and worked hard. I have done a lot of pioneering work over the past few decades. It is very worthwhile when I think about it now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moving from the National People&#39;s Congress to teaching at Fudan is also an adjustment arrangement for the school. At that time, Fudan was in great need of people. Compared with Renmin University, Fudan&#39;s development is more international. Many outstanding students have gone abroad after graduation. The teachers are getting older and their health is getting worse every year. We teachers and students know each other very well, and we see this situation with our eyes and are anxious in our hearts. Therefore, the school raised this expectation and hoped that we can come back to shoulder the heavy burden. I came back without saying anything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the beginning, there was a lot of pressure and a heavy burden. Journalism was delayed for many years by the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and is in urgent need of development. The desire for talents is everywhere. So whether I stayed at the National People&#39;s Congress or was later called by Fudan University, I just taught with peace of mind, constantly opening new courses and recruiting new students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This has been the case for these years. It can be said that when there is no time to breathe, there is no chance to sleep peacefully. Although we were very tired at the time, we soon overcame these difficulties and continued to make new progress in our work. Looking back now, I still think it was worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Understand your mission”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;/span>;In your opinion, what is the overall shift in current journalism research and what are its deficiencies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing: &lt;/strong>;Differences in theoretical viewpoints are inevitable, natural, and reasonable. (The development of journalism research) I think it ultimately depends on the progress of journalism practice. You are right to insist on your point of view. As a result, newspapers and radio and television have been successfully run. This shows that theory guides practice. On the other hand, if your theory is sound and sound, but no one reads your newspaper or listens to your broadcast, it shows that your theory has no power. Isn&#39;t this a problem? This is where we theorists feel ashamed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, there is still a strong culture of self-appreciation in the academic world, which should not be the case. The academic community should review this and analyze the reasons behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Journalism has always faced the &quot;news What do you think of the questioning and debate about &quot;no learning&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tongbing:&lt;/strong>; The &quot;no-learning theory&quot; has long-term influence on the development of journalism, mainly due to several circumstances. Journalism started relatively late, and there are not many independent scholarships and works. The aspect of journalism that has a deeper impact on China is practice. Running newspapers, radio stations, and television stations are all based on practical work. There are not many people who actually engage in theoretical research, and achievements have not been achieved. Not big either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These understandings affect the status and image of journalism in various liberal arts majors. After we got PhDs, China&#39;s journalism research gradually got on the right track and started to have something decent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;How do you understand journalists Mission? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Child Soldier:&lt;/strong>; Journalists must understand their mission. The simplest and simplest requirement is to report the truth to the people. , real news, that’s the most important thing. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Journalism Freshman Can you give some life advice to college students who have just entered school? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; This is a very broad proposition. I think the life development of college students is the same as the operation characteristics of our entire country. , one wave after another, one tide after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As teachers, we hope that the new students can inherit the good traditions of the school and develop them stronger, so that the university will become better and better, and the college students themselves will also become better and better. We can continue to make progress. Only in this way will our country become better and better and our career become more and more brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So after college students enter university, the first thing is to understand their mission. Everyone should have their own arrangements and expectations. This is not just lip service, it is actually something that must be done. We all came slowly from undergraduate to master&#39;s and doctoral degrees. New students especially need to have a sense of mission and have expectations, prospects, and arrangements for the future. I think this is the most important thing. Time flies so fast. Even if you look at the four years of undergraduate studies, half of it has passed in the blink of an eye. However, the task is actually endless. We still need to continue to work hard, strive for, and develop in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;College students should not be afraid of being tired. Only by constantly exploring their own prospects can individuals have new goals, new directions, and continuous progress. Learn more every day, overcome your shortcomings, and show new expectations. This is my common expectation for our college students, whether they are undergraduates, masters, or doctoral students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“机场判官”再曝住宿骗局：虚假定位误导消费者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;July 5, 2020, Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Visual China Map&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/c903be4634.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/c903be4634.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;July 5, 2020, Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yi is a self-media flight blogger. He daily researches where to find tickets and where the airport services are better. He published &quot; Video content such as &quot;How to get a refund for an expensive ticket&quot; is more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the &quot;free transit accommodation scam&quot; at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport was exposed on September 12, 2023, Liu Yi has released 16 videos related to Xi&#39;an Airport, pointing out Its existing management problems have been called the &quot;airport judge&quot; by netizens. With the update of this series of videos, the Xi&#39;an transfer strategy that Liu Yi originally wanted to do has gradually evolved into a &quot;spy war drama&quot;. Netizens not only liked and followed it, but also continued to provide clues to Liu Yi. In Liu Yi&#39;s account (the account name is &quot;This is not too much&quot;), videos related to Xi&#39;an Airport have become &quot;top-rated&quot; content, and many of them have more than three million views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of November 20, Liu Yi once again released a video saying that hotels and B&amp;Bs around Xi&#39;an Airport posted false positioning on the OTA platform (online travel hotel platform) For hotel information, he searched these platforms for a B&amp;B several hundred meters away from the airport, and actually had to take a car there. Previously, the person in charge of Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport promised in a media interview that a more powerful comprehensive management mechanism would be established to address the problems existing at Xi&#39;an Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 23, staff of the Airport New District Management Committee of Xixian New City, Xi&#39;an told Southern Weekend reporters that the Market Supervision Branch, Comprehensive Law Enforcement Detachment, and Public Security Bureau that day Staff from the Guangde Road Police Station and the Beidu Street Office have formed a joint law enforcement team to inspect the B&amp;Bs in Bianfang Village and Dashoudou Village and urge them to make rectifications. “Regarding Xi’an’s city image, we are still very Attention.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Falsely positioned B&amp;B&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as Liu Yi released the 10th video related to Xi&#39;an Airport, security personnel can be seen almost everywhere at Xi&#39;an Airport To maintain order, the &quot;liars&quot; who were previously exposed to solicit customers in violation of regulations are hard to find. In the video released on November 20, Liu Yi deliberately took the high-speed train from Beijing to Xi&#39;an in order to avoid leaking his itinerary, and then took a bus to Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport to &quot;patrol&quot;, which confirmed that the positioning of B&amp;Bs around the airport on the OTA platform was fraudulent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this video, Liu Yi searched for the hotel with the closest straight line distance on a platform, and the first-ranked &quot;Jiaxuan Boutique B&amp;B&quot; was marked &quot;from Xianyang The international airport is 340 meters straight.&quot; In fact, the passenger arrived at the online car-hailing parking lot, which is the hotel pick-up location. Then he searched on another platform, and multiple Huangzhixiang Hotel branches appeared on the page, one of which was &quot;119 meters &quot;Straight-line distance from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport&quot;, but when I called, the other party told me that the hotel is behind the terminal and that I need to wait for the car to pick me up. Finally, the Shitouji Inn, which was &quot;&lt;100 meters away from you in a straight line&quot; on the third platform, was also falsely positioned. . Liu Yi believes that these B&amp;Bs are engaging in fraud on the OTA platform and are operating in bad faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 20, 2023, Liu Yi used the online travel hotel platform to search for nearby accommodation at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6921534e57.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1120&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6921534e57.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 11 On March 20, Liu Yi used the online travel hotel platform to search for nearby accommodation at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the video posted by Liu Yi, many netizens provided screenshots of the above-mentioned negative reviews of the falsely positioned hotel: &quot;Didn&#39;t pay attention to the words above The straight -line distance is too strong. The hotel is actually more than 8 kilometers away from the airport. It is actually the room near the airport. Comments mentioned problems such as remote and room -like pictures, but such homestays still ranks among the platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan discovered the false positioning of the above homestays, which are set at the online car parking lot, T3 terminal, and T2 terminal of Xi&#39;an Airport. According to the information he collected, these homestay owners are basically villagers from Bianfang Village and Shitou Village around the airport. Because they are closer to the airport, these villages have developed into the industry for transit accommodation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 22, reporters from the Southern Weekend searched on the platforms such as Ctrip, Tongcheng, Flying Pigs and other platforms. Airport &quot;, but does not show specific distance. The three false positioning homestays mentioned in Liu Yan&#39;s video are key to search, and the Ctrip platform has removed all the three shops; however, some platforms can still find Jiaxuan boutique apartments, showing that they cannot pre -order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The address page of the Flying Pig Search Jiaxuan Business Hotel is still marked &quot;about 300 meters west of the T2 terminal T2 at Xianyang International Airport in Xi&#39;an&quot;. The reporter from the Southern Weekend asked as a customer and asked whether the hotel was in the terminal when the hotel was in the terminal of the terminal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan said that these falsely positioned homestays not only appeared on the above platforms, but also existed on other platforms. On another OTA platform, a shop labeled &quot;less than 100 meters away from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport, about 1 minute&quot; on the 20th, and has been revised on the 22nd to &quot;4.5 kilometers away from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport, about 9 minutes.&quot; When a reporter from the Southern Weekend asked why he saw a distance of only one minute walking before, the store did not respond positively, but emphasized that &quot;it is impossible to be so cheap in the airport outside the airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 22, the reporters from the Southern Weekend contacted the four OTA platforms of Ctrip, Tongcheng, Flying Pig, and Meituan, and did not receive a reply. According to the analysis of the OTA platform industry who do not want to be named, the platform needs to verify its address before the hotel is launched. After the launch, it is also necessary to do daily verification and inspection. License or lease contracts, such as the address on the contract as the online address, is difficult to distinguish the platform. At the same time, each online travel hotel platform also has some agency housing, and some houses are closed on one platform, and the vest on other platforms. &quot;If the platform is not effective, it is difficult to investigate and deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The person in charge of the above-mentioned Airport New City told the Southern Weekend reporter that the local market supervision department has interviewed the three OTA platforms in the past two days and ordered them to strengthen the homestays around the airport. Information review. Offline, the joint law enforcement teams formed by them also conduct key investigations on several issues mentioned by bloggers, including the name of special industry licenses, business licenses, and door plaques, and whether the pictures on the platform are consistent with the actual situation. etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;旅客维权困境&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘懿发布视频后几天，网友们纷纷留言，说起自己在厦门、昆明、大理、 Airports in Shanghai have also encountered similar problems, but there are not many people who choose &quot;hard&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Netizen Zhang Ning landed on Fuzhou Airport on September 4th. At that time, a platform was selected to introduce a hotel just 200 meters away from the airport. The man who took the plane drove for more than ten minutes and took her to a self -built building, saying that this was the hotel. Zhang Ning and the hotel&#39;s front desk theory, why the hotel location and photos are different from the platform. The other party said, &quot;That&#39;s an old shop, it has been closed&quot;, and does not provide specific addresses, letting her take a taxi. At that time, it was late at night. Zhang Ning could only live after weighing again and again, and asked the pick -up personnel to return her back to the airport the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;I originally wanted to give a bad review, but because he had my personal information and dare not give it.&quot; Zhang Ning said that she was worried about being retaliated and did not want to give herself. The travel manufacturing is unnecessary. After a few months, Zhang Ning recorded this in Liu Yan&#39;s video review area, &quot;I hope that more people will see these problems and support him to defend his rights.&quot; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the video recorded by Liu Yan, the process of exposing the accommodation scam was quite tortuous. On September 12, as a flying blogger, Liu Yi went to Xi&#39;an Airport to experience the transfer of accommodation for the first time. I did not expect that the &quot;scammer&quot; directly took the guests at the door of the airport. Liu Yan simply recorded the video exposure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Previously, Liu Yan reported that Xi&#39;an Airport&#39;s transit accommodation was taken by the&quot; Li Gui &quot;. The airport promised to continue to improve the passenger experience. Visual Chinese map&quot; src = &quot;http: // images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/a242806d6d.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;heart =&quot; 864 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/ Medias/Image/23/11/29/A242806d6d6d.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260052 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-align: center; &quot;>; Netizens report that Xi&#39;an Airport has transferred accommodation accommodation accommodation Passenger by &quot;Li Gui&quot;, the airport promised to continue to improve the passenger experience. Visual China Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On September 20, the Shaanxi Airport Public Security Bureau stated that it has increased the inspection and control of the inspection and control. The disruption behavior has been fined 148 people since September, and 3 people have been detained. But soon, when Liu Yan arrived at Xi&#39;an Airport again, the scammer shifted from 324 to 322 from the airport, and the security guard did not effectively intercept. In the meantime, Liu Yan began to receive various complaints and private messages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wait until Liu Yan landed for the third time Xi&#39;an Airport, and the security target of the security guard became Liu Yan himself. He shouted &quot;He has passed&quot; in the walkie -talkie. In that trip, some netizens informed Liu Yan&#39;s itinerary information. According to the screenshot provided by netizens, Liu Yan flew to Xi&#39;an in Shenzhen on October 24th. The news of Liu Yan was about to go to Xi&#39;an at the black car group at the Xi&#39;an Airport at 18:42, reminding everyone to be careful. To this end, Liu Yan had to report to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the next video, he once said that he would buy 15 tickets and fly from Shenzhen to Xi&#39;an once a week to inspect the improvement of the airport. He believes that compared to ordinary passengers, he can enjoy the gifts and discounts of many airlines as a flying blogger, which provides a basis for rights protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But Liu Yan said that the follow-up processing of his personal information was not satisfactory. Police found security guards that distributed information, but they could not pursue who leaked more deeply. He can also understand this that the leak of personal information of passengers involves the chain too long and it is difficult to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters several telephone contacts to contact the Public Security Bureau of the Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department of the Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department, and they were not connected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Yan&#39;s courage to insist on defending rights has caused many fans to empathize. Liu Yan said that the most content in the backstage was the help of netizens in various places, including the airport&#39;s stolen mobile phone, deceived and accommodation, etc. &quot;Most of me can only comfort it.&quot; The communication between Liu Yan and the relevant departments of the airport has always belonged to the &quot;intervals of the air&quot;. Liu Yan said that the airport management department had contacted him after sending the relevant video for the second time, expressed his hope that he could communicate in the face of Xi&#39;an. It was convenient, and declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The person in charge of the above-mentioned Airport New Town Management Committee said that Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport, Xixian New District Airport New City, and Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department Public Security Bureau had On the day, a comprehensive governance office was formed to rectify the passenger behavior of the airport terminal building. At present, this problem has been basically resolved. On November 23, they had a further contact with Liu Yan, and continuously improved the problems that he reflected. &quot;There are such enthusiastic bloggers pointed us to some problems in development. We go to correct it. I think it is also helpful to improve.&quot; On the 24th, Liu Yan updated the video of Xi&#39;an Airport again. He asked the fans to experience the homestays around Xi&#39;an Airport, pointing out that there are still problems such as different photos of these homestays that are different from the actual situation and the store signboards are inconsistent. It will not bring good results. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Liu Yan, Zhang Ning in the text) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[任伯年和他的公孙大娘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 08:37:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/2dJwOHFCf1QgUgg5MyRO7rgRrqXLoLotXOVfkc18.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/2dJwOHFCf1QgUgg5MyRO7rgRrqXLoLotXOVf kc18. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259265&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Wei Art Museum, Shaoxing, Zhejiang, &quot;The Impermanence of the Pen, the Elegance and the Richness&quot; by Ren Bonian Painting exhibition site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total length is nearly 13 meters and it is opened for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that Xu Wei&#39;s &quot;Flowers of the Four Seasons&quot; collected by the Palace Museum has left the palace. Going out of the palace means going home. At this moment, it is lying quietly in the Xu Wei Art Museum in Shaoxing. This is the first time it has been unfolded so completely. Prior to this, due to the limitations of the exhibition space, this long scroll had never been completely opened. Visitors to the exhibition could only see part of it. Even in the album, it could only be broken down piece by piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flowers in the four seasons have never been in full bloom at the same time. Peonies and peonies in spring, grapes and bananas in midsummer, osmanthus and pines in autumn, bamboo branches and old plums with snow in winter, all splashing together to create a wonderful achievement. The &quot;Rise of Smoke and Clouds&quot; by Xu Wei, the founder of Chinese freehand brushwork and a giant of the generation. The self-revealed poem at the end of the volume is even more sophisticated: &quot;I am dripping with ink while playing games. Flowers and plants will be mixed all the time. No wonder there are two strokes missing in the painting. The way of heaven has been very bad recently.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening time of Xu Wei Art Museum is different. It was only officially put into use in 2021, which was still during the COVID-19 epidemic. Since the opening of the museum, there have been only three large-scale exhibitions, but each of them was &quot;flawless&quot;. The opening exhibition was the exhibition of the &quot;freak Ivy&quot; Xu Wei himself, followed by Chen Laolian. By 2023, It is a special performance by Ren Bonian, and each performance is worth a special trip. The 13-meter &quot;Flowers of the Four Seasons&quot; came from Ren Bonian&#39;s exhibition. Although Xu Wei and his fellow countryman Ren Bonian are more than 300 years apart in time, the intersection in space and the transmission of culture can be called the inheritance of pen and ink in a broad sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/HPXewWe9C11GQigdCrEXNX4QPRGcowIm1pwsasyB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/HPXewWe9C11GQigdCrEXNX4QPRGcowIm1pwsasyB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259263&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhong Kui in the works of Ren Bonian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Bonian, a painter in the late Qing Dynasty, was a leader among the &quot;Shanghai School&quot; and the &quot;Four Rens&quot;, especially the figures. Good at painting. When Ren Bonian was young, his family ran a rice shop, but his father was good at painting and taught him in his spare time. It is said that Ren Bonian was able to draw lifelike figures very early. It is said that one time someone came to see his father, but his father was not there. When he came back and heard about it, he asked Ren Bonian who the visitor was. Bonian was only ten years old at the time and could not answer the guest&#39;s name, so he had to take a piece of paper and draw the person&#39;s name. His appearance was obvious to his father at a glance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ren Bonian was 22 years old, the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom invaded Shaoxing and his father was killed. Ren Bonian was also involved in the war and held the flag for the Taiping Army. He later lived in Ningbo and Shanghai and made a living selling paintings. Ren Xiong and Ren Xun among the &quot;Four Rens on the Sea&quot; are Ren Bonian&#39;s clan uncles, and they both taught him painting, but he soon became better than his master. In this exhibition of Ren Bonian&#39;s paintings titled &quot;Impermanent Brushwork, Elegance and Richness&quot;, his paintings are displayed together with the other &quot;Three Rens&quot;, making a judgment, although he learned from Ren Xun The complicated &quot;nail head and rat tail&quot; brushwork, but the same painting of people, Ren Bonian&#39;s stylist Fa Chen Laolian immediately got rid of Ren Xun&#39;s vulgarity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Wu shepherding sheep, Xizhi loves geese, Zhong Kui...these are common themes in Ren Bonian&#39;s works, and they are characters he repeatedly painted. The Zhong Kui he painted is especially chic, with a high attitude and a swaggering look. The knights, often in these works with new and surprising shapes, you can get a glimpse of the painter&#39;s true temperament and sense of humor. The same goes for his paintings of flowers and birds. The fat bird with its big white eyes comes from Bada Shanren, but the extraordinary rise of Bada turned into joy in Ren Bonian&#39;s place. The chicks that have just emerged from their eggshells under the crape myrtle flowers are fluffy and childish. His gait and expression are like those of a gangster, he is still young and arrogant, which makes people smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Egpnr7tr8haTxsmnwxwnPmwCUl88sESebNpNhPcg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;461&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Egpnr7tr8haTxsmnwxwnPmwCUl88sESebNpNhPcg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aunt Gongsun is considered the best master of sword dancing in the prosperous Tang Dynasty&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most interesting one is &quot;A Picture of Aunt Gongsun Dancing with Swords&quot;. It is said that Aunt Gongsun was the number one dancer in the prosperous age of Kaiyuan, and was promoted to be the best dancer in the prosperous Tang Dynasty for her sword dancing. Zhang Xu, the grass sage, understood the essence of cursive script from her sword skills, and Wu Daozi, the painting sage, also learned about Gongsun Auntie’s dance by watching her dance. Use the sword to learn how to use the pen. What the actual situation is cannot be determined now, but look at Ren Bonian&#39;s painting of sword dancing. Gongsun danced the two white blades as if they were practiced softly. The artist did not hesitate to draw hundreds of circles to record the imaginary and the real. All the traces of the sword flying across the air, the leaves on the big tree branches behind Aunt Gongsun trembled, as if they felt the sword energy, but Aunt Gongsun herself remained unmoved, her expression was quite calm, she was the one who stood firm among the thousands of changes. The core of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Beihong once said: Ren Bonian is &quot;the first Chinese painter after Qiu Shizhou (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qiu Ying&lt;/span>;) &quot;I don&#39;t care whether this statement is fair or not, but at least it reflects Xu Beihong&#39;s preference for Ren Bonian. This preference may be related to Ren Bonian&#39;s position. He lives in Shanghai all year round and makes a living selling paintings. Therefore, his paintings combine literati paintings and fireworks. Indeed, we can see many traces of connecting the past and the future, connecting China and the world. It is a rich and flexible tradition of calligraphy and painting, which is at the confluence and turning point of the tide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都新力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261516]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The power of a city to move forward largely comes from the new strength of the new youth. Looking at the country, Chengdu can be one of the leaders in exploring and embracing this urban power engine. From building a nest to attract &quot;Rongcheng drifters&quot;, to building a &quot;City of Volunteers&quot;, to new young people and new careers, we observe the uniqueness of this Chengdu from a top-down perspective.</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>