<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[陕西回应强砍国槐树事件：属违规占用永久基本农田]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260438]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 19:24:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to online reports that &quot;more than 30,000 Chinese locust trees were forcibly cut down in Danfeng County, Shaanxi Province&quot;, the local government has established a An investigation team composed of the County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, County Resources Bureau, County Forestry Bureau and other units conducted on-site investigations. Relevant departments in Danfeng County released the following investigation results on November 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the location where the problem was reported is located in Taizimiao Village, Caichuan Town, Danfeng County. On July 3, 2023, Caichuan Town received the &quot;Rectification Order for Suspected Pattern Issues of Permanent Basic Farmland&quot; from the Tianchang Office of Danfeng County. It reported that three satellite patches in Taizimiao Village were suspected of illegally occupying permanent basic farmland and requested rectification within a time limit. . After field investigation, it was found that walnut trees and Sophora japonica were planted on the farmland involved in the feedback map, which was indeed an illegal occupation of permanent basic farmland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the rectification notice, town and village staff repeatedly publicized the farmland protection policy to the people involved, mobilized cooperation and support for farmland protection work, and in accordance with the laws and regulations of the &quot;Land Management Law&quot; and &quot;Basic Farmland Protection Regulations&quot;, A notice for rectification within a time limit was issued on the spot, and three people refused to make rectification within a time limit. Subsequently, town and village cadres visited the plot many times to help with sales and reduce losses to the masses. However, due to the high density of seedlings planted and the occurrence of dry rot in large areas, no company purchased it. After that, town and village cadres came to communicate with each other many times without success, and the above three people refused to make rectifications within a time limit. On November 2, the Caichuan Town Government, together with the County Agricultural Law Enforcement Brigade, cleared and replanted walnut trees and Sophora japonica seedlings illegally planted on permanent basic farmland. Because planting seedlings on the involved plots of land is illegal and illegal, occupying permanent basic farmland, no compensation matters are involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[台剧这十年，内卷+外卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260427]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The 58th Golden Bell ended at the end of October At the awards, you can see the grand fight between gods in Taiwanese dramas: &quot;Copycat&quot;, &quot;Her and Her&quot;, &quot;A Rampage Female Surgeon Comes to the Village&quot;... There are many excellent products and the competition is fierce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Taiwanese dramas have shown a trend of comprehensive revival and diversification of genres since 2019, completely reversing the decline caused by the decline of idol dramas around 2010. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does it get out of today&#39;s new situation? Today, let’s talk about the past ten years of Taiwanese drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Involution: The self-rescue of a veteran TV personality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the minds of many viewers, Taiwanese dramas were once equated with &quot;idol dramas&quot;. After the millennium, youthful idol dramas such as &quot;Meteor Garden&quot;, &quot;Prince Turns into a Frog&quot;, &quot;Mischief Kiss&quot;, &quot;Princess Little Sister&quot; and &quot;Destined to Love You&quot; dominate the airwaves, with an innocent and dreamy style that is earthy and sweet. It captured the hearts of many young audiences and became many people’s youth memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e295fca9ac060796c53c5306d316b9c6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e295fca9ac060796c53c5306d316b9c6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5d3af5f82213fe907ee7f9bbcd2a0d63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;769&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5d3af5f82213fe907ee7f9bbcd2a0d63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the good times lasted less than ten years. Due to copy-paste and audience fatigue, Taiwanese dramas have entered a period of depression and depression. Idol dramas cannot produce new ideas, local dramas cannot retain audiences, and coupled with the outflow of talent, Taiwanese dramas are in a precarious situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, the well-known TV personality Wang Xiaodi joined forces with eight directors including Tsai Ming-liang, Chen Yuxun, and Qu Youning to establish a company and launched the &quot;Theater Planting&quot; and &quot;QPlace&quot; plans, aiming to build a platform to &quot;give access to It is a space where writers, actors, directors and post-production staff with ideas can be nourished and developed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Zhi Theater&quot; is mainly divided into four sections: love growth, thriller mystery, horror and supernatural, and drama adaptation. Dramas such as &quot;Love Sandstorm&quot;, &quot;Twilight&quot;, &quot;Please Close Your Eyes after Dark&quot; and &quot;Sixties Boy Turns Adult&quot; have launched the first shot of innovation in Taiwanese dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tumi&quot; was born out of an idol love drama, mixing elements of parallel time and space to explore different directions of love stories. It is indeed innovative at the time of 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/6b932ede0feef3a482a4e13ed7afbe8a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;483&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/6b932ede0feef3a482a4e13ed7afbe8a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Sixtieth Century Boy&quot; &quot;Become an Adult&quot; and &quot;Love Sandstorm&quot; are rooted in family dramas, focusing on the daily style that touches people with emotion, less of the horse-grabbing style of &quot;Taiwan Acheng&quot; and &quot;Unforgettable&quot;, and more of the warmth of the flow of life. In the face of traditional Taiwanese dramas that often have 40 or 200 episodes, the small-scale short drama model of &quot;Zhitheater&quot; appears to be the essence of the drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/16852e4bffbe38ab732831c217b55e53.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/16852e4bffbe38ab732831c217b55e53.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Plant Theater &quot;Adopting the model of stars bringing up new stars, we use well-known actors such as Wu Kangren, Rainie Yang, and Lan Zhenglong to act together with the newcomers they discovered. Nowadays, Xu Guanghan (&quot;Want to See You&quot;) and Liu Guanting (&quot;Tears of the Fire God&quot;) are shining stars, as well as Sun Kefang (&quot;Gu Wei&quot;) and Chen Yu (&quot;The Distance Between Us and Evil&quot;) who are gradually gaining a foothold in the new generation. 》) and others all grew up in this model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2e0c16691b6093f7b15be2265ca265be.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/2e0c16691b6093f7b15be2265ca265be.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022, &quot;Zhi Theater&quot; has been upgraded to &quot;Zhu Theater&quot;, adding reportage and biographies to the original type of drama, and planning to film &quot;The Mystery Bookstore of Dripping Water&quot;, &quot;Green Island Golden Soul&quot;, &quot;Walking Through the Wilderness of Love&quot; and &quot;Who Said Mother is Like the Moon&quot; Waiting for the series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, established TV stations are also gaining momentum to promote the in-depth development of traditional dramas. PTV&#39;s &quot;A Handful of Green&quot; (2015) is adapted from the short story of the same name by Bai Xianyong. The director and screenwriter built branches and flesh and blood. The love-hate entanglement in the pilot&#39;s family village reflects the chronic diseases of the times, and composes a heart-stirring, sad and touching song. Past events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ae351f9ce4641ad0c32041c414a1a9e9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ae351f9ce4641ad0c32041c414a1a9e9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Television&#39;s &quot;The Rise of a Common Girl&quot; (2019) has achieved the best performance of China Television&#39;s self-produced drama in the past ten years. It juxtaposes the spaces of Taipei and Tainan, and the time of childhood and middle age, focusing on the life choices of a 40-year-old woman, and perfectly hits the theater-watching group who wanders in the city and laughs at themselves as &quot;losers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5ebcc3d9264824785423719cc3e03b8e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5ebcc3d9264824785423719cc3e03b8e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Original from TVBS The drama series &quot;In This Life Time&quot; (2023) is called the &quot;male version of &quot;Vulgarity&quot;&quot;. It tells the story of a failed middle-aged man who decides to die. It is healing and heart-warming, and it also resonates with people who have full-time children and middle-aged unemployment. social issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/36149784d72d77a2281adf518c4ea3b1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/36149784d72d77a2281adf518c4ea3b1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;External volume: The business expansion of streaming media platforms&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The local efforts have formed healthy competition, while the outward business expansion has brought new momentum to Taiwanese dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, HBO, Netflix, Disney, etc. have all vigorously expanded overseas business, and Taiwan has become the first choice for co-production of Chinese dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foreign streaming media brought the industrialized shooting model, fast-paced, short series, high-investment and attractive American dramas in the first two episodes to Taiwan. In the words of producer Liu Yuxuan, compared with the mature industrial model, the previous way of filming dramas was nothing more than &quot;homemade steelmaking.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HBO is the first streaming media to try its luck in Taiwan. In 2017, it collaborated with Public Television on &quot;Psychic Girl,&quot; a drama that combines elements of fantasy and girl growth and achieved a ratings miracle. In 2019, the two parties joined forces again to create &quot;The Distance Between Us and Evil&quot;, which is rooted in realism. This drama that discusses indiscriminate murders from different perspectives has become a hit of the year. In 2020, the drama series &quot;Workers&quot; about the lower class people once again set off a craze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c1cbbc89cd33f8cfc37e9d9dfa82c785.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/c1cbbc89cd33f8cfc37e9d9dfa82c785.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netflix in 2018 &quot;Your Child Is Not Your Child&quot; was launched in 2011, and its in-depth discussion of East Asian education issues aroused widespread resonance after being broadcast. &quot;The Dreamer&quot; in 2019, &quot;Who is the Victim&quot; in 2020 and &quot;Copycat&quot; in 2023 focus on large-scale suspense. The quality of the series is not first-class, but the popularity and topicality are both high. The 2021-2022 &quot;The Lights Come on&quot; has better completed the shaping of group portraits. The retro era texture and heavy life tragedy make it different from ordinary romance dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab84f678d8ad4eaa60683992f4a3587a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab84f678d8ad4eaa60683992f4a3587a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257944&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FOX provides technology The supported &quot;Want to Meet You&quot; is a phenomenon-level hit drama in recent years, with a significant long-tail effect. It not only put Xu Guanghan on the front line, but also spawned a movie of the same name. If you look at it dismantled, it is an addition to the campus puppet show, smoothly integrating the fantasy elements of parallel time and space, giving people a refreshing feeling. Of course, in the end, the Möbius strip-like narrative clues are no longer important, and its trump card is still the local advantage of being good at touching people with delicate emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3555ee32ddb4ce49a0018ec6cd3a0c58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3555ee32ddb4ce49a0018ec6cd3a0c58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foreign streaming media The choice of subject matter tends to be a fusion of genres, and sometimes it feels like it is stacking popular elements. For example, &quot;The Dreamer&quot;, which combines suspense, crime, and the supernatural, has many highlights that are popular on the Internet, but the whole drama is tiring and tiring to watch. confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/616c2deebca29768dc10519ee6e576f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/616c2deebca29768dc10519ee6e576f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257947&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The preparatory stage is often It is dominated by big data, so there are gangster fantasy idol dramas &quot;The Ultimate Daughter&quot; that think they have hit the high point but are not, Chinese and Western supernatural mash-up drama &quot;Marriage on the Other Side&quot;, dark suspense cult family drama &quot;Who&#39;s Beside You&quot; and many more Too successful an attempt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e56bf0fe61d21154e84e13e494dd430e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e56bf0fe61d21154e84e13e494dd430e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Observe the co-production drama It is not difficult to find the hit hits: they are all dramas with more prominent local elements. For example, &quot;The Distance Between Us and Evil&quot; is adapted from real cases in Taiwanese society, and &quot;The First Light&quot; touches on Taiwan&#39;s special tact culture after the Japanese colonial period. . How to maximize the strengths of Chinese and Western cultures when they meet is a key consideration for Taiwanese TV people involved in co-productions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab1939a869b6f7561f2e39b29513e610.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;605&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ab1939a869b6f7561f2e39b29513e610.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/4f83e45663cf1e49c4b04bf40c3a2a35.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/4f83e45663cf1e49c4b04bf40c3a2a35.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, video platforms such as Tencent and iQiyi It has also actively launched an &quot;overseas&quot; strategy to produce films and TV dramas in Asia. Taiwan, which has the same cultural roots and has a mature film and television chain, will undoubtedly take the lead in cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the mainland video platform brings to Taiwan is an industrialized marketing model that will not interfere too much with the creation of its drama series. The drama series will be broadcast simultaneously on the video platform, triggering an upsurge in watching dramas on both sides of the Taiwan Strait. The platform carefully selects potential new artists from Taiwan to help them expand their business outside the island, and it seems to have plans to promote new Chinese idols. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Forever No. 1&quot; and &quot;Second No. 1 Counterattack&quot; launched by Tencent WeTV are benchmarks for same-sex themes. Young artists such as Jiang Ruizhi and Lin Zihong have also gained great attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The iQiyi International Station covers more genres, including &quot;The Ninth Lesson&quot; about taboo teacher-student love, the suspenseful crime drama &quot;Reversal&quot; that exposes the dark web, and the highlight of brothers&#39; CP. The supernatural fantasy urban drama &quot;The Obsessed Eliminator&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the hit series, veteran actor Zhou Yimin became famous again, and newcomers Zeng Jinghua and Chen Haosen each had their masterpieces after &quot;The Name Engraved in Your Heart&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5482da2c9b92aa2cb3d50b61c64e7a8b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/5482da2c9b92aa2cb3d50b61c64e7a8b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257948&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall , the revival of Taiwanese dramas is the result of the joint efforts of many parties. Internally, we are constantly innovating, and externally, we are also extending an olive branch of opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has also led to a steady increase in the number of viewers watching Taiwanese dramas in recent years. The dramas to be aired by high-quality Taiwanese artists are often looked at with high expectations, and more expectations are placed on them. This is the reward of a virtuous cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And when these high-quality Taiwanese dramas come to domestic entertainment, what kind of answer should we hand over? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“上岸”成了年轻人的执念？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;In 2023, Fangcao Magazine, an institution affiliated with Wuhan Federation of Literary and Art Circles, announced a special recruitment list. Young writers Ban Yu, Chen Chuncheng, and Wang Suxin , Danbao (Liu Xueting) is on the list. The &quot;Writer&#39;s Examination for Editor&quot; once again caused netizens to lament that &quot;the end of the universe is the editor&#39;s examination&quot;. In recent years, as the number of applicants for the postgraduate entrance examination has continued to rise, the word &quot;going ashore&quot; is always on the lips of young people.</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她年少成名，十四年后拍出新片再得大奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260408]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, for the promotion of the movie &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot;, director Liu Jiayin registered for the first time Weibo. In order to learn how to use it skillfully, she specially asked a friend to teach her online, wrote her first tweet, and left an anxious message to the producer&#39;s account: &quot;I seem to have #(marked) the wrong content, why is it different from yours?&quot; ?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; is Liu Jiayin&#39;s third feature film, but she said, &quot;To a certain extent, this is my debut film.&quot; This film is her first time working with professional actors and a filming team, which requires a lot of communication work. The introverted Liu Jiayin needs to take a brand new step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JOgJRXabKSXRlbZ1QshfSkuDgbg7YvsEQMbBRIbh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, director Liu Jiayin released her new feature film &quot;Worth It&quot; after a lapse of fourteen years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiayin is a teacher in the Literature Department of Beijing Film Academy. In her 17 years of teaching, she has often been criticized by her colleagues. Ask the same question as the students: &quot;When will you make a movie again?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, Liu Jiayin can be regarded as famous at a young age. In her first year of graduate school, at just 24 years old, she made her debut with the feature film &quot;Cowhide&quot; shot on DV. &quot;Won an important award in the Youth Forum section of the Berlin Film Festival. At the age of 28, she was shortlisted for the Cannes Film Festival Directors&#39; Fortnight for &quot;Cowhide 2&quot; and became a young director of great concern to the international film community. But for the next fourteen years, due to various reasons, she had no new films released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People around me are asking why I stopped filming? The motivation brought by pressure is huge.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first two movies, Liu Jiayin took care of almost all the affairs of the crew by herself. She was the director, screenwriter and photographer, as well as the producer and starring role. &quot;It was the era of DV, and I am particularly grateful to this period. I was definitely a beneficiary of it. This equipment was very suitable for my personality of &#39;working alone&#39;.&quot; Liu Jiayin recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Liu Jiayin began to officially write the script of &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot;. The final version was more than 60,000 words long, which is more than twice the length of ordinary scripts. Liu Jiayin also wrote a novel of more than 100,000 words for the characters in the script, describing the life of the novel&#39;s protagonist Wen Shan in more detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original title of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; was &quot;Listening&quot;, not only because Wen Shan&#39;s work in the film requires listening to complete, but also because of Liu Jiayin&#39;s insights in life, &quot;Listening is not hearing. It’s about understanding the other person and learning to think from the other person’s perspective.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan, the protagonist of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;, is a frustrated screenwriter. He gave up his original profession because he couldn&#39;t write the stories that Party A needed, and accidentally became a eulogy writer. . This new career requires him to learn to listen to other people&#39;s stories and restore the emotions of the deceased to the deceased, and his own life has also turned around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time he receives an order, Wenshan will visit the relatives and friends of the deceased and take a lot of notes to learn as much as possible about the deceased. He interviewed his sister who felt sorry for her brother who always acted as a &quot;good guy&quot; and could not let go of him until his death; he met a son who was busy with work and neglected to communicate with his old father when he was still alive, so he could only regret it for the rest of his life; he also got to know the man who had traveled thousands of miles from Gansu to A persistent girl in Beijing who explores the true state of deceased netizens... Among Wenshan&#39;s many clients, there is also Aunt Fang, a cancer patient who booked a eulogy for herself early. After learning that she had cancer, she chose to actively &quot;fight towards death&quot; born&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this job, Wenshan healed his clients and himself. Starring Hu Ge told Southern Weekend reporters that Wen Shan&#39;s work is to influence others, &quot;nourishing the living with the dead&quot; and allowing the living to feel the meaning of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the film, Wenshan finally had the courage to face his past failures, and he could face the script that he could not finish no matter what, and write characters he believed in. &quot;The most important thing is that life recognizes Wen Shan.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the 25th Shanghai International Film Festival awarded the Best Director Award to Liu Jiayin, and she was once again recognized by the Class A film festival. In September, &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; was officially released, which was Liu Jiayin&#39;s first movie to be released in public. After the movie was released, her Weibo really played a &quot;listening&quot; role. She received hundreds of private messages from viewers. People shared their feelings about watching the movie with the director in text, pouring out their deepest feelings to their relatives and friends. emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/3xag3euF7p72ekhzeSAG05CHQ01sjah9F058FATw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the process of directing a new film, listening and cooperation have taken on a new meaning for Liu Jiayin (second from right). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A pair of elderly sisters in their seventies, suffering from lung cancer and breast cancer respectively, They actively treated each other and encouraged each other, while accompanying their 95-year-old mother until her old age. After watching &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; four times, my sister wrote in a private message: &quot;We wrote eulogies for our mother, but we were shy to express our love in front of her; just like Wen Shan, when he was down and out, he was confused and inferior, and he struggled to give up... Your story allows us to see ourselves.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young girl shared the story of her mother who died after eight years of suffering from cancer. &quot;It would be great if my mother could leave the traces of her short life on paper. I am also a filmmaker. I hope that one day I can have my mother&#39;s story well recorded...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Some of the people who shared regretted being too rebellious when their grandma was alive, some did not catch up with their relatives for the last time, and some opened up their hearts with their families because of this movie... These stories flew into Liu Jiayin&#39;s mailbox one after another, and she would Try to reply one by one during work breaks. &quot;These strangers gave me a lot of encouragement. This is the most meaningful part of the movie.&quot; Liu Jiayin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Very specific fears” bring huge creative motivation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;When you first made a movie, you chose one person to do everything. Isn’t this a very common approach? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it were the kind of movie machine that I used to have, I might not be able to afford it, nor would I know how to cooperate with others. I was using a DV player. At that time, there were still many doubts about using such a special method to shoot movies. So I chose not to listen, thinking that I could just make it myself. I grew up slowly after the age of 30 and began to learn how to communicate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The earliest name of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; is &quot;Listen&quot;, how do you understand this name? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After working, I gradually discovered that in life we ​​really need to listen. Listening is not about hearing, but about truly understanding the other person. Not only have I been misunderstood by others in my life, but I have also misunderstood others. After something like this happens again and again, you need to constantly correct your views on others, and you need to listen to them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people may be concerned about the aftermath of &quot;Niuhide&quot; , why did it take fourteen years to make a movie, and why is this &quot;A Journey Well Worth It&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am not a person who does things very quickly. I have my own rhythm, and I may not have waited for the story I particularly wanted to tell. The things I encounter every day in my daily life are very specific, and there are also some rewards and fun, so I have a lot of &quot;excuses&quot; not to create. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, the prototype of the character Wen Shan came into being, and it took several years. The character didn&#39;t have a name at the time, but I felt that he often appeared in my life, even in my room, and I would always think of him, so I gave him a name and determined to write his story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your previous two movies are very close to your own life Yes, you and your family are directly on the scene. &quot;It&#39;s a Worth It&quot; is a completely fictional film. What is its relationship with your own life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The previous creations were quite experimental, and &quot;Worthless Journey&quot; is different in every aspect. To a certain extent, it is My debut novel. But this movie still has a lot to do with my personal experience. It is a summary of my life over the past ten years, and everything I want to say is in it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back over the past ten years, do you think you What are the changes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was filming &quot;Cowhide&quot;, I was young, so I just gritted my teeth and made the film. Now my mentality is more complicated and requires greater drive. will be more rational. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t made a movie for a long time, and there is a high probability that I will never make another one, but I almost never stopped thinking about it. As I get older, I realize that time is limited, and I am afraid of it. If I don’t do something, I can predict what will happen in the future. This is a very specific fear, and it brings great motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2006 to the present, you have been a university teacher for seventeen years. What impact has your teaching experience had on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If I want to teach my class well, I must understand my students. This process is not particularly easy for me, especially since I am very bad at interacting with people. Every time I open the door to meet new students in the new semester, I need to do some mental construction. But what I teach is how to write stories. You must know why students write such things. You can&#39;t just say whether it is good or not. You need to understand them through stories. After slowly adjusting, I roughly knew how to express myself and take care of every student as much as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;You can find the answer by living seriously&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Wenshan needs to come into contact with all kinds of people in his work. Several of his customers appear in the movie, and they all have their own stories. Do these characters have life prototypes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no prototype. It mainly comes from daily observation of life and the screenwriter’s skills. A screenwriter should write in a way that makes people believe. In fact, I don’t have any creative skills, I just live seriously. The client&#39;s story is different in age, relationship with deceased relatives and friends, and understanding of emotions. It is similar to the situations we encounter in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wen Shan can’t be a good screenwriter, what do you think? Where is the problem stuck? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Human beings have a natural part, coupled with their experiences from childhood to adulthood, they have shaped us together and made us what we are today. look. I think Wen Shan encountered too many rejections in his previous work as a screenwriter. He was thought that the things he wrote were too ordinary, not enough for this, not enough for that. In short, the characters he wrote were &quot;not worthy&quot; of being the protagonists. After Wen Shan was denied again and again, he gradually began to doubt himself. Especially when you still can&#39;t pay the rent a few years after graduation and have to ask your parents for rent, it&#39;s a very difficult feeling. This sense of failure not only denies work, but also denies values. Do you think, &quot;Is the way I look at life wrong?&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Wenshan has not tried to defend himself, but his voice is too soft. In this case, a person&#39;s personality will also change. But to a certain extent, a screenwriter who fails to defend his story is failing to defend himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think life finally recognized Wen Shan? What does it look like specifically? Recognition? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After writing the eulogy, he found that what he had been denied before found answers in life. We can be affected by some small things, and we can also establish real connections with other people. These people are either very dramatic people in the script, or ordinary people who are inconspicuous, but they are very important to the people around them and are important to them. They themselves are also important. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this, Wen Shan will continue to write stories without any obstacles in his heart. We are often like this, always troubled by some invisible and intangible things, but I am convinced that we can find the answer as long as we live seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you hope the audience will see through this movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For most people, it is much easier to deny themselves than to affirm themselves. This may be the life of adults. But people still have to care about themselves in the end. &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; tells the story of Wen Shan&#39;s process of starting to care about himself. He realized that his feelings and things he did were important. This may also be the reason why many viewers left me messages saying they saw themselves in the movie. Those who are completely indifferent after watching this movie are the lucky ones, because no one in this movie really succeeds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The appearance of &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; can Does it solve some of your previous life confusions to a certain extent? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Jiayin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it was because I solved these confusions that I came up with this movie. In other words, after knowing yourself, you must accept yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[担心被称“普信”，不敢接触异性：一位大学老师对男生女生的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent Friday, at 2:30 in the afternoon, I parked my car in the parking lot of Guangzhou University and found that the playground There were two boys playing basketball, and they came to play so early. My curiosity drove me to get closer. I pitched and chatted with them. They are freshmen from the School of Foreign Languages. They are not only classmates, but also fellow Zhanjiang fellows. It happened that there were no classes or homework on Friday afternoon, so we were bored, so we met to play basketball. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Men and women are clearly differentiated&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As I walked, I asked how many people were in their class. They told me that there were 34 girls and 5 boys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why didn&#39;t you think about asking the female classmates in the class to go out for fun?&quot; I asked casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were quite surprised by my suggestion: &quot;Teacher, I don&#39;t know any of the girls in the class.&quot; &quot;Teacher, I know two girls in our class, but they asked me to date them. This is absolutely impossible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are 34 girls, how many people have you added to WeChat?&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I added 5 people, but I don’t have much contact with them.” Classmate A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three, and they are all cadres in the class, but I only contact them when something happens.&quot; Classmate B replied to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You are a freshman now. You should have a lot of courses, and there should be many opportunities to take classes together.&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes, we have classes together almost every day. The problem is that although we are in the same classroom, boys sit with boys and girls sit with girls. In class, they mainly listen to the teacher&#39;s lectures; after class, they disperse separately. , there is little communication and interaction with each other.&quot; Student A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Both boys and girls, everyone deliberately keeps their distance. Everyone agrees that as soon as they enter the classroom, boys and girls will sit separately.&quot; Classmate B added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, college students should have relatively free control of their time. Their physical and mental development has matured, and their need for interaction with the opposite sex is relatively strong. It is normal for them to date and become friends with the opposite sex, but the reality is not in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although classmates in the same class can meet every day and have many contact opportunities, having contact opportunities does not necessarily mean that substantial familiarity, understanding and understanding will occur in real life. Where is &quot;Geng&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing the confusion on my face, classmate B told me the whole story, &quot;Teacher, have you heard of some hot words on the Internet, such as &#39;licking the dog&#39;, &#39;lowering the head&#39; and &#39;Pu Xin&#39;?&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After his explanation, I realized that among boys and girls, the one who takes the initiative to add the other party’s WeChat account or asks for the other party’s contact information will be considered by a small number of members of the opposite sex to be a “dog licker” and a “lower” person. This situation is relatively common for boys who take the initiative. In other words, when a boy takes the initiative to add a friend to a girl he is interested in or finds interesting, some girls will think this is a strange thing and ask, &quot;What do you want to do?&quot; &quot;What are your intentions?&quot; &quot;Do you want to pursue her?&quot; Me?&quot; If the boy is not the right person for the girl, the girl will think that the boy is &quot;general trustworthy&quot;, which means &quot;ordinary but confident&quot;. The problem is that some girls may not think this way, but in order to avoid girls thinking this way, boys do not want to be misunderstood and bear the stigmatized label of &quot;normal men&quot;, so they would rather or simply not be active or take the initiative to avoid embarrassment, even in the face of The girl you are most attracted to or the girl you like the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Does the teacher know about the &#39;campus wall&#39;?&quot; Classmate A asked me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I don’t know. He explained to me this way: “It is a public platform for students to publish information. It seems that every university has it. For example, once I join someone else and I am rejected, they will remove me. If I post screenshots of others on the &#39;campus wall&#39;, then all the students in the school will know about me, and I will be polite and sweep the floor in school, unable to hold my head up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t control the other person&#39;s thinking, thoughts and actions. ，我更加没办法面对与规避这种风险的发生，所以我不会做主动亲近异性的事。”同学B无奈地说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;无形的墙&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这令我想起：一年前一次与大四毕业班的几个男生打球，他们告诉我，四年了，他们都认不全一个班的同学，或叫不清同班同学的名字，一个班或一个专业的异性学生，在他们眼里，仅仅是“同班同学”而已，而非“朋友”“密友”“闺蜜”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据我的观察，一个基本的感觉是，当下大学生同专业或同班同学之间尤其是异性之间的友情或情谊非常淡薄，他们要么各自忙，要么各自闲，各忙各的，或各闲各的，哪怕有可能对某个异性同学有好感，也断然不会主动或积极地表达交友或交往的需求或意愿。换言之，进大学之后，男生与女生之间，突然出现一堵“无形的心墙”，这堵墙禁锢着少男少女，谁都不想主动拆掉这堵墙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进大学之前当然是高中，高中时期的同班同学关系普遍很好，天天朝夕相处，一起讨论做题，一起玩娱解压，男生递个暧昧的纸条给心仪的女生，女生多看几眼心仪的男生，下晚自习在校门口某个角落见面约着一起回家，激动的时候牵牵对方的手，给对方以温暖、力量或鼓励，这是多么正常的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的大学时代&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我不禁想起我的大学生涯，那是1997-2001年。军训结束后第一周的第一次上课，班主任老师花了整整两节课的时间让每位同学上讲台做了自我介绍，然后大家一起去校门口一家餐厅共进午餐，彼此迅速熟络起来。男生女生约着一起晨读、早餐、上课；晚饭后，大家一起上晚自习，下自习后就在学校一条宽阔的马路打上一小时的羽毛球。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候的公开示爱，也是极其常见的事。对于心仪的异性，大方开朗的人就直抒胸臆，“我可以约你看电影吗”；腼腆内敛的人则托个中间人做媒，通过小纸条或信件的方式表达约会的意愿。如果两个人一起吃了饭，看了电影（通常是通宵电影），然后牵了手，那基本上就宣告“亲密的男女关系”基本确立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;换言之，喜欢谁，中意谁，表达这种情绪或情愫，是很正常的事。我记得很清楚，我们班共计42人，男生22，女生20，大四毕业那会儿有多达5对情侣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;关切当代大学生的价值观及真实心理&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当下的男生普遍对恋爱没有兴趣，不想认识与了解女生吗？抑或相反，当下的女生普遍对恋爱没有兴趣，不想认识与了解男生吗？我感觉都不是。面对就业压力普遍大的整体环境，一些人从大一就开始紧张起来，忙碌于考研、考公、大学英语四六级、驾驶证、教师资格证等，但在“日理万机”之余，他们的内心还是有孤寂或孤独的时候，他们也渴望邂逅或拥有一份唯美的爱情，问题是谁都不想被认为是“舔狗族”“下头族”或“普信族”，谁都不想主动出击去接触与了解异性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当代大学生与同班同学相对生疏，那么，他们与谁相对熟稔呢？据了解，相对于上公共课或专业课的同学，他们与有相同或相似兴趣或爱好的人熟络起来更容易一些。打个比方，街舞社团、文学社团、篮球社团、戏曲社团等社团内部的同学关系，要亲密过上同一门专业课的同班同学。究其原因，各类社团更吻合同学们的兴趣或爱好，这是他们内心喜欢或中意做的事，大家一起交流与切磋技艺，一起密切配合与协作，往往能酝酿出感情的种子，而在专业课课堂上，或许课程本身难度相对大，大部分同学没有多大兴趣一起研讨或交流，亲密关系的建立自然相对漫长。从空间角度看，专业课堂是正式、正规与严肃的空间，各类社团则是非正式、非正规与闲适空间，后者让人相对松弛、轻松与自然，此即非正式空间（informal space）的功效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让大学生们轻松与轻盈一些，让他们身心愉悦一些，让他们敢于和勇于做吻合他们这个年龄段的“分内之事”，让同学情谊回归纯真与深厚，让谈情说爱成为理所当然的事，这是当代大学生新气象的应有之义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了达致上述目标，余以为有关方面当多一点关心与关切当代大学生的价值观及真实心理与心态，各大学开设关于大学生心理方面的公共必修课，鼓励与崇尚构建开放包容与和谐的男女关系，破除制造性别对立与敌意的各种观念藩篱与阻梗。课程学习方面，任课老师不妨多鼓励同学们进行小组讨论，且建议男女搭配成组，营造异性讨论的良好氛围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，有关方面要在课余时间方面寻找突破口，要用尽量多的公共活动填充同学们的课余时间，创造机会让男女同学彼此接触、了解与认识，譬如组织同学们开展校园游、都市游、郊游、秋游、周末徒步或聚餐等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系广州大学社会学系教授）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[辛柏青：适度的，饱满的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;时间&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2020年，导演张律从韩国回北京，按当时的新冠疫情防控政策，在广州的酒店隔离两周，期间他写了一个剧本，发给辛柏青，说主角谷文通是为他写的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷文通是北京人，离了婚，女儿寄养在姐姐家，自己住母亲留下的老屋，和一个年轻的女孩儿暧昧又分开，少年时最好的朋友在他乡自杀。这位曾经写诗的人，如今靠写美食文章为生，在北京的大街小巷游走，孤零零的，有种无法稳定下来的漂泊感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;演员辛柏青此前跟张律合作了《漫长的告白》（2021）——立春和立冬兄弟俩从北京去日本，找与二人年少时都有羁绊的姑娘柳川，大家各怀心事。辛柏青演的立春已有家庭，人到异国，通过满不在乎的方式掩藏自己的孤独和不自在。他说，“张律导演比较偏爱写这种有漂泊感和孤独感的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青在片场休息或者出神的某一瞬间，让张律看到了这种感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷文通家住白塔旁边，辛柏青也在北京长大。张律说过，辛柏青身上有一种老北京人的“不急”。不急的人，看似慢半拍，身上时间的痕迹更重，和过去的关系比不停往前奔的人要紧密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《白塔之光》中的谷文通一出场像被困在时间里的人，穿懒汉布鞋，只有一件姜黄色条绒外套和一个软塌塌的双肩包，多数时候走路、偶尔坐公交车，吃“五十岁以上老人儿才惦记”的卤煮，与当下发生的一切隔着一层，习惯对所有人说不好意思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么这样的人会让我多看几眼呢？”张律接受《看电影》采访时说，“因为在这种人身上，过去的时间还在，现在的时间发生了微妙的变化，两个时间的东西挤压在了他的身上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于谷文通来说，过去的时间和现在的状态都与缺失的父亲有关：五岁那年，父亲被指控在公交车上猥亵妇女，被母亲赶出家门。等他人到中年，突然有了父亲的消息，当年的“流氓罪”是冤案，这么多年，父亲一直远远注视着他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父子和解的场面很短暂，两人在简陋的房间里伴着上世纪的DVD画面跳了一段交谊舞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个大男人一起跳舞，不是中国人的情感表达方式，更不是辛柏青的。他问张律，怎么跳？张律说，到时候就能跳。他又问饰演父亲的田壮壮，剧本里所有的戏他都能理解、都能想象得到最后呈现的样子，可跳舞这场戏，怪怪的。田壮壮也说，到那天会有办法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了那天，辛柏青先说一句台词：爸，你站起来。两个人身体僵硬地跳了几下。辛柏青对田壮壮说，爸，你手上的血管像蚯蚓——这是女儿之前对谷文通说过的话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田壮壮看了眼自己的手，接着顺势把手搭到辛柏青肩上。跳舞的戏水到渠成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太对了，辛柏青感叹。 “就通过这一个动作，父亲那么多年的情感落到手上，放到了我的肩膀上。这个动作很小，但是内容太多了。”他想，“当你直奔结果、直奔目的而去的时候，会觉得怎么这么难？但是把这个结果和目的忘了，享受过程、表达过程的时候，结果自然呈现。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《白塔之光》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人保戏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月27日，《白塔之光》上映。这部电影在年初入围了第73届柏林电影节主竞赛单元。 4月，导演张律在北京电影节参加《白塔之光》映后活动，评价说，“辛柏青表演是含着的。努着劲的表演容易拿奖。辛柏青太应该拿奖了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从名气上看，辛柏青可能不算一线的明星演员。有几年，他的影视作品不多。但到电影《妖猫传》（2017），寥寥几个镜头，观众完全被他演的李白吸引住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;剧本里他只有一场戏：高力士把李白扛到极乐之宴，李白醉醺醺作了首诗，“云想衣裳花想容。”醉是基调。辛柏青想，真的要演醉吗？ “我对李白的认知，那是李白特别清醒的时期，因为他对仕途的所有幻想都已经破灭。所有人都在夸他可以当大官，他太清楚，到此为止了。”要有醉态，但一定要特别清醒，不能演醉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在片场，导演陈凯歌说，待会儿不用走戏，直接拍。太好了，辛柏青后来说，“我愿意碰撞最鲜活的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个镜头，一遍就过了。到监视器那儿，陈凯歌先说了句题外话，“咱以后还得合作”；然后给辛柏青看监视器：辛柏青上来一坐，很舒展，还在金龟上蹭蹭，然后悠悠冲着杨贵妃问，你是谁啊？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈凯歌说，这就是李白。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电视剧观众可能通过早些年的《幸福像花儿一样》（2005）或者近年的《大秦赋》（2020）认识了辛柏青。真正让他被记住的角色是年代剧《人世间》（2022）里的周秉义——东北普通家庭里的大哥：下乡知青，考上北大，后成为改革开放时期有突出贡献的官员，有特殊时代很多人的影子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;编剧王海鸰接到改编邀约，看梁晓声的原著小说，觉得描写周秉义的笔墨相对单薄，比如他主政一方之后，拆迁自己长大的棚户区“光字片”的过程，几笔带过。在王海鸰的故事里，弟弟周秉昆代表的家（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;基层百姓&lt;/span>;）、哥哥周秉义代表的国（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;政府官员&lt;/span>;）是主干。于是她下了大力气写周秉义成为领导干部之后的戏。 “非要说的话，这个剧的前半部分是周秉昆的主场，后半部分是周秉义的主场。”她说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人世间》播出大约一半时，王海鸰和辛柏青在一次活动中遇上。周秉义的重头戏还没播出，王海鸰不知道辛柏青能演成什么样，双方只泛泛客套几句，她似乎听辛柏青说了句“这个剧本的文学性很强”，她想，这不过是人家客气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等到看完全剧，王海鸰后悔没多跟辛柏青聊聊，“这是一个太好的演员了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“略举一例：看剧中棚户区拆迁那场戏前，我心情是有点紧张的，那场戏我给了周秉义一段几千字的台词，剧情到那了只能那么写，想拍摄时导演也许会有办法减少这段戏的表演难度——不敢期待演员能达成心愿，那时我印象中辛柏青是一个文艺片的小众演员——不承想，那十几分钟的戏就那么一镜到底一气呵成地拍下来了，辛柏青用他对人物的理解、气质上的天赋、台词功底成功赋于了一个执政者应具有的真实的高尚。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;距离《人世间》首播已经一年有余，周秉义在棚户区拆迁现场处理纠纷、给从小认识的邻里朋友讲政策的片段，还在自媒体上流传，成为表演也是演讲的经典范例。王海鸰写小说出身，后来调入总政话剧团做戏剧，她说，“彼时常听前辈老师们说，戏保人，人保戏。周秉义这个角色的成功，当属人保戏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;一个人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《人世间》之后，辛柏青接到大量官员类角色。但他不想被类型化，新鲜的角色才能激起他的好奇心。他拍了纪录片导演徐童的首部剧情片《三个十年》，演反角闫永刚，和演警察贾国志的段奕宏搭戏。在春风得意的年代，闫永刚于一次追捕行动中打伤警察贾国志，贾没死，闫也没被捕，结了血仇，但是生出了棋逢敌手的惺惺相惜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童在自己的原著小说《珍宝岛》里是这样写官员子弟闫永刚的：出手黑，人白净，带着一股阴气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童和辛柏青一起去作家阿城家讨论《珍宝岛》的改编，那是他第一次见辛柏青，刚停车下来，看到后面辛柏青开着一辆SUV也到了，一个人，没有团队，没有助理。 “当时我就觉得很舒服，他是很自然的、一个人的状态。没有演艺圈的习气，或者说演员的做派。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿城家见过面之后，阿城跟徐童说，你注意看，柏青含胸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童后来仔细观察，辛柏青一点儿也不含胸，一米八几，挺直溜个人。徐童问辛柏青，一直就是这个形体？辛柏青说是，几十年一直这样，一点儿没胖，也一点儿没瘦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐童明白了，阿城指的并不是形体，而是辛柏青给人一种含胸的印象。 “因为他的消瘦气质，他身上的含蓄。”类似的，徐童发现辛柏青有一种特殊的眼神，“他看事物看东西，不是那种眼睛放光，直接看，而是感觉好像隔着一层东西，光往回收，含在里面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意识到这两点，再看辛柏青塑造的角色，徐童觉得，“他的表达是适度的，同时也是饱满的，饱满是说他背后的东西是饱满的。”陈凯歌对辛柏青有类似的评价，他说辛柏青“吃得很深，吐得很少”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年春天，《三个十年》在陕西开机。辛柏青答应徐童提前进组，推掉了别的安排。 “他说过完春节之后，我就溜达过去了。”徐童回忆，“至今回想起来我们那一段时间的工作，我都觉得他不是一个演员，他没有把我们这个合作当成一个项目，他就是创作一个人物。熟悉环境，进入空间，然后进到这个人物当中去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开机前有剧本围读，大家谈得不多，徐童说，辛柏青和段奕宏已经把人物翻来覆去吃透，再谈多，反而影响现场的即兴感。他用“非常刺激，又非常惊喜”形容两位演员的表演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然合作愉快，但徐童和辛柏青在那部戏之后的交往并不多。部分原因是徐童有意为之，“我需要跟演员保持一个距离，是为了产生一种陌生感，私交多了会影响未来对人物的想象力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他觉得辛柏青更懂这个道理，所以在角色之外很少露面，“如果观众对你这张脸太熟悉了，当你再去塑造一个人物的时候，那个人物的可信度就会降低，或者说冲击感就会降低。”好演员需要保持相当程度的孤独状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“三板斧”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我们找到的辛柏青的合作伙伴都很愿意谈论他的表演，但是要和他本人聊表演并不容易，像张律说的，他是含着的；或者像徐童说的，他是往回收的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比起细致地讲述心路历程，他更愿意这样总结：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我的工作方法就是尽量把文学描述变为可视化的形象。第一步，我的形象从哪而来？他是什么样子的，大概什么发型，穿什么衣服，戴不戴眼镜，他走路的姿势，他说话的方式，他有没有习惯动作，这其实都是上学的时候学的最基础的。然后，剧本的一些背景，剧本没有写的，但是我要给他丰富的一些情感关系，或者是一些经历，自己去更多地为这个人物想象更深的一个维度。这样演出来以后这个人物就没有那么片面和单一化，观众就会觉得他可能有更多的侧面和立体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这演员的基本功是观察生活，没别的技巧，没有什么新的内容，全是三板斧，但是这三板斧你要扎扎实实地做好，那就是演员武装到自己的牙齿。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就是靠着这三板斧，他一次次离开自己的舒适区，迎接新角色的挑战。 “我接戏只考虑我感不感兴趣，而不会考虑我能不能掌控。我看到一个新角色，我掌控不了，就不演了，永远没有进步。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乍一看，《漫长的告白》中的立春和辛柏青一点都不像。制片人徐佳含回忆，剧组最早定下的演员是张鲁一，演弟弟立冬，一个有点执拗的罹患癌症的文艺中年。他们问张鲁一，你给自己找个哥哥，看谁合适？哥哥立春有点像立冬的反面，世俗、外放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张鲁一回答：辛柏青。他觉得辛柏青有点“闷骚的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有了辛柏青和导演张律的第一次合作。一场戏，在日本的民宿，立春和年少的恋人柳川相对而坐，说话，辛柏青眼泪唰地流下来，“那是在诉说，在悔悟。那种表现我觉得特别清晰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张律喊咔，再来一条，让辛柏青冲着墙说台词。 “我当时就想，刚刚那个不好吗？当然我没跟导演探讨，既然已经有表达强烈一点的了，我就来一遍导演说的。”下一条，辛柏青背对镜头，喃喃自语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成片里，张律用了后一条。辛柏青想，也对，立春也许是对柳川有感情，也许只是为了寻找自我来到此地，“而我那种表演把所有的可能性局限在了一种，反而让路子更窄了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青迅速理解了张律的风格，他说，看张律的电影像读诗，没有标准答案。 2020年底，我采访张律时，他确实说，电影应当像诗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凭借立春这个角色，辛柏青获得了中国电影金鸡奖最佳男配角奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到《白塔之光》，两人已经非常默契，没有过多的讨论。张律会问他，演得舒服吗？挺舒服的。那就行了，拍下一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所谓的舒服（就是），我觉得都对了。这场戏没有&#39;个个楞楞&#39;的，没有那种很难受的、过不去的动作、行为、语气。是波澜不惊的、静水深流的表达方式，而不是哪个音符蹦出来了，变得强烈了；哪个音符又变得低沉了。可能用在这个电影里，舒服的感觉是这个样子的。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;背负着时代和家庭的不如意，在暧昧的两性关系和戏剧化的父子关系里，谷文通这个角色可演的地方很多。但辛柏青知道张律要的是不外化的表演，甚至是不演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他就经常说，生活当中人是多面化的，你也许上一秒还在挺高兴地说一件事，下一秒可能就陷入到一种很自我的情绪里边了，不知道为什么。人也会经常跑神，也会说一些不着边际的话，这都是真实的生活状态。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这就对表演者提了更高的要求，不演，需要特别强大的内心定力，要不然会觉得，我没演，是不是不对？但恰恰是我不怀疑自己、内心特别笃定的时候，可能生出来另外一种无法言说的状态。观众会捕捉到。不演反而可能内心需要更充实，这种充实不是说目的性更充实，而是你的过往人生、阅历，你的气质、思想内涵在那一瞬间，都会让人能够感受得到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月29日，北影节闭幕式暨颁奖典礼举行，如张律所说，辛柏青果真拿了奖。他凭借《白塔之光》获得“天坛奖”最佳男主角。这是他拿到的第一个影帝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;话剧《狂飙》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;游戏感&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;影视角色之外，辛柏青一直是国家话剧院的演员。第一部大剧场戏是导演田沁鑫的《狂飙》（2001），他演主角田汉，戏里有打破第四堵墙的自述，有和表妹、和妻子、和红颜的情感，还有若干戏中戏，比如田汉翻译的《莎乐美》中的叙利亚少年、写的剧本里的关汉卿，都由辛柏青演。后来在《红玫瑰与白玫瑰》（2007）中，他演个全上海都知道的“柳下惠”。 《四世同堂》（2010）里，他演胡同里汲汲于名利、向日本人求官的冠晓荷——拿了话剧金狮奖表演奖。到《青蛇》（2013），他演法海，有人性，有神性。 2023年他还在排田沁鑫的新戏《苏堤春晓》，演苏轼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青记得多次合作的导演田沁鑫的一句话：戏剧和影视最大的不同，或说戏剧最大的魅力在于，可装扮性更强。影视剧不会找辛柏青的，田沁鑫会找。 “去装扮这个角色，就特别有游戏感，这一下让我豁然开朗。这件事变成了一件好玩的事儿，不是说我要苦大仇深地去塑造一个什么，戏比天大，这么大一个枷锁给你套上，不是的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在舞台上二十多年，辛柏青的角色不算多，两只手数得过来，现在回看，每一个角色的故事他都还能想得起来。与影视相比，戏剧离名利远，辛柏青自己有时候也想为什么一直没有离开戏剧呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“名利可能就是某一瞬间，我这戏播火了真好，被这么多人认可了，很享受，但很快就会过去。但是演话剧，在排练场里天天连滚带爬地排练，这种简单的快乐太难得了。岁数越大，面临的事、社会环境、关系也越来越复杂，（演话剧）这事儿就是不复杂。我能回到简单的地方，找到小的时候的状态就会特别快乐。”辛柏青说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他身上有一种非常干净的气质。这份干净是很难得的。”田沁鑫说过，在排练场，她有时会突然被辛柏青感动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，新版《狂飙》上演，辛柏青作为观众去看，觉得年轻一代演员比自己当年演得好。 “我年轻的时候有点没心没肺，每天就是乐呵、傻玩，并不过脑子，事儿不往心里装。因为装多了以后挺痛苦的，你知道吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但是没办法，生活就硬往怀里塞，这么多年也塞了不少了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活给他塞了什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“柴米油盐，都往里装。具体你真的说不出来。这就是活着，过日子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青演的那版《狂飙》，有一段，田汉在东京看戏，一段自白，大意是，找到了自己热爱的志业，像是行星找到了轨道一般：“小时候我就有些迷障，我大概是无法悟道了。我只热爱我要的颜色，我会听凭它牵引出一条轨道，引我自由公转。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说出这段台词，问辛柏青在年轻时是否很有共鸣，他否认了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小的时候真的不知道这是什么意思，只是把这词念出来了，为赋新词强说愁的一种状态。什么人生，什么牵引，什么我的颜色，到底我要什么，我不知道。现在到了这个岁数了全都知道了，反而也可以不用说这样的话了，一切感悟都在，却道天凉好个秋了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过作品，很难寻觅到他在表演上爬坡的轨迹。他也没有给出所谓的“开窍时刻”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我明白你的问题，但是没有一个具体节点。因为生活本身没有节点，我的生活四平八稳的，但是四平八稳的生活，愿不愿意去用心体会？用心体会了，年龄、岁月带给人的就会潜移默化、一点点积淀。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他只说，如果现在再演田汉，应该是不一样了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;钝&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2008年，导演姜伟拍《潜伏》，最先考虑的是请辛柏青和朱媛媛两口子出演余则成和翠平，他觉得辛柏青身上有文人气。不巧赶上朱媛媛怀孕，姜伟说辛柏青一个人去也可以，辛柏青为了陪产也没去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《潜伏》播出之后，成了现象级电视剧，全国各地拿奖。辛柏青有遗憾，但不后悔。与喜爱的角色擦肩而过，这不是唯一一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾经辛柏青最想演的角色是浮士德。在歌德的戏剧《浮士德》里，这位博闻的学者与魔鬼梅菲斯特做交易，出卖自己的灵魂以换取无尽的学识和智慧，甘愿在死后投身地狱。后来真的有人来找他演《浮士德》的时候，他拒绝了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么这个机会到我手边的时候，我又不去演了呢，我纠结了好长时间，后来发现我想演的不是歌德的浮士德。”他无法用只言片语解释自己想演的浮士德是什么，但是他清楚自己不要什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我给人感觉挺钝的，生活当中给人感觉反正也不大灵光不大聪明的。”辛柏青这样说自己。但他有自己的小世界。特别累的时候，或者坐车赶路，他在网上看别人下四国军棋，有时候看到棋出得太臭，他也说，这看不下去，给关了，过会儿再点进去看看。 “就诸如此类，我自己心里边玩得特别高兴，但是跟别人一沟通起来，又变成了一个特别无聊的人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辛柏青喜欢潜水。把生命搁在水底，杂念被迫压缩到最少，氧气含量、潜水深度、方向，都没问题了，终于可以放下心来看一眼海底的时候，他觉得，可能跟到了太空的感觉差不多，心情一下就变得开阔了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做演员的人都敏感，但是敏感有时候会伤害自己，作为“内向的、不善于表达的人”，辛柏青用这种方式让自己放空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐佳含是《漫长的告白》和《白塔之光》的制片人，她说，“柏青老师在现实生活中，跟剧组人员都特别客气，特别融洽。”《漫长的告白》到日本拍摄，辛柏青不懂日语，但是“会尽量适应，不愿意给别人添麻烦”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但你总觉得他有点小秘密，恰好在剧本里找到了一个出口。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1997年，中央戏剧学院表演系1993级本科生临近毕业，排练的间隙，十来个同学跟着老师去蹭饭。走在学校门口的东棉花胡同里，老师问了一句，你们毕了业谁还能坚持演话剧？本来欢快的气氛一下子安静了。那个时候演话剧意味着清贫，谁也没吱声。辛柏青接了一句，“要让我一辈子演话剧我都乐意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，辛柏青50岁了，当年的老师有的已经离世。每当排话剧、同学聚会、给老师扫墓，他都会回想起那一幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微短剧的“危险”狂飙]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260414]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 14:33:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Micro short dramas are booming from all levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of market size, according to data from a third-party research report quoted by Chinese Online, the market size of short dramas in 2022 will be more than 10 billion yuan, and the scale of micro short dramas in 2023 is expected to exceed 30 billion yuan. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of market supply, according to data from the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television, the number of micro-short dramas registered for the whole year in 2021 is 398, while the number of registered micro-short dramas in 2022 is close to 2,800, a year-on-year increase of 600%; March 2023 -In August, the number of national key online micro-short dramas that have been approved for planning and registration was basically over 260, and in July and August they were 361 and 401 respectively, indicating a significant increase in supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a company perspective, Chinese Online, Huace Film and Television, Mango Super Media, Huayi Brothers, Ningmeng Film and Television, Palm Reading Technology, and Changxin Media have all increased investment in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the other side, due to the &quot;kitsch&quot; of the subject matter, the market supervision of micro-short dramas still remains uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 10, Chinese Online closed at 25.40 yuan per share, a decrease of 9.19%. Previously, from November 2 to 9, the company&#39;s stock price doubled in just 6 trading days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257894&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The micro-short drama &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; starring Yang Rong has been viewed more than 800 million times on Douyin short video platform. Image source: Poster from the show&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Comfortable and Intensive&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The biggest feature of micro-short dramas is their high recycling efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese Online, a popular micro-short drama concept stock, stated in the investor exchange minutes that short dramas are characterized by short content and a large number of episodes, usually 80-100 episodes, each episode is less than two minutes, and the plot is It has strong drama, the creative content is more in line with the needs of the masses, the story is quick to reverse, and the plot is exciting and intensive. Rely more on platform advertising to reach C-end customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, micro-short dramas have a short commercial verification cycle and high recycling efficiency. They mainly rely on advertising. As long as the streaming side can achieve the first-day recycling target, they can continue to optimize the distribution strategy. Then achieve high ROI recovery. From script polishing to filming, production, and delivery verification, a work can complete verification and closed-loop in a short time, with a high asset transfer rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the production cycle of micro-short dramas is short, the production cost is low, and the shooting cycle is generally within a week. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If it doesn’t work, just change the subject. The cost is too low. Just shoot for another.” A micro-short drama entrepreneur told a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This allows Chinese online, which has a weak film and television foundation, to quickly enter the core track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The company has the advantage of massive IP. At present, short drama scripts are mainly derived from adaptations of online novels. The company has 5.5 million IPs and can continuously provide high-quality short drama IP adapted scripts, with outstanding long-term running capabilities.&quot; Chinese online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old content giant Huace Film and Television is also rapidly entering this market. The company disclosed that it began researching the short drama track in the second half of last year and started building teams in June this year. There are currently 6 teams, and it is also introducing screenwriters, producers, and cooperating with casting companies. &quot;The future positioning is to enter the top five of micro-short dramas.&quot; Huace said. What it considers to be its advantage is obviously its production capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively, film and television giants still have advantages in laying out this track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Ningmeng Film and Television, at the beginning of 2023, its micro-short drama &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; had a total playback volume of more than 800 million times on the Douyin short video platform, and the average playback volume of each episode exceeded 40 million times, related topics have been played a total of 1.45 billion times on the entire site, which is the highest level among Douyin short video micro-series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at present, the biggest feature of micro-short dramas is their &quot;refreshing feeling&quot;, and there seems to be little demand for high-quality productions. Everyone from micro-short drama entrepreneurs to middle-level executives of leading film and television companies admitted to 21st Century Business Herald reporters that the current advantages of leading film and television companies in this market are relatively limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, after the second season of &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; was released, it ranked TOP 1 on the most popular micro-short drama list and occupied the TOP 1 spot on Douyin&#39;s micro-short drama list for 5 consecutive weeks. However, the popularity has dropped significantly compared to the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Platform Changes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the popular short drama is a lonely long video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many project leaders of film and television companies lamented to reporters from the 21st Century Business Herald that as platforms “reduce costs and increase efficiency,” it is becoming increasingly difficult to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The financial report shows that iQiyi’s content costs in 2022 will be 16.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 20%. In addition, the company is also promoting self-produced dramas. At present, the proportion of iQiyi’s self-made content assets continues to rise, from 32% in 2018 to 63% in 2022. iQiyi also revealed that among the new key dramas released every year, the proportion of original content will increase from 20% in 2018 to more than 50% in 2022. All of the above have squeezed the profit margins of film and television projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incentive for this change is the fragile profit model of long videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second quarter of this year, iQiyi’s revenue was 7.802 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 17.2%; net profit attributable to the parent company was 365 million yuan, compared with a net loss of 214 million yuan in the same period last year. But from a quarter-on-quarter perspective, iQiyi’s revenue is in a declining range. Driven by &quot;Hurricane&quot;, in the first quarter, its revenue reached 8.349 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15%; the net profit attributable to the parent company was 618.1 million yuan, while the net profit in the same period last year was 169.1 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why the performance of long video is so volatile is that user demand is becoming fragmented and the monetization efficiency is relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Analysys Qianfan data, in September 2023, iQiyi’s monthly active users dropped to 568.67 million, and Tencent Video’s monthly active users dropped to 450.17 million. During the same period, Douyin’s monthly active users dropped to 797.67 million, and Kuaishou’s monthly active users dropped to 522.36 million. The difference between long and short videos is obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, from the perspective of advertising, advertisers are rushing to short videos due to higher monetization efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiangpiaopiao disclosed that in the first half of the year, its frozen lemon tea sales increased by 547.09% year-on-year, and its online channels increased by 235% year-on-year. Douyin channels accounted for about 30%, and the cumulative repurchase rate remained high. Jinzai Food also stated that in terms of online channels, the company’s new media channels such as Douyin performed well, with a year-on-year increase of approximately 600%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the marketing department of a leading beverage company told a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that compared with long video platforms such as iQiyi, short videos have a more direct marketing effect and are much more efficient in monetization. “There are basically no big expectations for the monetization of long videos,” he said. Another founder of outdoor sports products also expressed similar views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the double attack of traffic and revenue, the long video ecology is moving towards the stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, content companies have to rush to micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Uncertainty&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, the micro-short drama market is also facing various problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large number of film and television companies and even platforms are currently unwilling to be too high-profile in this business. The core lies in the policy instability of micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standardized supervision of short dramas can be traced back to August 2020. The State Administration of Radio, Film and Television has added a rapid registration and filing module for online micro-short dramas to the key online film and television drama information filing system, marking the official inclusion of micro-short dramas into the supervision system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television issued a document clarifying that the review of domestic online dramas, including short plays, will be included in the management of administrative licensing matters, and it is necessary to obtain a distribution license from the relevant radio and television administrative departments before they can be broadcast and released; In November, we issued an article to carry out special rectification of mini-program micro-drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While guiding the standardized development, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television also provides necessary support to short plays. In December 2022, the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Prosperous Development of Short Play Creation&quot; proposed to cultivate and expand the main body of short play creation. Provide tilted support to short plays in terms of resources, talents, marketing, broadcasting, and publicity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It must be noted that at present, cool dramas are still the mainstream in the market. According to Juduo Engine, the core of current short dramas is &quot;cool&quot;, and 90% of the themes are based on &quot;cool&quot;. There are various ways to be cool, including God of War, time travel, counterattack, rebirth and other themes. As a result, there is a tendency of &quot;kitsch&quot;. According to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald, regulators are paying close attention to a large amount of &quot;edge&quot; content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The market direction is full of uncertainty.” Many upstream and downstream participants in the industry stated this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, from the perspective of market size, micro-short dramas are still limited compared to long videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, iQiyi alone’s revenue will reach 29 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 5%. This data far exceeds the overall market size of micro-short dramas in the same year and is close to the expected size of micro-short dramas in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are three main types of terminal profits from short dramas. They provide membership payment, advertising monetization and e-commerce delivery respectively. Membership payment includes regular membership fees and the purchase of a single drama. The monthly membership price for mainstream long-form video platforms is 22-25 yuan, and the membership fee for short-drama exclusive platforms is higher, around 30 yuan; the single-drama payment standard is 1-25 yuan. 3 yuan/episode, and a single episode of popular dramas can cost up to 10 yuan. Advertising revenue is also an important part of short drama revenue, including pre-roll advertising, ad placement, and IP authorized marketing. Among them, pre-roll advertising is exclusive to long video platforms, and soft advertising placement is a common method for short video platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, this profit model still tends to be short-term and fast, and is still far from a truly mature business model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[此情可待成追忆：本师吴金华先生逝世十年祭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzzlOu07pkyhn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzz lOu07pkyhn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Wu Jinhua, Distinguished Professor of Fudan University and Researcher of the Institute of Ancient Books (1943-2013) 2007 Photos taken during his visit to the United States in December. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, nine years had passed since I graduated from Nanjing Normal University with an undergraduate degree in ancient literature. One spring afternoon, I went up to the fourth floor with my four-year-old daughter in my arms. When I took out the key and opened the door, I woke up from my own heavy breathing. Because I was unwilling to let my life go down, I decided to go back to college to start another kind of growth. At that moment, I thought of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after graduating from college, I stopped thinking about you for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I saw you in college, you had a bald head like a European monk, energetic eyes behind big glasses, and thick lips that were always smiling. Except in summer, he seems to always wear a blue or black tunic suit with one or two pens in the top pocket. A classmate from the previous class said that they saw you wiping the blackboard with the sleeves of your Mao suit while you were engaged in class. We didn’t take your class very often, so we never saw you do this in class, but I did see you darken your face after class. The corners, cuffs, pockets, etc. of the tunic suit looked like they were stained with chalk dust. I was admitted to Nanjing Normal University in 1984. The various inexplicable and severe restrictions I had suffered before led to strong rebellion in the tolerant university. During those four years, I couldn’t see anything, including you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As graduation approaches, my view of you has changed a lot. I went to your home to receive guidance on my graduation thesis. That was the only individual communication in the past four years. The house was very crowded and there was no desk, so you invited me to sit down at a small round dining table filled with books and started talking about my thesis. During this period, I have been attracted by a copy of &quot;The Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; spread out in the middle of the table. The blank space on the opened page is filled with long and short school slogans written in different pens. When you talk about it later, you forget why, as if you are looking for an example to illustrate, you start to flip through the book. Then I saw clearly that every page of the book was filled with colorful words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; annotated by Mr. Wu Jinhua. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very ashamed. What you talked to me about academics that day was quickly forgotten. Only the appearance of this book still comes to mind from time to time. After graduating from Nanjing Normal University, I returned to my hometown of Changshu. After only a year or two, my arrogance naturally turned into decadence. In the next few years, I rarely read. When the weather is bad, I wander aimlessly by Shang Lake at the foot of Yushan Mountain, letting the rain and snow fall from my head. Try to persuade yourself and try to play cards day and night with all kinds of people from all walks of life. Smoking more and more aggressively, especially when alone. I often drank, got drunk late at night, and sat alone in the darkness on the side of the road, crying silently. It wasn&#39;t until this spring afternoon that everything came to an abrupt end. I decided to start over and do something seriously for a long time. What came to mind again at that time was the &quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; filled with words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I wrote to you. I didn’t even know that you left Suiyuan two years ago (Editor’s note: the former site of Yuan Mei Suiyuan, the old campus of Nanjing Normal University). Your reply from Shanghai said that it was a pleasure to know that you wanted to come to study. Professionally, as long as we don&#39;t completely abandon what we have learned and review it, not many people can compete. What you have to do is to concentrate on preparing foreign languages. In the winter of that year, in the last two months before the postgraduate entrance examination, it seemed to be raining all the time. I locked myself in a room, lowered the curtains, put away the clock, and read, recited, and dictated, day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I came to your home after being admitted to Fudan University, you came out of the study. Because you still retained the memories from ten years ago, you looked much older and had less hair, but your eyes Still energetic. I said, I came too late, I should have come ten years ago. You immediately said with a smile on your face, it&#39;s not too late, I just started at your age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year, you asked me to translate the papers of Japanese scholars in conjunction with foreign language learning. Before submitting the completed translation, you asked me to write a translator&#39;s note. For those few hundred words of notes, you revised it four or five times. Through repeated frustrations, I began to slowly understand what &quot;negative rhetoric&quot; is. When you finally changed the schedule, you smiled and said gently that it seemed that you had been away from school for too long and you were no longer in the mood. But it doesn’t matter, just start slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the first school year, you asked me to go to the library to borrow different versions of &quot;Jiankang Records&quot; and use my summer vacation time to do the revision. After school started, I reported the findings of the review to you, and you seemed very happy. I remember when my wife came over to pour us water, you turned around and said to your wife seriously, &quot;Ji Zhongping is very attentive. I have read this book so many times, but I didn&#39;t see many of the problems he found.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; height= &quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qing Yi Xun Tang published &quot;Jiankang Record&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I came to Fudan again to study for a Ph.D., it was the first time I talked about choosing a doctoral thesis topic. You introduced what you discovered. A category of words created using classic sentences. I blurted out that the use of such words should be to make the rhetoric more elegant. After hearing this, you patted your thigh with an exaggerated movement that was completely beyond my expectation and said, Great, this understanding is great, this is your invention. Well, let&#39;s call this type of words Yayan words, and you can do this topic. The next day, I went to class in the liberal arts building and saw my senior who had just finished class and said to me, the teacher said in class that you have an important invention. A few days later, I met a friend from East China Normal University and told me that Teacher Wu went to their school for a meeting and said at the meeting that I had an amazing invention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those years when I was studying at Fudan, after having long conversations with you, on the way back to school late at night, I would always stand up and pedal my bike hard, eager to sit down at my desk the next second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a teenager, I read books such as &quot;The Detectives of Sherlock Holmes&quot; and &quot;Three Heroes and Five Righteousnesses&quot;. I imagined that when I grew up, I could become a detective who pursues the truth and an impartial judge. However, I realized that this was unrealistic when I became an adult. . You taught me how to do collation and exegesis, and how to make reliable inferences through thorough investigation and meticulous analysis. I will pursue the truth relentlessly and base myself on the facts without any compromise. Everything depends on me. Discovering a typo is like exposing a villain; restoring an original word is like clearing up an unjust case. Sitting at my desk late at night, I felt like Sherlock Holmes sitting in a carriage on his way to investigate a case, or like Bao Zheng sitting in the lobby of the Kaifeng government office. I don’t have any great talents to gain wealth in the world, nor do I have any ambition to achieve greatness in the world. When I come to this world, I have to live in a certain way. If I can live my life with this feeling besides being harmless to humans and animals. I have been content for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remember one time, when I said goodbye to you and said I was leaving because a friend had an appointment to play football, you asked me, does football really fascinate you so much? At the time I just said yes. I didn&#39;t tell you that day why I never tire of football, because it was the only relatively fair game I could participate in. On our court, there are only simple and clear rules, relying only on one&#39;s own skills and efforts, everything is under the sun, and all power and influence are meaningless. I don&#39;t know any skills other than poetry, I just like to participate in this kind of game with my own ability and enthusiasm. Only this kind of game can allow me to truly feel the joy of life, even though no one cheers, there is no income, and there is even the risk of breaking my muscles and bones at any time. I am very superficial, and my understanding of knowledge is no different from playing football. Although I still play football twice a week to this day, I know very well that in my lifetime, my strength and speed will gradually fade away. One day, I will no longer be able to run as much as I want on the court. However, even then, , I can still continue to experience the same fun on my desk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met you, I brought you some tea. You told me seriously that this would never happen again. We don’t need this when we get along. If you can write an article and show it to me, that would be better than giving me anything. From then on, all I can think of in return is to write something to you. In the days I spent with you, I don’t remember saying any words of gratitude in front of you in a serious manner. You passed away suddenly in June 2013. I rushed back to Shanghai from Kyoto. I came down from your house alone late that night and sat in the small garden next to the building. I regretted that I had not had time to say many things to you in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know if we can meet again in another world in the future. If not, then we will never have the chance to say those words in person, so I have no choice but to write the above words. Although It&#39;s just a very small part of it. If you have a soul, you will surely understand what I mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua and Mr. Jao Tsung-I (left), taken in 1993. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to gratitude, there is also an apology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my lifestyle has changed completely since I came to Fudan to study, some of the beliefs I formed since I was a student at Nanjing Normal University have not changed. Those beliefs may just be a joke in the eyes of others today, but I am willing to stick to them for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for a master&#39;s degree at Fudan University, the Institute of Ancient Books Collation held a meeting for students to evaluate scholarships. The meeting had a section that was equivalent to self-declaration. The students who spoke in front talked about what they had done and what they had published, and they talked very enthusiastically. Although I have done some research and published papers in journals, I cannot speak like they did. Seeing that it was almost my turn, I stood up quickly, picked up the blank form that was given to me, handed it to the teacher who was hosting the meeting, and said that I was ashamed and felt that I could not compare with them, so I quit first. The next day, you called my dormitory and told me seriously that as long as you applied, you would have won at least the second prize. This is very important, don’t do this next time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, I still don’t think this is important. My idea is very simple, because I didn’t win this award, I got through with it. What kind of honor can there be for an award that requires application only? After the doctoral thesis was written, you told me twice that after the defense, we would go to the Academy of Social Sciences to apply for the Lu Shuxiang Award, or go to Peking University to apply for the Wang Li Award. The first time I pretended not to hear, but the second time I told you clearly that I would not apply. When I was studying for a PhD at Fudan University, I won the highest award in liberal arts, but I never thought about applying. You applied privately on my behalf. You suddenly called me after 11 o&#39;clock the next night and told me that you had applied for me, and now you only need me to go to the award meeting the next day to make an introduction. I hesitated for a while and reluctantly agreed. Of course I know this is all your hard work, and I really can&#39;t bear to disobey you late at night. The next day I only used half of the allotted time and ended my uncomfortable self-cutting hastily. When I left the venue, I felt relaxed all over. I didn&#39;t care whether I won an award or not. I just felt that I had gone through this process, which was more or less an explanation to you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I like football very much, I rarely take the initiative to ask people to play football. Because I don&#39;t like others to accompany me reluctantly because of my invitation. I don’t like the state of being in my heart but not in my heart, and I certainly don’t want my friends to be like this. The games we play are just a bunch of ragtag games, but everyone is united physically and mentally. It is a game without any dirty things other than football. Although my technical level is limited, I thought I was enjoying the real joy of gaming. Any association with anything other than football would probably make me feel uncomfortable. It makes me feel a little sad to think that one day we all in this world will inevitably end in clouds and rain. However, I am not depressed at all when I think that all the hard work I have done will eventually be wiped out. Every run, every pass, every shot, while doing your best, the fun is in it. The moment I came off the field, I had finished enjoying football. In the days to come, if you tell me how I was in that game, I actually feel nothing. I rarely remember what kind of goals I have scored, even if they were just played yesterday. What I never forget every day is just where to start the next game. I have little knowledge and cannot give any lofty meaning to my profession. I just hope that the research I engage in can be as pure as football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height= &quot;742&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua graduated from the Chinese Department of Nanjing Normal University in 1966. In 1968, he was assigned to teach in a middle school in Ganyu County, Xuzhou area. In 1978, he returned to his alma mater and studied the history of Chinese under the tutelage of Mr. Xu Fu. After graduating in 1981, he stayed at the school to teach. In 1986, he won the second prize of the Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. In 1991, he was promoted to professor. In 1995, he was transferred to Fudan University. Institute of Collation of Ancient Books, author of &quot;Exegesis of the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;Research and Interpretation of Shishuoxinyu&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on Ancient Documents&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I quit my original job when I came to study for a Ph.D. During the holiday in early October of the first semester, you asked me to go to your house for dinner. During this period, you asked me if I have any requirements for my workplace after graduation. I said it didn&#39;t matter to me, as long as I had a bite to eat. You said, then see if you are willing to stay. I said of course that&#39;s good, so I can always be by your side. Then you said that you believed that I would have no problems with my business, but you hoped that I could do some things outside of business to ensure that I could stay. I told you on the spot that I didn&#39;t want to. I just wanted to make a living based on my own ability. You mentioned it twice after that, and I explicitly rejected it both times. The last time, I even said that if I had to do that to stay, then I would go somewhere else. If I have to do academic work that way, then I would rather live on the streets pulling a cart and carrying bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I know that&#39;s arrogant and rude to say. In fact, I have never seen and can&#39;t imagine anyone talking to you like that. Of course I fully understand that you have my life in mind, but if I do what you say, I will have trouble sleeping at night. These beliefs have been rooted in my heart since I was a teacher in Nanjing. They are the promises I made to myself. Even when I was dissolute, I never violated them at all. Perhaps, for others, there shouldn&#39;t be any doubts about doing something like that, because everyone does it, but I am me, and in my opinion, no matter how many people do it, it is impossible to change this kind of thing. nature, I cannot deceive myself, so I am willing to accept the life I choose. I think if the research we did is credible, it must be the only judgment made based on real materials and strict logic. The beliefs I adhere to are the same kind of non-dual judgment. It is impossible for me to change because of the intervention of anyone other than facts and logic, not even you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are very strict with students. My wife once told me privately that even several older doctoral students were scolded by you until they cried in front of them. I don’t know why you are so tolerant to me. You have never spoken harshly, so that I have the confidence to speak freely in front of you again and again, especially for those beliefs that are ridiculous in the eyes of others, but you always smile gently and make some remarks. Advice, and ultimately make it clear that you respect my choice. I admit that if you were still alive, I still would not apologize to you for things like the above. Because although I am stubborn, during the time when I was studying with you, I regarded you as the judge of this world to a certain extent. I need to state the facts clearly to you, and then get a fair ruling from you. . It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t respect you, but I&#39;m afraid that my apology will change your original decision. In my opinion, such a change of judgment, even if it is beneficial to me, no longer has the meaning of a ruling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been ten years since you went to another world, and I no longer need you to make any judgments. Therefore, please accept my apology now. I apologize to you for all my past arrogance. Apologize. Forgive me, more than 20 years ago, I just wanted to go back to the peach blossom land I once had. I didn’t know it at that time. Things have changed, and the place I yearned for has already kept pace with the times. But I have always been like that warrior who is searching for a sword, stubbornly guarding that place. mark. Forgive me, I don’t want to live just for food, that’s no different than a dolphin or a dog. I want a life with wine. The gentle smile you show in the face of those unbridled smiles is a great comfort to an inappropriately lonely student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People often say that once you are a teacher, you will always be a father. This is just a matter of etiquette, because how much emotion can be created in a day&#39;s interaction. Deep feelings are the accumulation of emotions generated after long-term mutual understanding. I know there are teachers who are different from you, but for more than ten years, you are the only one to me. To this day, I still feel lucky that on that spring afternoon twenty-six years ago, when I said goodbye to comfort and wanted to start another kind of growth, you adopted me, just like a father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品集采12小时：“割肉”也不想丢标]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;This collective purchase 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased, and the prices of the selected drugs were reduced by an average of 58%, the second largest price reduction in history. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;If the company&#39;s market share in the next four years was determined within 12 hours, how would you choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of Monday, November 6, 2023, the temperature in Shanghai dropped sharply, but there were crowds of people outside the Fengxian District Conference Center and the discussion was lively. The ninth batch of centralized bulk procurement of state-organized drugs is underway here, and representatives of various pharmaceutical companies carrying sealed quotation information materials are waiting anxiously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;We have ten manufacturers bidding together for our drug varieties, and the competition is fierce, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;Long procurement cycle&lt;/span>;) is both a temptation and a challenge. I personally think it will prompt companies to further lower their quotations.&quot; A representative of a pharmaceutical company from Shangqiu, Henan told a reporter from Southern Weekend that the company is It was my first time to participate in the national centralized drug procurement, and I started preparing for this round of application since passing the consistency evaluation half a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Starting at eight o&#39;clock, business representatives poured into the first floor of the conference center. Within 12 hours, a total of 382 products from 262 companies participated in the bidding. The staff of the notary office will unseal, announce and read out the product specifications and quotations of each pharmaceutical company one by one, and then release the list of proposed winners; the proposed pharmaceutical companies will then Transfer to another hotel conference center to wait - enter into groups according to the order of drugs, and select and confirm the supply area in the next four-year procurement cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that there were pharmaceutical distribution, local state-owned enterprises and other related enterprises inside and outside the site eagerly waiting for the event. Although these companies themselves are not participating in this collective purchase, they are also looking forward to the results of the ninth batch of collective purchases, especially if they can collide with some cooperation opportunities with the selected pharmaceutical companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At about 19:00 on November 6, the National Medical Insurance Administration announced that 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase, and the average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%. It can save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year - the second largest price reduction in history, second only to the previous record high of the first national procurement after the 4+7 pilot (59%). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Once the bid is lost, it will be &quot;sidelined&quot; for the next four years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The ninth batch of centralized procurement It covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. At present, during the period of high incidence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, the much-anticipated azithromycin oral suspension is also on the list of this centralized purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is different from the first eight batches of centralized procurement is that once selected, the procurement cycle will be extended from two years to four years, that is, from the implementation date to December 2027 March 31st. This is more attractive to pharmaceutical companies than in previous years. On the morning of November 6, many business representatives kept discussing the topic of extending the procurement cycle while waiting for declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;While waiting, a representative of a Jiangxi pharmaceutical company looked embarrassed while holding a thick stack of written documents. &quot;During the eighth batch of collective purchases, we did not win the selection for an exclusive product with a high market share, and most of the volume on the market was &#39;divided up&#39; by several successful bidders. Therefore, we participated in this collective purchase, even if we &#39;cut the meat&#39; We don’t want to lose the bid, we have to keep the production line.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Hengwei, deputy general manager of the marketing center of Zhonghuan Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd., introduced to Southern Weekend reporters that the three projects they applied for Two products are planned to be selected. “Both are new products that have just been introduced into the Chinese market, and are also recommended drugs in the diagnosis and treatment guidelines. Although the current market sales are not large, it is expected to have a large growth in the next four years. Taking into account the patient Drug accessibility and hospitals will give priority to the centralized procurement of drugs from the winning bidders, and we have shown the greatest sincerity for this centralized procurement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Jiang Changsong, assistant to the dean of the National Medical Insurance Research Institute of Capital Medical University and director of the price procurement office, said that the procurement cycle of centralized procurement has been extended to four years for the first time, further ensuring The stability of drug use in medical institutions also means that if pharmaceutical companies &quot;lose their bids&quot;, they will have to watch their huge market share &quot;sideline&quot; in the next four years. &quot;National centralized drug procurement means large and stable quantities, and the supply cycle To ensure long-term growth, companies must exchange prices for volume and ensure supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;根据国家医保局通报，参与本次集采的医药企业中，205家企业的266个产品获得拟中选资格，其中包括200家国内药企的260个产品，5家国际药企的6个产品（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;包括1个原研药和5个进口仿制药&lt;/span>;），投标企业拟中选比例约78%，平均每个品种有6.5家企业拟中选。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;治疗心律失常的胺碘酮注射剂、用于抢救休克的多巴胺注射剂、用于催产的缩宫素注射剂等5种短缺药品和急抢救药品，通过“带量”采购方式稳定企业预期，实现保障供应与合理降价的多元目标平衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月6日上午，药企代表在上海奉贤区会议中心一楼提交申报材料。南方周末记者黄思卓/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;鏖战：药企供区之争&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月6日上午，申报材料受理和申报信息公开结束后，拟中选企业们还不能放松神经，因为当日下午他们将迎来另一场“鏖战”——供应区域选择和确认。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;根据国家组织药品联合采购办公室2023年10月13日发布的《全国药品集中采购文件》，拟中选企业首先要确定自己的主供地区，第一顺位企业优先在供应地区中选择1个地区，所有拟中选企业按顺位依次确认剩余地区，每家企业每次选择1个地区，重复上述过程，直至所有地区选择确认完毕。备供区域的选择程序类似。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;同时，所有药品在各省份地区不同规格的采购量也一并公布，可供申报企业依此制定选区策略。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月6日下午，选区现场准备了两间大型会议室，一间供企业代表候场，另一间用于确认供应区域信息。主办方按照药品品种逐一叫号，查验身份证和授权书后，企业分组入场选区。这个过程从当日14时左右开始，一直持续至晚上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;齐鲁制药集团销售总公司常务副总经理田勇对南方周末记者坦言，企业选区会有多重考虑，“第一看供区医院报量有多大，第二看省份市场容量，第三看企业对不同区域的重视程度，比如企业倾向于选北上广可以提升品牌知名度，再比如我们山东企业当然想选自己家门口的区域，但也可能选不上，被顺位高的企业选走了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;也有企业代表提到，个别西部省份由于报量较低、配送成本较高，可能并非选区环节的“香饽饽”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;南方周末记者在现场注意到，第一轮企业进入会议厅择区后，花了一个多小时才陆续有人出来。药企代表要根据竞争对手的选区情况适时调整自己的选区方案，有人不仅记录了自己的择区情况，也把其他顺位的企业择区情况一并做了备注，写满字的笔记引得围观者竞相拍照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;确定药品主供备供区域，很大程度上是为了避免集采药不能及时足量供应或中选企业取消中选资格等情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“从今年（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;集采药保供&lt;/span>;）情况来看，比以前要好很多。”上海市第七人民医院副院长高晓燕对南方周末记者说。首都医科大学宣武医院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称宣武医院&lt;/span>;）药学部主任张兰也表示，医院都希望集采药品能保质保量供应，这需要长效机制的保障，包括相关部门做好中标企业的监督和评价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月6日下午至晚上，拟中选企业按药品品种分组入场并选择供应区域。南方周末记者黄思卓/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;科学用药和合理用药引关注&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“国家药品集采从最开始的大品种为主，到现在已经进展到临床认为有必要覆盖的品种也都包括进去了。每一批的落地执行中，瑞金医院覆盖的品种是比较多的，截至目前已经完成了前五批集采药的采购周期，第六批正在进行。”上海交通大学医学院附属瑞金医院（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称瑞金医院&lt;/span>;）药剂科主任卞晓岚表示，现在医疗机构都很关心下一步如何更好地科学用药和合理用药。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2018年以来，国家医保局已组织开展九批国家药品集采，共纳入374种药品，平均降幅超50%。宣武医院药学部主任张兰表示，集采常态化开展，临床医生端也已经对集采仿制药的疗效观察一段时间了，在尊重患者意愿的基础上，医生会结合诊疗指南和患者病情为患者选择合适的药物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;针对集采中选仿制药疗效或不如原研药的一些声音，宣武医院牵头多家研究实力较强的医院，分批进行集采中选仿制药的真实世界研究。最近公布的一项覆盖全国16省29家医疗机构、约14万真实病例的研究显示，集采中选仿制药的临床疗效和安全性与原研药相当（详见南方周末10月22日报道&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/259061&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《14万病例，2年PK，集采仿制药疗效和安全性怎么样？》&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“目前来看，（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;集采中选仿制药和原研药&lt;/span>;）差异都在可控范围内。而且不同医院的药品配备会根据实际情况略有不同，我们医院倾向于集采药和原研药都配备，以患者为中心，结合他们的疾病进展、过往用药等情况，综合考虑用药方案。”卞晓岚对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;瑞金医院根据临床特色，选择内分泌代谢相关药品和心脑血管类药品，参与了宣武医院牵头的第二、三批国家集采中选仿制药品真实世界研究。卞晓岚表示，现在评价体系和工具越来越多，比如上海在做药品临床综合评价管理体系，以后会有相关研究公布。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;张兰介绍，第四、五批国家集采中选仿制药品真实世界研究已经启动，未来原始数据的采集和上报流程会更加完善，为临床用药提供循证支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[危险的快递驿站：一场不该发生的意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;589&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“医生让我们做好最坏的打算”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年8月25日中午，出差在外的张象接到了妻子受伤的电话，赶回山西太原时，已是下午两点多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿子在候诊区的铁椅子上坐着，手里保管着妈妈的手机、近视眼镜，还有从二楼掉下时甩落的那双白色凉鞋。林梅躺在病床上，眼睛睁着，脸色苍白，很快她就被送进重症监护室（ICU）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这天中午，林梅切好了菜，手机上天猫APP推送的消息显示，给儿子网购的橡皮泥到了小区附近的菜鸟驿站。她放下菜刀，随意穿了一条牛仔裤、一双白色凉鞋，带着儿子出门取快递。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果一切顺利的话，10分钟后，她会取完快递回到家中，做好午饭。这套新房才刚刚入住，开发商曾打电话让他们夫妻俩一起去办房产证，不巧当时房管中心下班了，他们约定出差回来第一时间去办。她和丈夫是高中同学，相识20年，结婚十几年，一起打拼到现在终于有了车、房和一个10岁的儿子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;该驿站一楼为便利店，二楼为菜鸟驿站&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从后来的监控视频可以看到，取件时，林梅一边看着手机上的取件码，一边在货架上找快递，根本没有注意到，脚下还有一个敞开的洞，她侧身寻找快递时不幸掉入脚下的洞中。洞口是老板平时用来上下货的，从二楼洞口到一楼地面高度为2.8米，洞口通常应该关闭，但事发时没有及时关上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这家菜鸟驿站用钢架和钢板结构把一个商铺的空间隔为两层，一楼是便利店卖水果蔬菜，二楼取快递，通常需要自己到二楼找件，自助扫码取件。快递驿站和便利店是同一个老板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据驿站老板描述，他也曾从洞口掉下去过，当时不小心闪了一下摔下去，只是腿受伤休养了一段时间。“他是有心理防备的，但是我老婆没有任何心理防备，她掉下去的时候完全懵了，根本不知道发生了什么。”张象说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在病床上的林梅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在ICU门外，张象写了几行关于“勿念”的纸条让护士送进去，又在纸上空白处补充“每天下午五点可以探视”，画上两个笑脸，附带一支笔让林梅可以写点什么。后来纸条送出来的时候，纸是湿的，没有字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生命体征稳定以后，陆续做了三场手术，出现各种并发症，肺炎、泌尿系统感染、压疮、血栓，“四大并发症占全了，每天都有新的挑战。”张象在一个多月的时间里瘦了十多斤，“太痛苦了！”他描述，治疗血栓的过滤器，做的时候从大腿植入到血管，取的时候从脖子上取出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次大手术，是颈椎手术，张象印象深刻。他记得林梅从手术室出来的时候，她躺着，但表情放松，面带笑容，“因为觉得手术终于做完了，觉得可能很有希望，可能很快就能好了。”后来，这样的笑容越来越少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西医科大学第二医院康复医学科主治医生张昱告诉《南方人物周刊》，林梅在摔落的过程中，头撞到侧边的墙壁上，颈椎骨折造成的颈部脊髓损伤，导致四肢瘫痪。下肢完全不能活动，上肢活动很差。双腿的感觉和运动都处于丧失状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林梅在ICU时，张象写的纸条&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，颈脊髓是大脑脑干往躯体椎管内延续的一部分脑组织，受到损伤之后，不受大脑脑干支配，所以会出现瘫痪症状。脊髓损伤造成向大脑传输感觉的功能缺失，导致下级神经元会产生异常。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“医生让我们做好最坏的打算。”张象说，“太痛苦了，如果癌症是判了死刑，脊髓损伤就相当于凌迟。”林梅无法自主翻身，甚至不能动动脚趾，只有病理性的抽搐，神经无法自主控制，没有出汗功能，感知不到冷和热。她会突然之间颤抖，但不觉得冷。有时候又觉得特别冷，像在冰天雪地里一样，实际上被子盖得好好的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上肢力量小，拿不住碗筷，只能喂饭吃。张象在医院附近租了一个房子，给爱人做饭，平时家属和护工轮换照顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱表示，完全性脊髓损伤恢复希望非常小，几乎是没有希望恢复。“林梅目前来看是完全性损伤的状态，双腿恢复的难度非常大，但是在时间上还不能下定论。我们医院一般是3个月左右，如果3个月后还是这样的体征症状的话，就可以下定论了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，林梅累计治疗费用已超18万元，未来还将有很多开支。而在多次沟通下，截至目前菜鸟方面仅支付了2万元，菜鸟驿站店主支付了3.5万元。事发之后一个多月内，这家菜鸟驿站还在正常营业，甚至那个洞还在使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场不该发生的意外，彻底改变了一个家庭的命运和一位37岁女性的人生，儿子刚上小学五年级，而她的下半生都有可能将在病床上度过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意外背后暴露出快递驿站模式存在的诸多隐患。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;危险的发生：菜鸟驿站是如何运营的？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;某县城菜鸟驿站老板告诉《南方人物周刊》，自己的这家店于两年前开设，店内另有两位亲属帮忙，“正常驿站两三个人就够了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他描述，菜鸟不收取加盟费，开一家菜鸟驿站的前期投入并不算高：需要到菜鸟官方购置扫描枪、工作台、云监控、货架等设备，成本约为1万元左右；再加上保证金3000元、门面租金、水电费，基本上开一家菜鸟驿站的成本在3万元左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在店铺审核上，“需要在看好地方和房子之后，在网上提交申请，店铺的要求不严格，申请好了之后他们会过来看。之后直接去跟快递员或者快递公司片区负责人谈好价格就可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站的收入来源，主要是跟快递公司合作，由快递公司支付给驿站老板派送费及寄件收入。菜鸟驿站官方网站显示，每件快递的派送费为0.5-1元，寄件收入为3-5元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站模式之所以覆盖迅速，也与快递行业愈演愈烈的价格战相关。快递公司用价格换规模，必然影响利润，导致网点派送费降低，利润空间进一步被压缩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为节约“最后一公里”的末端配送成本，快递驿站可谓应运而生。中国物流协会调查数据显示，末端配送成本占物流行业总成本的30%以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈君曾是某电商平台旗下自营快递的网点经营者，负责“最后一公里”的末端配送，“公司确实下了不少本。”她提到，快递公司负责租房费用和电费水费，并免费配备电脑设备、安装摄像头，需要发该网点3个人的基本工资，之外还需要付每个快件的派送费，经营者只需要交一笔保证金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和亲戚经营该网点约6年时间，派送费从最早的4元，逐渐减少到1.5元、1元。在该店内，两个人负责送快递，一个人守店，负责分件、寄快递、处理退货等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个客户他们都会送货上门，挨个打电话。凌晨4点多，需要起床去高速路口接快递，然后回来卸货、扫码分件。每天的件必须当天派送完，直接面对消费者，会碰到各种不同的情况，想做好这份工作，必须要有很强的服务意识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，这家电商平台因物流成本高而关停了旗下的自营快递公司，陈君便也不再经营。“相比我们以前做的那些，现在这种快递驿站模式确实给快递公司省了不少成本，节省了快递员的精力，但对用户来说没以前方便了。”末端配送从快递公司全盘负责，变成了驿站老板自负盈亏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;行业竞争激烈，快递驿站的品牌越来越多，极兔速递驿站、圆通妈妈驿站、中通兔喜生活……甚至一个社区会出现多个快递驿站，有网友以自身经历吐槽：“因为小区比较大，取6个快递，竟然在6个不同的驿站。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;派送费也在持续下跌，《南方人物周刊》采访的两位菜鸟驿站的老板表示，在他们所在区域，派送费分别只有每单0.3元、0.5元，均比几年前的价格有所下跌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我家小区菜鸟驿站两年都换了七八个老板了。”一位网友表示，这种驿站的转让费一般并不低，亦出现驿站老板靠转让费“割一波韭菜”的情况——靠经营驿站赚的钱还没有转让费赚得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，经营副业便成了一个能够增加收入来源的选择。根据菜鸟驿站官网，其在介绍“菜鸟驿站是怎么赚钱的？”中提到：除了稳定的派费收入之外，依靠驿站带来的固定人流量，可以经营副业、售卖生活用品快销品等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但问题也在于，作为高频的生活场景，快递服务关键的“最后一公里”，店主若不能投入足够的精力，便难以保证服务质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梅出事的菜鸟驿站便是如此。在这家店里，驿站成了副业，主业是蔬果超市。“大家既然都要来，这是一个天然的引流渠道，所以他们把蔬菜水果放到一层，取快递在二层，且是自助的。”张象提到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在钢架结构私自开“洞”，存在安全隐患。事发时“洞”为敞开状态，林梅从中掉落&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被诟病的加盟模式以及法律风险&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国家邮政局的数据显示，2010年至2022年，我国快递业务量规模增长了47.3倍，电商的快速发展给快递业带来了巨量的需求增长，快递驿站模式应运而生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京东从2007年开始自建物流，凭借自有物流的优质服务赢得了客户的口碑。阿里深知自建物流所要耗费的成本高昂，为了提升平台的快递服务质量，它于2013年联合零售、地产、物流等企业打造菜鸟网络，其模式较轻，定位是物流体系中的“数据中枢”，即物流平台，采用加盟模式，菜鸟公司不承担驿站具体的运营成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，马云还曾表态“绝对不做物流”，这对于发展淘宝、天猫和拉拢物流公司起到了作用，得以进一步掌握物流环节的话语权。菜鸟既有阿里电商提供的流量，又具备稳定的物流配送网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据阿里2023财年年报，菜鸟集团成为阿里巴巴集团内增长速度最高的业务，收入为556.81亿元，同比增长21%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月26日，菜鸟智慧物流网络有限公司正式向港交所提交上市申请，成为阿里“1+6+N”组织变革以来首个正式开启IPO进程的业务集团。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8年前，菜鸟在安徽芜湖推出首个提供快递代收服务的“菜鸟驿站”。招股书显示，菜鸟如今在全球已有380多个物流分拨中心和17万个驿站，运营着全球最大的菜鸟驿站网络，日均处理包裹超8000万个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种加盟模式也引来争议，其本意是为消费者提供多元化的最后一公里服务，提高配送效率，但也极易出现相互推卸责任的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕竟，快递公司只负责到驿站这一环，而驿站直接赚的是快递公司的钱，而不是赚消费者的钱，菜鸟和消费者之间不存在直接的交易关系。菜鸟具有品牌影响力，但难以对每家加盟驿站严格监管，因此就难以让客户获得较好的服务体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快递驿站模式本身也存在一定的法律风险。国务院2018年发布的《快递暂行条例》第二十五条规定，从事快递业务的企业应当将快递投递到约定的地址、收件人或者收件人指定的收件人，并告知收件人或者收件人当面验收。收件人或代理人有权当面验收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在驿站模式下，很难做到送货上门。上述县城菜鸟驿站老板表示，的确有不少送货上门的诉求，“都可以送，现在如果说驿站不送的话，可能就落到快递公司上面了。快递公司让快递员给他派送，后续投诉驿站的话会有罚款。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在社交平台，有用户表示“投诉也没用，会被驿站拉黑名单，以后就不给你入库了，每次都从驿站返到快递网点，你的快递总会比别人的慢，目前来说没有什么有效的方法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京衡律师事务所合伙人钱颖刚告诉《南方人物周刊》，未经消费者同意，快递公司无权将消费者购买的商品放入快递驿站。消费者通过网络签订的电子商务合同，约定以包邮或支付邮费的方式将购买的商品运送至指定的地址，“快递公司如果未经消费者同意擅自更改送达地点或送达方式构成违约，应当承担继续履行合同或其他补救方式，并承担违约责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对驿站监管不力带来的安全隐患，后果则更为严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在菜鸟驿站官网，提到驿站店铺的具体要求为：位于一楼（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;与马路平行&lt;/span>;），写字楼、商业体不限楼层。但林梅出事的驿站并未遵守此要求，私自搭建钢架结构，且在经营时间内未受到菜鸟公司的监管和整改。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“消费者完全不知道，总公司跟网点之间是什么关系，只知道菜鸟是个大公司，去取件，完全是天猫后台给我们推送的信息，这里是公共经营场所，但完全没有安全保障可言，导致了悲剧的发生。”张象说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱颖刚表示，在林梅事件中，“在加盟情况下，从保护消费者角度考虑，按特许经营来理解，特许人和加盟店应当对外承担连带责任。驿站老板因为自身的疏忽、过失，在服务过程中导致损害他人后果的，赔偿责任一般来说不能免除。在未经消费者同意的情况下，快递公司也应当承担共同侵权责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;坠落之后&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;每天一觉醒来是张象最痛苦的时刻，会觉得这是真的吗？如果是一个梦该多好。可现实如此残酷且真实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但他需要振作精神，在爱人抑郁、崩溃大哭的时候给她安慰。他在床边给林梅读苏东坡的诗词，读史铁生的文章，告诉她一个人的命运不可能是完美的，总会有一些坎坷曲折。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个多月以来，林梅大部分时间都在病房躺着，偶尔可以看到窗户外面的云，“你看外面的云越来越多。”她望着云，对张象说。这让他想起过去的某个普通的日子，两个人一起散步时，林梅会说：“你看天上的云，其实我们一起在外面走一走，看看天上的云，吹吹大自然的风就很幸福了。”张象说，“现在想来那个时候是最幸福的，但那时候我还不以为然。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张象眼里，林梅是一个特别简单、很会操持家务的人，只有她知道家里所有物品的摆放位置。出事之后刚开始一段时间，张象回家住过一晚，但“完全睡不着，每天晚上都很难受，看到家里所有的地方都是她的痕迹，都是她的影子，我完全没办法睡觉。在出租屋里，陌生的地方反而好一些”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从在一起以来，每年过生日的时候，林梅都会亲自给张象包饺子吃。不久前，张象生日，林梅对他说，“今天不能给你包饺子了。”“后来我妈包饺子，我回家取来，她也没吃多少，只吃了五六个。”张象回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出差之前，张象去超市买了条鲫鱼，做了一道林梅最喜欢吃的鲫鱼豆腐汤。他记得那天林梅特别开心地吃完了，把他的皮鞋拿出来擦，黑皮鞋的白边擦得雪白，“像新买的一样。”张象叹口气，“等我赶回来以后，看到这双鞋边还是白的，但是人已不是以前了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱提到，在医院，黄金康复期是3-6个月。如果长期瘫痪，难以避免的并发症是心肺功能的降低，如果没有经济上的压力，可以做一些康复训练，用可动肢体去代偿失控肢体在生活工作上的一些训练，使身体的其他机能维持在一定的水平。后续护理、家庭康复阶段对照顾者的要求较高，家人和陪护人员需要付出很大的辛苦。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我曾经承诺带她去一些地方，本来计划今年要去的，不管以后恢复成什么样，哪怕是坐轮椅也要带她去，当然坐轮椅会很不方便，所以就想一定要把她尽量治好，要实现我对她的承诺。”张象说他会继续“讨个公道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身为青年作家的张象，8月份有一本新书出版，林梅出事后出版社给他快递样书，他发现自己还只能去菜鸟驿站取，“感觉我一辈子都不想再去那个地方，但是没有办法，必须去拿我的书，因为没有选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中林梅、陈君化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最近，在社交媒体上火了一款运动裙裤，让人意外的是，这条“神仙裙子”既不是中产必备的Lululemon，也不是耐克安德玛等知名品牌，而是广大直男的老朋友——迪卡侬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一直以平价天堂和直男最爱著称的迪卡侬，这次为什么靠女性出圈了呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;数据显示，2022年至今，小红书上有关迪卡侬的笔记就已高达10w+，随着流量的激增，也带动了旗下女士产品的销量，据其淘宝官方旗舰店销量top5显示，排名最低的女性瑜伽裤都有高达3w+的销售量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，迪卡侬年销售额达到140亿欧元，中国成为最大的海外市场之一，其中女性需求最为耀眼，在迪卡侬官方店中，女士产品数量约占半数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这跟中国户外经济的发展有着密切的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2020年中国户外用品市场规模达3150亿元，2025年预计达到5990亿元，与欧美国家相比，我国户外经济市场规模仍有较大发展空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有调查显示，国内参与户外运动的群体主要为一线及新一线的青年女性，花得多、买得多、省得多成为当代女性旅游消费的三大特点，逐渐掀起小众运动之风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，迪卡侬看到了“女性消费者+小众运动”的发展潜力，今天，“知道”带你探索迪卡侬的转型秘诀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;封面.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>