<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[福原爱或面临2年以上监禁：抚养权的归属应以有利于孩子成长为原则丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260062]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 15:05:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The love affair and marriage changes of Fukuhara Ai and Taiwanese Jiang Hongjie have always attracted widespread media attention. Currently, due to a criminal complaint filed by her ex-husband with the police, &quot;Ai Fukuhara may face more than 2 years in prison&quot;, which has triggered a lot of discussion on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mainland netizens have always had a good impression of Fukuhara Ai. She is cute, fluent in Chinese, and her Northeastern dialect, which tastes like corn pancakes, is very friendly. After Fukuhara Ai&#39;s affair and marriage change, many mainland netizens still regard themselves as &quot;family members&quot; and are willing to speak for her. This has led to a very interesting phenomenon: At present, Fukuhara Ai&#39;s public opinion image in Japan and Taiwan is relatively negative, but in mainland China it is still positive. This is probably the power of true love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fukuhara Ai was born in 1988. He started playing table tennis at the age of 3. He was once the main player of the Japanese national team and participated in many Olympic Games. He is perhaps the most popular Japanese athlete among the Chinese people. Jiang Hongjie is a table tennis player on the Taipei team. The two officially announced their marriage in September 2016. They gave birth to a daughter in 2017 and a boy in 2019. They announced their divorce in July 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the marriage change, some Japanese media reported that Fukuhara Ai looked happy on the surface, but in fact she had silently endured years of verbal violence from her husband and his family; her husband&#39;s family also treated her as a cash cow. The information read from it is that Jiang Hongjie&#39;s family &quot;eat soft food&quot; and are not grateful. At that time, public opinion was overwhelmingly sympathetic to Fukuhara Ai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, things soon took a turn for the worse. During her marriage, Ai Fukuhara was photographed by the media having a very intimate behavior with a married man, and they went to a hotel to spend the night together. At that time, she did not admit that she had cheated on her, saying that the other person was her good friend and they lived in a room each. After the divorce, Fukuhara Ai and the man openly fell in love. Then, the man&#39;s ex-wife came out and complained that their divorce was due to the intervention of a third party by Ai Fukuhara. This caused the persona and image that Ai Fukuhara had worked so hard to cultivate to suddenly collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frankly speaking, Jiang Hongjie and his family have verbally despised and insulted Ai Fukuhara, treating her as a tool to make money. Outsiders have no way of confirming the truth and can only have a matter of opinion. However, Ai Fukuhara was later caught cheating and lying, which became a real evidence, which lowered the credibility of these revelations. Many people will speculate that these so-called revelations are because they have a new love, and in order to reduce the moral pressure and public criticism of their marriage, they deliberately feed it to the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, when Fukuhara Ai was exposed to have cheated on her, her mother was still at Jiang Hongjie’s house and returned to Japan soon thereafter. Media reports stated that the mother decided to return to Japan because she felt she had no position and was embarrassed to stay any longer. Later, her mother even refused to live with Fukuhara Ai, indicating that she had objections to her cheating and divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 27 this year, Jiang Hongjie held a press conference in Japan and said: Due to the complete loss of contact with Fukuhara Ai, he has not seen his children for a year. Previously, Fukuhara Ai secretly brought her son back to Japan from Taiwan on the pretext of visiting. Jiang Hongjie announced: &quot;I have something to report. I received the judgment result from the Japanese court on July 20. The content is the court&#39;s order requiring Miss Fukuhara Ai to deliver the child to me. I am very grateful for the Japanese court&#39;s judgment and hope to hurry up.&quot; Meet the children.&quot; Fukuhara Ainori stated through her lawyer: The Japanese court&#39;s ruling is only a temporary sanction and not a final judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, more than two months have passed and the matter has not been resolved, so Jiang Hongjie took further legal action. According to the Japanese Criminal Code, there is the crime of &quot;abduction and abduction of minors&quot; (Article 224), and the perpetrators may be sentenced to 3 months to 7 years of hard labor; there is the crime of &quot;abduction and abduction for the purpose of transfer abroad&quot; (Article 226), Seizing and abducting people abroad may result in a sentence of not less than 2 years of hard labor. This has nothing to do with whether the perpetrator is a relative or whether it is for profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Jiang Hongjie’s purpose is to get his son back, not to put Fukuhara Ai in jail. How this matter develops remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two direct interpretations of this matter. First, the concept of rule of law in Japanese society is quite strong. The court ruled that it respects the merits and legal principles of the matter, neither conciliates nor acknowledges the fait accompli, nor does it favor Fukuhara Ai because she is a Japanese national. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the family values ​​and moral concepts in Japanese society are quite strong. Public opinion has a low tolerance for marital infidelity and lies. It’s okay to complain that your marriage is unhappy and that you want to pursue freedom and true love, but please wait until you’re divorced before talking about it. If a public figure cheats on his wife and lies to the public, after the cheating is confirmed and the lie is exposed, the backlash and recoil will be considerable, and his persona, image and career will be greatly affected. Influence. In the eyes of the public, on the basis of these criminal records, secretly taking the child away from the father and refusing to comply with the court&#39;s order is morally and legally unreasonable, and it is difficult to empathize and sympathize with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A further thought is: Even if we promise each other before marriage, some marriages will always break down, and if there are children, they will often involve custody battles. If one party wants the other party not, this is easy to handle and can be solved through a divorce agreement. It is more difficult to handle whether both parties want it or neither wants it. There have been cases in China where couples wanted to divorce, but neither wanted custody of their children, and then the court refused to allow the divorce. The worst among them was the children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both parties want the custody of their children, but the agreement cannot resolve the matter, and it finally goes to court. How should the court decide? Of course, the child&#39;s wishes should be taken into consideration and which party he wants to be with. However, when a child is unable to express his or her wishes at a very young age, or the wishes expressed by the child may not be in his or her best interests, how will the court consider this? It is still necessary to consider which parent&#39;s custody is most beneficial to the child&#39;s physical and mental health and growth, and the interests of adult men and women cannot be placed above the interests of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One party has better economic conditions, educational background, and a legitimate and stable career, which should be an advantage. Because children living with such a father or mother will not only get better care in life, but the adults themselves are also good role models and can teach children better family education through precepts and deeds, especially values ​​education, which is more conducive to children&#39;s good health. Character development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If one party makes a major mistake during the divorce process, violates morality or the law, and shows problems with personal values ​​and character, then the child&#39;s values ​​may be distorted by living with such an adult. Few people face up to their mistakes, so when they make major mistakes, they either distort the facts and give their children a wrong version of the narrative, or they distort the standards for judging right and wrong, which are values, for example, beautifying one&#39;s own infidelity as the supremacy of true love. No matter what kind of situation, it is detrimental to the growth of the child, or it may make the child hate adults who are not at fault, or it may make the child&#39;s mind and values ​​​​very different from ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if the court must determine the ownership of child custody, the principle that is most conducive to the child&#39;s growth should be established, and the child should be allowed to stay with the adult who loves him/her the most, and should not condone fighting for custody. In order to fight for a larger share of property, or to fight for custody rights as a means of revenge on the other half. Children should be the purpose, not the tool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新鲜白菜凑厨余？垃圾不仅要分，更要减]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260032]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/06/3adc4c0617.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 06/3adc4c0617.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257159&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 31, witnesses saw a piece of garbage on the streets of Zhongguancun At the bucket station, sanitation workers unpack fresh cabbage and chop it into pieces to collect food waste. Interviewee/Photo provided&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The round, crispy and fresh Chinese cabbage was not brought to the table, but spread on the floor. A sanitation worker at the garbage sorting bin station used a shovel to chop the vegetables into pieces. The green and white chopped vegetables were dumped into the green trash can for &quot;food waste&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, staff from the China Biodiversity Conservation and Green Development Foundation were investigating plastic waste. Unexpectedly, at the corner of Zhongguancun Street in Haidian District, Seeing such a scene, many surrounding residents also stopped to watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Everyone feels sorry for this cabbage. It&#39;s such a waste. The sanitation workers ignore us and just shovel vegetables.&quot; An eyewitness told Southern Weekend reporters that they I was surprised and angry when I saw the sanitation worker&#39;s skillful movements, so I took a video and uploaded it to the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This video quickly attracted attention. On the evening of November 1, the Zhongguancun Sub-district Office issued a statement on the official WeChat account &quot;Lohas Zhongguancun&quot;, admitting that the location of the garbage classification bin station posted online is located in the Baofu Temple bungalow area of ​​Kexu Community in the street. The person involved is Beijing Green. An employee of Xincheng City Environmental Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Beijing Luxin&quot;) &quot;because the kitchen waste sorting task for the month had not been completed at the end of the month, the cabbage from the company&#39;s internal canteen was used as food waste for disposal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4906186e28.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1267&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4906186e28.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of November 1, 2023, the Zhongguancun Subdistrict Office released a situation statement on the official WeChat ID &quot;LOHAS Zhongguancun&quot;. Screenshot of public account&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Jianguo, a professor at the School of Environment at Tsinghua University, told Southern Weekend reporters that Beijing&#39;s garbage classification has made significant progress in recent years. Citizens&#39; awareness of garbage classification has greatly increased, and their behavior has also improved. is more common, but the problem of imbalance and inadequacy still exists. &quot;On the surface, this incident is an absurd behavior taken by a third-party company for its own interests. It actually reflects the difficulty of waste classification management in reaching the responsibility of waste generators.&quot; Liu Jianguo said that waste classification is a grassroots social governance that involves thousands of households. Work is essentially about people, not garbage. In actual work, “you can’t just see garbage but not people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What is the task of sorting food waste?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At about 15:00 on November 2, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters came to the &quot;Baicai Gong&quot; At the site where the &quot;food waste&quot; incident occurred, the sanitation worker wearing a bright orange uniform in the video was not at the scene. Only a worker wearing a blue vest was cleaning the station. When asked about the incident of &quot;Chinese cabbage being used as kitchen waste&quot;, the worker said, &quot;I don&#39;t know, I just came here today&quot; and claimed that &quot;the neighborhood committee transferred me here (to work) on the first day, and I am currently employed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The garbage classification bin station marked No. 004 in the video has been cleaned, and there are no traces of cabbage on the ground. Multiple trash cans are placed in an orderly manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/f372f11b49.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/f372f11b49.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257161&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 2, 2023, a new sanitation worker at the garbage classification bin station where the incident occurred was cleaning, and no trace of cabbage could be seen on the ground. . Photo by Southern Weekend intern Xi Lijie&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beijing Domestic Waste Management Regulations&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Regulations&quot;) will be implemented on May 1, 2020. Domestic waste is divided into four categories: kitchen waste, recyclables, hazardous waste, and other waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why does the company involved still have the task of sorting food waste every month? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Garbage classification is a complex systematic project with interlocking links. The relevant assessment indicators are normal, such as the awareness rate of garbage classification and the amount of various types of garbage sorted. (or separation rate) and so on.&quot; Lan Yajun, chairman of Guizhou Gaoyuan Environmental Protection Consulting Co., Ltd., told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the Regulations, Beijing will formulate rules to guide social investment into areas such as domestic waste cleaning, collection, transportation, processing and recycling. The above-mentioned &quot;Situation Statement&quot; also mentioned that Beijing Luxin&#39;s daily work is to ensure that the area around the bin station is clean and tidy, and to urge residents to correctly dispose of food waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In real life, some residents do not sort the garbage at home or do it incorrectly. When they arrive at the garbage station, they have to be sorted twice by the garbage classification instructor.&quot; Lan Yajun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters visited the communities around the incident and found that nearby citizens generally have a strong awareness of garbage classification, and different garbage goes into different trash cans. Commissioners will be there to remind citizens to sort their food waste and ensure that paper and plastic are not allowed in food waste. However, citizens do not need to break the bags when disposing of food waste. Commissioners are responsible for subsequent inspection and re-sorting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Qichacha&quot; shows that the company involved, Beijing Luxin, was established in July 2014 with a registered capital of 3 million yuan. According to the official website of Beijing Greenxin, it has more than 260 employees and hundreds of various types of environmentally friendly operation vehicles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It is indeed difficult for us now. We are actively solving the problem. Our employees should be punished. We are currently meeting to discuss this issue.&quot; On the morning of November 2, Beijing The relevant person in charge of Luxin told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As to what kind of punishment Beijing Luxin will face in the future, and whether it can continue to provide garbage sorting services for Zhongguancun Street in the future, the person in charge of the publicity of the Street Office declined on the phone. Interviewed by Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Food waste classification assessment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the incident, there were comments that as a third-party operation and maintenance company, Baicai collected food waste in order to obtain Government subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Haidian District Work Plan for Promoting Domestic Waste Classification&quot; released in 2017 shows that &quot;food waste separated by property units or professional companies will be subsidized according to the amount (1,700 yuan/ton)&quot;. Compared with the subsidy of 1,700 yuan/ton, the recent wholesale price of Chinese cabbage in Xinfadi, Beijing, is around 0.3 yuan/jin, or 600 yuan/ton. The cabbage has become food waste, and its value has tripled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Different levels of economic development in different regions place different emphasis on waste classification. Some subsidize based on the number of barrels, while others, like Beijing, subsidize kitchen waste based on the tonnage. The subsidy level of 1,700 yuan/ton is relatively high in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the &quot;Regulations&quot; implemented in 2020 only mention that Beijing will formulate incentive policies, without mentioning the amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Operation and maintenance companies like Beijing Luxin are actually third-party services purchased by the government. In addition to secondary sorting of food waste, there are other tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, on September 25, 2023, Wangjing Street, Chaoyang District announced the winning bid for third-party garbage classification services in 2023-2024. The total winning transaction amount was 5.58 million. Yu Yuan, Party B&#39;s organizer must be responsible for collecting kitchen waste, ensuring the purity of kitchen waste, and re-sorting mixed waste that is not put in according to specifications; Party B also needs to be responsible for cleaning the trash cans and establishing a renewable resource recycling system; cooperate Local communities and properties carry out garbage classification work and accept government inspections and assessments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The original intention of the waste classification subsidy and food waste sorting rate system is good, encouraging companies to better complete waste classification work, but policymakers may We didn’t expect companies to ‘take shortcuts’.” Lan Yajun said, “If a company fails to meet the assessment targets, not only may it be difficult to obtain subsidies, but it may also be criticized by local competent authorities, which will affect subsequent contract signings. The competent authorities may also have to bear the responsibility. Responsibility for poor supervision.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only do companies have indicators, the government also has assessment pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The official WeChat ID of the Haidian District Urban Management Committee &quot;Haidian City Affairs&quot; shows that the district&#39;s domestic waste classification work leading group has assessed the waste classification work of each street and town. Announcement and ranking of red, yellow and green lists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking February 2023 as an example, Zhongguancun Street ranked third on the yellow list with a score of 77.76, ranking 11th on the entire list, and belongs to the upper-middle level of Haidian District . Southern Weekend reporters noticed that in Beijing’s Haidian District, in addition to comparing the effectiveness of garbage classification among streets, communities also compete for the top spot, and those who perform well will be publicly praised. Similar evaluations can be found in major cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the assessment of Haidian District, Beijing, the food waste separation rate accounted for 10 points out of a total of 100. It is worth noting that Southern Weekend reporters did not find specific assessment indicators for Beijing’s food waste separation rate from public information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/88286f46cd.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;886&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/88286f46cd.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257162&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 14, 2023, the Haidian District Urban Management Committee released relevant information on garbage classification assessment on the official WeChat ID &quot;Haidian City Affairs&quot;. Screenshot of official account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the domestic waste assessment methods announced across the country, there are almost no specific requirements for the food waste sorting rate. Most of them are based on comprehensive performance assessment, but In actual work, some regions have specific requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Jianguo told Southern Weekend reporters that the assessment indicator set by Beijing is around 18%. The above-mentioned bidding announcement of Wangjing Street in Chaoyang District also mentioned that food waste collection and clearance, with a collection rate of over 18%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters searched for information and found that 18% is not high nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take Shanghai, which has better garbage classification, as an example. According to data from the Shanghai Greening and City Appearance Bureau, the amount of wet garbage separated is basically stable at 35% of the total dry and wet garbage. Around; according to data from the Shanghai Environmental Sanitation Engineering Design Institute in June 2023, kitchen waste accounts for about 30% of the total domestic waste. According to the environmental sanitation industry self-media &quot;Voice of Environmental Sanitation&quot;, the sorting rate of food waste is generally 20%-30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 3, CCTV reported that the separation rate in certain areas of Haidian District must reach 20%. The person in charge of a domestic waste disposal point said, It is difficult to achieve this indicator in winter because there are less skins and cores of fruits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lan Yajun’s view is that the company involved did not separate out enough kitchen waste. It must be wrong to use cabbage to make up the numbers, but the food waste separation rate is not only It is the work of third-party companies, and it also depends on whether the early publicity and mobilization efforts are strong, the level of citizen participation is high, and the targets are easy to complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Source reduction is more important&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In waste management, classification is only the front-end work, and the separated kitchen waste needs to be disposed of later. The price is high, and equipment investment can easily reach hundreds of millions of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 3R principle has been popularized for many years. In the order of reduce, reuse and recycle, reduction ranks first. First. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2021, Li Wei, director of the Urban Management Command Center of Haidian District, Beijing, wrote that the amount of food waste separation in the district is growing rapidly and the separation rate is stable. At more than 18.5%, the volume of other waste dropped by 28.68% year-on-year. The growth rate of domestic waste processing volume entering waste incineration and landfill facilities was controlled within 4%, and the total source volume of domestic waste was controlled within the target of 972,200 tons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lan Yajun, who has been engaged in garbage classification for more than ten years, also agrees that the purpose of garbage classification is not to carefully divide it into four categories, but to reduce it from the source, without just staring at it. The amount (or separation rate) of food waste is an indicator. He believes that indicators that deserve more attention include the reduction in the total amount of waste entering landfills/power plants (or per capita amount) and the cost of treatment (or per capita cost). &quot;The government is also tightening its belt now. Where does the money for garbage classification come from? How to spend it wisely? Improving quality and efficiency is a very practical issue.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会11月4日闭幕，累计境外采购商比上届增长超50%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 13:00:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, in the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, A buyer passes by a large panda doll.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/d53c3c3321.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the venue of the third phase of the Canton Fair, buyers passed by a large panda doll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, the 134th Canton Fair concluded successfully in Guangzhou, and the online platform operated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The total exhibition area of ​​this Canton Fair is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibiting companies and a total of 74,000 booths. The exhibition scale has reached a new high. A total of 198,000 overseas purchasers attended the exhibition during the 15-day exhibition period, an increase of over 50% compared to the previous session. There were 126,343 buyers from countries co-constructing the “One Belt and One Road”, accounting for 63.9%, an increase of 68.6% over the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/2da5a01466.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257150&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the cumulative number of overseas buyers attending the 134th Canton Fair increased by more than 50% compared with the previous session. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas buyers were trying out massage seats.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /06/12519afa74.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, several overseas Buyers are trying out massage chairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year&#39;s Canton Fair has been attended by overseas buyers enthusiastically. The more open and dynamic Canton Fair has attracted buyers from all over the world. Offline export transactions reached US$22.3 billion, an increase of 2.8% over the 133rd session, showing a restorative growth trend. The export turnover of brand enterprises was US$6.35 billion, an increase of 7.8% over the 133rd session, accounting for 28.5% of the total export turnover. Transactions with countries co-building the Belt and Road Initiative amounted to US$12.27 billion, an increase of 2% over the 133rd session. Exhibitors said that the &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the exhibition. In addition to signing orders on-site, buyers are constantly making follow-up appointments to visit factories, workshops, and production capacity, and are expected to reach more cooperation in the future. The quality of overseas purchasers attending this Canton Fair has improved and they are actively placing orders, which further enhances the confidence of enterprises in foreign trade exports next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a bubble machine attracted the attention of overseas buyers.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/ac1d0fb344.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a The bubble machine has attracted the attention of overseas buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting colorful dolls and toys.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/b645302e77.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting colorful dolls and toys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, the optimization of the exhibition area structure of this Canton Fair has achieved remarkable results, and innovative exhibits have emerged in large numbers. Exhibitors have uploaded a total of more than 2.75 million exhibits to the online platform, including more than 700,000 new products, about 110,000 smart products, more than 430,000 green and low-carbon products, and about 230,000 independent intellectual property products. A total of 401 new product debut events were held. The 2023 Canton Fair Design Innovation Award (CF Award) award ceremony was held to award 141 innovative products from 118 units. New products, new technologies, new materials, new processes, and new services are emerging one after another. High-end intelligent, green and low-carbon products have become mainstream, and innovative and creative products are deeply favored. From small and beautiful new consumer products to cutting-edge cutting-edge technology, from simple OEM to going global with their own brands, from selling products to providing solutions, from traditional industries to emerging fields, Chinese companies continue to climb to the mid-to-high end of the industrial chain, demonstrating This reflects the strong development resilience and innovative vitality of China’s foreign trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair were selecting cute animal dolls.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/7a1ea2d941.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257154&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong , overseas buyers in the third phase of the Canton Fair are selecting cute animal dolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas buyers negotiated in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/06/e9d743c1c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, overseas Buyers are negotiating in the exhibition area of ​​a baby stroller brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in this year&#39;s Canton Fair Import Exhibition, focusing on displaying products such as intelligent manufacturing, quality home furnishings, and leisure life. The participating countries of the “Belt and Road Initiative” accounted for 60% of the exhibitors. Overseas exhibitors said that the Canton Fair Import Expo has built a fast channel for them to enter the Chinese market, allowing them to share the &quot;super traffic&quot; of the Canton Fair, while also meeting a large number of customers from all over the world, bringing new opportunities to expand the global market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition was attended by 650 companies from 43 countries and regions&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/06/4e80921716.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257156&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 4, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Import Exhibition. A total of 650 companies from 43 countries and regions participated in the exhibition&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 4, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair Exhibition General The total area is 1.55 million square meters, with more than 28,000 exhibitors and a total of 74,000 booths.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/36c7b8c2a9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 257157&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the 134th Canton Fair has a total exhibition area of ​​1.55 million square meters, and exhibitors There are over 28,000 exhibitors, with a total of 74,000 booths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that after the closing of this Canton Fair, the online platform will continue to be open. In addition to the functions of exhibitor connection and appointment negotiation, the other functions will be operated on a regular basis throughout the year. The 135th Canton Fair will be held from April 15 to May 5, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;quick return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/cb7159e811.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas buyer was browsing a brochure. The &quot;rapid return&quot; of overseas buyers has boosted the &quot;warmth&quot; of the Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天津助学金事件通报：不存在国家助学金名额遭“挤占”情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260050]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:23:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, students have reported on the Internet about our school’s scholarship evaluation issues, which has attracted social attention. We are very grateful to the media and netizens for their concern for our students and their supervision of school work. The school set up a special work class to review relevant archives and materials, get an in-depth understanding of the situation from relevant teachers and students in the school, and organized a working group to conduct on-site visits and investigations in three students&#39; places of origin. The relevant situation has also been reported to relevant students. The relevant situation is now reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, since the student concerned raised objections to the identification of students with difficulties in the class on September 18, the person in charge of the financial aid work at both the school and college levels has maintained communication with the student and listened patiently to him. The opinions and appeals indicate that the school understands its actual difficulties and meets the conditions for receiving national scholarships in accordance with regulations. The specific grade is determined after comprehensive evaluation in accordance with relevant procedures. Since the student&#39;s enrollment, the local government and relevant relatives have guaranteed his tuition and living expenses. He has received second-class national scholarships for his freshman and sophomore years, and all have been paid out. The comprehensive evaluation for the junior year is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship. The college has announced the evaluation results from October 24th to October 27th. There is no &quot;crowding&quot; of the national scholarship quota. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the family and personal circumstances of the other two students involved meet the conditions for financial aid for needy students. One student is expected to receive a second-class national scholarship this school year through comprehensive evaluation, and the other student is evaluated comprehensively for this school year. The candidate is expected to receive the National Inspirational Scholarship. No material fraud was found, the assessment complied with relevant regulations, and no &quot;malfeasance and abuse of power&quot; issues were found. The daily necessities alleged in the video were purchased with the above-mentioned students’ income from their work-study studies or were gifts from their relatives. Their high consumption behavior has been verified to be untrue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After repeated investigations by the school, there are no children of martyrs among the students at school, and there is no situation where the children of martyrs are not supported. All orphans among current students who have been identified by the civil affairs department have enjoyed state funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation also found that the relevant departments of the school were insufficient in their sincerity and care for students when carrying out funding work. The school will carefully summarize, further refine and optimize the student aid work, and provide more warmth and care to students from families with financial difficulties. We would like to thank all sectors of society for their concern, support and assistance to our school and related students, and welcome all sectors of society to continue to supervise and guide the work of our school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寒潮来袭羽绒服涨价，你有在准备过冬吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260042]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, strong winds, cooling, rain and snow have occurred in many places in the north. The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue orange blizzard warnings, cold wave blue warnings and strong wind blue warnings at 6:00 on November 6, and the heavy snowfall in Northeast China has entered its strongest period. Some media visited many wholesalers in Yiwu and learned that due to the increase in raw material prices this year, the purchase price of down jackets has generally increased. In addition to offline stores, e-commerce platforms are also celebrating Double Eleven, and gloves, thermos cups, and thermal underwear from many brand stores are also selling well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, summer is not over yet for some areas in the south, such as Guangzhou. Since summer officially started on April 11, the summer of 2023 in Guangzhou has exceeded 200 days, and this fall may be late. Moreover, an El Niño event is currently taking shape, and under its influence, temperatures in most central and eastern parts of my country will be higher than normal for the same period of the year. For many southern friends, down jackets are only used for a few days a year, and there are many who have never even bought a down jacket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are you prepared for winter? Are you considering buying a down jacket for winter? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年各级政府支持就业创业资金超2000亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;1337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257144&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security Learned&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year various types of funds from governments at all levels&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Direct support for employment and entrepreneurship has exceeded 200 billion yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adjustment and optimization of employment stabilization policies&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Continue to implement the return policy until employment is stabilized&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to expand from absorbing employment subsidies&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To promptly restart the one-time employment expansion subsidy&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accelerate the release of policy dividends&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Injecting strong impetus into employment growth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10.22 million new jobs were created in urban areas across the country&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Complete the full-year target 85% of the target&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national urban surveyed unemployment rate at the end of September was 5%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lower than the same period in 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment situation has generally improved and remained basically stable&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》，没写进报道的那些事丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260011]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Is there anyone else you particularly want to interview now? I was asked this question. I tried to count them on my fingers, but there seemed to be only a few. Qiu Litao may be one. I&#39;m looking forward to it after watching &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; at the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be able to create a huge allegory with big scenes of banging, banging and jingling bells, allowing the audience to take what they need and understand each other, is an amazing creative power. I wonder how this person recognizes his own expression. But Qiu Litao is obviously not someone who can talk about this. This may be a bit embarrassing for him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, when asked questions that are too serious and strict, he will usually say &quot;I didn&#39;t think so much&quot; and &quot;I can&#39;t make a movie if I think so.&quot; For example, when it comes to anarchism - which he corrects to anarchism - he says that the definition is too vague and he doesn&#39;t know what everyone is talking about when they say these words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao definitely does not &quot;think so little&quot;. This is my feeling when I watched the movie &quot;The Decameron of Sex Workers&quot; directed by him. Regarding the young lady&#39;s situation, the mockumentary had a lot of back and forth, flashes of swords and swords. They are not expressions of &quot;pretentiousness&quot;, but are full of market acumen, speculation and ridicule. It&#39;s quite clever, but also quite embarrassing, like someone has taken off your clothes. Qiu Litao doesn&#39;t like clear things. From a utilitarian point of view, he is of course more tolerant of gray and vagueness. You can call him rough, but there are so many things that help him enrich his semantics. Who can I ask to explain? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first watched &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, I liked the sense of relaxation - many things that others have to put effort into laying out - such as whether this character is convincing or not, whether he resembles that era or not, it is not Qiu Litao Something that can be confusing. His camera flicked by, and his lack of restraint even formed a style. But that’s it, sometimes it works sometimes... I want to explain to readers that I don’t think this is a very good movie, although it is not without its merits. For example, the audience can see people and people in the early 1990s in the cinema. society. One of my interviewees felt that Qiu Litao might need a good screenwriter to help him overcome the cultural barrier of making films outside of Hong Kong. This is a tolerant statement, and after completing the reporting and writing of the report, I am willing to give a tolerant understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; uses many details to restore the social scene of the early 1990s. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Qiu Litao has leg problems and walks with a long stride, but he works hard enough to make People ignore this. People should be able to understand this feeling. When we were young and could not travel far away, the TV was a magical door at home, which could take us to different countries and distant starry skies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, I wrote an email to Director Qiu Litao and asked him to introduce the interviewees. He felt that it would be a bit embarrassing for him to come forward and tell his partners, &quot;The media did an exclusive interview with me, and I would like to interview you to talk about my story and working methods.&quot; But he listed the right names and ways I could contact them. This is not his responsibility. I am grateful for his understanding and sympathy for media work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed the main creators behind &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, such as the producer, screenwriter, action director and assistant director. In addition to talking about Qiu Litao, I also talked about their own work. Some stories that couldn’t be written into the main manuscript, I wanted to record in my notes. I hope I live up to their expectations and time, and I hope this information is useful to readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When screenwriter Chen Daming received the invitation from Chinese Pictures, he heard that multiple versions of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; had been written. Chen Daming is familiar with that history. In the late 1980s, he stayed at the Beijing Film Academy to teach. During the period when &quot;trafficking&quot; was most popular, most of the people lining up in the hall of the film school and making phone calls were not talking about art, but reselling color TVs and jeeps. The most successful business was selling MiG fighter jets - this last detail was written into the film. The character played by Andy Lau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What he wanted to show in the script was animality. &quot;People don&#39;t care about anything when they are hungry.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain Miao Qingshan played by Huang Xuan is nicknamed Old D. He likes to listen to Shostakovich&#39;s music. There is not much metaphor in this setting. Originally, Chen Daming wanted to call him Lao Bei, referring to Beethoven, but it didn&#39;t seem to fit him, so he wanted to find a Russian composer. One day he met a neighbor in the courtyard, an Englishman who was a conductor in China, and recommended Shostakovich. Chen Daming feels that his works have &quot;black elements&quot; and &quot;seem to be fighting against black forces and evil forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257131&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scene after the Shostakovich concert in the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, action director Li Zhongzhi was filming with Jackie Chan , there is no script for the scenes he is responsible for, just one word, play. Now the action scenes have to be integrated with the plot of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Gui Youming made great efforts to introduce me to the team of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The art designer Zhao Hai has worked on &quot;Ming Dynasty 1566&quot; and &quot;Toward the Republic&quot;, and one of the computer special effects production teams has worked on &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. With the help of a digital imaging technology referred to as DIT, Gui Youming can see the shooting scene from anywhere with his iPad. Because of this technology, producer Andy Lau was able to follow up on-site shooting every day in the quarantine hotel at the time. Gui Youming believes that this is a characteristic of the industrialization of the film industry. This technology is very helpful when shooting movies of a scale similar to &quot;The Wandering Earth 3&quot; and &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As the producer of the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, Andy Lau (left) relied on high-tech communications to improve work efficiency during the filming of the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao was particularly impressed by the scene at the international train track-changing station interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deputy director Wen Zhenwei contacted the National Railway Administration and got back a lot of information. Qiu Litao was not concerned about the ins and outs and technical details of the train&#39;s track change at the Sino-Russian border. He only wanted to know where the people on the scene should be and how they reacted when the different carriages were raised. For example, that is when the flight attendants are most busy and when passengers are most curious. Few people have seen the train changing tracks at the border. At this time, the robbers rush in. &quot;It is a good timing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vasily, played by Andy Lau, has many fake passports. The fake name on one of them is Wen Zhenwei, which is the name of the assistant director. In order to avoid misunderstandings about the real names, the names of the staff will be used as much as possible when making movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Daming once saw some photos in National Geographic magazine, taking pictures of abandoned rocket bases around the world. He especially hopes to film a crime-related gunfight scene in such a place in the future. There is such a scene in &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. Gui Youming said to Zhao Hai, have you ever seen a movie called &quot;Oriental Condor&quot; (there is a similar scene in the film), I want to make it bigger than that. . So they referred to a lot of information about abandoned Russian rocket bases. &quot;I remember that day Uncle Zhi (Li Zhongzhi) came to the scene and said, &#39;What are you doing? Why is it so big?&#39;&quot; Gui Youming warned that we must make full use of this scene: &quot;Blow up here and there, run around, inside and outside Use everything, don’t waste it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chen Daming, the earliest draft of the script ended with a courtroom scene. Vasily was sentenced to 5 years in prison, suspended for 2 years. Policeman Cui Zhenhai patted him on the shoulder and said, if you look back, Vasily saw his daughter. In the original script, the daughter was 15 years old and attending a technical school. The daughter looked at her father from a distance, nodded, and that was how it ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao made major changes to the ending. In addition to adding the scene of the rail-changing station, he also changed Vasily&#39;s ending to one in which he was blinded due to a gun accident. Chen Daming thinks that there is a bit of blank space in this ending, and many people are guessing whether the daughter Vasily met at the end is real or fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[流连菖蒲河的老人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpIRG4hA5NAwK4U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpI RG4hA5NAwK4U. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The social stage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, the ancient trees along the Changpu River in Beijing are still lush, and pairs of wild ducks inhabit the dark green stream. Every Tuesday and Saturday, when the sun is at its strongest, the classical promenade in Changpu River Park is filled with elderly people looking for partners, and the golden light spots add romantic vitality to them. The red wall of Huangshichen blocks the busy traffic of Chang&#39;an Street, bringing the park a secluded space suitable for romance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t expect a successful match based on true love.&quot; This is the sincere warning to latecomers from an old man who often comes to parties in Changpu River Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman in her fifties, dressed in an emerald-colored Tang suit and with exquisitely braided hair, refused to communicate with any of them in depth after an afternoon of ballroom dancing with a few uncles, and stayed alone. The pillars of the gallery rest. Asked why she wasn&#39;t looking for a partner in Changpu River Park, she said she wasn&#39;t looking because &quot;the blind dates here come with various conditions, and people are sold like livestock.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bald man in his sixties who always wears gold-framed sunglasses from Beijing has been here for 15 years. He can freely blend into any dating gossip and naturally bring together any interested couple. men and women. But when the other party&#39;s ambiguous signal reaches him, he always laughs at himself: &quot;I won&#39;t look for it. I have no money. If I don&#39;t have money, I can&#39;t find the right one.&quot; With a 14-square-meter bungalow and a retirement salary of more than 4,000 yuan, he always Can extinguish the other person&#39;s enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changpu River Park has been criticized by the elderly, but it always has the magic to tie them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During a conversation in the corridor, it was like a default etiquette to ask each other about houses, household registration, salary, and medical insurance information. No one wants to be dragged down, everyone is rushing to get better conditions. After a while of &quot;greetings&quot;, there is a more detailed matching of needs. As long as you stay here for a day, the old people will not help but tell you that there are only a handful of people who set marriage registration as their goal; there are not a majority of people who are sincerely looking for a long-term wife. Maybe what the other person wants is just an ambiguous opposite-sex friendship or an extramarital affair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a common and decent ending to look down on each other. We can also become nodding friends - old acquaintances who say &quot;here we come&quot; to each other. And getting along emotionally involves the risk of paying for lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a week of official dating, his girlfriend asked Uncle Zhou to use his savings to buy her a gold ring worth 20,000 yuan. Uncle Zhou emphasized that &quot;that is pension money and cannot be touched.&quot; Afterwards, they broke up, and Uncle Zhou kept blaming himself for being a fool. Sister Qin met a man in his sixties in the park. During a video call at 9 o&#39;clock one night, other women vaguely appeared in the other party&#39;s kitchen. &quot;He didn&#39;t tell me at first that he had a relationship with more than one woman. I didn&#39;t like that he kept talking about sexual matters between men and women all day long.&quot; Sister Qin blocked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical temporary union occurred between a Northeastern woman in her fifties and a Beijing man in his seventies. One needs wealth and shelter, the other desires youth and care. After a period of time, there will always be a reason to bring an unhappy end to the relationship due to the ownership of the house, differences in consumption concepts, and the opposition of the man&#39;s children. After they broke up, the woman thought she was cheated of sex, and the man thought he was cheated of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changpu River Park, some people can adapt to this &quot;exchange&quot; rule, while others find it chilling. Uncle Chen, 63, has a monthly rent income of 30,000 yuan. After ending his romantic relationship with a woman in her forties, he always took the initiative to compensate her with something, whether it was a big meal or a red envelope: &quot;Why should I let you, an old man, take advantage of me?&quot; Uncle Zhou would say Lamenting under the street lights at night, &quot;This place is like a microcosm of society. There is true love, but too little. Everyone has lost faith and only has the word &#39;profit&#39; in their eyes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who complain, People who have been deceived, people who are ready to break up, and people who seem to be watching indifferently will eventually return to the Changpu River. They persuaded the elder sister who was eager to be a matchmaker and register information for the elderly: this place is too chaotic and not a serious place to find a partner. They themselves are willing to be trapped in chaos. They always come here on Tuesdays and Saturdays to chat, strike up conversations, dance, and play cards. An old man riding a bicycle claimed that he was not here to fall in love, but on the blind date day, he would shuttle back and forth between the east and west gates of the park to observe and inquire around. He pointed to the winding corridor and said: &quot;This is the big stage of society. (I am here) to see how these people perform here wearing masks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Late release&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>; Geng Tielin wears a peaked cap and a mask and often hangs out in gathering areas where Northeasterners gather. He is from Harbin. He is 1.76 meters tall, well-proportioned and lean, and his posture when climbing up the river is brisk and flexible. It seems hard to believe that he is already 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m not looking for a date, I&#39;m just here for a walk. Besides, as a tall guy like me, I don&#39;t have to worry about no one liking me.&quot; Geng Tielin is confident in his charm. When he comes to the park, he just needs to stand there and many women will come and add their WeChat messages. He will approve the application out of politeness, but the only people he is interested in are &quot;tall, good-looking, and under 60&quot;; the only people he agrees to get along with are people who don&#39;t covet his money and &quot;don&#39;t want this or that.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his chat history, there are three women in their fifties who he calls &quot;sisters&quot;. When chatting with other elderly people in the park, Geng Tielin referred to them more as &quot;friends&quot; - people who can meet up to eat, travel, and sleep in the same bed without binding each other to a fixed identity. The sisters came from a well-off family and never asked Geng Tielin to bear any expenses. He sent a wedding red envelope to the son of one of his sisters, but the other party politely returned it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since his divorce 35 years ago, Geng Tielin has never had a long-term girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When my wife left, my daughter was only 5 years old. In order to raise his daughter, Geng Tielin worked as a driver, a chef, and opened a breakfast shop to help her get admitted to a graduate school in a Beijing university. The daughter found a job in a bank in Beijing, and the old father moved to Beijing with her and cooked in a factory canteen in Daxing. Geng Tielin was very proud when talking about his daughter who bought a house with an area of ​​more than 80 square meters and a value of more than 6 million yuan in Chaoyang District with an annual salary of one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Tielin said that he had not touched a woman for more than 20 years after his divorce. The biggest reason is that he doesn&#39;t want the shadow of his &quot;stepmother&quot; to hinder his daughter&#39;s growth. But he has desires - physiological desires that cannot be channeled and are born at the wrong time. In those days, having sex outside of marriage was considered hooliganism. Geng Tielin did not dare to tell anyone, so he could only hold back or solve it on his own. &quot;It&#39;s such a shame, I was so miserable during those twenty years.&quot; After the millennium, he gradually tried to date different women. Sometimes it’s a hotel clerk you meet while driving, sometimes it’s an acquaintance whose husband is crying to him about his loss of sexual function due to cerebral palsy. However, no romance has turned into a stable relationship. Geng Tielin believes that it is impossible for him to ask others to adapt to his &quot;bad habits.&quot; Worrying about his daughter and raising a family, he often stayed awake all night, pacing back and forth and scrolling through his cell phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, he suddenly took off his peaked cap and showed me that his almost smooth head had only short, gray and sparse hair, dotted around the ears. At this time, he became a 65-year-old man. &quot;Our family has good genes, and no one has ever lost their hair. My grandfather was lying in a coffin at the age of 90 with black hair. It was because of his insomnia in those years that my hair became like this. I also want to have a wife to love, and have My wife loves me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frugal and chic single life is also what Geng Tielin enjoys. He refused to live under the same roof as his daughter and rented a house of more than 20 square meters in Yanjiao to live alone, paying only 400 yuan in rent per month. Sauce elbow is Geng Tielin’s specialty. The price of raw materials in Yanjiao is only half of that downstairs in my daughter&#39;s community. Geng Tielin feels that now is the best time in life. His daughter has a future and he does not have to worry about raising his granddaughter. He is in good health and lives a comfortable life. There is no new partner to divide one&#39;s salary, but there are tender greetings and the joy of traveling together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On National Day two years ago, while wandering around, Geng Tielin accidentally discovered Changpu River Park. Although the elderly people here &quot;have their own thoughts,&quot; the situation of single elderly people is very similar to his. Even if he can&#39;t find a satisfactory &quot;friend&quot;, Geng Tielin still likes to chat here. He said he was not lonely at all, and his life of walking in the park and recuperating at home was well arranged. He also said that after his daughter got married, she was too busy and made fewer phone calls than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I met Geng Tielin, a slender lady with wavy hair reaching her waist, wearing a silk scarf, took the initiative to sit next to him, and the two talked and laughed. When I met him for the second time two days later, he said he wanted to delete the other person. According to him, the two went on a date to visit Zhongshan Park, and the man paid for the trip. Naturally, the lady ordered an extra bun, and asked Geng Tielin to buy the &quot;Pulse&quot;. She also insisted on asking for a 50 yuan hat in the scenic spot. Three more days later, I saw him for the third time. While chatting, Geng Tielin suddenly held his chin in a daze and murmured to himself: If there is someone better than those sisters, he will fall in love with her, and he will live with her wholeheartedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Live a life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compare calamus Among the other well-dressed ladies in He Park, Zhang Ming&#39;an&#39;s clothing is obviously pragmatic. Her short hair was dyed jet black but didn&#39;t appear to be trimmed carefully. The upper body is a warm but bloated dark blue fur coat, the lower body is black pants and black shoes, and a styleless cross-body bag hangs casually in front of the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In just one hour by bus, Zhang Mingan can go to the park from his home near Tiantongyuan. At 9:30 a.m. on Saturday, the elderly people who live further away have not yet arrived. The promenade of the park is a bit quiet. Most of the people here are local Beijingers like Zhang Mingan who live in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Zhang Mingan also wanted to find a local who lived in the city to be her wife, but it was obvious that she had not met anyone she was satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Beijing gentleman communicated with her back to back for a while, then turned and left. She pouted and looked at the other person&#39;s back, and said to me during the interview: &quot;You have a wife, why are you here? Aren&#39;t you Huo Huo&#39;er (Note: Beijing dialect, spoiling, destroying things)? What have I become?&quot; &quot;The uncle&#39;s legally married wife has been living abroad for a long time, and he has participated in the Beijing senior dating program &quot;Choice&quot; three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Mingan’s words, these are all “fancy” relationships. At the age of 62, she has only one simple request, which is to find a wife who can &quot;live&quot; with her and spend the last twenty years of her life together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingan has no children. In her thirties, she underwent surgery to remove uterine lesions due to uterine lesions. After that, she divorced her first husband. At the age of 50, she found a partner with whom she could travel around the world, Lao Fang. Zhang Mingan told me with a smile that in the past 10 years, they had participated in affordable tour groups and visited the United States, Thailand, Japan and South Korea. When she was 60 years old, Lao Fang died of pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took more than a year to get out of depression, and Zhang Mingan figured out that he should live for himself. I danced and played ball with the retired sisters from my workplace, watched anti-Japanese dramas, and kept my house tidy. &quot;If you can&#39;t move, go to the nursing home. Just make sure someone collects the body for you. There is no need to find your wife.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Zhang Mingan realized the vulnerability of being alone. After she was infected with the new coronavirus, she lay alone on the sofa at home. The coffee table and water glass were very close to her, but she was too weak to reach the water. She was thirsty on the sofa all day. She really hoped that there was someone beside her who could give her some medicine and make some porridge. &quot;If I can&#39;t survive, you will take care of me. If you can&#39;t survive, I will take care of you. Be sincere and support each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I am a good helper in life.&quot; Zhang Mingan thinks so. Fried pancakes, baked pies, and steamed flower rolls are all here. Neighbors said she had a mysophobia, her home was always clean, and she would pick up even a trace of hair on the ground. Neighbors also said that Lao Fang was really lucky because he could not move after being ill. Zhang Mingan was always there to wash his feet and cut his nails every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingan can never find anyone with whom he can live a good life. When I went on a blind date at an agency, the other person kept talking about how he owned more than a dozen houses. Zhang Mingan pointed out that she didn&#39;t believe it and didn&#39;t want it. There were many outsiders at the sorority, which did not meet her expectations in choosing a mate. After coming to Changpu River Park, the people who came to ask her were either people with wives, or people who were just dancing or just having fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of offline dating platforms is also a problem. Zhang Mingan recalled that he needed to pay 1,000 yuan to register for an introduction at a wedding agency in Changping. In Dongcheng District, the price is more than 10,000. After the Changping family registered, a year passed between the first and second matches for her. Offline gatherings are more efficient, but she only knows the daily gathering locations at Changpu River Park on Tuesdays and Saturdays and Temple of Heaven Park on Sundays. Zhang Mingan also hopes that in offline activities, household registration, marriage, property and other status can be authenticated by real-name authentication to reduce unnecessary communication costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Obsession&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In In the dating circle of Changpu River Park, the reputation among outsiders, especially women from outside the area, is not very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to some people, they left their hometown in their fifties and hoped to establish themselves in Beijing. They dragged their luggage to the park as soon as they got off the train and were willing to live with an old man if he gave him money and a house. The condition is to undertake all housework. An old man from Beijing told me that he once met a beautiful 39-year-old woman from other provinces. After the woman found out that he was from Beijing, she immediately expressed her intention to marry him - this was to obtain a Beijing household registration for her son. She said that it would be easier for her to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University for the Beijing College Entrance Examination. According to another uncle, a woman from another province always talked about the conditions for bride price, which made him feel a huge gap in concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the hearts of locals, even if not all foreign women who come here are like this, the four words &quot;ruthless and profit-seeking&quot; are secretly engraved behind this geographical name card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hongzhen, who comes from out of town, seems to be able to accept this label openly. Her friend Meng Shuying from Inner Mongolia hopes to find a long-term partner with a foundation of love in Changpu River. Wang Hongzhen hates that iron cannot be made into steel: &quot;Her idea is impossible to find here. While I am still in good health, I will make money when I can. It is impossible to find a long-term life here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The money she talks about is working as a nanny in the man&#39;s house with a salary of more than 3,000 yuan. Before August 2023, she lived in the home of an 88-year-old professor in Beijing until his daughter took him to the United States. In addition to doing housework, Wang Hongzhen accompanied him to buy groceries, exercise, go to the park, listen to him talk about history, and help him bathe and rub his back. They stayed alone under the same roof for two years, and Wang Hongzhen couldn&#39;t tell whether this was considered emotional or whether he was considered the other&#39;s wife. But she thinks this is no longer important. &quot;Making money is the main priority, and the objects are secondary.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15 years ago, Wang Hongzhen, like her friends, was eager to regain marriage and happiness through the platform of Changpu River Park. . This dream was later shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2000, 41-year-old divorced Wang Hongzhen came to Beijing with his two sons to work hard. She has opened a beauty shop and worked in an agency and a travel agency. In 2007, when Wang Hongzhen was still a flower in Changpu River Park, he met a widowed water plant manager here. The other person was about the same age as her, tall and handsome, and the two fell in love. But under the strong opposition of each other&#39;s children, they could not go on. Every year when Wang Hongzhen returns to Beijing from his hometown, he will bring a souvenir to his former lover to express his gratitude. During her most difficult time, he helped her rent a house and see a doctor. The relationship with the second partner was not as intense as the first, but the relationship also ended due to the fear of the other partner&#39;s daughter. The story that followed was not sweet. One year after Wang Hongzhen registered her marriage with a man, he dumped her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, in the eyes of Wang Hongzhen, the men in Changpu River Park are all people who trick people into sleeping and then kick the woman off after having enough fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her obsession became having an independent residence in Beijing. With his own strength, Wang Hongzhen cannot buy a house in Beijing. Living with her eldest son in Dachang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hebei Dachang Hui Autonomous County&lt;/span>;), she had to take care of the housework for the family of five. &quot;They are too busy at work. I take care of the two children for walks, cooking, and laundry. I will get sick after living there for three months.&quot; Working as a nanny is actually a kind of rest. Another consideration of Wang Hongzhen is, &quot;Now that I am in good health, I don&#39;t want to trouble my sons by living in their house. If you have conflicts over time, how will you find someone to help you when you get older? How unjust.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;If he must form a male-female partner, Wang Hongzhen’s requirement is: first of all, he must have a place to live in Beijing. Second, either register the marriage and ask her to move her household registration to Beijing after two years; or do not register but give her a sum of money every month. She said that with a Beijing household registration, you can apply for affordable housing even if you get divorced, and you can reimburse medical expenses in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An uncle sent Wang Hongzhen a tender invitation to dinner. She always had a premonition that the other party was trying to cheat, so she threatened him back: &quot;You register your marriage with me now, write down my name in the house book, and I will marry you.&quot; Eat, or else you&#39;ll fall down.&quot; The uncle on the side blamed her for being too domineering: &quot;You have to have an emotional foundation before talking about these financial contributions, otherwise how can we call it love?&quot; Wang Hongzhen smiled and did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are always more people on Saturday night than on Tuesday, and the elderly don’t have to rush to pick up their grandchildren from school. After 6 o&#39;clock, the sky turned dark blue, the dance music at the end of the corridor was still playing, and the banquet had not yet come to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I met an interviewee who appeared on Chen Xiaonan&#39;s show &quot;Talk to Strangers&quot;. It was this program that unearthed the senior dating corner in Changpu River Park and exposed it to the media spotlight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This interviewee is not as high-spirited as in the show. He admitted that in the 6 years since the show was broadcast, he has been searching here and had several relationships, but he still has not found his ideal partner. He said, &quot;On Tuesdays and Saturdays, the Changpu River, on Thursdays, Zhongshan Park and Taoranting, and on Sundays, the Temple of Heaven Park. The same group of people go to every place.&quot; This has become a place where old people check in to work. Even if you can&#39;t find someone, it&#39;s better to spend time together than to be alone at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are all old people. Maybe one day, one of them will no longer be able to come.&quot; During the conversation, an old man suddenly tripped while going up the ladder. The interviewee and several younger people around him were relatively young. The elderly man hurriedly ran up to help him up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(To protect the privacy of the interviewees, the characters in the article are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt; br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt; /a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《老友记》钱德勒一生对抗毒瘾：美国“鸦片危机”有多严重？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260017]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 28, 2023, the actor who plays Chandler in the famous American sitcom &quot;Friends&quot; Matthew Perry was 54 years old and died of suspected drowning in a hot tub at his home in Los Angeles. Local law enforcement said &quot;no drugs were found at the scene and there were no signs of foul play.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case is still under investigation, and no drugs have been found at the &quot;scene&quot; yet, but this does not mean that there is no drug abuse background in this case. In fact, Matthew has been addicted to alcohol and drugs since the first season of Friends in the mid-1990s. In his memoir &quot;Friends, Lovers and the Big Terrible Thing,&quot; he said: He has been fighting drug addiction his whole life, during which he was near death twice, costing him as much as $9 million (equivalent to 65.85 million yuan). But he was still defeated in the end. At the worst point, he swallowed 55 pills of Vicodin (opioid analgesic) every day and drank 1 liter of vodka. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Very similar to this incident, on February 11, 2012, the 48-year-old American singer Whitney Houston suffered a heart attack due to a drug overdose at the Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, Los Angeles. After losing consciousness, he slipped into the bathtub and drowned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier, on June 25, 2009, American rock star Michael Jackson suffered a heart attack after his personal doctor Conrad Murray injected him with a fatal dose of propofol (a short-acting intravenous anesthetic). die. Prior to this, Jackson also used a large number of painkillers and anesthetics for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the banner of these big-name celebrities taking drugs, Americans are taking drugs and abusing addictive drugs extremely seriously. According to the classification standards of the National Center on Drug Abuse Statistics, there are eight main types of drugs: alcohol, marijuana, cocaine, heroin, fentanyl, methamphetamine (methamphetamine), opioids (controlled psychotropic substances), and prescription stimulants agent. The United States accounts for less than 5% of the world&#39;s population, but uses 80% of the world&#39;s opioids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): Among the approximately 280 million Americans aged 12 and above, there are approximately 31.9 million drug users. On average, 1 in 12 people takes drugs, accounting for 12% of the total number of drug addicts worldwide. On average, about 300 people die from drugs every day. Drug abuse kills 100,000 people every year, of which about 71,000 die from fentanyl abuse. The number of drug deaths is eight times that of Americans who die from gun accidents, far exceeding the number of Americans who die from AIDS, car accidents, and gun accidents. Of the total number of deaths, 70% were men between the ages of 25 and 54. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2022 report of the &quot;Joint Economic Committee of the U.S. Congress&quot; pointed out that the abuse of opioids caused nearly 1.5 trillion US dollars in losses to the United States, accounting for about 7% of the GDP that year. In 2022, compared with before the outbreak of the &quot;new crown epidemic&quot;, the United States will lose about 6.3 million labor force, about 20% of which are caused by drug abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter in terms of loss of life, economic loss, social security, moral corruption... the United States has fallen into a large-scale, long-term nationwide &quot;opium crisis.&quot; Unlike the disaster in the late Qing Dynasty from 1840 to 1842, the Americans&#39; &quot;opium crisis&quot; did not involve external force invasion. It was completely directed and acted by them: the youth group is the age group with the fastest growing number of drug addicts and the fastest growing number of deaths in the United States. 18 -The drug abuse rate among people aged 25 years old is 39%; among people aged 26-29 years old, it is 34%; and 70% people who have tried illegal drugs before the age of 13 have a clear trend of drug use at younger ages. This trend shows that traditional American values ​​are collapsing, just as Lee Kuan Yew talked about the dissipation of the &quot;American spirit&quot; in &quot;China and the World&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former deputy secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services said: The current drug and substance abuse in the United States is one of the most devastating public health disasters. This crisis is a reflection of the failure of multi-system supervision by the US government, and urgent, unified and comprehensive response measures are urgently needed. The National Public Radio (NPR) in the United States lamented that &quot;American liberalism&quot; has caused the tragedy of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;New Liberalism&quot; (New Liberalism), also known as progressivism, which has led to the proliferation of drugs, is an ultra-left ideology. It is diametrically opposed to classical liberalism. The freedom advocated by the latter is the right to act according to one&#39;s own will without interfering with the rights of others. There is no freedom without law. Private property is inviolable and everyone is responsible for their own actions. The freedom it advocates is: behavior without any restrictions and without any consequences, that is, &quot;do whatever you want, do whatever you want&quot;, and it is best for the government or society to pay the bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American liberalism has set off many &quot;progressive&quot; social movements in the West through sexual liberation, sexual indulgence, drug use, decadent literature and art since the 1960s. It has continued for decades to this day, leading to the gradual disintegration of marriages and families, the proliferation of drugs, and rampant crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The root cause of the &quot;opium crisis&quot; in the United States is difficult to eradicate. The U.S. police once said: If the strict anti-drug measures of Eastern societies were followed, more than one million drug dealers would have to be executed, all U.S. prisons would be emptied and the capacity would be expanded by ten. times, used for forced detoxification. But this is simply unimaginable in the United States and Western society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. Democratic Party government is engaged in &quot;conceptual innovation&quot;: if drug use is legalized and it is not considered a crime, then won&#39;t the drug-related crime rate drop? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, drugs are divided into &quot;hard drugs&quot; and &quot;soft drugs&quot;. Those with slightly less addictive and harmful effects, such as marijuana, are allowed to be used legally (for medical purposes) in 31 states in the United States. ), 10 states allow legal recreational use of marijuana. Then, Oregon passed &quot;Bill 110&quot; and became the first state in the United States to decriminalize the possession of &quot;hard drugs&quot; such as heroin, methamphetamine, and cocaine: possession of less than 1 gram of heroin, ecstasy, and less than 2 grams Cocaine, methamphetamine, less than 12 grams of psilocybin, less than 40 doses of hallucinogens, oxycodone, etc. will no longer be considered crimes and will instead be punished by a $100 fine or a health evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This concept innovation has &quot;remarkable results.&quot; The US &quot;Capitol Hill&quot; reported on August 28, 2022: A Gallup poll showed that the number of Americans smoking marijuana hit a record high, surpassing smoking for the first time. Number of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the phased strategy of &quot;hard drugs&quot; and &quot;soft drugs&quot;, the US pharmaceutical industry has also launched an &quot;opioid (opium) prescription drug&quot; strategy. Hill, director of the Robber Drug Rehabilitation Center in Ohio, believes that compared to other countries, Americans are more likely to choose drugs to relieve pain and release stress. The main driving force that contributed to the formation of this social culture was the &quot;most generous marketing campaign in pharmaceutical history&quot; that large American pharmaceutical companies invested heavily in in the mid-1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most typical one is that in 1995, the American &quot;Purdue Pharma&quot; promoted Oxycontin (OxyContin) developed by it and took the lead in launching the &quot;opioid harmless theory&quot; propaganda campaign. After its launch, Within six years, Purdue sponsored 20,000 missionary projects. Opioid manufacturers and distributors spent $880 million over 10 years on marketing advertising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opioid drugs greatly reduce the content of opium derivatives, and drug users take countermeasures to increase the amount of drugs they take. For example, Matthew, mentioned above, once swallowed 55 opioid analgesics every day, taking drugs in a &quot;curve&quot; way according to legal prescriptions prescribed by doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deep-seated social problems caused by drugs include: drugs cause damage to the brain nerves of drug users, cause psychological abnormalities and cognitive impairment, induce mental illness, aggravate emotional agitation, lead to family crises, violent crimes, Problems such as psychological trauma in children; violent disasters such as gang crimes and homicides caused by drug trafficking affect social stability and generate upstream and downstream crimes such as money laundering. At the social level, the proliferation of drugs has reduced the labor base of American society and affected the average life expectancy of the American population; at the spiritual level, drugs and the crimes they induce have destroyed traditional values, annihilated justice and conscience, destroyed morality, and unleashed the worst evil in human nature. A devastating crime that breaks down society, shakes the foundation of the country, and destroys the spiritual and ideological foundation of future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;opium crisis&quot; in the United States has become difficult to recover from and will continue for a long time. The proliferation of drugs has become a chronic disease that is deeply hated by traditional groups in American society, but it is difficult to truly eradicate it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被诬偷拍的人，不可逆转的伤害]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260001]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 23:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On November 3, the &quot;Chengdu Subway Framed and Hidden Photography Case&quot; opened for trial. In recent years, &quot;secret photography&quot; incidents have occurred frequently. Faced with the embarrassment of being publicly accused of secret photography and perversion, can those who are wronged have no choice but to swallow their anger? How should we defend our rights rationally?</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走，去大自然丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 22:00:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuw SokpK2C. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, members of the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition summit team were rushing to the summit&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /www.infzm.com/contents/259430&quot; title=&quot;Memory of Glacier: Sixty Years of China&#39;s Scientific Expedition on Mount Everest&quot;>;Memory of Glacier: Sixty Years of China&#39;s Scientific Expedition on Mount Everest&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past two years, I have often missed a world of yesterday that may not have existed. Just like Zweig described his father&#39;s generation, a generation blinded by idealism holds optimistic illusions, firmly believes that tolerance and friendship are indispensable binding forces, and sincerely believes that the boundaries and beliefs between various countries and sects are Differences will gradually be resolved through people&#39;s friendship, and the entire human race will enjoy the most precious wealth: peace and security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For various reasons, I have to face all kinds of people in my work and life, understand all kinds of ideas, communicate, get close, understand, and explain. And as my colleague M described it, I often want to &quot;withdraw from human society immediately.&quot; At this time, I will choose some topics that have nothing to do with humans, animals or plants, rivers or mountains. Whether elephants run away or floods occur, whether glaciers melt or forest fires occur, these all reflect the insignificance and stupidity of human beings, as well as their concession and self-rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was the original motivation for me to report on the scientific research on Mount Everest and the melting of glaciers. Simply put, even Mount Everest can detect DDT (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Organochlorine pesticides&lt;/span>;), even the East Rongbuk Glacier. After losing ground, shouldn&#39;t humans put aside their prejudices and differences for the Himalayas, a young mountain range that spans five countries, and trust and cooperate with each other? Indeed, in interviews, glacier researchers generally view the world as one. Facing nature and the universe, disputes and conflicts lose their meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although, global warming is not only about the environment, but also about fairness. The most vulnerable people and ecosystems have been disproportionately affected by loss and damage and are suffering from the adverse impacts of climate change that are disproportionate to their responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like the debate on &quot;rewriting literary history&quot; and the humanistic spirit in the 1980s and 1990s, the intention to strip away one&#39;s stance in literature is a stance, and the intention is to transcend conscious biases to record scientific work. Perhaps It is a conscious choice in itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In interviews in Lanzhou and Tibet, what unfolded before me was an open world, the endless treasure of the Creator. These scientists who are engaged in glacier research in western China love field scientific research, partly because they love freedom and pursue a free and unrestrained life. They can endure the hardship of being stationed at the foot of Mount Everest for ten years. This is because they are not stingy with their time and can feel the pulse of the earth. And the magnificent luck of Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was an interview in the evening. We were sitting on the playground of Lanzhou University. The interviewee told me that sometimes I sympathize with you big city people. With so much pressure, you will never be able to get out of the reinforced concrete city. forest. I suddenly thought of the birth of Impressionism: urbanites who experienced the industrial revolution began to dislike London, which was filled with industrial smog, and yearned for the countryside and nature. Later, born out of Impressionism, freer Fauvism, Cubism, and Expressionism were born. China has also completed its industrial revolution. Do Chinese people today also yearn for nature and countryside? Longing to leave the conflicts and struggles in the small environment or the big environment? Will this give rise to new cultural forms? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to concerns about global warming and glacier melting. The guilt I feel is that some people who study glaciers and sense the pulse of the earth have scientifically proven that human activities have severely harmed the environment. It seems that they are not concerned about environmental changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But recently, I read an exposition of Jin Guowei’s creation and felt somewhat comforted and even self-consistent. He is a world-renowned documentary director for his films such as &quot;Free Climbing&quot; and &quot;Thailand Cave Rescue&quot;. He said: &quot;I like to photograph the positive side of human nature, the qualities that can inspire us to become better. I have many friends who photograph human nature. The other side of the world is war, conflict, controversy. Obviously, I have not made a work on this theme. There are so many discouraging things happening in the world, which make people sad and angry. I hope to try to make something that can be related to I think this is the contribution I can make to the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>