<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[知名潜水员韩颋遗体已被打捞上岸]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259302]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 20:27:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;About Jiudun Skylight, Daxing Town, Du&#39;an Yao Autonomous County&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;One person&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Report on the search and rescue situation of lost contact during diving&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han, a well-known person in the diving industry After Ting lost contact while diving in Jiudun Skylight, Daxing, Du&#39;an on the evening of October 7, Du&#39;an immediately organized relevant departments and domestic professional search and rescue teams to participate in the search and rescue. At 18:33 on October 25, an underwater intelligent robot salvaged the body ashore, and it was confirmed that it was Han Ting himself. We are deeply saddened and deplored by this. At present, relevant accident investigation and aftermath processing are in progress. Thank you to the vast number of netizens for their concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Du&#39;an Yao Autonomous County Emergency Management Bureau&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 25, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首批博士诞生40周年启示录：不应仅是量的扩张]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259272]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/BPzHgFihCdHzGeLCnnQ5SVXaV4XQ3lwzvhmcV0He.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;799&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BPzHgFihCdHzGeLCnnQ5SVXaV4XQ3lwzvhm cV0He. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fudan University professor Ge Jianxiong is the first doctor of history in New China. (People’s Vision/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 27, 1983, 17 students walked into the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. They received 200 yuan in clothing fees in advance. One of them bought a suit specially, but he couldn&#39;t tie it, so he had to ask his instructor for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are the first batch of Ph.D.s in New China. Except for one who was doing postdoctoral research in the United States and did not attend, these 17 people received the &quot;Doctorate Degree Certificate&quot; with the golden national emblem at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reform and opening up, doctoral training started in a hurry, and the research fields of the first batch of 18 PhDs also highlighted a country&#39;s yearning for modernization. 17 of them were PhDs in science and 1 was a PhD in engineering. . &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;40 years later, the questions that confused Su Buqing are also asking more people. According to the &quot;2022 National Education Development Statistical Bulletin&quot;, 82,300 doctoral students will graduate in 2022, and 556,100 doctoral students will be studying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the 40th anniversary of the graduation of the first batch of doctoral students in New China. The birth of the first batch of Ph.D.s witnessed the development of China’s degree system from scratch. Nowadays, facing the huge group of doctoral students, further improving the quality of training has become a new development focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang, a professor at the School of Education of Central China Normal University, believes that doctoral education should not only expand quantity, but &quot;quality must be the lifeline of doctoral training.&quot; In his view, China has spent 40 years going through the path of exploration that other countries have taken for hundreds of years, and has formed a doctoral education system that is in line with China’s reality and is still gradually improving. “The 40-year development history of doctoral education is also a doctoral education system. A History of Educational Reform.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Twisted Exploration&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The establishment of China’s doctoral system has been full of twists and turns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, although there was a degree system covering bachelor&#39;s, master&#39;s and doctoral degrees, no doctorate was awarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang explained that although the system had been established, the country was poor and weak at that time, and the number of undergraduate and master&#39;s students was limited, which &quot;was not enough to support the development of doctoral education.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 1956, the seventh year after the founding of New China, the &quot;Degree Regulations of the People&#39;s Republic of China (Draft)&quot; were submitted to the central government for approval, dividing degrees into master&#39;s and doctoral levels. However, due to various reasons, the regulations were not formally promulgated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the exploration of the associate doctorate system is also underway. In 1955, the Chinese Academy of Sciences officially proposed to learn from the Soviet Union and establish an associate doctorate system, and announced the first batch of 65 admissions the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Soviet Union, an associate doctorate was second only to a doctorate, and was also called a &quot;candidate doctor.&quot; A doctorate was not obtained through postgraduate education, but was applied for after accumulating many years of work experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the &quot;First Five-Year Plan&quot; had been implemented, which clearly proposed the establishment of a preliminary foundation for socialist industrialization. Zheng Gang told Southern Weekend reporters that there is an urgent need for high-level talents in both industry and higher education. Under the background of learning from the Soviet Union, associate doctoral students came into being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this exploration also failed to continue. Soon after, the former Ministry of Higher Education issued a notice, &quot;It was decided not to use the name &#39;associate doctoral students&#39;. All associate doctoral students recruited last year (1956) will be called graduate students.&quot; More than a month later, it was decided not to award an associate doctorate. Zheng Gang learned that &quot;the vast majority of associate doctoral students who had enrolled at that time only received graduation certificates and no degree certificates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this are not only the influence of international politics, but also the difficulty of connecting the associate doctorate system with the mainstream international degree system. In addition, some universities recruit associate doctoral candidates who are not part-time workers, causing many university teachers and hospital doctors to have their work affected in order to obtain a degree. Ai Zhisheng, then deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Tsinghua University, once described him as &quot;ignoring what is going on outside the window and focusing on getting a doctorate degree.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the establishment of China’s degree system ushered in another opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 12, 1961, Nie Rongzhen, then Vice Premier of the State Council and Director of the State Science and Technology Commission, proposed to the central government “suggestions on establishing a system for degrees, academic titles, engineering and technical titles, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He elaborated on four reasons in his suggestions, including urging intellectuals to march towards the peak of science and culture, encouraging and promoting the rapid growth of a large number of young intellectuals, and accelerating the formation of China&#39;s strong scientific and cultural team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also believes that the implementation of the degree system is also an effective way to directly promote the development of science and technology, &quot;Because in order to give degrees, it is necessary to make academic evaluations of the research work of relevant scientific and technical personnel. Through this Academic evaluation can promote academic prosperity and improve the level of science and technology in our country.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eleven days later, in his speech on &quot;Promoting a Large Number of Young Technical Cadres&quot;, Deng Xiaoping proposed, &quot;It seems that we can&#39;t do it without a degree. You can make a plan first.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Benxia, ​​former director of the Office of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, once wrote an article recalling that at the end of 1963, the Ministry of Education received a call from the responsible comrade of the Science and Technology Cadres Bureau of the State Council. Deng Xiaoping had reviewed and approved the &quot;Degree Regulations (Draft)&quot; and reported Other leading comrades of the Central Committee circulated it and &quot;everyone felt very excited.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The excitement did not last long. Due to various reasons, the draft failed to enter the national legislative process and was once again shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to determine the award criteria? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1978, postgraduate enrollment resumed. Although the degree system has not yet been established, some schools have begun to train doctoral students with good foundation before admission and outstanding achievements after admission according to the requirements of doctoral students. Zheng Gang told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The practice of doctoral training is earlier than the system, which reflects society&#39;s eager need for doctors.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of students are taking the lead in pursuing doctoral degrees? Among the first batch of 18 doctoral degree recipients, 7 are from the University of Science and Technology of China. The article &quot;Some Experiences of the First Batch of Doctoral Training in Our School&quot; published by the Graduate School of the school in &quot;Degrees and Graduate Education&quot; provides more details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the seven graduate students at the University of Science and Technology of China as an example. Their average age is 34 years old, they have family burdens, some have not completed formal university courses, and their studies were useless after graduation, but their basic qualities are very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The University of Science and Technology of China realized that the seven graduate students were not admitted according to degree standards. &quot;Are they supporting and encouraging them to become doctoral students, or are they all indiscriminately restricted to the master&#39;s degree? This is a test of our Can we adhere to the principle of starting from reality?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While exploring doctoral training, the establishment of a degree system has once again been put on the agenda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 24, 1979, Hu Qiaomu reported to Deng Xiaoping on the issue of establishing a degree system, &quot;It would be a great good thing if the decision can be announced soon.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Benxia participated in the drafting work. He wrote that the drafting team collected archival materials from the previous two Degree Regulations (Draft) and investigated the development of foreign degree systems since the mid-1960s. A symposium was held to conduct on-site research on the current situation of higher education, and it took nearly 7 months to complete the first draft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 1, 1980, the State Council submitted the &quot;Degree Regulations (Draft)&quot; to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress for review. Wu Benxia attended the meeting as a non-voting delegate. &quot;Everyone unanimously raised their hands and applauded warmly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Degree Regulations&quot; are scheduled to come into effect on January 1, 1981. This is the first law in the field of education in New China, clarifying that degrees are divided into three levels: bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree, and doctoral degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the State Council approved the first batch of 151 doctoral degree-granting units, 812 disciplines and majors, and 1,155 instructors. Among the disciplines and majors, there are 265 engineering, 233 science, and 153 medicine. Shen Wenqin, deputy director of the China Doctoral Education Research Center at Peking University, told Southern Weekend reporters that the first batch of disciplines and majors are concentrated in basic fields and are urgently needed by the country. &quot;The selection of doctoral supervisors is also very strict.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming the first batch of doctoral degree-granting units, the University of Science and Technology of China wants to take another step forward and award doctoral degrees to graduate students recruited in 1978 who have reached the academic level of a doctoral degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 5, 1982, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council responded to the Ministry of Education and the Chinese Academy of Sciences, agreeing to provide doctoral degree course education and thesis defense for individual graduate students with higher academic levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, 8 units including the University of Science and Technology of China, Fudan University, and East China Normal University were approved for pilot testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the real problem for these schools is how to judge the criteria for awarding a doctorate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to make the opinions more representative, the University of Science and Technology of China hires up to 9 experts at a time when reviewing graduation thesis. When reviewing Li Shangzhi&#39;s paper, the opinions of experts were not unanimous. Three people believed that it had reached a doctoral level, and another one believed that it had reached a &quot;master&#39;s degree or above.&quot; Li Shangzhi then wrote two more papers, which finally passed the review smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/jJQqzvhOzZtwDScsCXl9N0nfnrzijZCdTBzvPhhZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/jJQqzvhOzZtwDScsCXl9N0nfnrzijZCdTBzvPhhZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Among the first batch of 18 Ph.D.s in New China, 7 are from the University of Science and Technology of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Who will train doctors? &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Who trained the first batch of PhDs? Since the establishment of the degree system in 1981, a method has been formulated and implemented for the unified review of doctoral supervisors (hereinafter referred to as &quot;doctoral supervisors&quot;) by a national organization. After five batches of reviews, 8,043 doctoral supervisors were approved nationwide, and by the end of 1993, a total of more than 14,000 doctoral supervisors had been trained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a doctoral supervisor qualification review process was once helpful in ensuring the quality of doctoral training, but it has gradually exposed problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhanjun, former deputy director of the Degree and Graduate Education Development Center of the Ministry of Education, once analyzed that with the increase in doctoral authorization units and doctoral authorization points, the scale of doctoral student enrollment has gradually expanded, and the doctoral supervisor review cycle is long, the procedures are cumbersome, and the positions are Shortcomings such as alienation are increasingly mismatched with the development situation of higher education, and &quot;the enthusiasm of higher education institutions cannot be fully mobilized.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The corresponding change is that in the 1990s, several batches of Ph.D.s mainly stayed in universities after graduation. Shen Wenqin told Southern Weekend reporters that they were already equipped to take over the academic field. Developing the capabilities of the next generation of Ph.D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Underlying the discussion on the qualification review of doctoral supervisors is the issue of &quot;unity over control&quot; of universities, which is directly related to the autonomy of universities in running schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 1993, the &quot;Opinions on Further Reforming the Examination Methods for Degree Authorization&quot; reviewed and approved by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council stated that doctoral supervisors should be determined by the degree-granting units themselves in accordance with the basic standards and conditions established by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, the power to approve doctoral supervisors will be delegated to all doctoral granting units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To solve the problem of who should train doctors, we must also solve the problem of positioning of doctorate training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical case is that because the medical doctors trained in China focus on experiments and scientific research training, there is a phenomenon that graduated clinical medical doctors are not qualified for clinical medical work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang said that society has diverse needs for talents. In addition to people who specialize in academic research, there is also a need for people to solve practical problems raised by society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, doctoral education ushered in another important change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April of this year, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council reviewed and approved the &quot;Several Opinions on Adjusting the Type of Medical Schools and Establishing Medical Professional Degrees&quot;, establishing a professional doctorate in clinical medicine for the first time, requiring a focus on engaging in a specific occupation. Practical work ability, with the goal of cultivating applied talents for senior clinicians, stomatologists, health and epidemic prevention, and new drug research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above opinions point out that this &quot;is conducive to the targeted training of various specialized talents with different natures and different professional backgrounds, and is conducive to the society&#39;s selection and use of various types of specialized talents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Fengliang, a professor at the Graduate School of Education at Tsinghua University, told Southern Weekend reporters that the landmark significance of this move is that &quot;doctoral education is developing in a diversified direction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, China has established six professional doctorate types: engineering, stomatology, education, veterinary medicine, clinical medicine and traditional Chinese medicine. According to statistics from the Ministry of Education, as of 2019, China has awarded a total of 48,000 doctoral professional degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There is a long way to go”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a doctor at the highest level of academic education, he must be able to deal with the practical problems that the country needs to solve most. “If a doctor can’t solve it, Who else can solve it?&quot; In Zheng Gang&#39;s view, the baton has been passed to the new generation of doctors. &quot;The burdens on them are no lighter than those of their predecessors, or even heavier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the number of doctors continues to increase, Against the background of growth, in 2007, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, the Ministry of Education, and the former Ministry of Personnel jointly launched a systematic investigation of doctoral training. As of that year, a total of 240,000 people in China had been awarded doctorates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After going deep into 289 doctoral training units across the country, 69,133 questionnaires were collected, and after interviewing more than 400 people, the investigation team recommended that the development scale of academic doctoral education be controlled and that academic doctoral education should shift from focusing on scale to Shifts that focus on quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this survey, new policies that focused on quality had already appeared in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1999, the then Minister of Education Chen Zhili proposed that not only outstanding doctoral theses should be selected, but also other theses should be randomly checked to ensure that the overall quality of Chinese doctoral degrees continues to improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2000, the Department of Degree Management and Graduate Education of the Ministry of Education has been responsible for conducting random inspections of doctoral theses. The evaluation content includes the innovativeness of the paper, the theoretical basis and expertise embodied in the paper, and scientific research capabilities. Since then, the number of random inspections has been increased. In order to achieve &quot;zero interference&quot; with the inspected units, degree-granting units are no longer required to submit thesis materials, but will be retrieved directly from the National Library after extraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it is stipulated that degree authorization sites with a high proportion of &quot;problematic theses&quot; or a large number of papers will be ordered to make rectifications within a time limit. If the requirements are still not met after rectification, the degree authorization will be revoked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council issued the &quot;Some Opinions on Carrying out Periodic Evaluation of Doctoral and Master&#39;s Degree Authorization Points&quot; and decided that starting from that year, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council would conduct regular evaluations of doctoral and master&#39;s degree authorization points every six years. Regular evaluation, the main content of the evaluation includes &quot;talent training situation, especially the quality of talent training.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Improving the quality of doctoral training is also reflected in the selection of students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, examinations were an important way to select doctors. Shen Wenqin told a reporter from Southern Weekend that candidates with scientific research talents or abilities are not necessarily good at taking exams. If standardized tests are used to screen talents at the doctoral level, &quot;the effect is not so ideal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the General Office of the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Recruiting Doctoral Graduate Students in 2017&quot;, proposing to promote and improve the &quot;application-assessment&quot; enrollment and selection mechanism, and strengthen the professional quality and academic level. , comprehensive evaluation of scientific research capabilities, innovation potential and overall quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;application-assessment&quot; system means that candidates no longer take the entrance examination uniformly organized by the school, but review materials such as academic transcripts, proposed scientific research ideas, and original research results. Afterwards, each department will assess the application through written examinations, experiments, interviews, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same year, many universities such as Nankai University, Harbin Institute of Technology, and Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications implemented this system. Starting from the 2023 academic year, the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences will fully implement the “application-assessment” system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back on the 40 years of doctoral education in China, from scratch to excellence, &quot;doctoral education has a long way to go&quot; and there are different problems and challenges at each stage. Zheng Gang said that these 40 years of exploration It proves that only &quot;reform can solve problems in the development process.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Reference books:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&quot;History of Graduate Education and Degree System of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&quot;40 Years of Implementation of China&#39;s Degree System&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[轻松筹回应“女童被咬”善款：未使用的所有善款全额原路退回]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259300]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 19:24:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 25, @easilychouweibo issued refund instructions stating that on October 23, the injured girl After being transferred out of the ICU, the situation is relatively stable. After communicating with the sponsor, Easily raised all unused donations and returned them in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/399b5d22ab896e0a0c40e1caf050c24d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;1108&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/399b5d22ab896e0a0c40e1caf050c24d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255520&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“新中国第一号”博士马中骐：做冲不走的“小砖头”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259255]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/P7xXNaTDXAkIna4pKxhQtqnW8vXDjgK9QLKN8EGj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;979&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/P7xXNaTDXAkIna4pKxhQtqnW8vXD jgK9QLKN8EGj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255315&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi is the first Ph.D. in physics in New China and the &quot;No. 1 in New China&quot; &quot;PhD. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi, a native of Hangzhou, Zhejiang, was born in Shanghai in March 1940&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1951 -1956, studied at Shanghai Shidong Middle School;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1956-1961, studied at the Department of Physics, Lanzhou University, majoring in theoretical physics , stayed at the school to teach after graduation;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1964-1967, studied as a graduate student in the Department of Physics, Peking University, and returned to Lanzhou University after graduation Work; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;From 1978 to 1981, he studied for the second time as a graduate student at the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and stayed to work after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;On March 4, 1982, the Degree Evaluation Committee of the Department of Mathematical Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences unanimously passed a resolution approving the award to Ma Zhongqi, a graduate student at the Institute of High Energy Physics. Doctor of Science degree. Ma Zhongqi became the first doctorate awarded a degree in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;In 1993, he was rated as a doctoral supervisor by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Retired in 2005. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Served as a researcher in Room 4 of the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, doctoral supervisor, member of the academic committee and director of the academic committee of the institute, China Member of the Society for High Energy Physics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/YcleIKlNGLrq5XGrFLHKlennKjtBLgG4hg4GQqU7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1268&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/YcleIKlNGLrq5XGrFLHKlennKjtBLgG4hg4GQqU7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi’s doctoral degree certificate. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sitting in a nursing home by Yangcheng Lake in Suzhou, 83-year-old Ma Zhongqi still remembers 40 years the afternoon before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 27, 1983, the first batch of doctoral and master’s degree awarding conferences in New China was held in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. In the venue, the upper and lower floors were filled with teachers and students from various universities. Ma Zhongqi was the only doctor sitting on the rostrum. He was &quot;extremely nervous&quot; to speak as a representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason he was selected to speak is most likely because he is the &quot;first&quot; among the first batch of doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Zhongqi comes from the Institute of High Energy Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. Qian Sanqiang, a nuclear physicist, then director of the Department of Mathematics and Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and a member of the faculty, issued his doctorate certificate. The certificate number is &quot;10001&quot;. New China Number one. Now, this degree certificate is collected by the National Museum of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PvhSs5QMiwrJaa2O2ggAxEZXIvchQDuFY3sKRytC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height= &quot;762&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PvhSs5QMiwrJaa2O2ggAxEZXIvchQDuFY3sKRytC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi at the defense of his doctoral thesis. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On that day, a total of 18 people were awarded doctorates. Among them, 6 are from the Chinese Academy of Sciences, 6 are from the University of Science and Technology of China, 4 are from Fudan University, and two are from East China Normal University and Shandong University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“One of the obvious characteristics of the first batch of graduate students who obtained doctorate degrees is that they are older, generally around forty years old.” In his speech at the scene, Ma Zhongqi mentioned age. At that time, Ma Zhongqi was 43 years old. It took him 16 years from his first graduate school to graduating with a doctorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, 16-year-old Ma Zhongqi entered the physics department of Lanzhou University and stayed at the school to teach after graduation. In 1964, the state mobilized on-the-job cadres to take postgraduate examinations. Ma Zhongqi was admitted to the Department of Physics of Peking University and studied under Hu Ning, a theoretical physicist and member of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. His studies were interrupted a year later during the political movement. In 1967, Ma Zhongqi returned to Lanzhou University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until 10 years later, in 1977, that the State Council approved the Ministry of Education&#39;s &quot;Opinions on the Recruitment of Postgraduate Students in Colleges and Universities&quot; and postgraduate education was resumed. In 1978, 38-year-old Ma Zhongqi was admitted to Hu Ning&#39;s graduate school again and entered the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Institute of High Energy&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have been holding back for ten years and cannot do scientific research. I am very anxious.” Ma Zhongqi said in an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. Due to his previous academic accumulation, this time he became the &quot;big brother&quot; of his classmates in the Institute of High Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 1980, at the 13th meeting of the Standing Committee of the Fifth National People&#39;s Congress, the &quot;Degree Regulations of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; was reviewed and approved, and three-level degrees including bachelor&#39;s, master&#39;s and doctoral degrees were established. The regulations have been implemented since 1981. The Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, the University of Science and Technology of China, Fudan University, Shandong University, and East China Normal University became the first batch of pilot units and began to train doctoral students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Zhongqi recalled that in August of this year, the organization talked with him and decided to select a group of graduate students with good foundations to become doctoral students directly. He was selected as a &quot;pilot&quot; and asked to &quot;write a high-level doctoral thesis as soon as possible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In four months, Ma Zhongqi completed writing his graduation thesis. On February 6, 1982, Ma Zhongqi defended his thesis in a classroom of the Institute of High Energy. The defense committee has a luxurious lineup, consisting of 7 top experts in the field of physics: the chairman is Peng Huanwu, the father of the &quot;two bombs and one satellite&quot;, and there are also 4 members of the academic department: Hu Ning, Zhu Hongyuan, Dai Yuanben, and Gu Chaohao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, Ma Zhongqi stayed at the Institute of High Energy and was engaged in theoretical physics research, focusing on group theory methods and their physical applications, until his retirement in 2005. In 1991, he was awarded the title of &quot;Chinese Doctorate Recipient with Outstanding Contributions&quot;. He has enjoyed special government subsidies since October 1992, and has won the second prize of the Chinese Academy of Sciences Scientific and Technological Progress Award three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Physicist and Nobel Prize winner Yang Zhenning commented that Ma Zhongqi&#39;s research results are &quot;work that can be retained.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s great to leave a hilltop like Mr. Yang did.&quot; Ma Zhongqi said that his work is like &quot;little bricks.&quot; &quot;When the flood comes, the sediment is washed away, but the &#39;little bricks&#39; can stay.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Assigned&quot; to study physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you were an undergraduate student at Lanzhou University, your chosen major was physics. How did you become interested in physics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1956, the central government issued a policy on developing the northwest and authorized Lanzhou University to go to Beijing, Shanghai, and Tianjin before the college entrance examination. Each high school selects students. I went to high school in Shanghai Shidong Middle School. Before the college entrance examination, the principal talked to me and asked me to apply for the Physics Department of Lanzhou University. At that time, the party&#39;s needs were my wishes. If I was asked to go to Lanzhou, I went without any objection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The major was also decided, and I was asked to choose physics. When I was in high school, I heard from my relatives who were in college that the physics department was the best and I could learn a lot. At that time, I wanted to study physics myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 60 students went to Shanghai in that session. We took the train to Xi&#39;an, and then chartered a &quot;stuffy truck&quot;. We got on the train in the morning and arrived in Lanzhou the next evening. As soon as I got off the car, I was hit by a gust of wind carrying loess. At that time, tap water was not yet widely available in Lanzhou, and there were still water trucks on the road, clanging and clanking to deliver water. At school, we lived in a bungalow with no glass, just paper windows. At that time, living conditions were very difficult, but the enthusiasm was very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is it going in school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1956, I studied hard in school for a year. It is a pity that since 1957, with the &quot;Ming Fang&quot; movement, anti-rightist movement, and then the &quot;Great Leap Forward&quot;, people basically stopped studying. I also saw wood, made steel, and carried loads at the waterworks. I didn&#39;t have enough to eat at that time, and I was reluctant to leave the canteen every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the school would show movies every night, telling everyone not to study and to rest. But everyone finally got the opportunity to go to school, and they all studied hard. Many people fell ill due to swelling from studying, and even after being admitted to the hospital, they continued to study. It was really hard to study at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What did you do after graduating from Lanzhou University in 1961? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduation, the school assigned me to stay at Lanzhou University as a teaching assistant, and the teaching task was very heavy. I taught 3 courses: mathematical methods, theoretical mechanics and electrodynamics, each of which required very high mathematics. There are a total of 240 students. I will correct every assignment. A pile of exercises is handed in every two weeks. When the assignments are handed in, I basically don’t leave the office for two whole days. I also have Q&amp;A classes 4 times a week, once every two hours, and I can’t stop talking. Before I even went to the classroom, students began to line up and surrounded me from all directions to ask questions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for doing laundry on Saturday night, there is no extra time left, not even time for watching movies. We were already &quot;996&quot; at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, I didn’t study well in my own classes, so I just got through in college. The three years I spent as a teaching assistant gave me time to learn the basics of physics in a down-to-earth manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1964, the state mobilized serving cadres to take the postgraduate entrance examination, and you went Graduate student at Peking University. Can you tell us about your experience preparing for graduate school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The condition for in-service cadres to take the postgraduate examination was that they must return to their original units after graduation. When I took the postgraduate examination in 1964, my employer decided to let me take the exam. Each teaching and research section of the school sent a teacher to take the exam, and the theoretical physics department chose me. I decided which school I should go to, and I chose the Department of Physics of Peking University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our theoretical physics exams are quantum field theory, electrodynamics, and quantum mechanics. You choose two of the three professional courses, as well as politics, Chinese, and English. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three years of teaching, I happened to have learned the physics department courses by heart. Basic knowledge can withstand the test, and when it is familiar enough, students will not be afraid to ask any questions. Therefore, sometimes good things turn into bad things, and bad things turn into good things. It’s hard to explain. When I took on the teaching task at that time, I had no idea that I would still have the opportunity to take the postgraduate entrance examination in 1964. When the opportunity came, I immediately went to graduate school. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Learn to &quot;do scientific research&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How is life as a graduate student at Peking University? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My tutor is Hu Ning, who is very good at teaching students. His training method is that he specifies the research direction, and the students find and read the literature themselves. Group meetings are held twice a week, and all students come. Anyone who has read the literature and is willing to report can report it - what new ideas does this literature have, what makes sense, what is wrong, and where should we start? Go ahead and develop your own ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the report, Mr. Hu will discuss it on the spot. If he thinks what you said is reasonable, he will organize a few people to study the issue in depth. Mr. Hu is very democratic, he will listen to our different opinions, and his discussion method is very free. I have been a graduate student for one year and have already published two papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What influence did Mr. Hu have on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have never done scientific research before, and I learned what it means to do scientific research from Mr. Hu. To engage in scientific research, you just have to have an idea, come up with something, and it is valuable. From then on, I also learned to do scientific research myself. At that time, our students were very conscious and fully unleashed their originality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that you studied for one year As a graduate student, what was the situation like at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After studying at Peking University for one year, he was sent to the countryside to carry out the &quot;Four Clean-ups&quot;. In 1967, when the fighting began at Peking University, I returned to Lanzhou University. At that time, the school&#39;s theoretical physics laboratory had been disbanded, the library was closed, and there was nothing left. The students are still there, but they are no longer studying. I give lectures to students at the Workers&#39;, Peasants and Soldiers&#39; College, starting from the most basic middle school mathematics of making negatives plus plus, one course a week, all the way to calculus. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Cultural Revolution, I was not involved in politics and never participated in it. I didn’t even write a single big-character poster. I study when I have time, and work the rest of the time. I am tall and in good health, and I am among the first to work. I&#39;m kidding. I am neither a driving force for revolution nor an object of revolution. I am just a commodity for labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Graduate student enrollment resumed in 1978. You were 38 years old at that time. How did you resume your studies? What about those who went back to school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1977, everything began to return to normal. For the first time in my life, I took a train to Dalian to attend a semiconductor research conference. On the way, I ran to Beijing to visit my mentor Hu Ning. Mr. Hu is very anxious. He is engaged in particle physics, but there are no students left and no one is engaged in it. He asked me if I still wanted to engage in particle physics. I said that the school’s theoretical physics department had been disbanded and I couldn’t do it if I wanted to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the central government had a red-headed document supporting &quot;returning college students.&quot; College students who enrolled in 1964 and 1965 only went to college for one or two years. The central government paid for them to return to school. Tuition for a year or two. Mr. Hu suddenly had a sudden idea and asked me if I would like to be a &quot;returning graduate student.&quot; Of course I do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1978, graduate students began to enroll students. The enrollment plan stipulates that the upper age limit is 35 years old. I was 38 years old at the time and could not take the exam. Mr. Hu contacted a group of old faculty members and proposed at the National Science Conference held that year that the graduate students admitted in 1964 and 1965 were of good quality but had not completed their studies, and they should be recalled as graduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, about 50 days before the exam, I saw a notice in a newspaper advertisement: graduate students admitted in 1964 and 1965 are not subject to age restrictions. After seeing this, I quickly signed up and chose the Institute of High Energy Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, where Mr. Hu also had an enrollment quota. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;就剩50天时间，怎么准备考试？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1978年考研究生，和1964年那次差别太大了。 1964年研究生非常难考的，但1978年考研究生，我的对手差太远了，我是正经的大学生，还上过研究生，业务也一直没放。 38岁当然年纪大了一点，但还是壮年，脑子反应还快着呢，考试是没问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这次读研，正好赶上是改革开放。你觉得当时社会环境的变化对你有什么影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;1978年,启动恢复研究生招生，这是邓小平主持的，就要广集人才嘛。从新中国成立到当时，组织的意见跟个人意见有矛盾的时候，我从来是以组织意见为准。唯一的例外就是1978年考研究生。如果个人要考，单位不放，以个人为准，这是以前从来没有过的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我憋了十年不能搞科研，急得很。有了这个机会，当然要拼命干。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4个月完成博士论文&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;第二次读研，和第一次有什么不一样？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;感觉完全不一样。都40岁了，还自己不会搞科研，还能干嘛？因为自己基本掌握了科研的方法，就自己选题自己做，每两个礼拜骑车到北大给胡先生汇报一次。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时别人都要上专业课，就我可以不上。我只用上政治课、英文课，还有我自己选的微分几何，胡先生给我课程成绩。他跟我说，“赶紧搞科研，学什么基础课？早就会了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在研究生期间是很特殊的研究生，大家都知道我以前当过研究生，而且我能够搞科研。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1980年，广东举办了一场粒子物理理论讨论会，有四五十位在国外当教授的华人参加，李政道、杨振宁都来了，在国内谁能提出学术报告，并且在大会上发言？我那时候有论文，交了论文后获得批准，可以参加。上台发言的基本上都是老师，学生很少的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;什么时候知道你要从研究生直接成为博士？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1981年，学位条例实施。 8月，组织上跟我谈话，要从研究生里找一批人直接当博士生。学校决定把我作为“试点”，要我抓紧写篇高水平博士论文出来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1981年，磁单极研究是个热门选题，杨振宁先生就在做这方面的研究。正好我在《复旦大学学报》上看到了谷超豪先生（数学家，中科院学部委员）发表的文章，他提出怎么用数学方法去研究磁单极理论。我一下子感觉到这是个可以选的方向。高能所专门派我去上海出差找谷先生。他审查后觉得我选题的想法、原则都很好。回到北京，我就用群论的方法，花了大概两个半月完成了计算。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;算好后，高能所又派我出差，去上海找谷先生审查我算的结果合不合理，水平够不够，能不能当博士论文。他一点头，我就赶紧回来写论文了。 1981年11月交稿，12月，学校就把这篇论文送给全国各地研究磁单极理论的教授审查，没有收到否定意见后，就通知我准备答辩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;还记得博士答辩的情况吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1982年2月6日，在高能所的一个教室里举行的博士论文答辩，也是第一场博士论文答辩。我的答辩委员会是最盛大的了。答辩委员会主席是“两弹一星”元勋彭桓武，答辩委员有我的导师胡宁，还有谷超豪、高能所粒子物理的权威朱洪元，理论物理所粒子物理的权威戴元本，他们都是中科院学部委员。另外，还有西北大学教授侯伯宇和中山大学教授李华钟，他们是当时粒子物理和磁单极领域最出色的专家。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;基本的工作就是重要的工作&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我注意到你的屋子里放了不少杨振宁的书籍、照片。他对你的学术生涯有什么影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;杨先生给我的影响太大了。 1984年，他邀请我到纽约州立大学石溪分校做访问学者。第一天见面，我给他汇报工作计划，我说还想继续在磁单极方面做研究，另外我提前做了准备，知道杨先生对量子力学很基本的一个定理——Levinson定理在做研究，我说我也想在Levinson定理上做工作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨先生给我说，磁单极跟着别人后面做做可以，但Levinson定理就不一样了，这是基本的工作。他说，基本的工作就是重要的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，他把他的文章和133页的计算稿给我，我花了两个月时间把那个稿子彻彻底底弄懂了。掌握了这个方法，我再去研究Levinson定理，把它的适用条件作了修改，并把定理推广到相对论情况。后来我就变成Levinson定理的权威了，回国后这方面的文章都叫我审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我就想，Levinson定理是杨先生给我的题目，我只是重新做了计算，写文章时我就打算跟杨先生合作，杨先生不干，还是让我一个人写。后来我才明白，他是爱护年轻人，如果这篇文章是我们合作发表，那人家肯定认为这是杨先生的文章，跟我就没关系了。他考虑得非常周到，给了年轻人很多机会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;杨振宁曾评价你的研究成果是“能留得下来的工作”，怎么看这个评价？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;“基本的工作就是重要的工作。”这句话是杨先生跟我说的，也是我的座右铭。我这辈子的科研都比较重视抓基本的工作。基本的工作，只要没算错，它就留下来了。像Levinson定理，我算得对就站住了，这个东西是我的，清清楚楚，上了教科书，这叫留得住的工作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果是赶时髦的工作，整个方向就错了，过段时间就没有了。就像磁单极，最后证明磁单极没有发现，所有磁单极的工作就报废了，这就叫作留不住的工作。现在文章99%都是留不住的工作，留下来的工作是很少的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为杨先生的教导，我就比较重视找基本的工作。有这样的工作我就非常兴奋，而且花大力气去做。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;近些年还在做什么研究吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;住进养老院后，我出了三本书，有一本《Group Theory For Physicsts（物理学中的群论）》是关于群论的，是我年轻时想解决的问题，但上班时比较忙，没时间做。现在我花时间把它彻底证明、推广了。今年2月份，我收到出版社寄来的账单，有人一下买了100本。这说明把它选成教材了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在1993年出版了一本《Yang-baxter Equation And Quantum Enveloping Algebras(杨-巴克斯特方程与量子包络代数)》，出版社每年给我发账单，每年都有人买。虽然数量不多，但是有。有跟没有是不一样的，说明这东西站住脚了，30年过去，还有人看这本书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得对现在的大学生来说，什么是最重要的？有什么建议吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马中骐：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我很幸运，我喜欢研究物理。别人开玩笑说，不给我发工资我都想搞，何况还有工资（笑）。我真喜欢物理，而且我只会干这个。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大学生应该多听一听，看一看，搞清楚自己喜欢什么，然后在这上面独立地钻研，不能光是玩游戏或者光是找工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[透视我国增发2023年国债1万亿元的深意]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;24日，十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议表决通过了全国人民代表大会常务委员会关于批准国务院增发国债和2023年中央预算调整方案的决议，明确中央财政将在今年四季度增发2023年国债1万亿元。增发2023年国债目的何在？增发的国债用于何处？万亿元的国债资金如何管理？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;为何增发：支持灾后恢复重建、提升防灾减灾救灾能力的必要之举&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;今年以来，我国多地遭遇暴雨、洪涝、台风等灾害，部分地区受灾严重、损失较大，地方灾后恢复重建任务较重。同时，近年来各类极端自然灾害多发频发，对我国防灾减灾救灾能力提出了更高要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中共中央政治局常务委员会8月17日召开会议，研究部署防汛抗洪救灾和灾后恢复重建工作。会议提出，“加快恢复重建”“进一步提升我国防灾减灾救灾能力”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些重点工作离不开“真金白银”的保障。财政部相关负责人表示，尽管年初预算已经安排了相关常规救灾和防灾减灾资金，但难以满足提升防灾减灾救灾能力的需要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在北京大学经济学院财政学系主任刘怡看来，叠加化解地方政府债务风险、保障“三保”支出等因素，地方通过自有财力大幅增加相关领域资金安排的余地较小。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“增发2023年国债，是党中央、国务院作出的重大决策部署，是践行以人民为中心发展思想的重要举措。”财政部有关负责人表示，以强有力的资金保障有关工作落实，集中力量支持灾后恢复重建和弥补防灾减灾救灾短板，整体提升我国抵御自然灾害的能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“从国际上看，不少国家也会在年中根据经济社会发展实际情况进行一些预算调整。”中国财政科学研究院研究员石英华说，根据今年我国的灾情，中央财政增发国债、调整预算，是务实之举，体现了财政加力保障重点支出的导向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何使用：增发国债将于四季度发行资金全部安排给地方&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据了解，结合灾后恢复重建和防灾减灾救灾工作需要，并统筹财政承受能力，中央财政将于四季度增发2023年国债10000亿元，并通过转移支付方式全部安排给地方。其中，今年拟安排使用5000亿元，结转明年使用5000亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中央财政增发国债，但具体资金使用全部都在地方，这有助于缓解地方财政收支压力，进一步优化了财政支出结构，也进一步优化了债务结构。”石英华说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;资金使用方面，据财政部介绍，将重点用于八大方面：灾后恢复重建、重点防洪治理工程、自然灾害应急能力提升工程、其他重点防洪工程、灌区建设改造和重点水土流失治理工程、城市排水防涝能力提升行动、重点自然灾害综合防治体系建设工程、东北地区和京津冀受灾地区等高标准农田建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“此次资金使用安排跨越今明两年，体现了政策的连续性。资金使用方向兼顾了当下和长远，在支持灾后恢复重建、保障民生的同时，还着力补短板、强弱项，加强抵御自然灾害的长期能力建设，有利于促进高质量发展。”石英华说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次增发的国债将在今年四季度发行。 “我们将及时启动国债发行工作。目前，财政部已对四季度国债发行计划作出调整，为增发国债留出空间。”这位负责人说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，国家发展改革委、财政部将会同有关部门，加强项目审核把关，尽快将资金落到具体项目。财政部还将及时下达国债项目预算，推动加快形成实物工作量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“国债资金投入使用后，也有利于带动国内需求，有助于进一步巩固经济回升态势。”刘怡说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;怎样管理：中央预算相应调整增发国债资金纳入直达机制&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在增发国债之后，2023年中央预算也作出相应调整。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，2023年中央本级支出不变，中央对地方转移支付比年初预算增加5000亿元；地方一般公共预算支出预算相应增加5000亿元，支出增幅由5.2%提高至7.4%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，财政赤字也相应增加。 2023年全国财政赤字由38800亿元提高至48800亿元，中央财政赤字由31600亿元增加到41600亿元，预计财政赤字率由3%提高到3.8%左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，中国政府负债率低于其他世界主要经济体。在刘怡看来，当前我国政府具有增发国债的空间，此次增发后风险整体可控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万亿元的国债资金，如何管好用好？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财政部有关负责人介绍，下一步，将充分利用直达机制，将国债支出资金全部纳入财政直达资金范围，实施全流程跟踪监测，确保资金按规定用途使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们还将组织财政部各地监管局建立常态化监管机制，盯紧盯牢国债资金使用，严查挤占挪用国债资金等违法违规行为，有效防范政府债务风险。”这位负责人说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京市委常委、副市长靳伟因北京长峰医院重大火灾事故被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259288]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:49:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;日前，经中共中央批准，中央纪委国家监委对北京市委常委，市政府党组成员、副市长靳伟在北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故中的失职失责问题进行了立案审查调查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;经查，靳伟同志作为分管卫生健康工作的北京市委常委、副市长，贯彻落实党中央关于安全生产的指示要求存在差距，对北京市卫生健康部门安全管理力量薄弱、医疗机构消防安全隐患突出的问题重视不够，督促市卫生健康部门履行“管行业必须管安全”职责、医疗机构落实安全生产主体责任不到位，对事故发生负有重要领导责任，应予严肃问责。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;依据《中华人民共和国监察法》《中华人民共和国公职人员政务处分法》等有关规定，经中央纪委常委会会议研究并报中共中央批准，决定由国家监委给予靳伟同志政务警告处分。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“要么赢，要么死” 加沙至暗时刻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:03:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“加沙很危险，但是哥哥坚持要回去。因为那里有他的妻子和4个孩子——最大的13岁，最小的只有1岁。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月23日下午，在广州工作的巴勒斯坦小伙沙里福把哥哥送到了机场。他的哥哥要从广州直飞埃及，待口岸开放时，寻找机会返回故乡加沙。在那里，军事实力占优的以军正开展猛烈打击。实拍的视频画面中，炸弹从天而下，许多房屋成了碎片和瓦砾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙里福告诉南方周末记者，回去是哥哥自己的决定，“他别无选择”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着巴以冲突升级，加沙地带正在发生一场人道主义危机。截至10月24日，巴以本轮冲突已致双方超7200人死亡。另据联合国儿童基金会24日消息，加沙地带有2360名儿童死亡，另有5364名儿童受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冲突爆发以来，以色列军方要求加沙北部居民限期迁移到南部，否则就会被视为“恐怖分子的同谋”。但是，仍有包括沙里福家人在内的众多巴勒斯坦人依然留在北方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据多家国际救援组织披露，10月21日-23日，累计有57辆救援卡车进入加沙。但对于超过200万的加沙人来说，这无疑杯水车薪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“到处都在封锁，我们如何离开？就算有人撤离，路上也会被空袭炸死。更重要的是，我们不想离开自己的土地。”沙里福说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;在沙里福的故乡拜特哈农，轰炸过后，居民房屋化为一片废墟。（受访者供图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在沙里福的故乡拜特哈农，轰炸过后，居民房屋化为一片废墟。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我在加沙看到了三次战争，这个最难”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月19日，沙里福与加沙的家人一度失联。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙里福的家在加沙北部小城拜特哈农（Beit Hanoun），这里靠近以色列，被称为“危险的地方”。19日当天，沙里福从新闻报道中看到家乡遭遇了轰炸。随后他多次联系家人，但对方的手机总是提醒，“不在服务区”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到6个小时后，沙里福才重新联系上他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了能更好取得联系，沙里福为父母购买了ESIM卡，“就像国际漫游卡一样，在加沙也能用以色列或者埃及的网络服务”。沙里福补充说，这样的卡不是所有时候都能收到信号。使用时，人必须要站在高处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙里福来自于加沙一个商人家庭。多年来，他和家人奔波于义乌、广州和加沙，做糖果、摩托车配件、家电等百货贸易。他和哥哥在广州生活、工作多年，哥哥的两个孩子还曾在白云区读书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚来中国不久，沙里福就让父母有朝一日一定要来中国看看。“我爸爸今年本来要来参加广交会。但是，战争改变了这一切。”沙里福说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争爆发一周，沙里福就失去了多位亲人——“我的叔叔和叔母去世了，他们的儿子和孙辈也不在了，整个家族一起消失”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;冲突开始一周，沙里福就失去了亲人，他的叔叔一家不幸遇难。（受访者供图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;冲突开始一周，沙里福就失去了亲人，他的叔叔一家不幸遇难。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，沙里福的家人也聚在了一起。他的父母、5个兄弟、2个姐姐，以及兄弟姐妹的孩子们，合计超过50个人。“一大家子已经离开了加沙北部的家，迁移到了&#39;不能透露&#39;的新地点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2008、2012、2014、2021年，加沙都曾经历过“战争”。但是这次似乎不一样。“我的家人告诉我，这次的轰炸不同于以往任何一次，声音听起来像是一种新武器。”沙里福说，“停止战争，这是救他们的唯一办法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样在加沙，26岁的年轻人伊斯梅尔正在担心一家人的口粮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月23日深夜，伊斯梅尔给关心自己的中国朋友安妮发了求助信息。他想向安妮借1000美元，还许诺“战争结束后还给你”。他和家人目前在一个位于加沙学校中的安置点，但救援机构给予的帮助有限。市面上的食物又少又贵，且需要用美元交易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;安妮告诉南方周末记者，伊斯梅尔曾在浙江一所大学留学，懂中文。两人在一场聚会中偶然相识。就在冲突前不久，伊斯梅尔还曾向她咨询，如何为高中毕业的弟弟办理来中国留学的手续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;安妮说，伊斯梅尔日常使用两个手机号，分属于加沙和以色列地区的运营商。这次冲突爆发后，加沙地区通讯设施大范围受损，伊斯梅尔通过以色列手机号勉强蹭网，这才与安妮取得了联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“联系上我的时候，他们一家正准备去家附近的避难点。因为他家没有汽车，一大家子靠步行撤离不太现实。”安妮说。当被问到近况如何时，伊斯梅尔用中文回复，“还没死”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月24日白天，筹好美元的安妮再次联系伊斯梅尔，但迟迟收不到回复。10月25日上午，终于收到了伊斯梅尔报平安的消息。据他描述，那里的战局“非常非常厉害”，“轰炸和爆炸的声音没有停止”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我以前在加沙看到了三次战争，这个最难的。”他写道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;救援处处掣肘&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“在加沙，我们从未设想过这样的情景：200万平民会在猛烈轰炸中生活，面临水、食物、电力和药品的中断。我们应立即采取一切措施来避免这种情况的发生。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间10月9日，红十字国际委员会近东和中东地区主任法布里奇奥·卡尔博尼在社交平台发声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在以色列全面围困两周后，有限的援助物资终于抵达。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据公开披露，当地时间10月21-23日，已有三批人道主义救援物资进入加沙地带，累计装运57辆卡车。其中包括医疗用品、用于水处理的消毒氯片等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这些物资对于加沙地带超过200万民众来说，实在是杯水车薪。欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔10月23日在卢森堡发表讲话称，在正常情况下，如果没有战争，每天有100辆卡车进入加沙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很明显，20辆（卡车），是不够的。”博雷尔呼吁，当前重要的是提供更多的人道主义支持。尤其要提供燃料的支持，这样才能使发电站和海水淡化站运转，从而尽快“恢复水和电力供应”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处（近东救济和工程处）发言人塔玛拉·阿里法伊也表示，加沙对于燃料的需求“就像对水和食物的需求一样迫切”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管国际救援机构一再警告，但以色列一方依然把燃料列入禁运清单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列总理高级顾问马克·雷格夫（Mark Regev）10月23日接受采访时公开表示，即使所有人质都被释放，以色列也不会允许燃料进入加沙地带。雷格夫就禁运理由解释称，“这些燃料可能被哈马斯窃取，用于为火箭弹提供动力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在各方矛盾难以调和下，加沙地区医院运转陷入困境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“死亡、破坏和流离失所的程度令人震惊。”10月24日，红十字国际委员会公共关系官员克里斯多夫·汉格（Christoph Hanger）接受南方周末记者书面采访时表示，该机构在加沙的团队实地探访了北部地区的医院。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们睡在医院的楼梯间里。数千人无处可去，在医院寻求庇护。建筑物的墙壁因附近的爆炸而摇晃。如果情况没有改善，没有清洁饮用水和拥挤的庇护所，疾病爆发的可能性就会急剧增加。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电力与燃料的短缺，让加沙地区的医院陷入困境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“没有电，医院就会变成停尸房。”克里斯多夫表示，加沙断电后，医院也停止供电。保温箱里的新生儿和需要吸氧的老年患者面临风险。肾透析中断，X光片不能拍。他指出，加沙的大多数医院已无法正常运转，他们需要电力来维持其服务。因燃料供应不足影响了发电，这让医院处境更加艰难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自加沙Al Shifa医院外科医生的报告显示，他们每天工作24小时来照顾伤员；当他们尝试对患者分类时，却发现无法应付大量的伤亡，“整个系统已经饱和”“所有手术室都被占用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“医生报告称，在之前的升级冲突中没有出现如此大规模伤亡的先例。”克里斯多夫说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月17日，加沙北部一座医院遭到轰炸，带来一定人员伤亡。加沙卫生部门和以色列国防部相互称对方为袭击者。联合国秘书长古特雷斯随后强烈谴责针对加沙医院的致命袭击，表示医院和医务人员应该受到国际人道法的保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另据巴勒斯坦红新月会10月22日披露，当天圣城医院附近遭到猛烈炮击。其公布视频画面中，袭击发生瞬间，身穿红新月会制服的工作人员紧急在墙壁、柱子、救护车等地寻找避难点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自这场冲突爆发以来，联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处已有35名雇员遇难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们无言以对。”近东救济和工程处10月23日在社交平台上发帖称，“我们向10月7日以来在加沙遇害的35名同事表示敬意。他们不仅仅是数字。他们是我们的朋友和同事。许多人是我们学校的老师。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“要么赢，要么死”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;冲突爆发后，以色列切断了对加沙地带的水电供应。10月9日，以色列宣布“全面封锁”由哈马斯控制的加沙地带，并动员了30万预备役军人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大战在即，以色列对加沙北部民众发出了一纸“驱逐令”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军10月13日凌晨向联合国通报称，已通知加沙地带北部约110万巴勒斯坦人，要求他们在24小时内撤离至加沙南部。14日上午，以色列国防军再发通告，要求加沙地带北部居民在当天上午10点至下午4点期间通过“疏散走廊”撤离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在印有以色列国防军标志的橘黄色纸质传单上，以军向加沙民众发出警告。其中写道：“任何一个不从加沙北部山谷撤离到南部的人，都可能被认为是恐怖组织的成员。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多名受访巴勒斯坦人向南方周末记者确认了这一消息。但他们认为，极短的时间里，不是所有人都有便利的交通工具离开。同时，撤离路上也并不安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在沙里福发来的视频中，坐着拖挂式大货车撤离的民众，在路途中遭遇了袭击。原本坐满妇孺儿童的露天厢板上，只留下残肢与鲜血。另一则视频中，行驶着小汽车、摩托车、驴车的撤离道路前方，突然升腾起炸弹的黄色火焰，车辆纷纷掉头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“实际上，加沙的南方、北方一样被轰炸。”沙里福说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古特雷斯在13日举行的安理会巴以局势闭门磋商前说，将超过100万居民从一个被彻底围困、人口稠密的战区迁往一个没有食物、饮用水和住房的地区，这是“极度危险的”，在某些情况下甚至“不可能”。他呼吁取消驱逐令，希望各方避免事态进一步升级和蔓延。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙里福告诉南方周末记者，即使边境重新开放，他的家人也不会离开加沙。“如果我们离开了，就会永远失去我们的家园，像1948年和1967年一样，我们不会重蹈覆辙。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;民众撤离之后，未能带走的牲畜留在废墟里。（受访者供图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;民众撤离之后，未能带走的牲畜留在废墟里。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在沙里福看来，以色列想强迫居民离开加沙……他们一步一步来达成目标，“首先是关闭边境，将我们从北部送到南部，然后叫我们离开加沙去埃及”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沙里福的担心并非空穴来风。巴以冲突升级后，美国总统拜登访问以色列时，美以共同提出把加沙人转移到埃及的提议，但埃及对此明确反对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们（以色列）以为炸掉所有面包店、医院和房子，人们就会离开加沙，四处逃走。但他们错了，这里的人们永远不会离开，要么赢，要么死。”沙里福说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;热莎（Rasha.G）住在约旦河西岸的巴勒斯坦地区，和丈夫、孩子一起做点儿巧克力生意。受加沙地区战事影响，这里气氛也变得紧张，“生意很冷清、人们没有什么事可以庆祝”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如她所说，某种程度上西岸比加沙地区安全，因为暂时“没有炸弹、没有空袭”。但热莎却有一种深深的危机感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;热莎告诉南方周末记者，在一次次巴以冲突中，有很多巴勒斯坦人向别处撤离，或者移居到邻近国家，比如埃及、约旦、叙利亚、黎巴嫩，或者移到约旦河西岸。但他们大都住在难民营里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你根本不能想象难民营的生活有多艰苦，狭小的空间里住着很多人，环境非常差。”热莎说，在巴勒斯坦，很多难民的教育只能依靠联合国近东救济和工程处。难民可以在巴勒斯坦找到工作，少部分可以做生意，但是在其他国家，这些难民甚至“没有被当作公民对待”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;热莎受过良好的教育，英文流利，在欧洲生活过两年。但她还是回到了巴勒斯坦。“我从没想过撤离，我不会离开家园然后去做个难民，我宁可选择去死。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;分歧&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;加沙地带的人道主义危机迫在眉睫，但关于是否停火开展救援，各方仍有分歧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至目前，西班牙、荷兰、爱尔兰、斯洛文尼亚和卢森堡等公开支持人道主义停火。爱尔兰外交部长迈克尔·马丁表示，“加沙迫切需要获得水、食物和医疗用品”“人类遭受的苦难是巨大的。我们必须区分加沙平民和哈马斯平民”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为欧盟国家的领头羊之一，德国没有响应停火呼吁。德国外交部长安娜莱娜·贝尔博克表示，向加沙提供援助固然重要，但针对以色列的大规模火箭袭击正在发生。“当加沙的恐怖主义持续存在时，我们无法结束人道主义灾难”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国国务院发言人马修·米勒于10月23日对媒体称，停火将“让哈马斯有能力休息、整顿并准备好继续对以色列发动恐怖袭击”。美国总统拜登也在同一日表示，只有在哈马斯释放所有被扣押的人质后，才有可能讨论加沙停火的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于以色列政府来说，早在战事之初，就展示了此次行动的目的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这应该是我们在加沙发动的最后一次地面攻势，原因很简单，这之后哈马斯将不复存在。”以色列国防部长约阿夫·加兰特公开表示，以色列将对加沙地带发动持续数月的地面攻势，旨在彻底消灭哈马斯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此背景下，巴以冲突持续进行中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据以军的最新声明，以色列国防军在10月23日空袭了加沙地带哈马斯组织的四百多个目标，包括其武装人员集结地、指挥中心以及一条通往海边的地下隧道，并打死了数十名哈马斯指挥官及其武装人员。以军还出动坦克、火炮和直升机，对哈马斯组织的军事哨所以及反坦克导弹发射阵地进行了打击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月23日，外交部发言人毛宁在答记者问时表示，中方对巴以冲突造成大量平民伤亡，人道局势急剧恶化，感到非常痛心。以暴制暴只会陷入恶性循环，当务之急是尽快停火止战。各方都应当切实遵守国际法和国际人道法，保护平民，全力避免发生严重的人道主义灾难。国际社会应当向加沙的民众提供更多的人道主义援助，缓解他们遭遇的人道灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，中方将继续支持一切有利于推动对话恢复和平的努力，为落实“两国方案”，推动巴勒斯坦问题得到全面公正持久的解决作出努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末记者顾月冰、南方周末实习生翟桓对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[温州实现数据资产“入表”第一单，万亿市场仍藏水面下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259268]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrTtK2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrTtK2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;数据交易所如雨后春笋般涌现。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者施璇/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据资产化迎来新进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月上旬，温州市大数据运营有限公司的数据产品“信贷数据宝”完成了数据资产确认登记。温州市财政局在通告中称，这是温州数据资产确认登记第一单，也是目前国内有公开报道的、财政指导企业数据资产入表第一单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;入表，是指将数据资源确认为企业资产负债表中“资产”一项，在财务报表中体现其价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信贷数据宝是基于温州政务区块链“数据资产云凭证”体系研发的，通过个人或企业授权后，为金融机构提供信贷业务相关的数据服务，简化申贷材料和流程，提高授信审批效率及银行核查精准度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年4月，数据被升格为与土地、劳动力、资本和技术并列的第五大生产要素，一系列与数据资产化相关的政策紧密出台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你在两年前问我，我会告诉你大多数企业对数据资产化一无所知。”如今，数据资产化已然成为热门话题，但据用友集团数据治理专家石秀峰观察，大部分企业仍未真正触及其本质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据资产化还存在什么困难？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;水面下的万亿市场&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“首先须明确，不是所有的数据都是数据资产。”国家发展改革委价格监测中心副主任王建冬对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照中国信息通信研究院（下称信通院）的定义，数据资产是指由组织（政府机构、企事业单位等）合法拥有或控制的数据，以电子或其它方式记录，例如文本、视频、数据库、传感信号等结构化或非结构化数据，可进行计量或交易，能直接或间接带来经济效益和社会效益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，只有能为组织带来价值的数据才是数据资产，其形成需要对数据进行主动管理并有效控制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵州数据宝网络科技有限公司董事长、华东江苏大数据交易中心总经理汤寒林向南方周末记者解释，数据资产化就是将数据资源转化为数据资产，其核心在于充分释放数据资源的价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，公共数据的开发使用和市场化运营还在探索中。2022年12月，《关于构建数据基础制度更好发挥数据要素作用的意见》（又称数据二十条）出台并提出，“推动用于数字化发展的公共数据按政府指导定价有偿使用，企业与个人信息数据市场自主定价相结合的价格形成机制。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石秀峰从企业发展的角度分析，企业在过去20年的信息化过程中，沉淀累积了大量数据。如今这些数据能够产生更大的价值，因此推动企业开始进行数据治理，实现数据资产的利用和价值最大化，最终实现企业的数字化转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信息化，指的是通过网络、计算机、数据库等信息技术，实现企业的业务流程管理和数据记录，如财务电算化、OA协同办公等。数字化则是用云计算、区块链等数字技术，实现对企业业务和管理的创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石秀峰在数据领域有超过16年的工作经验，业务涉及企业数据治理、数据资产管理、数据应用等领域的咨询和交付，曾主导传统制造、能源等行业中多个大型数据项目的规划和落地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石秀峰认为，目前80%的企业仍处于形成数据资产的过程中。王建冬表示，短期看，数据基础制度将催生3000亿-5000亿元规模的数据交易市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这千亿的交易会撬动背后万亿级市场。”王建冬说，进一步考虑围绕数据资产的评估、质押、融资等衍生市场，整个数据资产市场的潜在规模将超过10万亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他介绍，像土地等生产要素一样，数据要素也可探索使用分级治理。数据一级市场是对数据资源持有权和开放使用权的流转，数据二级市场是数据产品和服务市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“企业数据资产化的主体部分仍藏在水面之下。”王建冬解释，目前在社会机构拥有的数据中，只有一小部分进入流通交易环节，其它绝大部分数据均以各种形式在零级市场流通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;零级数据市场是指未进入交易环节，但发生数据共享交换和权益流转的市场行为，如在企业内部以及具有一定业务或股权关联关系的企业间。再如互联网企业内每时每刻都在发生数据的共享交换，但并不会对外交易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王建冬称，据初步测算，当前数据零级市场中的数据资产及其质押、融资等衍生市场的潜在规模是一、二级市场的30倍-60倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;先占一个位置&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“高层热，基层冷。”资深数据行业人士程果向南方周末记者形容当下的数据资产化进程。他曾多次参与企业调研和行业规则的制定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在程果看来，本轮国务院机构改革，唯一新设立的副部级国家局就是国家数据局。该局隶属于发改委，和国家粮食局及国家能源局并列，足以说明高层将数据视为核心战略资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月25日上午，国家数据局正式挂牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多项相关政策的出台，也促使数据交易所的筹备建设掀起新一轮热潮。2020年四季度后，数据交易所如雨后春笋般涌现，山西、上海、深圳、福建等地均在其列。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信通院发布的《数据要素白皮书》显示，截至2023年8月，全国已先后成立了53家数据交易机构，仅2023年1月至8月，国内就新成立了5家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但总体来看，早期建设的数据交易机构大都没有找到成功的商业模式，多数已停止运营或转变经营方向，发展未及预期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汤寒林所在的华东江苏大数据交易中心（下称华东数交）成立于2015年，是国内最早建成的数据交易机构之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他坦率地说，以前没有明确规定数据交易一定要走场内交易所，华东数交更多起到公告平台的作用——让供需双方更好地了解对方，以促成双方线下交易为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在程果看来，数据资产化的重要性已在国家层面得到强调，但地方政府还比较迷茫。“他们（地方政府）的想法是，虽然我还看不明白这个新东西，但我先占一个位置。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月，深圳数据交易有限公司成立，之后在其基础上组建了深圳数据交易所（下称深数所）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“深数所前几年的工作重点都不是提高交易额，而是培育市场生态。”2022年9月底，深数所副总经理王冠在一次会议中透露，深圳数据交易市场无论是在交易额还是在交易活跃度上，都已领跑全国。但市场供需不太平衡，供给方相对较少，需求方又很多，同时第三方服务机构和数据商的数量也不丰富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“高质量的数据产品供给是最关键的。”上海数据交易所（下称上数所）副总经理韦志林向南方周末记者强调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年11月底，上数所几乎与深数所同时成立。其目标明确，以“构建数据要素市场、推进数据资产化进程”为使命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韦志林透露，截至目前，上数所挂牌超1600个数据产品，月交易额已超一亿元，预计2023年全年交易额突破10亿元。上数所目前重点提供金融、航运交通和贸易等领域的数据产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，金融业数据交易市场存在时间较长，交付产品和金融方式更加成熟，是数据密集型行业。近五年来，金融业数据要素采购项目数量复合年增长率达40%，远超金融业采购总项目数量复合年增长率26%，显示出金融业数据交易市场规模发展迅速。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但韦志林也坦陈，当前整个数据要素市场场内交易的规模占比相对较小。“场内交易的建设至关重要，其在合规、可信、效率和资产化方面的作用不可替代。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;896&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年5月6日，天津滨海新区，一名行人从筹备中的北方大数据交易中心前走过。视觉中国/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王建冬表示，数据资产化未来的发力方向之一是鼓励企业尽可能多地进场交易，通过场内交易实现对其数据资产价值的确认，让交易所内形成的价格成为对数据资产估价的“锚”，这样交易所也会活跃起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“相当于企业入场不是只为了挣交易那笔钱，而是通过交易得到资产增值的机会。”王建冬解释，企业数据资产价值得到市场认可，在后续实现资本化操作，企业才有更大积极性参与场内交易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汤寒林相信，对企业数据资产入表的要求，会推动数据交易市场发生很大改善，今后供需双方会更希望通过场内交易对数据资产形成一套公允的价格体系，这样才便于估价并入表。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;确权难题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年8月和9月，财政部和中评协先后就数据资源入表和数据资产的评估发布相关文件，分别为《企业数据资源相关会计处理暂行规定》（下称《暂行规定》）和《数据资产评估指导意见》（下称《指导意见》）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两套文件一出，竞天公诚律师事务所合伙人、数据法律专家袁立志立刻接到了客户的咨询。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“会计师、审计师和评估师都希望我们律师能先出一份法律意见，作为企业数据资产入表或资产评估的基础。”袁立志对南方周末记者说，他们担心的根本原因在于数据资产的权属无法得到确认。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;业内普遍认为，实现数据资产化有三大环节也是三大挑战，分别为法律角度的数据资产确权、市场角度的数据资产估值与交易和会计角度的数据资产入表。其中，数据资产的确权是一切的前提。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在数据生产、流通、使用等过程中，个人、企业、社会、国家等相关主体对数据有着不同利益诉求，且呈现复杂共生、相互依存、动态变化等特点，传统权利制度框架难以突破数据产权困境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据二十条提出，建立数据资源持有权、数据加工使用权、数据产品经营权“三权分置”的数据产权制度框架，淡化所有权、强调使用权。在一定程度上破解了数据资产确权难题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王建冬表示，“三权分置”提供了一条解决问题的基本思路。目前在技术上对数据资产登记确权已无根本性障碍，而具体实施中的难点在于缺乏上位法的支持。如证券法之于证券登记，物权法之于不动产登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中华人民共和国民法典》第一百二十七条规定，“法律对数据、网络虚拟财产的保护有规定的，依照其规定”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前与之相关的法律法规，如个人信息保护法、数据安全法和网络安全法等，更多从数据安全和隐私保护的角度入手，均未对数据确权作出明确规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袁立志介绍，在实际案例中，由于涉及的利益相关方较多，企业在开发及利用数据资产时或会碰到从各种角度提出的利益诉求，如个人信息保护、不正当竞争、商业秘密、知识产权、合同债权等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果在调研时发现，在此情况下，一些企业对于其数据资产入表也显现出顾虑。入表，意味着企业要接受严格审计，但目前许多企业很难说清其数据真正的权属。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，上述《暂行规定》和《指导意见》只是对现存相关规则的细化规范，“并没有突破现有的财务会计制度”。在袁立志看来，产权制度是市场交易的前提。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袁立志表示，在出正式的法律文件时，律师们对数据资产合法性的判断已相对成熟，对其权属的认定则会比较谨慎。“尤其在涉及第三方权益时，我们会根据一般的法律原理作出判断，但会保留意见”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关部门在出台规定时显然也意识到了其中难点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果将《暂行规定》称为对数据资产的“小入表”。原因在于该文件并未针对所有数据资产，而是根据数据资源是否符合《企业会计准则——基本准则》中资产的确认条件，将其分为满足条件可“入表”的数据资源和不满足条件的“不入表”的数据资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，《暂行规定》是未来适用法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果表示，一些企业在数据资产化的投入主要在前期，之后每年仅进行规律性的小部分投入，其入表的数据资产仅以新增投入为基础计算，不会对企业的资产规模产生太大影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;另辟蹊径&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;短时间内，确权难题无法解决，市场主体也开始另辟蹊径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韦志林看来，数据产权“三权”中数据产品的经营权，解决的便是所谓的确权难、定价难，包括数据的监管问题。在此基础上，上数所提出“数据产品”的概念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韦志林称，只有将数据按照一定的需求和应用场景组织加工成数据产品，才能形成有需求和供应关联的市场。这样，才能建立起相应的交易规则、标准制度、技术、生态和监管等流通交易体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，如果流通交易的是原始数据，将会涉及数据的安全和确权等目前难以破解的问题，而“数据产品”概念的提出，很好地解决了数据的权属问题。将企业持有的原始数据加工形成的数据产品，赋予企业确定数据产品的权利，基于数据产品，企业可以享受该数据产品的经营权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前有媒体报道，在建设具体的数据产权制度方面，知识产权制度是唯一正在试点实践中的制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海对外经贸大学法学院讲师高阳曾公开表示，知识产权作为保护无形资产财产权的制度，适用于数据具有正当性。数据经过人类创造性智力劳动方能获得较高经济价值，符合知识产权保护智力成果的范畴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高阳在上述采访中说，通过对满足条件的数据授予知识产权，为数据交易主体提供明确指引，提高了数据交易的安全性及效率，进而激励企业数据产品创新，以解决市场中数据产品供给不足的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汤寒林同样认可知识产权制度在数据确权中的应用。2023年4月，江苏省知识产权局出台《江苏省数据知识产权登记管理规则（试行）》，华东数交是江苏省数据知识产权试点单位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他透露，华东数交已经和江苏省知识产权局直接打通。“我们的数据交易商在交易所提交数据产品后，可以直接经由江苏省知产局审核，进行在线确权，由此完成一个确权的闭环服务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《新华日报》报道，2023年10月中旬，江苏省联合征信有限公司（下称联合征信）研发的一款数据产品“企业批量查询”，在交通银行江苏省分行获得质押融资1200万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合征信是经江苏省政府批准设立的金融科技公司，是获得了央行备案的征信机构。“企业批量查询”是联合征信在对数据清理加工的基础上，通过四十多个维度指标建构模型，最终形成的企业信息查询类数据产品，主要用于反映企业信用状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述报道称，作为全国数据知识产权工作地方试点，江苏省于2023年5月颁发第一批数据知识产权登记证书。截至10月11日，江苏省已有125笔数据知识产权登记，已实现数据知识产权质押融资额五千余万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在数据资产的价值评估方面，王建冬一直呼吁，在国家未来的数据资产登记平台中，应该包含数据溯源功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这意味着企业需说明其数据资产在形成过程中每一个环节上的数据来源。通过这样的方式，可以更加公正地评估该数据资产未来的价值潜力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随着数据资产入表和实现有效评估，企业在会计报表上有了表达，就有了实体经济活动的支撑。”韦志林认为，数据资产化的进程在入表的基础上，一定会取得更大的突破和创新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他总结，数据资产创新应用主要有六大方向，包括数据资产入表、数据资产增信、数据资产质押融资、数据资产保理、数据资产作价入股以及数据资产证券化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者通过电话约访温州市财政局并发送采访函，对方婉拒了采访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，程果为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查报告公布]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259282]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:08:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年4月18日12时50分，北京市丰台区靛厂新村291号北京长峰医院发生重大火灾事故，造成29人死亡、42人受伤，直接经济损失3831.82万元。日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。经国务院事故调查组调查认定，这是一起因事发医院违法违规实施改造工程、施工安全管理不力、日常管理混乱、火灾隐患长期存在，施工单位违规作业、现场安全管理缺失，加之应急处置不力，地方党委政府和有关部门职责不落实而导致的重大生产安全责任事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故发生后，党中央、国务院高度重视。习近平总书记立即作出重要指示，要求全力救治受伤人员，妥善做好遇难者善后和家属安抚工作，并尽快查明火灾事故原因，依法严肃追究责任。强调各地区和有关部门要时刻绷紧安全生产这根弦，切实把安全生产责任落到实处，加强安全管理，彻底排查各种风险隐患，坚决防范遏制重大安全事故发生。李强总理等领导同志作出重要批示，对善后处置、事故调查、专项整治等工作提出明确要求。北京市立即组织抢险救援、伤员救治和善后处置等工作。应急管理部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局等部门立即调度部署，并派工作组赶赴现场指导应急处置工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4月21日，北京市人民政府成立事故调查组开展调查工作，国务院安委会对该起事故查处实行挂牌督办。鉴于该起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，依据有关法律法规规定，经国务院批准，成立由应急管理部牵头，公安部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局、全国总工会和北京市人民政府参加的国务院北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”火灾事故调查组，在北京市前期工作基础上，对该起事故进行提格调查。事故调查组按照科学严谨、依法依规、实事求是、注重实效的原则，通过现场勘验、调查取证、视频分析、检测鉴定、模拟实验、专家论证等，查清了事故经过、发生原因、人员伤亡、直接经济损失和有关单位情况，查明了地方党委政府、有关部门和单位存在的问题和责任，总结分析了事故主要教训，提出了整改和防范措施建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组查明，事故直接原因是北京长峰医院改造工程施工现场，施工单位违规进行自流平地面施工和门框安装切割交叉作业，环氧树脂底涂材料中的易燃易爆成分挥发、形成爆炸性气体混合物，遇角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花发生爆燃；引燃现场附近可燃物，产生的明火及高温烟气引燃楼内木质装修材料，部分防火分隔未发挥作用，固定消防设施失效，致使火势扩大、大量烟气蔓延；加之初期处置不力，未能有效组织高楼层患者疏散转移，造成重大人员伤亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查查清事故暴露的主要问题是医院主体责任严重不落实，施工单位违规动火交叉作业，地方党委政府防范化解重大风险意识薄弱，医疗卫生机构行政审批和安全管理短板明显，建设工程安全监督管理存在漏洞，消防安全风险防控网不严密等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组按规定将调查中发现的地方党委政府及有关部门公职人员履职方面存在的问题等线索及相关材料，移交中央纪委国家监委追责问责审查调查组。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对事故中暴露的问题，事故调查组总结了五个方面的主要教训：防范化解重大风险意识薄弱，医疗卫生行业行政审批和安全管理不严格，建设工程规划、施工安全监管存在短板漏洞，消防监督检查和专项整治不深入，初期应急处置能力不足。同时，提出五项整改和防范措施建议：切实扛起防范化解重大风险政治责任，着力补齐医疗卫生机构安全管理短板，坚决堵塞建设工程安全监督管理漏洞，全面织牢织密消防安全风险防控网，加快提升基层一线应急处置能力和水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院事故调查组相关负责人就北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查工作答记者问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:16:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。记者就该事故调查中社会关注的热点问题，采访了事故调查组相关负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：国务院事故调查组是怎样组成的？调查的过程如何？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故发生后，党中央、国务院高度重视。 4月21日，北京市人民政府成立事故调查组开展调查工作，国务院安委会对该起事故查处实行挂牌督办。鉴于该起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，依据有关法律法规规定，经国务院批准，成立由应急管理部牵头，公安部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局、全国总工会和北京市人民政府参加的国务院北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”火灾事故调查组，在北京市前期工作基础上，对该起事故进行提格调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组认真贯彻落实习近平总书记重要指示批示精神和党中央、国务院决策部署，按照科学严谨、依法依规、实事求是、注重实效的原则，通过现场勘验、调查取证、视频分析、检测鉴定、模拟实验、专家论证等，查清了事故经过、发生原因、人员伤亡、直接经济损失和有关单位情况，查明了地方党委政府、有关部门和单位存在的问题和责任，总结分析了事故主要教训，提出了整改和防范措施建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查认定，这是一起因事发医院违法违规实施改造工程、施工安全管理不力、日常管理混乱、火灾隐患长期存在，施工单位违规作业、现场安全管理缺失，加之应急处置不力，地方党委政府和有关部门职责不落实而导致的重大生产安全责任事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：事故发生的主要原因是什么？为何会造成大量人员伤亡？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故调查组通过视频分析、现场勘验、检测鉴定及模拟实验分析，认定事故直接原因是北京长峰医院改造工程施工现场，施工单位违规进行自流平地面施工和门框安装切割交叉作业，环氧树脂底涂材料中的易燃易爆成分挥发、形成爆炸性气体混合物，遇角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花发生爆燃；引燃现场附近可燃物，产生的明火及高温烟气引燃楼内木质装修材料，部分防火分隔未发挥作用，固定消防设施失效，致使火势扩大、大量烟气蔓延；加之初期处置不力，未能有效组织高楼层患者疏散转移，造成重大人员伤亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组对起火原因、火灾蔓延原因、人员伤亡原因进行了逐一分析。起火原因方面，北京长峰医院南配楼三层ICU改造工程施工现场，作业人员开展自流平地面施工和净化门门框安装切割动火时，违规交叉作业；自流平地面施工涂刷的环氧树脂底涂材料中易燃易爆成分挥发，加之现场未保持有效通风，形成爆炸性气体混合物，且浓度达到爆炸下限；角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花，遇爆炸性气体混合物引起爆燃，并引燃西北门外坡道下方堆放的可燃物。火灾蔓延原因方面，爆燃发生后，作业人员未将现场形成的多处火点全部扑灭且未第一时间报警，事发医院工作人员发现火情后也未第一时间报警，未有效组织初期火灾扑救，固定消防设施失效，自动喷水灭火系统和消火栓系统管网无水，未能有效控制火势；坡道和医院通道墙面采用木质装修材料、施工区域与非施工区域未按规定采用不燃材料进行防火分隔，导致明火蔓延至东楼主体建筑内；部分管道竖井未进行防火封堵且未设置防火门，部分楼梯间防火门闭门器损坏无法正常关闭，北通道五层东侧楼梯间常闭式防火门未保持关闭状态，南通道六层西侧楼梯间防火门上方石膏板隔墙被烧穿，导致烟气蔓延扩散。人员伤亡原因方面，未能及时转移疏散、吸入含一氧化碳的烟气是造成大量人员伤亡的主要原因。火灾初期事发医院未启动应急预案，未有效组织疏散转移被困人员；病区设置不合理，事发医院将行动不能自理或行动不便的患者集中安置在七层、八层等高楼层，大部分患者无自主逃生能力；危重病患者移动难度大，楼内通道狭窄、转移条件差，救援转移困难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：涉事医院及相关单位存在哪些违法违规行为？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;调查发现，涉事医院、施工单位存在诸多违法违规行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主要有以下方面：一是医院主体责任严重不落实。长峰医院公司违反医疗机构管理规定，未按照要求进行床位数变更登记、医护配比不符合规定，住院部公共走道宽度1.4米，明显小于规范要求的至少2.1米；未履行建筑施工法定义务和施工现场安全管理职责，2017年以来陆续进行的38个装修改造类施工项目均未按规定向相关部门申请办理施工许可或向街道乡镇申请办理开工登记手续，未发现并制止ICU改造工程现场违规动火、交叉作业行为；未按规定履行消防安全主体责任，符合界定标准但未进行消防安全重点单位申报，未对消防设施、器材定期组织维修，火灾自动报警系统、自动喷水灭火系统、室内消火栓系统未保持完好有效。二是施工单位违规动火交叉作业。中源信诚公司施工现场安全管理缺失，作业人员在未办理动火审批手续违规进行明火作业、现场无人监护、未对现场可燃物进行清理的情况下，使用角磨机进行切割作业；未针对易燃易爆物品制定防火安全措施，违规在作业场所调料；环氧树脂自流平地面施工与净化门安装交叉作业；未保持建筑业企业资质许可条件，且未按规定设立安全生产管理机构并配备专职安全生产管理人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故中地方党委政府和有关部门存在哪些问题？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故调查组查明了地方党委政府和有关部门职责落实方面存在的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是地方党委政府防范化解重大风险意识薄弱。北京市丰台区未认真履行安全生产属地管理责任，对街道乡镇基层安全监管能力建设重视不够，2022年全市安全生产和消防工作考核排名倒数第一，未有效组织开展建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查，事故信息报送不及时、伤亡人员情况报告迟缓。北京市安全发展理念不够牢固，对相关部门未认真落实属地医疗机构、施工现场等重点场所安全生产和消防安全管理职责的问题失察，未有效督促指导丰台区委、区政府严格落实属地安全生产管理责任。二是医疗卫生机构行政审批和安全管理短板明显。丰台区卫生健康委未严格履行医疗机构校验管理职责，对北京长峰医院长期未按规定申请床位数变更登记、人员配备不符合要求等问题监管不力，未履行对北京长峰医院ICU改造工程无施工许可的行业监督管理职责，未检查发现工程存在的消防问题隐患，未通过正式渠道向丰台区委、区政府和区应急办报告事故伤亡人员信息。北京市卫生健康委未认真履行“管行业必须管安全”安全监管职责，对丰台区卫生健康委履行行业安全监管职责不力等问题失察失管；指导落实北京市医疗机构消防安全组团体检式检查、建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查要求不力，未有效推进隐患整改工作。三是建设工程安全监督管理存在漏洞。丰台区住房城乡建设委未认真履行行业安全监管职责，对不具备取得施工许可的建设工程监管不力；未对移交街道乡镇管理的限额以下建设工程进行有效业务指导和服务配合；对限额以上的北京长峰医院ICU改造工程未取得施工许可证的行为，未依法依规予以查处。北京市住房城乡建设委落实建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查要求不力；未按要求对建筑业企业资质进行动态监管，对施工单位未保持建筑业二级资质许可条件的问题失察失管。四是消防安全风险防控网不严密。当地消防部门未认真履行消防监督管理职责，日常消防监督检查和消防安全专项整治不扎实。丰台区消防救援支队（原丰台区公安消防支队）2012年对北京长峰医院东楼内部装修工程进行消防验收时，在未检查管道竖井封堵完整性、未对建筑内部装修防火等进行评定，以及在消防用电设备未采用专用供电回路的情况下，违规出具验收合格评定结论；长期以来未将北京长峰医院确定为消防安全重点单位。北京市消防救援总队指导落实北京市医疗机构消防安全组团体检式检查、建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查工作不力，未有效推进隐患整改工作。此外，国务院事故调查组还查明，北京市规划和自然资源委员会丰台分局未认真履行制止和查处违法建设职责，未及时发现并查处北京长峰医院部分建筑未办理建设工程规划许可证违法行为；丰台区应急办在首次获知事故信息后4小时24分才正式报告，违反北京市应急值守工作有关规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故暴露出哪些深层次的教训？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;这起事故教训十分深刻，暴露出当地消防安全存在诸多突出问题和明显短板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是防范化解重大风险意识薄弱。一些领导干部对本地区存在的重大风险认识不足，没有及时发现并有效防控重大风险，也没有把他人的教训当作自己的教训，对相关重特大火灾事故暴露出的违规动火或电焊作业问题没有引起足够重视。这些问题根本原因在于，学习贯彻习近平总书记关于防范化解重大风险的重要论述不认真不深刻，没有结合实际认真研究和排查本地区风险隐患。二是医疗卫生行业行政审批和安全管理不严格。丰台区卫生健康部门工作作风不实不细，审批许可流于形式，1998年以来先后对事发医院校验18次，在病床数量成倍增加却未变更登记、医护配比不符合要求等情况下，每次校验结果均为合格；对安全生产工作面上重视，实际却撤销安全生产科；没有定期开展医疗卫生机构消防安全检查，也没有对事发医院近3年消防检测发现的重大问题进行督促整改。三是建设工程规划、施工安全监管存在短板漏洞。北京市住房城乡建设部门对建筑业企业资质条件保持情况疏于监管，动态排查清理不符合条件企业工作滞后。北京市建设工程施工管理自我设“限”，对限额以上未办理施工许可证的建设工程未主动开展监督管理，把不具备申请办理施工许可条件的建设工程排除在监管范围外，“只管合法、不管非法”；对限额以下工程施工安全疏于管理，对属地培训指导、协调督促又没跟上，导致基层接不住、管不好。北京市城乡规划部门履行制止和查处违法建设职责不到位，未能有效指导属地政府及其相关部门违法建设查处工作，对辖区内无规划手续即新建、扩建的行为查不出、管不住。四是消防监督检查和专项整治不深入。当地消防部门未认真履行消防安全监管职责，2009年事发医院已符合消防安全重点单位界定标准，至2022年才将其确定为重点单位进行监管；确定为重点单位后，消防监督检查质效依然不高，未及时发现和督促整改消防设施、消防供电等问题隐患。北京市消防救援总队在全市部署开展的建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查中，未能有效指导丰台区消防救援支队严格落实消防监督检查职责。五是初期应急处置能力不足。这次事故中，自流平地面和净化工程作业人员均为临时雇佣人员，未经任何施工交底和安全教育培训直接上岗，违规交叉作业导致发生火灾，之后作业人员均未第一时间报警。医院值班人员、管理人员和医护人员，在发现火情后均未第一时间报警，医院未有效组织初期火灾扑救和人员疏散。同时，这次事故也暴露出一些政府部门和单位存在事故信息报送特别是伤亡人员信息报送不及时不规范等问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，为进一步汲取教训，防止此类事故再次发生，有哪些整改和防范措施建议？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;为深刻汲取事故教训，举一反三，坚决防范遏制重特大事故发生，事故调查组提出了五个方面的整改和防范措施建议：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是切实扛起防范化解重大风险政治责任。各级领导干部要结合学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想主题教育，全面深入学习领会习近平总书记关于安全生产重要论述，坚持人民至上、生命至上，牢固树立安全发展理念，进一步增强防范化解重大风险的政治自觉、思想自觉和行动自觉。各地区、各部门、各单位要切实提高风险隐患排查整改质量，切实提升发现问题解决问题的强烈意愿和能力水平，进一步压紧压实企业主体责任、部门监管责任、地方领导责任，建立安全风险防范长效机制，坚决守牢安全红线底线。二是着力补齐医疗卫生机构安全管理短板。各级卫生健康部门要加强医疗卫生行业安全管理，督促各类医疗卫生机构严格执行安全生产和消防安全管理规定，加强安全风险分级管控和隐患排查治理，组织开展医疗卫生机构安全生产和消防安全专项排查整治。严格医疗卫生机构登记校验、行政审批等，组织开展医疗卫生机构依法执业情况核查，严查不如实申报情况、超许可范围执业、违规开展医养结合服务等行为。督促医疗卫生机构统筹考虑院感防治和病患应急疏散转移，指导各类医疗卫生机构制定专项灭火预案和应急疏散预案。三是坚决堵塞建设工程安全监督管理漏洞。各级住房城乡建设部门要加大资质审批后动态监管力度，严格建设工程施工许可管理，加强施工现场特别是施工动火作业安全管理，及时发现并消除事故隐患。城乡规划等部门要加大对违法建设的巡查和处置力度，对新增违建实行“零容忍”。四是全面织牢织密消防安全风险防控网。各地区要按照“三管三必须”要求，进一步压实行业部门消防安全管理责任，推行行业消防安全标准化管理；对职能交叉和新业态新风险，及时明确监管责任。推动街道乡镇建设应急站、消防所，发挥公安派出所、社区、网格等群防群治力量，切实加强对小场所小单位的消防安全管理。各级消防部门要严格履行消防监督管理职责，推动公共消防安全治理模式向事前预防转型，切实提升消防监督检查质效。五是加快提升基层一线应急处置能力和水平。各地区要进一步强化对各类企事业单位应急预案、演练、培训等应急准备的组织指导、监督检查。加强基层一线作业人员安全教育和应急培训，深入开展实操实训应急演练，确保熟悉作业场所现场处置方案。加强应急文化建设，强化应急科普宣传，切实增强社会公众安全意识，做到人人讲安全、个个会应急。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[聚焦北京长峰医院火灾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/247513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年4月18日12时50分，北京市丰台区靛厂新村291号北京长峰医院发生重大火灾事故，造成29人死亡、42人受伤，直接经济损失3831.82万元。 日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>