<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从奥本海默到“核武之王”，这70年经历了什么？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256964]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/r6FiloQ2QNq1q67PqYHr7zhROxZiFIGrf2SP6ELu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/r6FiloQ2QNq1q67PqYHr7zhROxZiFI Grf2SP6ELu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251162&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 15, 1957, local time, in Princeton, the United States, the creator of the atomic bomb, Robert Oppenheimer. A new film about Oppenheimer&#39;s life and his leadership in creating the world&#39;s first atomic bomb during World War II will be released in theaters on July 21, 2023, local time. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the summer movies, &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; is one of the most eye-catching ones. The protagonist in the film is Julius Robert Oppenheimer, a genius Jewish scientist known as the &quot;Father of the Atomic Bomb&quot;. His &quot;work&quot; directly changed the face of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, as the conflict between Russia and Ukraine continues to escalate, at a critical moment when the Ukrainian army launches a large-scale counterattack, Russia demonstrated a powerful weapon-the &quot;Sarmat&quot; land-based intercontinental ballistic missile. This giant intercontinental missile has been put on combat readiness to prepare for possible crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From Oppenheimer to &quot;Sarmat&quot;, what has happened in the past 70 years? Let&#39;s review the history of nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Oppenheimer&#39;s &quot;Legacy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer, a name closely associated with the atomic bomb and the &quot;Manhattan Project.&quot; This Jewish genius scientist has shown extraordinary talents since he was a child. In his childhood, he was influenced by his mother and dabbled in various fields such as art, literature, philosophy, history, science and language. The youngest member of the Mineral Club, he graduated with first place from Fieldston School of Arts and Sciences in New York at the age of 18 (many political, business and cultural celebrities in the United States came from this school) and was admitted to the Department of Chemistry at Harvard University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from college, Oppenheimer first entered the famous Cavendish Laboratory of the University of Cambridge in England. After that, Oppenheimer was taught by the founder of quantum mechanics and the winner of the 1954 Nobel Prize in Physics. Born’s recommendation led him to the famous University of Göttingen. In 1927, Oppenheimer received his PhD for his research in quantum mechanics and decided to return to the United States not long after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of his life was presiding over the United States&#39; nuclear weapons project, the &quot;Manhattan Project.&quot; As the commander-in-chief of the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot;, which cost US$2.5 billion and involved more than 500,000 people at its peak, Oppenheimer fully demonstrated his scientific literacy and management skills. In the movie, Oppenheimer called the project a &quot;gamble&quot; - he won the bet, and the United States also won the bet: at 5:30 in the morning on July 16, 1945, the first atomic bomb in human history was dropped on Los Angeles A successful explosion in the Alamos Desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the rest of his life, Oppenheimer suffered from humiliation and trouble because of this project that brought him great fame. The movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; vividly reproduces how he was persecuted by politicians represented by McCarthyism and General Strauss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 18, 1967, Oppenheimer died of throat cancer at the age of 63. What legacy did he leave to the world in the half century that followed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of early 2020, data from the Stockholm Peace Research Institute shows that the United States, Russia, the United Kingdom, France and other countries possess approximately 13,400 nuclear weapons, of which 3,720 have been deployed with combat troops, and approximately 1,800 of them are on high alert. . These nuclear weapons are specifically carried by a variety of delivery systems, including land- and sea-based long-range ballistic missiles, heavy bombers, fighter-bombers, air- and sea-launched cruise missiles, air defense and missile defense interceptor missiles, torpedoes, and depth charges . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hans Christensen, director of the &quot;Nuclear Information Project&quot; of the Federation of American Scientists, believes that both the United States and Russia possess very large nuclear arsenals, backed by short-range tactical nuclear forces, including intercontinental ballistic missiles, Sea-launched ballistic missiles and aircraft capable of carrying nuclear weapons constitute the &quot;trinity&quot; of long-range strategic nuclear forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some other countries have &quot;two-in-one&quot; medium-range nuclear forces and/or long-range nuclear forces (that is, they have any two of the three elements of the &quot;trinity&quot;). Some are transitioning to the &quot;Trinity&quot;, and there are rumors that Israel may already have the &quot;Trinity&quot; nuclear power. In addition, Pakistan and India possess short-range nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that after 70 years of development, nuclear weapons have not only changed the form of military struggle, but also had a profound impact on the development of human society and the international strategic pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The birth of the &quot;King of Nuclear Weapons&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Sarmat&quot; intercontinental ballistic missile was born in a time of crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the disintegration of the Soviet Union, Russia, which inherited its legacy, is not comparable to the Soviet Union in terms of armed force building. Unlike the Soviet Union, Russia is a resource-based country and therefore far inferior to its rival NATO in terms of conventional weapons. Nuclear power has therefore increasingly become the core of Russia&#39;s military power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Land-based nuclear forces are the foundation and pillar of Russia’s “trinity” nuclear forces. Russia&#39;s nuclear power was inherited from the Soviet Union. The three old intercontinental ballistic missile systems of SS-18 &quot;Satan&quot;, SS-19 &quot;Dagger&quot; and SS-25 &quot;Topol&quot; installed by the Strategic Rocket Force account for half of Russia&#39;s land-based nuclear weapons delivery vehicles. As mentioned above, these three old missile systems will reach the end of their service life. Once decommissioned, it will have a huge impact on the stability of Russia&#39;s strategic nuclear forces. Therefore, Russia decided to develop a new intercontinental ballistic missile to replace the SS-18 that is about to be retired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, the &quot;Sarmat&quot; intercontinental ballistic missile was developed by the Makeev Design Bureau. It conducted ejection tests in December 2017 and March 2018 and achieved success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of performance, this &quot;national weapon&quot; that Russia has high hopes for is really amazing. &quot;Sarmat&quot; is about 35 meters long, about 3 meters in diameter, has a take-off weight of about 200 tons, a payload of up to 10 tons, and a range of up to 17,000 kilometers. The hit accuracy is about 200 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; adopts a cold launch scheme. During launch, a gunpowder accumulator is used to eject the missile to a height of 20-30 meters above the launch silo, and then the missile ignites itself and takes off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; can carry up to 10 heavy or 15 light independently targeted separately guided nuclear warheads, or 24 &quot;Vanguard&quot; hypersonic boost glide bombs, which can target different targets Deliver devastating strikes and identify attacks from multiple targets. When carrying 10 submissive warheads, the yield of each warhead reaches 750,000 tons of TNT. The missile warhead adopts a variety of advanced penetration technologies, such as stealth technology and materials, separately guided multiple warheads and decoy bombs, hypersonic boost-glide warheads, and maneuverable and flexible orbit-changing capabilities. Its strike power is equivalent to 1,600 times that of the atomic bomb exploded in Hiroshima. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; has three unique skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, hit far. This type of missile has a range of 17,000 kilometers. The ultra-long range allows this missile to be launched from any area in Russia and can effectively hit predetermined targets around the world. It is speculated that the &quot;Sarmat&quot; can fly over the Antarctic, completely bypassing all current U.S. missile defense systems, and strike against the United States. Others speculate that it has partial orbital bombing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to play skillfully. This cleverness is reflected in the super defense penetration ability. In modern warfare, the penetration capability of surface-to-surface missiles has increasingly become an important indicator for measuring the comprehensive technical level of missiles. This type of missile uses stealth technology and materials in its shape design and coating. The missile&#39;s boost section is short, which makes it more difficult for enemy radars and satellites to detect, track and intercept. The powerful power gives it an ultra-long range, the ability to fly over both poles to carry out attacks, and may even have partial orbital bombing capabilities to avoid anti-missile systems to the greatest extent. The missile can carry more than ten separately guided warheads and use multiple decoy warheads at the same time, which greatly improves the identification difficulty of the anti-missile system and its own penetration probability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;Sarmat&quot; can also carry the &quot;Pioneer&quot; hypersonic gliding warhead. This warhead has extremely fast speed and super orbit-changing capabilities, and can effectively protect enemy air defense and anti-missile systems. Almost impossible to intercept. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to hit accurately. &quot;Sarmat&quot; adopts a composite guidance method of inertial guidance, starlight guidance and GLONASS satellite guidance. The three methods combine with each other and complement each other, reducing the missile hit accuracy to about 150 meters, while the SS-18 missile using inertial guidance has a hit accuracy of 350 meters. The improvement of strike accuracy is the improvement of strike power. In this regard, &quot;Sarmat&quot; has done an excellent job and is at the world&#39;s advanced level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sarmat&quot; is a liquid-fuel missile. For ballistic missiles, the difference between using solid fuel and liquid fuel lies in specific thrust, toxicity, safety, and ease of control. Liquid fuel has a greater specific thrust than solid fuel. Therefore, the number of segments of a ballistic missile using liquid fuel is one less than that of solid fuel. The refueling takes a long time, so it is not suitable for use as a means of nuclear counterattack - it is more suitable for a &quot;preemptive&quot; nuclear strike, which invisibly increases the deterrence against NATO. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The future of nuclear weapons&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As the most destructive force on earth, the development of nuclear weapons will show several trends in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the means of delivering nuclear warheads will develop towards hypersonic missiles. As modern missile defense systems continue to mature and evolve, how to improve the penetration capabilities of nuclear missiles has become an important issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the current equipment, new concept weapons such as hypersonic missiles are beginning to stand out. Hypersonic technology refers to aircraft technology that can fly at speeds exceeding 5 times the speed of sound. It is the commanding heights of aerospace technology in the 21st century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outstanding advantages of hypersonic missiles are mainly reflected in three aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it basically flies in the upper atmosphere, with a flight altitude of only 30-80 kilometers, and the terminal altitude may be only more than 20 kilometers, which greatly affects the detection capabilities of the early warning radar of traditional ballistic missile defense systems. . Early warning radars represented by the US &quot;Pave Claw&quot; have a detection range of long-range and intercontinental missiles up to thousands of kilometers, but the detection range of hypersonic weapons flying at an altitude of tens of kilometers is only a few hundred kilometers. Therefore, the ballistic missile defense system&#39;s defense effect against such aircraft is greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is that because it flies controlled in the atmosphere, it has good maneuverability compared to the dull trajectory of traditional ballistic missiles. Coupled with the speed of hypersonics, the difficulty of intercepting it has increased significantly, further weakening the interception capabilities of traditional ballistic missile defense systems. In other words, hypersonic gliding vehicles have significantly improved penetration capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hypersonic glide vehicles can also be used in conjunction with traditional ballistic missiles. Although such a combination increases the risk of interception during mid-flight, it greatly increases the actual range of the missile. This technological trend has been very obvious in the &quot;Sarmat&quot; missile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, the deep sea may become an important space for nuclear weapons projection. Due to the special physical characteristics of the deep sea, radar waves cannot penetrate, so military operations are very concealed. The &quot;Poseidon&quot; nuclear torpedo developed by Russia was developed based on this logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the maximum speed of &quot;Poseidon&quot; will exceed 200 kilometers per hour (about 110 knots), and the maximum diving depth will exceed 1,000 meters. With such a high speed underwater, it cannot be effectively intercepted. The fastest nuclear submarine currently in service has a maximum speed of 35 knots, and the most advanced torpedoes equipped in Western countries have a maximum speed of 55 knots. This makes existing torpedo weapons &quot;Poseidon&quot; cannot be intercepted. The torpedo can carry a nuclear or conventional warhead with an equivalent of 2 million tons of TNT. When it explodes near the enemy&#39;s coast, it can trigger a huge tsunami, causing devastating blows to ports, cities, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is estimated that it can form a huge tsunami impact with a span of 550 kilometers and a maximum wave height of 500 meters. No ship anchored in the port can survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the world&#39;s first atomic bomb successfully exploded at the test site, Oppenheimer once quoted a sentence from the Hindu scripture &quot;Bhagavad Gita&quot;: Now I have become death, the destroyer of worlds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development of 70 years, the progress of missile technology will force the further improvement of anti-missile technology. New concept weapons such as high-energy lasers and electromagnetic guns will likely be used in missile defense systems. Human war will thus kick off another round of offensive and defensive games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue between Oppenheimer and Einstein in the film shows that there is still no answer to the confusion about personal destiny and future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is the deputy director of the Northeast Asia Research Center of Shanghai University of Political Science and Law)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年轻人买金，老年人卖金？广州市民卖1公斤套现44万多元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256960]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 14:30:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;I received an order last month, 1 kilogram, and gave him more than 440,000 yuan.&quot; One person Said an industry insider who has been engaged in gold recycling for more than ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the price of gold in the domestic retail market has continued to rise, once exceeding 600 yuan per gram. Topics such as gold prices have been hotly searched. So far, consumers’ enthusiasm has not diminished. Amid the gold buying craze, gold The recycling market is also experiencing a gold selling boom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the working day of September 18, Nandu reporters visited the gold wholesale business district of Changshou West Road in Liwan District, Guangzhou and the supermarket in Tianhe District, Guangzhou. They saw that many people still went to consult or buy gold. The gold price that day It has dropped from last week, and the gold recycling prices online and offline, and for different brands, are different, with big differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, most young people have been buying gold recently, and they are particularly fond of gold beans, which cost around 500 yuan each and weigh 1 gram, as a way to save, which has aroused heated discussion. It is worth noting that after visits, we also found that many middle-aged and elderly people are selling gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“People in their 40s and 50s come to sell”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At around 1:00 noon on September 18, Changshou West Road, Liwan District, Guangzhou, Signs such as &quot;Recycle Gold and Silver Jewelry&quot; and &quot;Recycle Gold at High Prices&quot; are hung up. At the street intersection, there are many young people hurriedly entering the gold shop, as well as middle-aged and elderly people holding small bags in the store and looking around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen Shuibei is known as the &quot;barometer&quot; of the gold and jewelry market. Hengtai Jewelry, located in the gold wholesale business district of Changshou West Road, is the Guangzhou branch of Shenzhen Shuibei. The reporter found that within half an hour, , the number of consumers in the store has always remained above 20, and most of them sit around the display cabinet to inquire about and buy gold jewelry. One row sells gold jewelry with smaller grams such as Jin Doudou, and the other row sells gold bracelets with larger grams. Waiting, &quot;We are getting married, so we came to buy during the lunch break. Today (September 18) the price is a little lower than before.&quot; A pair of young people are buying gold bracelets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/82a468ff6fffb6646188ca3ce6d49589.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1383&quot; height=&quot;1086&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/82a468ff6fffb6646188ca3ce6d49589.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251166&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Changshou West Road, Liwan District, Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the gold recycling area in the corner of the store, there is an electronic screen showing the continuously fluctuating price: gold repurchase is 468.98 yuan, and the highest price of the day is 471.72 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The price of recycling at the end of last year reached more than 400 yuan.&quot; According to the staff of the store, the price of gold in the whole store that day was 471 yuan, the price of recycled gold bars or gold sheets was 468 yuan, and the price of recycled gold was 468 yuan. Accessories cost 5 yuan less, calculated as 463 yuan, which is 2 yuan lower than at the weekend. At present, most of the gold sheets on the market are mainly one kilogram, and such as gold beans and bracelets are gold jewelry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In about half an hour, two citizens over the age of 50 came to inquire about the gold recycling market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Recently, gold sellers have to line up outside, and the whole street is filled with gold sellers.” An industry insider who has been engaged in gold recycling for more than ten years also opened a store in the gold wholesale business district. He opened a jewelry store specializing in gold recycling. On that day, he also recycled gold for 463 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are many grams of recycling, and the recycling price can still be negotiated.” This industry insider said that the recycling price has risen to more than 460 yuan in the past half month, and the recycling price reached the highest level of 479 yuan per gram last week, maintaining the same level. In half a day, &quot;I received an order last month with a unit price of more than 440 yuan per kilogram, and I gave him more than 440,000 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In about half a month, the recycling price increased from more than 440 yuan per gram. to more than 460 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, prices in the domestic gold retail market have continued to rise, driving the growth of the recycling business. According to an industry insider, he recycled one order that day and has made more than 20 orders in the past ten days. “They are all in the 40s or 50s. There are no young people to sell to people who are 20 years old.&quot; said the above-mentioned industry insider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The price difference between the recycling of branded gold jewelry is more than 100 yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the wholesale market, the recycling market in supermarkets in Tianhe District, Guangzhou is relatively cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 3 pm, almost every gold brand store in Tianhe City in Tianhe District had people shopping. The listed prices of gold in different brand stores are different, all above 600 yuan per gram, and some are as high as 600 yuan per gram. The gold price is 610 yuan per gram, but there are basically price discounts ranging from 20 to 40 yuan. According to many staff on site, the price of gold has dropped by a few yuan from the peak last week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for recycling services, only a few brands provide them and the recycling prices are low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the staff of Tianhe City China Gold Store, the gold price after discount is 568 yuan per gram, and the recycling price is 405 yuan per gram. There are relatively few people coming to sell, &quot;Today (September 18) ) No one recycles it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The selling price of Jinzhizun gold is 609 yuan per gram, and only the investment gold bars are recycled, which is recycled at 430 yuan that day. Lao Fengxiang and Chow Tai Fook do not have on-site recycling services. Among them, Chow Tai Fook’s gold price is 608 yuan per gram, and the recycling price is 451 yuan. According to a staff member of Chow Tai Fook, this store cannot recycle, and you have to go to the store on Beijing Road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/cf496b79e899c0812c38fc1f670143aa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/cf496b79e899c0812c38fc1f670143aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251167&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangzhou Tianhe City Chow Tai Fook Store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to offline platforms, many e-commerce platforms also provide gold recycling services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter randomly searched for &quot;Guangzhou gold recycling&quot; on Taobao, Tmall and other platforms, selected 4 stores with sales of 1,000+ payments, and inquired from customer service. They all said that the recycling price was 465 yuan per gram, and the price was 465 yuan per gram in the same city. You can come to your door for recycling and pay on the spot; but if the store is in other cities, it needs to be evaluated online. The consumer takes a photo of the store link and mails it to the merchant. After the merchant signs and checks the gram number, the merchant pays the consumer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the recycling prices of gold jewelry of different brands are different online and offline, and there is a big difference. For the wholesale market, it is generally 8-10 yuan less than the gold price sold; for brand stores in supermarkets , the difference is more than 100 yuan; while the online recycling price is 2 yuan more than that in the offline wholesale market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Some supermarkets need to pay nearly a thousand yuan for redemption&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I just received a customer to redeem.” The reporter said Visiting supermarket brands also found that although many brand stores do not recycle gold and can only exchange old items for new ones, and the method is complicated, many consumers come to consult or exchange for the styles they like. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Trade-in means that the gold products in the hands of consumers are discounted according to the current gold price and then purchased in-store at the current selling price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/086b9e703a353149adb07af4c5f76fde.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/086b9e703a353149adb07af4c5f76fde.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251168&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hengtai Jewelry Store on Changshou West Road in Liwan District, Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the staff of Lao Fengxiang, if you want to exchange for gold that is not of this brand, based on the gold listing price of the brand that day is 608 yuan per gram, the discount per gram you want to exchange is 30 yuan, and the number of grams must also be calculated. 10% off, 30% more grams purchased. In other words, if you have 10 grams of gold to redeem, which is originally 6,080 yuan, you need to calculate the price based on 9 grams of 578 yuan, which is 5,202 yuan, and an additional 3 grams of gold, which is 1,824 yuan, for the total exchange price That’s 7026 yuan. In other words, you need to make a minimum payment of 946 yuan to redeem it, and the crafting fee is additional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, China Gold, Chow Tai Fook and other stores have different discounts for redemption. Among them, China Gold staff said that if you want to exchange for gold that is not of the same brand, you will have to pay a price difference of 40 yuan per gram, and there is no labor fee. You can choose the type and quantity of the exchange. According to the staff of Chow Tai Fook, there are two options. If you have 10 grams of gold to redeem, first, you need to exchange for a product heavier than 10 grams, and the discount is calculated at 85 yuan per gram; second, you need to exchange for a product with twice the gram, that is, 20 grams, based on the selling price of the day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the gold wholesale business district of Changshou West Road, reporters also found that many consumers exchanged for gold products. At noon on September 18, two Guangzhou citizens in their 50s brought 10.06 grams of gold chains to change styles and walked into a gold store. A sign hanging outside the gold store read &quot;Old gold for new, one gram for one gram.&quot; According to reports, the gold chain is charged based on the recycling price of 463 yuan plus 15% handicraft fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽十元“盒饭姐”爆火后流泪，围观的边界感在哪？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[苹果“芯”，闭环未完成丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256950]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 11:57:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1423&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46 XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX. png&quot; data-key=&quot;251156&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Communications &amp;amp; Chip&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.qualcomm.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1351/qualcomm-announces-agreement-with-apple-for-chip-supply&quot;>;&lt;strong>; Qualcomm and Apple reached a three-year chip supply agreement&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 11, Qualcomm announced that it had reached a new agreement with Apple. Qualcomm will provide Apple with chips in 2024, 2025 and 2026. The iPhone launched in 2017 supplies Snapdragon series 5G modem and radio frequency systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Apple released the iPhone 15 series, bringing a full range of smart islands, USB-C interfaces, and 48 million main cameras. Among them, iPhone 15 Pro and iPhone 15 Pro Max were upgraded to use the world’s first 3nm process Process chip, 6-core image processor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The iPhone&#39;s baseband chip has long been tied to Qualcomm. In 2010, Apple introduced Qualcomm&#39;s 3G/4G baseband products for the first time on the iPhone 4. Since 2011, Qualcomm has become the exclusive supplier of iPhone basebands and takes 5% of the sales price as a patent licensing fee. Around 2018, disputes broke out between the two parties during contract renewal negotiations for 5G baseband chips, and they initiated patent lawsuits against each other. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold; &quot;>;At the same time, Apple is also trying to create a closed loop of self-developed chips. In July 2019, it acquired most of Intel&#39;s mobile phone baseband chip business for US$1 billion. In March 2021, it invested in the construction of a new European semiconductor laboratory in Munich, with the first phase of investment. 1 billion euros. According to the six-year licensing agreement reached between Apple and Qualcomm in 2019, Apple will stop purchasing 5G baseband chips from Qualcomm after 2024. However, judging from this supply agreement, although Apple’s 3nm process chips are currently leading the commercial market, self-developed baseband chips are still on the way, and Qualcomm cannot be untied yet. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1973239/000119312523216983/d393891df1.htm&quot;>;ARM is included in the list Stark listing&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 14, ARM, a chip design company under SoftBank Group, was officially listed on Nasdaq with the stock code &quot;ARM&quot;. A total of 95.5 million American depositary shares were issued. After the IPO, Japan&#39;s SoftBank Group still retains about 90% of the company&#39;s shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the 2021-2023 fiscal year, ARM’s R&amp;D investment will be US$814 million, US$955 million, and US$1.133 billion; its revenue will be US$2.027 billion, US$2.703 billion, and US$2.679 billion respectively. ARM’s revenue mainly includes two parts: licensing and royalties/royalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : ARM was founded in 1990. It was initially jointly invested by Acorn Computers, Apple Computer and VLSI Technology. Since then, it has experienced ups and downs in the capital market until it was acquired by SoftBank in 2016. At present, most electronic consumer products such as smartphones, computers, and smart wearable devices have chips based on the ARM architecture. According to ARM&#39;s own data, a total of 250 billion chips based on the ARM architecture have been shipped since its release. In fiscal year 2023, more than 30 billion chips based on the ARM architecture will be shipped. There are 15 million developers in the ARM ecosystem. The closing price of ARM on its first day of listing increased by 25% from the issue price, with a market value of US$65 billion. With the rise of artificial intelligence, a new era in which computing power is king has arrived, which is also a new opportunity for ARM. (Tong Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/open-networks-ecosystem-competition-successful-projects&quot;>;&lt;strong>;UK £88m for O&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;O&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;pen&amp;nbsp;RAN&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;scheme&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;September 14 , the British government announced 88 million pounds (US$109 million) in funding for 19 projects to demonstrate the Open Radio Access Network (Open&amp;nbsp; RAN) potential to achieve better mobile services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The projects come from the winners of the Open Networks Ecosystem (ONE) competition, the UK government’s £250 million ($312 million) 5G telecoms supply chain diversification strategy (&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/5g-supply-chain-diversification-strategy&quot;>;UK 5G Supply Chain Diversification Strategy&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;). The competition aims to showcase Open&amp;nbsp;RAN, a new way of building mobile networks that provides fast, reliable connections in busy places where wireless connections are needed. It allows technologies from different companies to work together, rather than using only one company&#39;s equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Open RAN refers to an open wireless access network. Currently, British telecom operator Vodafone has officially commercialized 5G Open RAN in Europe. The UK is using real money to promote the Open RAN research and development plan, aiming to break down the barriers between different companies and equipment. For users, at least signal coverage must be improved. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/K4GEB1hyOslOY5qNLxVAKA&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Huawei takes the lead in completing all 5.5G functional tests&lt;/strong >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, Huawei completed all functional test cases for 5G-A (also known as 5.5G, full name 5G-Advanced, the name officially determined by 3GPP for 5G evolution), covering Uplink and downlink ultra-wideband and broadband real-time interaction 5G-A key technologies. As an evolution and enhancement of 5G, 5G-A has achieved a 10-fold improvement in network capabilities such as connection speed and latency. At the same time, it has introduced new revolutionary technologies such as synaesthesia integration, passive Internet of Things, and endogenous intelligence. It is the key to building the future. Infrastructure for smart societies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The iteration of mobile communication technology from 5G to 6G will take time. During the transition period, 5G-A has high hopes. At the 2023MWC Shanghai World Mobile Communications Conference, Huawei Vice Chairman, Rotating Chairman, and CFO Meng Wanzhou said that in 2024, Huawei will launch a full set of 5.5G network equipment for commercial use to prepare for the commercial deployment of 5.5G. Every upgrade of communication technology will bring about new developments in the industrial ecology. (Zhao Jun)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Car&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en /press-room/20230911IPR04912/state-of-the-eu-ukraine-green-deal-economy-china-artificial-intelligence&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The EU will launch a countervailing investigation into Chinese electric vehicles&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a >;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Ursula von der Leyen, President of the European Commission, stated in her “State of the Union Address” at the European Parliament that she would launch a campaign against China’s electric Anti-subsidy investigation of automobiles. Von der Leyen stressed the importance of a fair transition for farmers, households and industry and said Europe would maintain its competitive advantage &quot;at all costs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : In 2021, 2022 and the first half of 2023, China&#39;s automobile export sales will be 2.01 million, 3.11 million and 2.14 million vehicles respectively, a year-on-year increase of 102%, 54% and 76% respectively, of which new energy vehicles account for the majority. In the first half of 2023, it will replace Japan as a major automobile exporter. The situation is very good, but the total amount is still very small, and we should not be overly optimistic. We must be adequately prepared and coping with the complexity and intensity of international competition. (Zhao Jun)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://global.honda/en/newsroom/news/2023/c230912eng.html?from=latest_area&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Ford, BMW and Honda&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Join to build charging network&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 12, Ford Motor Company, BMW Group and Honda Motor America announced the establishment of a new charging network. The company ChargeScape aims to build a platform that connects power companies, car manufacturers, and electric vehicle owners. Car owners can feed energy back to the grid through charging management, energy sharing services, etc., thus saving money and even earning profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ChargeScape will also provide power companies and system operators with secure energy data to enable smart use of electric vehicle batteries. The three automakers will share equal shares in the new company, and other automakers are welcome to join. However, the new company still needs regulatory approval and is expected to begin operations in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Electric vehicles are not only energy users, but also energy storage carriers. With the integration of cars and networks, car manufacturers have finally joined forces to take action. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Technical News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scitranslmed .abo6889&quot;>;&lt;strong>;New ideas for stabilizing microtubules in the treatment of chronic traumatic encephalopathy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, research was conducted by the Shanghai Institute of Organic Chemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences and the University of Pennsylvania. Cooperating with institutions, a publication titled&lt;em>;A&amp;nbsp;microtubule&amp;nbsp;stabilizer&amp;nbsp;ameliorates&amp;nbsp;protein&amp;nbsp;pathogenesis&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;neurodegeneration&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;mouse&amp;nbsp;models&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;re in Science&amp;nbsp;translational&amp;nbsp;medicine petitive&amp;nbsp; A research paper on traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injury&lt;/em>;reports that repetitive traumatic brain injuries (repetitive&amp;nbsp;traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injuries,&amp;nbsp;rTBI) can induce physiological tau protein to cause Alzheimer&#39;s disease (AD)-related Pathological changes and further promote the pathological spread of tau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, researchers from the above-mentioned research team used a previously developed microtubule stabilizer CNDR-51657 to treat mice with repeated brain injuries. This microtubule stabilizer can penetrate into the brain and play a role. After a period of medication in mice, the neuronal projections in the optic nerve tract were restored, the deposition of punctate tau protein was reduced, and the activity of neurons in the visual cortex was restored. The mice&#39;s vision Functional recovery, behavioral experiments showed that the mice&#39;s cognitive function also improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above studies have proven that microtubule stabilizers may play an important role in regulating the abnormal aggregation and spread of tau protein, and may be beneficial to brain tissues such as chronic traumatic encephalopathy, Alzheimer&#39;s disease (AD), and frontotemporal lobe dementia (FTLD). It provides new therapeutic targets and ideas for neurodegenerative diseases in which pathological deposition of tau protein occurs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Screening for autism through single-cell brain organoids developmental defects&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Nature published a paper by a research team from the Institute of Molecular Biotechnology (IMBA) of the Austrian Academy of Sciences (IMBA) and ETH Zurich&lt;em >;Single-cell&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;organoid&amp;nbsp;screening&amp;nbsp;identifies&amp;nbsp;developmental&amp;nbsp;defects&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;autism&lt;/em>;&amp;nbsp;.该研究开发了一种CRISPR-人类类器官-单细胞RNA测序系统，简称CHOOSE系统，研究人员可在单细胞水平上追踪每个突变的影响，并绘制每个细胞的发育轨迹。该系统使用经过验证的gRNA、基于诱导CRISPR-Cas9的基因敲除和单细胞转录组学，对嵌合型大脑类器官进行了功能缺失筛查，揭示了36个与转录调控有关的自闭症风险基因突变对大脑类器官不同细胞命运的影响，其中背侧中间祖细胞、腹侧祖细胞和上层兴奋性神经元是最脆弱的细胞类型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：自闭症被称作人类大脑的最复杂的疾病之一，上述创新方法为自闭症研究提供了新见解，通过了解致病基因共同的分子机制，也为自闭症临床研究带来新希望。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qiluguquan.com/guquan-article-read-11391.html&quot;>;&lt;strong>;齐鲁股权交易中心“专精特新”专板开板&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;9月13日，由齐鲁股权交易中心负责建设的山东区域性股权市场“专精特新”专板正式开板，首批226家企业登录专板。根据企业不同发展阶段，齐鲁股权交易中心在“专精特新”专板设置了孵化层、规范层和培育层，并发布了入板规则；聚焦专板企业服务，搭建了以“六大服务载体、七大专属服务工具、八大重点服务产品”为主体内容的“六七八”综合服务体系，强化上市培育体系建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;点评：区域性股权市场，也被称为“四板市场”，过去一直不太受关注。齐鲁股权交易中心此次高调推出“专精特新”专板，是服务中小企业融资的重要举措。 2023年9月1日，中国证监会发布《关于高质量建设北京证券交易所的意见》，提出要加强多层次资本市场互联互通，开展新三板与区域性股权市场制度型对接。这一“专精特新”专板，若能打通企业进入多层次资本市场的渠道，倒是真有可能开启“四板”的创新试验田。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨妞花不放过余华英：这样的不宽容彰显正气与血性丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256958]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月18日，贵阳市中院以拐卖儿童罪判处余华英死刑。法院认定：余华英1993-1996年期间伙同龚某良（已故）为牟取非法利益，在贵州省、重庆市等地流窜，物色合适的孩童进行拐卖，得手后二人将被拐儿童带至河北省邯郸市，其间共拐卖11名儿童。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英当庭表示上诉，这是她的权利，也说明她对这个判决既不服，也不想死。不过，想想被她诱骗、绑架与拐卖的11个孩子，哪个父母不对她恨之入骨？ &amp;nbsp;当孩子不见了，父母急火攻心、以泪洗面、茶饭不思，在本地找、去全国各地找，正常的生活、工作被打乱，失去欢乐、家庭破碎。在这个过程中，有的父母陷入自责不能自拔，人生失去意义，或自暴自弃，或抑郁而终，有的父母在某个节点放弃了希望，但心里永不愈合的伤口还会时常隐隐作痛甚至急性发作，也有父母不依不饶、不止不休，但以中国之大，找回自己孩子又何其难也。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庭审现场，就有受害者家属甚至当年被拐卖、现在已成年但永远是父母眼中的“孩子”在场，杨妞花就是其中的一个。在将余华英绳之以法、予以应有惩罚的过程中，杨妞花起到了不可替代的作用，正是她的坚持与不依不饶，余华英才最终落网，我们才能看到9月18日的那一幕。一句话，杨妞花是当之无愧、令人感佩的英雄。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年，杨妞花出生于贵州织金县，是家中最小的女儿，有一个幸福的家庭，有很多难忘的童年回忆，正是这些不可磨灭的回忆成了她心中不灭的光，助她找到了回家的路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英及其团伙租住在杨妞花家附近，她对“自己和姐姐很好，会带姐妹俩逛街，会给买东西”。有一天余华英趁家中没有大人时，骗走并拐卖了时年5岁的杨妞花，价格是2500元。杨妞花忘不了：被骗上火车之后，余华英随即变换出一张凶狠的脸，不仅对她拳打脚踢，还将暖壶里的开水直接浇到她的头上，这是为了“降低管理成本”的服从性训练。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，杨妞花开始了漫漫寻亲之旅。 2021年4月，她在短视频平台上发布寻亲信息，回忆起和家人相处的点点滴滴：自己掉进水坑差点淹死，爬上来后姐姐在一旁哭；从猪圈摔下头破血流，姐姐背着自己哭着去找妈妈。同年5月3日，杨妞花的视频引起了贵州织金县一位杨姓女孩的关切，她从小听长辈说，有个堂姐在1995年时丢了。经过DNA比对确认，被拐26年的杨妞花终于踏上了回家之路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不幸的是，在她被拐后，她的父亲因伤心过度饮酒过量于1997年去世，母亲因承受不住精神打击也于翌年离世，姐姐遂成为孤儿。后来，姐姐告诉她，那时一到晚上，父母就会带着姐姐到火车站里找人，夜里就在车站打地铺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接受媒体采访时，杨妞花表示：“之前我在没有找到家的时候，我从来没想过去找人贩子。是找到家之后发现家里面变故那么大，才下决心要找人贩子的。”2022年6月，杨妞花向贵州警方提供线索。 24天后，余华英被贵阳市公安局南明分局抓获。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，贵阳市南明区检察院以“拐卖儿童罪”对余华英提起公诉。据杨妞花的代理律师王文广透露，检方最初建议判处有期徒刑14年。杨妞花对这一量刑建议并不满意，她委托律师申请，将此案由贵阳市南明区法院移交到贵阳市中院审理，后面的部分我们都看到了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余华英此次被指控的11起拐卖儿童案件，并不包括之前已审理结案的，也不包括她卖掉的自己的亲儿子，正是这一次的收益，让她尝到了甜头与血腥味，从此一发不可收。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末报道，庭审时，余华英曾两次对被拐家庭道歉，希望获得他们谅解，也希望法院能从轻处罚。但杨妞花难以接受余华英的道歉。这样的不宽容，彰显的是正义和血性！ 《论语》有一段经典对话，或曰：以德报怨，何如？子曰：何以报德？以直报怨，以德报德。一个人遭受很大的伤害，被剥夺权利、被凌辱，失去本有的生活，当然有权向施害者索求自己应得的正义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受害者有权索求正义，与TA最终能否得到正义，当然是两件事，前者也不能自动导向后者，而是需要受害者本人“做功”。杨妞花不放过人贩子，于她而言的直接动机，是为自己、为自己的父母讨回一点公道，而她同时也为所有被拐卖的孩子及其家庭讨回了公道，也给我们这个社会树立了正气与血性。主观为自己，客观利他人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，惩恶扬善，不惩恶何足以扬善？坏人得以善终是对善与正义的最大嘲讽。只有当这个社会的正气与血性越来越多，心怀不轨者才会有所顾忌，欲行不轨前而三思，我们才能安享更大的自由与安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赛百味700亿卖身：降不住中国胃的轻食还会越吃越肥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，全球知名快餐连锁品牌赛百味（Subway）成功“卖身”了。据其官网消息显示，它同意私募股权公司Roark Capital的收购提案，收购价约合人民币700亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消息一出，立马冲上热搜，很多吃货留言感慨，巅峰时期门店数量曾超过麦当劳和肯德基的连锁快餐巨无霸，已经不香了。数据显示，自2014年起，赛百味就陷入了经营困境，截至2022年11月，赛百味在全球的门店数量已经减少近8000家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国，赛百味的门店主要集中在一二线城市，一个三明治售价30元，主打比普通快餐“更健康”，曾因提供新鲜定制的三明治、卷饼、沙拉等在减肥健身圈广受欢迎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，随着餐饮行业的竞争加剧，在健康的名号之下，生酮饮食、代餐、代糖的浪潮一波接着一波，各种各样的“减脂餐”层出不穷，渐渐地，赛百味失去新意的三明治在追求健康消费的中国吃货眼里已不再入时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;层出不穷的减肥餐&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为了成功减肥，人们在饮食上煞费苦心，而这总是能够被敏锐的商家捕捉到，所以这些年来打着减肥名号的饮食浪潮一波又一波。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今声势颇为浩大的是代餐。代餐，顾名思义，可以取代部分或全部正餐，它是一种快速、便捷、定量地为人体提供适量蛋白质、脂肪、碳水化合物及纤维等其它必要营养的食品类型，有代餐粉、代餐奶昔、代餐粥、代餐零食等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;代餐起初主要面向一些特定疾病患者和宇航员、登山运动员等人群，之后迅速在减肥人群中流行，市场规模迅猛扩大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据天猫统计，2021年代餐轻食类商品的销售额同比增长290%，代餐消费者人数在3年时间里增长了78%，人均年消费金额已超过3000元。而全球市场调研公司欧睿国际的统计数据显示，2017年，中国代餐市场规模约为571.7亿元，预计2022年能够达到1200亿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与代餐相近的是代糖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;代糖拥有与蔗糖相似的甜美，却不会产生热量或热量极低。这在饮料、零食上最为常见，它们纷纷打上“零糖”“零卡”标签，告诉消费者既可以满足口腹之欲而且还不会发胖。比如以元气森林为代表的打着“零糖”旗号的饮品，就是通过添加代糖“赤藓糖醇”和“三氯蔗糖”调节口感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些减肥者的刻板印象里，糖分和碳水是肥胖的元凶，所以除了避免糖分以外，有的人也千方百计地少碳水甚至不吃碳水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拒绝一切碳水化合物的生酮饮食开始走红。中国人传统的饮食习惯碳水含量过高，生酮饮食走向另一个极端：只吃瘦肉和蔬菜，不吃含有碳水化合物的主食，以此产生大量酮体，迫使身体燃烧脂肪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再来就是减脂餐了。简单地说，就是能够减掉脂肪的餐饮，它一般是少油少盐、热量低，跟生酮饮食不同，它的营养相对均衡。大多数减肥的餐饮都不好吃，减脂餐如今在社交平台上脱颖而出，就在于它可以是“好吃”的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如有人竟然在碳水巨头里的汉堡、炸鸡里找到曙光。一方面，汉堡、鸡腿不仅可以为人体提供优秀的蛋白质和必需的脂肪，另一方面，它的热量并没有想象中的那么高。比如有些汉堡的热量也就450大卡。而我国成年女性一天的热量摄入在1800千卡左右，成年男性在2250千卡，所以一餐吃个汉堡问题不大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;跟其他减肥餐相比，减脂餐正成为社交平台上的流量大户。其他减肥餐基本只能向商家买，不好吃且价格贵，而减脂餐适合DIY，社交平台上有花样繁多的菜单分享，各种美食一应俱全，好吃还能减肥，何乐不为？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不一定奏效&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;只是，网红减肥餐，真的能够减肥吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，不少网红减肥餐似是而非，只是求求心理安慰而已。比如这两年很流行的各种代餐零食，什么燕麦脆、压缩饼干、谷物酸奶、即食玉米片，含糖量并不低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些代糖饼干，虽然把蔗糖换成了代糖，把小麦粉换成富含更多膳食纤维的粗粮粉，但主要成分还是淀粉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再比如现在外卖平台上火爆的沙拉套餐，堆满青菜、水果也堆点肉，看上去很健康。实际上，水果虽然补充维生素，但含糖量不低；牛油果脂肪含量不低；几粒紫米/糙米，只是观感上像粗粮，很可能是精制碳水；更关键的是各种提升口感的酱料，很有可能热量爆表……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外卖平台上的沙拉套餐往往并没有提供准确的能量表，只是没什么营养学知识的商家随心调配，消费者花了更贵的钱只是买一个心理安慰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不一定奏效就算了，网红减肥餐还可能带来健康风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如代餐虽是营养素补充和减少能量摄入的一种方式，可代餐的营养成分无论如何无法取代均衡的饮食，并且有研究表明，长时间饮用代餐奶昔，会影响肠道蠕动，降低新陈代谢，严重的话会导致机体的内分泌紊乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;代糖产品亦然。吃了糖，人体自会进行葡萄糖代谢反应，进食了代糖，却没有摄入应有的热量，正常的葡萄糖代谢反应会调节减弱，导致随后的葡萄糖耐量下降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生酮饮食的风险更大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据《中国居民膳食指南》的标准，成年人每天摄入能量中，应有55％-65％来自碳水化合物。拒绝碳水化合物的生酮饮食，会让人体所需的能量不足，带来疲劳乏力、胃肠道功能紊乱、心律不齐等副作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《柳叶刀》一项研究表明，碳水化合物的摄入量和预期寿命存在U 形关系，低碳水化合物饮食会缩减预期寿命长达4年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于各种减脂餐来说，其存在的最大bug是，我们可以连吃一个月达到降脂的目的，但我们能吃一辈子吗？一旦不能的话，随之面临的一个问题是：反弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有资深营养师指出：“单一的食物减肥方法其实都是偏离了健康的膳食模式，结果都是越减基础代谢会越低，反弹会越厉害。”长期处于亏空习惯的身体，在接触到碳水、脂肪时进行充分吸收，以帮助机体恢复正常运作水平，体重就会很快反弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不就是“赔了夫人又折兵”？一顿操作猛如虎，最后还是回到老样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;管住嘴，迈开腿&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;到底什么才是真正有效的减肥方法？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实就是老生常谈的六个字，“管住嘴，迈开腿”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;管住嘴不是说不要吃，而是说适当控制饮食，并确保饮食均衡。 《中国居民膳食营养素参考摄入量》写得清楚明白：成年人膳食推荐供能比例为碳水化合物50%-65%，脂肪20%-30%，蛋白质10%-15%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人不是机器，只有摄入足够均衡的营养才能维持正常的代谢。暴饮暴食当然不足取，可如果盲目地节食，一旦摄入量无法覆盖基础代谢，就会对身体带来负效应，造成肌肉、骨质流失。所以哪一种减肥餐，都必须以健康为基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人的胖瘦，不仅与每日摄入的总热量相关，也与每日消耗的总热量相关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果热量盈余，那么身体就会发胖，如果热量消耗大于热量摄入，那么体重就会减少。想要成功减肥，就应该让总摄入的能量低于总消耗的能量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多网红减肥餐，都是在降低摄入上做文章，只是它的低能量摄入已经跌破了健康底线。健康的减脂公式是：热量消耗＞热量摄入＞基础代谢所需热量，身体的热量赤字在总消耗的10%～15%之间。而消耗热量的最好方式，就是迈开腿，动起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以追捧网络上形形色色、价格还不低的网红减肥餐，还真不如老老实实地“管住嘴，迈开腿”。保持正常、均衡饮食，同时确保一定的运动量，或许不会让你立即瘦成竹竿，但会让你拥有均匀的身材和健康的体魄。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何评价历史人物？从“被泼脏水”的隋炀帝说起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Over the years, there are probably very few &quot;tyrants&quot; in history who have not been demonstrated by researchers or history buffs He is &quot;actually a talented and strategic monarch&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, the images of many &quot;tyrants&quot; left in history books, especially their images in traditional literature, are often far from their historical prototypes. After a change of dynasty, if the new dynasty wants to prove its legitimacy, the history books will throw dirty water on it. The identity of the &quot;tyrant&quot; has been recognized, and folk literature and art like to use him to tell erotic and violent stories - after all, deep in human nature, there is such a hobby, but it is not appropriate to place this hobby on a good person, so the &quot;tyrant&quot; &quot;It&#39;s always good to make it very pornographic and violent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fate of popular emperors in literary and artistic works such as Shang Zhou and Sui Yang Emperor is probably always like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the question is, peel off the outer layer of skin, what is the inner layer exposed? Let’s take Emperor Yang of Sui Dynasty as an example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty first came to the throne, he inherited a powerful empire that had not been seen for hundreds of years after the fall of the Han Dynasty, and it was also a huge powder keg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, long-term divisions have been unified in a very short period of time, and some people are dissatisfied with the current regime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, his father, Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty, had some important institutional reforms and policy practices, which were very beneficial from the national level, but felt uncomfortable at the social level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the household registration management in the Sui Dynasty was particularly good. According to official population statistics, the population has increased from 29 million to 46 million in less than 30 years. These 17 million people are definitely not just the result of everyone trying their best to have children when the world is at peace, but the population that was originally hidden has all been plundered. From the perspective of the imperial court, the country had extremely abundant manpower and material resources at its disposal. However, if you look at the perspective of ordinary people at that time, these people did not have to pay taxes or serve in the military. Now all these burdens have been placed on them, and they are not necessarily happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these people are all in disarray, there is nothing they can do even if they are dissatisfied. But Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty also made another major reform, which was to change the three-level local administration of state-prefecture-county to the second-level state-county administration, and abolish the county level. As a result, tens of thousands of people, from county chiefs to ordinary officials, were about to be laid off. From a national level, this is reducing staff and increasing efficiency. But with so many officials losing their vested interests, they will definitely be furious. If the Sui Dynasty returned all the savings to the people, then the people should be very happy to see these people lose their official positions. But the problem is that the Sui Dynasty concentrated all the profits in the court, and the people of the Sui Dynasty did not get any benefits from this reform that could have benefited them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two reforms, together with other new policies, resulted in a great increase in the income of the Sui Dynasty and a decrease in expenditure. Therefore, many scholars have noticed that when it comes to ancient dynasties, it is said that In terms of &quot;national wealth&quot;, it is unmatched by the Sui Dynasty. But at the same time, this also means that as long as someone wants to rebel, there will immediately be tens of thousands of unemployed officials with administrative organizational skills, and tens of millions of dissatisfied people who can take advantage of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty was completely unaware of the existence of this problem. He was from a good background, had a smooth life since childhood, and was really smart. He had no ability to empathize with the pain of ordinary people. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He only saw that there were so many resources in the court now, so he wanted to do big things, so he dug the Grand Canal and conquered Liaodong three times, which were all extreme tests of social endurance. It was not that Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty did not feel that his throne was threatened, but it was not from this huge powder keg, but from the Guanlong Group that the Sui Dynasty relied on for its success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before becoming emperor, Emperor Sui Yang was particularly successful in commanding the war in the south. His ability to win over the southern nobles far exceeded that of the older generation of famous generals and ministers of the Guanlong Group. This gave him the illusion that I have new forces available, and you are nothing special. This intensified the division of the ruling group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the excluded Guanlong dignitaries at the top, the laid-off officials at the middle level, and the ordinary people at the grassroots level who are overwhelmed by heavy labor and taxes will have full anger from top to bottom. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emperor Sui Yang was indeed not the nymphomaniac or sadist in literary works, but when faced with the challenge, he seemed completely unqualified as a politician. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are too willful when things are going well. I don’t want you to think so. I want you to think that you can’t do things and never give up even if you hit a wall. But when it comes to adversity, they lack resilience and willpower, and their willpower collapses immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world was in chaos. When Emperor Sui Yang arrived in Jiangdu, he actually no longer expected to recapture the north. But his troops were all from the north, and they were afraid of not going back, so they were discussing rebellion. A palace maid heard the news and told Queen Xiao. Empress Xiao is still very smart, so you can speak for yourself. As soon as the result was mentioned, Emperor Sui Yang became furious. Are you qualified to say this? Just kill this palace maid. Later, there were more and more news that the army was going to rebel. Queen Xiao told the people in the palace that there was no need to talk to His Majesty. Why add to his worries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in terms of the combat effectiveness of Emperor Sui Yang&#39;s army at that time, it was still very powerful, but at the last moment of his life, Emperor Sui Yang had given up treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The summary is that as a political figure, Emperor Sui Yang:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, he was unable to reconcile complex political and social contradictions;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, Failed to build a core team that was loyal to itself and capable;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, there was no awareness of changing course when the situation started to go unfavorable;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, there was no persistence when the situation was very unfavorable. will. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the things he did, such as building the Grand Canal, you might as well look at it this way: When discussing long-term history, even if a person is an emperor, his influence may not be that important. The study of factors such as finance and taxation, technology diffusion, productivity, economic and social structure is enough to explain the problem, and it might as well not involve character evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To evaluate a character, you need to look at the history of a short period of time. A short period of time in the historical sense is a lifetime for ordinary people. The great social collapse of the late Sui Dynasty triggered by Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty caused the death and displacement of tens of millions of people. This is real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, traditional history books and literary works often apply too much paint to characters. This problem does exist. But if you think the truth is revealed by turning traditional records over, you might as well save it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人贩余华英获死刑，受害家庭：“几十年的辛酸，终于清楚了”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256948]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:16:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, Yu Huaying was charged with child trafficking. Sentenced to death. (Guiyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, the Guiyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court publicly pronounced the verdict on the crime of child abduction and trafficking against the defendant Yu Huaying. Yu Huaying was sentenced to death for child abduction, deprived of political rights for life, and confiscated all personal property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the video shot by the media, Yang Niuhua read the verdict to the parents looking for relatives at the door of the court, hoping that they could all see hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Niuhua was abducted and trafficked by Yu Huaying when she was 5 years old. She successfully found her relatives 25 years later. In 2022, Yang Niuhua reported the case to the police and provided clues, and the child abduction and trafficking case of Yu Huaying was officially filed. (For details, please see the relevant report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/253854?source=134&quot;>;Human trafficker Yu Huaying was sentenced to death: abducted 11 children and also sold her own son&lt;/a a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The trial by Guiyang Intermediate People’s Court found that the defendant Yu Huaying collaborated with Gong Mouliang (deceased) from 1993 to 1996 for profit Illegal interests circulated in Guizhou Province, Chongqing City and other places, looking for suitable children to abduct and traffic. After they succeeded, the two took the abducted children to Handan City, Hebei Province, and through the introduction of Wang Moufu and Yang Moulan, they found a buyer for the sale. , profiting from this, during which a total of 11 children were abducted. The Guiyang Intermediate Court held that the defendant Yu Huaying had repeatedly abducted and trafficked children in order to obtain illegal profits. His behavior constituted the crime of child abduction. The crime was particularly serious and extremely harmful to society and should be severely punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Huaying appealed in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I hope she will die, but I don’t want her to die”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although it was only a first-instance verdict, Cai Huiying, a family member of the victim who attended the sentencing, Feeling devastated, she told her relatives on the phone: &quot;We have finally figured it out after decades of hardship and fatigue. We finally understand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;After Cai Huiying walked out of the court, she started calling her family. The first one is the abducted party - his younger brother Cai Zhansheng. Cai Shengsheng was 6 years old when he was abducted in Zunyi and disappeared with his brother. A few months later, the elder brother came back alone without seeing his younger brother. It was not until the end of 2022, after the Yu Huaying case was filed, that Cai Shengsheng went home through DNA comparison. Thirty years later, Cai Zhansheng can no longer remember many details, but he still remembers Yu Huaying with high cheekbones and a long face. Cai Huiying said that her brother was also very happy to learn that Yu Huaying was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Huiying called her parents for the second time. After his younger brother was lost, his father insisted on going out to look for his relatives for more than 20 years, traveling to Yunnan, Sichuan, Guangxi, Guangdong, Fujian, Henan, Jiangxi and other places. Wherever there was news, my father immediately went out to verify it. He went out with hope again and again, but his hope was shattered again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Logically speaking, my father should hate Yu Huaying very much. But two months ago, when my father learned that the prosecutor recommended the death penalty for Yu Huaying in the first trial, &quot;the first sentence he said was that I hope she (Yu Huaying) dies, but I don&#39;t want her to die.&quot; Cai&#39;s father hopes that Yu Huaying will be sentenced to death because she has brought endless harm and pain to his family; he does not want her to die, but he wants to give her some time to tell the story of the children who have been abducted and trafficked over the years, so that more parents can Find the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Huiying replied to her father: &quot;This is our common idea, but can she do it?&quot; Cai Huiying once attended the first trial. At that time, Yu Hua Ying expressed that he was &quot;unclear&quot; and &quot;cannot remember&quot; many of the circumstances of the crime. Only when talking about his son and daughter, Yu Huaying burst into tears and choked with sobs. This made Cai Huiying quite angry, and she clenched her fists from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Huaying abducted 11 children, involving 8 families. This time the court pronounced its verdict, and relatives from five families came to listen. One mother had two sons abducted, another mother had a son and a daughter abducted, and yet another mother had a son abducted. When Cai Huiying saw the mother who came from Zunyi, after Yu Huaying was sentenced to death, she stood up with excitement and seemed to want to beat her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During lunch, Cai Huiying chatted with several mothers about their respective situations: the children of five families were recovered one after another after Yang Niuhua reported the crime. However, the relationship between the biological family and the foster family is quite complex. Some abducted children find it difficult to cope with the situation, fail to accept family recognition, and rarely come back for reunions. &quot;But we are all grateful to Niuhua, because she reported the crime and we were able to find our relatives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The regret of broken family ties has appeared in many victim families. In Dazu, Chongqing, Bai Ticai, whose son was abducted by Yu Huaying, was completely unaware of the court verdict. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the child had never seen him since the spring of 2020 when he recognized his relatives, and the two had lost contact. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, parents looking for relatives gathered outside the gate of Guiyang Intermediate Hospital. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Encourage parents looking for relatives to &quot;don&#39;t give up&quot;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;On September 18, outside the gate of Guiyang Intermediate Court, there were still three floors inside and three floors outside surrounded by parents who came to look for relatives, just as they did during the court hearing in July. Everyone held a family-searching information board in front of their chests, on which the information about the abducted children was printed in the most conspicuous yellow letters on a red background. The children were still young when they were abducted, and the printed photos show them when they were one or two years old, and most of them are blurry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the court hearing in July, Southern Weekend reporters saw An Shiming, who came to search for his son. He came to the court door early holding a family search information board to broadcast live. This time when the verdict was announced, he once again came early with some parents looking for relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Cai Huiying arrived before 8 o&#39;clock, more parents saw this search than at the first trial. She stood far away and did not dare to walk into the crowd. &quot;I felt that as soon as I stood there and heard what they said, I naturally couldn&#39;t control the emotion.&quot; For parents who are still looking for relatives, Cai Huiying feels that what she can say is feeble: &quot;Have more courage and continue.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Niuhua Dare to speak to parents looking for relatives. In a live media broadcast after the trial, she once again encouraged parents looking for their children not to give up. She mentioned her own example: the first time she took blood to find her relatives was in 2012, but there has been no news in the past ten years. But in 2021, in just over a month, she miraculously found her home through the short video platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After finding a home, Yang Niuhua lived in Hebei, Yu Huaying was in Chongqing, and the trafficking case occurred in Guizhou. The three places were far apart. It seemed that it was very difficult to find human traffickers. Disaster. But now, Yu Huaying has been punished by law. &quot;Really never give up,&quot; Yang Niuhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before and after every court session, Yang Niuhua’s schedule is tight and busy. On the one hand, families looking for relatives hope to take this opportunity to spread the information about finding relatives, and find her to live broadcast and record videos together; on the other hand, media interviews continue, and Yang Niuhua repeatedly recounts her experience of being abducted and the hardships of growing up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sister Sang Ying felt a little distressed when she saw Yang Niuhua always rushing ahead. Both sisters were actually victims. After Yang Niuhua was abducted in 1995, her parents were extremely sad and died in 1997 and 1998 respectively. Sangying lost her home and was forced to go out to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电诈受害者的银行卡困境:报案后要被冻结多久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256940]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/2ea2e16682.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/2ea2e16682. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 10, 2023, the Beijing police were promoting anti-email fraud. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within a week of being defrauded of more than 30,000 yuan, Shenzhen citizen Li Zheng kept asking the police, The bank proved that she was sober and would no longer transfer money to the scammer. On the day she was defrauded, all the debit cards and credit cards in her name were taken protective stop-payment measures by the police and could not be used. The reason was to prevent her from being defrauded again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called protective stop payment means that in order to protect the victim from further losses, the payment function of the bank card is stopped. Only transfers can be made, but transfers and cash withdrawals cannot be made. The customer service of Li Zheng&#39;s bank card bank informed him that the one-month payment stop measure for bank accounts that are likely to be defrauded again is consistent across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protective stop payment suddenly made Li Zheng unable to use her bank card to buy groceries, take a car, or even pay school fees for her children. She felt extremely inconvenienced. She found that she was not the only one trying to lift the protective stop payment. There were victims across the country who encountered the same problem. Many of them were still burdened with mortgages and were so anxious that they didn&#39;t know what to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The card was frozen after taking the initiative to report the crime&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 7, 2023, Li Zheng was on the noisy street when she received a fraud call. The other party asked her to confirm that her social account was in the security center. The &quot;million protection insurance&quot; is not free. Li Zheng hurried to do things and didn&#39;t want to pay attention to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person on the other end of the phone said it would only take a few minutes, just follow the instructions to confirm. Li Zheng listened to the other party&#39;s voice on the road, and responded intermittently. He downloaded a &quot;bank APP&quot; according to the other party&#39;s request, entered different business numbers and order numbers back and forth, and tried to see whether the transfer was successful, starting from 7 yuan to 8 yuan. Small transfers ranging from RMB 20,000 to large transfers of more than 20,000 yuan. After turning the corner and walking into a secluded place, she suddenly realized that she had been cheated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zheng immediately hung up on the scammer and dialed 110 to call the police. At this time, she had transferred more than 30,000 yuan to the scammer, and she didn&#39;t know whether she could get it back. The Futian Police Station of the Futian Branch of the Shenzhen Municipal Public Security Bureau quickly received the call and called her to wait where she was for the time being. A police car would be sent to pick her up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Police from the police station took her for questioning and taking notes. Li Zheng said that at that time, the police only froze the suspect&#39;s account and did not mention that they would implement a protective stop payment on his bank card. The police also uploaded the report details to the national anti-fraud APP, and you can also see relevant information when you log in later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9 o&#39;clock that night, police officers from the Nanshan Branch Merchants Police Station where Li Zheng lived came to her door, asked her if she had been defrauded, and spread anti-fraud knowledge to her. Li Zheng thought that the handling of the fraud case had come to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when she was about to pay with her mobile phone the next day, she discovered that the two debit cards and one credit card in her name could no longer be used. After consulting the account bank, she learned that it was a protective stop payment operated by the anti-fraud police and was frozen for one month according to regulations. If she wanted to lift it, she could consult the Nanshan Branch Anti-Fraud Center. However, Li Zheng found that the call was not easy to get through, so he complained through the national anti-fraud hotline 96110. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Li Zheng received police calls from Futian Police Station, Shenzhen Public Security Bureau, and Futian Branch. The answers they received were all &quot;In order to protect you from being deceived again, your bank card needs to be frozen for one month.&quot; Li Zheng did not agree with this. She took the initiative to report the crime when she realized that she had been deceived, and she also suffered property losses. &quot;How could it be possible to transfer money to the scammer again?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She believed that the stop-payment measure had caused her many problems. It is inconvenient that bank cards are needed for food and clothing at home and for company transactions. Now everything is &quot;immobilized&quot;. However, the credit card still needs to be repaid and may face the risk of overdue payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, at Li Zheng’s strong request, the police accompanied her to withdraw more than 7,000 yuan from two cards. Despite this, she believes that it is still difficult to maintain daily life because the debit card cannot be transferred and the credit card cannot be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the Anti-Fraud Center of the Nanshan Branch to inquire. The staff of the Anti-Fraud Center stated that the bank card under Li Zheng’s name was indeed in a “protective stop payment” status and would stop payment within 48 hours. The payment will continue to circulate until one month. How to cancel it can be consulted with the Nanshan Branch. But before that, Li Zheng had communicated with the Nanshan Branch Investment Police Station many times, but the payment stop could not be lifted. Futian branch police told Southern Weekend reporters that what Li Zheng encountered was an ordinary telecommunications fraud case. The matter of lifting the protective stop payment has been communicated and coordinated with the Nanshan branch. More details of the case cannot be disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Li Zheng rushed between two police stations, she discovered that the situation she encountered was not an isolated case. There were many victims of electronic fraud at the scene who came to complain about frozen bank cards. On the Internet, there are also victims on various social media asking how to lift the protective stop payment. Their ID addresses include Jiangsu, Hubei, Zhejiang, Fujian, Anhui, etc.: &quot;The stop payment on the 21st of last month has not been lifted yet. Do you know how to deal with it? &quot;I still have bank mortgages affected&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;The original intention is to prevent &quot;obsession&quot;&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhi, a lawyer at Beijing Yingke (Shenzhen) Law Firm Hao has been paying attention to card unfreezing cases for a long time and provides legal consultation on unfreezing cards. According to his understanding, the protective stop payment originally originated from the &quot;card disconnection&quot; operation in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, on October 10, 2020, the State Council convened an inter-ministerial joint meeting to combat new illegal crimes in telecommunications networks and decided to launch a nationwide &quot;card disconnection&quot; operation from that date. The main purpose is to deal with a major root cause of the continued high incidence of telecom network fraud - the out-of-control management of phone cards and bank cards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Guo Zhihao said that after the &quot;card disconnection&quot; campaign began, the number of bank cards frozen due to the inflow of unknown funds increased. He received hundreds of inquiries about unfreezing cards a week, among which protection Inquiries about sexual cessation of payment also appear occasionally, but the overall proportion is low. From 2020 to 2022, among the 100 cases inquiring about unfreezing cards, only one or two were protective stop payments; since 2023, the number of consultations on such cases has increased, with four or five out of 100 cases. Regarding the protective stop payment, Guo Zhihao suggested that if the client does not need to use the bank card urgently, there is no need to find a lawyer to represent him, because most of them will be automatically lifted after one month, and &quot;the tossing and tossing is only a week or two in advance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the reason for the increase in the number of stop-payment inquiries, Guo Zhihao did not find any new public documents in 2023. It should only be implementation adjustments in individual regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that since June 2023, public security agencies in many places across the country have issued the &quot;Notice on Carrying out Anti-Fraud Dissuasion and Protective Emergency Stop of Payments&quot;, in which the time and method of lifting the payment stop are specified. Different expressions: The Yuanzhou Branch of the Public Security Bureau of Yichun City, Jiangxi Province mentioned in an announcement on June 7: “If you have transferred money to the account involved in fraud, the branch will immediately implement a protective stop payment on your account, 48 It can be lifted on your own after an hour.&quot;; The Public Security Bureau of Xining City, Qinghai Province reminded in an announcement in August: &quot;If the bank account under your name only accepts payments but does not pay, please go to the nearest public security agency as soon as possible to explain the situation and request to lift the suspension. Pay and restore the normal use of the bank card.&quot; Guo Zhihao believes that the original intention of stopping payments in various places is the same, to prevent victims from being obsessed with transferring money to fraudulent accounts again, but there are no clear regulations on implementation standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted a victim who had been &quot;obsessed&quot; during the interview. Chen Qiang, a 27-year-old doctoral student in Guangzhou, was deeply involved in an investment and stock fraud group in July. It was a well-designed scam. When opening an account, the other party could verify it via video. The transfer provided was a third-party public account, and the company existed and was operating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Qiang was convinced and transferred &quot;investment&quot; to the account for three consecutive days. On July 19, the anti-fraud police took him to the police station and told him that he was transferring money to an &quot;early warning account.&quot; Chen Qiang didn&#39;t believe it at all. &quot;I can&#39;t be cheated.&quot; The police repeatedly &quot;educated&quot; him for two hours and asked him about his behavior. The account adopts a 48-hour emergency payment stop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Qiang was doubtful and told the scammer the information that he had been tipped to be deceived. The scammer first sent him a private message, telling him that he had also been called to the police station because of the company&#39;s bank account risk. The &quot;agency&quot; was currently investigating and it would not affect investment safety. The next day, the &quot;agency&quot; issued a processing notice. After several operations, Chen Qiang believed in the liar again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the emergency stop payment, Chen Qiang continued to transfer money to the scammer. It was not until a few days later that the scammer induced him to invest all his money. Chen Qiang suddenly realized that his more than 50,000 yuan had been locked and could not be withdrawn. . Chen Qiang admitted that it took him several days to get out of the scam, and the 48-hour emergency stop payment did play a role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case is not rare. Wang Xueni, who lives in Zhejiang, was not aware of the problem when she was defrauded on August 11. It was not until the public security organs discovered that the fraudster&#39;s bank account had received transfers from her, prompting her that she was experiencing telecommunications network fraud. On the same day, she went to the police station to be questioned by the police, and all bank cards began to stop payment for 32 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another victim in Guangzhou, Lin Qingqing, was prompted by the police to report the crime to the local police station and take notes. However, Lin Qingqing said that the process of lifting the payment stop went smoothly. After filling out the &quot;Application Form for Lifting Protective Stop Payment&quot; at the Anti-Fraud Center, police from the police station near her residence came to verify and conduct anti-fraud propaganda. Soon her bank card was unfrozen. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Application Form for Lifting Protective Stop Payment&quot; posted by Lin Qingqing on her social account, in addition to basic information, the form also requires filling in &quot;whether you have met with the police to dissuade you&quot;; The purpose of the stopped payment bank card after the stop payment is lifted. The transaction details must indicate to whom the transfer is to be made, and the reasons for the transfer should be attached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the process of lifting the payment stop is not smooth for many netizens. On Zhihu, a netizen with an IP address in Jiangxi said that the local police had stopped payment, and after the lifting, over-the-counter transactions were still restricted. A netizen in Jiangsu said that it would take 40 days to lift the local payment stop, and he had to go there in person; some people were very panicked. He said that he was about to repay the loan, and he didn’t know when the stop payment measure would be lifted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f282d2ba16.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f282d2ba16.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Application Form for Lifting Protective Stop Payment&quot; posted online by Lin Qingqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Post-disaster reconstruction&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Qiang describes his life after being cheated It is &quot;post-disaster reconstruction&quot;. He had been attending school all these years and what little savings he had was wiped out in this fraud. &quot;After being deceived, I would even hesitate to eat beef noodles for 15 yuan.&quot; Chen Qiang said, and what is even more suffocating is that such days are expected to continue for more than a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, he reflected on his greed and arrogance, and felt ridiculous about his performance when he first entered the police station, &quot;(his) attitude was very bad.&quot; After he came to his senses, he called the police who took the notes at the time and asked if there was any possibility of recovery. The other party told him that it was difficult to recover overseas fraud, not to mention that it had been too long since the transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Chen Qiang hopes that &quot;post-disaster reconstruction&quot; will go smoothly. Seven days after he stopped transferring money and got out of the scam completely, he received a call from the public security bureau in his hometown, informing him that all bank card payments would be suspended for one month. &quot;After finally being defrauded, I looked away, but my card was blocked.&quot; Chen Qiang said he didn&#39;t know how long the payment stop would last. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xueni also mentioned the anxiety after her bank card was stopped. She called the police and the bank where she opened her account many times to ask when the payment stop would be lifted, but the other party only said &quot;wait a little longer.&quot; Before the accident, she had borrowed a micro loan, and after the payment stopped, she could only borrow money to repay. Before she knew the exact time to unfreeze, she was very worried about not being able to repay the money she borrowed from friends. Wang Xueni did not tell her family that she had been cheated, and she had no money to use after the payment was stopped, so it was easy for her to reveal her secret. Because of this, she couldn&#39;t eat or sleep well. &quot;A protective stop payment is actually a punishment for the person who was defrauded. Let yourself remember this lesson.&quot; Wang Xueni said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zheng does not agree with the term &quot;lesson&quot;. She believes that she is a victim and being deceived is already a huge lesson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, there are many posts seeking relief from payment stoppages. Zhu Jingxian from Zhejiang was defrauded of 630,000 yuan due to her husband&#39;s negligence. After reporting the crime, her bank card was frozen for 48 hours. However, 25 days after the incident, the bank card was still protected from payment, and at the same time, various street police stations were called to inquire about the situation of being defrauded. After 35 days, his bank card was still unresolved. After explaining the situation to the Public Security Bureau, he had to wait another 48 hours for a reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zheng understands the netizen who posted the message. She believes that the specific situation should be analyzed in detail. Victims who have awakened can lift the payment stop early, rather than applying a blanket approach. On September 13, police from the China Merchants Police Station unfrozen all the credit cards in Li Zheng&#39;s name and temporarily unfrozen a savings card so that she could repay the company loan first. Li Zheng said that on September 14, the person in charge of the Futian Police Station informed him that the police station had internal discussions on the case and believed that there was a problem of insufficient exchange of information within the police, and that the police should be considerate of citizens&#39; demands and help solve the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（除郭志浩外，文中均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大科学装置“夸父”首次亮相]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256934]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The sun is the source of life&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sun is a symbol of light&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, humans want to create a &quot;sun&quot; on the earth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let energy be inexhaustible, water clear and sky blue, and life sustainable&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency reporter&#39;s exclusive visit&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;China’s large scientific installation &quot;CRAFT&quot; under construction&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at this research platform&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to develop an &quot;engine&quot; for the future &quot;artificial sun&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/a963d796ae46fc31456463f2c9833a29.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot; 634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/a963d796ae46fc31456463f2c9833a29.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rendering of the &quot;Kuafu&quot; park (Photo courtesy of the Institute of Plasma Physics, Hefei Institute of Physical Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scientific name of &quot;Kuafu&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fusion Reactor Host Key System Comprehensive Research Facility (CRAFT)&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a major national science and technology infrastructure project established during the &quot;13th Five-Year Plan&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;December 2018 Approved to start construction in May&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected to be fully completed by the end of 2025&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18 /72f3a1a844b0a5a10a625b33b41fcbe0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/72f3a1a844b0a5a10a625b33b41fcbe0.png&quot; data -key=&quot;251114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The actual construction scene of the &quot;Kuafu&quot; park taken on September 11. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhou Mu&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From scratch&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China’s scientific researchers and project builders work day and night&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While building and using at the same time&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the &quot;Kuafu&quot; park has been delivered and put into use&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come, let&#39;s &quot;ride&quot; a drone&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Have a taste of the majesty of &quot;Kuafu&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/d5a2f74e5b6917a7281e18ba39ef16a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/d5a2f74e5b6917a7281e18ba39ef16a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/859da3df9eb8f315ac8bde9a98f1857e.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/18/859da3df9eb8f315ac8bde9a98f1857e.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The growth of all things depends on the sun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sun shines and heats because of the internal Nuclear fusion reaction&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a &quot;sun&quot; could be built on the earth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humanity is expected to achieve energy freedom&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humanity began to research nuclear fusion energy in the mid-20th century&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Our country started the dream of &quot;artificial sun&quot; in the 1970s&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After several generations of scientific research workers&#39; relay efforts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China has now completed the construction of the &quot;artificial sun&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&quot;Eastern Superring (EAST)&quot;, &quot;Chinese Circulator&quot;, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A batch of &quot;artificial sun&quot; experimental devices&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A number of major achievements have been achieved&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f03086a0e373dcc66506720de669e12b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;863&quot; height=&quot;1294&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f03086a0e373dcc66506720de669e12b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China’s independently developed EAST device&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Has more than 200 core technologies and nearly 2,000 patents&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gathering &quot;ultra-high temperature&quot;, &quot;ultra-low temperature&quot; and &quot;ultra-high vacuum&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ultra-strong magnetic field&quot; and &quot;ultra-large current&quot; cutting-edge Technology in one furnace&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/bbe72b3589ffbb990f5c0dc75f7827a7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1000&quot; height=&quot;838&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/bbe72b3589ffbb990f5c0dc75f7827a7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On this basis, China&#39;s next generation &quot;artificial sun&quot; -&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Fusion Engineering Experimental Reactor (CFETR) has completed the engineering design&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Key technologies are being studied for the construction of CFETR&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;It is the main mission of &quot;Kuafu&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with EAST&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CFETR will be larger, higher, more precise and more advanced&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Currently in the laboratory of &quot;Kuafu&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can already see the prototype of some components of CFETR&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, this huge &quot;orange petal&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/b5ee6877a7d005912032db75b6125974.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1778&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/b5ee6877a7d005912032db75b6125974.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an important part of the future &quot;artificial sun&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The appearance is spectacular&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scientific and technological connotation of &quot;Kuafu&quot; is even more impressive&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Kuafu in ancient Chinese myths and legends&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heart-minded Ambition, yearning for the bright, not afraid of hardships, and courageous to pursue dreams&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 100 domestic cooperation units&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 60 international cooperation units&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 1,000 builders &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than 5 years&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overcoming a series of scientific research and engineering technical problems&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/18/316d9093e6869944dd0436025acd1e96.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/18/316d9093e6869944dd0436025acd1e96.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, the staff at &quot;Kuafu &quot;Installation and debugging equipment in the park. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhou Mu&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/244c718348dc72838a1e15059416ebd1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;670&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/244c718348dc72838a1e15059416ebd1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, this is the actual generator of the early fusion device in the &quot;Kuafu&quot; park that symbolizes the spirit of self-reliance and hard work. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhou Mu&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Toward the light&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Towards a better future&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China’s &quot;Kuafu&quot; is working hard to move forward&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《装腔启示录》导演李漠：梅菲斯托在身边]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256868]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/FM7VX0iOsJ6arOkmiBSYPNhTTwMO1lKzTzZnPSPd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/FM7VX0iOsJ6arOkmiBSYPNhTTwMO1lKzTzZ nPSPd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Li Mo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewed (Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a Douban review of the TV series &quot;Apocalypse of Acting&quot;, Li Mo, the director of the show, wrote that he has &quot;professionally acted as an actor for 30 years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In junior high school, he couldn&#39;t stand the smell of sweat in the boys&#39; dormitory, so he sprayed on a Saint Laurent women&#39;s perfume, becoming the first person among his classmates to wear perfume (later he compromised for Nivea&#39;s because the smell was too strong) Walking beads of sweat). At the book rental shop in front of the school, he avoided Jin Yong, Gu Long, and Liang Yusheng, who were all reading, and picked up a copy of Freud&#39;s &quot;Introduction to Psychoanalysis.&quot; Later, because I despised popular philosophy, I read a few pages of Hegel&#39;s &quot;Little Logic&quot;. He has studied Shakespeare&#39;s sonnets and pondered the differences between ancient and modern English expressions. After watching &quot;007&quot;, he went to the bar to imitate James Bond and order a Martini. He was once a professional music student, playing the guqin since elementary school. He gained his rock and roll enlightenment from Radiohead&#39;s &quot;Ok, Computer&quot; and has been playing in the band for more than ten years. He mainly plays guitar, plays drums, is the lead singer, does programming, and plays bass. He was admitted to the Conservatory of Music, dropped out after one year and was admitted to the Beijing Film Academy. He struggled for nearly ten years to become a director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This all explains his excitement when he saw the novel &quot;The Pretender Revelation&quot;. &quot;Closing the book, I thought, probably no one is better at filming this than me. Clear yet euphemistic, hypocritical yet sincere, timid yet brave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the TV series &quot;Pretend&quot;, adapted from the novel of the same name, &quot;Revelations&quot; was broadcast, with a Douban score of 8.1, becoming his third Douban score of 8 after &quot;I&#39;m Very Good in a Foreign Country&quot; (2021, a score of 8.1) and &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot; (2022, a score of 8.4) The above works. For current domestic TV drama directors, this achievement is impressive enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/T1a3hqh7ssxmzIxwXb5AT5XoqEoaWNA8s4ZPhDc8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/T1a3hqh7ssxmzIxwXb5AT5XoqEoaWNA8s4ZPhDc8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Mo plays a policeman in &quot;I&#39;m Very Good in a Foreign Country&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three dramas in three years, all focusing on the plight of contemporary urban youth. &quot;I&#39;m Good in a Foreign Country&quot; tells the story of strangers in a big city who experience various tests in life, career, and relationships while wandering. In &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot;, the protagonist Zhao Sanyue accidentally works as a makeup artist in a funeral parlor, witnessing the life and death of the deceased, and reflecting the portraits of all living beings. The story of &quot;Apocalypse of Pretending&quot; takes place in Beijing CBD. Investment banking elite Xu Ziquan and lawyer Tang Ying meet. While coping with the pressure of work, they try their best to maintain an elegant urban life. From testing each other to gradually letting go of their guard, they Come together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Mo, who was born in 1988, experienced similar difficulties. After graduating from college, he played the piano, made movies, wrote novels, became a teacher, and almost took the Ph.D. exam, saying that he &quot;wanted everything.&quot; Finally, under the guidance of his mentor, he carefully read the &quot;Heart Sutra&quot; and &quot;Diamond Sutra&quot;, calmed down to get inspiration from religion, and was more sure of the answer in his heart: &quot;I just want to do the work of expression and creation. I You can experience a different life.&quot; Being a director is his current way of expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/MBhjCuHSJicaNAGq0yKfmTzIsjDx8iMtxu5Jiqj8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/MBhjCuHSJicaNAGq0yKfmTzIsjDx8iMtxu5Jiqj8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;The Apocalypse&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Mo&#39;s WeChat name is Mephisto (Mephisto), and his WeChat signature is: &quot;I can give you everything you want, but you just pay yourself.&quot; (I can give you everything you want, but you have to pay your soul.) They come from the poetic drama &quot;Faust&quot; created by the German writer Johann Wolfgang von Goethe . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book, Faust is getting old, studying in a dark study for half his life, and feels extremely tired. At this time, the demon Mephisto comes and lures him to sign an agreement: to satisfy everything he had during his lifetime. Asked to take his soul until his death. This is also a bet between Mephisto and God. In pursuit of truth, Faust went through many hardships and traveled all the paths that humans have pursued. He often failed and sank, but he did not give up and finally gained salvation. Li Mo likes this work very much and has read it many times. He feels that Faust and Mephisto are the two sides of human beings. &quot;As people grow up, the soul seems to be less and less important. I wrote that sentence in my signature, hoping that all the people I know will think of this when they see it: If it is not so important, it will be in you. If you don’t even explore it, how about selling your soul? After Faust experienced everything, he found that the soul is the most important. This is the meaning of Mephisto. I want to be a Mephisto by my side People, remind everyone, remind me, give you everything, sell your soul, okay?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/16/C9UzP4aOLdFWxcahhdVh9OxRytG7qk1xOTnIljuN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16 /C9UzP4aOLdFWxcahhdVh9OxRytG7qk1xOTnIljuN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Li Mo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Powerlessness&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is the most&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;ability&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;The dilemma of urbanites that makes me empathize&lt;/strong>;——Conversation with Li Mo&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Positive expression of &quot;I love you&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In &quot;The Apocalypse of Pretending&quot;, Xu Ziquan wrote a perfume name for Tang Ying, but it was not the one in the original work One. There are many similar details in the play. Did you change these? Why do we need to change this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The model in the original book has been discontinued. A lot of the modifications were made in the hope that it would become closer to the present. I predict that people will be sensitive to these things. For example, the Le Labo balm that Xu Ziquan used on the plane at the beginning of the play was not mentioned in the original work. That is one of my personal favorites. I find it very convenient and can take it with me on the plane at any time. Later I learned that that one had also been discontinued, but it was still in production when I was writing the script. I want to change the TV series to be closer to some of my life (actual situations), and the wine used in it is also the same. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How the props are presented is part of the expression. This is not about selling goods. I think people like him probably use such things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is there a proposal scene in the ending? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many lines are carried over from the book, but the act of proposing is not in the book. Because the play is over, I hope to give the audience a sense of closure, a ceremonial explanation. He proposed, not got married. I don&#39;t think they got married. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a big difference between proposing and getting married. Proposing means my determination and intention. I want to be with you forever. I didn’t say we’d grow old together, but I wanted to build our own world with you. I know that we may encounter many difficulties after entering marriage, but I believe that you and I have the ability to live our lives the way we want. This is the determination I want to say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Idealism and materialism are not contradictory. I thought so in my heart. I want to take some actions to prove it. When I have the financial resources, I will buy a diamond ring to express my love to my lover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I put such a scene in the ending just to tell the audience that Xu Ziquan is a sincere person. Many viewers thought he was handsome, his butt was perky, he owned a car and a house, and he was a financial man... so they concluded that this (proposal) was not true, that this love was a fairy tale, and that he could not like a third-year lawyer so much. ——It looks like that. But love is not a business. There is no reason to fall in love with someone. I just love you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the time of the final proposal, Xu Ziquan&#39;s view of love had changed. He was willing to build &quot;our world&quot; with Tang Ying, and was willing to turn one person&#39;s life into &quot;our two lives.&quot; , I think this is the value and meaning of marriage proposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am willing to advocate the positive expression of I love you and my willingness in my plays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this also your view on love? This positive expression and belief? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I keep exploring what love is before I can believe in it. I believe love begins when I meet my wife. A large part of Xu Ziquan is my projection. He didn&#39;t think there was such a person in the world who could support me, who could see the worst in me and still love me, who could tolerate me and understand me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Ying is the one who talks about love and understands love. Xu Ziquan understands teasing and skills. He knows how to make people like him. I like the scene in the bathroom the most. When Xu Ziquan was very bad, Tang Ying did not criticize him for being bad, but told him: You should tell me that you are not in a good state, you should share with me, and you should tell him that you are not in good condition. Show me your good side, don&#39;t worry, I can catch it, I think you are the best, you don&#39;t even know how good you are. This is a moment that I have experienced in my life, which makes me feel that I am loved, wrapped and supported by others. She made me feel that even though I was in such a bad state, I had such mood swings, my career was at a low point, and I couldn&#39;t see the future, she still didn&#39;t despise me, didn&#39;t measure me based on these, and didn&#39;t condemn me. She told me: I love you, you don’t even know how good you are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That moment made me understand what love is. It turns out that love is not about asking or giving, but about giving to each other. It means being able to see the worst side of him and still love him. This is the concept of love I want to tell you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/RUmrzlT0NgeYRX9rp0B9x0P0HAmubDRtmCGSdJwj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/RUmrzlT0NgeYRX9rp0B9x0P0HAmubDRtmCGSdJwj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;The Pretender Apocalypse&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;No results will come if you don’t work hard None&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said you like Han Dongjun (playing Xu Zi Quan), why does this feeling of fatigue touch you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the people in the circle I want to talk about are not worthy of saying they are tired or saying they have worked hard. They earn more money. In the context of the play, it is unacceptable for people who earn more money to suffer miserably. But when he truly comes into contact with the lives of these people and their difficulties, he cannot tell others that he is tired, miserable, or unhappy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You work in CBD, you are so busy, you were admitted to Peking University and Tsinghua University, you graduated from the fourth department of the fifth college, you went to the red circle institute, you went to SDIC, you did it Middle level, this life is already at its peak, what else do you want? What else are you miserable about? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The worst thing about them is that they are not qualified to say they are miserable. There are seniors and juniors above them, and there are competitors beside them. If they make a mistake, they will be overthrown by others. No one can see the current situation of their lives. People think you deserve it, you deserve it. Why do you scream miserably? I can&#39;t even eat, I don&#39;t even scream miserably. You live in fine clothes and food every day, and go to luxurious occasions. Why are you so miserable? So I can&#39;t scream for them in this scene. I can only show their state. This is the feeling of fatigue. He can&#39;t express it. He can only smile and say to people, yes, you are right. This is how I feel about the people I know. Of course I don&#39;t think they are miserable either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I want to talk about this group of people, I have to capture the most unique part of this group of people. For me, this part is that these people are very tired, but they can’t express it. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You filmed &quot;I&#39;m Good in a Foreign Country&quot; and &quot;Three &quot;Joy Has a New Life&quot; and &quot;Pretending to Be Apocalypse&quot; have received good reviews. What do you hope to express? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;They are all about urban life, and they are all about the plight of urban young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been in trouble before, and maybe I am in trouble now. Difficulties will help people grow and hone themselves better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which dilemmas in the drama are you most sympathetic to? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s the feeling of powerlessness at work. I clearly know that this thing can be done well, and I know how to do it well, but I just can&#39;t do it. At times like this, I feel very small in this city. I don’t know what the problem is, I’ve done everything I can, but things are still like this. This is the plight of urbanites that resonates most with me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I want to tell you more, don’t give up in the face of this dilemma. Giving up is a kind of self-protection, because if you don’t have expectations, you won’t be disappointed or hurt. Whether facing work, love or family relationships, they all protect themselves in a way of withdrawal. It&#39;s fine if I&#39;m alone, it&#39;s fine if I don&#39;t go up, it&#39;s fine if I lie down, and I still get paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even so, we should try. How terrible is failure? How terrible is falling out of love? Sometimes I feel that falling out of love is a very happy thing. I can feel many emotions that I can&#39;t usually feel. What a valuable life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You see, everything I talked about is quite idealistic. The material aspect is also important, but in fact you can live no matter what, and you don’t have to make a lot of money. The main thing is to figure out the standard of living you want, and if you do well in what you do today, it will be great. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you feel like you have gotten out of this predicament now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s hard to get out. I still feel powerless. Even if I feel I have done more than before, I still have things to do. Less than. The longer I work, the more powerless I feel. There are very few things that people can control. The director seems to have quite a lot of power and can decide many things, but I can&#39;t decide whether it will rain today or whether there will be a meeting tomorrow. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you feel powerless, it means you have not found the right way to get along with the world. Once you find it, you can feel the support the world gives you, rather than you and the world. opposition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you begin to feel that the world was giving you help and support? Not resistance? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I am not fighting with the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The powerlessness brought about by the current social structure The feeling may not be resolved. The reality is that our efforts may not necessarily bring positive returns, and individuals cannot achieve a change in their destiny just by working hard. Have you ever thought about this reality in your expression? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Mo: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I plan to talk to you about this in a later project. It is about a young man born in the 2000s who has been very ambitious since he was a child. , was admitted to a very good university in Beijing, and enrolled in 2019. After three years of the COVID-19 epidemic, I couldn’t find a job after graduation. I am currently writing a script and will film this project next year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think now is an era of change, which is different from before. Everyone must accept the change. Every generation will face changes in the times, such as social fluctuations, wars, and changes, so there is no need to panic. You said that in the face of structural problems, people need to adjust their goals and self-positioning in the face of this era. It does not mean that the times have changed and I will not get the same results as in the previous era if I work hard, so I don&#39;t work hard. Efforts in this era will have results in this era. Without efforts, there will be no results. Working hard is not a choice, working hard is what you should do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe when I finish filming the scene next year, I can bring some discussion to everyone. I want to tell everyone how to be down-to-earth in that scene. But I still want to tell you here, don’t give up. When you are lying down in this era, a group of people who are not lying down will take away the opportunity. This is the case in every era. The opportunities you give up will be taken away by others. If you work hard, you may find opportunities. Facing life positively is not a bad thing in any era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>