<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[做人生转折时刻的强者：不作无谓的精神消耗，而是活在意义之中]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257940]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;People have different attitudes and approaches when encountering major turning points. Most people panic and are in a dilemma. In contrast, the narrative of a Weibo blogger gives people a refreshing and enlightening feeling, which is quite enlightening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Weibo blogger recounted that her husband’s unemployment happened suddenly. In the morning, he was still complaining about too many people on the subway and was a few minutes late. Then he sent her a message saying: I was in a meeting and something was wrong. Condition. It turned out that after their project was launched, there were so many bad reviews that his boss was completely heartbroken. After a weekend of thinking, he decided to dissolve the company immediately. While there was still money in the company&#39;s books, more than 200 people in the company were given N+1 Everyone rushes towards their own future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course this is a responsible boss who treats his employees well enough, but for the workers, the bleak ending is already a fact. Her first reaction was that although the incident was sudden, unemployment was a foregone conclusion and she needed to plan for the next step immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Their rent in Beijing just ends on September 30. She came to his company to confirm: disbandment is a foregone conclusion. After completing the formalities today, she won’t have to go to work tomorrow. She got N+1 beautifully. The two then spent 10 minutes analyzing the pros and cons, and decided to discuss it with the landlord, quit the rent on the 30th, and move back to Chengdu before the National Day. Next, he went to resign, and she contacted the landlord and the agent, explained the situation, and went through the check-in procedures for the two cats. She also immediately placed an order for the cartons, tape, plastic wrap and other things needed for the move and had them delivered in the same city. Then I announced to my close friends that I was leaving Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the standard performance of a time management master: when he left the company at 15:00, she had already made a list of what things at home needed to be unused and what things should be kept for return to Chengdu. . At 17:00, the agent came to take photos. She canceled her flight and hotel booking to Seoul for the weekend and rebooked her flight back to Chengdu. Around 19:00, she was already posting like crazy in the community’s idle group. At 20:00, she called two other more experienced good friends to help her husband revise his resume and teach him interview experience for the next job, because he had not moved around since graduation and had no experience in finding a job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is my attitude towards life. Now that I have decided, there is no need to delay for one more second. Look forward, the sooner the better.&quot; Her emotion triggered the reaction of many netizens. Sadness and sympathy. In the face of such a thrilling fate, how could a person calmly make a handover with fate in just a few minutes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 20 years ago, I once &quot;drifted to the North&quot; for several months. In order to compete for a position in a magazine, for a whole month, I went from &quot;audition&quot; to &quot;audition&quot; among hundreds of people. Semi-finals&quot; and even the 4-person &quot;finals&quot;. When I finally lost my job opportunity with another &quot;unlucky guy&quot; because I didn&#39;t have a college degree, I was immersed in the emotions of shock, dissatisfaction, and unwillingness. It took a long time before I hesitated and went south in frustration. Compared with this &quot;time management master&quot;&#39;s never-procrastinating style, I am really ashamed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are always disappointments in life, and unemployment is just one of them. When people reach middle age, some people get divorced, lose their spouses, lose their close friends, or encounter other unfortunate things. It’s not surprising to feel down and up and down at this point. So people often advise &quot;caged people&quot; to go out and relax. It has to be said that traveling far away does help to relieve the mood. However, regardless of whether you have the intention to go out, even if you go out, the troubles hanging in the air will continue to affect your mood. Didn’t you see that some of the wanderers became even more depressed after they came back? Therefore, this method of shelving conflicts and pain and adjusting time and space is not the best solution. The best solution is actually &quot;long-term pain is worse than short-term pain&quot;, do whatever you need to do, and never be sloppy or indecisive. The aforementioned blogger set an example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively, because the blogger was mentally prepared and built up for her husband&#39;s unemployment, instead of being suddenly laid off, when the moment did come, the blow he suffered was naturally less severe. What&#39;s more, since the compensation can be described as generous, it has also greatly relieved the bitter taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is not the key reason why he can maintain a calm and free style in times of turmoil. The key reason is to &quot;cut through the mess with a quick knife.&quot; Whether it is dealing with large or small matters and trivial matters, or making an immediate decision to move, it all reflects the philosophy of using speed to make things easier, and using pain to get rid of pain. Turning pages so quickly can minimize the impact of shock. Selling away most of the company-related artifacts is also to erase traces of the old job as soon as possible and reduce memory trauma. It is conceivable that at that time, their minds were occupied with other important things, so how could they squeeze in the pain? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be thought from this that modern people are greatly superior to the ancients in terms of material living conditions. But why does it seem that our stress is much greater than that of people in the past? Why do so many people seem to be depressed today? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, today we are indeed in a state of &quot;volume&quot; in many affairs, and pressure exists objectively, but have we ever thought about this problem: The ancients were often busy planning for rice every day, and rarely did they have to worry about it. I have free time to think about things, so much so that I have to &quot;steal&quot; even &quot;half a day&#39;s free time&quot;. Nowadays, people have more leisure in a materially rich environment. Once people are free, it is easy to get stuck in a corner and be unable to get out, amplifying the pressure. In fact, today, our situation is much better. For example, although the journey to school is extremely difficult, fortunately, examination or selection information is becoming more and more transparent, and at least there is certainty after studying hard, which is much better than in the past when imposters and secret operations were frequent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, leisure and non-idle are only relative, and how to deal with problems in specific circumstances also varies from person to person. However, no matter what era you are in, if you want to get out of trouble, people are given requirements and needs. The tactics adopted are actually the same, that is, the more extraordinary the period, the more meaningful things to do and the more meaningful issues to think about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you become stronger in this changing situation because of your timely stop loss and seeking changes, how heavy will the troubles of a person in a unit be? When a person can make himself bigger and stronger at the macro level of life - for example, becoming a person with a skill in his spare time and establishing extraordinary influence in a certain field - at this time, in a small space, because of interpersonal relationships and Can the waves caused by income disputes have a fatal impact on him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically speaking, in the context of life transitions, it means not to consume unnecessary energy, but to live in meaning. On the basis of acknowledging reality, turn around quickly and move from one state of affairs (stage) to the other as quickly as possible. Entering another state of affairs (stage), self-stimulating upward courage, it is too late and there is no time to feel sorry for yourself. This is the &quot;sharp weapon&quot; that the strong keep secret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:25:21 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戴佩妮：写歌根本就是老天爷要我做的事情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/xDUbigKtQgtDIq3lncCbMYixioK3gMnfPWRa24AO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/xDUbigKtQgtDIq3lncCbMYixioK3gMnfPWRa2 4AO. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252435&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Penny Dai in &quot;Time Concert·Friends&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the program team)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chinese music scene in 2000, a 22-year-old girl made her debut by releasing an album with original songs. In the mature record industry system What are the chances of finding a way out? Dai Penni told the audience through her actions that she might not be able to become an instant hit, but her talent will be recognized. The proof of this is the &quot;Nomination for the Best Newcomer Award at the 12th Golden Melody Awards.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the time since his debut was extended to 23 years, and the purely original album was released to his 13th, the singer entered another evaluation system, which consists of various criteria such as persistence, resilience, and having ideas. It seems that he can Separated from worldly judgments such as market and sales, the base is stacked with time and works. The &quot;status in the world&quot; shows the scarcity of music and the longevity of talent. Dai Penni is firmly on top, resting in a corner. She said: &quot;Writing songs is basically what God wants me to do.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She seems to have been accustomed to her situation: writing some songs that dig deeper into herself, and having a stable group of people who work with her The fans who grew up lived a contented life. As she said: &quot;I have always been a nobody, living a life where second place doesn&#39;t matter.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Penny Dai&#39;s most popular clips on the Internet were presented by fans in an almost joking way. A few years ago, she sang her masterpiece &quot;How&quot; live, and handed the microphone to a fan. The other fan grabbed the picture, went out of tune, and burst out laughing in the middle of the song. She was stunned, took back the microphone, and finished singing this sad love song while holding her thighs. After singing, she was not annoyed and told the other party gently: &quot;Feixiang &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(fan&#39;s name)&lt;/span>;, keep up with the time.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;This less than two-minute clip was made into various videos and emoticons and went viral on various platforms. It was dubbed by some media as &quot;probably the most popular day since Dai Penny&#39;s debut.&quot; Until now, many people have seen Dai Penny staring at fans with complicated expressions, but they have not listened to the full song &quot;How&quot; she sang at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Penny Dai’s life is littered with similar jokes of fate: she has written hundreds of songs, but still can’t read music. Her explanation for this was: &quot;This is a talent and a mission.&quot; She made up her mind to enter the music scene, and the first song she released was called &quot;Don&#39;t Want to&quot;. She was nominated for the Golden Melody Award for Best Female Singer many times, but she missed it every time and always regretted it. The album that finally won the award was called &quot;Purely Accident.&quot; She loves female singer Ani DiFranco. This pioneer in the original music industry has a unique personality and follows absolute DIY principles. He founded a record company to release his own solo album. Since his debut, he has been competing with the mainstream because of his clear views and controversy. While yearning for it, Dai Penni wrote about her endless self and subtle emotions in her songs, becoming part of the mainstream - being two extremes from being an idol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing that is good about original singers is that the audience does not have to work hard to outline the singer&#39;s mood and story from the twists and turns of lyrics and music, especially for a creator like Dai Penni, who uses direct or indirect life experience as a Based on the original creation, the expression is strong and direct. &quot;My songs are my diaries,&quot; she said. With more than a dozen albums arranged by year, Dai Penni has been along the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at Dai Penny&#39;s music career, we can find that she is really full of energy. In addition to her dozen albums and hundreds of songs, she also has a large amount of unreleased inventory. In 2011, she gathered her friends to form the rock band Buddha Jump Over the Wall, serving as the lead singer. With her first album &quot;Buddha Jump&quot;, she was nominated for the Best Band Award at the 23rd Golden Melody Awards; her second album &quot;Show You&quot; won the 2015 Golden Melody Awards. Won the Best Arranger and Best Orchestra awards. She helped write lyrics and music for Peng Jiahui, Xu Guanghan, Pingguan, Jiang Meiqi, Liu Sihan and others. She won the Best Album Producer Award at the 25th Golden Melody Awards for the album &quot;Embrace You&quot; produced for Liu Sihan. In addition, she has also served as music video director and album photographer. Before her debut, she once wanted to become a professional dancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Penny Tai was born into a scholarly family in Malaysia and started learning dance in the fourth grade of primary school. In high school, she participated in the first music competition in her life. She adapted a text written by a friend into a song and made it to the finals. The winner of that competition was later musician A Niu, and Leung Jingru won the Best Performance Award. Also participating were Zhang Zhicheng and Fang Jiongbin, who later became Dai Penny&#39;s few friends in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Dai Penni participated in the recording of Hunan Satellite TV&#39;s program &quot;Time Concert·Friends&quot;. In the previous four episodes, she invited her friend Zhang Zhicheng, who competed with her, and producer Yaya, who has been working with her for many years. She said that she doesn’t have many friends, but if anyone needs her, she will definitely stand up. “My loyalty can be exaggerated, and sometimes I forget that I am a girl.” In the program, they looked back on the past and pulled back the time to a long time ago. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the competition in high school, she caught the attention of musicians Chen Zihong and Huang Yi, signed up to &quot;Like Music&quot;, and released her first solo album &quot;Penny&quot; the following year. Until the release of her second album &quot;How&quot;, she had not decided whether to be a singer-songwriter or a professional dancer in the future. The song &quot;The Love You Want&quot; from the album was recommended by the company as the ending song for the TV series &quot;Meteor Garden&quot; and resounded throughout the streets as the TV series became popular. As she walked on the street, audience members came to say hello, &quot;For the first time, I felt like I was recognized by everyone because of my music.&quot; The energy of this song lasted for many years, and it is still one of her masterpieces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Penny Dai’s music has rich genres and diverse emotions, which is one of her attractive features. She said: &quot;I&#39;m really vulnerable when I&#39;m vulnerable. I can be soft and strong. I don&#39;t hold back. I cry when I need to cry, feel sad when I need to be sad, and be fierce when I need to be fierce. Just like my lyrics, these Song just cut me open for you to see, without reservation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/nVi6rXdNtNPN8bTDlIET40hATrkyb30SMVgcJdlW .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/nVi6rXdNtNPN8bTDlIET40hATrkyb30SMVgcJdlW.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot;Time Concert·Friends&quot;, Dai Penni and her friend Zhang Zhicheng sang &quot;Three O&#39;clock in the Morning&quot;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Provided by the program team/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Every song of mine has a secret - Dialogue with Dai Penni&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you participate in the recording of &quot;Time Concert·Friends&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was a flying guest in the first season and sang a cover of &quot;Coward&quot;. In fact, I was very afraid of singing the cover. But the atmosphere was very warm at the time, and Mr. Arai’s team was also very good. I was also invited to be a flying guest in the second season, but I missed it because I had Yang. This season is &quot;Friends&quot;, and the content has been changed to find your best friends, which attracts me even more. Through this program, I can let everyone know more about my friends who have been on the music road for more than 20 years and how they have helped and influenced me. I have very little exposure and rarely talk to people about these things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not afraid of strangers and make friends easily. But until now, since my debut, I have very few real good friends as an artist. Most of them are the staff behind the scenes, the producers, costumers, etc. who shoot the MV. Stylist, makeup artist, music teacher, so I also want to use this show to make friends and learn about other musicians’ musical journeys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/BF0w2SdlxmEpTSofejPSmEzZ3N3prWLOD7UhKyo1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;591&quot; height= &quot;523&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/BF0w2SdlxmEpTSofejPSmEzZ3N3prWLOD7UhKyo1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Penny&#39;s first full creation in 2000&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is it because we rarely become friends with artists because we have less opportunities to chat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have some bad experiences. As long as I treat the other person as a friend, I will stand up for the other person when they need me. I will definitely show up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not very clingy with my friends. The friends we met in the early days were not like today. Now everyone makes friends through Moments, but the content shared in Moments may not necessarily be what he really wants to say. I don’t reject the idea of ​​a circle of friends. I used to have a circle of friends, but I rarely posted them. I was always looking at them. As I watched them, I began to speculate or worry about the other person (whether something was wrong). I felt that this was actually not very healthy. Gradually, I followed my previous approach and closed the circle of friends. If you have anything to say, we&#39;ll talk to you face to face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am both passive and active, and I am very willing to take the initiative to help others, but if he doesn&#39;t mention it or doesn&#39;t let me know, I will feel that he doesn&#39;t need me at this moment, and I don&#39;t need to be too &quot;chicken bitch&quot; , I have to take care of others. The friends around me now will come to me if they really need some advice, but I don’t think I need to be so enthusiastic that I can take the initiative to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TxAvFrk8RV2VqY6CM4ElzKo5Q8OQKF0DqhIvX47D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;536&quot; height= &quot;746&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TxAvFrk8RV2VqY6CM4ElzKo5Q8OQKF0DqhIvX47D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Purely Accident&quot; 2013&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/ strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When will this mentality change be completed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2017, I wrote &quot;Passive Audience&quot;. I deeply feel that even though I have very few contacts with people, I will still be hurt by rumors. I want to resolve this misunderstanding spread by word of mouth. In the end, neither party can be friends. All my intentions are kind. In the end, you will be distorted and you will feel like what are you doing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We won’t talk about the specific incident. Anyway, my trust and understanding of people and interpersonal communication collapsed in an instant. Many things and people would change, so I later opened up. Passive mode, this is also the homework I need to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/y7Ad7ElXm2PjhPPDPUVT0fbuJalNQSwmVFihrlC0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;460&quot; height= &quot;366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/y7Ad7ElXm2PjhPPPDPUVT0fbuJalNQSwmVFihrlC0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Thief&quot; 2016&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But by 2017 it has been almost 20 years since you debuted. Has it been so long since you have been in the industry that you feel the power of rumors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, you should rarely hear much from me. I rarely go out. Why aren’t my things being shared on social media? It’s because I feel bored. I’m not practicing or eating well at home. I won’t share who my friends are over the years. I am very protective of my circle of friends and my life, because for me, my life is my creation. Well... my songwriting is already a part of my life. From my debut until now, people have been guessing my appearance through my songs. This is natural. &quot;A person who doesn&#39;t often share too much about his life.&quot; In the circle I live in, it may be very contradictory for a person who wants to be exposed or publicized, but I just have this kind of rebellious personality. I don’t think this environment can only accept the existence of one type of artist or one type of business model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ICY90xMKpkkZtKafCIbLZwq7whvIOCsxqivBS2IT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 540&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ICY90xMKpkkZtKafCIbLZwq7whvIOCsxqivBS2IT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Passive Audience&quot; 2022&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Characters Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you don’t want to expose your personal life, there are quite a few reality show parts in this show, and there are a lot of self-revealing parts. . Don&#39;t you care? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the show, I am sharing my music life. I don’t mind this part. I will not take the initiative to tell everyone that I am in the show every day. Why, but when I meet fate and meet friends, I will talk freely. So this goes back to what I just said, I am not afraid of strangers or making friends, I am very willing to share. It’s just that I use music to share more than making friends to sit down and share with everyone. My life is my music, but I don’t want to just use social media to share my life. I hope I can find a more appropriate platform. I think this program is a very comfortable platform to talk about music. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have written all the most important things in the song, and I have already cut myself open enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the content written by some singer-songwriters may not necessarily be their own (experiences), but I choose to be a narrative singer-songwriter. I feel that I feel deeply and I only write when I have something to say. That&#39;s why I tell everyone that my songs are my diaries. I don’t like keeping diaries, but I love writing songs. Every song has people, things, things, and every song has secrets that you don’t know, yes, only I know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What does secret mean? For example, what&#39;s the secret in &quot;The Love You Want&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It refers to a lot of code words in words, which are things that only I understand. &quot;The Love You Want&quot; is relatively straightforward. The funniest thing about it is that the big boy in this song is actually me. It was a very young love affair, and I was too strictly controlled, so I wanted to be like a big boy and be free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in fact its story is not what you think, it is the other way around, but no one knows it. As the person who sings it, everyone will definitely think that I have met a boy who wants to be free. No. But I don’t want to explain this thoroughly. It’s like some movies where you don’t know whether the ending is happy or bad. In fact, it’s an open ending, and many things just need to be stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;How&quot; is obviously a touching love song, but it was changed into another style by a handsome fan friend of mine, and I didn&#39;t expect this change. I didn&#39;t know it at all. This change will occur. But I am loyal to the reason why I wrote this song in the first place. The changes in my life and things will not affect the picture in my mind when I sing this song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people are worried that I can no longer sing this song, no. When I sang this song, I knew what secrets I was hiding. I knew the time, place, and people. Of course, there would still be funny scenes when we talked about it, but it would not affect the reason why I wrote this song in the first place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you think you have improved in writing lyrics and music over the years? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it is the time that has given me different perspectives on things and different interpretations, and the words I use are different. So for me it’s not just aging, it’s maturing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I didn’t know how to use the word “nurture” before. Later, I heard a senior say that I think this word is very good, because different environments will cultivate different personalities. . Therefore, the word &quot;nurture&quot; has been used frequently in the past two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was only after I finished the song &quot;Passive Audience&quot; that I learned to make peace with myself and often have meetings with myself. I was often in a state of binary opposition before. I would be worried about a lot of things at once, and I couldn&#39;t find the answers, so I started asking people for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote the song &quot;I Yearn&quot; in the album to remind myself. I have participated in so many programs in the past three years, and I am very afraid that I will go astray and forget my original intention. So I wrote this song to remember what I yearned for, &quot;The days I yearn for have sunrises, and the mess I yearn for is taken care of by you.&quot; By the second paragraph, I started writing and realized that my mentality had changed, so this song The song is to remind yourself not to get lost by filling in the gaps in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said you couldn’t make a decision before, so you started asking people everywhere, But your songs show that you seem to be a very courageous person. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Things that are bold are very bold, and things that are not bold are not bold. I am very decisive now when it comes to big things. Now I use very unscientific methods to make decisions, such as throwing coins. My life is destined to be good, and the more I think about it, the less likely it will be. My whole life has been unintentional. I can only sum it up with this sentence. At the age of 45, from the beginning I didn’t want to be a singer-songwriter and just gave it a try, and now I have followed this path, and it feels like I was destined to do it. If the first album doesn&#39;t work, I&#39;m going to go back to dancing or something, no, it&#39;s just going to be like this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can only admit that this is my mission. There are many people who can sing well, look good, and can create better than me, but not everyone can eat this. Have a meal. What makes me happiest is that my hobby is my job. I do things that interest me every day. At the same time, I can empower others through song, or give them a place to find release. This is the identity belt I have now. It gives me, supports me, and is the main reason why I still want to come out and sing and chat with everyone no matter how tired I am. Because this is basically what God wants me to do. If he didn&#39;t want me to do it, he would have asked me to go home and dance on the first album (after the album). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/xkHR1nMNeASpTkionE5GrJKnAOtgxeTdAMM8TkMs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/xkHR1nMNeASpTkionE5GrJKnAOtgxeTdAMM8TkMs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot;Time Concert·Friends&quot;, Dai Penni plays games with Yu Wenwen (left) and Meng Jia (right)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Provided by the program team/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If this It is a kind of mission. Have you ever thought about making it more vivid? For example, like your favorite singer-songwriter Ani DiFranco, write some songs that are closer to social reality and grand narratives, instead of always exploring the emotions of individual stories? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Penny Dai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;How do you know I don’t have one? Maybe it&#39;s secretly hidden in the song? Something only I know. Yes, I won’t tell you what’s right. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(laughing)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡服骑射：五百里国运浮沉丨古国多少事④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257358]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The distance from Handan to Gaoping is about five hundred miles. A country, just within these five hundred miles, has staged the ups and downs of its national destiny from rise to decline, from glory to annihilation. Sometimes, history can not only be examined with time, but also measured with space...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Congtai&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Climb high and have a bird&#39;s eye view, the lake lingers. In early autumn, the leaves of the wood are slightly yellow, and under the morning sun, their slender shadows wade across the lake and fall towards the square tower. The tower and the corridors at both ends are shaped like a giant bow. ——This reminds people of the several-meter-high statue in the square a few hundred meters away, also holding a bow. What&#39;s even more interesting is that when I walked into the blue-brick paved terrace, I saw that there was also a statue in the corner of the terrace, depicting the same person, also holding a bow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This man was once the master of this square tower, this city, and this vast land. He is the founder of the glorious history of Zhao State: King Zhao Wuling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/SUG0kgzgaydIkLLurgUzAZf3TVhKEoQy8BrWm0hb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1370&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/SUG0kgzgaydIkLLurgUzAZf3TVhKEoQy8BrWm0hb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of King Zhao Wuling in Congtai Square, Handan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During my visit to the Zhao ruins, I was reminded several times of British scholar John Keegan&#39;s conclusion in &quot;History of War&quot;: Kings are created by great war horses. Although he is talking about the king of the West, King Zhao Wuling, the Eastern monarch, was also created by war horses. Of course, in addition to the war horse, there is another thing that must be added, and that is the bow in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three families were divided into Jin, and Zhao State had the largest territory and was also the most remote. Its main territory is in central and northern Shanxi, northern Henan, and southern Hebei. When talking with Fei Yi, King Wuling of Zhao said, &quot;Today, our country has the river and Boluo River in the east, which is shared with Qi and Zhongshan... From Changshan to Dai and Shangdang, there are the borders of Yan and Donghu in the east, and the borders of Donghu in the west. Bordering Loufan, Qin and Han.&quot; - A section of the ancient Zhangshui River in the eastern part of Zhao State bounded by the Yellow River and Boluoshui (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; in present-day Hebei Julu&lt;/span>;) serves as the border with Qi State and Zhongshan State; from Changshan to Daijun and Shangdang, it borders Yan State and Donghu State to the east, and Loufan, Qin State and South Korea to the west. From this point of view, Zhao was surrounded by the Qi, Zhongshan, Yan, Han, Qin and other princes, as well as the Donghu, Loufan and other tribes. If Daliang, the capital of Wei, is a city with four wars, then Zhao State is even more unfortunate. The entire country is a country with four wars - enemies are eyeing on all sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to achieve long-term peace and stability with strong enemies around. Especially under the law of the jungle where the strong bullies the weak and the masses bully the mob. King Wuling of Zhao sighed sadly all night long. He said, &quot;Today Zhongshan is in my heart. There are Yan in the north, Hu in the east, Linhu and Loufan in the west. If there are no strong soldiers on the border of Qin and Han, the country will be destroyed. What can I do?&quot; ?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you are poor, you want to change. This is the driving force for the princes in the Spring and Autumn and Warring States periods to compete for reform and self-improvement. King Zhao Wuling was no exception. So, there was Hufu riding and shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boundary between the monsoon area and the non-monsoon area is also the 400 mm equal precipitation line, which runs through the northern border of Zhao State. Zhao State is at the end of agricultural civilization and adjacent to nomadic civilization, especially Dai County of Zhao State. , and even closer to the nomads. The advantage of this proximity is that Zhao can obtain horses more easily than other princes. Before the industrial revolution, horses were mankind&#39;s most powerful and reliable source of power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The disadvantages are also obvious. Once the climate becomes dry and the pastures wither, it will be difficult for the nomads in non-monsoon areas to survive, and they will have no choice but to go south to plunder. At the beginning of the founding of Zhao State, it often faced intrusions from Donghu and other tribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reforms of King Wuling of Zhao surprised the people at the time - he ordered to learn from these barbarians who often invaded Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speed and maneuverability of horses are not only incomparable to humans, but also to chariots. Moreover, in the era of King Zhao Wuling, the early aristocratic competitive chariot battles had evolved into a bloody and cruel life-and-death fight. The bulky chariots and the war ethics of not drumming and not rowing had long been unable to meet the needs of the times. Therefore, the heavy infantry represented by Wei Wuzu of Wei State came to prominence. However, the hoplites marched too slowly and had insufficient impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What King Wuling of Zhao thought was that if the soldiers were allowed to ride on flying horses like the Hu people, and shoot and charge on the horses, the mobility and flexibility of the army would be greatly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest problem is that the Chinese clothes are not suitable for riding horses. During the Warring States Period, the clothes of the various vassal states of the Huaxia tribe were generally the same. Today we generally refer to clothes as clothes. At that time, clothes meant upper garments and Shang meant lower garments. There are types of jackets, such as jacket, brown, coat, fur, robe and so on. Shang is a bottom garment, similar to a skirt, and is the same for both men and women. There is another type called Shenyi, which means the clothes and clothes are connected together, which is equivalent to the dress in later generations. ——As you can imagine, whether you are wearing a skirt and robe or a dress, it is really difficult to ride a horse, or even gallop on a horse, and perform various complex and difficult movements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how did the nomads do it? It turns out that their clothes are different from those of the Chinese people. The main features of the Hufu of the nomadic people are a short jacket with narrow sleeves and crotch trousers. The former is convenient for archery and the latter is convenient for horseback riding. In addition, the shoes of the Chinese people are made of cloth, while the shoes of the Hu people are made of leather. Leather boots are naturally more suitable for outdoor sports than cloth shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When King Wuling of Zhao disregarded many objections, including from his own uncle, and vigorously promoted Hufu riding and archery, he was like a magical magician who in the blink of an eye transformed the remote and weak Zhao country. Rising powerfully at a speed that dazzled the princes. The first real cavalry in Chinese history was born. The flying cavalry caused a dimension-reducing blow to the cumbersome chariots - from a historical perspective, King Zhao Wuling&#39;s Hufu cavalry not only marked China&#39;s transition from the era of chariot warfare to the era of cavalry warfare, but also meant that Hufu&#39;s It has become the common clothing of Chinese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on the cavalry, Zhao conquered the three Hus. &quot;King Lin Hu offered his horse&quot; and &quot;Xiang Zhao Gu took control of Hu and sent his troops.&quot; Zhao State&#39;s control of Sanhu means that it can continuously obtain war horses, further increasing the strength of the cavalry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is particularly important is that after conquering Sanhu, Zhao State annexed Zhongshan, which lay across the middle of Zhao State and blocked Zhao State from the north to the south. In order to destroy Zhongshan, King Wuling of Zhao used troops several times. Zhongshan was weak and Zhao Guo was strong, so Zhongshan had to constantly cede territory and seek peace.每一次割地求和后，赵国愈强，中山愈弱——把自己的安全寄托于贿赂敌人，只能使敌人更加贪婪——几年后，赵军攻克中山首都，末代中山王被流放，中山亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中山既灭，赵国解决了心腹之患，南北疆土再无障碍。并且，中山虽较七国弱小，但也是千乘之国，赵国因之国力大增。 《战国策》称：“中山之地方五百里，赵独擅之，功成名立利附，天下莫能害。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;急剧扩张后，赵国疆域达到极盛：“北至燕、代，西至云中、九原。”从敌人手中夺取的每一寸疆土，都回响着马蹄的脆响和劲弓的长鸣。以潮水般涌向敌阵的骑兵为背景，赵国迎来了空前绝后的光辉岁月……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初秋的邯郸，风有些凉。下午，丛台广场人来人往，赵武灵王高大的塑像投下浓重的阴影。两千多年前，丛台竣工了。那时的丛台，远比我现在看到的这座清代建筑更庞大更壮观。丛台的主要功能，乃是供赵武灵王检阅部队、欣赏歌舞。建筑物普遍低矮的先秦，一马平川的平原上，高高矗立的丛台，它是君王权柄的象征。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万众仰望中，赵武灵王一步步登上丛台。这高高在上的君王，他因远离众生而愈加神秘、威严。当急速扩张的疆土与所向披靡的骑兵，使赵国成为彼时诸侯中，惟一有力量与秦国抗衡的国家时，顾盼自雄的赵武灵王，他注视着台下那些随时将为他一声令下而血染黄沙的将士时，宰割天下的雄心恍似春潮激荡……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/QEreryEQMOEb9mCKtYQkcNHIeg5xtuTanyqIesQd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1428&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/QEreryEQMOEb9mCKtYQkcNHIeg5xtuTanyqIesQd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;邯郸古丛台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;沙丘&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;前298年，秦都咸阳，在位十年的秦昭王接见了一位来自赵国的使者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使者的气质和言谈，令秦昭王颇有些意外。等使者辞别后，他越琢磨越觉得不对劲儿：这绝对不是一个普通使者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;秦昭王派人追查，才知道使者已经返回赵国了。不过，使者的一些随行人员还没来得及动身。询问随行人员后，他们的回答让秦昭王君臣大吃一惊：那位“其状甚伟，非人臣之度”的使者，竟然是赵国的主父。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓主父，乃是赵国前国君赵雍——后来谥号武灵，史称赵武灵王。前一年，赵武灵王把王位传给儿子赵何，自称主父，相当于后世的太上皇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵国的主父，为什么要乔装打扮到秦国去见秦王呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来，在并三胡、灭中山之前，赵、秦之间，只有赵国西南部与秦国东北部一小部分接壤。诸侯要攻打秦国，必须经由秦国东部的函谷关西进，而函谷关易守难攻，诸侯奔袭千里，却对一夫当关万夫莫开的秦国无能为力。随着赵国占领云中和九原，形势悄然巨变：云中和九原在秦国北部，这就意味着，赵军可以从北向南，由秦国北方南下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵武灵王就是这样设想的。为了侦察秦国国情，他冒险扮作赵国使者前往秦国——两千年后，另一位远隔万里的帝王也像赵武灵王一样乔装打扮，深入到邻近各国考察，此人就是俄国的彼得大帝。彼得大帝为了使落后的俄国强大起来，曾化装成水手，造访西欧各国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前往秦国前，赵武灵王在宫中会见群臣，宣布把王位传给不到十岁的小儿子赵何，由肥义任相国，他自称主父。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵武灵王内禅给儿子，其目的是想摆脱国内具体政务，把全部精力投入到伐秦战争中。当然，他这样做还有另一番考虑：赵武灵王的长子赵章，此时已成人，按礼制，应该立赵章而不是赵何。但是，由于赵武灵王曾经十分宠爱赵何的生母吴娃，而吴娃刚去世不久，对吴娃的追怀与对小儿子的怜爱交织在这位多情的君王心中。于是，他决定立赵何为王。赵何年龄太小，他希望用禅让的方式让他尽快进入角色，趁自己还健在，教会他如何治理天下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，废长立幼却引发了可怕的后果，也使赵国的崛起如同昙花一现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵章被废后，赵武灵王封他为安阳君，但赵章对父亲的安排耿耿于怀。并且，朝臣也分为两派，一部分同情赵章，一部分支持赵何。关键时刻，赵武灵王又犯下大错：他看到成年的长子以臣子的身份跪在幼子脚下时，对长子的处境产生了怜悯之情，竟打算把赵国一分为二，让两个儿子各自称王。这一想法，遭到了肥义等人坚决反对。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵武灵王的计划未及实施，双方的矛盾已经到了不可调和的地步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悲剧，最终在一个叫沙丘的地方上演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;司马迁在《史记》里三次写到沙丘。或者说，沙丘这个小地方，至少发生过三起重大历史事件：其一，商纣王建肉林酒池；其二，秦始皇最后一次出巡时病死；其三，赵武灵王父子相残。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广宗属河北邢台市下辖县，距邯郸市区约七十公里。广宗县城西北的大平台乡，公路附近，立着一对阙台，台后，树着两块碑，上面的字都是：沙丘平台遗址。碑后，栅栏封起一座土堆，那就是历代相传的沙丘宫遗址——从商朝直到秦朝，虽然天命流转，天子走马灯似地变幻，但这里一直建有行宫。如今，野岭荒郊，草长鸦飞，丝毫看不出宫殿的迹象。唯有一旁的小树林里，一群脏兮兮的山羊正埋头咬着铁丝一样的枯草，牧羊人坐在石头上，和山羊一样面无表情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵武灵王在两个儿子之间摇摆不定，对他和他的国家而言，都是一场空前的灾难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前295年，赵武灵王在沙丘宫举行朝会，赵章及其追随者发动兵变，肥义被害，赵何在将军高信保护下逃走，而早有准备的支持赵何的公子成——公子成系赵武灵王叔父，曾坚决反对胡服骑射——火速率军从邯郸赶来，包围了沙丘宫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵章眼见大势已去，便逃进宫中，希望得到父亲庇护。但是，公子成和李兑却将赵章杀死。此时，赵武灵王已失去了对政局的控制，公子成和李兑既不敢弑君，更不敢撤围。于是，便令宫内所有人员退出，独独不放赵武灵王出宫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;缺吃少喝，赵武灵王只得生食幼雀，终至“三月余而饿死沙丘宫”。这位雄才大略的英主，竟以这种窝囊的方式在空荡荡的行宫里悲愤死去。随同他的肉身一起腐朽的，是赵国称雄天下的霸图和它恍如流星划过的辉煌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，经由赵武灵王变法打下的坚实基础，还将在相当长时间里继续支撑赵国。自齐、楚被打残后，赵国就是秦国以外实力最强的诸侯。因此，赵武灵王的子孙，还可以凭借他改革的余荫，继续与秦国周旋：咸阳宫里，蔺相如完璧归赵；渑池会上，蔺相如折冲樽俎；阏与城外，赵奢大破秦军——这一切，仰仗的都是赵武灵王胡服骑射以来积累的实力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只不过，这实力，随着后代子孙的不肖，随着国运的此消彼长，必将日益式微，直到丛台五百里外，一场大战爆发……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;长平&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;去高平前，我看过一段视频：一道二十多米长、大半米高的断崖上，泥土之间，如同镶嵌着石头那样，镶嵌着密密麻麻的人骨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种令人惊悚的景象，对高平人来说，一点也不陌生。多年来，一场大雨或是一次基建，都可能惊现大量白花花的人骨。没有人知道他们是谁的儿子，谁的父亲，谁的丈夫。人们只知道，自古以来，作为兵家必争之地，高平的黄土下掩埋了难以计数的尸骨。其中，仅仅是秦赵之间的那场大决战，双方死亡人数就可能在六十万以上——如今，整个高平市的常住人口，也不过四十五万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高平，古称长平。战国时，属韩国。七国中，韩国最弱，又与秦国毗邻，被吊打的可悲命运几乎是注定的。高平所属的上党，即今山西长治一带，位于太行山西南，太岳山之东，王屋山之北，“其所最高，故曰上党也”。这里地势高耸，对周围有居高临下之势。穿越崇山峻岭的太行八陉，有四条在上党。通过它，东进华北平原，西入临汾盆地，南指洛阳，北望太原，自古就是兵家必争要地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前262年，秦军攻占野王（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今河南沁阳&lt;/span>;），上党与韩国主体分割，成了一块孤零零的飞地。为此，韩国不得不答应把上党割让给秦国，以换取和平。然而，上党人民不愿被以残暴著称的虎狼之秦统治，上党郡守冯亭派使者到赵国，请求把上党所属十七座城池献给赵国，赵国派兵保卫上党。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从天而降的十七座城池，到底要不要接受，赵国君臣有过一番争论。最终，赵何之子赵孝成王赵丹实在拒绝不了如此大的诱惑，在平原君赵胜鼓动下，他接纳了上党，并派重兵布防。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;眼看上党已成囊中之物，没想到半路杀出个赵国，秦国自然不会善罢甘休。并且，秦相范雎认为，此前，秦国攻占了楚国大片土地，又曾兵逼大梁、新郑，打得魏、韩没有还手之力，却仍然没能称王天下，主要原因就是赵国未屈服。所以，必须占领上党，再攻打赵国首都邯郸以西地区，威胁赵国腹心地带，以逼赵国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，中国历史上最著名的战役之一——长平之战爆发了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高平市区，丹河流过。溯丹河而上，在高平市以北，有一座名为长平的小村庄。长平村，即古长平城。丹河两岸，谷地平坦，更远处，东西山峰逶迤。就在这片谷地及附近，还有许多地名让人联想起那场惨烈的决定国运的大战：围城、箭头、白起台、骷髅山、廉颇屯、将军岭……在这样的地方寻幽访古，你能感觉到，历史并不只是书写在纸页上，还烙印在山川间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;秦、赵两国大军，各沿长平城左右五十里的山地构筑营垒。秦军由王龁率领，赵军由廉颇率领。廉颇认为，秦军士气旺，意在速战。赵军弱小，处于劣势，最好筑垒固守。从前260年七月起，双方在几次小型交锋后，廉颇便令赵军凭借有利地形固守不出。秦军求战不得，渐渐失去锐气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两军对峙长达两年有余，秦国开始实施反间计——反间计是秦国惯用伎俩，且每每收到奇效——秦国间谍潜入赵国，大肆散布流言，声称秦军真正害怕的是赵括，而非廉颇。赵孝成王本就对廉颇采取守势有所不满，怀疑他怯战，及至听到流言，信以为真——他如同秦人希望的那样，把身经百战的廉颇撤下来，换上了纸上谈兵的赵括。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得知赵国易将，秦昭王大喜，立即派有战神之称的白起秘密前往长平，取代王龁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悲剧，已然不可阻挡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵括上任后，一改廉颇法度，由守势变攻势。白起佯败退走，却从背后偷袭赵军补给线，并将赵军截为互不相连的两部分——一部分是赵括亲率的主力，一部分是守卫营垒的留守。赵括返回营垒的归路被切断，陷入秦军包围圈，只好就地坚守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了吃掉赵军，秦昭王下令全国总动员——所有十五岁以上男丁，全部征集入伍。可以说，为了长平之战，秦国几乎倾整个国家的力量孤注一掷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵括被围，得不到补给，绝粮一个半月后，军中甚至发生了士兵自相残杀、以尸体为食的惨剧。赵括几次组织精锐突围，均被秦军击退。最后一次突围时，赵括亲自上阵，却被一阵乱箭射死。主帅阵亡，军中断粮已久，赵军兵无斗志，只得向秦军投降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;投降的赵军，人数多达四十万。白起认为，这些赵军将士，秦国既没法把他们改编为秦军，又不可能将他们释放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;惨绝人寰的大屠杀就这样发生了。四十多万赵军将士，除二十多名年幼者被放还外，其余全部被杀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四十万这一数字实在过于庞大，以至后人怀疑《史记》是否有所夸大。然而，高平地区不断发现的累累白骨，却证明了大屠杀曾真实发生。只是，到底有多少人死于非命，则是一个永远的谜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长平之战纪念馆里，有一座用玻璃保护起来的尸骨坑。透过玻璃，层层叠叠的尸骨发出白生生的幽光。那天，纪念馆里除我之外再无他人，凝视着这些两千多年前非正常死亡者的遗骸，我仿佛听到了兵器击中肉体的闷响，以及此起彼伏的绝望的惨叫……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/EXiG7MlCUKRdWHYtFlxAnpwVCdVbfxsm64C088yE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1439&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/EXiG7MlCUKRdWHYtFlxAnpwVCdVbfxsm64C088yE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上海博物馆收藏的战国时期赵国钱币尖足布&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长平村以南十几公里的山谷中，有小村名谷口，据说就是白起杀俘的地方，又名杀谷、哭头、省冤谷。村里，有一座骷髅庙，丹河就从庙前缓缓流过。这座四合院形制的庙宇，始建于唐。史载，唐中宗时期，还是潞州别驾的唐玄宗路过长平，长平之战留下的漫山骷髅，令他十分伤感，遂下令收集安葬，并立庙祭祀。不过，我看到的骷髅庙已是清朝重建。正殿里，供奉着赵括夫妇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;令人意外的是，庙里还有一间小屋，门前挂着一块红底白字的牌：烧豆腐坊。烧豆腐是高平的一种特色美食，又名白起肉。 ——因痛恨白起坑杀数十万赵国将士，高平人发明了这种食物：把豆腐当肉，再用豆腐渣和蒜泥、生姜调成汁，当白起的脑浆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长平之战遗址纪念馆外，也有一尊塑像，塑的还是赵括。塑像下方，有八个字：空谈误国，实干兴邦。历史以哭喊、血泪和累累白骨在无声地警示后人。至于后人是否真的会记取教训，历史从来都无能为力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/S6c4GwGZPNSL6jutwDgjJT6u8QGIhYQvavuMleQT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1458&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/02/23/S6c4GwGZPNSL6jutwDgjJT6u8QGIhYQvavuMleQT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;225444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;邯郸老火车站，2018年停用后已被拆除，包括广场上胡服骑射的雕像。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长平之战的惨败，距赵武灵王胡服骑射，时隔四十七年；长平之战三十二年后，秦军攻破邯郸，赵亡。那时，无论丛台阅兵的意气风发还是沙丘被困的绝望长叹，抑或长平惨败的举国恸哭，都已化作过眼烟云。赵国，也走完了它一百七十余年的坎坷岁月，湮没于波澜不兴的时光之河……&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;【主要参考书目：《史记》《战国策》《资治通鉴》《中国历史地图集》《中国战争史》《中国风俗通史·两周卷》《邯郸市志》《广宗县志》《高平县志》】&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年诺贝尔生理学或医学奖揭晓！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258036]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 18:01:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;北京时间10月2日，瑞典卡罗琳医学院宣布，将诺贝尔生理学或医学奖授予Katalin Karikó、Drew Weissman，以表彰他们在核苷碱基修饰方面的发现，这些发现使得针对COVID-19的有效mRNA疫苗得以开发。他们将平均分享1100万瑞典克朗的奖金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/e2fd64108e043ee3fdfa87b0032be35b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/e2fd64108e043ee3fdfa87b0032be35b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252943&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[夜游磁器口古镇丨指尖华夏④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257585]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At night, the scenic area of ​​Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, Chongqing has focused on &quot;night food&quot;, &quot;night nourishment&quot;, &quot;night appreciation&quot;, &quot;night fun&quot; and &quot;night shopping&quot; and other business formats, deeply exploring Chongqing&#39;s characteristics, striving to build a night-time economy and attracting many tourists. play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/57OkanvMQMYOKYvOkADBTgnNi0s4QSmHv3aA8cFi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/57OkanvMQMYOKYvOkADBTgnNi0s4QSmHv3aA8cFi.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town in Shapingba District, Chongqing City is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous, attracting many tourists. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/VY2GMvoB4MASoXdnYXT7dqBKwMxJmllQc0MaHquE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/VY2GMvoB4MASoXdnYXT7dqBKwMxJmllQc0MaHquE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Night view of Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/phbsrWVOJhSFbd9uvf9R0kaiOO2BpYXENT9wM57A.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/phbsrWVOJhSFbd9uvf9R0kaiOO2BpYXENT9wM57A.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Night view of Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/DCeJmye9kvL6DrmI7B46VIi3yVPjtnV2AydS7Cma.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/DCeJmye9kvL6DrmI7B46VIi3yVPjtnV2AydS7Cma.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous , attracting many tourists to come and play. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Rs0Juw5S6ZBlDbE0CKroYDN0NBHjaTFdx5xAgdGd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;728&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Rs0Juw5S6ZBlDbE0CKroYDN0NBHjaTFdx5xAgdGd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists dressed in Sichuan opera costumes in Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing Take photos in costumes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/0PQSnc5ef6CyDM1lf1tyYpzt81gzzokwiONrJtRT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/0PQSnc5ef6CyDM1lf1tyYpzt81gzzokwiONrJtRT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ciqikou Ancient Town, Shapingba District, Chongqing is brightly lit and the night is gorgeous , attracting many tourists to come and play. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Sun Kaifang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王嘉男跳远摘金，“惊人一跃”后的卫冕之战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258034]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/02/Cb6yv52uGM0jve15u01uI2vlWW65BkgNwmgUqO9w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/Cb6yv52uGM0jve15u01uI2vlWW 65BkgNwmgUqO9w. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 1, 2023, champion Chinese player Wang Jianan (middle), runner-up India Contestant Sri Shankar (left) and third runner-up Chinese player Shi Yuhao at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 1 In the evening, at the men&#39;s long jump final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Wang Jianan was the last to appear. Everything was ready. He clapped his hands as if to cheer himself up, and there were cheers on the field. After a moment, he took a few steps back, started running, accelerated, got on the board, jumped, and landed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first jump was 8.22 meters, which was very close to his own Asian Games record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second jump was 8.15 meters; the third jump was 8.06 meters. The first three jumps all exceeded 8 meters, showing stable performance. Wang Jianan voluntarily gave up on the fourth jump to accumulate energy for the next two jumps, but the fifth and sixth jumps were not scored due to fouls. With his excellent performance in the first jump, he won the Asian Games championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this Asian Games competition, Wang Jianan continued his distinctive personal style: good results often appear in the first few jumps. In the qualifying round the day before, Wang Jianan was still recovering due to an injury to his front foot. He only jumped 1 jump in the qualifying round and advanced with a score of 7.76 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview after winning the gold medal, he said frankly: &quot;Coming here as the defending champion is quite stressful. I have never defended my title before. Last time in Budapest, as the defending champion, my performance was average. So this time I really hope to win the Asian Games gold medal, but I am also afraid that this gold medal will put too much pressure on myself, so I have been adjusting myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, more than a month ago, At the 2023 World Championships in Budapest, Wang Jianan jumped 8.05 meters in the first jump in the final, but he failed to exceed this score in five subsequent attempts. He failed to defend his title and unfortunately missed the podium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long jump tests explosive power, and the victory is decided in seconds. Behind it is the athletes’ years of training and hard work. Ups and downs are normal. What is difficult is to have the confidence to face success, and even more to have the courage to face failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3UocneDe9x73yhQsmADXWFxF5t4RW68db8QMFUBG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3UocneDe9x73yhQsmADXWFxF5t4RW68db8QMFUBG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2023, Chinese player Wang Jianan competed &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Genius boy, a blockbuster&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan is a typical &quot;genius boy&quot;. He was discovered to have talent in track and field sports when he was very young. He was born in Shenyang, Liaoning Province in August 1996. He participated in the Shenhe District Games in 2005. Although his performance in the 100-meter dash was average, he was spotted by Yang Keqiang, the coach of the Shenyang Sports School. Coach Yang saw Wang Jianan walking on the playground and found that although he was not very tall, he had long legs and a &quot;bumpy&quot; walk. &quot;He has the energy of an athlete, and I feel like he is a good prospect.&quot; At that time. Wang Jianan is still in primary school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, he lived up to the expectations of his enlightenment coach. Yang Keqiang commented that he &quot;trains very hard, is very smart, and has strong comprehension ability. Many technical moves can be adjusted after a few times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;At first, Wang Jianan was not a long jumper, but a decathlete, and his best event was the pole vault. At the age of 14, Wang Jianan entered the Xuzhou track and field team; at the age of 16, he was selected by the Jiangsu Provincial Sports Team to represent Jiangsu Province in the national indoor men&#39;s decathlon competition, scoring 7063 points. This is the second best result among world youth athletes in 2012: long jump 7.80 meters, 100 meters run 10 seconds 88, pole vault breakthrough 5 meters, high jump 1.94 meters - this was called a &quot;decathlon genius&quot; at the time &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan jumped 8 meters for the first time at the age of 16. He won the national long jump championship with a score of 8.04 meters. You know, this is a result that can only be achieved by a veteran who has been training for many years. Chinese men&#39;s long jump has been seeking breakthroughs since it broke the 8-meter mark in the early 1980s. However, most athletes have not made a splash on the international stage. Their best results were achieved in domestic or Asian competitions until Players such as Li Jinzhe began to appear on the international stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also allowed Wang Jianan to focus on long jump in early 2013 and was selected for the national team. &quot;I switched to long jump because of my love for track and field. I am a decathlete athlete, and I still love all track and field events. I always have a kind of self-confidence: I feel that no matter what I practice, it will not be a problem. I am not an ordinary person. , I can do it.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a &quot;genius long jump boy&quot; Wang Jianan, his journey has indeed been relatively smooth. Some people call him &quot;lucky,&quot; and he doesn&#39;t shy away from it. He felt, &quot;From winning the bronze medal at home in 2015 to creating the best ranking in history at the 2016 Rio Olympics, strength is the foundation, but my luck is better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2013, in Pudong, India At the Asian Championships held there, in the absence of China&#39;s &quot;first brother&quot; Li Jinzhe in the long jump, 17-year-old Wang Jianan won the long jump championship with a time of 7.95 meters. He had never even participated in the World Youth Championships. Qualification for the World Championships in Moscow. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 24, 2014, Wang Jianan, who was under 18 years old, became a blockbuster in Eugene, USA. He won the men&#39;s long jump championship at the World Youth Athletics Championships with a time of 8.08 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2015 Beijing World Athletics Championships, at the Bird&#39;s Nest competition, three players of the Chinese men&#39;s long jump team, Li Jinzhe, Gao Xinglong, and Wang Jianan, appeared in the final at the same time. At that time, someone exclaimed, &quot;The best era for China&#39;s long jump It&#39;s already here.&quot; 19-year-old Wang Jianan won the long jump bronze medal, becoming the first Chinese and Asian athlete to reach the men&#39;s long jump podium at the World Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this also puts pressure on Wang Jianan. &quot;To be honest, after winning that medal, my confidence did not increase significantly, but it put more pressure on me. This medal is the only Asian medal in 32 years, and I won it, and It was a score of 8.18 meters, neither high nor low. Did I think this score was convincing at the time? This led to my results in 2016 being not particularly good throughout the whole year. I felt that I was suppressed by the bronze medal. .&quot; In an interview with CCTV, he admitted that he was carrying a burden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 National Track and Field Championships and Asian Games Trials, Wang Jianan jumped 8.47 meters, which not only tied the men&#39;s long jump national record held by Li Jinzhe, but was also Wang Jianan&#39;s personal best. In the men&#39;s long jump track and field finals of the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games, Wang Jianan won the gold medal with an Asian Games record-breaking performance of 8.24 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/hlG2dACpPpI9xL1HZ1aEZYGboeSy1vRF9XUXdI3D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/hlG2dACpPpI9xL1HZ1aEZYGboeSy1vRF9XUXdI3D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2023, in the men&#39;s long jump final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Wang Jianan won the gold medal with a time of 8.22 meters&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hibernating after failure, reaching the top again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the smooth journey, there are injuries , there are also upcoming surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the 2016 Rio Olympics and the 2017 National Games, Wang Jianan underwent two knee surgeries on his left and right knees. When he learned that he had torn his meniscus, he even &quot;didn&#39;t want to practice anymore and wanted to retire.&quot; He took anti-inflammatory drugs for more than a month before he began to gradually improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next major blow to his career was his failure to compete in the Tokyo Olympics. At that time, Wang Jianan had high hopes and was the only athlete in the jumping department of the national track and field team with a medal mission. Although he got a spot to go to the Tokyo Olympics, he did not perform well due to running-in problems with his coach and great pressure. He only jumped 7.81 meters and missed the finals. &quot;It was also a big blow to me. I feel that all the problems arise from my own problems.&quot; He took all the responsibility on himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This blow did not defeat him. He summed up his experience, regained his confidence and prepared to fight again. &quot;How much worse could it be?&quot; he recalled that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next step was his &quot;amazing jump&quot; at the World Championships in Eugene, which made more people remember this Chinese face. Before heading to the World Championships in Eugene, Wang Jianan shared a calendar on his mobile app on social media: &quot;It has been 3,078 days since I joined the national team, 2,058 days have passed since the 2016 Olympics long jump final, and my first meniscus surgery has passed. 1928 days, 1565 days have passed since the second meniscus surgery...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Wang Jianan did not continue his past style. Until the last jump, his score of 8.03 meters was only ranked second. fifth place. On the big screen showing the results, the third place score was 8.15 meters. &quot;It&#39;s not very high. I think I should be able to sprint. Even if I jump with my head up, I can win a medal.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On July 17, 2022, after the last jump, he glided perfectly in the air and landed. He looked back at the sand pit and felt confident. When he saw the score of 8.36 meters displayed on the big screen in the arena, Wang Jianan squatted on the ground, covered his face and cried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/VBqSOdlm1LeWgX4cPeNrTmafyIaYCCjMlzec8A6L.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/VBqSOdlm1LeWgX4cPeNrTmafyIaYCCjMlzec8A6L.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 16, 2022, Wang Jianan won China&#39;s first ever World Championships men&#39;s long jump gold medal at the World Athletics Championships in Oregon, and became the first man in history to win a World Championships. The Asian athlete who won the long jump championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, 25-year-old Wang Jianan won the men&#39;s long jump final at the World Athletics Championships in Oregon With his final &quot;shattering leap&quot;, he broke the Asian record and won the championship. He became the first Chinese male athlete to win the field championship at the World Athletics Championships. He was also the fourth Chinese male athlete to win the field event after Liu Xiang, Wang Hao and Chen Ding. The Chinese male athlete who won the gold medal at the World Athletics Championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jianan, who became famous in one battle, will have to face how to surpass himself and break the world record, but this is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lewis, a world-famous athlete and American track and field athlete, once forwarded an article on a social platform called &quot;Why is the world record for the long jump so difficult to break?&quot; The article mentioned: In 1968, Beamon set a long jump of 8.90 meters. World record, if Powell had not broken the world record with a score of 8.95 meters in 1991, then no one could come close to Beamon&#39;s score of 8.90 meters in 1968. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/6ybnrDlU8AxDOYAn5Ra5skfpKlbffXKimTaCIMxV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/6ybnrDlU8AxDOYAn5Ra5skfpKlbffXKimTaCIMxV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 24, 2023, in the men&#39;s long jump final of the 2023 World Athletics Championships in Budapest, Hungary, Chinese player Wang Jianan won fifth place&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 84 years, the world record for long jump has only been held by three people. Jesse Owens held it for 25 years, and Bob Bee Mon lasted 23 years and Mike Powell lasted 31 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recent World Championships in Budapest, Wang Jianan ranked fifth, and at the Hangzhou Asian Games, he finally successfully defended his title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the game, he mentioned, &quot;The result of 8.22 meters may be a little bit lower than my competition goal. Originally, I wanted to break my own competition record, but I was still 2 centimeters short. Next, I will still To find problems in the competition, the results of the World Championships in Budapest were not very satisfactory, and it also taught me a lesson. I hope to apply the experience of the World Championships in Budapest and the Asian Games to the Paris Olympics, so that I can achieve a relatively good result. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hardships will make you successful.&quot; He once said that he has always believed in this sentence, from the failure of the Tokyo Olympics to the leap to create an Asian record, and then to the successful defense of the Hangzhou Asian Games. , along the way, Wang Jianan himself is the best confirmation of this sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不受理“知假买假”，可能会有怎样的结果？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258016]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Market Supervision and Administration Bureau in a place in Sichuan issued a warning, strictly prohibiting profit-making activities such as buying fakes based on known fakes. Consumers make complaints and reports. The announcement stated that once a complaint is determined to be malicious, the Municipal Supervision Bureau will not accept it. At the same time, if the complaint is used for extortion, threats and intimidation, the complaint will be transferred to the police to investigate the criminal responsibility of the malicious complaint reporter. Not surprisingly, this &quot;letter of caution&quot; caused great controversy. The bureau later deleted the document from its social media accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time such an announcement has appeared. In recent years, many places across the country have issued similar announcements. The municipal supervision department stated that its purpose is to &quot;create safe and comfortable consumption and a good business environment&quot; and &quot;equally protect the legitimate rights and interests of consumers and business entities.&quot; However, it is the legal duty of the municipal supervisory department to supervise illegal goods such as counterfeit and shoddy goods. If &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot; is considered a malicious complaint and refused to be accepted, it is suspected of neglecting the performance of duties and administrative inaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Profit-making anti-counterfeiting&quot; is also commonly known as &quot;professional anti-counterfeiting&quot;. Its legal basis is mainly the relevant provisions of the Consumer Rights Protection Law, Food Safety Law, and Drug Administration Law. The Consumer Protection Law stipulates that if an operator commits fraud in providing goods or services, in addition to compensating the losses suffered by consumers, the amount of compensation should also be increased by three times the price of the goods or service fees. If the amount is less than 500 yuan, the compensation shall be 500 yuan, that is, &quot; If you give a false one, you will lose three.&quot; The Food Safety Law and the Drug Administration Law stipulate that if you produce food, counterfeit drugs, or inferior drugs that do not meet food safety standards, or you sell and use food that you know are not in compliance with food safety standards, or you know that they are counterfeit or inferior drugs, you are &quot;counterfeit.&quot; &quot;Ten for one&quot;, the minimum is 1,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these legal provisions, a group of &quot;professional anti-counterfeiters&quot; were born. They look for substandard goods, food and medicines in the market, and after purchasing them, they complain or sue in order to obtain three or ten times the price. Additional compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cracking down on counterfeit and shoddy goods and maintaining food and drug safety are the legal responsibilities of market supervision departments. However, the market is very huge, and it is difficult to detect all illegal activities solely relying on the power of market supervision departments. The purpose of punitive damages stipulated in the law is not only to protect the interests of consumers, but more importantly, to make the criminals who make and sell counterfeit goods pay a greater price through punitive damages, so as to curb the behavior of counterfeiting and counterfeiting. With the incentive of punitive damages, professional anti-counterfeiters also have greater incentives to discover counterfeit and shoddy goods and report them to regulatory authorities. In this sense, professional anti-counterfeiters are actually helpers to regulatory authorities. It is much more efficient to discover illegal activities through the clues they provide than it is for the regulatory authorities to find the needle in the haystack on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are indeed some people who actually engage in extortion in the name of fighting counterfeiting. For example, some people frame the situation first and then &quot;crack down on counterfeiting&quot;, placing expired food taken away in supermarkets and framing merchants for selling expired food. Some people deliberately hide the food that is about to expire in the supermarket. The supermarket fails to find out that it has not been collected in time. They wait until it has expired and then buy it, claiming for selling expired food. Some even failed to find problematic products and threatened merchants with reports to pay &quot;consultancy fees.&quot; These actions are no longer a crackdown on counterfeiting, but a &quot;black crackdown&quot;, which is illegal and criminal. It is necessary to crack down on these &quot;black crackdowns&quot;. However, for the majority of professional anti-counterfeiters who legitimately exercise their rights conferred by the law and demand compensation in accordance with the law, the regulatory authorities simply refuse to accept their reports and complaints because their anti-counterfeiting behavior is &quot;profit-making&quot;. There is no legal basis and they are suspected of neglecting to fulfill statutory obligations. Responsibilities may encourage the trend of counterfeiting and selling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The criteria for regulatory authorities to identify &quot;malicious complaints&quot; include purchasing the same product again after receiving punitive damages and then complaining. But if substandard goods are completely removed from the market after being discovered for the first time, how can professional counterfeiters buy the same substandard goods again? If you continue to sell substandard goods after being punished for the first time, but the regulatory authorities no longer accept subsequent complaints, will the counterfeit merchants be able to continue selling fake goods unscrupulously? Do such regulations protect consumers or counterfeiters? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that, at least in the field of food and drugs, the judicial system supports &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes.&quot; The Judicial Interpretation &quot;Provisions on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Law in the Trial of Food and Drug Dispute Cases&quot; issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2013 clearly states that for food and drug quality disputes, producers and sellers of food and drugs with quality problems shall use the consumer&#39;s knowledge to purchase fake products. If the defense is false, the court will not support it. That is to say, we support consumers to “know fakes and buy fakes.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a government department, the Market Supervision Bureau prohibits &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot; and considers it &quot;malicious&quot;, which is contrary to the regulations of the judicial organs. Once the counterfeiters are sued for administrative inaction, they will be sued in court. I&#39;m afraid I will inevitably lose. According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, a professional anti-counterfeiter once reported that many units in Guizhou, Yunnan and other provinces were selling counterfeit medicines. After the market supervision department verified it, they found that he was not buying for consumption purposes and was seeking improper benefits. He was refused a reward and he filed a lawsuit. The court ruled that the municipal supervisory department lost the lawsuit and he should be rewarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unscrupulous merchants selling counterfeit goods not only harm the interests of consumers, but also harm the interests of legitimate merchants. To &quot;optimize the business environment&quot; and &quot;protect the interests of business entities&quot;, we should crack down on extortion of enterprises and protect the interests of legitimate business entities. If there is a blanket ban on &quot;knowing about fakes and buying fakes&quot;, it will only condone &quot;knowing about fakes and selling fakes&quot; and objectively protect the interests of unscrupulous businessmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[摇滚之城惹热议：中国哪儿人最把摇滚刻进DNA里？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fc790a5708bf0500e071a8465b07a524.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/25/fc790a5708bf0500e071a8465b07a524.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252071&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, cities such as Shijiazhuang and Xinxiang in Henan have also successively played the &quot;rock card&quot; and announced that they will compete for the city and hometown of rock. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Speaking of Shijiazhuang, the public may feel unfamiliar, but when it comes to some rock bands in Shijiazhuang, music fans are familiar with them. Many rock bands such as Universal Youth Hotel and Dawn&#39;s Leader have a certain connection with Shijiazhuang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How glorious was Chinese rock music?&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back at history, there have been several rock music in China. After ten years of development, rock music also has fertile soil. As early as the 1980s, with the reform and opening up and social changes, local rock music secretly sprouted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 1986, 24-year-old Cui Jian sang &quot;Nothing&quot; in a high-pitched and roaring voice at the Beijing Workers&#39; Gymnasium. When the passionate lyrics came out &lt;span>;, thousands of spectators in the audience sang and shouted loudly, and Chinese rock music began an unprecedented process. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Subsequently, a number of outstanding bands and musicians emerged one after another. The Black Panther Band, the Tang Dynasty Band, and the Stinger Band, which originated in Beijing and Xi&#39;an, came out of nowhere and successively released albums such as &quot;Black Panther&quot;, &quot;Dream Back to the Tang Dynasty&quot;, and &quot;Chinese Fire I&quot; with lightning speed. Set off a wave of Chinese rock music. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In that era when materials were still scarce, the albums of rock bands sold like crazy. The Black Panther Band&#39;s self-titled album &quot;Black Panther&quot; sold 1.5 million copies, and the Tang Dynasty Band&#39;s &quot;Dream Back to the Tang Dynasty&quot; sold 2 million copies, becoming a hit that is still difficult to match. Young people wear big waves, bell-bottom pants, and play these albums repeatedly with tape recorders, making it fashionable to listen to these rock music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994 is known as the peak year of Chinese rock music at that time. Dou Wei, He Yong, Zhang Chu, Tang Dynasty Band, etc. gathered in Hong Kong and performed a &quot;China&#39;s New Rock Forces&quot; concert that had nothing to do with the Hong Kong Philharmonic at the Hung Hom Arena, which represents the trend vane of pop music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage, with the sounds of &quot;Advanced Animals&quot;, &quot;Bell and Drum Tower&quot;, &quot;Flying Birds&quot; and other songs, in the audience, the audience from Hong Kong and all over the world watched again and again for more than three hours. He jumped up and down and roared until his throat became hoarse. After the concert, major media in Hong Kong used headlines to record this classic moment with &quot;rock soul, shocking Hong Kong&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/d5332f9dd68b222b6707f7425e603845.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/d5332f9dd68b222b6707f7425e603845.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252068 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Who is the hidden rock city in China&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Now, decades have passed since the 1990s, and the development of Chinese rock music has undergone tremendous changes. , the position of rock music is also changing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Beijing and Xi&#39;an, once the most important rock and roll venues, are showing a current situation of replacement of old and new. Rock seniors such as Cui Jian, Xu Wei, and Zheng Jun have become more epoch-making memories flowing in people&#39;s minds, while new bands such as Pain Yang Band, Black Sa Band, Xuan Band, and Island Mood have become the mainstream of current performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leaping cities of Shijiazhuang and Xinxiang, Henan Province represent the extension of rock DNA. In Shijiazhuang, local bands such as Universal Youth Hotel, Relativity Band, Small Town Spring, and Plasticine Band have emerged one after another. In particular, the birth of the Universal Youth Hostel, which combines rock, punk, folk and other elements, was born like a sharp blade. Songs such as &quot;Kill That Shijiazhuang Man&lt;span>;&quot; and &quot;Qinhuangdao&quot; can be called the secret codes of many music fans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In Xinxiang, Henan, the rock genes that once attracted Tang Dynasty, Samsara, Zero Point, Overload, etc. to perform are continued. Bands such as Little Pumpkin were also born in a small area. , Mad Doctor Band, Cyclops Band and many other bands that represent the power of rock music for the younger generation. In the local area, even the owner of a milk tea shop or noodle shop can put down his kitchen utensils and play a musical instrument at any time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the rock flavor of Shandong is permeated in various music festivals. Jinan Erli Music Festival, Rizhao Ocean Music Festival, Qingdao Phoenix Music Festival, Weifang Guochao Music Festival, Dongying Strawberry Music Festival, Binzhou Midi Music Festival and many other music festivals have also turned the release of rock elements into cultural life. daily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thousands of miles away in Chengdu, the land of abundance, is another important narrative venue about rock and roll. Whether it is Tang Lei’s tavern band or the founder of bands such as Sound Toy, Mr. Turtle, and Asura, they all have incomprehensible connections with Shu. Chengdu rock music has also continued to spread across the country starting from the live house on Yulin Road. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The possibility of the development of Chinese rock &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be found that today’s Chinese rock is no longer It is limited to a certain place, but has become popular among young people in more regions and cities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, influential and highly sung songs have quickly captured the hearts of young people, allowing young people in different cities to whisper and resonate with each other through music. On the other hand, with the popularity of music variety shows such as &quot;Summer of the Band&quot; and the holding of various music festivals starting in 2019, young people have become more aware of the connection between rock and music by watching competitions and attending events in person. charm, and also hatched more music fans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of music festivals, although there are old brands abroad such as Woodstock Music Festival, Glastonbury Music Festival and other very influential music festivals, Festival, but with the creation of rock cities in Shijiazhuang, Xinxiang and other places, as well as the urbanization and large-scale promotion of various music festivals, music festivals in China are gradually rising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strawberry Music Festival, Midi Music Festival, Simple Life Music Festival, etc. have gradually become well-known music festival brands. They have strong appeal and influence in the country and can attract audiences everywhere. Many music fans went to watch. In the future, it is not impossible to go abroad and cooperate with some foreign music festivals, or to host them in other cities in Asia, Europe and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, as the professionalization of rock and pop music increases, professional learning and training in modern pop music, including rock, has also taken shape. Midi Music School in Beijing &lt;span>; now offers a variety of majors. By teaching modern music courses covering pop, punk, rock, etc., students who like rock music can study systematically. The school has also produced Rock musicians such as Zhao Meng, bassist of New Pants Band, and Mao Chuan, lead singer of Escape Plan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, as a form of music and art&lt;/span>; expression, rock music has recorded the confusion, thinking and emotions of reality and contemporary young people in different social periods. . In the music atmosphere of the new Generation Z, the presence of rock and roll is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future of Chinese rock music, the collision and integration of cultures and creators from different regions will bring more possibilities to music and will also give birth to new &lt;span>; dazzling stars in the team of tomorrow. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花西子眉笔引发的行业审视：直播电商，成也主播，毁也主播？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258032]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor was live broadcasting products on the booth. Pictures and texts Unrelated. Interface News Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor broadcast live on the booth. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Interface News Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After briefly entering the live broadcast room, a domestic beauty brand established for more than two years decided not to enter the show again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is both a fame and fortune fair and a place at the forefront of the limelight. The most recent farce was on September 10, 2023, when super anchor Li Jiaqi criticized netizens while selling Huaxizi eyebrow pencil. The turmoil has been postponed to this day, and the Huaxizi brand has become the target of public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people in the industry are re-examining the sales ecology of anchors bringing goods. A brand manager Chu Shi (pseudonym) is also a melon-eater. For her, the high commissions and pit fees required by big anchors are difficult for small brands to resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;last straw&quot; that caused Chu Shi to give up the live broadcast was exactly a live broadcast. The brand invited a top anchor with tens of millions of fans, and the position fee was about 70,000 yuan, with an agreed sales guarantee of 210,000 yuan. They have high expectations and regard it as the &quot;most important event&quot; since its inception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end, the leading anchor only sold a few thousand yuan, and did not refund the corresponding amount according to the contract. Chu Shi called this incident a &quot;trigger&quot;. Although she felt that the business was unhealthy before, she was willing to abide by the rules of the industry. This time she was in the whirlpool and felt chilled: &quot;Given such a high commission, there are still pitfalls. For a bit fee, a brand like ours cannot play like that.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The brand went to the police station to report the crime, and then won the lawsuit through litigation. However, the refunded fees have not yet been received, and the anchor is still active in the live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“So much profit goes to the host”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For this new brand, the first “obstacle” to live broadcast admission sounds humble: identifying the reasons for rejection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu Shi and the others contacted thousands of anchors and bloggers. Chu Shi recalled: “In the first year, we really hoped to increase the brand’s exposure through some experts. I put a lot of effort into promoting it and its popularity. But the result is really not very good.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sending products to popular live broadcast rooms is the preferred way for small brands to gain popularity. Data from the live broadcast e-commerce industry blue book released by the China Institute of Metrology and other units show that in the first half of 2023, the sales of live broadcasts on key monitored e-commerce platforms reached 1.27 trillion yuan, with more than 110 million live broadcasts and more than 70 million live products. , the number of active anchors exceeds 2.7 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following the anchor&#39;s product selection process, they will communicate with the other party&#39;s business personnel and wait for feedback. If there is no feedback, it means it is inappropriate by default. It’s like rushing through the sand, “maybe less than 10% of anchors or business people will reply to us in this link.” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first Chu Shi would feel confused, not knowing where he was stuck. Later, the picture gradually became clearer, &quot;In fact, it is not the product at all, but the dissatisfaction with the price or commission.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that anchors would focus on promoting the same product in various categories, making it particularly difficult for new products to emerge. The products that were strongly promoted by the anchors were actually the ones for which the brand offered high commissions. “For example, there are several products we know that offer commissions of 60 to 70 points, and they have already sold to the top in that category. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;70% commission means that if a product sells for 100 yuan, 70 yuan will be given to the anchor. The remaining costs should cover product development, raw materials, packaging materials and other costs, as well as warehousing logistics, site and labor costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We think this business is very unhealthy.” Chu Shi believes that high commissions force costs to be reduced. “So much profit is given to the anchors. They charge such high commissions, but they do not Without creating corresponding social value and providing more jobs, the profits of upstream brands and the supply chain have been reduced. Brands can only continue to reduce costs, and their products will become worse and worse, and the treatment of employees will also be worse. It’s getting worse.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four or five years ago, she worked with anchors for beauty brands at the time, with commissions ranging from 20% to 30%. However, the live broadcast ecosystem gradually evolved. “From the year before last to last year, the commissions continued to increase. It’s rising. I don’t think it’s because the anchors are raising the price, it’s because the industry is too complicated, whether it’s beauty or live streaming, it’s all too complicated.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beauty is recognized as one of the most popular fields. Nanshan, co-founder of the beauty MCN organization May Beauty, also feels the same way. Although there is a lot of beauty traffic on the platform, there are also a lot of people entering the platform. &quot;I think it started to roll out in 2019 and 2020, and every year it is better than before. He kept curling more and more without stopping.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of the volume, the mechanism of the volume, the content of the volume, the capital of the volume... the prices of things of the same quality are constantly falling in the competition, but the commissions for the anchors are gradually increasing. &quot;I think this volume is good in all aspects.&quot; , product homogeneity is also very serious, and every price range is full of competitors.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang, director of Hangzhou Xijiang New Retail Research Institute and former deputy director of Alibaba Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that taking eyebrow pencils as an example, from the perspective of raw material processing fees, including factory delivery The cost plus tax may be less than 10 yuan. The biggest cost of cosmetics is sales expenses. Previously, this part included marketing and channel expenses, that is, advertising, celebrity endorsements, channel deduction fees, and profits from offline wholesalers and agents. Now, if you sell through live e-commerce, it is a direct retail. The most important ones are traffic fees, advertising fees, anchor commissions for bringing goods, and pit fees. &quot;These fees account for a very high proportion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out that the biggest problem with the current live broadcast sales system is the trend of low prices. “After the emergence of live broadcast e-commerce, China’s retail market has been turned upside down. Everyone is fighting for low prices. &quot;If a company has no profits, it will have no money to do product research and development and innovation, and bad money may drive out good money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Only care about three points: price, commission, and pit fee&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Price and gifts are the key points when attracting consumers to place orders in the live broadcast room. At this point, super The head anchor does have a higher say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Lei (pseudonym), the person in charge of a domestic brand who once sent products to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, told Southern Weekend reporters that Li Jiaqi’s pit fee one or two years ago was “not expensive,” “about 8. &quot;More than 10,000 yuan&quot;, the commission is 30 to 40%, which is almost the same as other anchors. But Li Jiaqi&#39;s prices are very low, even at prices the merchant himself has &quot;never sold before.&quot; &quot;He doesn&#39;t care how much you originally sold them for, he will only tell you &#39;how much I want to sell them for.&#39;&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;He will demand &#39;I am the lowest&#39;, but he will not tell you openly. He will only tell you a price to see if you can give it.&quot; Qiao Lei said that both parties It is also necessary to sign a price guarantee agreement to ensure that there will be no lower prices, including the brand&#39;s own live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This condition is almost harsh, but a large number of businesses are still willing to accept it. Even now, there are still small brands that are eager to get into the super live broadcast room and are waiting hard. Lillian (pseudonym) is the person in charge of branding and e-commerce at a start-up company that makes functional skin care products. For her, the road to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room has not yet been opened. “I have been following them for half a year, and I still have During the data review stage.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Super anchors such as Li Jiaqi (first from left) will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Like Li Jiaqi (first from left) Super anchors will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Chu Shi has come into contact with &quot;very few anchors who are truly professional.&quot; Brands provide product selling points, and anchors follow the script. &quot;They rarely ask us professional questions about products.&quot; , because today’s anchors have too many choices, and merchants of all sizes are waiting for them to deliver products. They don’t know the raw materials, ingredients and functions of the products. What they care about most are three points: How much is the price, how much is the commission, and is there any pit fee?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo (pseudonym), an anchor who has been doing live broadcasts for five years, told Southern Weekend reporters that she would learn about the product information before the live broadcast. Go to the live broadcast room every hour and communicate with the operation about the overall situation. During the live broadcast, consumers are mainly told three pieces of information: how favorable the price of this product is, how easy it is to use, and when and in what scenario it will be needed. If consumers are tempted but are still hesitant, they will emphasize the accompanying gifts and the decreasing inventory, &quot;to force another order.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chu Shi’s observation, this is because the time to explain each product in the live broadcast room is very limited. Within a few minutes, the strength of the discount is reflected in order to impress users and make them purchase. &quot;Use &#39;Quantity&#39; is the fastest way for them to reflect the value of the product.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo has been a brand external anchor for a long time, and has worked with 30 or 40 brands. She is charged by the hour. &quot;Selling more or less all depends on my own professional ethics and KPIs.&quot; There is not a lot of pressure on sales.” Recently, she decided to go it alone and collect commissions for selling goods. The more she sold, the more she earned, which gave her a greater sense of urgency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the platform will analyze the live broadcast data in real time, display the product placement expenses, sales volume and total sales of the day, and also conduct vertical comparisons. Increasingly intuitive data also tests the ability of anchors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The game mechanism between brands and anchors&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to create a super anchor. May Beauty, where Nanshan is located, once failed to become a super anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This MCN organization has incubated more than 60 beauty experts. Nanshan recalled that the company originally “wanted to go towards the top.” At the end of 2021, they tried to support a beauty blogger with more than 10 million fans. At his peak, the blogger could bring in 5 to 6 million yuan in goods per sale. But they soon discovered that the top anchors were &quot;not that easy to do&quot; and it was difficult to obtain &quot;a particularly good mechanism&quot;. The frequency of live broadcasts could not be increased, and the commission rate was relatively low. It was very likely that &quot;the work was in vain and no money was made.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the keys to being stuck in the top spot is the mechanism, that is, the brand merchants give the anchors product prices, gift configurations, commission sharing or other incentive resources. The differences in the mechanisms obtained by different anchors are obvious. Nanshan compared its own anchors with the leading anchors in the industry. The same shampoo was sold in both live broadcast rooms for 119 yuan for two bottles of 1,000 ml. At the head anchor, those who place orders can get an extra 400 to 500 ml of shampoo, but they may only get 100 to 200 ml. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sales that exceed brand expectations, make products a hit, have good daily video and live broadcast data, and excellent business negotiation skills can all help anchors get better mechanisms, &quot;If Without a good mechanism, it will be difficult for users to continue paying for it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Nanshan also observed that compared with the previous two years, brands have made less and less &quot;sacrifice&quot; in terms of mechanism. &quot;In 2021, brands are more willing to sacrifice some mechanisms for anchors. For example, if he sells it for 119 yuan in his flagship store, he may give 99 yuan to our live broadcast room.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out, The relationship between the brand and the anchor is essentially a game. The brand previously offered low prices in the hope of attracting fans to its official website account and paying direct attention to the brand itself through the use of anchors to promote products. Anchors need to keep the products in the live broadcast room low-priced, maintain their original fans, and increase their value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of the product in the live broadcast room, the commission ratio that the anchor can get, and the gifts for consumers are all the focus of the game. In August 2023, Nanshan negotiated a cooperation with an anchor with one million fans at a price of 180,000 yuan, including two or three short videos, two live broadcast warm-ups and one special live broadcast, and brought five products. The main demands of brands are to reduce commissions and reduce gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both parties held the mechanism table in their hands, went through two or three rounds of meetings and discussions, and finally chose to take a step back. The average commission has dropped from about 31% to 28%, and the product has gone from 119 yuan for two 600ml bottles and a 150ml gift to 128 yuan for two bottles and a 300ml gift, which is equivalent to &quot;getting three bottles at once for 128 yuan.&quot; Both parties are satisfied with the results. After two or three live broadcasts, the brand&#39;s initial investment &quot;will come back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanshan mentioned that some brands have also formed new cooperative relationships with anchors. That is, before the product is launched, the brand will let the anchor participate in product development, and the brand will communicate with the anchor: &quot;I &quot;How much do you think is appropriate for the product?&quot; &quot;I want to change the parts that are not suitable yet.&quot; The two parties will lengthen the line of cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Because anchors have a characteristic, they understand consumers better, which will make the entire industry chain closer to consumers.” Li Yongjian, director of the Research Office of the Institute of Financial Strategy of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, pointed out that the relationship between brands and anchors In-depth cooperation between enterprises is relatively beneficial, can improve the efficiency of the supply chain, and is conducive to the rapid formation of domestic brands. However, we need to be wary that some anchors may take advantage of consumers&#39; trust to further squeeze consumers. &quot;(Remember) you represent the interests of consumers and help them find high-quality and low-priced products.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Live streaming is still the direction of this MCN organization’s efforts in 2023. Nanshan’s basis is that consumers’ minds have been formed and they have the habit of buying things in live broadcast rooms on a daily basis. At the same time, live broadcast consumption behavior has become more rational. In addition to price, the suitability of the product will also be considered. “At this time, we use live broadcasts to In this way, we can &#39;grow&#39; users and let them place orders.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In May 2023, a beauty e-commerce company in Hangzhou was live broadcasting. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 2023, a beauty e-commerce company in Hangzhou conducted a live broadcast . Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Where is the “ceiling” of live streaming e-commerce? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Different brands enter the live broadcast room for different purposes. Qiao Lei said that for some big brands, live broadcast is just a channel, and they value the &quot;grass planting&quot; effect more than the amount of goods brought by the anchor. New brands and small brands are different. They need to &quot;plant grass&quot; and &quot;mow grass&quot;. They hope to have enough sales volume, return the cooperation costs, and increase the turnover rate of goods. As for himself, the more important purpose is promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effect is obvious. Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast brought hundreds of thousands of visitors to their store. “The original daily sales were 50,000 to 60,000 yuan. Maybe after he helped us bring goods through the live broadcast, , the daily sales reached 80,000 to 90,000, and the influence is expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Yongjian pointed out that &quot;reliance on chefs&quot; is the biggest shortcoming of the live broadcast e-commerce ecosystem. For a new brand, telling a good brand story, making good products, and forming brand power are the most basic. It is very difficult to rely on top anchors to build a brand. &quot;There are individual (successful) cases, but whether this case can be sustained, if If there is no brand power and product power, I think it is questionable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the &quot;ceiling&quot; of live broadcast e-commerce has appeared. He said that the basic logic of e-commerce is to stretch the supply chain and shorten the marketing chain. &quot;Now suddenly there is an additional anchor, and 25% and 30% will be cut off. This business logic itself has problems.&quot; An imperfect profit distribution mechanism, a chaotic price system, and uneven development among anchors are all chaos in the live broadcast ecosystem, which has led to new problems, such as data traffic fraud and false orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Qiao Lei, the development of the live broadcast field has become mature. Regardless of whether the number of fans is large or small, the age of the audience is old or young, and whether the field is hot or cold, there are corresponding competitors. &quot;In fact, there are people occupying every card slot, and any vertical track It’s basically all covered.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Lei found that in the past, each platform and each anchor had its own audience and had little influence on each other. However, during major promotion periods such as &quot;618&quot; and &quot;Double Eleven&quot;, several The overlapping rate of consumers on the platform will be significantly higher, and all anchors carrying goods will be drawn into the same arena, making the strength of their competitiveness particularly obvious. &quot;When it comes to large-scale promotions, the living space of tail anchors is actually very small, and head anchors are still the main ones.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, small brands that are not very competitive will also choose to participate in major promotions. &quot;Lie down&quot; to protect yourself and withdraw from the fierce battlefield. Lillian said that traffic costs will increase during major promotions. She does not have the ability to seize traffic and divide the market, and will actively avoid the war. &quot;Normally (big promotion festivals) we are not anxious, we just put it away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Haoxing, a professor at the School of Economics at Zhejiang Gongshang University and a member of the Zhejiang Provincial Consumption Promotion Expert Committee, told Southern Weekend reporters that the current ecology of the live broadcast field is not sound. On the other hand, they have raised the sales price and made huge profits. All the dividends have been concentrated on the Internet celebrities. The profit distribution in the ecosystem is seriously unreasonable. This phenomenon must be broken in the future.&quot; He suggested that the market regulatory authorities strengthen supervision and hoped that the supply chain would become more mature and complete, with reasonable distribution of upstream and downstream profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the live broadcast industry has now reached a period of transformation. Various types of vertical industry chain live broadcasts, factory live broadcasts, and expert live broadcasts are all playing a greater role, and &quot;small but beautiful, small and specialized&quot; have emerged. Features, this is also the development direction of &quot;future version 2.0 live broadcast&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访许鞍华：因为不服气，所以继续拍电影丨影视大咖谈④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FAMbdwT9pAbp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FA MbdwT9pAbp. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 29, 2021, Xu Anhua attended the screening of &quot;The First Incense&quot; in Shanghai Post-communication activities. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Beginning of Winter in 2021, Xu Anhua was in a good mood. She flew from Beijing to Xiamen , planning to make this the last stop of her trip to the mainland. On May 22, 2019, the new film &quot;The First Incense&quot; directed by Xu Anhua started filming in Gulangyu Island, Xiamen. Two and a half years later, she returned here with the film. At the screening event, some audience members whispered to each other: &quot;I heard that this movie was not shot well?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is a good thing to have discussions.&quot; Talking about the reputation controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot; , Xu Anhua&#39;s attitude is very calm. Although her career has encountered many failures and doubts, the rating of &quot;The First Incense&quot; on Douban is only 5.6, becoming Xu Anhua&#39;s lowest score in 43 years of acting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Liu Ren told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Due to various reasons, &quot;The First Incense&quot; did not have a premiere. The director came to Xiamen this time to thank those who helped us during the previous filming. It is completely We paid for it at our own expense. The reason for the word-of-mouth controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot; is very complicated, which has nothing to do with the current publicity and distribution rules of the film industry. Ann (Ann Hui&#39;s English name) is not indifferent to this, but she often I cheered her up and said it didn&#39;t matter. Although she was angry, she would not be sad. She would fight back, learn from experience and continue filming - you see she is a confrontational person with a revolutionary heart.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot; The filming of &quot;The First Incense&quot; will most likely fail&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have been working on this project for seven years, and it is really a long story.&quot; Liu Ren, the producer of &quot;The First Incense&quot; said, &quot; &quot;The First Incense&quot; is the first project I produced. The company &quot;Blue Bird&quot; was handed over to me by my teacher Xia Meng (note: Hong Kong movie star, well-known patriot) before her death. She told me to make good movies. , so I asked director Xu Anhua to shoot &quot;The First Incense&quot;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film adaptation of Zhang Ailing&#39;s &quot;The First Incense&quot; has been going on for decades. During her lifetime, Zhang Ailing had liked the movie star Lin Dai to play the heroine Ge Weilong. Later, Lin Dai committed suicide and the matter was ignored. In the 1980s, Jade Bird Film Company, founded by Xia Meng, started a trend of co-productions between Hong Kong and the Mainland, investing in three films: &quot;The Wrath of the Sea&quot;, &quot;Heroes from Ancient Times&quot; and &quot;Back to Time&quot;. Xia Meng also considered purchasing the copyright of &quot;The First Incense&quot;, but due to some changes in the production environment of Hong Kong films, Xia Meng left the film industry, and the matter was delayed again. In the 1990s, Xu Feng, the producer of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; purchased the copyright of the novel and contacted Yang Dechang, but due to various reasons, he did not make the film. It wasn&#39;t until 2014 that Liu Ren, who was working in the Shanghai publishing industry at the time, was chatting with friends and came up with the idea of ​​adapting Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel into a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Zhang Ailing&#39;s many novels, Liu Ren chose &quot;The First Incense&quot;. After some twists and turns, in 2015, he bought the five-year adaptation rights of the novel from Song Yilang, the copyright holder of Zhang Ailing, and set out to find his favorite director. In 2016, he received Xu Anhua&#39;s approval to serve as the film&#39;s producer. &quot;Ann told me at the time how difficult it would be to adapt this movie, and that adapting &quot;The First Incense&quot; would most likely fail. She suggested that I find a young director to make it. Because even if this movie doesn&#39;t work well and is controversial, young people People have a young person’s perspective, and it’s a good thing to have controversy.” Liu Ren told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2016 to 2019, Liu Ren has been doing various tasks for the filming of the movie, encountering various accidents and misfortunes. Seeing that the adaptation copyright is about to expire, the management proposed to ask Xu Anhua to be the director. . At that time, Ann Hui had just completed the movie &quot;When Will There Be a Bright Moon&quot;. She compared several job offers at hand and finally decided to take on the directorship of this film. She hired someone who had collaborated with her in the stage play &quot;The Story of the Golden Lock&quot; Writer Wang Anyi served as the screenwriter, and the prototype of the movie &quot;The First Incense&quot; gradually took shape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Anhua was born in 1947. When &quot;The First Incense&quot; is released in October 2021, she will be 74 years old. In 2020, when the COVID-19 epidemic broke out, Xu Anhua completed the post-production of the film and learned that the Venice Film Festival was going to award the Lifetime Achievement Award to him. She is the first female director in the world to receive this honor, which is seen as a victory for female filmmakers around the world. Xu Anhua delivered a speech in English when receiving the award, saying that he would go back to help more young people so that they would also have the opportunity to receive the Lifetime Achievement Award in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2020, a documentary &quot;Making Movies Well&quot; chronicling Xu Anhua&#39;s 40 years in film premiered at the Hong Kong International Film Festival. The director of this work, Wen Nianzhong, has served as the director of several of Xu Anhua&#39;s films. The art director showed the audience some fragments of Xu Anhua&#39;s life in his later years from the perspective of friends and collaborators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anhua Xu has never been married and has almost no emotional experience. She once said, &quot;Movies are my husband or wife, and literature is my mistress.&quot; She only has eyes for movies. She often falls down when she is too involved in her work. The most anxious thing is that there are no movies to shoot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Ren told the Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;When we were filming in Gulangyu Island, Ann fell in the bathroom one day and landed on the back of her head, which was very scary. She sent me a message as soon as she regained consciousness and said , &#39;Xiao Liu, I fell, I dare not move, can you come and see me?&#39; I rushed to take a look, and there were purple bruises from the back of her head to her neck, and I quickly took her for an MRI. Tell me, the first thing that comes to mind is that if something really happens, call A Kwan (director Kwan Jin Peng) to come (replace her). Ann is really a person who works hard for the movie, so many times I Forget that she is an old man in her seventies, we will continue to cooperate in the future, and I hope she can make two more movies before she is 80 years old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6, 2021, Despite negative reviews, the movie &quot;First Incense&quot; still grossed more than 60 million yuan at the box office, and is expected to become Xu Anhua&#39;s second-highest box office film in the mainland. The next morning, Southern Weekend reporters conducted an exclusive interview with Xu Anhua in Xiamen. At the end of the conversation, she suddenly said: &quot;Let me ask you a question too. To be honest, what do you think of &quot;The First Incense&quot;?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Anhua based on Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel of the same name The film adaptation of &quot;Half Life&quot; (1997), starring Anita Mui (right) and Wang Zhiwen (left). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;Zhang Ailing has become an inviolable writer&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The First Incense&quot; has received so much criticism on the Internet this time. To be honest, I am a little surprised , judging from the ratings on Douban.com, this is the movie with the worst reputation in your career. I would like to know, what do you think of the word-of-mouth controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t expect there to be such a loud voice, but I think if this drama doesn’t get good reviews, it’s good to be controversial. of. It’s great if everyone can openly talk about their ideas about the movie and discuss the show together. It would also be good to talk more about other social issues. Maybe because of the epidemic, everyone is a little confused, and we can take this opportunity to clarify some basic concepts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have seen some interviews and you said you are filming After watching &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; and &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot;, I no longer want to make another movie adapted from Zhang Ailing&#39;s work, but why did I continue to make &quot;The First Incense&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s not that I don’t want to shoot Zhang Ailing. In fact, I really want to shoot it, but I really haven’t thought about how to shoot Zhang Ailing’s works so that the audience can accept them. In other words, how to shoot to make people feel that the artistic quality of the movie is even higher. After the filming experience accumulated in the first two films, I realized that adapting Zhang Ailing&#39;s works is very difficult to please. It is neither easy to please the Western (audience) nor the Chinese (audience). To be honest, &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot; was rejected by the Venice Film Festival. They originally enthusiastically asked me to bring the film to Venice, but after watching it, they felt that it was a very ordinary love movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, &quot;Half a Life&quot; was screened in the United States, and a well-known film critic said that we could treat this movie as William Wyler (director of &quot;Roman Holiday&quot;) This is a touching and decent romance film shot by a technically savvy director. They saw &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot; in this way, so I wasn&#39;t unaware of the consequences when I made &quot;The First Incense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, they couldn&#39;t tell the difference between the real scenes and the fake ones that we overcame huge difficulties to shoot. They also didn&#39;t understand the background of the characters and thought it was an ordinary &quot;soap opera&quot;. Because they have never seen Zhang Ailing, we have made a difficult adaptation based on the original text, and we have done enough work. They don&#39;t think it is different from Hollywood movies in the 1940s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both &quot;The First Incense&quot; and &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; have very long lines. These lines are particularly unpleasant in the movie, but if the sentences in the original work are not used, readers will not let them go. I. Zhang Ailing&#39;s readers will demand that your work be the same as or better than the original work, but I know that many of Zhang Ailing&#39;s stories are not creative, because her creativity lies in her writing method, not the story itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have never thought about how to make a good film. I can&#39;t make it into a niche art film because I won&#39;t get money. During this period, I heard various feedbacks and became more and more aware that the market had changed. What&#39;s more, over the years, Zhang Ailing has become an inviolable writer. There are many fanatical fans who are more familiar with Zhang Ailing than me. A slight mistake will be very troublesome. I am deeply aware of these problems, but I haven&#39;t figured out how to overcome them. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I made a story like this for the current &quot;post-90s&quot; and &quot;post-00s&quot; generations. They may not understand the relationship between the characters. They don&#39;t know who the uncle is, what the second wife is, and the life experience of the aunt. What&#39;s going on? It&#39;s not that they are ignorant, it&#39;s that they don&#39;t have these things in their experience. For example, if a girl loses her virginity in the countryside in the 1940s, she will be dipped in a pig cage. That&#39;s not the case now. It&#39;s understandable for girls to covet a comfortable life. That era was actually very hypocritical. No one talked about money, and a woman would not admit it even if she wanted money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under such circumstances, I have to make the story understandable and reasonable for young audiences, while at the same time staying true to the original work. It is difficult to balance these. I&#39;m not trying to defend myself because I can&#39;t take good pictures, I just want to share some of the problems I&#39;ve experienced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You seem to have said &quot;The First Incense&quot; and &quot;The Fall of the City&quot; Do you think it is better than the latter? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, definitely. It was completely wrong before, but now it may be a little deviated from the original work, but I did it on purpose. I shot &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; hoping to make it a very touching story, but in fact it should be the least touching story. It just has a seemingly good ending. This is Zhang Ailing&#39;s creativity. But because I grew up reading a lot of romantic novels, I wanted the hero and heroine to feel like they were &quot;war-torn mandarin ducks.&quot; This was actually wrong and completely violated the spirit of the original work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The First Incense&quot; from preparation to filming What do you think is the most difficult part of the process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just finding funds is already very difficult, but it wasn’t me who found it, it was the producer who looked for it for three years. . After I bought the copyright, people talked about how &quot;The First Incense&quot; was (good) and how Zhang Ailing was (good), but when it came time to actually pay for it, no one was there. I don&#39;t blame them, because it&#39;s easy to calculate the box office by just calculating it. This is a literary film, which may require huge funds. It may be difficult to recoup the scenery and costumes of that era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, I think it is not a big problem to choose the actors and the filming team. Because of Zhang Ailing’s appeal, everyone is willing to give it a try. The second difficulty was choosing the location for filming, which was quite difficult. Later I chose Gulangyu Island. When it came time to actually shoot, because we already had such a mature team, there was no problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that it is difficult to find money for this film, but it is relatively easy to find actors. Yes, but the most controversial aspect of this film is the selection of actors. Did you receive any interference from capital during the process of finding actors? For example, will they tell you who you should and should not choose from a box office perspective?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There will be, but they are all normal discussions. , they didn’t give me much difficulty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Anna Hui (left), costume director Emi Wada (middle), and producer Liu Ren (right) on the set of the movie &quot;The First Incense&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“I am no longer anxious about the box office”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the documentary about you &quot;Making Movies Well&quot;, you expressed directly that every time you shoot After finishing a movie, you will worry about the box office, which is a very anxious thing for you. Throughout your career, you have almost never stopped working, which is not easy in the Hong Kong film environment. Can you talk about your cooperation and competition with different film companies at different times? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t need to talk about the previous difficulties in detail, and starting from &quot;The First Incense&quot;, what you just said The anxiety is gone because for me, the success of a movie is no longer entirely judged by the box office. In the 1970s and 1980s, Hong Kong (movies) could not do without selling money, so they would not be able to find the money for the next movie. I feel that as long as it can win an award, a small number of viewers will think it is particularly good, and if the director is well-known, he can still find investment. Of course, this does not mean that you will definitely be able to shoot the ideal thing, because investors still have to evaluate whether the film is profitable. But I realized that I don’t need to be anxious anymore. What I’m anxious about is that I won’t be able to film, not that others will scold me or that I won’t be successful, so this problem no longer exists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In retrospect, every drama has different difficulties. If I talk about it in detail, it seems to be a complaint, which is unnecessary. This is part of my job. If you don&#39;t accept it, don&#39;t do it. There is no benefit in complaining all the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Generally speaking of you, everyone will think of the artistic films you have made. , will say that you are very caring about society. In fact, you have also tried many types of movies, such as martial arts movies and horror movies. Are you influenced by the market when making these movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, &quot;ghost movies&quot; like &quot;Ghost World&quot; have never been popular, and few people have made them; martial arts movies are It was once popular, and I wanted to shoot it because I am a &quot;martial arts fan.&quot; I only made a few movies that were purely for work, such as &quot;Shanghai Vacation&quot;. It was because I was waiting for the next movie to start shooting. Someone told me that the director of &quot;Shanghai Vacation&quot; had quit and asked me if I wanted to film it. , I read the script and thought it was pretty good. I will only shoot a script if I agree with it, and I won’t shoot it if I don’t agree with it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everyone always has the feeling that Hong Kong movies as a whole are The environment is very commercial. Movies like &quot;Into the Wrath&quot; and &quot;A Thousand Words&quot; that you made are not mainstream enough and almost no one makes them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hui: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s not true. There are actually many directors in Hong Kong who make these films, but the output is not large. I think there are at least a dozen or so. , such as Guan Jinpeng, Zhang Wanting, Luo Qirui, and Tan Jiaming, who was at the same time as us... Actually, there were many people making this kind of movies in the 1970s and 1980s, and I was not the only one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Obviously there are some differences between you and them, such as 1982 You paid attention to the subject of Vietnamese refugees in 2008&#39;s &quot;The Wrath of the Sea&quot;. At that time, few Hong Kong directors filmed people and events outside Hong Kong. Does this have anything to do with your personal experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It has something to do with it. In 1978, I was working at TVB and wanted to make a realistic drama series &quot;Under the Lion Rock&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I chose to shoot this subject, so I did a lot of homework and even went to a refugee camp. I became interested in their previous lives in Vietnam and found that many of the refugees were actually Chinese. Their Chinatown was quite similar to the Macau where I lived when I was a child. I was particularly emotional about this kind of place and wanted to capture these scenes in the movie. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So you have always paid special attention to social reality? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I rarely put concepts first. I always see people and things first, think they are good, then think about them slowly, and finally Will work out a logic to answer various questions. For example, when telling the screenwriter why he chose such a story, many of them are considered after the fact. In the beginning, it is often based on impulse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I know the reason why you took over the filming of &quot;First &quot;Incense&quot; actually has some connection with &quot;Journey to the Angry Sea&quot;, because of the company Blue Bird. Why did Xia Meng invest in &quot;Journey to the Angry Sea&quot; given the general environment in Hong Kong at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It has always been difficult to find money for this kind of movies, but Xia Meng has her own ideals and her strong backing, they made this The film is not intended to make money at all, it is mainly to make a film with a sense of culture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You won the award for your film debut &quot;Crazy Heist&quot; You were successful and won the Golden Horse Award; &quot;Into the Furious Sea&quot; won the Academy Award. You were less than 35 years old at the time, but in the following ten years, several of your films were not very satisfactory, until &quot;Woman Forty&quot; Your career has taken off, how did you survive this period? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I want to know why this is happening. Is there something wrong with the movie I made, or is there something wrong with me? I don’t understand society and Is there an audience? I was actually quite curious and wanted to know why some films were not good, so I continued to shoot whenever I could. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back today, did you find this The reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, in fact, each film is different. Generally speaking, the period from 1985 to 1995 was the heyday of Hong Kong action movies. Workers in the entire industry are used to that way of working, and are completely uncooperative with our semi-industrial approach, which is similar to student homework. They all do several groups of things at the same time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was not in a good mood at the time. I felt that I was out of tune with them and that I had not done a good job. Because the staff is very tired when shooting commercial films and doing several sets at the same time. I also feel that the entire environment does not support the kind of films I make. After 1994, this wave of climax ended, and Hong Kong&#39;s film industry began to slow down, and everyone almost returned to the state of one film at a time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During this process, have you not thought about the issue of transformation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I filmed &quot;The Book of Swords and Enmities&quot; in 1986, but it was unsuccessful. Around 1991, I filmed &quot;Yakuza&quot;, a gangster film, but it was also unsuccessful. The main reason is that I really don’t like shooting action. I cooperate with the action director and leave it to him. When he comes to show me, I am not used to communicating repeatedly. In fact, the action director directs on the scene, and I should stay behind and constantly study with him how to shoot, but I don&#39;t like this form of cooperation very much. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So after &quot;Woman 40&quot;, you Only then do you find what kind of movie is more suitable for you - maybe a movie that doesn&#39;t have a particularly large investment but can maintain your own style? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, that’s true. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The film &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; (1984) adapted by Ann Hui based on Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel of the same name, with Chow Yun-fat (second from right) and Miao Qianren (first from right) playing the male and female protagonists. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;I am actually more like a mainland director&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are one of the first Hong Kong directors to come to the mainland to film. In 1985, when you were filming &quot;Book, Sword and Enmity&quot;, you were in I have lived in the Mainland for a whole year. Later, your &quot;Half Life&quot; was regarded as a model of co-production films at that time. When it comes to movies such as &quot;Jade Goddess of Mercy&quot; and &quot;The Golden Age&quot;, it can be said that mainland capital almost accounts for the main part. But you are not like directors such as Peter Chan who focus entirely on the mainland. Or like Tsui Hark, he can be regarded as a &quot;Hong Kong New Wave&quot; director like you, but he is also very comfortable shooting theme films like &quot;Changjin Lake&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. I think in the 1980s when I was filming &quot;The Wrath of the Sea&quot; and &quot;The Book of Swordsman&quot;, the mainland&#39;s film industry was very backward. Now compared to Hong Kong, the mainland&#39;s film industry has become very developed. For example, if you walk into a late-stage company, everything has been arranged and it is very mature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hong Kong commercial film directors have different ideas from mainland directors. They have their own creativity, but they focus entirely on the market and only pursue good-looking films. But in the Mainland, even directors of commercial films still have a set of ethics. If they want to express their stories, they must have a core theme before filming. I&#39;m actually more like a mainland director, I need to have a theme running through the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You majored in literature at the University of Hong Kong. I think you are You attach great importance to literature in movies, and you like to use some literary elements in movies, such as the poetry in &quot;Man 40&quot;. I think these elements are the origins of the characters in your movies. Your movies are different from directors such as Wong Kar-Wai. The characters always have an origin. It may be a physical origin, or it may be a spiritual origin. This origin Often Mainland China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, these may be related to my experience, but they are not intentional. Sometimes they are not added by me, such as &quot; The scenes of reciting ancient poems in &quot;Man 40&quot; were all original works by screenwriter An Xi. The things in &quot;Autumn Regret on a Passenger&#39;s Journey&quot; are real things. My grandfather taught me to recite poems, and I didn&#39;t add them deliberately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You worked hard on the few movies you shot in the mainland With various explorations and attempts, &quot;Aunt&#39;s Postmodern Life&quot;, &quot;Jade Guanyin&quot;, &quot;Golden Age&quot;, etc., almost every one of them is controversial. Especially the first two films, because they are modern dramas, people will think that you don’t understand life in the Mainland very well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Controversy is good, but there are indeed some gaps. For example, the audience sometimes doesn’t like the dubbing, and sometimes they don’t like the language. With accents, they are all different. They care a lot about whether the lines are spoken well, but we Cantonese don&#39;t really care about this. We just speak naturally and casually. There is no so-called training in the cadence of the lines. This is a big difference. I think that in the future I may still take photos of life in the Mainland, but it depends on the subject matter. Of course I can take photos if I can, but I’m afraid it will be more difficult because I don’t know a lot of the details of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have been here since &quot;The Golden Age&quot; Is it easier to circumvent these cultural barriers when filming period dramas? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, because sometimes I don’t understand the Internet. Especially in this Internet age, I don’t even know the basics of food, clothing, housing, and transportation. It’s completely different. For example, I don’t know how to interact with others or how to talk on the phone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;Directing is a profession for young people&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2020, you won the Lifetime Achievement Award at the Venice Film Festival. At that time, you said that you wanted to focus on cultivating the younger generation of filmmakers in the future. What kind of work might you do in this regard in the future? Your generation of directors is called the &quot;Hong Kong New Wave.&quot; Do you think there will be a new wave of young directors from the Chinese-speaking region in the future? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just do it if you have the chance. I will not deliberately open a company. I am not good at doing these things. If there are any problems, it would be great if we all discuss them together, but it is not really a big deal. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I talked about the &quot;New Wave&quot; so much that I couldn&#39;t stand it at first. In fact, at that time, some people who studied film from abroad returned to Hong Kong and started working in television stations. I happened to shoot a movie around the same time. At that time, the traditional film studio system was a little confused about where to go. A group of us made some realistic things for TV, and then we continued to film them. In fact, it was not the idea of ​​the French New Wave that revolutionized film history and language. It was quite prosperous at that time, and everyone had movies to shoot, and they were very happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there have been good young people coming out in recent years, but they may not be called &quot;new wave&quot; because they are not so concentrated. Hong Kong is still very small. Looking at mainland directors from various film festivals, some young people make very good films. If they insist on making a few more films for a few years, they will become hardcore elements. This is the same as the &quot;Hong Kong New Wave&quot;, except that It’s just named like this without much fanfare. In fact, your media can really give them more exposure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is good to give young people opportunities, but there is no need to talk about helping young people and turn it into an unpreset slogan. I feel that what young people need is spiritual support, not running away. When you become a producer, if something goes wrong, do you replace the other person, or do you support him in doing something you don&#39;t agree with? I don&#39;t want to make this a full-time thing because I don&#39;t like managing people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can it be understood that you don’t want to care about others at work? , and don’t want to be controlled? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, making a movie is a highly collaborative job. How can you not cooperate with others? But I have some standards of my own. There are things that others can’t control, otherwise you’ll be wasting your money. There are some things that others can control, so you just need to know them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it also depends on the specific situation. For example, if you really want to make a certain movie, the bottom line may be lower, or the requirements may be higher. I maintain this flexibility. I can&#39;t tell myself how I will do it early on, because I might slap myself in the face later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are 74 years old. I am really curious about how you are doing. Keep making movies. Many of your contemporaries and even some juniors have retired. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have been asking this question myself. I never thought about overcoming any difficulties when I was working, because difficulties are certain, director This industry has something to do with your own inspiration and how much you want to take pictures. Some people feel that they want to make money or change careers when they are done shooting. I am afraid this is not because of any setbacks. It is actually difficult for a person to make movies all his life. Directing is a profession for young people. When you are over fifty, your physical strength cannot keep up, nor can you keep up with the times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before filming &quot;Women at Forty&quot;, when I was only in my forties, some friends told me to retire, but I just wasn&#39;t convinced and there was nothing I could do beyond making movies. of this matter. Of course, my example is just an isolated case, and it can be used as an encouragement to others, but it may not be of much use. You can’t make a fortune as a director, so you can keep filming as long as you like it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The mainland film market has been particularly prosperous in the past few years, and some people will have the idea to The illusion that you can gain some fame and fortune by becoming a director. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It doesn’t matter, as long as you figure out when to stop and why you are shooting. I think that when you do everything, you need to think clearly about why you do it, not just follow what others do. The best thing to do as a director is to constantly challenge yourself. If it was the same every time, the same thing coming and going, I probably wouldn&#39;t continue filming. In addition, in this rapidly changing world and society, the director&#39;s position is changing rapidly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been thinking about filming something that people will want to watch, and maybe filming a TV series. To be honest, the most important thing is to keep healthy. Without this, you can&#39;t do anything. As for what you want to shoot and whether you will achieve success, these are not guaranteed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Speaking of age restrictions, even older people in Europe and the United States are still filming There are quite a few directors, such as Clint Eastwood, who is still making movies in his nineties, but there are almost no such directors in Asia. Do you think it has something to do with culture? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course. Their team is more suitable for older directors, because the division of labor is relatively detailed and the shooting system is relatively complete. They may only shoot for 6 hours a day. They are all moderate and it is easier. They are not as hard-working as ours, but The phenomena you mentioned are actually very rare. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[代长胖、代健身、代赶高铁……这些赚钱的路子你能看懂吗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>