<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[澳大利亚籍人员成蕾被国家安全机关依法执行驱逐出境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258395]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 11, 2023, Australian citizen Cheng Lei was detained by Beijing after serving her sentence. The Municipal State Security Bureau carries out deportations in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Cheng Lei, female, born in June 1975, Australian national, formerly employed by domestic media. In May 2020, Cheng Lei was coaxed by personnel from an overseas agency, violated the confidentiality clause signed with the employing unit, and illegally provided the state secrets she mastered at work to the overseas agency through her mobile phone. After filing an investigation, the Beijing National Security Bureau took criminal coercive measures against Cheng Lei in August 2020. After Cheng Lei arrived at the case, she truthfully confessed the facts of the crime and voluntarily pleaded guilty and accepted punishment. After a trial, the Beijing No. 2 Intermediate People&#39;s Court sentenced Cheng Lei to two years and eleven months in prison, plus deportation, for the crime of illegally providing state secrets abroad. Cheng Lei did not appeal. China&#39;s judicial organs handle cases strictly in accordance with the law and fully protect Cheng Lei&#39;s rights in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又疑似吃出鼠头？高校食堂为何难让学生满意？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258385]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 10, the topic #North China University of Technology Canteen Was Exposed to Eat Rat Heads# was on the Weibo hot search list . On that day, students from North China University of Technology reported that they ate an unknown object that looked like a mouse head in the food in the cafeteria. In the picture that broke the news, there were a few hairs on the dark meat held between the chopsticks. The student in question said that his roommate bought the food in the school cafeteria. It looked like a mouse head, but the store owner in the cafeteria said it was beef. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/bHGuwl0bM6nfGSKilvSIK06xyBtSAutZYsTt8k4X.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/bHGuwl0bM6nfGSKilvSIK06xyBtSAutZYsTt8k4X.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253726&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Screenshots of student revelations&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 10, the official website of North China University of Science and Technology released an announcement It is said that Ningbo Jianghui Food Catering Co., Ltd., which contracted the canteen involved, violated relevant food hygiene regulations on October 10, 2023, and food hygiene problems occurred during the operation process. The school has terminated the entrusted operation contract with it and will pursue its relevant responsibilities in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/HxIHBEWmuQhfQFhcFvXgEEl0MS7kXKFBJfGHvTWh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height= &quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/HxIHBEWmuQhfQFhcFvXgEEl0MS7kXKFBJfGHvTWh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253727&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;School announcement screenshot&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(North China University of Science and Technology official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is no longer a university For the first time, the canteen was on the hot search list because of its rat head. Just in June this year, Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College caused a storm of public opinion due to the &quot;rat head and duck neck&quot; incident. In addition to food hygiene issues, students often complain about the unpalatable food in university cafeterias. In March 2019, Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications was on the hot search list because #南PTcanteen is unpalatable. In September 2020, the Ministry of Education also issued a document requiring school canteens to improve the taste of dishes and cooking techniques. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 11, 2023, the Shandong Provincial Department of Education issued a document requiring that by the end of August 2026, all student cafeterias in colleges and universities in the province should be able to operate independently in principle. This is also considered to be a pilot project to solve the problem of college cafeterias, and may be promoted nationwide in the near future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should the school cafeteria be managed so that students and parents can feel at ease and satisfied? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[哈马斯“瞒天过海”，破灭以色列“情报神话”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258388]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 14:57:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/2rusj5FGboq151HgW6R36rtGXJtzmHphrKAmlB5m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2rusj5FGboq151HgW6R36rtGXJtzmHphrKAmlB 5m. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is a rocket fired towards Israel taken in the Gaza Strip on October 7. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 7, 2023, at an international music festival, a shrill air raid siren sounded The sound suddenly sounded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this moment on, the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement (Hamas) continued to fire thousands of rockets into Israel. Since the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot; in 1973, the most serious conflict in 50 years has broken out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of October 10, according to the latest news released by Israeli media and Palestinian medical institutions, the conflict has caused more than 1,900 deaths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with such a large-scale attack, why did Israel, which has always claimed to be the number one military power in the Middle East, not aware of it in advance? As the conflict continues to escalate, this question has also become the focus of international public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, both Israel and the Western media believe that there is a &quot;big problem&quot; in Israel&#39;s proud intelligence system. Hamas said it had been secretly preparing for the attack for more than a year, but that Israeli security and intelligence agencies did not issue any advance warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Is the “intelligence myth” shattered? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The highly security border barrier is covered with Israeli surveillance cameras and guard soldiers. Surveillance drones also appear in the sky from time to time, constantly &quot;buzzing&quot;. This scene has been going on for Palestinians in Gaza for nearly 30 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But before Hamas launched a new round of attacks, Israel&#39;s intelligence system seemed to &quot;close its eyes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hamas broke through the Palestinian-Israeli border barrier and sent hundreds of armed personnel to infiltrate into Israeli-controlled areas. Efraim Halevi, the former head of the Israeli intelligence service Mossad, publicly stated that they had not received any form of warning and that &quot;the outbreak of the war was a complete surprise.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CNN reported that the Gaza Strip is blockaded and closely monitored by the Israeli army, and Palestinian armed personnel are rarely able to enter Israel. But Halevi said the number of rockets fired by Palestinian militants was &quot;unprecedented&quot; and that it was &quot;the first time&quot; they were able to &quot;penetrate deep into Israel and take control of villages.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Israel is no stranger to Palestinian attacks, this time the Israeli military found itself &quot;unprepared.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The entire intelligence system failed, it was just one component and failed to provide the necessary defense for Israeli civilians.” said Jonathan Conricks, former international spokesman for the Israel Defense Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Israel withdrew from Gaza in 2005, it has spent hundreds of millions of dollars building a smart border with sensors and underground walls to protect the border from attacks, Reuters said. The Israeli military also &lt;span>;with the help of the United States developed an &quot;Iron Dome&quot; defense system&lt;/span>; specifically designed to intercept rockets and mortars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli intelligence agency has been written into a &quot;myth&quot; by domestic and Western media because of a series of &quot;achievements&quot; over the past few decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this time, the &quot;myth&quot; seems to have been shattered by Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Israeli general Amir Avivi said that militants in Gaza have found ways to evade technical intelligence collection, preventing Israel from fully understanding their intentions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They have returned to the Stone Age.&quot; Avivi explained that armed personnel do not use phones or computers, but handovers in specialized technical rooms or underground rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian, a researcher at the Foreign Policy Institute of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that although Israel has a complete intelligence system, looking at it conversely, for every set of Israeli practices, the Palestinians in the Gaza Strip The armed forces are also constantly summarizing and taking precautions, and they even have spies in Israel. &quot;It&#39;s entirely possible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel&#39;s &quot;Haaretz&quot; revealed that hundreds of Hamas personnel had been preparing for the raid for months, even more than a year, &quot;but did not leak it&quot;, and the results were obviously disastrous. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian said that by summarizing long-term struggle experience, the Palestinian armed forces may also have grasped some of Israel’s “preventive weaknesses” and found some “preventive rules.” Israel’s military intelligence team cannot be unilaterally assumed So powerful that it is invulnerable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another point worthy of attention is that Israel’s judicial reforms and political disputes since the beginning of the year have brought about domestic divisions and confrontations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zou Zhiqiang, a researcher at the Middle East Studies Center of Fudan University, told Southern Weekend reporters that the current political instability and internal strife in Israel are higher than in the past, which has distracted Israel&#39;s own attention and energy and weakened morale. Therefore, Israel was unprepared for Hamas&#39;s &quot;innovative, multi-channel&quot; blitz attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;All-round attack by land, sea and air&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hamas members penetrate from three routes: land, sea and air.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Israel Defense Forces spokesman Daniel Hagari said that since 6:30 a.m. local time on October 7, more than 2,200 rockets have been fired from the Gaza Strip towards Israel. At the same time, dozens of armed men stormed the wall, blasting away barricades with explosives and attacking in multiple locations with bulldozers, hang gliders and motorcycles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zou Zhiqiang believes that from the perspective of an irregular armed organization, Hamas’s operation has an overwhelming advantage. It has caused such a large amount of damage and blow to the tightly defended Israel, which is quite serious from a military perspective. Noteworthy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the attack method, Hamas armed personnel infiltrated into Israel through multiple channels of sea, land and air. Israeli police stations, settlements and multiple military bases were attacked, and Israeli heavy weapons including main battle tanks and armored vehicles were seized. A large number of Israeli soldiers and ordinary Jewish settlers were captured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of military expert Zhang Xuefeng, the key to Hamas&#39; rapid &quot;results&quot; lies first in the &quot;battle surprise&quot; achieved by Hamas&#39; armed forces. According to Western accounts, Hamas has developed a coordination and communication system that does not rely on electronic systems such as mobile phones, making it impossible for Israeli intelligence agencies to spy on it, while hiding its offensive intentions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Hamas used drones and missiles to attack Israeli air defense systems and military bases. It also sent submarines and speedboats to penetrate and land on the Israeli coastline, breaking through Israel&#39;s coastal defenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Before the raid, Hamas was ready to pay the price.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang said that the armed men who rushed into Israel never thought about going back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As more details emerge, the outside world increasingly believes that this operation was &quot;well prepared.&quot; A training video released by the &quot;Qassam Brigades&quot;, an armed wing of Hamas, shows that Hamas has long built a simulated Israeli stronghold in Gaza, where its members practice landings and raids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Reuters reported that since 2021, Israel has sought to maintain basic stability in the Gaza economy by providing incentives including thousands of licenses. Also in the past two years, Hamas has not taken military action against Israel, which has caused Israel to relax its vigilance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zou Zhiqiang believes that from the perspective of Israel’s long-term strength advantage and reliance on technical means, they may have become lax and have a tired mentality due to their past experience in responding to the Gaza conflict many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the long run, Zou Zhiqiang said that Hamas may not be able to get Israel to make concessions this time. On the contrary, Israel may intensify its &quot;retaliation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Copy&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Yom Kippur War&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This time Hamas launched a blitzkrieg against Israel on the occasion of the 50th anniversary of the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot; (the Fourth Middle East War). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 6 every year happens to be the Jewish &quot;Yom Kippur&quot;. Israel will have a national holiday on that day, suspending all normal activities. On the afternoon of October 6, 1973, Egypt launched an attack on Israel. The Egyptian army forced across the Suez Canal and broke through the Bar-Lev defense line. Israel was caught off guard and faced the danger of national subjugation. Of course, Israel eventually reversed the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many Western media have commented that the major mistakes made by Israel and the United States on the intelligence front are comparable to Israel&#39;s performance before the outbreak of the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the war, the Egyptian army repeatedly recruited and demobilized reservists, causing Israel to lose its alertness. Active-duty troops frequently moved forward and retreated to cover up military deployments. The war started on the &quot;Yom Kippur&quot; day, which coincided with the Jewish fast, which was not conducive to rapid mobilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There is a certain comparability and a certain correlation between the two.” Zou Zhiqiang believes that Hamas chose the second day of Yom Kippur to carry out a surprise attack. The method of the raid was similar, and Israel was caught off guard. The reaction is quite similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many experts and scholars interviewed told Southern Weekend reporters that Hamas&#39;s attack was not only to commemorate the same &quot;secret&quot; operation 50 years ago, but also to take advantage of the fact that that day was Israel&#39;s &quot;Sabbath&quot; , attack him unprepared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The New York Times believes that although more than half a century has passed since the large-scale war, villages have been occupied again and civilians have been killed or taken hostage, awakening people&#39;s &quot;primitive fears.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zou Zhiqiang said that because the Fourth Middle East War involved Egypt and Syria uniting to attack Israel, it was a large-scale frontal battle between countries. Now Hamas is implementing an asymmetric guerrilla war. The intensity of the battlefield and the confrontation between the two sides cannot be compared with the former. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What is different from 50 years ago is that the Palestinian-Israeli issue has been marginalized now. This has caused a very disappointing and even desperate mood in Palestine.&quot; Li Weijian believes that under the mixture of various emotions, the Palestinians People hope to make an impactful action by themselves in an attempt to draw the international community&#39;s attention to the Palestinian-Israeli issue again. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The multi-party game behind the conflict&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The conflict between Palestine and Israel has been going on for a long time. In 2020, the leaders of Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and Bahrain signed the Abraham Accords at the White House, agreeing to normalize bilateral relations and cooperate in economic, technology, security and other fields. The agreement is considered a historic breakthrough in the Middle East. However, countries such as Palestine, Iran, and Turkey oppose and criticize this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hamas has always opposed Arab countries to go beyond the Palestinian-Israeli issue and improve relations or establish diplomatic relations with Israel.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang analyzed that the traditional consensus among Arab countries is to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli issue first and then resolve the issue. Arab-Israeli question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is widespread speculation that Hamas is only a local armed force in the Palestinian Gaza area, and its military strength is very different from that of Israel. Will this &quot;go all out&quot; raid be supported by other countries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to now, countries and organizations such as Iran, Lebanese Hezbollah, Qatar, Kuwait, Iraq, and Syria have publicly spoken out in support of Hamas. Most of these countries have considerable conflicts with Israel and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The American &quot;Time&quot; magazine believes that Iran has always been the largest single &quot;sponsor&quot; of Hamas. In addition to military training and humanitarian assistance, more than $100 million in military assistance is provided annually. After Hamas launched a raid on Israel, Iran set off fireworks in &quot;public celebration&quot; on the evening of October 7. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hamas spokesman Ghazi Hamad also said in an interview with the British Broadcasting Corporation on October 8 that the organization has received support from its ally Iran and help from &quot;other countries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, on October 8, the Iranian mission to the United Nations stated in a statement, &quot;We firmly support Palestine. However, we will not participate in Palestine&#39;s actions because this is entirely Palestine&#39;s own decision.&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also many people who side with Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the conflict broke out, the United States stated that it &quot;will stand with the Israeli people and government.&quot; The White House also specifically stated that the United States will &quot;continue to provide support to Israel, including in-depth intelligence exchanges.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the US &quot;Time&quot; magazine, the United States provides more than $3 billion in defense assistance to Israel every year, making it the largest recipient of aid, and &quot;it is conceivable that this number may increase.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, the Middle East has been one of the &quot;core areas&quot; for great power competition. Now that the situation between Palestine and Israel has escalated again, secret games between all parties are indispensable behind the scenes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zou Zhiqiang believes that the conflict will still be limited to Palestine and Israel. In the short term, the Palestinian-Israeli issue may return to the center stage of Middle East diplomacy, but in the long run, it will still be difficult to change its marginalized status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian believes that if Israel goes on a killing spree and retaliates wildly, causing a large number of deaths, it may intensify internal conflicts in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, the spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs called for a ceasefire as soon as possible to protect civilians. At the same time, the international community should increase its sense of urgency, increase investment in the Palestinian issue, and make practical efforts to promote the &quot;two-state solution&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Lin Xi and Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[墙塌压坏菜园成最高法案例，民间调解呼唤“新乡贤”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258381]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Supreme People’s Court issued a number of typical cases for resolving post-disaster conflicts and disputes. In one of the cases, the courtyard wall of a family in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province collapsed during heavy rain, crushing the neighbor&#39;s vegetable garden. The two parties had a dispute and wanted to go to court. The judge conducted mediation before the lawsuit, and the conflict was finally resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wall of my yard collapsed and destroyed my neighbor’s vegetable garden. Apart from some vegetables, there was no other major loss. This is a small matter, and in many places, it is possible for the two families to resolve it privately, or to resolve the dispute under the auspices of the village mediator, without going to court. For example, in a village in southeastern Shandong Province, there is an old man in his sixties who is the most senior member of his clan. He is very prestigious because of his eloquence and impartiality. When conflicts and disputes arise between villagers, they are willing to come to him to administer justice. Many disputes were resolved through his mediation. As &quot;Southern Weekend&quot; reported some time ago, &quot;Mazu consultation rooms&quot; set up in many places in Putian, Fujian also played an important role in resolving civil disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of mediation mechanism, presided over by local &quot;mediators&quot; and based on the endogenous ethical norms of local society, is one of the important channels for resolving civil disputes. Not long ago, the &quot;Implementation Plan for the &quot;My Hometown, I Build&quot; Activity jointly issued by the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, etc. proposed that a group of prestigious and fair-minded returnees should be hired as mediators of neighborhood conflicts to actively Explore working methods such as &quot;package resolution&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Traditionally, Chinese society is a rural society. Most civil disputes in rural areas are resolved through local mediation. Because of the disputes between villagers, most of them were trivial matters such as the Zhang family&#39;s cow eating a few seedlings from the Li family, or the Wang family&#39;s chicken pecking a few vegetables from the Liu family, and the interests involved were not very large. The countryside is made up of acquaintances and even people of the same clan, who have close relationships with each other. In the long-term relationship, a common set of behavioral norms has been formed, which has become the customary law of the village. Those who preside over the mediation are mostly local respected people, either clan leaders, elders, or local sages who have retired and returned to their hometowns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of China&#39;s rural areas live together with ethnic groups. The villagers in many villages are descended from the same ancestors. Of course, there are also some villages where two or more surnames live together, or there are a few families with small surnames. But generally speaking, these villagers have lived together for generations and have developed a way of getting along with each other, and they also have people they believe in in common. Especially within a clan, the patriarch has high authority. When conflicts arise among villagers, most of them are willing to seek their help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of various contradictions and disputes within the village, this kind of mediation is not only a referee, but also a process of reasoning and education. Fei Xiaotong once said in &quot;Country China&quot;, &quot;Mediation is a new term, and the old term is judgment. The so-called mediation in the countryside is actually an educational process.&quot; Therefore, these mediations are often more likely to lead to conflicts than official referees. Most will be implemented voluntarily if all parties are convinced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the rapid social changes and increased population mobility in recent years, the original acquaintance society in rural areas has also begun to become unfamiliar and atomized. It has become difficult to find a &quot;mediator&quot; who is universally convinced by the residents. In some rural areas, especially those on the outskirts of cities, many outsiders come to rent houses. These tenants have no historical connection with the village and are “outsiders” to the village. They often do not fully identify with the original authority in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the number of villagers moving out has also increased significantly. Many villagers are away from home all year round and seldom return to the village. The contact with other villagers gradually decreases, and the relationship between clan members and neighbors becomes weaker and weaker. In addition, their long-term experience in stranger societies in other places also makes them more sympathetic to the legal rules of stranger societies, rather than the traditional rules of the countryside and the traditional authority under rural rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defamiliarization and atomization of these two aspects have reduced the prestige of the original authority in rural society, and the function of determining divisions and ending disputes has been continuously weakened. There is no traditional authority that both foreign tenants and local villagers believe in. Villagers who have been away from home for a long time are increasingly less convinced by the elders in the village. As a result, when conflicts arise between foreign tenants and indigenous people, or even disputes among villagers, they are less willing to apply the previous local rules, and are more willing to turn to institutional authorities such as the government and courts for solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To rebuild the traditional civil mediation mechanism, it is necessary to find a new &quot;mediator&quot; with sufficient prestige in the community. &quot;Xinxiangxian&quot; is a possible option. Letting these &quot;new rural sages&quot; come forward to uphold justice can often resolve disputes. Compared with the formal judicial process, the social cost is lower. Their mediation is also more likely to be recognized by all parties to the conflict, and the mediation plan is easy to implement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even trivial disputes in rural areas are turned to the courts. This can indeed be said to be a &quot;modernization&quot; of the rule of law, but at the same time it dissolves tradition and makes the judicial system unburdened. To give full play to the role of civil mediation in settling disputes and resolving minor conflicts on the spot, it is necessary to rebuild the cohesion of the community and find &quot;Xinxiang wise men&quot; who are familiar and convinced by residents and have considerable modern legal knowledge to act as &quot;mediators.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲击波里的人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258379]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 12:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/RNMXhTWmmzgEdNZZYxb1YtlDDqmJIaXkAcSUimk0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/RNMXhTWmmzgEdNZZYxb1YtlDDqmJIaXkAcSUimk0 . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253628&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is a rocket fired towards Israel taken in the Gaza Strip on October 7. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it were not for the sudden sound of gunfire, October 7, 2023 would have been a pleasant day Saturday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tel Aviv, Beijing tourist Liu Zihui will usher in the last day of her National Day trip. According to the plan, she was going to visit the Jewish Museum of Tel Aviv University and then go to the ancient city of Jaffa. In Rehovot, Chinese chef Zhang Feng is getting ready for work. This is the busiest time of the week for Chinese restaurant business. Many Israelis choose this day to go out to eat and relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an area near the Gaza Strip, 27-year-old female music fan Millet Ben Haim and her friends were partying all night at a music festival. At this moment, she and her friends were looking forward to for several months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the young Israeli scholar Haim Ketzman stayed at his home in Holit, which is only 1.5 kilometers away from the Gaza Strip, as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A sudden attack suddenly changed the course of their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of them witnessed the white tracks of rockets streaking across the sky, some heard gunshots from all directions in the wilderness, and some encountered Hamas armed forces head-on. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Crisis, from South to North&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, young music fans sang and danced at the &quot;Parallel Universe&quot; Music Festival In full swing. This music festival originated in Brazil and has a history of 23 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters saw from the timetable announced by the organizer that the music festival will start at 23:00 on October 6th and continue until the afternoon of the 7th. This means fans can head out for an &quot;all-night dance party.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Music fans are looking forward to this long-awaited music festival, and Milit is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The music festival is held near Rem Kibbutz, which is about 1.25 hours&#39; drive from Tel Aviv, Israel&#39;s largest city. Many music fans drive here. At the same time, it was only a few kilometers away from the Gaza Strip, which foreshadowed the subsequent tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, danger begins to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, Hamas fired thousands of rockets at Israel, and many armed personnel used homemade simple gliders to infiltrate into the disputed area from the Gaza Strip isolation area. Videos and pictures that appeared on social media showed that Hamas militants also entered Israeli-controlled areas in pickup trucks and motorcycles. Those along the Palestinian-Israeli separation zone bear the brunt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Around 6:31 in the morning, the music stopped and the siren sounded.&quot; Millit recorded the moment with a video on social media. &quot;More and more rockets were flying into the sky and we realized we had to leave immediately,&quot; she wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A video circulating on social media showed dozens of young people running in panic in an open field, surrounded by abandoned cars and followed by intensive gunfire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Along the flight route of the rockets, air defense sirens continued to sound in many places in Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the central city of Rehovot, Chinese chef Zhang Feng was also woken up by a &quot;sound&quot; at around 6 a.m. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is between the Gaza Strip and Tel Aviv. Zhang Feng saw &quot;wave after wave&quot; of rockets passing over the city and heading north, &quot;many of which were intercepted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack began, Zhang Feng and his colleagues squeezed into the small bomb shelter again and again, listening to the sound of air defense sirens, flying artillery shells, and explosions after being intercepted. The first wave of attacks lasted for two or three hours. After more than two years in Israel, Zhang Feng felt that &quot;this was the most powerful one.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Feng works in a restaurant in Rehovot. On the morning of the 7th, he and his colleagues received a holiday notice, which surprised them. According to him, every Saturday, many Israelis take their families out to eat, which is often the busiest time for restaurant business. Although they have experienced air raid warnings many times before, they will still go to work normally after the danger is lifted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We rarely had holidays in the past. The fact that we can have a holiday this time shows that the situation is very serious.” Zhang Feng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the northern city of Jerusalem, Liu Zihui and her companions set off from the hotel by car at around 9 o&#39;clock. Taking advantage of the National Day holiday, she embarked on an &quot;in-depth cultural tour&quot;. According to the original plan, they would arrive in Tel Aviv on the morning of the 7th, stay one night and then return home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, not long after setting off from Jerusalem, Liu Zihui and his party heard an air raid siren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The driver stopped immediately and the tour guide took us to hide in the concert hall on the roadside.&quot; Liu Zihui heard from the staff of the concert hall that they also received a short notice to cancel the performance. After the alarm was lifted, the staff also made a special trip to apologize, saying &quot;I&#39;m sorry for causing you such a bad experience during your trip.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For safety reasons, the originally planned trip was canceled and the tour guide took everyone directly to the hotel. Because the reserved room was not ready yet, the group of people waited in the hotel lobby, and lunch was ordered and delivered from a nearby Chinese restaurant. Liu Zihui&#39;s room is on the 10th floor, and &quot;helicopters flying over&quot; can be seen directly outside the window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 7 p.m., air raid sirens sounded several more times in Tel Aviv. Liu Zihui said that everyone had to eat dinner in the hotel&#39;s safe room. It didn&#39;t become calm until after 9 p.m. &quot;My companions and I slept in the same clothes, and we didn&#39;t dare to take a shower or pack our things until three o&#39;clock in the morning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Evacuation, crowds flocked to the airport&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the crisis occurred, Chinese tourist Amy was taking a bus to the center of the Israeli vortex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amy loves traveling and has always been curious about the religious Middle Eastern countries. In previous years, she has been to Egypt and Turkey, and the destinations of this trip are Jordan and Israel. Amy and her husband plan to enter Israel from Jordan so that the two countries can play together and &quot;it is also very convenient to apply for a visa on arrival.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Amy and her husband, there was also a young Arab-American carpooling together. According to the plan, the group was going to take the border crossing in central Jordan, but after the raid, the crossing was temporarily closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When the driver said he couldn’t go, we couldn’t believe it and insisted on going over to find out, but there were also police stopping us on the road. When we saw the bloody scene displayed by the driver, the three of us were shocked. &quot;Amy said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli-Palestinian conflict has been going on for a long time, and Amy and her group didn’t take it seriously at first. As more and more news of the conflict came in, they decided to abandon their original plan and proceed via the northern border crossing instead. &quot;Time was very tight, and we couldn&#39;t think too much. Coupled with the language barrier, the driver said no matter what, so we went along,&quot; Amy said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The northern Jordanian border crossing is relatively remote and sparsely populated. Amy and her husband wanted to find someone to carpool with and asked multiple transit passengers, but they were all rejected. When Amy was about to call the insurance company for help, they &quot;miraculously&quot; hailed a taxi on a street farther away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, people at the border crossing were saying that it was impossible to fly today, and we were worried that the flight would be cancelled. In addition, it was the Sabbath and there were few people going to work, so we were also worried that we would not be able to get to the airport on time.&quot; Go to On the way to the airport, Amy and her husband repeatedly called the airline to confirm whether the plane was taking off normally. At the same time, they had to call the insurance company to inquire about the claim settlement. &quot;They were on tenterhooks all the way.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They arrived at the airport at 3:30 pm and saw many passengers waiting in line. &quot;Thankfully, I checked in early. If I missed my flight, it would be more difficult to return home in the future,&quot; Amy said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amy’s worries are not unfounded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the raid, Delta Air Lines and American Airlines canceled flights from New York to Israel scheduled for the 7th and 8th. Lufthansa also announced on the 7th that it would significantly cancel flights to Tel Aviv. In addition, the Feichangzhun App shows that the recent round-trip flights from Shanghai and Shenzhen in China to Tel Aviv in Israel have also been cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Amy&#39;s &quot;multiple countries in one day&quot;, Liu Zihui took a flight home the day after the attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early in the morning on the 8th, Liu Zihui packed her luggage. According to the plan, they will fly from Ben Gurion International Airport to the capital Beijing. After arriving at the airport, Liu Zihui found that although there were many people, they were in good order. During the exchange, Liu Zihui discovered that some people arrived on the first day because they were afraid that the airport would be closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The big flight screen was all red, leaving only sporadic green. &quot;A large number of flights have been cancelled, and only a few are flying normally.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t until the plane took off that Liu Zihui&#39;s hanging heart fell to the ground, and she fell into a deep sleep for the rest of the journey. At 5:28 a.m. on October 9, the plane landed at Beijing Capital International Airport, and warm applause erupted in the cabin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I saw the bright lights on the ground in Beijing through the porthole, and I felt a little excited. I have landed countless times, and I have never been as excited as today.&quot; Liu Zihui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Unfortunate news&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not everyone can evacuate as smoothly as Amy and Liu Zihui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 9, staff of Jiangsu Zhonglan Overseas Employment Company, which engages in overseas labor dispatch business, told Southern Weekend reporters that as of 11 a.m. that day, the company knew that three people were missing in Israel, and the others were missing. The situation is still being updated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, a spokesperson for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated that the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and relevant embassies and consulates abroad have issued safety reminders in response to the current situation in Israel and Palestine, advising Chinese citizens not to travel to Israel and Palestine for the time being. Local Chinese citizens and institutions remain highly vigilant, strengthen safety precautions, prepare for emergencies and take shelter on site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millit experienced a &quot;near escape&quot; while attending the music festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Milliet’s account on social platforms, she and her friends initially fled in a car. When they crossed a main road, they encountered a double attack from the attackers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Someone was screaming and attackers were shooting at people who were going there, so I turned around as fast as I could. Two minutes later, I saw there were more attackers going in the other direction,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Millet and her friends escaped in the wilderness. After about three hours, weak and frightened, they hid in the bushes and covered themselves with leaves. During this period, they tried to call the police, but the police did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millet&#39;s experience has attracted the attention of many media, and the &quot;Washington Post&quot; quoted her experience in a report on October 8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack, the organizers of the &quot;Parallel Universe&quot; music festival issued a bilingual announcement in Hebrew and English to search for missing persons. Comment sections on social platforms are crowded with anxious people. They kept leaving messages asking about their missing relatives and friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are shocked and pained.&quot; The organizer &quot;New Star Tribe&quot; said in the announcement that it is making every effort to assist the security forces in searching for missing persons in the area. The organization also provides an online missing person statistics form, where family members can upload their details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We pray that good news will come to you and me soon,&quot; the announcement said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also close to the border with the Gaza Strip, the young Israeli scholar Haim Ketzman died in his home in Holit. On October 8, Katzman’s mother announced the news on social platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kettsman is a young scholar engaged in Israel studies. His resume is still hanging on the official website of the University of Washington. It can be seen from this that he studied for bachelor&#39;s, master&#39;s and doctoral degrees at the Open University of Israel, Ben-Gurion University, and the University of Washington. His research interests include Israeli religion and politics. Katzman’s mother, Hannah, works for an Israeli NGO. After Katzman was killed, the organization also publicly mourned on social platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the information released by Ketzman’s mother, it can be seen that at first she mistakenly believed that Ketzman had been “kidnapped”. For this reason, she also posted missing person information on social platforms. When the bad news came, the missing person information was corrected, &quot;He died at home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Avital Alajem, Katzman’s neighbor and friend, was interviewed by CNN on October 9. She said Ketzman hid in the closet with her when Hamas militants broke in and shot her. She herself was not injured in the attack and &quot;Katzman saved my life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kettsman received the 2019 &quot;Kimmerlin Best Graduate Thesis Award&quot; from the Israel Studies Association. The award honors the memory of Baruch Kimmerling, an Israeli public intellectual and sociologist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winning essay, Ketzman had this speech: Dedicated to all forms of life between the Jordan River and the Mediterranean Sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ketzmann’s friend Marwa Maziad wrote in her eulogy, “He truly believed that all life forms were equal and beautiful, including the plants in his care. Israel /Palestine, Arab-Muslim/Jewish, may his soul rest in peace.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Liu Zihui, Zhang Feng, and Amy are pseudonyms, Southern Weekend interns Xu Ziyi, Bao Jingyue, and Zhai Huan also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用利息生活小组火了，但攒钱，能不能攒到]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/60fb01dc9ced91e2ce8a37e4e3964ea2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/10/60fb01dc9ced91e2ce8a37e4e3964ea2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Young people who were once considered the most individualistic, advocating instant gratification, and embracing &quot;consumerism&quot; have begun to quietly save money and clock in. I don&#39;t know when. A saving trend is taking over social media. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;How hard can young people of this generation work to save money? It can be said that only you can’t think of it, but there is nothing young people can’t do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Contemporary people’s new hobby: don’t consume, save money like crazy&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;In Between going to work and making progress, this generation of young people choose incense; between buying bags and getting drunk, they are more likely to choose to buy lottery tickets; between ideals and reasons, financial management is the favorite of young people - the main thing is One saves money and makes money! &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Douban&#39;s &quot;Living with Interest: Savings Group&quot; now has more than 100,000 members in the group, &quot;Living with Interest: Investment and Financial Management&quot; group , the number of team members exceeds 600,000. Not to mention the &quot;Stingy Women&#39;s Association&quot; and the &quot;Stingy Men&#39;s Association&quot;, with a total of millions of people joining the groups. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to save money, some people choose to keep accounts and plan carefully, some choose to live with interest, manage finances and buy funds, and some choose to do both their main business and side business, and become a slash youth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When using the accounting APP, sorting out personal bills regularly is just an entry-level step. Learn from the collective wisdom of various money-saving groups and discover various wool-gathering artifacts, shopping red envelopes, Membership discounts, point deductions, live group buying, multi-platform price comparisons, and resolutely not letting go of any hidden benefits are the new life wisdom that young people get. For example, there are young people who squat after midnight every day to grab expired food and leftovers. boxes to reduce the cost of food expenses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These can be regarded as an evolved version of actions for young people, and students at higher levels have already started playing special forces to save money. Compare banks across the country to see whose interest rate is better. Higher, choose to travel thousands of miles to go. Some media reported that after bank interest rates were lowered this year, some young people traveled 2,000 kilometers a day and spent 330 yuan on fares just to earn an extra 1,800 yuan in interest. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some people feel that this is too unfair to themselves. The reason why young people are happy to live in peace with the &quot;hard life&quot; is that there is a high probability that saving money is like a snowball, and seeing themselves The small treasury is getting fuller day by day, and the sense of accomplishment can, to a certain extent, make people forget the hardships in the early days. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As the Japanese writer Yataro Matsuura once wrote in &quot;Getting Rich Slowly: Money and Work Rules to Make Your Life Richer&quot;: &quot;It is easier to save money than to spend it. After all, there are many ways to spend money, but there is only one way to save money, and that is to &#39;spend less&#39;.&quot; Because the path is single and clear, as long as the goal is firm enough and you continue in the established direction, you will always succeed. Realization, and therefore, attracts more and more young people to join the game. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Rejecting the trap of consumerism, young people have truly become sober in the world. I am no longer obsessed with following trends and buying the latest electronic products; I no longer order takeout frequently, but choose to go to the market with the aunts to buy food and bring my own meals; I no longer have to take a taxi every time I walk, but can walk. Walk, take the subway and never take a taxi. The money saved at every step is like a trickle, which eventually converges into a stream or a river. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/db7bc1d8642781493c9860d7666c2e84.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/db7bc1d8642781493c9860d7666c2e84.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253558 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Saving money, can you save money&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So when it comes to saving money, to what extent do young people hope to save money? A report shows that more than 53.7% of 30-year-olds believe that saving 100,000 yuan can be regarded as having a certain basis for savings. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, the cold reality is that a survey by China Business News shows: with a deposit of more than 100,000 yuan, you have already surpassed 53.7% of your peers. More than half of young people have less than 100,000 in savings, and it is a reality that they are &quot;powerless&quot;. Young people who are trying their best to save money find that money is like fine sand. The tighter you hold it, the more it will be lost. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The road to financial freedom is full of thorns. However, the will of young people is gradually firming up, and they are no longer attracted by the lavish spending of consumerism. Instead, they do not want to buy and save everything, and everything is compromised for the enrichment of their small coffers. What social trends does it reflect that young people are working hard to save money? Some people&#39;s ambition to save money is to retire early and implement a FIRE plan (Financial Independence, Retire Early); others are saving money for more security and more confidence to cope with the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After all, the greater the balance, the greater the sense of security. Money means having enough protection against unknown risks. It can help young people live without panic and ask for help less when encountering problems. In the final analysis, it is essentially due to the inherent risk aversion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As Ulrich Beck said in &quot;Risk Society&quot;, life risks are always present, and individuals are forced to face the individualization process, which is constructed in the early modernization stage. The security system can no longer provide protection for individuals, and individualization has therefore entered a new stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Increased social mobility, the increasingly blurred boundaries between unemployment and employment, the disintegration of clan-based family relationships, work and intimate relationships, all of which are unavoidable issues for this generation of young people. Making young people aware of risks also inspires their desire to cling to something stable when the wave of risks strikes, so as to seek peace and tranquility in their own years. But before the dawn of dawn, money becomes the coordinate axis of reality, and saving money is the magic weapon for young people to resist risks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If you think that young people save money without spending it, you are totally wrong. Different from the older generation who simply save money, young people focus on saving money and spending money when they should. In this Houlang’s value perception, saving money is to spend money better, to spend money wisely, and to pursue a higher sense of value and cost-effectiveness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Bill Gates once said: &quot;It is as difficult to spend a sum of money wisely as to earn it.&quot; Therefore, if you feel it is worthwhile, travel to see the world and learn New skills and new experiences are worth saving money to achieve. However, if you feel that it is not worth it, such as a takeaway meal that has increased in price, or expensive ugly clothes in the mall, then you are not willing to pay extra for it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Young people who often surf the Internet have given various &quot;painless money saving&quot; methods a new title, naming them &quot;Princess Money Saving Method&quot; &quot;365-day money saving method&quot; &quot;Muyu money saving method&quot;...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Even in order to increase the sense of ritual of saving money, when achieving the goal, you will appropriately increase yourself Rewards, such as saving 50 yuan a day and saving up money for a concert ticket in three months, will not affect your normal living standards, but at the same time, you can satisfy your hobbies and interests, just like making a coin-operated wish, in the wilderness of life Here, brave people are at the forefront, enjoying the world first and creating their own unique style and lifestyle. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Bulk up your wallet and enrich your life. Are you in love with this young generation’s view on saving money? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[主持人实名举报，法院12368热线能不能外包？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258377]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 11:13:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Host Zhang Zequn. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/851df93244.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/11/851df93244.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253625&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moderator Zhang Zequn. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, CCTV host Zhang Zequn reported to the Chaoyang District Court in Beijing with his real name on social media. He said in multiple updates that the court&#39;s 12368 litigation service hotline was outsourced, and &quot;the staff did not know what a collegiate bench was, and there was dereliction of duty.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Immediately, Zhang Zequn’s report became a hot search topic, attracting the attention of netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that outsourcing of the court’s 12368 hotline is relatively common. According to a cursory search, dozens of courts at the provincial, municipal, and county levels across the country , there is a phenomenon of public bidding for hotline outsourcing services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some netizens raised questions about the functions, responsibilities and positioning of the 12368 hotline. What is &quot;12368&quot;? Can it be outsourced? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In order to meet the multi-level and diverse judicial needs of the people, the People&#39;s Court has established a 12368 litigation service hotline and vigorously promoted the &#39;one-stop service&#39; work.&quot; Supreme Court Liu Xuemei, deputy director of the filing division of the People&#39;s Court, once told the media that as of the end of 2022, all four levels of courts across the country had opened a 12368 litigation service hotline, helping to resolve an average of 59,000 claims every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;As of the end of 2022, all four levels of courts across the country have opened litigation service hotlines, and an average of 59,000 claims have been resolved every day. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6139ffd0d2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;906&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/11/6139ffd0d2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253626&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of the end of 2022, the national All four levels of courts have opened litigation service hotlines, and an average of 59,000 claims are resolved every day. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Send a work order to the judge”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information shows that &quot;12368&quot; is the number determined by the Supreme People&#39;s Court. Judicial information public welfare service number common to the national court system. Beijing is the first pilot area for the &quot;12368&quot; judicial service hotline, which was officially opened on January 7, 2009. The &quot;Beijing Court 12368 Hotline&quot; has set up a main platform in the Beijing High Court, and has set up sub-platforms in all middle and grassroots courts. Six courts, namely Dongcheng, Xicheng, Chaoyang, Haidian, Fengtai and Daxing, have set up direct dial lines and do not need to be forwarded through the Municipal High Court&#39;s main platform; calls from other court sub-platforms will be uniformly answered and accepted by the Municipal High Court&#39;s main platform, and will be forwarded according to the situation of the call. The case shall be handled by the lower court on separate platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report in 2021, the 12368 direct sub-platform of Xicheng Court consists of 5 lines, and staff will receive more than 200 calls every day , looking for judges, investigating cases, answering questions, receiving opinions, making demands, etc. According to the relevant person in charge of the Beijing High Court, if parties call the 12368 hotline to ask for simple matters such as checking the progress of the case, submitting applications and materials, and procedural litigation consultation, the hotline will &quot;answer the lawsuit&quot; as soon as possible and give a direct reply; If the exercise of judicial power or matters closely related to the case require a response from the judge, the hotline will issue a work order to the judge, who will handle it in a timely manner within the specified time limit to ensure that the contact rate of the judge reaches 100%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Zequn reported to the Chaoyang Court 12368 hotline. On October 8 and 9, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters called the hotline several times to inquire about the &quot;collegial panel&quot; and hotline outsourcing. On one occasion, the operator responded that he could ask the judge about the legal terms and the circumstances in which they appeared, and he would give a reply within two days. Another time, the operator replied that 12368 is mainly responsible for registering complaint information and cannot directly handle complaints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another call occurred at around 8 pm. The artificial intelligence voice assistant provided a self-service intelligent voice query service. When the keyword &quot;Collegial Court&quot; was mentioned , gave a more detailed answer. However, artificial intelligence voice assistants may have unclear or inaccurate hearing from time to time, and if there is a semantic recognition error, they will continue to output large sections of legal or procedural regulations and cannot be interrupted manually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The role of 12368 focuses on information consultation.&quot; A lawyer surnamed Liu told a Southern Weekend reporter that the customer service line of the 12368 hotline mainly relies on the query system. No special professional answering ability is required; more professional questions related to court functions can mainly be completed by calling the legal aid hotline 12348 or going to the court case filing window. Lawyer Liu often interacts with courts and does legal knowledge popularization work on Internet platforms in his spare time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also introduced that many parties involved in the case have little contact with the court and do not understand the existence of 12368. In contrast, lawyers entrusted by parties are the group who have more contact with the 12368 hotline. For lawyers, 12368 is mainly used to understand the progress of the case and to inquire about other channels for detailed consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Outsourcing is more common&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;April 2023, Beijing The &quot;Beijing Higher People&#39;s Court 12368 Hotline Litigation Platform Service Fee Project Winning Announcement&quot; published by the Municipal Government Procurement Network revealed that China Mobile Online Services Co., Ltd. won the bid for &quot;Beijing Higher People&#39;s Court 12368 Hotline Litigation Platform Service&quot; at a price of 7.74972 million yuan. &quot;Fees Project&quot;, the service period is 12 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Introducing the &quot;overall model&quot; in the announcement, the 12368 manual hotline service adopts the access model of the main platform of the High Court and the sub-platforms of the middle and grassroots courts to provide the society with 5× 8 hours service. The bidder provides workplace wiring services, as well as operation team recruitment, training, management, call quality inspection, callback, etc. The number of seats in the operation team shall not be less than 65, and there shall be no less than one full-time call quality inspector. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to media reports, in 2022, the number of manual calls to the Beijing Court’s 12368 hotline reached 1.4942 million, a year-on-year increase of 67.2%, ranking first in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;You will know after going to the court a few times to do things. They really have a lot of things to do and are very busy.&quot; Wang Cailiang, director of Beijing Cailiang Law Firm, once organized lawyers to go to the court. The &quot;Legal Aid Hotline 12348&quot; of the judicial system provides free consultation. He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that it is very common not only in the court system, but also in some government agencies and institutions to outsource hotlines involving legal issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He said that if normal bidding procedures are followed, this kind of outsourcing behavior is not a bad idea. The key is that the legal professionalism of the outsourcing unit must be excellent so that it will not be criticized by the outside world. &quot;If you are not professional, wrong and knowledgeable, you will not be able to satisfy the masses,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people are unwilling to do consultations and receive public consultations.&quot; Wang Cailiang explained that staff in some units regard receiving public consultations as a kind of burden and therefore tend to outsource this work. He believes that communication and consultation are originally good opportunities to resolve conflicts. If used as a burden, conflicts will accumulate and expand, thus consuming more judicial resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s search found that the outsourcing of &quot;12368&quot; is common in courts at all levels across the country, but the specific bidding details vary greatly. Due to different levels of economic development, the business volume of courts in various regions varies greatly, and the contract amounts therefore vary significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, a provincial high court in an economically underdeveloped southern province issued a bidding announcement in July 2023, which showed that its “12368 litigation service hotline outsourcing The project&#39;s budget is only 600,000 yuan; while the contracting budget of another large city district court in March 2023 reached 1.5 million yuan. In addition to the separate bidding model for each court, a province in East China has adopted a model of &quot;provincial centralized deployment and social outsourcing of the 12368 litigation service hotline of the province&#39;s courts&quot;, with an overall budget of more than 24 million yuan, requiring intelligent voice, intelligent work orders, Intelligent agent assistance and a unified litigation service knowledge base empower the core engine, open up the litigation service system, and realize the entire process of consultation, inquiry, appointment, and processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The contract period of these outsourcing services usually ranges from 1 to 3 years, and subcontracting and subcontracting are expressly prohibited. Among the winning bidders, state-owned enterprises and private enterprises It’s both. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, there are no regulations that clearly allow or prohibit outsourcing.&quot; Wu Liwei, a lawyer at Beijing Beidou Dingming Law Firm, often calls the court hotline because he needs to check the progress of the case. Consultation was conducted, but I felt that many outsourcers did not understand legal issues. &quot;Since it is a litigation service hotline, it is to facilitate parties, lawyers and other people who may be involved in the lawsuit to understand relevant legal issues and litigation processes. From this function, internal court personnel should be responsible for answering calls and answering questions.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, Wu Liwei also believes that outsourcing the court hotline may involve leaking privacy. He explained that lawyers and clients often need to call the hotline to inquire about the progress of the case. Although the specific details of the case will not be involved, the &quot;cause of the case&quot; itself contains a lot of private information. &quot;For example, who files a divorce lawsuit against whom, and who sues whom for defamation, insult, or damage to reputation, all involve the privacy of the parties concerned.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[误认家长为人贩子被打：一场基于双向误解的冲突]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258369]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a netizen told an experience of his on social media, which caused widespread attention and controversy. The blogger herself described the version as follows: She said she had a &quot;fracture on her face&quot; and was beaten by her parents because she felt her parents looked like human traffickers. She then had a sense of justice and finally the two parties went to the police station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She wrote: At the police station...it was said that I hit him with a pole first, and then he hit me. In fact, I just followed them from beginning to end, constantly asking the little girl: &quot;Kid, is he a member of your family?&quot; Once or twice I tried to gently hold her hand to confirm with her what the relationship between this man and her was. The little girl didn&#39;t say anything, and I didn&#39;t dare to confirm whether he was a trafficker, so I kept delaying time and told him to stop and not leave. My purpose was to wait until the police came to investigate clearly. He was too fierce, and I was afraid that he would beat him. I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then he was really beaten: Later, when he walked near his car, he suddenly put down the child, turned around and punched me on the head several times... and broke the handle (of the camper) with all his strength. He hit me on the head with the broken end of the metal handle...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this Weibo, there are those who sympathize and support, but also those who ridicule and ridicule. Of course, what we can see so far is the blogger’s unilateral perspective and description, which may not be accurate or complete. To understand the full truth, the media should interview the other party or ask the local police for information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the subject of the facts described by the blogger is true, that is, he is well-intentioned, suspects that the parents are human traffickers, and then follows them, talks to the child, and &quot;once or twice tried to gently hold her hand.&quot; &quot;Hand&quot;, because the child kept silent, &quot;I had to keep stalling for time to tell him to stop and not leave.&quot; This is one party’s perspective. What if we look at it from the perspective of the child’s father? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a father, he carried his child to a private car. Suddenly a stranger appeared and was following me. He also approached the child and kept saying incomprehensible words. He also tried to touch his child and questioned whether he was the child&#39;s biological father. A normal reaction would be to get angry. When he got near his car, he felt that the child was safe, so he decided to teach the other party a lesson, letting the child know that his father would protect him, and venting his anger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be said that protecting one&#39;s children is a normal reaction of any parent. If strangers continue to behave in this way, parents with children will see it as provocation or bad intentions. As for children not answering strangers&#39; questions, it is normal. They may be introverted, or they may not want to talk to strangers of unknown origin due to safety education at school or at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is rumored that in order to snatch children from their parents, one of the tricks used by traffickers is to snatch the children from their parents when the parents are not paying attention, and then lie to passers-by that they are the parents of the children, or Lie that it is a dispute between husband and wife and snatch the child, in order to dissuade passers-by from intervening, so that passers-by will be less willing to intervene. And these urban legends (Urban Legends) actually have their roots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A father posted a video introduction. On the evening of July 13, 2023, his wife took her child out to play. A woman directly tried to snatch the child. Fortunately, she was not far from the child and stopped her in time. &quot;The woman She kept telling others that she was her child, but the people around her didn’t dare to interfere. Later she tried to run away, but I restrained her.” According to a local police report: The woman involved had a history of multiple medical treatments for mental illness. Although the woman was proven to be mentally ill and not a trafficker, she used the phrase &quot;it&#39;s her child&quot; when she robbed the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also sane people who snatch children from others in public. On December 17, 2019, Ms. Wang and her mother came to Shanghai Station with their 2-year-old twins, preparing to take the bus back to their hometown in Zhengzhou. When they were resting at the southeast exit of the station, a middle-aged woman pushing a stroller and wearing a black coat picked up her little daughter and prepared to leave in public. Ms. Wang and the surrounding passengers hurriedly stopped the woman and immediately called the police. The woman lied that she &quot;had the wrong hug.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going back to the case at the beginning of the article, the logical chain may be that the woman believed that the child’s father was a suspected human trafficker; conversely, the child’s father probably also regarded her as a suspected human trafficker or mentally ill, which led to A conflict based on misunderstandings on both sides. The starting point of the blogger involved is worthy of recognition, but in fact, when an adult walks on the street holding a child, from the &quot;prior probability&quot; (prior probability), the probability that it is a parent holding their own child is still extremely high. At the same time, there is no reason why it is normal for parents to have close interactions with their children anytime and anywhere. If the child who is being held cries and screams and says he wants his mother, he clearly says &quot;Who are you? I don&#39;t know you, I want my mother.&quot; That&#39;s indeed a bit suspicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident also reminds us that it is a good thing to have love and a sense of justice, but we should proceed from common sense and rationality, based on reliable judgment, and on the premise of safeguarding our own safety; when we meet the real In suspicious situations, do not directly conflict with the other party. It is best to use legal means to solve the problem. Of course, acting bravely should be encouraged, but it must be objectively true, such as stopping an ongoing crime. If you misjudge the nature of the matter, you are actually infringing on other people&#39;s personal freedom and reputation rights, which will inevitably lead to the consequences of misjudgment and wrong actions. This is the revelation beyond what is right and what is wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高人民检察院依法对殷美根决定逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258375]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 10:05:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate today (11th) that the former deputy party leader of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress The case of secretary and deputy director Yin Meigan suspected of accepting bribes was investigated by the National Supervisory Commission and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Yin Meigan on suspicion of bribery in accordance with the law. The case is under further processing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海老年相亲圣地，常客们不谈爱情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258371]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/10/8025efd915.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 10/8025efd915.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253621&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of September 12, 2023, in Shanghai, in the IKEA restaurant Elderly people. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A meal for 9 people, 13 dishes, and the average cash per person was 72 yuan. Wiping his mouth and getting up, another day passed by. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;68-year-old Hong Jianming stood in front of the neon-lit hotel lobby, watching old friends walking in twos and twos, supporting each other across the zebra crossing until they disappeared. He took steps in the darkness across the road. “They don’t know that I live nearby, and I don’t want them to know.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are single old men whom Hong Jianming met at the IKEA restaurant in Xujiahui, Shanghai. In order to &quot;eat more diverse dishes&quot;, we get together to eat together every Tuesday. Neither of them knew each other&#39;s names, and they seldom asked because there was no need. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of the single elderly people who go to IKEA restaurants want to find a companion. While they boldly express their love for the person they like, they can&#39;t help but be suspicious and wary out of self-protection, lest they suffer a loss. As time goes by, everyone has become acquaintances who maintain a sense of boundaries, and they get together just for fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Loneliness is the background here after all. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Private land&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Lack of a communication platform for the elderly&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;It is rainy in Shanghai in early autumn, but the IKEA Xuhui Shopping Mall at No. 126 Caoxi Road is bustling with people. On the afternoons of Tuesdays and Thursdays, the young people dining in the restaurant on the second floor slowly dispersed, and crowds of elderly people poured in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 3 pm on September 12, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters first arrived at the IKEA restaurant. At first glance, the dining area with nearly 700 seats was scattered. It was completely occupied by elderly people sitting apart, and there were always people walking around in the aisles, chatting with each other. Occasionally, someone walks up to the reporter, looks at the new young face and asks: &quot;Are you here to see some company?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a place where the elderly in Shanghai spontaneously Set dating angle. Xuhui Mall, opened in 1998, is IKEA&#39;s first store in mainland China. It&#39;s hard to explain how its restaurant came to be occupied by a group of singles. As long as you buy a cup of coffee for 7.9 yuan and get free refills, you can hang out in the restaurant with the mug in hand all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;71-year-old Chen Cuixia remembers that 18 years ago, the Xuhui shopping mall was still a small two-story building. She and her six sisters came to play as a single person. I walked around the mall and found that there was food on the second floor. &quot;It&#39;s pretty good here. Let&#39;s talk about it after it&#39;s over. How about we come back next time?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, more and more people gathered together. At the most, More than 300 single elderly people gathered here, all looking for companionship. The entire hall had to rely on shouting to communicate, &quot;the sound was so loud that it could knock off the roof.&quot; Someone suggested that everyone pick a day to get together. Tuesday is the big day and Thursday is the small day. Chen Cuixia feels that the elderly actually have no other place to chat&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;“Except here, it is the People’s Park, and there is a lack of a platform for the elderly to communicate.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest degree of aging in the country . According to the 2022 Shanghai Municipal Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for nearly 40% of the total population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;IKEA restaurant has undoubtedly become a private place for them to relieve their loneliness. Every Tuesday, a 90-year-old old lady takes bus No. 456 from Sanlin. After spending more than 40 minutes arriving at the restaurant, she just sits silently in the corner and watches the crowds of people; The wife treated her like a sister, so she packed some pumpkin seeds in a plastic bag for the old lady to eat. The two have known each other for four or five years since they met in the restaurant. When asked if they were looking for company, they shook their heads and said, &quot;Just chat, as long as Allah (in Shanghai dialect, we) are happy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Guicheng Coming from a farther place, he sets out from Fengxian District every Tuesday and takes two and a half hours by bus and subway. He comes here to chat and eat, and then goes back. He loses 70 to 80 yuan a day, just because he is lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 71-year-old is a matchmaker in Shanghai People&#39;s Park. He has worked for decades, but now he is also facing the dilemma of not being able to find a partner. &quot;Dating for the elderly is the same as dating for young people. They are all about business. Are your conditions good? How much money do you have?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Guicheng said, it is the same as all dating angles. , the most important condition here is also money. Everyone&#39;s opening remarks are nothing more than a few questions: Are you from Shanghai? How old are you? Have children? Is there labor insurance (retirement pension)? Have a house? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A 65-year-old old lady told Zhang Guicheng that she wanted a gift of 500,000 yuan. Zhang Guicheng also asked her this set of questions: Is there labor insurance? No; do you have a house? nor. Zhang Guicheng couldn&#39;t hold back a word, &quot;You have nothing, why would anyone give you 500,000? You just don&#39;t want the gift, and no one wants it from you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;Contempt chain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Old ladies and old men will lose money in getting certificates&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;On the surface, the people who come to the IKEA restaurant are all wealthy elderly people, and bright gold jewelry is the most indispensable decoration here. Most of the men wear short-sleeved shirts and a bunch of keys on their waist belts, which makes them look well-behaved; those who are more individual like to wear a peaked cap upside down and stand up the collar of their short-sleeved shirts; a man often wears a brightly colored suit. The clothes, with big logos and patterns on them, reveal his wealth. He said he has had seven or eight girlfriends here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Women have also mastered the secrets of fashion. Sunglasses, silk scarves and cheongsam are all necessary items to enhance their temperament. There are also people who attract everyone&#39;s attention with their slender figures and use black masks to cover their wrinkled faces, giving them a sense of mystery. Another woman in her sixties from Gansu wears a purple top hat with huge flowers sewn on it. She speaks softly and smiles. However, because she is a foreigner, she has not found a partner yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/50a46731bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;743&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/50a46731bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253622&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 21, 2023, two women over sixty took a group photo at the IKEA restaurant in Shanghai. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As long as you spend an afternoon in an IKEA restaurant, you will clearly feel the chain of contempt among the elderly dating circle. Shanghai men with houses and high pensions are the most popular here. If you are more particular, you can also classify people from various districts in Shanghai into different grades. As for women, young and beautiful Shanghainese are the hot commodity, and some pensions are the best. Outsiders, regardless of gender, are at the bottom of the contempt chain and will be suspected of having ulterior motives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Past lessons tell the old people here that there are all kinds of &quot;traps&quot;. According to the old people&#39;s stories, there are men who dress in gold and silver and lie about how rich their family is just to sleep with the woman they &quot;took&quot;; there are women who claim they are in good health, only to expose their full body after they get together. Because of her illness, her male partner had to take her to the hospital every day; young women from other places often came to this place to &quot;talk about friends&quot; with single Shanghai men in their eighties or nineties with no children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Song Xiaofei is the &quot;confused person&quot; that everyone calls &quot;the trick&quot;. He is an 80-year-old old Chinese medicine doctor who is thin and has a slimy food residue at the corner of his mouth. Wang Xiumin, who is in her 40s, sits opposite him and peels longans for him. The two got together just a few months ago. Due to the huge age gap, they treat each other as father and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Song Xiaofei receives a monthly pension of 8,000 yuan, which is quite high in a restaurant. All the pensions were given to Wang Xiumin for safekeeping. Song Xiaofei would receive 50 yuan of pocket money every day, which he would put into the interlayer of the veteran&#39;s preferential treatment certificate and used to buy cigarettes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Xiumin said that she felt sorry for Song Xiaofei&#39;s experience. Song Xiaofei has experienced three failed marriages, and his first wife made him suffer for 18 years. After the two divorced, the woman&#39;s natal house was allocated to Song Xiaofei. This house was divided into half during the second marriage. After the third marriage ended, the house was completely divided. Now Song Xiaofei can only rent a house in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The third wife is Song Xiaofei whom she met at an IKEA restaurant&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &quot;She said she owned three houses. We got a marriage certificate, but later we found out that she didn&#39;t own any of them.&quot; Song Xiaofei divorced decisively and became alone again. &quot;The third one has a very bad conscience. Now I want to find someone with a good conscience.&quot; Song Xiaofei looked at Wang Xiumin next to him, &quot;She has a pretty good conscience.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Xiumin described Song Xiaofei&#39;s experience as a cow turning into a sheep, the sheep turning into an egg, and finally the egg shell was gone. Song Xiaofei smiled after hearing this, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, I see clearly. As long as I have been around, it will all be in vain if I leave.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to avoid falling into the &quot;trap&quot;, the most common way for the elderly is not to get a marriage certificate or transfer the name on the real estate certificate . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past, Wang Liren talked about a beautiful female companion in a restaurant. &quot;We got along pretty well at first, but then she asked me to put it on the real estate certificate. Her name. I said if I don’t have a son, all three houses will be given to you after my death, but I have a son.”&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;Finally, considering that the two had already slept together, Wang Liren gave his female companion 2,000 yuan as compensation, and the female companion clutched the money and left angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No one wants their property to be divided in their old age. &quot;If the old woman and the old man don&#39;t have a good negotiation, they will lose money in getting the certificate! For example, if you have 500,000 yuan and want a divorce, you have to give her 250,000 yuan.&quot; A man raised his eyebrows and said that he was old &lt;span>;to&lt;/span >; said in a tone that he had already seen through the group of women in front of him. The woman on the side was not happy to hear this. She even supported the popular saying: Love without the purpose of marriage is a hooliganism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people take the example of a successful couple in a restaurant: the man&#39;s financial conditions are not as good as the woman&#39;s, but his pension is high, so he gives all his pension to the woman and lives in the restaurant. Entered the woman&#39;s home. A few years later, the two of them did not get a marriage certificate, and their relationship was still good. &quot;It&#39;s enough to have company with each other, even if we don&#39;t get a certificate, we can live the same life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Loneliness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot; I sold myself for my son”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lao Zhang, a frequent customer in the restaurant, is also a famous &quot;confused person&quot; in IKEA restaurants. Some elderly people describe him as Being a &quot;bad guy&quot; (a dialect word for fooling around) also ruined the atmosphere of the restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is 78 years old and has lost all his teeth. He relies on the friction of his gums with black roots to eat. He can only eat mashed potatoes and liquid food, and chew a small bite of fried food. The chicken steak needs to be chewed slowly for seventy or eighty times before it can be completely swallowed. The soft chin moves the loose skin of the neck up and down, and the heavy gold chain flashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everyone used to call him the &quot;little tailor&quot;, which was a label for his poor days. When he was working in a garment factory, he had no money, so he would spend the night in a bathhouse near the factory. But 8 years ago, due to the demolition of his old house in Shanghai, Lao Zhang received 5 million demolition funds, became rich overnight, and more and more women began to surround him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lao Zhangtu was cheap and spent 1.5 million to buy two 92-square-meter houses in Qidong, Jiangsu. Almost every half month, he takes away a female companion from the IKEA restaurant and takes a bus back to Qidong to look at houses. He calls such women &quot;temporary workers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I spend money to buy someone to accompany me, take care of me, cook for me, wash clothes, 200 to 1,000 yuan a day.&quot; Lao Zhang said, he Prices will be based on age and appearance. The younger and more beautiful the price, the more expensive it will be. &quot;The younger ones are in their forties (years old) and want to sleep together and cuddle&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;48-year-old Shen Sufen is the &quot;temporary worker&quot; called by Lao Zhang. She served Lao Zhang for a period of time, earning 300 yuan a day. One time, I went to Lao Zhang Qidong&#39;s house. The smell was overwhelming. The things in the refrigerator had been there for a month or two. They were all packed and brought back by Lao Zhang after eating out. The ceiling was almost covered with mosquitoes and moths, and Shen Sufen spent three days cleaning it up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;My daughter doesn&#39;t care about me, she&#39;s busy.&quot; Every two or three months, my daughter will come to see Mr. Zhang and give him a wad of 3,000 yuan in cash. Zhang squandered all the money on his three major hobbies in life: coffee, mahjong and women. &quot;It&#39;s lonely every day, but having someone by your side will at least make you richer.&quot; In fact, what Lao Zhang is most worried about is that if one day he falls ill, there won&#39;t even be anyone around him to call 120. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ca8bf0b00a. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ca8bf0b00a.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;253623&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 20, Lao Zhang was going to take a bus from Shanghai back to Qidong. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The blind date story that happened in the IKEA restaurant is not all about love and love. Some of the old people are living for the next generation. And abandoned by the next generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time in the past, there was a beautiful woman in the restaurant who was looking for a companion. She was born in 1975. There was no restriction on the age and appearance of the man she was looking for. The only condition is to give her two million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason for making such a request is because my son is getting married soon and there is not enough money to collect. As long as you have 2 million yuan, you can buy a house and a car in your daughter-in-law&#39;s hometown, and you can also pay for the lottery gifts. The woman said, &quot;I sold myself just for my son.&quot; Later, she became what the old people called a &quot;psychopath&quot; and never came back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Jianming told another story about a single woman in Shanghai wearing a green dress who often hung out in restaurants. Ten years ago, her daughter asked her to help take care of the children at home. Now that the children have grown up, her daughter and son-in-law want her to live out. After several years of looking for a companion, no one wanted her, and she is still living at her daughter&#39;s house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She told me personally that they had two bedrooms and one living room, and the house was large. When her daughter and her family all went to bed, she went in quietly, washed up, and went to bed. Don’t meet them.” As he spoke, Hong Jianming waved the woman over to chat, and the woman waved her hand. &quot;Her brain has been damaged. She has no other idea but to find an old man to take her home to live with.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Old Face&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;If we can&#39;t become partners, at least we have a common topic&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After 5 o&#39;clock in the evening, the old people After getting up and going home one after another, 68-year-old Pan Yinhua chose a corner and sat alone. She laid out the cold steamed buns she brought from home, picked up a glass of hot water, and started to eat her dinner. “I don’t want to go back to that home and see He just makes a noise&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is Pan Yinhua’s ex-husband. It has been 10 years since their divorce, but neither one wants to move out of the house and they are still roommates. Pan Yinhua hopes to marry a Shanghai man who owns a house and then move out of that house. &quot;When I first got divorced, I just wanted to find a good and convenient one, so I divorced. I didn&#39;t expect it to be so difficult to find, and I was already discouraged.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Once, Pan Yinhua and an 80-year-old man fell in love with each other. The man took her home and looked around, and Pan Yinhua was quite satisfied. &quot;But that house is not his, he only has the right to use it.&quot; Pan Yinhua could see that the man wanted to form a companion, &quot;But I think he is pitiful and has no children, and I just want to remain friends with him. He is old and has difficulties. Call me and I can help him&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the 80-year-old man was attracted by a Shenyang woman in her forties who came to the restaurant, and he rented out the house in Shanghai. I followed the woman back to the Northeast. &quot;If this woman has a good conscience, she can take care of him and live for two more years. If it costs a lot of money for the old man to fall down, she will definitely not spend it.&quot; In the end, Pan Yinhua was still worried, &quot;He can talk to me very well, you can He&#39;s a reporter, can you go to Shenyang to find this old man?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everyone who frequents IKEA restaurants knows that finding a partner here is extremely difficult. The blind date of the elderly is quick and decisive. On the basis of &quot;well-matched&quot;, the role of companionship is far greater than love. According to the usual process, as long as there is a compatibility in the first meeting, it means that the first level has been passed. Generally, the man will take the initiative to invite the woman to visit his home. If the conversation is good, they will live together. If the conversation is not good, don&#39;t waste each other&#39;s time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0081db2f79.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0081db2f79.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253624&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 21:00 on September 21, 2023, the remaining three elderly people were chatting at the IKEA restaurant in Shanghai. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past two years, Hong Jianming has taken seven or eight people he photographed home to visit, but none of them came to fruition. . &quot;Weird, why are you so weird?&quot; Some of the women brought back by Hong Jianming from the IKEA restaurant and People&#39;s Park frowned and spoke in a tone that made him uncomfortable, and some had lost their sexual needs in their later years. Hong Jianming knew it was inappropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Often after the two parties chat for half an hour, Hong Jianming will politely send the other party to the subway entrance downstairs and tell her to go home slowly. But what Hong Jianming wants most is another scene of seeing off guests: &quot;I told her, go down by yourself. Do you know the way?&quot; This means that Hong Jianming is &lt;span>;favorite&lt;/span>; of the other person. &quot;I will tell her that she will come again in the future, so I don&#39;t necessarily have to pick you up at the subway station every time, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to be in my own When the person he likes appears, he shows his intentions. Hong Jianming has practiced his &quot;lines&quot; many times &lt;span>; carefully and carefully. &lt;/span>;“I have thought about how to speak and how to answer the conversation, but no one can let me say it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have been living alone for a long time. , Hong Jianming often feels that he has been forgotten. In this city with a population of more than 24.18 million, the hustle and bustle belong to young people. Time pushed him into his twilight years, accompanied by intense loneliness, and there was no way around it. Facing the same old faces day after day, it is impossible to become a partner, so just chat with each other as friends. Get together on a fixed day, at least there will be a common topic to pass the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is also because people are old and have nothing to do. From time to time, salespeople selling real estate and cemeteries come to the IKEA restaurant and organize sightseeing tours for the elderly. Pick-up and drop-off are included, and a free lunch is included. Some elderly people enthusiastically signed up. There is also an old man who has been developing business in a restaurant all year round. He organizes group trips with familiar people to travel to other places, and the business is constant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Every now and then, an old face will disappear here. After asking each other, they heard bad news: some old people who no longer come to IKEA restaurants have passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti ; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, all names in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 09:25:16 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳龙华街道工作人员抢记者摄像机，已被免职]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258355]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Situation Report (2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;About &quot;A reporter from Guangdong TV station was improperly blocked by street staff while conducting interviews and reports near Longhua Bus Station on the morning of October 10th.&quot; Longhua Street issued a relevant briefing on the afternoon of October 10th (see the picture below for details) and immediately organized relevant activities. Situation investigation. After deliberation at the Longhua Subdistrict Party Working Committee meeting, it was decided to remove Zhou, the person involved, from his position as director of the key area governance office of the subdistrict. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/187e8c7d64171ae94152275cc831efb2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1147&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/187e8c7d64171ae94152275cc831efb2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253613&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Longhua Subdistrict Office, Longhua District, Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;October 10, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>