<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[难以推开的石门，看完很扎心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 22:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;In recent years, female-themed works have exploded, but most of them Focusing on the plight of urban women, there are still very few films with small town women as protagonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which was recently released on streaming media, is a precious image of the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The directors of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; are rising independent film stars Huang Ji and Otsuka Ryuji, who are a husband-and-wife team. The two co-produced the &quot;Women&#39;s Trilogy&quot; &quot;Eggs and Stones&quot;, &quot;Stupid Bird&quot; and this &quot;Stone Gate&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;391&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in Hunan In the small town, Huang Ji&#39;s perspective mainly focuses on the survival plight of rural women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eggs and Stones&quot; focuses on the left-behind girls who were sexually assaulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stupid Bird&quot; &quot;Through the carrier of &quot;mobile phone&quot;, it shows the growing confusion of left-behind girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height= &quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot; It takes the experiences of female college student Lin Sen as a slice to reflect reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ages of the heroines in the trilogy are consistent, they are 14, 17 and 20 years old respectively, and the same actor Yao Honggui was chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is more mature than the previous two films. The film style is very similar to the early works of domestic sixth-generation directors that we are familiar with. It uses non-professional actors, talks about marginalized groups, and prefers extreme Life-like scenes and an objective and calm perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the kernel , with Huang Ji’s own characteristics and personal experience, his friend and work partner Otsuka Ryuji can also make some observations about the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The narrative of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; relies on the three identities of a 20-year-old girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, she is Lin Sen, a beautiful female college student, studying as a flight attendant at a vocational school. She has a stable relationship with her boyfriend Liu Long, who even paid for her to enroll in an English training class. With the unexpected pregnancy, Lin Sen&#39;s life also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen&#39;s My parents run a small clinic. The father is disabled, the mother is addicted to micro-business, and a medical accident that caused a female patient to miscarry made the family worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sensible Lin In order to help his family pay off debts, Sen started working crazily to earn money. She worked as an opening welcome model and also went to shopping malls to sell milk powder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height= &quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpected pregnancy and Family debt caused Lin Sen&#39;s originally peaceful life to plummet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen has no intention of becoming a mother, her boyfriend cannot be held responsible, and her creditor wants a child. With the help of her parents, she agreed to an incredible plan to give birth to a child to pay off the debt to the poor woman &quot;Yinfang&quot; who unfortunately had a miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pregnancy is a unique life experience for women. The difficulties unmarried young women face when they have an unexpected pregnancy, whether to have an abortion or not, are common themes in feminist films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Romanian film &quot;April, Three Weeks and Two Days&quot; and the French film &quot;As It Happens&quot; are both set in the last century when abortion was not accepted by most countries. Due to the complex social status quo, women Uterine autonomy is often not possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American movie &quot; &quot;Juno&quot; and the Norwegian film &quot;Ninja Babies&quot; focus on the physical changes and mental stress that pregnancy and childbirth bring to women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In domestic movies , Li Yu&#39;s &quot;Beautiful Beauty&quot; also reproduces the various pressures faced by women after unexpected pregnancy, mainly due to the relatively conservative social public opinion environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference in &quot;Stone Gate&quot; lies in the alternative way of handling the heroine Lin Sen&#39;s pregnancy - not having an abortion but abandoning her for adoption. ‍‍‍‍‍‍Children are also used as a commodity to solve her immediate life problems. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, this is Lin Sen’s active choice, but the film also pays attention to the soft coercion she suffered. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like at the beginning of the film, her boyfriend took her to an English speaking training venue. Others were communicating freely, and the topic revolved around the country they wanted to go to. After Lin Sen found that she couldn’t fit in, she went to the Start playing with your phone on the sofa. She has no strong desire to improve her English. She came here because her boyfriend took the initiative to make the choice for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;842&quot; height= &quot;375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍This one , we can clearly feel the girl Lin Sen&#39;s numbness towards life and new life, the lack of vitality and confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high frequency of static shots in the film further exaggerates this sense of silent despair. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen She rarely showed her emotions. Even when her boyfriend asked for an abortion, she didn&#39;t make a fuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the pain in her breasts during pregnancy and the tearing during childbirth, as well as Lin Sen’s unbearable expression and voice, tell us that her pain is indeed real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In pain and In confusion, she gradually lost control of her destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The plot of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is not complicated, but the film is 147 minutes long because the director placed many shots on the social landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many scenes, Lin Sen does not participate in the main narrative, appearing as a background board and becoming a silent observer. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, she would watch her boyfriend shoot a Douyin wedding promotional video, and watch underground industry managers openly interview young girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen’s mother Obsessed with selling three-no products and telling his story at the organization&#39;s annual meeting. ‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outbreak Later, crowds of people gathered at medical equipment institutions to buy medical masks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is &quot; The biggest feature of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is also the film&#39;s problem. On the one hand, the unrestrained display of shots greatly affects the rhythm of the narrative, and too many idle strokes make the movie long and boring. On the other hand, it also leads to the heroine becoming a tool, making the entire story biased towards curiosity and lacking the power to move people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although film and television works showing women in small towns have been relatively scarce in recent years, they were not uncommon in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excellent works can maintain an excellent balance in grasping female narratives and social and cultural landscapes. Let’s not mention the classic representative works of the fourth and fifth generation directors, such as &quot;Qiu Ju&#39;s Lawsuit&quot;, &quot;The Love of Humans and Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Beginning of Spring&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here is an example of an unpopular masterpiece - &quot;The Crying Woman&quot;. The director and screenwriter of this film, Liu Bingjian, used the story of Wang Guixiang, a Guizhou woman who made money through mourning, to show the public that China has a long history of funeral culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wang Guixiang Her strong vitality, her shrewd and kind feminine charm, and the warmth and warmth of people in rural society can all leave a deep impression on people. &quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which failed to do this, also formed a contradiction, with its novel subject matter but bland plot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth mentioning that &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is almost the same as a documentary in terms of realism. It is a story that grows out of the shooting environment and the actors&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors who play Lin Sen’s parents are director Huang Ji’s biological parents. They run this clinic in reality, and their home is also the real residence of the director and his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie Filmed over a ten-month period following the pregnancy cycle, and with a limited budget, it didn&#39;t have a set designed in advance like many films, and the actors were thrown directly into real space. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha is the main filming location. The lens captures its glamorous and prosperous side, as well as its chaotic and dark corners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍‍In addition to the director The camera strives to be close to reality, and also tries its best to show the living conditions of girls in non-developed areas. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original setting of the heroine Lin Sen was an imaginary image of a proactive female college student. But this was completely different from the state of actor Yao Honggui at the time, and it was also different from the current situation of many young college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director and his wife rewrote the character design, and the protagonist’s story is a mixed experience of female college students obtained from interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the unexpected pregnancy experience of a small town girl, the film reflects the structural dilemma of this group. It originates from many constraints such as patriarchy, commodity society, and power class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine was The oppression does not occur openly, but it does not mean that multiple exploitation does not exist. This complex structural dilemma creates a low margin for error in women’s choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, it seems that Lin Sen can make different choices, take the initiative to have an abortion, not pay off the debt for his mother, or give birth to a child and raise him, but no life path will become easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are too many stone doors in her life that are difficult to push open, and she can only avoid falling by climbing hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending of the film It is open-ended, and we have no way of knowing the final fate of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the audience can see is that the male employer hopes to postpone the adoption date due to the epidemic. The heroine Lin Sen, who is waiting for the handover, was triggered by the child&#39;s cry and got chest pain and got out of the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it hurts and there is no escape. Escape, the pain is still there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of hope in her life made her breathless. However, instead of floating helplessly in the ocean of life, it is better to fight hard and push open the stone door to try to welcome new life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“上海警察上门抓德牧”成事件：警犬军犬的谣言为何大行其道？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news about &quot;Shanghai police came to arrest German Shepherd&quot; triggered a &quot;storm in a teacup&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was first reported online that on October 24, the police from Wusong District, Shanghai came to the door and seized a 16-year-old German shepherd. The owner surrenders the dog. In the videos and texts circulating on the Internet, the dog has become a &quot;retired police dog&quot; or even a &quot;retired military dog.&quot; The words &quot;18 special police officers in three vehicles broke down the door and caught a 16-year-old dying old dog&quot;. Hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, the Shanghai Wusong Subdistrict Office issued a notice on this matter. The report stated that a resident of Haibin San Village was raising large and aggressive dogs (wolfdogs with hybrid blood) without a license, and had repeatedly walked dogs without leashes and large dogs without muzzles and other illegal dog-raising behaviors. After receiving reports from surrounding residents, police officers from the police station, staff from the Dog Breeding Office, comprehensive law enforcement officials and the district&#39;s special police detachment jointly came to rectify the situation. The dog owner took the initiative to open the door and cooperated with the work, and took the initiative to hand over the dog to the relevant departments for containment and disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After careful review of this incident, there are many contradictions and inconsistencies between the information transmitted online and the official report. Even after the report was released, many people expressed &quot;disbelief&quot; and need to be analyzed one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;bloodline&quot; of the dog involved. Someone on Weibo said it was a retired police dog, but the &quot;uniform&quot; in the video posted online only had &quot;POLICE&quot; in English and no Chinese &quot;police dog&quot;. This is obviously inconsistent with the &quot;standard dress&quot; of domestic police dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the first batch of retired police dogs in Shanghai were opened for adoption on September 5, 2022. The eight police dogs announced at that time were all from the police dog training base of the Songjiang Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau. Bradford, Malinois, Rottweiler, Springer Spaniel, German Shepherd, Doberman, etc., but only one Springer Spaniel and two Labradors are open to the public for adoption, and the remaining five including the German Shepherd are retired Police dogs can only be adopted by units. At the same time, adoptive citizens also need to receive follow-up visits every three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, there is indeed a German Shepherd among the retired police dogs open for adoption in Shanghai, but it was not given to citizens for adoption. Therefore, the rumors that the dogs involved were just &quot;retired police dogs&quot; and &quot;German shepherds&quot; are self-defeating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;retired military dog&quot; theory, there is a lack of any supporting information, and it directly conflicts with the &quot;POLICE uniform&quot; in the online video. China&#39;s &quot;Interim Regulations on the Work of Military Dogs&quot; defines military dogs as special combatants and an integral part of the military&#39;s combat effectiveness. After military dogs retire, they will generally enter military dog ​​breeding and training bases to &quot;live out their old age&quot;. Military dogs with meritorious service will also enjoy recuperation treatment. Even if adoption is open, adopters have very high requirements, including &quot;must love dogs&quot;, &quot;must have experience raising large dogs&quot;, and &quot;cannot be a living environment in an urban community&quot;. Some units will also require adopters to have Military personnel will vouch for them, and they must have a stable income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Zhengzhou 10 million reward for finding retired military dogs&quot; incident on July 9, 2023, the &quot;retired military dog&quot; gimmick instantly proved that this is a &quot;starting picture, the rest are all It’s fake news, because the description in the “reward notice” is completely contrary to the regulations for the adoption of retired military dogs. In this incident, the terms &quot;retired police dog&quot; and &quot;retired military dog&quot; are inconsistent and can be proven to be pure rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether the dog owner’s dog-raising behavior is legal and compliant, and the truth behind the door-to-door rectification actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 12, paragraph 3, of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; passed in 2011 and revised in 2016, prohibits individuals from raising aggressive dogs. Violators of this provision will have the aggressive dogs taken into custody by the public security department. The &quot;Shanghai Catalog of Prohibited Individual Breeding of Violent Dogs&quot; stipulates 24 types of ferocious dogs, including German Shepherds, French Wolfdogs, and Kunming Wolfdogs. Therefore, whether the owner of the dog involved adopts a German shepherd or a hybrid wolfdog, it is undoubtedly a violent dog breed that is prohibited from personal breeding, and dog registration, annual inspection and dog management fees are out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the official report, the owner of the dog involved also engaged in illegal dog-raising behaviors such as walking the dog without a leash and without wearing a muzzle. This is also consistent with the &quot;20 reports from surrounding residents&quot; in the online information. The statement is consistent. Articles 21 and 30 of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; also clearly stipulate that dog owners shall abide by public order and shall not interfere with the normal lives of others. Residents&#39; committees also have the right to formulate and supervise dog breeding conventions or regulations in their residential areas. Management, dog owners should comply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that the illegal dog-raising behavior of the dog owner involved has been confirmed, surrounding residents naturally have the right to report and request the public security department to take in the dog. This request is reasonable and reasonable, and the joint door-to-door rectification by various local departments is also in line with current laws and regulations. Judging from the live videos and pictures, &quot;18 special police officers&quot; is also false information, and relevant social media bloggers have deliberately exaggerated it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this incident also shows that relevant public issues have lost focus, which may not be a blessing to the public interest. Faced with the public issue of &quot;how to regulate dog ownership,&quot; some people are willing to mobilize by creating fake news and create traffic and attention with &quot;tragic narratives.&quot; Similar behavior is no longer a public discussion, but an out-and-out &quot;information war&quot; and &quot;public opinion war&quot; method, trying to blur the focus and muddy the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, laws and regulations regulating dog breeding have been implemented in various places for many years, in order to better protect people&#39;s rights. Dogs are not civil subjects and are the private property of their owners. &quot;Conflict between humans and dogs&quot; is a false issue that does not exist. The real issue is how to regulate dog breeding: only when the premise of protecting human rights is established can we talk about protecting people&#39;s property rights to dogs. Protecting people from being hurt by dogs and preventing &quot;dog bites&quot; should still be a real issue that public opinion pays attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报深圳欢乐谷过山车碰撞事故救治情况：目前17人留院诊治]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259549]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;821&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社会总要“毒打”每一个准社会人丨 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259535]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o2oKFU2EiDUXRbLqoSU8L1WMxan6W8ITAbEXeCc5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;880&quot; height=&quot;658&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o2oKFU2EiDUXRbLqoSU8L1WMxan6W8ITAbEX eCc5. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, Guangzhou, the theme of the South China University of Technology was &quot;Shenzhen It is a double-selection meeting of the &quot;State-owned Enterprises 2024 Campus Recruitment&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Details of relevant reports See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/258798?source=131&quot;>;&quot;Who is in the cold?&quot; Who&#39;s popular? The first job fair for the Class of 2024&quot;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a journalism student, when interviewing job fairs, I pay special attention to the situation of media units. However, after the four double-election meetings, I only saw one news website from Foshan, which was on September 28, 2023, at Guangdong University of Foreign Studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The HR of this news website used the pseudonym Huang Li in the manuscript. After a brief introduction, I was allowed to sit aside and ask questions or observe on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a form on the table to record the basic information of job-seeking students. Nearly three hours have passed since the double selection meeting, and about twenty names have been filled in. The next column is &quot;Education,&quot; almost all of which are master&#39;s degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I heard that Guangzhou Foreign Studies University (graduated this year) has 150 master&#39;s degrees in new communication.&quot; When she said this, Huang Li had a subtle smile on her face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven minutes ago, she just rejected a girl&#39;s resume on the grounds that &quot;the resume was not suitable.&quot; A girl wants to apply for the social media platform operation of a news network, but she only has user operation experience in an ordinary company. It’s hard to tell what the essential difference between the two “operations” is, but it doesn’t prevent Huang Li from thinking that they don’t match each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I speculate that what she meant was that there were many students applying for jobs and she could choose as much as she wanted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In media reports, the number of graduates has been rising year after year - 9.09 million in 2021, 10.76 million in 2022, and 11.58 million in 2023 - making each year replace the previous year and become a new &quot; The most difficult employment season.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following interview with Xu Yang, the organizer of the double election conference, confirmed this point. He told me that in recent years, the supply and demand for jobs at the double election have become increasingly asymmetric. On the one hand, students&#39; enthusiasm for employment is actually increasing and the number of participants is increasing; on the other hand, the number of participating companies and the number of jobs released is decreasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiamin, a master’s degree student in materials science from Sun Yat-sen University who has been mentioned in many reports, was someone I met at South China University of Technology. At that time, she was sitting outside the venue and resting against the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Across the wall, countless red posters hang low, and there are one or two nervous-looking HRs in front of each booth. The aisles were narrow and cluttered, leaflets scattered everywhere, and it was dark and stuffy, like a trench. Li Jiamin smiled bitterly: &quot;Looking for a job requires physical and psychological torture.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Employment is indeed like a battle, and everyone is prepared. But after each battle, it seems that everyone has lost their armor and lost their armor, with no victory or defeat in sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the bathroom of the same double election meeting, I also saw a young HR with a childish look on his face. She was still breastfeeding and asked me in a low voice to help close the outer door of the toilet. I was secretly surprised by how hard he worked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the manuscript was released, Li Jiamin’s demands for salary were considered by some readers as “having not withstood the severe beatings of society”. Like a motto of the times, society always wants to “beat” every (quasi) social person. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn’t it normal for job seekers to want higher wages and better jobs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, companies also have their own grievances. When Huang Li commented on today&#39;s young job seekers, her dissatisfaction could not be concealed in her words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For those of us who were born in the 1980s and early 1990s, our family conditions were not that good when we were young, so we all consciously cherished our jobs. But today’s young people have good family conditions, have no worries about food and drink, and have many choices of work. A lot. For them, the boss doesn’t fight against the west, right? As long as there is something that doesn’t fit the idea, just leave.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to improve the so-called recruitment retention rate, the job seeker’s hometown It became a question she repeatedly asked. From whether she is from Foshan, to whether she has relatives and friends living in Foshan, to her identification with the city of Foshan, she did not let go of any clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng, who was at the same double selection meeting as Huang Li, is the head of the Guangzhou branch of a public examination training institution. On this day, his booth was almost always surrounded by people. This is very unusual for a small and micro enterprise with less than 50 employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is difficult to tell whether the crowd who gathered around him was attracted by the several &quot;Guangdong Written Examination Questions for Selected Students&quot; on the table or by the institution itself. Wu Feng seemed not to think about this problem. Before the interview, he gave me a set of real questions with the same enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 5 pm, the interview came to an end and I was ready to leave. But he stopped me and asked about the end time of my internship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There&#39;s still one month left.&quot; I said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Then after your internship is over, you can sign up for an internship with us.&quot; Wu Feng said that they are short of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弃养致死，那些变相杀害孩子的父母]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/QxImREUiIkRx7hQBSB6y1vFdwO3z0acGg8wkGHnx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/QxImREUiIkRx7hQBSB6y1vFdwO 3z0acGg8wkGHnx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 5, 2022, children watched carp streamers in Koshigaya City, Saitama Prefecture, Japan . Today is Children’s Day in Japan. On this day, people hang carp streamers to pray for their children &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do parents do this? Become the murderer who personally caused the death of a child? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than 20 years, Japanese writer and journalist Haru Sugiyama has continued to investigate cases of parental abandonment in Japan. In many cases of abandonment that shocked society, young children eventually starved to death because they had no ability to take care of themselves. Or die of illness. These cases are driving the revision of Japan&#39;s Child Protection Act, but the situation of deaths due to abandonment remains serious. &quot;Most of the parents who have lost their children seem to be young people, prejudiced people or people with disabilities.&quot; In October 2023, 65-year-old Haru Sugiyama told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; in an email interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After children are born, does the world provide them with a safe and protected growth environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022 alone, 77 children died from abuse in Japan. Data from the Japan Children and Family Agency show that the number of child abuse consultations in Japan in 2022 has set a new record for 32 consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 23, 2023, a case involving the death of an abandoned baby was opened in Japan. 33-year-old Narumi Taniguchi, who works in a custom shop, gave birth to a baby girl alone on a street in Osaka City on January 30. She put the baby in a bag and abandoned it in a coin-operated locker. The baby eventually died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the South Korean police discovered the remains of two infants in a refrigerator in an apartment in Suwon City. This incident attracted great attention in South Korea. South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Health and Welfare stated that as of July 18, there were more than 2,123 unregistered &quot;ghost babies&quot; in South Korea, and 249 of them were confirmed dead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What initially led Haru Sugiyama to investigate the phenomenon of &quot;child abandonment&quot; was a death case of a girl that shocked Japanese society. On December 10, 2000, a girl died in Aichi Prefecture, Japan. A pair of young parents put their 3-year-old daughter Mana Murata in a cardboard box at home for nearly 20 days. During this period, Mana barely ate, she eventually starved to death. At that time, Masami Murata, a mother, was pregnant and raising a 1-and-a-half-year-old son with her husband Tomonori Murata. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugiyama Haru graduated from the First Faculty of Literature of Waseda University. He worked as a magazine editor and later became a freelancer. He writes reportage about parenting and parent-child issues, parents killing their own children, etc. His works include focusing on women. The poverty-stricken &quot;Documentary·Abuse - The Case of Two Children Abandoned to Death in Osaka&quot;, &quot;Thoughts from Child Abuse: How Society Pressures Families&quot; which explores the seriousness of family relationships in Japanese society, and &quot;Parenting Abandonment - Trapped Mothers&quot; The Chinese version of &quot;With the Neglected Daughter&quot; will be published in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SLJxrzToY7rJMxC11QGsHQ2fvLN081Dr1nnwGzrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SLJxrzToY7rJMxC11QGsHQ2fvLN081Dr1nnwGzrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255435&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugiyama Haru met the Muratas while they were serving their sentences and continued to correspond with them. Sugiyama Haru&#39;s child is one and a half years older than Mana. During the investigation, Sugiyama Haru &quot;the closer he came into contact with the case, the more unable he was to escape from his mother&#39;s perspective.&quot; After three and a half years of interviews and research on this case, Haru Sugiyama finally recorded this tragedy caused by the parenting environment in modern society in a way that is close to line drawing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother who abandoned her daughter was also a daughter who was abandoned since she was a child. In Japanese society with structural gender inequality, women&#39;s own needs are always ignored. When her daughter Mana&#39;s health condition worsened, Masami turned to her husband Tomonori for help. After being treated indifferently, the frustrated Masami no longer cared about her daughter&#39;s condition, but turned to her own mother Hideko, and flattered her husband who had already remarried. The mother expressed her love passionately and tried hard to imitate a &quot;well-behaved daughter in her mother&#39;s eyes.&quot; The 24-year-old Yamei was afraid of her haggard child and did not dare to touch her daughter, waiting for her child to die in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a society where mothers assume the main childcare responsibilities by default, lack of social awareness of childcare, and economic inequality, the tragedy of young children dying due to abuse and abandonment is not an isolated case. The circumstances and details in the &quot;Mana&quot; case have appeared repeatedly in subsequent &quot;childcare abandonment&quot; cases. The parents of these children often suffered violence or abandonment when they were young. They grew up in isolation. As adults, they still face tremendous pressure to survive and lack the ability to live stably in society. Haru Sugiyama said: &quot;Twenty years of continuous interviews have given me the feeling that cases of death by abuse are also affected by the contraction of social functions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BBiMfnmVj1JPaa4U1MSOG6MhKdmSSDILBNSDxy9o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/BBiMfnmVj1JPaa4U1MSOG6MhKdmSSDILBNSDxy9o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255439&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is an interview between &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; and Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unable to Why don’t parents raising children seek help? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the 1990s to the present, Japan’s &quot;childcare abandonment&quot; &quot;How has the phenomenon changed?&quot; What kind of fluctuations have the incidence rate shown, and what are the social and temporal reasons behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, about 70 cases of killing children occur in Japanese society every year. Of course, in the period of social chaos after the war, children suffered even more. In the second half of the 1970s, there were approximately 200 cases of child abuse-related death each year. In the first half of the 1970s, in Japan, which was experiencing rapid economic growth, cases of babies being thrown into lockers at train stations often occurred. That was an era when a large number of young people moved from rural areas to cities. Such cases occurred frequently, probably because the society at that time did not provide cultural and institutional support for families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have been paying attention to &quot;nurturing&quot; since the 1990s Children” topic, especially the phenomenon of “parenting abandonment” or improper parenting in Japan. What is the general appearance of the families you met during your research, such as their economic status? Are they all from the bottom of society? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Haru Sugiyama:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I interviewed six families that were torn apart by child abuse. Some of the children in these families were abused to death, and some were on the verge of death. . Some of the interviews involved me meeting directly with family members, while others I simply attended court proceedings. Objectively speaking, the families I interviewed were all facing financial difficulties. Even if they do not fall into the low-income group defined by society, these families are still in considerable financial difficulty. In addition, parents who lose their children seem to be more likely to be young, prejudiced, or disabled. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Childcare requires an investment of resources. British urban anthropologist Sandra Wallman believes that there are six types of necessary resources for family life: structural resources; land (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;住宅&lt;/span>;）；劳动（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;服务&lt;/span >;）；资本（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;金钱&lt;/span>;）；组织资源（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;使构造性资源投入实际使用的资源&lt;/span>;）；时间、信息、自我认同（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;归属感、自尊心&lt;/ span>;）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们有必要认识到自己有资格并可以随意使用这些资源，否则就很难使用救援服务。生活困难的人不能杀掉自己的孩子，而应该主动寻求帮助、想办法从困境中挣脱出来。备齐社会资源固然重要，但我认为更重要的是要解决社会明明提供了资源、人们却无法主动求助的问题。一定要让大家认识到，有困难就要借助社会资源、社会为大家做足了准备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这些家庭中，母亲往往是最受关注的，她们通常处于何种状态？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我参与的案件中，每个母亲都有精神创伤，心理问题都很严重。身心健康的母亲可以利用各种资源跨过困难。心理问题的形成，与母亲童年时缺乏关爱、童年和婚后反复遭受暴力有关。性暴力的体验尤其会给人留下深刻的创伤。很多案件中的母亲似乎都曾在自尊未得到保护的情况下遭遇过性暴力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，在这些案件中，援助的一方都没能充分地发挥作用。当事人通常缺乏相关知识，不知道自己可以接受帮助。 2010年，大阪市西区发生了一起案件。孩子的母亲是全职主妇，育儿时虽然全面接受了社会援助，但离婚后却连儿童抚养津贴都拿不到，而她丝毫没想过寻求任何社会援助。这令我非常吃惊。 （&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;记者注：2010年，日本大阪市西区一位母亲连续50天将1岁的男孩和3岁的女孩弃之不顾，导致他们饿死。母亲离开了家，将两个孩子留在家中，再也没有回来。&lt;/span>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;关于寻求帮助，教育程度和社会阶层不同的母亲会呈现出什么区别？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我没有调查过教育、阶层的不同会对家庭造成怎样的影响。但即便是知识水平出众、高学历的母亲，若被人夺去了自尊、不再相信自我价值，也存在无法寻求妥当援助的情况。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，也有借助智慧克服困境的人。困难加剧时，就更需要知识战胜它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有调查显示，单亲妈妈中约有一半人存在生活困难。即使女性渴望工作，往往也只能以打零工等方式走入职场，无法成为正式员工，这也就意味着，她们领不到正常的收入。有时候，仅靠母亲的收入是无法养活孩子的。这是整个社会需要解决的问题，不该仅让母亲为此买单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在多个具体案件中，我发现，男人们害怕脱离自身成长的社会阶层的恐惧，似乎渐渐成了他们对家庭成员施暴、对孩子动粗的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本社会目前经济下行，社会职能也在逐渐紧缩，这增添了做父母的烦恼。 20年来的持续采访给我的感觉是，儿童虐待致死的案件也受到了社会职能紧缩的影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Z4NhPACsTexDnNlEpygQrFeZAvgbSuBzce4y7338.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Z4NhPACsTexDnNlEpygQrFeZAvgbSuBzce4y7338.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月23日，日本兵库县神户市，一名6岁男孩被虐待致死并抛尸，人们在其住所前献上鲜花和小吃&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;缺席的丈夫，缺席的社会&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你的大量调研中，“男主外，女主内”的家庭格局是普遍存在的吗？丈夫在家庭育儿中的参与比例是否有变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;目前日本的经济发展处于停滞时期，我想社会对女性的要求早已不局限于守护家庭。大概只有嫁给非常有经济能力的男人，才可以被允许只“主内”吧——也有少数家庭虽然非常贫困，丈夫却不允许妻子外出工作。只不过，父权主义的价值观仍然非常强势，大家仍然认为家庭价值掌握在男人手中，女性只是予以辅助。这一观点也在无意识中束缚着许多人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与过去相比，日本社会中父亲参与育儿的比例应该是提高了。二三十年前，去幼儿园接送孩子的父亲少之又少，但现在的情况比那时候改善了不少，大家也开始认为父亲接送孩子是很正常的事。允许员工休育儿假的公司变多了，男性参与育儿比从前寻常了许多。大型企业的男性产假制度逐渐完善，男性请产假的成功率也变高了。这意味着社会的意识改革正在进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;日本存在类似于中国的“隔代育儿”（由祖父母或外祖父母养育孩子）现象吗？日本存在“留守儿童”的问题吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;“隔代育儿”在过去也有过，但现在的日本社会，祖父母、外祖父母往往由于养老金不足而无法维持生活，还是得去社会上工作。每个地区的情况或许有所不同，但上一代人能游刃有余地帮忙育儿的家庭应该很有限。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于“留守儿童”的问题。现在的日本社会，从小地方去大都市工作的年轻人数量较之前有所减少。外出务工现象曾经盛极一时，但现在已经有了变化。另外，经济困难的年轻人，多数似乎都选择不结婚、不生育。少子化是日本社会需要面对的一大问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“隔代育儿”和“留守儿童”现象也反映了部分中国人对育儿的理解——育儿是一个家庭甚至家族的“公共事务”，这与日韩在文化层面对育儿的理解有所不同，你如何理解这种差异？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;原来在中国，育儿是家族的“公共事务”啊。这一点很有意思，原来育儿还有公共性，这让我很感动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，育儿的属性是私人的，给我的感觉是，育儿基本都以小家庭为中心，或者说，小家庭实际上不是“私”，而是肩负职责的极简主义的“公”。受局限的“家庭”背负了一切，亲子关系非常紧密，也有部分孩子被母亲控制。日本的未成年护理者问题也亟待解决，有些家庭的父母缺乏基本能力或有行为障碍、精神疾病，而不得不由孩子看护他们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不管是强调对受虐儿童的救助，还是对虐待行为的司法惩戒，都存在滞后性，伤害已经造成了。育儿责任的社会化是否重要，目前日本在这方面有怎样的进展，有哪些是本该提供却没提供的支援？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;你说得很对。现代社会中的家庭制度随着经济和资本主义社会的发展，已经越来越难维系了。过去人们靠家中的产业生活，现在的社会则要花钱购买劳动力，家庭的代际性已经缺乏。为家庭生儿育女的时代虽然对现在还有一定影响，但家庭的概念和形态已经有了变化。如果社会意识不到这个问题，育儿的人恐怕会永远处在痛苦之中。在我看来，目前的日本还缺乏社会化育儿的意识。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/1BOnhzrjk82P9hZmXn1pzMruYmoidjR9Xi1UPhsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;956&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/1BOnhzrjk82P9hZmXn1pzMruYmoidjR9Xi1UPhsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;是枝裕和导演的《无人知晓》剧照。电影取材于1988年日本西巢鸭弃婴事件：一名母亲为了与新男友同居，抛弃了四名子女&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（《无人知晓》/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;年轻人逐渐成为弱势群体？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年6月韩国发生了“水原冰柜死婴案”，你如何看待韩国的生育环境？韩国的“禁止堕胎令”在2021年才正式失效，而且避孕药价格高、相关的避孕流程仍然很麻烦。日本的生育环境是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为，孩子之所以会被父母杀害，是因为女性在当下的社会中无法自主选择生育与否。社会应当做出改变，让女性能为自己的人生做主。另外，社会的力量也非常重要，有责任精心呵护、养育每一个生命。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本的避孕药，尤其是紧急避孕药也需要医生下诊断才能开，并且价格高昂，不是女性能随意获得的。目前的状况是孕妇本人无法决定是否要产下婴儿。社会缺乏共同抚养孩子的意识，女性个体在要孩子的问题上又无法为自己做主。这次的采访更让我意识到，日本的女性不得不背负育儿的重任，社会的救助手段却十分缺乏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;韩国在2022年成为全世界生育率最低的国家。低生育率的背后呈现了当下人们怎样的心态？又折射出怎样的社会现实？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本社会的不平等正在迅速扩大。有经济能力的人像以前的人一样结婚生子，将孩子养育成人。缺乏经济能力的人则会为育儿付出诸多辛苦，很难感到幸福。因为社会没有给他们提供支撑。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为了缓解低生育率状况，韩国政府密集出台一系列生育“补丁”，比如提高补助标准、增加托儿所，日本政府又是如何面对低生育率问题的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;提高补助标准非常重要，社会至少不该让任何孩子挨饿。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本的托儿所增加后，满足入园条件却无法入园的孩子迅速减少。这是以降低儿童的看护标准为代价实现的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本还调整了教育制度，使孩子可以接受免费教育。贫穷家庭的孩子也靠无偿奖学金得以升学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，学校的设施尚有不完善之处。或是有些陈旧的设施之前可以轻松地更新，现在却迟迟没有做到。真正用在孩子身上的预算少得可怜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;政府目前已经向儿童食堂等机构投钱了，这些机构虽然良莠不齐，但都拿到了政府的资金。不过，国家无法为儿童食堂的质量做担保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要想让孩子们真正幸福快乐地长大，应该先从国家做起，重视每个孩子的成长，努力改善育儿环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“自己都过得不好，怎么生孩子？”——经济状况恶化、教育成本增加等等是许多年轻人考虑生育时要面对的问题。日本年轻人的心态是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杉山春：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本的年轻人中，能在一定程度上客观思考的人也倾向于认为“自己都活不好，为什么还要生孩子”。不过，也有一部分年轻人缺乏父母或社会的爱，试图通过性关系来弥补。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不要小孩的年轻人不断增加，反映出年轻人逐渐成为社会弱势群体的事实。年轻人没有得到妥善的对待，不认为自己应该是参与社会建设的主力军。而年长者对这一现状究竟有多少认识，这一点值得思考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[14只猫咪非正常死亡背后，警惕“踢猫效应”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259539]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/b8f04c2e41.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/b8f04c2e41.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月22日，虎丘山风景区盆景园，两只幼猫在阳光下漫步。 南方周末记者海阳|摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;连续几天，大黄、小黑和小黄都没现身，墙角摆放的猫粮也一动未动，这让虎丘山风景区茶舍的服务员韩雪揪紧了心。她担心三只小猫也和网传消息一样，吃了“坏人”投放的毒物死亡了。这一猜测立刻被身旁的同事纠正，“咱们没人亲眼看到，不能乱说”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月20日晚间，微博网友爆料称，苏州虎丘山风景区有大量流浪猫死于投毒，并附上猫尸体照片。这一信息在抖音、小红书等多个平台发酵，为流浪动物管理争议添上新的一笔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月22日，虎丘山风景区管理处的工作人员刘芳向南方周末记者证实，10月10日至16日之间，园区内发现14只猫咪死亡。但查看监控后，没有发现猫咪死于投毒的证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月16日，四川崇州罗威纳犬咬伤女童。有网友将虎丘流浪猫的死亡事件与狗咬女童关联，但南方周末记者采访发现，虎丘流浪猫的死亡大多发生在狗咬女童之前，意味着这更可能是一起孤立事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，近期社交网络上虐杀流浪动物话题数量骤增。中南财经政法大学法学院教授钱叶芳也注意到了社交媒体上的“仇狗仇猫”情绪，在她看来，其背后既有狗肉产业链从业者的煽动，也是“踢猫效应”的表现：“不敢向强者表达负面情绪，就向弱者发泄。层层向下传递，最后传给了不会说话的动物。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常年呼吁出台《伴侣动物保护和管理法》之余，钱叶芳在杭州市钱塘区海天社区开展了一场延续三年多的试验。对于流浪动物管理，她给出的解法并不新颖但任重道远：完善立法、倡导文明养犬、杜绝当街扑杀、合理处置以及多与民间力量合作等。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;景区已经报警&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;虎丘山风景区位于苏州西部，主体是一座海拔34.3米的小山，南北两处山脚下各设一出入口。在景区内盆景园工作的季杰告诉南方周末记者，南北入口以及盆景园的游客密度较小，又地势平坦，因此成为流浪猫们的主要据点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在季杰和同事们的投喂下，盆景区已生活着十几只猫。而景区管理处也发现了猫咪身上的流量潜质。虎丘山景区抖音官方账号2020年4月发布的一条短视频中，出现了一只叫“tiger” 的橘猫，名字寓意虎丘的“虎”。这条视频获得了482个点赞，是同期发布的花草风光视频点赞量的十倍以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场突如其来的死亡事件令不少员工感到难过。季杰回忆，一位参加过“小动物保护协会”的同事发现，一只从小喂大的猫咪抽搐、吐白沫，他试图灌水抢救。但小猫终究没救过来，还在挣扎之中咬了他一口。除了这只死在同事面前的之外，季杰估计盆景区还少了两三只猫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虎丘景区内，大多数职工白天都要值守岗位，而猫咪往往在傍晚游人稀少时候才出来活动。有的猫咪在入夜后死去，尸体在清晨被清洁工收走。多数人没有亲眼见到尸体，只是直观感到猫咪数量变少，随后才从网络上听闻“毒死”一事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;感到小猫变少的还有景区南门附近摆摊的梅阿姨。以往每天清晨上班，梅阿姨的手推车碾过路面的声音都会吸引五六只猫咪讨食。十一长假过完不久，这批小猫的数量减少到两三只。此后，她每天询问清洁工是否捡到小猫尸体，得到连续肯定的答复后，她非常悲愤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘芳表示，猫咪死亡地点主要集中在南门、西溪环翠（西园）、万景山庄（即盆景园）。从地图上看，这三片地带相毗邻，集中于景区南侧。季杰和盆景区的其他员工都提到，猫咪死亡事件的前几日，曾有游客投诉称在盆景区内被猫抓伤。这二者之间会不会有关联？除了蓄意报复，季杰实在想不到有什么理由能解释这一切。当然，他没有任何证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘芳表示，景区已经报警，派出所已介入此案。园方也调取了监控，检查了地面，但未发现毒物。“如果之后再发现猫咪死亡，我们会拜托公安部门第一时间物检，以确定这是否一起人为事件。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件发生后，景区进一步加强了现场安保巡查人员力量，及时清理散落地面的食物残渣，并劝阻游客随意投喂小动物。10月26日，刘芳表示，景区组织了猫咪关爱志愿服务队，在景区猫咪出入较多的点位安装智能猫箱，专人管理、远程监测、定点投喂，为猫咪创造安全的生活环境。同时，在景区播放动物保护倡议视频，制作关爱猫咪提示牌。“后期我们将持续关注景区内猫的生存状况，尽可能为它们提供必要的帮助和保障。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;流言核实，有真有假&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;狗咬女童事件后，伤狗、伤猫的舆论持续发酵。南方周末记者对其中部分爆料进行了核实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位杭州博主爆料称，10月18日，自己养的雪纳瑞和柴犬被房东的父亲偷走杀死，其中柴犬被扒皮剁碎，“怀疑他就是要吃狗肉”。三天之后，当事人删除原发表于小红书的事件经过相关笔记，并注销账号。当事人婉拒了南方周末记者的采访邀请，表示事情已经结束，不想被打扰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位接近该博主的人士披露，事件双方已由公安局调解，对方已经公开道歉并赔偿损失，当事人会将赔偿金捐赠给流浪猫狗公益项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一起爆料的真实性则存在争议。10月20日，一位微博用户爆料称，武汉凤凰花园小区物业于10月19日晚打死“三只4个月大的小狗和一只怀孕的猫妈妈”，附上了“凶手”保安、几只猫狗尸体照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月25日晚间，凤凰花园小区物业一位工作人员对南方记者表示，打狗一事属于讹传。真实情况是有多名小区业主投诉流浪猫狗吠叫扰民，于是物业组织保安对流浪动物进行驱离，而非扑杀。物业已于10月20日上午拨打110报警，向江夏区藏龙岛派出所民警备案，重申没有捕杀流浪动物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被“曝光”后，小区物业短时间内接到大量电话，有的“接起来就骂，说我们不是人”，影响了物业工作正常开展。南方周末记者拨打了其中一些号码，多数人表示，自己是在小红书、微信群而非微博上看到的爆料信息。目前小红书已找不到相关资讯，可能已被爆料者删帖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有微博博主利用识图软件辨识发现，有多起网传捕杀流浪狗的新闻实属“旧闻”或移花接木。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的伤害流浪动物新闻已得到证实。10月21日，四川科技职业学院通报学生宿舍内宰杀流浪狗事件：给予两名学生留校察看处分，已报警移交公安机关处理；搜狐千里眼报道，江苏镇江一居民在小区遛狗时发现草坪被投放大量疑似塞了药粒的“毒火腿”，小区内已有流浪猫误食死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;警惕“踢猫效应”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;钱叶芳认为，在庞杂的流浪动物死亡新闻中，除了区分真伪外，还有必要对行为性质进行界定：政府主管部门组织的捕获、收容以及后续的无害化处置，与个人对流浪动物的“私刑”处决乃至手段残忍的虐杀行为不可同日而语。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱叶芳从2018年开始关注流浪动物问题。在她观察中，每当出现狗咬人的事件，网络上也会随之掀起一股支持扑杀流浪动物的声浪。除了各方观点本身存在分歧外，钱叶芳认为，舆论场中还存在一些猫狗肉或虐待动物产业链的从业者在搅混水、带节奏，使得鼓励极端的声音不时占据上风。这其实是强者欺凌弱者——“踢猫效应”在社会情绪中的表现。比如一个人在单位里被老板批评了，回到家就把郁闷的情绪发泄到妻子身上，妻子再发泄到孩子身上。孩子的怒火无处发泄，出门看到一只猫，就上去踢了一脚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/9c19b8a38a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/9c19b8a38a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年6月18日，河南郑州，第32届“郑州领养日”线下公益活动举行，志愿者们为流浪猫狗寻找新家。视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和食用动物不同，猫狗作为伴侣动物，在有的国家和地区获得了免于被屠宰的特殊的法律保护。流浪动物问题上看似水火不容的两派也有共识。例如，钱叶芳一直呼吁出台《伴侣动物保护和管理法》，其中管理的重点就是文明养犬，既可以减少人犬矛盾，也可以从源头减少流浪动物的产生，利于动物福利。如果将流浪狗与流浪猫相比较，具体的处置流程又有所不同。与流浪狗相比，流浪猫伤人的风险相对不高，“所以虐杀流浪猫的行为没有法律的制度支撑，也没有道德、传统的支撑，是一个赤裸裸的暴行”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是流浪猫繁殖能力强，可能对鸟类等小型野生动物形成威胁。抓捕-绝育-放归（TNR，Trap Neuter Release）模式是目前推广的实践，在钱叶芳的TNR实践中，她还摸索出了一条低成本开展流浪猫绝育的路径：和附近的宠物医院合作，在社区宠物家长群里给医院做爱心宣传，作为回报，医院每月能够免费进行两例绝育手术，超过两例的则按照母猫100元、公猫50元来收费，非常低廉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（文中除钱叶芳外，其他皆为化名。南方周末记者黄思琪对本文亦有贡献。）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[斡旋巴以人质危机，卡塔尔凭什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259537]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 17:03:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;巴以冲突已持续三周，双方空袭不断，但有关人质释放的消息接连传来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当地时间2023年10月23日，拉法口岸，两名被哈马斯关押的以色列老年人质被移交给以色列国防军。被释放前，她们已经在加沙地带被扣押了17天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这是哈马斯释放的第二批人质。 10月20日，同样是在加沙边境地带，哈马斯释放了一对来自美国的母女朱迪思·拉南和娜塔莉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“人质问题让内塔尼亚胡左右为难，以色列想要彻底消灭哈马斯，并在加沙建立新秩序，而哈马斯则将劫持的人质作为谈判筹码，试图干扰以色列的地面进攻计划。”在复旦大学中东研究中心研究员邹志强看来，双方仍在持续的博弈之中，妥协难度极大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得一提的是，连续两批人质释放，卡塔尔都从中斡旋。在两名美国人质获救后，美国总统拜登公开对卡塔尔表示谢意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月25日，卡塔尔首相兼外交大臣穆罕默德再度就人质谈判进展进行回应。他表示，谈判仍在积极进行中，双方已有一些进展和突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在风云突变的巴以冲突中，海湾小国卡塔尔游走于烽火之间，就人质问题展开斡旋。人们不禁好奇：为何是卡塔尔这个“弹丸小国”？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;”释放的人质具有针对性“&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;深沉的夜色中，在哈马斯士兵陪同下，两名女性人质被移交给身穿红十字国际委员会制服的工作人员。两名哈马斯士兵脸蒙黑色面纱，手持钢枪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在离开之前，其中一名人质转身与哈马斯枪手握手告别，并说道“Shalom”。在希伯来语中，“Shalom”意指“和平”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月23日晚间，哈马斯分享了一段人质释放的视频。视频中被释放的两名人质分别是79岁的努里特·库珀和85岁的约奇里·利夫希茨，她们居住在以色列尼尔奥兹基布兹，那里紧邻加沙边境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月7日，哈马斯发起“阿克萨洪水”行动，1200名哈马斯武装枪手越过边境，对以色列南部发动袭击，并卷走了大批人质。库珀和利夫希茨也在被绑架的人质之列，一同被绑的还有她们的丈夫，目前仍被扣留在加沙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以色列军方称，被哈马斯扣押在加沙地带的人质为222人，“绝大部分还活着”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“事实上，通过突袭以色列，哈马斯的主要军事目标已经实现。绑架人质主要是为了让以色列有所顾忌，方便以后讨价还价。”邹志强分析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据利夫希茨的讲述，被绑架后，她被带进加沙地下一个巨大的隧道网络，那里“看起来像蜘蛛网”。她们和哈马斯守卫吃同样的食物——皮塔饼、奶酪和黄瓜。为了确保人质健康，每隔两三天就会有一名医生来查看他们的身体情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当被问及为何与枪手握手时，利夫希茨表示，劫持者对她很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;按照哈马斯的说法，人质释放是出于“人道主义原因”。但在受访专家看来，哈马斯释放人质，兼具施压和展现妥协姿态的双重目的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“在以色列持续空袭和大兵压境的双重压力下，哈马斯正在寻找时机，以释放人质为要挟，换取以色列军事上的让步。”邹志强指出，“截至目前，所释放的人质均为非战斗人员和女性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得注意的是，哈马斯释放的第一批人质为美以双重国籍，她们来自芝加哥。被俘时，两人正在以色列探亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“哈马斯选择释放的人质具有针对性。”中国社会科学院西亚非洲研究所研究员余国庆告诉南方周末记者，“哈马斯寄希望于美国尽可能向以色列施压，使其在地面军事行动中保留一定余地。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月18日，拜登踏上访以之旅，除了表示对以色列的坚定支持之外，拜登还和以色列总理内塔尼亚胡讨论了人质问题。拜登强调，确保美国人质安全回国是其首要任务。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但时至今日，仍有包括11名美国人在内的几十名外籍人士被扣留在加沙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“目前，人质是哈马斯与以色列对抗中最有价值的筹码，在双方实力不对称的情况下，哈马斯将充分利用这张牌打开局面。”余国庆分析，“什么时候释放人质，一次释放多少，哈马斯并不会听命于卡塔尔。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;合适的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;调解&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;者&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;哈马斯突袭以色列以来，加沙地区遭遇火箭弹无情炮轰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月25日晚间至26日凌晨，以色列国防军对加沙地带发起一次大规模地面进攻，24小时内进行了约250次空袭。内塔尼亚胡在电视讲话中称，“我们正向哈马斯倾泻地狱之火……而这仅仅是刚开始。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而距加沙千里之外的卡塔尔，则在巴以冲突之后变得热闹起来，各国政要纷至沓来。急匆匆出访卡塔尔的既有美国国务卿布林肯，还有法国总统马克龙的黎巴嫩问题特使。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;各国政要齐聚卡塔尔，人质问题成为一个绕不开的话题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;加沙是哈马斯的大本营，哈马斯将人质分批隐藏在庞大的地下隧道内。 “我们没有加沙每栋房屋和街道的具体数据。”在以色列军事情报系统工作了20年的迈克尔·米尔斯坦警告说，“这是以色列历史上遇到的最困难的人质局势。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;解救人质难上加难，斡旋成为人质获取自由的重要途径。在此背景下，卡塔尔国际调解者的独特角色愈加凸显。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;总部设在日内瓦的阿拉伯和地中海世界研究中心主任哈斯尼·阿比迪指出，“斡旋者并不多，而卡塔尔是最合适的调解者。这个小国没有自己的地区议程，也不关心调解的政治用途。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“卡塔尔财大气粗，而且交际广泛，长袖善舞，与美国和哈马斯均保持密切往来，这为其斡旋人质危机，提供了独特的优势。”余国庆表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;卡塔尔是美国18个“重要非北约盟友”中的一员。位于卡塔尔首都多哈西南35公里的乌代德空军基地，是美国驻海外最大军事基地之一，也是美国中央司令部的前沿指挥中心，部署着大约1万名美军和100架军机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年，美国从阿富汗仓皇撤军，乌代德空军基地就承担着“中转枢纽”的角色。据统计，美国从阿富汗撤出12.3万人，其中约5.7万经卡塔尔中转。事实上，美国和塔利班的撤军协议，本就是在多哈达成的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“在背靠美国之余，卡塔尔还与哈马斯、真主党等西方国家眼中的&#39;激进组织&#39;密切往来。”余国庆说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;卡塔尔是哈马斯重要的经济支持者，为加沙提供了大量的援助、投资、人道主义和基础设施建设。法国国际关系与战略研究所副所长迪迪埃·比利翁指出，卡塔尔每月向哈马斯提供3000万美元的财政支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;卡塔尔不仅与哈马斯在经济上保持密切往来，而且在政治上提供庇护。 2012年，卡塔尔埃米尔哈马德·本·哈立法·阿勒萨尼访问加沙。这是哈马斯2007年夺取加沙控制权之后，第一位到访该地区的国家元首。也是从2012年起，哈马斯领导人开始长驻多哈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在美国及其敌对势力之间两边周旋，卡塔尔的角色看似矛盾，实际上离不开美国的“包容”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“美国的中东战略具有内在缺陷，一方面，美国希望依托盟友体系实现中东意图，但另一方面，其拉一派打一派的做法又制造了形形色色的敌人，尤其是各种次国际组织和非国家武装团体。”邹志强分析，“当美国无法用武力压制来达到外交目的时，就必须找一个中间人从中斡旋，卡塔尔扮演的正是这样的关键角色。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;卡塔尔的雄心&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;卡塔尔三面环海，南部陆地与沙特阿拉伯接壤，似一叶扁舟停靠在波斯湾西海岸。与国土形状相似，在国际外交中，卡塔尔亦如同一艘“快速而灵活的小船”，在不同势力之间周旋平衡，扮演着传话人和调解者的角色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;积极斡旋巴以人质危机，只是卡塔尔扮演国际斡旋“热心人”角色的一个缩影。短短一个多月时间，卡塔尔已连续三次周旋，积极充当人质解救、换囚等活动中间人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月16日，卡塔尔政府宣布，在持续数月的调解之下，俄罗斯同意释放四名乌克兰儿童，他们将通过卡塔尔驻莫斯科大使馆，采取不同路线返回乌克兰。卡塔尔官方在声明中称，四名儿童遣返“只是第一步”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月18日，美伊正式交换五名分别被关押在美国和伊朗的囚犯，而换囚的地点恰恰是在多哈。实际上，这场谈判能够成功，离不开卡塔尔的斡旋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据公开报道，美伊之间的谈判是在多哈进行的。谈判中，双方代表互不见面，分别待在不同的酒店，而中间人卡塔尔则两边奔跑，扮演传声筒的角色。经过至少八轮隔空谈话，美国和伊朗最终达成换囚协议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;卡塔尔国土面积仅有约1.15万平方公里，总人口为300万。这样一个小国，为何能够频繁活跃在国际舞台上，在重大冲突事件中发挥远超自身体量的作用？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“20世纪90年代，卡塔尔就将&#39;外交立国&#39;战略写入宪法，此后一直采取多面下注的策略，在各个势力之间周旋平衡。与此同时，卡塔尔具有极其丰富的石油和天然气资源，雄厚的财力为卡塔尔的外交战略提供了有力支撑。”余国庆分析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;受访专家学者均告诉南方周末记者，卡塔尔“小国大外交”战略既是出于自身生存的需要，更暗藏着巨大的外交雄心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中东地区矛盾交织，冲突多发。 “夹杂在地区大国之间，卡塔尔不愿意被动受制于人，在不同势力之间选边站队。出于安全考量，卡塔尔寄希望于通过外交斡旋的高调方式，换取相关国家提供保护，以确保自身国家安全和政治安全。”邹志强表示，“事实上，卡塔尔之所以不怕引火烧身，很大程度上是因为背靠美国这棵大树。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“更为关键的是，以&#39;大外交&#39;的姿态在地缘危机事件中奔走斡旋，可以进一步凸显卡塔尔的地区重要性和国际影响力。”邹志强进一步说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;然而，卡塔尔并不是完全唯美国马首是瞻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;巴以冲突以来，美国力挺以色列，但卡塔尔并没有完全跟随美国的脚步。相反，卡塔尔外交部谴责称，以色列对局势持续升级负有全部责任，国际社会迫切需要阻止以色列违反国际法的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“卡塔尔有自己的考量，不会完全跟着美国的利益走。”邹志强指出，“采取多面下注战略在不同势力之间周旋平衡，而不是一边倒地投靠大国或跟随盟友，是卡塔尔扮演中间人角色的重要基础。只有长袖善舞，卡塔尔才能有更大的斡旋空间。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但这样的平衡外交并非没有风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2017年6月，以沙特为首的多个中东北非国家指控卡塔尔政府“支持极端势力、介入他国内政、制造区域不稳定局势”，突然宣布同卡塔尔断交，并对卡塔尔实施了关闭边境和空域等禁运和封锁措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;断交危机持续了将近四年才结束。直到2021年1月，沙特等国才宣布与卡塔尔达成和解，正式恢复全面外交关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[应该关掉各种班级群，给家长“减负”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259533]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，湖北襄阳市诸葛亮中学七年级一位老师在批改作业时给学生评语“全班最差，你是孤儿吗”，然后还拍照发在“七年级9班”微信群中。随后，当地教育局通报批评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老师骂出这个话，当然显得没有师德。这件事真正的问题在于，老师真的认为，批改学生作业，教学生文化课，是家长的事。她真的对家长很愤怒：“你们怎么不教孩子，不给孩子批作业？”她之所以这样骂，不是在骂学生，而是在骂家长，给家长施压。实际上，在现在的教育当中，这样认为的老师，绝不是她一个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这才是这次偶然事件背后的必然因素，这才是真问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还记得我小时候，老师布置家庭作业，都是下课的时候，老师在黑板上写，我拿着书圈出来，或者在本子上记住。这是每个同学都能完成的事。回家就做作业，不会的可能会问，也可能会留着不做，父母可能会签个字，但肯定不会一道题一道题地审核作业做对了没有。第二天交作业，老师会批改。错了，要求改，和第二天的作业一起交。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现在一切都变了。辅导作业、批改作业成了家长的事。老师每天在群里布置作业，家长看到了，按照要求辅导孩子完成。虽然教育部也三令五申不准给家长布置作业，但效果并不大。老师仍然会布置，家长仍然需要辅导作业、批改作业，上课。这当中，互联网化的家校联系，起到了很大的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使用互联网、智能手机进行家校联系，当然有很多好处。老师和家长可以随时进行沟通，不受时间和地点的限制，方便快捷。老师可以在群里布置作业，免得学生遗忘，还可以发布学生的学习情况、完成作业的情况、考试成绩等，家长也可以及时了解孩子的学习状况，然后及时向老师反馈。总之，通过微信群、QQ群、钉钉群等平台，家长和老师可以更好地互动，共同参与孩子的教育过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，任何事物的好处与坏处，其实在于目的。如果目的转换了，优势就可能变为劣势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各种家校群，发错消息之类隐私问题，都不算大事。关键的问题是，这些互联网渠道是一个高效地把压力、工作从老师分摊给学生家长的渠道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人说，以前的爱情很美，一封情书寄出去要反复等待，落后虽然落后，但却是浪漫的。而现在，微信联系时刻不停，让很多人觉得没有自己的空间。电影《手机》里就说：手机原来就是为了方便人的，没它的时候，人挺自由，有了它，人成风筝了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;渠道是会影响到内容的，工具是会影响到行为的。高效的电子渠道，把家长逼得无处可逃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前，家长可以说：孩子回家没说，我不知道。现在，家长没了这个空间，老师就会把压力全部转移到家长身上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老师是群主，某种程度上是一个小组织的领导，老师一对一和家长沟通的时候，相对会平等一些，但在群里沟通，老师会有很多支持者。老师在群里表扬谁，批评谁，就会在班级形成压力，然后这个压力传导给家长，给孩子。此次事件，老师也是拍照发在群里，肆无忌惮地给家长施压。这都会迫使家长去辅导孩子，加大对孩子学业的压力，最终形成较重的学业负担。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，反过来，当微信群、QQ群过多，也会给老师造成很大的压力，给他们增加一些额外的工作，增加他们的工作负担。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;降低家校联系的频率和方便程度，可以降低老师向家长传递的任务和压力。显然，如果没有电子渠道，没有群，老师也不可能一个一个地给家长打电话布置作业。这些工作、压力回到老师身上，老师也无法完成，最终，学生的学业负担就降低了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许有人会担心，没有高效的沟通、互动渠道，孩子学习下降怎么办？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，从大的政策层面，这个选择已经完成。有人认为，在落实“双减”改革的过程中，一方面要“减轻过重的学业负担”，多一些户外活动，少一些家庭作业；另一方面要“学好”，要让孩子们在兴趣盎然的状态下学得更多、更快、更好，不能把“减负”简化成“减轻学业”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种鱼和熊掌皆要的策略，从态度上是非常安全的，两边都不得罪，两边都要，对后果不承担任何责任。孩子负担仍然重，是因为要“学好”；孩子学得不好，是因为要“减负”。有改变，是因为要“减负”，没改变，是因为要“学好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鱼和熊掌不可能皆得。对大多数人来说，学习需要大脑高强度运作，学得越多，这个高强度运作的时间就越差。小学、初中的学生要减负，只有降低学业标准。实际上，现在很多地方的中考都降低了区分度，大家成绩考出来都差不多，这就是降低学业标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人认为，这会驱动家长让孩子不断去刷题，提升熟练度，但实际情况未必如此。一些人对于回报减少的策略，就是减少投入。比如，以前吃大锅饭，拼命干也能提拔、当劳模，但大多数人在这种不成比例的投入、产出面前，都会选择躺平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有群建立紧密的联系，的确可以加强学业，但与此同时，会带来家长负担过重的问题。既然政策大目标是“减负”，那么，就不应该通过给家长“加负”进而给孩子“加负”，此时通过群建立家校紧密联系的优势，也就变为劣势了。那么，减少家校联系频度，关掉各种班级群，乃至禁止互联网化家校联系，就是一个合乎逻辑的选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[通向世界的小作坊]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259455]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/d1QYAQWbkA9N7KOCeuSnuYX6WDwwSJcgAEI1NnpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/d1QYAQWbkA9N7KOCeuSnuYX6WDwwSJcgAEI1NnpD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;义乌城郊，在小作坊里干活的年轻人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摄影师王士杰的家乡宁波北仑，北面近海处是一片宁波港的港区。每天，无数集装箱从四面八方汇入北仑港，再从北仑港出发，流向世界各地，其中包括来自义乌的集装箱。无论经济景不景气，义乌的货总是照常到来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/kAfQ0GjaKoFiMwi6I5tlvS628UMPFD29e8F1uvPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/kAfQ0GjaKoFiMwi6I5tlvS628UMPFD29e8F1uvPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;工作台上堆积着大量的假发&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年春夏，经历过一轮严格的新冠疫情管控后，摄影师对源源不断生产出来的义乌货品产生了好奇，从北仑来到义乌。在水泥粉刷、红砖堆砌的家庭式作坊里，他看到了民间小商品经济的韧性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小作坊集中在城郊，样貌与市区恢弘大气的商贸城之间隔了几十年：一间老屋，几张台面，几排简易机器就是一个工厂。为了最大限度地利用屋内空间，原本的隔断墙和里屋门被拆掉，站在门口能一眼看到里屋的角落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/n1966CPc0LEncXp5tBurIuXC8FdJNTCu8HPIsCob.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/n1966CPc0LEncXp5tBurIuXC8FdJNTCu8HPIsCob.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;小作坊的员工住在10平米左右的小屋里，阿俊的下铺挂着彩灯&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里生产的物品五花八门，大多是廉价的小物件，类似洗漱包、手提袋、塑料垫、派对假发。它们工艺简单，只需要重复的手工劳动，所以只要价钱合适，工厂随时能更改制作的产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pEhw5O5jFmnmy2ec1iFGHrwXdhrSfjXIWm136uHd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pEhw5O5jFmnmy2ec1iFGHrwXdhrSfjXIWm136uHd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一个小作坊的工作台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初的小作坊是家庭式的，一家人一起做工，生意好了，便扩张成小作坊。同样大小的地方，城郊的房租只有市区的一半。有的小作坊在商贸城或者宾王市场有店面，能直接面向国际市场接触客源；没有门店的作坊主要靠亲友间的人情网络接单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;义乌吸引了大量的外地人到这里“讨生活”。大多数家庭式作坊的成员以外乡人为主，即使是义乌本地人经营的作坊也会雇佣外地打工者。一些外地打工者也更愿意在小作坊做工——在工厂领工资，要仰赖厂里的收益，行情不好的时候，工资就不好拿；碰上急用钱的时候，工厂也难以单独关照到一个人的生活问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vgfrqyuxn10VSwiXRFOpd5NqCI9quTBKM3dh0WlU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vgfrqyuxn10VSwiXRFOpd5NqCI9quTBKM3dh0WlU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;制作皮带的作坊墙上写满各种数据&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新冠疫情防控期间，作坊的工人戴上口罩继续做工，生活不停，手上的活也不能停，一天工作12个小时，能挣上两三百元。这样的忙碌一直持续到过年前，年轻人裹紧大衣，戴上围巾帽子，在透着寒风的砖房里，为寄回家中的钱增加几张数额。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/gBadLZGEdobkD7NPsXlwAVQeyvSwHwkKcIP6gY8S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/gBadLZGEdobkD7NPsXlwAVQeyvSwHwkKcIP6gY8S.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电视上正播放新闻&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作坊工人的生活单调重复，一天中醒着的时间几乎都在干活。摄影师想和年轻的工人们聊聊天，但他们无暇搭话。他们有着怎样的个性，喜好什么，无从知晓。只有指甲上蓝色的甲片和眼睛上的假睫毛、床罩里挂起的彩灯和明星海报、工位边的墙上涂鸦，掀开了他们内心世界的一角。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Cs7bu8mvUm2x8XieJgkB3NPy59bFDkIxFOefWU4d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Cs7bu8mvUm2x8XieJgkB3NPy59bFDkIxFOefWU4d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;云南的阿俊和广西的小林&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pWLsQYXIb4ZW50Dve5duSumv0Maonby4U4dOKbo6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pWLsQYXIb4ZW50Dve5duSumv0Maonby4U4dOKbo6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;小霞是制衣小作坊负责人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/hUWexWEnySSwa92KttSYkpKNMRthlW7ZtkBvcjPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/hUWexWEnySSwa92KttSYkpKNMRthlW7ZtkBvcjPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;来自四川的小董是制作皮带的熟练工&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/k2eYP485HTWTUol5Eedk3FeAQMGiKyF7lnoiBTpA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/k2eYP485HTWTUol5Eedk3FeAQMGiKyF7lnoiBTpA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;来自四川的小蓉在制作漆包线的小作坊里工作&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ecM1mf66ENbdCdCEaDuhtwKJDOTDJOkVSnUnPbcm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ecM1mf66ENbdCdCEaDuhtwKJDOTDJOkVSnUnPbcm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;来自安徽的小周和小林在给塑料袋封口&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GXa36oex5baZe2bcfOjyi0ttnXknSJcPmEwqLQYb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GXa36oex5baZe2bcfOjyi0ttnXknSJcPmEwqLQYb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;作坊的女青年精心装扮，准备约会&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王士杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国产科幻剧，走向成熟的一次试错]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259515]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;爱奇艺旗下的“迷雾剧场”，由于诞生过一批高质量悬疑剧，为剧迷所推崇。虽偶有失手，但因黑色质感和悬疑氛围到位，令剧集总体保持在及格线以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，该栏目推出的新作《仿生人间》，却招致不少批评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1919&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《仿生人间》的幕后班底并不差，总导演陈正道近几年颇为活跃，执导过《爱很美味》《盛夏未来》等口碑不错的影视剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1573&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外两位导演——柯贞年和许肇任，也都有佳作傍身，前者在2020年执导的《无声》，是聚焦残疾人遭遇性侵的话题之作；后者执导的《有生之年》，豆瓣高达8.9分，剧迷争相入坑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋威龙的颜值，文淇的灵动气质，也让《仿生人间》的卖相看起来不差，加之刘琳、刘丹等出圈老戏骨的加持，很难让人相信这部剧会扑得如此厉害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《仿生人间》是科幻题材。剧集一开始就交代了故事背景，未来不久，人类在基因编辑技术上突飞猛进，创造出和人类几乎一样的仿生人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唯一的差别在于，仿生人被植入了“初始执念”，或是成为至死不渝的爱人，或是变为听话懂事的孩子，只有通过特殊药剂，才能检验出仿生人与众不同的眼睛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255887&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仿生人的大规模出现，引发了一系列极端事件，让各国不得不改变策略，将仿生人重新召回处理。而唯一有能力调查和甄别仿生人身份的，便是“明眸”组织。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;剧集的主要内容，便讲述了宋威龙饰演的男主角程诺，作为“明眸”的调查员，不断侦破和仿生人相关的犯罪案件。由此，剧集用六个单元故事，呈现了仿生人和普通人之间的悲欢离合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255886&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在叙事模式上，它类似于《猎罪图鉴》《重生之门》，以主人公的特殊技能，串联起一桩又一桩奇诡案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;剧集的暗线，则是仿生人遭遇连环谋杀。程诺在调查时，也察觉此案和母亲意外坠楼有关，由此掀开了一起惊天秘密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;单纯从每桩案件折射的人性悲剧而论，《仿生人间》尚且可圈可点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255885&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘琳饰演的母亲陈心慧，对儿子方愿缺少陪伴，于是便定了一位和自己长得一模一样的仿生人，在工作繁忙时照顾儿子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没想到的是，陈心慧对方愿的严苛态度，到了仿生人眼里，就是恶意伤害。后者开始处心积虑，模仿陈心慧的言谈举止，并最终取代了陈心慧，甚至将她囚禁在地下室。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一次意外，陈心慧逃出了地下室，想从仿生人手中夺回儿子，却在厮打之中，死于仿生人之手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一直被蒙在鼓里的方愿，这才明白性情大变的母亲，原来是个仿生人，而为了不失去这“另一位母亲”，方愿向程诺等人谎称，是他失手杀了人，而被害者是仿生人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开篇的这桩吊诡案件，将陈心慧作为母亲的无奈和凄凉、方愿作为儿子的挣扎和孤独、仿生人作为中间者的良善与极端，都刻画得悲怆动人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255888&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘琳在此一人分饰两角，毫无捉襟见肘之态，娴熟地拿捏住陈心慧先冷漠后愤怒的心理变化，仿生人的先讷后疯批的性格差异，她出场时间虽短，但给人留下深刻印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种单元故事带来的情绪触动，还体现在仿生小女孩和养父母间令人动容的亲情羁绊中，也出现在孤独水手和仿生恋人之间甜蜜浪漫，但最终以悲剧收场的故事里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255889&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这当然是国产剧的擅长之处，从中诞生过很多热门剧。只是《仿生人间》只顾着强行催泪，忘记了夯实科幻设定的地基，在悬疑铺垫上也荒腔走板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一部科幻剧，除了开头部分交代了未来背景，正片的服道化风格，直逼现代都市犯罪剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“明眸”组织内部的开会场所，如同简单装修的办公室；城市外的犯罪现场，像极了等待拆迁的棚户区。用《银翼杀手》的“赛博朋克”风格来要求，或许显得过分，但以《相对宇宙》《使女的故事》这类科幻硬度稍软的剧集作为比照对象，就完全能凸显本剧在造景上的敷衍态度了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255891&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如若放大到科幻设定的细节，《仿生人间》的缺陷也很多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在类似设定的电影《人工智能》里，我们通过斯皮尔伯格的镜头，窥视到机器人们的悲惨遭遇。用之即弃，被污蔑成杀人犯，被当作垃圾处理，以及被架上刑场，供人类发泄仇恨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《仿生人间》用只言片语交代了偷渡行迹，以不到十分钟的转场，暗示普通人消费仿生人的皮肉相。但这些可怜巴巴的黑色一隅，大多语焉不详，遮遮掩掩，无法给我们提供一个清晰的视角，了解仿生人不为人知的世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255892&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你看不清一个群体遭受的苦难，你又怎能对其全然共情，恻隐相待呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说白了，科幻设定只是《仿生人间》的某种策略，用国产剧中极为少见的元素，试图挖掘被重复多次的人性母题。这也解释了，本剧不但在科幻层面左支右绌，于悬疑桥段也极难扣人心弦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程诺和文淇饰演的女主角安秋，调查杀害仿生人的连环真凶。这一过程里，程诺逐渐发现了安秋的真实身份，后者也在仿生人同类的洗脑下，逐渐迷失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255893&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程诺从一个对仿生人怀有偏见，嫉恶如仇的调查员，最终显露真面目，变成曾失手杀害过仿生人的灰色人物，这其中的性格变化，前后反差，我们几乎看不到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面是宋威龙稍显稚嫩的演技，让他无法细腻把握；另一方面，则是剧情设定有问题，悬念的铺排和揭秘，过于依靠李鸿其饰演的反派尹天宏在高潮部分自说自话了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于安秋从一位看似平常的心理师，变成全剧最关键的角色，同样被揭开得太早，也太草率了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在第六集最后，也是整部剧的中段部分，我们就从安秋和尹天宏的对手戏里，得知了谜底。甚至在这之前的不少桥段，也都拙劣地透露过安秋的真实身份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要知道，《仿生人间》最大的两个谜团，便是程诺失手杀人，和安秋乃是仿生人。这两个谜团，关涉到男女主角的情感撕裂，也折射出人性的幽微复杂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从最终的呈现效果来看，程诺和安秋的和解，更像是“爱情作怪”，没有了仿生人、初始执念等科幻设定所带来的深邃思辨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国产影视剧的科幻作品，已初露锋芒，不管是电影《流浪地球》系列，还是真人剧集《三体》，都是被观众认可的不俗作品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《仿生人间》确实质量不佳，但我更愿将其看作国产科幻剧，走向成熟的一次试错。毕竟，没有足够多的《仿生人间》，哪有更成熟的《流浪地球》和《三体》呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小镇阿姨们想象着法国织的毛线比基尼，真的到了法国]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259464]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIygYcmW1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIyg YcmW1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2023, Hu Yinping went to Paris to participate in the Paris Internationale Art Fair (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;International Paris Art Fair &lt;/span>;), this is her third exhibition in France for Xiaofang’s art project. The piece she brought this time was a knitted woolen bikini, which came from the aunties in the small town in Sichuan where she grew up. Since 2015, Hu Yinping has been customizing wool fabric products from her mother and aunts in her hometown in the name of the fictional French company agent &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;. Nowadays, the aunts imagine a woolen bikini woven from an ocean in France, and finally arrived in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small Sichuan town, the &quot;French company&quot; is the source of imagination for the aunts. They selected their own yarn at the Xiaofang base, mostly green, and initially knitted hats of various shapes. They appeared in the exhibition hall on the Champs Elysées, at the anti-Trump parade in the United States, and at Ireland&#39;s &quot;Cuckold Festival&quot;... …Later, the fabrics became more and more diverse: “Dirty Word Shock Wave” (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;weaves out the curse words that want to scold bad people&lt;/span>;), Pork Shop Aunt The &quot;pig intestines&quot; weaved by each family, the flags of their respective families, and the &quot;banana peels&quot;, &quot;dogs&quot;, and &quot;cactus&quot; weaved to protect the family in the face of danger... In between the busy farming and taking care of the children , these aunts weave their understanding of life with wool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Snow White Dove&quot; Paris Bikini Exhibition&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &quot;Stop it when it&#39;s good.&quot; In 2016, after Hu Yinping completed the first hat exhibition of Xiaofang&#39;s art project at Beijing Arrow Factory Space, a friend advised her because she was worried that the project would lose money. Hu Yinping graduated from the Sculpture Department of the Central Academy of Fine Arts with a master&#39;s degree. She used the income from sculptures sold as &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; as a commercial sculpture artist to subsidize Xiaofang&#39;s production. The original reason for all this was that she wanted to collect her mother&#39;s time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Yinping returned to her hometown in Sichuan and saw that her mother was packed up by two large bags of hats in a year and purchased at a low price. She wanted to buy her mother&#39;s hat, but her mother refused. After returning to Beijing, she asked a friend to play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; and made up the identity of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; as &quot;the Chinese CEO of a French company&quot;. &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; would come forward to buy her mother&#39;s hat at a higher price. She knitted hats as she pleased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are no secrets in the town. The aunts in the town found Hu Yinping&#39;s mother and wanted to join the production of Xiaofang&#39;s project. In the 1990s, silk cutting was once a way for aunts in the town to make money to support their families. After experiencing collective layoffs from state-owned silk cutting factories, most of these aunts became the eliminated urban surplus labor force. Now knitting wool is a way for them to pass the time and earn pocket money. The way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now the Xiaofang project has expanded to more than fifty knitting aunts, including &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, &quot;Snow White Pigeon&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;, &quot;United Nations&quot; and &quot;Standard Configuration&quot; and other five stages of different years. Proposition creation. Behind the creation lies the complex work of the artist. In sharp contrast to the work utopia created by Hu Yinping, is the cruel art market with clearly marked prices that artists face. Until now, the aunts still don’t know the origin of this “French company”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Yinping&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Hu Yinping&#39;s account: &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The aunt is very happy, the artist is very tired&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will be happier every time I go to Paris to organize an exhibition. Because Xiaofang’s project itself has something to do with France. Every time we have a project, we tell the aunties that the French company needs orders, invite the aunties to make it, and then pay the corresponding fees. This French company has always existed in the hearts of the aunties. At the beginning of production, we told our aunts that there was a beach in France and we were going to do a woolen bikini show on the beach. They imagined a beach and made a set of woolen bikinis for themselves and their families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang has a lot of such exchanges and work internationally. This French exhibition is aimed at There are more professional art professionals, corresponding to a large number of curators and museum directors. I also hope that Xiaofang will enter into a deeper and more international exchange and dialogue. To the public, Xiaofang may be a relatively warm story, but to me it is a very specific work. Behind Auntie, our entire team works very rigorously and professionally. Everyone can enter and understand this work in any way of their own, but it itself is the background of contemporary art works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The knitted works of the aunts are all placed in my warehouse in a village near Beijing. Aunts are very happy, but artists have a harder time. Xiaofang&#39;s team of six people needs to handle a lot of specific and trivial tasks. The aunties don&#39;t care. The time for their weaving is not fixed. They choose the threads and take them home to make them, and get some fees from it, whether it is to make money, kill time, or the so-called &quot;thinking&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before I called you just now, I was in contact with the art museum about the transportation and goods for this exhibition. Shan, to integrate all the work of Auntie, we need to do some very specific and serious work. In fact, the workload is quite heavy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For Xiaofang&#39;s project, there are too many times when the economy cannot sustain it. Yang Xiaofang spends every year It costs a lot of money, and I rely on selling sculptures of &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; to support Xiaofang, but last year it started to feel a bit flat. After Xiaofang had an exhibition in Shanghai last year, many people may have known more about Xiaofang. Last year, she actually made a profit of 800 yuan. If it could recycle itself, there would be no need to raise it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now Xiaofang’s new project is to open Xiaofang Bank in a shopping mall in Nanjing. Xiaofang&#39;s works themselves are extremely public. In addition to the dialogue in exhibitions in art museums and galleries, what feedback and possibilities it has when facing the real public is extremely important to us. Because the crowds faced by art museums and galleries are actually screened, but in shopping malls they face the real public and reality, without the protection of an incubator. The concept of this bank is that I hope that the banks of the future will be made of wool, I hope that the currency of the future will also be made of wool, and I hope that the weapons of the future will also be made of wool. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before the 1990s, the entire society was lacking in materials, and wool, as a craft of aunts, could make people The family was fed and clothed, and now the value of the wool had changed. Why are there so many people knitting now? When I held an exhibition in Shanghai last year, some people told me that they would do a lot of knitting during the epidemic. Small fabrics can actually bring you a lot of surprises and feedback, because handiwork itself has healing properties. What you exchange for time is a thing, which is an exchange of the most primitive labor force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s exhibition, I met a girl who imagined her belly when she was pregnant Knitting shoes and clothes for children. I met a diplomat in China who was making some woolen fabrics during the COVID-19 pandemic. She thought she had made an ugly mouse and an ugly little snake. When this silver-haired lady talked about her fabrics, she was as shy as a little girl. I like these things she made so much. , and can feel the warmth and healing in her heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang’s hat has a lifetime warranty. I don’t want it to break after I buy it back. hole, you just throw it away, which is a pity for manual labor. No matter what projects Xiaofang does in the future, it will always include the function of &quot;filling holes&quot;. We will also open hole-filling to the surrounding communities for free, hoping to form this kind of community. It’s not that we throw something away when it’s a little bit broken. I think we all do too much about abandonment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 510&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Auntie knitting bikini&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Surplus labor force in the city, remaining time in the town&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In order to protect my eyesight, most of the wool I gave to my mother was is green. Because green hats don’t have a good connotation in the Chinese context, the aunts still had some doubts when they used green wool to knit various hats. Later, VICE (a new media in the United States) wanted to do an interview for Xiaofang&#39;s art project, and helped find a place to buy cuckolds - St. Patrick&#39;s Day in Ireland. The traditional color of this holiday is green, and ordered a lot of cuckolds for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Ireland, these people wear hats to participate in festival gatherings, and the aunties also see those live photos. very happy. The same thing may have completely different meanings in different cultural backgrounds. I also hope to help aunties realize that the world is very rich. But I think it is more important for them to be happy and make free choices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I returned to my hometown in 2015 and was timid about being close to my hometown. Because I don’t go home very often, I want to know what my mother does on a daily basis. When she placed two large packages of hand-knitted hats in front of me, I realized, oh, she had knitted these two large packages this year and had been purchased by others at a low price. Moreover, the raw materials are too hard on the hands, and the threads are very hard and extremely rough. She doesn&#39;t have the pleasure and happiness of knitting. She just kills time, and this is the only reason left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think it’s better to collect it myself, but my mother won’t let me, so I invite friends Help me play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; of the French company, ask her to make hats, and let her do whatever she wants. In 2015, WeChat was not so popular, and my mother did not have access to WeChat in her hometown. However, because she had to work with &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, WeChat became a work skill that she must master. Because of her work, she learned to surf the Internet and send express delivery. In the past, my father&#39;s name was written on the express delivery because of &quot;Xiaofang&quot;. Later, when she sent express delivery, she always wrote her own name on the express delivery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, we have conducted research on the aunts who participated in the Xiaofang project. Almost all of them are eliminated urban surplus laborers. Women who work in cities are easily eliminated after the age of 55. Work as a delivery person or cleaner in the city. After a certain age, even if you are a nanny with many years of experience, it may be extremely difficult to find a job in a big city after the age of 55. This is the problem faced by these aunts in the process of urbanization. It is very common in the town for aunts who are almost in their fifties to return to their hometowns because they cannot find jobs. They take care of their children. Those with better financial conditions open small shops and knit with wool to earn pocket money in their free time. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the appearance of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;, the aunts have stopped knitting things for other places. In fact, the aunts all have their own jobs and things. Some aunts will definitely not be able to take care of making our things when the farming is busy. They only plant rice and harvest several times a year, with long idle time in between. Some aunts take care of their children at home. After school is free time. There are also some aunts who have their own small shops. When there is no business, she can do Xiaofang&#39;s business. Xiaofang actually fills up the remaining time of the aunts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s third stage &quot;Security&quot;, the aunt at the pork shop first imagined Not sure what to knit. We would guide her step by step. When she was at her busiest, Xiaofang called her and said, &quot;If someone were to rob your pork shop at this moment, what kind of weapons would you use to protect yourself and yourself?&quot; Benefits?&quot; She was holding a large intestine in her hand and said that if he tried to rob me, I would throw the intestine to him. This is a very direct reaction. When she is not busy, we will repeat her own words to her and encourage her to knit this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About Xiaofang, everyone is discussing the aunt&#39;s imagination, which is actually the artist&#39;s imagination supporting their work. Aunts are a group without imagination, but they can be guided. All they have to do is face their true selves and their own lives. I actually know what they are doing every time, but I am still surprised when I see what comes out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, Xiaofang sent me those hat packages made by my mother on weekends. I was very surprised every time I opened the package. This kind of surprise has never happened again. As I was very familiar with my mother, I suddenly discovered that she had a skill that I didn&#39;t know about. I knew that she had always been making hats, but I didn&#39;t know her. It was all fancy and messy and made so many fun things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The aunts still don’t know what’s going on behind Xiaofang. In fact, it’s not that clear whether they know or not. It&#39;s important because they don&#39;t care about it that much, but I don&#39;t want my mother to know. Some time ago, my mother went to Beijing and stayed for nearly two months. We emptied the entire studio of fabrics, leaving not a single yarn. My mother couldn&#39;t stay after playing for a week, so I asked &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; to come to the studio to give her some work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Actually, on my mother&#39;s side, I haven&#39;t given her too many themes. What I collected is not Representational fabrics, or requiring her to use her brain, did not require her to do so. I wish to collect a period of my mother&#39;s life. I want her to be more free and not want her daughter&#39;s business to become her business, which would be too tiring for her. It&#39;s good for her to live for herself. At this age, she should live for herself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;Frozen time, undulating waves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 1990s, my mother and the aunts in the town were Work in the town&#39;s silk-cutting factory. But China&#39;s textile industry also underwent a major reshuffle in the 1990s. At that time, a large number of laid-off workers were formed, including my mother and aunts. Silk cutting means that after the cocoons are cooked in a high-temperature machine, the silk is separated one by one, and the eight silks are wound into a thread. The finished silk is finally shipped to other places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The machines in the factory are always rotating at a constant speed, and people are changing. My mother is on this assembly line. Go to work. My childhood was spent sitting on the big machine in that factory. The aunts would change jobs. One would feed me a bite when eating, and the other would feed me a bite when eating. My entire childhood to elementary school was spent in that atmosphere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of familiarity between people and people is very good, and it is a very important memory for me , later Xiaofang had so many aunts involved, and I felt the familiar intimacy that I felt at that time. When I was a child, my mother’s workplace would give out various benefits, such as a thermos cup and some washing powder. I think this is very good and will make family members have a sense of recognition for her work. We keep this in Xiaofang. got this. In the past few years, we have distributed almost everything to aunties, from cups to fruits, washing powder, pots and pans to all small household appliances. Recently, because winter is coming, we have I bought a lot of quilts for my aunt, and now I don’t know what to give them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I held Xiaofang’s exhibition at Arrow Factory Space for the first time, my friend advised me to “see you soon.” Just take it.&quot; This suggestion is very sincere. As a friend, I advise me to stop the loss in time. But to me, this is not a work. To me, Xiaofang is a very real life scene between me and my mother, so it is not something that I can just accept, even though I know it will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, we all knitted them casually, and I worked hard to collect them. Later I found out that this was wrong. No matter how big a warehouse I rented, it wouldn’t be enough for these dozens of aunts to weave. If they make it, you have to pay. After paying, you have to help them sell the fabrics. Selling requires talent, and I don’t have it. With this talent, how many hats can several art museums sell? This is so cruel. We mainly work in the studio and rarely understand the operating rules of this world economy. In the process of Xiaofang, it was also interesting that we participated in this kind of work very realistically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang&#39;s work is still a very important part of my life. Because actually, for an artist, ten years can produce a lot of works. But Xiaofang and I have a growing relationship together. Xiaofang is implanted into my aunt&#39;s life, and at the same time, she is implanted into my mother&#39;s life and my life. I have also calculated an account. For example, if I make other things, I will also pay the money to the factory and the production unit. But when I pay the aunt, it does not actually form an internal cycle of the art system. Investing this part of the expenses on my aunt, I think, is investing on my own people, which makes me happier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Next month we will go to Mexico to set up an exhibition. Xiaofang has achieved so far, and there are so many reactions from the audience. Some people like it, and some don&#39;t. I&#39;ve used that metaphor from the beginning to now, I&#39;m a toothpick and I&#39;m also an observer. The aunties are jellyfish. I poked the jellyfish with a toothpick, and the jellyfish swayed in different postures in the sea. Whether it is criticism, praise, interviews or exhibitions, they are all part of the butterfly effect in the sea. My job is to watch these reactions and their postures after taking the plunge. Regardless of the posture of the jellyfish or the waves and waves produced in the sea, in my opinion, it is an extremely beautiful thing because it reacts. , rather than something inherently conservative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the future, I hope that many people will show me her works like the diplomat stationed in China. . I hope everyone will not be shy and face themselves bravely. There is really no ugliness in handmade things, they are all extremely high-quality. I want to redefine wool, I want to redefine Xiaofang’s cultural attributes. I am mainly doing this kind of work now, and I am continuing to advance it. In fact, artists work quietly in the audience most of the time. As for being seen or not being seen, what kind of reactions and discussions are caused are all external matters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sichuan is a basin. There is a river over there in our town, which is similar to all small towns in China. The same, a very solid group of people, a very solid time. There are only a few people in the town, but the aunts imagine a French company to do such a thing. I think this thing itself is quite cool. There are a group of aunts in that basin who are thinking about things all day long, and then go about their work in a serious manner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>