<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[公费定向师范生违约屡见不鲜，多集中于工作后]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the Education Bureau of Lufeng City, Guangdong Province issued the &quot;Guangdong Province Publicly Funded Targeted Training of Primary and Secondary Schools in Eastern Guangdong, Western Guangdong and Northern Guangdong&quot; Teacher (directed to Shanwei Lufeng) List of defaulters&quot; has attracted social attention. The list shows that a total of five graduates have failed to fulfill their obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, according to a Nandu reporter’s investigation, it is not uncommon for publicly funded normal college students to default on their contracts in recent years. As a class teacher for the school&#39;s public-funded normal students, Professor Xie Ailei, executive vice president of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Social Development and Education Policy Research Institute of Guangzhou University, said in an exclusive interview with Nandu that although the proportion of defaulters is not large, the number of defaulters is There is an obvious upward trend, and &quot;it is more common to break the contract after working.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, student breach of contract reflects the conflict between personal interests and public interests. If students&#39; personal sense of gain can be increased from policy and other levels, a win-win situation between public and personal interests can actually be achieved. To this end, he suggested that relevant government departments should carry out more &quot;post-incentive&quot; measures on the basis of &quot;pre-compensation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Phenomena: In recent years, there have been more breaches of contract after the announcement of non-performing lists in many places&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is understood that in 2020, the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education, the Office of the Institutional Establishment Committee of the Guangdong Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, and the Guangdong Provincial The Department of Finance and the Guangdong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security issued the &quot;Implementation Measures for the Publicly Funded Targeted Training of Primary and Secondary School Teachers in Eastern Guangdong, Western Guangdong and Northern Guangdong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is mentioned that in order to further accurately supplement rural teachers, optimize the allocation of teacher resources, and improve the overall quality of the teaching team in Guangdong Province, in accordance with the principles of &quot;voluntary registration, selective admissions, public-funded training, targeted teaching, and limited-time service&quot; , every year, we train a group of high-quality teachers in preschool education, special education, primary education (all subjects) and compulsory education for primary and secondary schools in eastern Guangdong, western Guangdong and northern Guangdong in urgently needed subjects such as music, physical education, and art, and train professional teachers for high school students. Teachers with outstanding and profound graduate education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4a95c819d799b760f5145616e3b18e61.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;2144&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4a95c819d799b760f5145616e3b18e61.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254228&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; An investigation by Nandu reporters found that the &quot;Guangdong Province Publicly Funded Targeted Training of Primary and Secondary Teachers in Eastern Guangdong, Western Guangdong, and Northern Guangdong&quot; was released at the end of September this year, and a total of 5 graduates failed to do so. Fulfillment of contract, graduation date is June 2023. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time that Shanwei Lufeng has announced the list of defaulters. In February 2022, 4 graduates failed to fulfill their obligations, and their graduation date will be June 2021; in November, two more graduates failed to fulfill their obligations, and their graduation date will be June 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in September this year, the Education Bureau of Leizhou City, Guangdong Province issued a notice that two people failed to perform their contracts due to personal reasons after graduating in 2023; the other two people graduated in 2022 and served for one year in Leizhou City due to No longer performing the contract due to personal reasons. In October, Chaozhou Chaoan also announced a list of defaulters. Three people failed to perform their contracts due to personal reasons, and their graduation date is June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fbe643db5c234a27039decf97890bc04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;2144&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fbe643db5c234a27039decf97890bc04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254229&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/317238fdb3fc3e6d86f92948bcb54bdc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;798&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/317238fdb3fc3e6d86f92948bcb54bdc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254230&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in recent years, places such as Shanwei Haifeng, Maoming Huazhou, Yunfu Yunan, Qingyuan Liannan and other places have also announced default lists. There are cases where fresh graduates have defaulted, and some have defaulted after working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the survey, public-funded normal school students teach in schools (including village primary schools and teaching sites) arranged by the orientation for no less than 6 years. During the prescribed service period, public-funded targeted training recipients shall not fail to perform the limited-time service agreement on the grounds of further education or transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how much is the cost of default? The &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; clearly state that for those who fail to fulfill the provisions of the agreement during the service period, all localities are responsible for recovering the training funds enjoyed by the public-funded targeted training subjects in accordance with regulations, and collecting liquidated damages based on 30% of the total training funds. If more than 1 Overdue payment penalties will be charged at a rate of 1‰ of the payable fee for each day within the monthly payment time limit. Any breach of contract shall be recorded in the personnel files and social credit system and announced. The default refund funds collected by various localities are specially used to support and subsidize the construction of local primary and secondary school teachers in accordance with the principle of &quot;who manages, who uses, and who is responsible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Analysis: Breach of contract reflects the conflict between personal interests and public interests&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“According to survey research, the proportion of defaults by public-funded normal college students is not large, but the number of defaults is significantly higher. The upward trend has therefore attracted widespread attention from society.&quot; Xie Ailei told reporters that breach of contract can actually be divided into active breach of contract and passive breach of contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the passive side, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; have relevant provisions. If students fail to obtain a graduation certificate or degree certificate within the basic period of study, or their studies are interrupted due to personal reasons (except for physical health or enlistment) If academic and other circumstances arise, &quot;with the approval of the training institution and the place of origin of the plan, the qualification for public-funded targeted training will be cancelled, and the host university will be responsible for handling it in accordance with relevant national regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of initiative, for fresh graduates, they are dissatisfied with the scope, current situation, and environment of the rural teacher job they want to go to after graduation, and hope to pursue a higher-level job unit. Some students also hope to further their studies. And breach of contract. For working graduates, the main problem is that their development demands are not met. Since they have accumulated enough experience and capital, graduates hope to move to better jobs and have enough financial foundation to pay liquidated damages and default. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some public-funded normal school students who are already working are unable to adapt to the actual local work conditions, culture and atmosphere, and leave their posts before reaching the contracted working period. According to investigations, some local competent authorities failed to scientifically predict, rationally plan, and make timely adjustments when formulating the needs of public-funded directional training plans, which led to problems in job matching for public-funded oriented normal school students after graduation, and the phenomenon of &quot;sending teachers wherever there is a shortage.&quot; &quot;Go&quot; and other situations where &quot;teaching profession and job position do not match or do not match&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally speaking, most defaults occur after graduation, and it is more common to default after working for several years.&quot; Xie Ailei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the head teacher of the orientation class, Xie Ailei also observed that not all students knew the actual situation of the project when they first enrolled. &quot;Including the students I teach, some of them were chosen with the help of their parents. They don&#39;t know much about the position of orientation teachers and their future work conditions.&quot; He told Nandu reporters: &quot;I have noticed some trends. Students who have just entered school are At that time, many people paid more attention to the cost and responsibility of breach of contract, but did not fully understand the place where they would work in the future. By the time they are in their sophomore year, students began to be anxious, thinking about what to do when they go back to work, whether there are other options after graduation, etc. In their junior year, students think about what to do if they don’t adapt when they go back, what will happen after six years of orientation, etc.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a sociological perspective, one of the major reasons for breach of contract is that students In the early stage, the reality was not recognized when making choices, and in the later stage, career identity was not fully developed. From the perspective of educational economics, breach of contract actually reflects the conflict between personal interests and public interests, and students cannot be blamed blindly; if it can increase students&#39; personal sense of gain, it can also achieve a win-win situation for public and personal interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Xie Ailei has carried out targeted intervention since the beginning of freshmen&#39;s enrollment. Through regular one-on-one communication, class meetings and other forms, he has popularized the rights and obligations of publicly funded normal school students and the connotation of teachers&#39; work. , future workplace environment, etc., and lead students to conduct surveys of schools in counties in eastern Guangdong, western Guangdong, and northern Guangdong, in order to enhance students&#39; sense of career and job identity. &quot;It has been observed that students who default after graduation mainly leave their jobs, but rarely leave the teaching profession. If schools and teachers can consciously intervene, students&#39; professional identity, career identity, and job identity will have better results.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Recommendation: Implement &quot;post-incentive&quot; measures on the basis of &quot;pre-compensation&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although there is a restriction mechanism at the policy level for defaults. But in Xie Ailei&#39;s view, punishment can only be said to be a cover-up, but it cannot fundamentally solve the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He suggested that students need to think more fully about their career plans and understand the work content and actual working conditions of rural teachers before entering publicly funded targeted projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For training institutions, it is necessary to focus on grasping the key time points in the early stage of volunteer application and increase publicity. After students enroll, colleges and universities must also start from a management perspective. While allowing students to fully master professional skills, they must continue to pay attention to and guide students&#39; career and job identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For local education departments, it is necessary to combine the actual situation of teacher education reform and development, scientifically predict the supplementary demand for teachers in shortage subjects in the basic education field in the region, and reasonably prepare annual public-funded targeted training plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, relevant government departments should also carry out more &quot;post-incentive&quot; measures on the basis of &quot;pre-compensation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, government departments can implement a classified and hierarchical reward mechanism based on the remoteness of the school, environmental conditions, etc. &quot;One of my students did a survey using data from middle school teachers in counties in eastern Guangdong, western Guangdong and northern Guangdong. It was found that the farther the school is from the economically developed areas of the Pearl River Delta, the more teachers want to move. If we look at this situation, is there a difference? A personalized reward mechanism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, rewards will be provided based on the number of years of performance, and more opportunities and preferential treatment policies will be given in terms of professional development and promotion channels to enhance the work motivation of public-funded normal school students. The &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; propose that targets of public-funded targeted training are encouraged to improve their academic qualifications through self-study examinations, correspondence courses, and on-the-job postgraduate studies. Xie Ailei also mentioned that high-level normal universities can be jointly established to establish targeted teacher training collaborative training centers to provide qualified graduates with high-level master&#39;s degrees in education and solve their worries in terms of institutional mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether students can obtain high-quality mobility after they have completed their obligations is also one of the methods worth considering.&quot; Xie Ailei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[原来还有这种工作？那些年轻人的新职业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258686]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/ixlq7CuqiKTEFc36f3raE7dUDrkxpTycW2Xp6LRI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/ixlq7CuqiKTEFc36f3raE7dUDrkxpTycW 2Xp6LRI. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In recent years, many new professions have emerged. In 2019, a &quot;rabbit taster&quot; working for a spicy braised food e-commerce company attracted attention. He tries to eat more than 2,000 rabbit heads every year. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China Pictures/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn, Wang Fei and her party prepared enough dry food and drove through the Gobi Desert for hundreds of kilometers. , there are heavy mountains ahead, no one can be seen, and there is no signal. They need to constantly observe weather changes, calculate the water and oil stocks, and put some dry food along the way when going to the mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The road in the mine was extremely narrow, and the wheels pressed against the edge of the cliff. They almost did not dare to take a big breath. Finally reaching an altitude of 4,500 meters, looking around, all kinds of jade materials are scattered on the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a microcosm of Wang Fei’s treasure hunting process. She is a gem hunter, a profession full of excitement and thrills every day. Her story was recorded in the book &quot;New Careers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data released by the National Bureau of Statistics, in August 2023, the national urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.2%, a decrease from the previous month and the same period last year. In April, the national survey unemployment rate for labor force aged 16-24 was 20.4%, and the youth unemployment rate exceeded 20% for the first time. Nowadays, with the downsizing within the system and layoffs in the Internet, more and more young people are no longer bound to a certain &quot;cubic room&quot;, but are beginning to break away from traditional industries and seek emerging careers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the &quot;2021 New Career Guide for Youth&quot; released by Bilibili and DT Finance showed that 12% of young people are already trying new careers part-time, 5.5% are working full-time, and 58.5% want to try but No action has been taken yet. 78% of young people prefer a new career because it “matches their interests and hobbies.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Taobao Unpopular New Career Observation in 2021&quot; takes stock of the top ten unpopular new careers, namely: doll doctor, dream painter, succulent foster nurse, game face pincher, organizer and storage master, cloud maker , cat food taster, armor caster, live broadcast room set designer, mobile phone embalmer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many new occupations are neither large-scale nor stable enough. For example, the cloud makers mentioned above, they simulate the appearance of clouds, from mold making, shaping, polishing to finished products, are stored in transparent cubes, but there are only a few practitioners. This does not prevent some new professionals from turning their love into a career and exploring a special way of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are some stories from those in new careers:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16 /kushWlXZWxL9CyRbDFg0KGmvYw6jGQv1hxQrJv1P.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;941&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/kushWlXZWxL9CyRbDFg0KGmvYw6jGQv1 hxQrJv1P.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;254138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Henna hand-painted looks somewhat similar to tattoos at first glance, but it is actually hand-painted on the skin with plant pigments. It subsides naturally in about two weeks. After becoming a henna master, Thirteen sometimes encountered strange looks. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Henna Master&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &quot;&lt;/strong >;&lt;strong>;Painted, it doesn’t hurt&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Shisan is often mistaken for a tattoo artist. Because she posted henna hand-drawn patterns in her circle of friends, before renting an apartment, her co-tenant mistakenly thought she was a tattoo artist and made excuses to refuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although they are all painted on the human body, henna hand-painting is actually a paste of plant pigments made from henna flowers that is painted on the skin. It is popular in the Middle East and India and is generally only left on the skin. It will subside naturally after about two weeks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s not written, it&#39;s not posted, it&#39;s painted! It doesn&#39;t hurt!&quot; Shisan deliberately hung a conspicuous slogan on the stall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from high school, Shisan moved around in different cities and lost count of how many jobs he had. She tried Henna hand-painting after being introduced by a friend and earned 2,000 yuan in 4 days. When she practiced most crazily, she painted almost all the places on her body that could be painted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Thirteen has been a full-time henna practitioner for five years. Every night at the market in Shenzhen, she immersed herself in painting, her long blue and red hair standing out among the crowd. Within ten minutes, a henna pattern incorporating vines, flowers and other imagery appeared on the back of the customer&#39;s hand. For her, the most difficult thing is to control the amount of paste squeezed out. If the amount is not appropriate, the lines will not be smooth and beautiful enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A client, an office worker who works in foreign trade, requested that Thirteen be painted somewhere that could be covered by his clothes. Her workplace requires formality. After get off work, she can be herself again and show off her body patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A junior high school student was brought in by his mother. His wrists were covered with self-inflicted scratches, hoping to cover them with drawings. Thirteen drew a cartoon pattern for him and said in a relaxed manner: After drawing such a beautiful pattern, I will no longer be able to scratch myself with sharp objects. The boy agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Occasionally, she would encounter strange people and strange looks. A strange man pointed at the &quot;shrimp line&quot; pattern on her neck and called her scary. Fortunately, Thirteen doesn&#39;t care, &quot;I can&#39;t change myself because of their personal aesthetics.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Organizer&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: “It’s a human home, so what?”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Nannan travels around the city every day Every corner of the house is sorted and summarized for different people. She received professional training from a housekeeping company and needed to organize clothes by category and color, or arrange cosmetics on the dressing table by bottle height. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the storage work is tedious and long, the secrets in those private spaces are nerve-wracking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One night at 11 o&#39;clock, Li Nannan went to a male anchor&#39;s home to do some storage and found that there were plus-size women&#39;s clothes and wigs in the closet. He speculated that he might be dressing up as a woman for a live broadcast. She said that this &quot;atypical living situation&quot; is very interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some houses are unimaginably messy. Once, Li Nannan dug out a large number of express delivery boxes from the corner of the room, and was about to sort them into categories. As soon as he opened the boxes, many squirming bugs, cockroaches and mice crawled out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s all a human home, so what? There&#39;s nothing particularly dangerous. What&#39;s more difficult to deal with is that the client&#39;s unresolved emotions are placed on me. Human situations are not easy to deal with. .&quot; Li Nannan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes customers would quarrel among themselves while they were sorting things out. Li Nannan was used to it and didn&#39;t feel embarrassed. Occasionally, some anger would burn into her, and customers would pick on her for no apparent reason, and the door-to-door collector would become the punching bag for conflicts in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once, a customer blamed her for putting valuables and worthless items together, blaming her for being unprofessional and uninformed. At this time, Li Nannan adheres to the principle of &quot;silence is golden&quot;, talking less and doing more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this job, Li Nannan has seen all kinds of things in the world. A junior high school student asked her to clean up his study room while his parents were not at home. The boy was always at home alone during that summer vacation. After cleaning up, he asked Li Nannan to stay and play games together. Later, Li Nannan went to play with him a few more times, as if he had seen himself as a teenager. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Simulated Pet Customizer&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Keep it with you&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Worked as a veterinarian for two years Chen Ziting has encountered many helpless situations. Facing the anxious faces of pet owners, she found it difficult to ask them to say their final goodbyes to their pets, and sometimes she even cried together. In the long run, it was difficult for her to bear so much sadness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, she began to make simulated pets out of wool felt, making them into pendants, ornaments or keychains. Some were only made for the head of the pet, and some were made for the whole body, which were all made stitch by stitch. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two-thirds of the customers who came to customize their pets had passed away. They took photos of their pets while they were still alive and hoped to use the simulated version as a souvenir. Many owners can&#39;t help crying when they see the appearance of their pets when they receive the express delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A customer customized a head ornament for her Garfield cat. This cat has been with her since graduation. Later, the kitten developed a skin disease, and the owner specially changed his job for him and moved to a drier city. But during one of her business trips, Garfield suffered a heart attack and died suddenly. She drove back overnight to have him cremated. She found Chen Ziting, hoping to keep it with her in another form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ziting also has a cat, and her pet is &quot;like a family member&quot; to her. She understands the owner&#39;s extreme sadness and reluctance after the pet leaves. She hopes that after the tragedy, &quot;there is still something more that can be done for them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Animal Communicator&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;It&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s need to be respected&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Animal communicator Luo Xinyan also tried to do something for these sad pet owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is a Taiwanese living in Guangdong, and her main job is to communicate with animals. In Taiwan, this is a relatively mature profession with specialized industry associations and training courses. Communicators believe that they can communicate with the souls of animals through sounds, images, thoughts, and even tastes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before starting communication, Luo Xinyan usually asks the owner to &quot;predict&quot; to the pet, informing them that a communicator will chat with them, and first obtain basic information and recent photos of the pet. She claimed that this would help the pets cooperate, &quot;I know you are coming to me because my mother said so.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the more special ones is the communication with the deceased pet. According to Luo Xinyan, it usually takes 7-14 days after the death of the pet to make an appointment. In her account, the &quot;conversation&quot; with a deceased puppy went like this:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How are you doing in the animal kingdom (heaven)? What are you doing?&quot; &quot;There is nothing to do. , sometimes it gets a little boring.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do you like the place where the ashes are placed?&quot; &quot;Yes, I also like the color.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An owner&#39;s puppy once died of illness Finally, he anxiously found Luo Xinyan and wanted to know how he was doing after his death and whether he had received the gifts and paper money he had burned. Luo Xinyan said that she explained to the puppy that the pile of soft paper next to it was money given by her father, and she also saw small objects such as balls and dolls. After hearing this, the man of the house excitedly confirmed that he had indeed burned these things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of the puppy, the hostess blamed herself deeply, believing that she had not taken good care of the puppy. Luo Xinyan said that the puppy asked her to convey that it was not their fault that her death was not their fault, so she did not need to worry about it and would live happily in the future. While no one else could hear or verify the authenticity of these conversations, the owners did find relief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Luo Xinyan, every animal is an individual, &quot;with feelings, love, innocence, and tolerance. They need to be respected.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/q9E8eOoBU0sCHOxb7q3GTwinSZbhy94j0vvXe505.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/q9E8eOoBU0sCHOxb7q3GTwinSZbhy94j0vvXe505.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Customers seeking doll restoration are mostly reluctant to throw away the dolls that have been with them for many years and treat them as friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Doll Restorer&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;It is not a toy, it is my friend&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Some people are reluctant to part with their pets, while others place their emotions on the dolls that have been with them for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xiaoxi has a white stuffed rabbit that has been with her for seventeen years. It is only as big as a forearm. As she grew from a child to an adult over the course of seventeen years, the little rabbit&#39;s originally dense plush began to fall away, becoming almost bare in some areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She accidentally saw someone on the Internet who specialized in doll restoration and wanted to send it for restoration, but the high price put her off. When Lu Xiaoxi was a child, she learned a little bit of sewing from her grandmother, and then tried to repair it by herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hair on the rabbit&#39;s mouth, hands, and feet was almost all gone, and the areas that needed to be repaired were large. She repaired them on and off for a month before re-planting the hair in these areas. After that, Lu Xiaoxi started taking orders and repairing dolls as a part-time job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some dolls are severely worn and need hair transplantation, some need to be filled with cotton, and some have just cracked lines and need to be mended. Restoring a doll usually takes a week or two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hair transplantation is the most troublesome. If there is only a small amount of hair loss, you can remove the floating hair from the doll, rub it into a small handful, and then press it back with tweezers according to the grid pattern in the doll. If the shedding is too severe, like her rabbit, you have to buy new wool cloth, pull out the hair and replant it. It usually takes two to three hours to transplant a small area, and the hands will be very painful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xiaoxi likes this new job very much. She feels that dolls carry many memories. Even if the doll is seriously damaged, the owner is reluctant to throw it away. She understands this sentiment very well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A customer once sent a bear that needed repair and included a letter. The letter was written in the tone of a little bear. He said that he had been accompanying his owner for thirteen years and had followed her to many places, hoping to help restore it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They are not toys, they are almost like friends.&quot; Lu Xiaoxi told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/PWA1ql1QbWM9wftp13WP5i6grXgwdrUR7iYcXxSI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/PWA1ql1QbWM9wftp13WP5i6grXgwdrUR7iYcXxSI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Makeup restorer Liu Cheng charges 20-40 yuan per order, and the price is based on the difficulty of the repair, with a monthly income of tens of thousands of yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Makeup Repair Technician&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Twenty yuan per order, monthly income of tens of thousands&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If the restoration of dolls is out of deep emotion, then the customers who repair cosmetics have more practical purposes. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workbench of makeup restorer Liu Cheng is like a laboratory, with sterilization cabinets, lipstick molds, powder compaction plates, films, beakers, etc. As a man who knew nothing about makeup not long ago, he is now familiar with the common brands on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He used to be engaged in real estate, and his entry into the industry was purely accidental. When he had nothing to do during the epidemic, he found that some of his wife&#39;s cosmetics were broken, but it was a pity to throw them away. He tried to repair them several times and the results were good. A few months ago, his wife started taking orders for him online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This job is quite delicate. When Liu Cheng repaired a certain powder earlier, he followed the established steps, but the effect was not very good. Later he discovered that the powder also had a baked texture and different techniques, so the method was certainly not universal. After studying the corresponding texture, it was finally repaired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, makeup repair bloggers are not uncommon. Their business covers a wide range of products, including powder repair, makeup packaging and packaging, lipstick color change, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Liu Cheng&#39;s observation, most of the customers are young college students. Generally speaking, there are women aged 18 to 40, and the market is very huge. Some of the people who patronize makeup restoration are thrifty and frugal, while others do so because the items were given as gifts to relatives and friends and do not want to part with the emotional meaning they carry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Powder powder and lipstick are most often repaired. Powder powder is usually broken and needs to be restored, lipstick may be broken, or the color may be changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Repair is not always smooth. Once to repair lipstick, Liu Cheng reworked it 4 times. In one case, there were still cracks and bubbles after the repair. In another time, the lipstick stuck to the wall of the cup during the melting process. Only a quarter of it was left after repair, so he had to Melted again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Cheng&#39;s repair cost is about 20 yuan per repair, and the more difficult ones cost 30 or 40 yuan. Currently, he can earn more than 10,000 yuan per month. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pet Agent&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Dedicated Talent Scout&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a pet agent, Shuangshuang&#39;s job is to connect brands and pet models, and to find pets of different species through various channels and to find cooperative models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One time while shopping in a shopping mall, she saw a girl walking by with a beautiful border collie. They both immediately chased after her, and it took them three floors to catch up, and successfully got the owner&#39;s contact information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its coat color is a rare three-color meteorite among border collie breeds, its eyes are particularly blue, and its body is not large. They both saw it as a good model at a glance. Moreover, it follows its owner obediently in a crowded shopping mall, which shows that it has good stability and is suitable for studio shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that Shuangshuang, the talent scout, has a good eye. On the day of the shooting, this border collie showed a high degree of cooperation. It only took 13 minutes to complete the shooting of seven different angles and postures, while the average mock-up shooting time for ordinary pets is half an hour to an hour. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shuangshuang is unwilling to disclose the specific price of the pet, which is considered a business secret. She introduced the general market situation. The daily appearance fee of a professional pet model is about 1,000 to 2,000 yuan. However, different pets have different values. If they have outstanding appearance, camera-like appearance, high stability and cooperation, the treatment will be higher. The owner’s easy communication and free time are also bonus points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be a good pet agent, Shuangshuang needs to collect as many varieties of pets as possible. The same variety also needs different colors and sizes. It is best to have three or four pets of the same size and color. If there is an accident during the shooting, you can replace them at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the shooting, Shuangshuang will transform into an assistant, following the pet model at any time to take care of, guide and comfort it. Once when I was on location, as soon as I arrived at the shooting location, the model dog started fighting with other dogs passing by. Together with her colleagues, she &quot;pressed down&quot; her own model and asked someone to quickly take the other one away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surrounding your pets every day makes you both feel happy. When she was feeling down, the dog stretched out its paw to touch her, which made her feel healed. &quot;Every moment was touching.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pet daycare manager&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“It’s like a child going to kindergarten”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Mengyin She likes animals. She has a cat and two dogs, the oldest is eight years old and the youngest is six years old. She has had pets since she was a student, and her time with them has dropped sharply after working. She found that this is also the current situation of most office workers. They leave early and come home late, and their pets can only stay at home by themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She co-opened a dog day care store with her friends, targeting these office workers. During the day, before they go to work, they leave their puppies in the store, &quot;just like children going to kindergarten.&quot; Most parents will apply for one &quot;semester&quot;, which is 30 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the morning, they use the &quot;school bus&quot; to pick up the dogs and send them home in the evening. Dogs usually have breakfast in the store, and they basically bring their own food. The daily &quot;school&quot; schedule is full, such as the afternoon tea session, and different activities are designed. Sometimes they are fed with leaky toys, or snacks are placed on the lawn for them to find and eat on their own. In the evening, Ren Mengyin and her colleagues will take their dogs for a walk by the stream outside the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as each class has students with different personalities, there are also &quot;i dogs&quot; and &quot;e dogs&quot; among dogs. They will &quot;teach students in accordance with their aptitude&quot;. For &quot;i dogs&quot; who don&#39;t like to socialize, what attracts them more is the smell, touch and atmosphere. When they first come to daycare, let &quot;i dogs&quot; slowly observe and adapt to the environment. Some small dogs The dog may find a comfortable place to sun itself. The &quot;e dog&quot; has a cheerful personality and will take the initiative to play with other dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three or four times a month, the daycare store will organize activities similar to autumn outings, taking the dogs to the beach or grassland and playing some circuit games or tug-of-war games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Mengyin always remembers that scene. It was raining once, bamboo leaves were swaying in the rain, and the dogs were sniffing the smell in the air in an area near the outdoors. Seeing this scene, she suddenly felt a sense of accomplishment, &quot;They are satisfied, and it seems like you have nothing else to ask for.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10天涨粉百万，普通青年“于文亮”如何引发热议？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日本知名音乐人谷村新司逝世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to a report by Japan&#39;s NHK TV station on the 16th, well-known Japanese musician Shinji Tanimura in October Passed away on the 8th at the age of 74. It is reported that Shinji Tanimura underwent surgery for acute enteritis in March this year and was hospitalized for treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Tanimura Shinji has been closely associated with China throughout his life. Many well-known singers have sung many of his works, such as Jacky Cheung&#39;s &quot;Distant Her&quot;. The original song of &quot;Distant Her&quot; is &quot;Romantic Railway (Falling)&quot; by Japanese singer-songwriter Shinji Tanimura. The lyrics and music were composed by Shinji Tanimura and was released in June 1985. In the same year, it was adapted and recorded in Hong Kong as the Cantonese version of &quot;The Distant Her&quot;, with lyrics written by Pan Yuanliang, arranged by Tony Lu, produced by Ou Dingyu, and starring Jacky Cheung. After the song was released, it became very popular and became a radio broadcast from the end of 1985 to the middle of 1986. One of the most popular singles, it also became one of Jacky Cheung&#39;s famous early singles along with &quot;Love Is Gone&quot;, &quot;Half Moon&quot; and &quot;Blue Rain&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4630dc403a13077145f08e9a16e4e068.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;796&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4630dc403a13077145f08e9a16e4e068.png&quot; data-key= &quot;254233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to Jacky Cheung, Teresa Teng, Luo Wen, Alan Tam, Anita Mui, Kwan Ching-kit, Tsui Siu-fung, Leslie Cheung, Aaron Kwok, Lai Lai and others have performed his works. He once said that Jacky Cheung and Alan Tam are the Hong Kong friends with whom he has the most tacit understanding. In 1984, he co-founded PAX MUSICA with Zhao Yongbi and Alan Tam, whose Chinese name is &quot;Peaceful World of Music&quot;, aiming to promote cultural exchanges and world peace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/15ae3ba9d860e52f686ac237bc41f4ed.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/15ae3ba9d860e52f686ac237bc41f4ed.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254232 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shinji Tanimura once performed on the same stage as Jacky Cheung. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Tanimura Shinji&#39;s most widely spread famous song is &quot;Pleiades&quot;, which has been adapted into different language versions. The Mandarin version is &quot;Another Kind of Nostalgia&quot; by Feng Feifei (lyrics by Chen Xi) , Jiang Yuheng&#39;s &quot;My Heart Has No Return&quot; (lyrics by Li Ziheng) and Chen Peter&#39;s &quot;Night Journey&quot; (lyrics by Chen Peter), the Cantonese version is Guan Zhengjie&#39;s &quot;Star&quot; and Luo Wen&#39;s &quot;Horn&quot; (both by Zheng Guojiang) Fill in the lyrics). He has also participated in and produced many performances on the friendship between China and Japan, including participating in planning a series of programs such as the large-scale gala celebrating the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Japan at the invitation of the Japanese and Chinese governments. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/f78d0d0c611de340af772974a715afb4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/f78d0d0c611de340af772974a715afb4.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254231&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Shinji Tanimura has visited China many times to sing this song &quot;Subaru&quot;. On March 24, 2008, Shinji Tanimura was awarded the title of Image Ambassador of the 2010 Shanghai World Expo. On September 16, Shinji Tanimura attended the Asia Night concert held at the Beijing Exhibition Hall Theater with singers from 13 Asian countries and regions in response to an appointment in Beijing, and sang his famous representative work &quot;Subaru&quot;. On April 30, 2010, Shinji Tanimura sang &quot;Subaru&quot; at the opening ceremony of the 2010 Shanghai World Expo in China. On June 12, he sang the song &quot;Subaru&quot; again at the &quot;Connect for a Harmonious Future&quot; themed performance held in the Red Hall of the Japan National Pavilion at the Shanghai World Expo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bad225c8659a8d0481aa62d81c50bfdf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bad225c8659a8d0481aa62d81c50bfdf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254234 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shinji Tanimura sang at the opening ceremony of the Shanghai World Expo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Tanimura Shinji devoted his life to music creation and promoting Sino-Japanese friendship. After the news of his death came out, many Chinese fans left messages on his last Weibo post to say goodbye. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fb60057e706d69d13617c15991642a81.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;757&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fb60057e706d69d13617c15991642a81.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254235 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Many Chinese fans left messages on his last Weibo post to say goodbye. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南郸城几百农民哄抢玉米上热搜：维护农业投资者权益不能和稀泥丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258678]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a video of a corn field being robbed by hundreds of nearby farmers in Dancheng County, Zhoukou, Henan became Social media hot spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Beijing News and other media, on October 14, 2023, a video of many farmers &quot;grabbing corn&quot; became a hot search on social media. In the video, a cornfield is crowded with people. The road next to it is filled with tricycles of all sizes, and some cars drive directly into the field. The voice of an eyewitness in the video said that the cornfield totaled 2,000 acres, and hundreds of acres had been robbed. The police could not stop it because there were too many villagers. The video also shows police arriving at the scene. At the end of the video, the local township government staff said that the township chief had arrived to maintain order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The local township government and the Dancheng County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau later denied that looting had occurred, saying that the farmers only went to the harvested plots to &quot;pick up&quot; the missed corn. According to the situation statement issued by the Dancheng County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, there are not as many corn fields as 2,000 acres, only 400 acres. After the company that contracted the land to grow corn contacted the township government, the township government &quot;immediately arranged for village cadres and police station police to go to the scene to maintain order, persuade the people to leave in an orderly manner, and the machine collection work was carried out normally.&quot; In the afternoon of that day, the company&#39;s 400 acres of corn had been harvested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it looting or picking up? Judging from the video, most people are indeed picking corn in the harvested fields. However, according to eyewitnesses, these people did follow the harvester to pick it up at first, but then many people gathered around and the harvester could not move, and many people started to grab it. To take a step back, even if the land has been harvested by machines, can we pick it up immediately? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In rural areas, leakage does exist. This is a good thing and prevents food waste. However, it can only be picked up after the owner harvests it. Nowadays, most people use harvesters to harvest crops, often missing a lot. Under normal circumstances, the owner will manually pick up the leaks again after the machine has finished harvesting. Only the rest can be picked up by others. If you follow the harvester directly to harvest, you will either pick it up or rob it. Judging from the action of the contracting company calling the police, it is obvious that they do not want to see these farmers &quot;picking&quot; corn after the harvester, not to mention that there may be people who run into the confiscated fields to &quot;pick&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the rural population decreases, governments at all levels encourage social capital to transfer land in rural areas for investment and entrepreneurship. However, cases of agricultural entrepreneurs being robbed are seen on the Internet from time to time: college students who return to their hometowns to start a business are robbed by villagers, watermelons are stolen from greenhouses contracted by outsiders, pumpkins are stolen, and peaches and apples are stolen... In short, no matter what Whatever entrepreneurs sow and raise, it can be stolen. Many entrepreneurs are forced to erect barbed wire fences, install video surveillance, and keep a few dogs to look after them. Not only is the cost high, but the results are not good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the robbery incident, the local government will use various excuses to excuse the farmers. Some, like in Dancheng, Henan, said that farmers did not steal, but &quot;picked up&quot; and picked up the leaks after the owner had finished harvesting; some said they were deceived by rumors that the owner did not want them anymore and could pick them up at will. ; Some even directly favored the thief. There was once a melon farmer who got into a fight with a melon thief, causing the melon thief to fall to the ground and suffer a slight injury. When the police arrived at the scene, they asked the melon farmer to pay the thief 300 yuan, which aroused great public attention. They just asked the thief to return the money and settled the matter. In the end, the theft was not recognized and the melon thief was not punished in any way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pick one or two watermelons, a few pumpkins, and dozens of corns. It doesn’t look like much, and it doesn’t seem like there’s much to “make a fuss about.” But once there are more people, the number of people who are picked off and taken away is not a small number. If the behavior of one or two people &quot;picking&quot; and &quot;picking&quot; crops is not strictly stopped and punished, there will be groups of people coming to &quot;pick&quot; and &quot;pick&quot;, causing huge losses to investors. The repeated occurrence of such incidents will seriously undermine the confidence and enthusiasm of agricultural investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of rural laborers has decreased, and land has been transferred to foreign investors for a fee to operate on a large scale and collect rent. Some people can also work on farms and receive wages. This is a win-win situation. However, if investors’ interests are not adequately protected, they may not come back. Without outside investors and no people in the village, the land would be abandoned and the farmers would have no income. Where to start talking about rural development? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To solve this problem, we must take a clear-cut stand to protect the interests of agricultural investors and crack down on theft and robbery. We can no longer be confused and &quot;lawless&quot;. Perhaps it is difficult to control all the robbers immediately due to the large number of people at the scene, but it is entirely possible to leave video evidence and ask them to return the stolen property afterwards and punish them in accordance with the law. In fact, as long as a severe penalty and a few people are punished, it is enough to deter those who are lucky enough to teach these locals a lesson and not dare to steal again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄罗斯总统普京抵达北京]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 09:36:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 17, Russian President Putin arrived at Beijing Capital International Airport by plane. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;President Putin will attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum and participate in related activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[通报落马官员，频现新表述]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258722]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/4qime8N3feVFJIWeLrzvDR8wlYUfoKhlVJdoAYEm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/4qime8N3feVFJIWeLrzvDR8wlYUfoKhlVJdoAYEm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The revised &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishment of the Communist Party of China&quot; will &quot;organize gangs within the party&quot; &quot;Gang&quot; is listed as one of the disciplinary violations. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 25, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reported that the former Shaanxi Provincial Fruit Industry Center Party Secretary Chu Jinfeng was &quot;double fired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The formation of huge debts has led to hidden government debt credit risks.” In addition to common violations of disciplines and laws, the notice specifically mentioned this point. According to public information, the same statement was not found in the reports of the dismissed officials by the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions at all levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, in recent years, new formulations have frequently appeared in the draft notices issued by the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions at all levels reporting the dismissal of officials. These new expressions mainly describe the new phenomena and characteristics of fallen officials&#39; violations of discipline and law, or reveal the true political attitudes of fallen officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that some new wordings, such as &quot;creating gangs within the party&quot;, &quot;arguing against the central government&#39;s policies&quot; and &quot;being a two-faced person&quot; have been revised twice in 2015 and 2018. It was written into the &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishments of the Communist Party of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Peng Xinlin, a professor at Beijing Normal University Law School, “The new expression is a theoretical refinement and generalization that can better grasp the new stage characteristics of the current anti-corruption work. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Increased “new formulations”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chu Jinfeng was born in March 1966. His official career started in the Weinan Municipal Finance Bureau, where he worked for 15 years. From December 2002, Chu Jinfeng served as the deputy mayor of Hancheng City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Weinan City). In Hancheng, he served successively as deputy mayor of Hancheng City, deputy secretary-general of the municipal government, director of the National Development and Reform Commission, mayor (deputy department level), and secretary of the municipal party committee, until he was transferred to the party secretary of the Shaanxi Provincial Fruit Industry Center in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The specific behavior of &quot;forming huge debts and triggering government implicit debt credit risks&quot; is that during his tenure as mayor and municipal party committee secretary of Hancheng City, Chu Jinfeng led the decision-making and implementation of a number of projects without project approval procedures. , failure to apply for construction permits, lack of land procedures and other irregularities. Data released by the Hancheng City Finance Bureau show that in 2022, the Hancheng City government debt balance will be approximately 4.432 billion yuan. In the same year, Hancheng’s fiscal revenue was only 3.361 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to causing hidden debt risks, there are also notifications that list fallen officials as disciplinary and illegal behaviors that lead to a sharp increase in local government debt risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission on July 27, 2023, Jiao Xiaoping, the former deputy commander of the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, was &quot;double fired&quot;. The report stated that it &quot;exacerbated the government&#39;s hidden debt risks and created financial problems.&quot; Security risks&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2023, the 2022 anti-corruption warning record &quot;Loyalty and Betrayal&quot; produced by the Hunan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision introduced the disciplinary and illegal behavior of Cao Jiongfang, the former secretary of the Xiangtan Municipal Party Committee. In May 2016, after Cao Jiongfang took office as Secretary of the Xiangtan Municipal Party Committee, he carried out large-scale demolition and construction in the city regardless of financial resources and reality. He blindly proposed to turn every urban road into a landscape road, a high-quality road, and a model road. A total of 345 paving projects were completed. The total investment is 61.7 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;According to the observation of Zhuang Deshui, deputy director of the Integrity Construction Research Center of Peking University, after 2015, disciplinary inspection and supervision agencies at all levels gradually increased the number of &quot;new references&quot; in the notifications of fallen officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An obvious node may be June 2015. The Fuzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Lin Lunjian, chairman of the Lianjiang County CPPCC, Chen Baifan, leader of the discipline inspection team of the Fuzhou Municipal Administration for Market Regulation, and Lin Zhong, deputy mayor of Changle City, committed &quot;serious violations of socialist ethics&quot;. According to the Beijing News, the issue involved by these three officials was an inappropriate relationship with a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, disciplinary inspection and supervision systems at all levels have frequently used new expressions in draft notifications. Southern Weekend reporters combed through and found that these new expressions mainly describe new phenomena and new characteristics of fallen officials&#39; violations of discipline and law, or reveal the true political attitudes of fallen officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhuang Deshui’s observation, the original website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the Ministry of Supervision was launched in September 2013 (renamed the “Website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission” in March 2018). As the website construction gradually matured, the investigation of fallen officials Public notifications were normalized, and new wording and expressions appeared in draft notifications around 2015. In addition, after the launch of the pilot reform of the national supervisory system in November 2016, the content of notifications against fallen officials has become more abundant, which is one of the reasons why new wording appears frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhuang Deshui explained that before the reform of the supervisory system, the Discipline Inspection Commission’s reports usually focused on the disciplinary violations of dismissed officials, and the illegal and criminal issues were basically not mentioned. The illegal and criminal issues were generally reported by the court after being transferred to the judicial organs. . After the reform of the supervision system, the proportion of illegal and criminal issues in the notification has increased significantly, and it will contain some rare statements that have not appeared before. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;New expressions and new questions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“There are two meanings behind the new expressions.” Zhuang Deshui’s analysis, the first is to analyze a certain issue at the factual level Underline officials&#39; disciplinary violations, illegal crimes, and summarize the characteristics of their disciplinary violations and the Party discipline and national laws they violated; secondly, the new expression actually reflects the newly exposed problems in the anti-corruption work, or the next stage of the disciplinary inspection and supervision system The issues that need to be investigated and dealt with are a benchmark for anti-corruption work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2021, Xiao Yi, the former vice chairman of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, was double fired. The notice stated that he &quot;abused his power to introduce and support companies to engage in virtual currency &#39;mining&#39; activities that are not in compliance with the requirements of national industrial policies.&quot; , this is the first time that virtual currency “mining” behavior has appeared in a report from the disciplinary inspection system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2022, Zhou Jiangyong, former member of the Standing Committee of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee and former Secretary of the Hangzhou Municipal Party Committee, was double fired. The notice mentioned that he &quot;colluded with capital and supported the ineffective expansion of capital.&quot; &quot;China News Weekly&quot; reported that this expression was used for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, Zhang Jinghua, the former deputy secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, was &quot;double opened&quot;. The report mentioned that he &quot;committed falsification of economic data in order to seek personal advancement.&quot; This statement was not included in the report of the disciplinary inspection system. precedent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2022, in a press release from Chen Jiadong, former director of the Standing Committee of the People’s Congress of Xiamen City, Fujian Province, it was stated that Chen Jiadong used public power to serve interest groups, resist organizational censorship, and engage in superstitious activities. Shangguan News reported that &quot;using public power to serve interest groups&quot; appeared for the first time in the notice of the fallen official. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Ji Guogang, a former member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the People’s Congress of the Tibet Autonomous Region, was “double fired” and reported that he had “wantonly abused central and local special funds.” &quot;Liberation Daily&quot; reported that this wording appeared for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuang Deshui noticed that after the emergence of these new formulations, some of them have been absorbed into party documents and listed as work goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The communique of the Second Plenary Session of the 20th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection held in January 2023 clearly stated that &quot;resolutely investigate and deal with corruption where political issues and economic issues are intertwined, and resolutely prevent leading cadres from becoming the targets of interest groups and powerful groups.&quot; Spokespersons and agents, resolutely prevent political and business collusion, capital penetration into the political field, etc. from damaging the political ecology and economic development environment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Institutional Norms&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;And Summary Compared with the new wording on the illegal behavior of fallen officials, the new expressions revealing the political attitudes of fallen officials have also attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2015, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Zhao Shaolin, former member of the Standing Committee and Secretary-General of the Jiangsu Provincial Committee, had been &quot;double fired&quot;. The draft of more than 300 words rarely used eight new expressions, including &quot;creating gangs within the party&quot;, &quot;engaging in wanton exchanges and transfers of interests&quot;, &quot;coining and corrupting leading cadres&quot;, &quot;openly disseminating and comprehensively strictly governing the party&quot; Remarks that contradict the requirements” etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2015, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Zhou Benshun, the former secretary of the Hebei Provincial Party Committee, seriously violated political disciplines and rules and &quot;made remarks that went against the spirit of the central government on major issues.&quot; This new statement was also Caused widespread concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 1, 2016, the revised &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishment of the Communist Party of China&quot; listed &quot;creating gangs within the party&quot; as one of the disciplinary violations, and &quot;unreasonable discussion of the central government&#39;s policies, undermining the &quot;Party centralization and unity&quot; is included in the category of violation of political discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2016, Zheng Xuebi, the former secretary of the Chengde Municipal Party Committee in Hebei Province, was &quot;double fired&quot; and the notice pointed out that he &quot;refuses to implement the party and the country&#39;s principles and policies.&quot; Jiemian News reported that this wording appeared for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2017, the Anhui Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection reported serious disciplinary violations by Yang Jingnong, the former Secretary-General of the Anhui Provincial Government, saying that he &quot;has no ideals and beliefs, is not loyal and honest to the party, and has long been a &#39;two-faced man&#39;&quot; &#39;&quot;. The term &quot;two-faced man&quot; has no precedent before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Effective from October 1, 2018, the newly revised &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishments of the Communist Party of China&quot; came into effect, with 11 new articles, including &quot;engaging in hilltop doctrine and refusing to implement the major policies set by the Party Central Committee&quot; , implement the disciplinary provisions for discounting or making changes in the decisions and plans of the Party Central Committee, as well as creating and spreading political rumors and other behaviors that endanger the unity and unity of the Party&quot; and &quot;engaging in double-dealing, being a two-faced person and other behaviors that are disloyal and dishonest to the Party.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The improvement of intra-party regulations is an important part of the construction of the anti-corruption system. Peng Xinlin believes that &quot;the revision of the Party Disciplinary Punishment Regulations is to promptly upgrade some new phenomena that actually appear in anti-corruption work, or some good experiences and practices into institutional norms.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一帧新发现之大千先生自画像稿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/EFEkjWo3Eja9vKdOM4zpri5jSaSTfgJaHBoy9XUI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;832&quot; height=&quot;1095&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/EFEkjWo3Eja9vKdOM4zpri5jSaSTfgJaHBoy9XUI. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254144&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Self-portrait of Mr. Daqian. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Daqian likes to make self-portraits. Taking into account only those that can be seen in public and private collections today, from the first painting he made at the age of 28 to the end of his life, there were more than a hundred self-portraits handed down to the world, and the number of those that have been lost is still unknown. In the history of world painting, even if this is not the &quot;best&quot;, it is certainly one of the &quot;best&quot;. If we look back at the history of Chinese painting, it will definitely be the best in ancient and modern times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The newly discovered self-portrait manuscript of Mr. Daqian was originally collected by Zhang Shizheng&#39;s &quot;Qinglian Bookstore&quot;. Master Zheng was born in Chaoyang, Guangdong. His father was an antique dealer in Hong Kong. He was very familiar with Mr. Daqian. In 1956, he ordered his son to become a disciple of Dafeng Hall. Later, he went to Brazil to live in Bade Garden. He was one of the four disciples of Bade Garden and was appointed by Mr. Daqian. The teacher named him Qian, with the courtesy name Shi Zheng. His teacher, Zheng Nai, was a young man who was cautious and spoke softly. In addition to studying painting, he also took care of the books, paper, ink, and stationery in the Bade Garden Studio. There is an unwritten rule in Bade Garden: any drawings, sketches, lesson plans, fragments of poems, or even banquet menus written by the teacher during daily painting and chatting, even if they are just pieces of paper, can be shared by all the students in turn. , Mr. Daqian is also happy to see this. If there are any scraps of old paper in the studio that are worthy of study, you can ask the teacher to keep them for yourself. Master Zheng was responsible for managing the studio and was close to the water, so he earned a lot of money. Later, he fell in love with another Bade Garden student, Wang Dandan. Three years later, in 1969, they both said goodbye to Bade Garden and returned to New York and got married. Six years later, he died of a brain tumor, and this frame has been preserved by Wang Dandan to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/MFBSGanK6l6rAI2YeklAjQ67AwM0OYJhsyLyKvb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;790&quot; height= &quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/MFBSGanK6l6rAI2YeklAjQ67AwM0OYJhsyLyKvb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254143&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Shizheng and Wang Dandan are in Bade Garden. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-portrait on paper, 45 cm high and 35 cm wide, without inscription, with Dandan inscription On it:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Da Qianfuzi&#39;s self-portrait drawing with silk thread. I don’t know the name of the thin paper, which is glossy and translucent and extremely cheap. It is commonly used by teachers and students of Da Feng Hall for shadow tracing. The teacher Zheng Bingxing respected calligraphy paper and was amazed by his master&#39;s unique skills in gossamer tracing. He found this painting among the discarded papers in the Bade Garden Studio. I re-examined the old box under the lamp because I recognized it. Dingyou is at the end of the year, every day. It was cold and rainy, and it didn&#39;t stop for two days. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three seals are &quot;Qinglian Bookstore&quot;, &quot;Dandan&quot; and &quot;Wang Xi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gossamer drawing is one of the so-called line drawings in &quot;Hua Shi Zhi Meng&quot; written by Ming Zou Dezhong, &quot;18 ancient and modern drawing techniques&quot;. Its meaning is as the name suggests. &quot;Haixian Painting Manual&quot; notes: &quot;Use a very sharp pen, like the pattern of Cao&#39;s clothes.&quot; (Editor&#39;s note: Cao Zhongda in the Northern Qi Dynasty and Daozi in the Tang and Wu Dynasties were both good at painting Buddha statues. Cao&#39;s brushwork is thick and overlapping, and the clothes are tight and narrow; Wu&#39;s brushwork is round Turning, the clothes and belts are fluttering, so later generations call it &quot;Wu belts are in the wind, Cao&#39;s clothes are flowing out of the water.&quot;) Mr. Daqian&#39;s lines in this frame are as thin as a gossamer, fluent, elegant and graceful, without any obstructions; not only does the beard and eyebrows grow, The line drawing also expresses the solid texture of the skin of the cheeks, nose, lips, and ears, and the shape is mastered. It cannot be achieved without a clear mind and a perfect hand. It can be said to be superb and jaw-dropping. Thinking of this, Sun Jiaqin, one of the four disciples of Bade Garden, was trying to identify the authenticity of Master Yiwujie&#39;s paintings. He opened the scroll and looked at it briefly, and said: &quot;There is absolutely no doubt! Others don&#39;t have this writing power, and they can&#39;t come up with this kind of charm.&quot; .&quot; Wang Dandan looked at this frame for the author, looked at it for a long time, and sighed: &quot;I will never be able to draw like the teacher in my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are several lines of short titles in the upper left corner of the self-portrait manuscript: &quot;Ape The baby is named Black, and he is cute and funny. During the day, he likes to climb outside the window of the big studio to paint. The teacher also loves him like a favorite. If he is sick, he will ask the local pediatrician to treat him, and he can be cured, which is also a miracle. Dandansaki remembers it again. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Daqian often tells people that this life is the reincarnation of a black ape. On the eve of his mother Zeng&#39;s delivery, she dreamed of an elderly man with a white beard holding a black ape on a gong and giving it to him, and told him to take good care of it. He also said: &quot;The black ape is afraid of meat and fish, and is afraid of being restrained.&quot; The gentleman said to himself: &quot;Dream Just listen to what the omen says. The strange thing is that after weaning, I really can&#39;t eat even a little bit of meat and fish, and I have been vegetarian since I was a child. It&#39;s not that my family doesn&#39;t let me eat meat, but it&#39;s that whenever I touch meat, I will turn my stomach and vomit. What&#39;s even weirder is When I was a child, I burst into tears when I saw the moon and kept crying for a long time. This happened repeatedly, and my family was surprised and believed in the theory that dreams portend black apes.&quot; His revered master Zeng Nongbeard had already felt that this disciple was very smart and enlightened. A person with abnormal spiritual power was born with dark skin and thick hair. Hearing this, he became more convinced and gave him the name &quot;Yuan&quot;. Since then, he has lived in various places, and Mr. Daqian has always followed him. He often used apes in his paintings, and he could be called a master of ape paintings during the reign of Emperor Yi and Yuan Ji of the Song Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;black baby&quot; was raised by Mr. Daqian in the Bade Garden in Brazil. The Taipei National Palace Museum also has a portrait of Mr. Daqian and Hei Baobao. It is one of the pages of the album. It has a similar composition but different pen and ink. The writing is simple and has a cursive style. The title is: &quot;My Little Monkey and I&quot; , is so cute, or is it actually transformed from this frame? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/8q9PJYQRAnYS52AzWalYSQJl3Dtf471ojIqs9B5y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; height= &quot;797&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/8q9PJYQRAnYS52AzWalYSQJl3Dtf471ojIqs9B5y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254142&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Daqian&#39;s &quot;My Little Monkey and I&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dandan told the author: &quot;Baby Hei will wait on the corridor in the morning and accompany the teacher hand in hand. Take a walk. The big wire mesh cage where it is kept is facing the big window of the studio downstairs in Bade Garden. It hangs and plays in it, looking at the teacher through the window. We play with it and feed it bananas, and it will come to get it and peel it by itself. He also likes to use his two paws to gently push your hair away, as if he is looking for something, and will hit you when he is unhappy.&quot; When Mr. Daqian travels, he often writes letters to the students in the garden. and. For example, the letter to Wang Dandan in 1967 ended with the question: &quot;Are cats, dogs, and black apes good?&quot; It made people smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/ZH1hpjAYsfpPby6s2izZtB9CqUHHW3wHM6xXjTUw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height= &quot;395&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/ZH1hpjAYsfpPby6s2izZtB9CqUHHW3wHM6xXjTUw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Daqian is in the Bade Garden studio, and Baby Hei is outside the window. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 1969, Mr. Daqian went to San Francisco for surgery due to worsening of his eye disease. He was depressed for a time. On January 15th, he wrote to &quot;Dandan&#39;s Nephew&quot; saying: &quot;I have become very exhausted after falling ill, and I really want to give up all my hobbies. Nephew and Brother Luo, Mr. Huang, Uncle Shen, and Brother Zhang will quickly send Hei Baobao, Xida immediately cooperated to send it to the zoo, and then gave the flower to the dog lovers. The fool will bite, and if there is anyone who can train him, he will give it away. The little flower was fed by the ugly girl, so love is not a problem. . Please discuss the matter with us as soon as possible, so that your love will not bear to part with you when we see you again. Best advice, best advice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For some reason, Mr. Daqian&#39;s instructions were not implemented. In late April of the same year, when Wang Dandan and Zhang Shizheng said goodbye to Mr. Daqian and Bade Garden and returned to New York, Hei Baobao and others were still in the garden. At this time, it was only a few months since Mr. Daqian decided to give up Bade Garden and move to California in the United States because the Brazilian government was about to take back the land to build a reservoir. On the day when teachers and students reunited in Mr. Daqian&#39;s new residence &quot;Huan Pi Temple&quot; in the small coastal town of Carmel, California, there was no trace of pets around the teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paper used in this frame is also worthy of research. As Wang Dandan said in the inscription, the paper is thin and translucent, with an oil-like waxy shine on the front and a silk color. The author has seen that there are several handwritten manuscripts of Daqian poems and early Dunhuang mural paintings in the old collection of Master Zhang Zheng Qinglian&#39;s bookstore, and they also use the same kind of paper. This paper is translucent and does not smear when receiving ink, so it is most suitable for line drawing or rubbing. Chang Shuhong&#39;s daughter Chang Shana lived with her father in Dunhuang Mogao Grottoes for many years. She heard her father talk about Mr. Daqian&#39;s method of rubbing murals, and she wrote a review of the Dunhuang rubbings left by Mr. Daqian. His &quot;Readme&quot; says: &quot;When Zhang Daqian copied the murals at Thousand Buddha Cave, he used thumbtacks to press the copy paper onto the murals. The resulting manuscript was very accurate, but the thumbtacks would inevitably make small holes in the wall. holes, destroying murals.&quot; Although the words were accusatory, they pointed out that the paper Mr. Daqian used for rubbings was &quot;copy paper.&quot; The National Palace Museum in Taipei has a painting of &quot;The Portrait of Samantabhadra of the Western Xia Dynasty at the Dharma Assembly in Cave 4 of the Yulin Grottoes in Anxi, Dunhuang, copied by Zhang Daqian, Sun Jiaqin, Zhang Shizheng during the Republic of China.&quot; There is an inscription written by Daqian himself, and it also mentions the paper used to copy the Dunhuang murals: &quot; In the second cave of Yulin Grottoes in Anxi (author&#39;s note: it was mistakenly thought to be the fourth cave), the Xixia people painted Manjushri and Samantabhadra going to the Dharma Assembly in one pavilion. The brushstrokes were all painted by Long Mian, and the background was also composed of Ma Xia, which is what the murals depict. Not yet. I was anxious to return, so I couldn&#39;t write it down, but I used oil sketches to draw the draft. The next year after I was surrendered, I revisited my old capital and found the second version of Chu Chu in the Song Dynasty. The length and width were about the same, so I used paper... ...&quot; I know that Mr. Daqian said that the paper used for his couch manuscript is called oil pigment, and the copy paper mentioned by Chang Shana should be the same thing, which is the paper used for this frame of Mr. Daqian&#39;s self-portrait. At that time, the origin of this paper was either domestic or imported, and it was yet to be learned by those who knew it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the author&#39;s personal opinion, it seems that this paper should still be named &quot;Oil Su&quot;. Firstly, it comes from the mouth of the person involved, Mr. Daqian, so I believe it must be well-founded; secondly, it sounds better than &quot; &quot;Copy paper&quot; is more Chinese and more elegant. Mr. Daqian used a wide variety of drawing papers throughout his life, including expensive ones such as ancient paper from the Song Dynasty and the following dynasties, and cheap ones such as Sichuan bamboo paper and Guizhou leather paper, as well as pineapple paper, Goryeo paper, Japanese Torizo ​​paper, Jinqian paper and even Taiwanese pineapple Xuan and other exotic products, as well as homemade Dafengtang rib paper and Maya Jingshe couplet paper. And this &quot;oil element&quot; should naturally be included in the list of &quot;Daqian Paper&quot;, and it cannot be judged by the secular world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Additional note: Regarding what Mr. Daqian calls &quot;oil-based&quot; paper, there is a sentence in the above article: &quot;Those who have yet to learn can be taught.&quot; Unexpectedly, I immediately received relevant clues from my friends. &quot;The Life of Qi Baishi&quot; written by Zhang Cixi, a member of the Baishi sect, said: Bai Shiweng&#39;s family was poor in his early years and could not afford to buy books to learn painting, so he borrowed a copy of &quot;The Biography of Mustard Seed Garden Painting&quot; from a customer&#39;s home, &quot;In the wages earned, even some With some money, I bought some oil paper, paints, brushes and other things that must be used. Oil paper is thin bamboo paper soaked in tung oil. It is very thin, transparent and does not bleed ink. After work at night, I went home and gathered some pine oil. Under the firewood lamp, I sketched one picture after another. It took half a year to complete the sketch of &quot;The Biography of Mustard Seed Garden Paintings&quot;, except for the incomplete one.&quot; Yang Danxia&#39;s &quot;Identification of Authenticity of Chinese Paintings and Calligraphy&quot; says : &quot;Mi Fu&#39;s &quot;Daolin Tie&quot; is in its early style. There are also copies made by the Qing Dynasty, using oil paper. This kind of paper is dark beige, and the surface of the paper is oily. When copying, it will not appear on the original. The ink penetrates into the original calligraphy. Jiang Heng, a calligrapher during the Yongzheng and Qianlong periods of the Qing Dynasty, was good at imitating the ancients. His grandson Jiang He once said in the inscription after a work that his grandfather copied Li Dongyang&#39;s calligraphy on oil paper. There are also records about Zha Shibiao&#39;s forgery in the Qing Dynasty rulers, saying that the Zha Tuo people bought this kind of oil paper, and then copied ancient works and sold them without letting anyone publicize it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, Mr. Daqian called this kind of rubbing paper &quot;oil-based paper&quot;, which is indeed not random, because the original name of the paper is oil-based paper; Chang Shana called it &quot;copy paper&quot;, which comes from the English transliteration of oil-based paper. The function of paper is the same as that of &quot;copy paper&quot; in the West, so it is confused and misnamed without careful study. Oil paper is a traditional paper product in China. It is made of bamboo paper dipped in tung oil. It has been used since the early Qing Dynasty at the latest. As for Yang&#39;s book, it is said to be &quot;deep beige&quot;, but the oil paper used by the author&#39;s eyes is like a silkworm cocoon and has a slightly light yellow color. This is probably because what Yang saw is ancient calligraphy and painting, and the color has become darker over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 08:25:26 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[努力模仿上层生活：中产窘迫之源]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258646]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There are often many &quot;middle-class Versailles&quot; on Chinese social media, for example, for houses, cars, houses in school districts and vacations cost anxiety. In fact, this is a common problem among the middle class in various countries. Let’s analyze the lifestyle and spiritual feelings of the middle class in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Europe and the United States, the middle-class life seems to be very good. They can vacation overseas, live in a house with a garden, and build a swimming pool. In the United States, companies purchase commercial insurance for their employees. Even if there are elderly people or children at home, the burden is not large. Life in the American middle class seems easy and comfortable. However, this may not be the case. On Buzzfeed, an American news aggregation website, an American netizen summarized &quot;what is the middle class&quot;, defining it as a life experience unique to the middle class that neither the rich nor the poor understand. The experience was not that great. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen summed it up like this: The middle class in the United States can take a vacation, but they need to be careful with their budgets, while the rich do not need to be careful with their budgets, and the poor do not take vacations; the middle class can buy a house, but they are struggling with what kind of house to buy and the loan, while the rich In many houses, poor people don&#39;t think about this at all; the middle class has double garages, but one of them is full of messy things and can only park one car, while the rich have large garages and storage rooms, and the poor have fewer cars and less stuff. ; The middle class has a lawn, but they need to mow it themselves, while the rich hire a gardener, and the poor have no lawn; the middle class goes to Costco to kill time and buy a large cart, but the rich are not interested in shopping at this level, and the poor cannot afford to go; Children have to bear heavy college loans, and the children of the rich have their parents to pay, and the poor can apply for various subsidies; middle-class families have various facilities, but they have to buy a complete set of tools to repair them themselves, because labor costs are very high in the United States, and the rich It doesn&#39;t hurt to hire someone to fix it, but the poor can&#39;t afford so much equipment...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, this netizen said three words: enough is enough. In fact, to a certain extent, the embarrassment of the American middle class is inevitable. Since we are middle class, we must be caught in the middle, neither above nor below. Compared with the lower class, it is more than enough. The middle class has got rid of material poverty and lives a relatively prosperous life. However, compared with the upper class, their abilities are limited, their desires are hard to satisfy, and they cannot take it easy like the truly wealthy class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of the times has deepened this feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the information technology revolution, although all classes of society lived on the same land, they were isolated from each other to some extent. Although the lower and middle classes also know about the life of the upper class, they only have a superficial understanding of it. The means of communication are only hearing and writing. Therefore, there is such a ridiculous cross-class imagination that &quot;the poles used by emperors and empresses to carry water are all made of gold.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the advent of movies and television, the lower class’s understanding of the life of the upper class has deepened. In the era of social media, this barrier has been completely broken by smartphones, Douyin, TikTok, and Twitter. Videos, live broadcasts, and real interactions all make cross-class showing off direct and intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People’s desire to consume is often influenced by the scenes they see on social media, movies, and friends circles. Those who exert influence are of course high-income people, and the goods they consume are regarded as symbols of &quot;accessible happiness.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This influence is dragging the middle class with their desire for a higher level of consumption. The middle class strives to imitate the lifestyle of the upper class, from clothing and diet to hobbies. The middle class can grit their teeth and save money to achieve expensive purchases such as pianos, horse riding, mountain climbing, and studying abroad. At the same time, this has also become a source of pain for the middle class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another reason is that the middle class feels more tax pain. The famous politician Benjamin Franklin once said a famous saying: &quot;In this world, the only things that cannot be escaped are death and taxes.&quot; For the poor, although they also have to pay taxes, such as consumption tax when shopping, but The welfare received by the poor is greater, and the net welfare received by the poor is greater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the rich, it is first of all more difficult for the state to collect taxes from them. There are many ways for rich people to avoid taxes, such as donating to charitable funds they set up and putting consumption into company costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, U.S. President George H.W. Bush signed a new law: levying taxes on high-end cars over $30,000, yachts over $100,000, valuable furs over $100,000, and private jets over $250,000. 10% &quot;luxury tax&quot;. The purpose of the luxury tax is to allow the rich to pay 10% more when buying a yacht, and the increased fiscal revenue can be used to help the poor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, although the wealthy can afford the 10% tax, their purchases are very flexible: they can buy yachts abroad and then bring them back to the United States as second-hand yachts. Moreover, they can no longer buy yachts, but take vacations, buy luxury watches and diamonds. But the yacht industry is not that flexible. It is impossible to switch to other products in the short term, and it is impossible for workers in the yacht industry to change jobs in the short term. As a result, taxes from the wealthy were not collected, but the U.S. yacht industry was severely damaged, causing industrial workers to lose their jobs. In 1993, President George H.W. Bush repealed the luxury tax on yachts, private jets and furs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, most of the middle class are engaged in mental work or manual work with basic skills, and mainly rely on wages and salaries to make a living. This makes their taxes easy to collect and easy to check. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, although the rich are richer and the absolute amount of tax burden borne by a single individual is higher, the number of rich people is very small. Therefore, for the country, the middle class is the largest tax base. A country&#39;s expenditures are all borne by the middle class, and the benefits the middle class receive are far less than the taxes they pay. More taxes are paid to support the poor and the state&#39;s expenses, which means that the consumption of the middle class is less than their own labor income. This also forms part of the source of pain for the middle class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The drag on consumption and the pain and burden of taxes will all lead to one result, which is the embarrassment of the middle class, thereby suppressing the fertility rate of the middle class. Of course, overall, the middle class invests more in education than the bottom class, and the quality of their offspring is also higher. From this perspective, making the life of the middle class easier is also a blessing for the country’s future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[外国游客飞无人机撞坏安阳文峰塔？当地称确有碰撞正了解详情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258682]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some netizens claimed that “several Korean men were operating drones to photograph Wenfeng Temple in Tianning Temple, Anyang, Henan Wenfeng Tower was destroyed by a drone when the tower was being destroyed.&quot; On October 16, Anyang Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau responded to Nandu reporters saying that a drone did indeed collide with Wenfeng Tower, and the specific situation is still being understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/0e27823c9e8a08f33ef86bc33f78928f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/0e27823c9e8a08f33ef86bc33f78928f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254147&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Netizen posts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 15, some netizens posted, “Several Korean men operated drones to photograph the Wenfeng Pagoda of Tianning Temple in Anyang, Henan. Improper operation caused the drone to destroy the Wenfeng Pagoda. Crash a piece.&quot; Netizens questioned why drones could be flown inside the temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters asked the netizen for details, and the netizen added, &quot;The incident happened on the morning of the 15th. The elderly in his family have the habit of going to Wenfeng Pagoda on the first and fifteenth day of the Lunar New Year, and happened to see the temple staff. After negotiating with the Koreans, we also saw the drone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 16th, staff from the Anyang Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau told Nandu reporters that a drone did indeed collide with Wenfeng Tower, and the specific situation is still being understood. For details, please consult Anyang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archeology, the direct management unit of the cultural relics. The staff member also introduced that there is no clear rule against flying drones in the scenic spot where the incident occurred, &quot;but generally you have to apply to the Anyang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology and get approval before you can fly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noticed Anyang Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau once responded to citizens’ questions on its official website, saying that the Tianning Temple Tower is an iconic ancient building in Anyang and is now managed by the Anyang Cultural Relics and Archaeological Research Institute. Nandu reporters called the Anyang Institute of Cultural Relics and Archaeology, but could not get through as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned that the full name of the Wenfeng Pagoda is &quot;Anyang Tianning Temple Pagoda&quot;. According to the official website of the Anyang Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau, the Anyang Tianning Temple Pagoda is located in the ancient Tianning Temple on Dasiqian Street, Anyang City, Henan Province. The pagoda was first built in the second year of Zhou Guangshun (952) after the Five Dynasties, and was repaired in the Song, Yuan, Ming and Qing dynasties. In 2001, the Anyang Tianning Temple Pagoda was announced by the State Council as the fifth batch of national key cultural relics protection units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[火锅吃微微辣？广东人四川人湖南人都不服]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 21:25:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>