<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“纳卡”再得一分、强力介入中东：埃尔多安玩转地缘政治棋局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259773]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the world situation has become increasingly turbulent, and conflicts between civilizations and regional conflicts among various ethnic groups have become increasingly intensified. Back to troubled times. Amid many conflicts and turbulence, Turkey&#39;s series of actions in recent years have become increasingly eye-catching. President Erdogan has earned himself the nickname &quot;Esultan&quot; with a series of dazzling combination punches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Syrian civil war in the past few years, it sent troops to northern Syria to support pro-Turkey armed factions and occupied and controlled part of the Syrian territory. In the process of fighting for the sphere of influence, Erdogan was bold and ruthless. He not only dared to take action against the Assad government forces, but also dared to shoot down Russian fighter jets and helicopters supporting the Syrian army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2020 &quot;Azerbaijan-Azerbaijan War&quot;, Turkey supported Azerbaijan, severely damaged Armenia, and once again hit Russia&#39;s prestige in the Middle East. As a result, Turkey&#39;s status in the Middle East has been greatly improved, and many Arab people regard Erdogan as a national hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Erdogan dares to challenge Putin mainly because of his membership in NATO. He knows that under the protection of this political and military bloc, Russia will not directly attack Turkey for secondary and smaller overseas interests. It is a good way to use the power of the West to enhance one&#39;s prestige among the Islamic community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Russia-Ukraine conflict broke out in 2022, Turkey shuttled back and forth between several parties and experienced ups and downs: On the one hand, its participation led to the negotiation of the &quot;Black Sea Food Channel&quot; and improved its status among NATO member states. status. On the other hand, it used its veto power in NATO to delay Finland and Sweden&#39;s applications to join NATO. This has further improved his status in the Middle East. In the eyes of the people, Erdogan is a contemporary hero who dares to say no to Russia as well as the United States and Europe. He is simply the reincarnation of Saladin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has given Turkey a lot of points in its competition with Saudi Arabia and Iran to become the leader in the Middle East. Originally, due to the collapse of the Ottoman Empire, the fact that the Turks belong to the Turkic ethnic group rather than the Arab ethnic group, the pro-Western line implemented by Kemalism in the past few decades, and many other factors, Turkey was once marginalized in the Middle East world. Now it has finally been &quot;Egyptian&quot; Sudan” regained many scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, Turkey will make another move in the Transcaucasus: supporting Azerbaijan and forcing Armenia to withdraw from the &quot;Naka ​​region.&quot; This not only enabled Turkey and Azerbaijan to win the geopolitical dispute, but also caused Armenia to break away from Russia, its old master that it had relied on for hundreds of years, out of consideration for its own survival. This move caused Russia to lose serious points in the geopolitical conflict in the Transcaucasus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After embarrassing Finland and Sweden for nearly a year and achieving its own political goals (Finland and Sweden agreed to weaken their support for the anti-Turkey Kurdish forces), Turkey approved Finland and Sweden’s applications to join NATO, and then Increased its influence in NATO and improved relations with the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, as the &quot;Hazra-Israeli conflict&quot; broke out in the Gaza Strip, Erdogan stood up to criticize Israel and criticized the United States and Europe, once again winning widespread support for him in the Middle East. Did he really want to revive the Ottoman Turkish Empire? How did he win so many times in a row over several years? This starts with Turkey’s political interests, cultural positioning, and geostrategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey’s national defense security depends on NATO, dominated by the United States, and its economic foundation mainly relies on the European market, dominated by the EU. In the modern world, it is simply impossible to allow Turkey to use force to retake the homeland of the former Ottoman Empire. Therefore, the main body of the secular and pro-Western concepts of &quot;Kemalism&quot; has not changed. Erdogan has worked hard for many years and always hopes to join the EU. When asked by the media whether he would go to the West or the East, he firmly answered: Go west and join the EU. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey is also a country that has great conflicts with the West culturally. As a politician, Erdogan must decide his policies based on real social foundations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early decades of the practice of &quot;Kemalism&quot;, Turkey adopted a one-sided strategy towards the West. But in the past decade or so, as the power of the Islamic world has increased, the Ankara authorities certainly cannot give up this huge resource. Therefore, they must strive for leadership in the Islamic world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the geostrategic level, Turkey has a unique advantage: as the strategic pillar of NATO in the southeast, it not only blocks the entrance and exit of the Black Sea, but also affects the security situation along the Black Sea coast and the Caspian Sea. The Transcaucasus and Central Asia have always been Russia&#39;s strategic soft belly, and Turkey has a profound influence on these two regions, whether in terms of geography, ethnicity, religion, culture, economy, etc. Turkey, which sits on the Anatolian Plateau, borders southeastern Europe to the west, Iran to the east, and the two river basins of Mesopotamia to the south. It plays a very important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Erdogan has made comprehensive use of political, religious, cultural, economic, military, geographical and other factors to combine vertical and horizontal movements and maneuvers, and has achieved many successes and expanded Turkey. geopolitical interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But behind this set of seemingly prosperous actions, Turkey has serious problems: their economic size cannot support the talents and strategies of &quot;Egyptian Sudan&quot;. Its inflation is very serious. On October 26, the Central Bank of Turkey announced that it would raise the benchmark interest rate by 500 basis points from 30% to 35%. This is the fifth consecutive interest rate increase since the Central Bank entered the interest rate increase cycle in June. Since 2022, Turkey&#39;s inflation rate has been running at a high level, reaching 85.51% in October 2022, and 47.83%, 58.94%, and 61.53% in the three months of July, August, and September 2023, respectively, and there is still an upward trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, &quot;Egypt-Sudan&quot;, as a medium-sized country in Turkey, has done too many political achievements at a loss and made a profit, and all the costs have to be borne by the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In history, many countries have adopted strategies of inciting nationalism, playing tricks at the top, and overdrafting national power. They have achieved jaw-dropping achievements in a relatively short period of time, but the results have mostly been tragic. The reason is simple: just like a person who is not in good health and has to exhaust his energy to run a marathon, triathlon, or decathlon, of course there will be no good results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Erdogan is trying his best to control the pace of the game. After achieving his goals, he may compromise with the United States and Europe. For example: when Finland and Sweden were finally approved to join NATO, he chose to keep a low profile when the US military shot down a Turkish drone (in order to safeguard its interests with the Kurdish community). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, in terms of national defense, Turkey relies on the United States; in terms of economy, with such a high inflation rate, it depends even more on the help of the European Union, and it has a large number of immigrants and workers in Europe, which has a great impact on Ankara. The economy is very important, and it is also Turkey’s long-term means of ethnic penetration, colonization, and cultural expansion into Europe. Therefore, whether it is a show, a show, or a dispute or conflict, it must be stopped in moderation and not completely fall out with the West. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Erdogan is playing a medium-scale geostrategic game with Turkey&#39;s national power and influence. His intention is to use his territory spanning Europe and Asia, and his political and cultural involvement in the two camps of Europe and Islam, to jump on several ships to expand Turkey&#39;s influence in modern Europe and the Islamic world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报女教师跳楼轻生事件：成立联合调查组，“加班数石榴”为不实信息]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259820]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, a female teacher from Jianxing Road Primary School in our district unfortunately passed away. In response to the incident, , the teachers and students of the school were deeply saddened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, the district education bureau attached great importance to it and immediately collaborated with relevant departments to set up a joint investigation team to investigate the incident and make every effort to comfort the family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, false information such as &quot;working overtime to count pomegranates&quot; appeared on the Internet. We hereby appeal to the majority of netizens to be rational and objective, and not to believe or spread rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the District Education Bureau will further enhance its care for grassroots teachers in the district, make every effort to care for the lives and psychological care of grassroots teachers in the district, and provide a good education and teaching environment for primary and secondary school teachers in the district . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guancheng Hui District Education Bureau&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 1, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/02/ac6d47e1881f43b216e87142e275f058.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;1018&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/02/ac6d47e1881f43b216e87142e275f058.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256651&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[花十几万去南极旅游，是花钱买罪受？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259372]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, &quot;The ticket price for an expedition to Antarctica has been reduced by 90,000 &quot;The post sparked heated discussions on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;You know, every November is when the Antarctic tourism season starts. Many domestic travel agencies have started selling Antarctic tour projects. The price of a trip is basically more than 100,000 yuan, and some high-end routes can be as high as 300,000 to 400,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time, the Antarctic trip has been a niche high-end project. Many people don’t know about it. This is the first time for many people to hear that it is okay. Travel to Antarctica. Is traveling to Antarctica difficult and expensive? Is traveling to Antarctica a matter of spending money to enjoy the unique beauty, or is it &quot;spending money to buy suffering&quot;? Will many people traveling to Antarctica damage the ecological environment of Antarctica? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/Ry46lJqqtjt2vMlY9w62dFLPyCkmUXDliLD7DCL3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/Ry46lJqqtjt2vMlY9w62dFLPyCkmUXDliLD7DCL3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Is it difficult to travel to Antarctica&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica is the southernmost point of the earth. It is the last one to be discovered on the earth and the only one without humans. A continent where people live and settle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a long time in the past, Antarctica was a mysterious place in the world until Antarctica was discovered in 1820. Since then, Antarctica has also been mainly used as a scientific research base. In December 1911, the Norwegian Amundsen expedition reached the Antarctic Pole for the first time. In 1985, my country established a scientific research station in Antarctica for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Antarctica is also a tourist destination. In the 1950s, the world&#39;s first international tourist group of 500 people went to Antarctica, and Antarctic tourism officially appeared. 2007 was the first year for China to launch Antarctic tourism, and China’s first officially recognized Antarctic tour line was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to statistics from the International Association of Antarctic Tourism Operators (IAATO), China is the second largest source of tourists to Antarctica. In the 2017-2018 Antarctic tourism season, a total of 51,707 tourists from around the world visited Antarctica, and the number of Chinese tourists reached 8,273, accounting for 16%, second only to the United States. A total of 1,464 Chinese people went to Antarctica in the 2022-23 Antarctic season. It is expected that in the 2023-24 Antarctic tourism season, Chinese tourists will return to 80% of the pre-epidemic number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica does not have four seasons, only two seasons, namely the warm season (November-March) and the cold season (April-October). The warm season is also the tourist season in Antarctica, because it is almost daytime and the temperature is higher, making it more suitable for tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Theoretically, as long as it is the Antarctic tourist season, everyone can travel to Antarctica, because traveling to Antarctica does not require a visa, and Antarctica does not belong to any nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a practical point of view, traveling to Antarctica is difficult. After all, our country does not have direct commercial flights to Antarctica. Tourists must first go to a country relatively close to Antarctica. , such as Argentina, Australia or New Zealand, and then go to Antarctica via cruise ships or flights from these transit countries. Therefore, if you want to apply for a transit country visa when going to Antarctica, you also need the help and services of a professional travel company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/bcdfUdi8XYsJEq5ytx0qk74142tITCWOEmb4Y18g.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/bcdfUdi8XYsJEq5ytx0qk74142tITCWOEmb4Y18g.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Appreciate beauty, or buy into suffering? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As you can imagine, Antarctica has breathtaking beauty. 98% of the Antarctic continent is covered with ice and snow all year round, making people feel like they are in a pure white world, which is extremely clear and translucent from the eyes to the soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Here, tourists will tremble at the miraculous workmanship of nature. They can enjoy the natural landscape of eternal daylight and interact with the masters of Antarctica - penguins, Blue whales, sea lions and various seagulls coexist harmoniously and happily...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctic tours can provide us with exclusive experiences that cannot be experienced anywhere else in the world. In order to enrich the fun of the journey, travel companies will also carry out outdoor activities such as hiking, kayaking and camping in Antarctica. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Going to Antarctica to appreciate the beauty behind it also requires paying a high cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind the long journey is the sound of money disappearing. Nowadays, the mainstream Antarctic tourism projects in China are to fly from China to Argentina first, and then take a cruise to Antarctica via Argentina. The departure point of most cruise ships is Ushuaia, the southernmost tip of Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The flight from China to Buenos Aires, Argentina takes about 40 hours (and you have to endure the troublesome transfer). It takes a long time to take a cruise from the Argentine port to sea. It takes between 2 and 5 days of sailing time to reach the Antarctic continent. Tourists can choose to spend only a few days in the Antarctic continent; they can also choose &quot;Antarctic Peninsula + Antarctic Circle&quot;, which will sail southward through the Antarctic Circle based on the Antarctic Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A trip to Antarctica can take about ten days if it is short, or twenty or thirty days if it is long. Depending on the aircraft cabin, cruise class and accommodation environment, the price also varies greatly. For example, the prices of various cruise companies are basically 60,000-200,000 yuan per person. Therefore, the total cost of a trip to Antarctica ranges from 70,000 to 80,000 yuan for a cheap trip to 30,000 to 400,000 yuan for an expensive trip, or even higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The challenge of traveling to Antarctica is not only the high price, but also the &quot;suffering&quot; during the journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cruise ships arriving at the Antarctic continent basically have to pass through the Drake Strait. This is the widest strait in the world and the deepest strait in the world. Due to the influence of polar cyclones, there are strong winds and huge waves all year round. The wind force is basically above level 8 all year round. When a cruise ship passes through it, the hull will inevitably shake violently, and the probability of seasickness and vomiting among tourists is extremely high, so much so that there is a saying, &quot;If you haven&#39;t fainted once in the Drake Passage, don&#39;t say you have been to Antarctica.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tourists who travel to Antarctica often have polarizing opinions about this journey. Some people think that the trip is worthwhile and it is a unique experience in life. Some people frankly say that spending money to buy the experience makes Antarctic travel &quot;so cold, so far, so expensive, and so boring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Will tourism harm Antarctica&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Antarctica is recognized by the world It is a nature reserve shared by all mankind, and the protection of Antarctica has long been established in the form of international conventions. On December 1, 1959, the Antarctic Treaty was signed and came into effect on June 23, 1961. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Antarctic Convention&quot; aims to restrict the activities of various countries in Antarctica, the only continent on earth without a permanent population, and ensure that countries respect Antarctica. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1991, the Special Meeting of the Antarctic Treaty Consultative Countries adopted the &quot;Antarctic Treaty Protocol on Environmental Protection&quot; with a view to environmental protection in Antarctica. As one of the negotiating countries, China signed the protocol. The protocol sets out strict protection measures to protect the ecological environment of the Antarctic continent and nearby areas from damage. Later, the International Association of Antarctic Tourism Operators also issued the &quot;Activity Guide for Antarctic Tourism Practitioners&quot; and the &quot;Activity Guide for Antarctic Tourists&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the constraints of these treaties, travel to Antarctica must abide by some principles. For example, large ships cannot stay in a certain place for more than 5 hours; each trip to the island Only 100 people can log in; you cannot take the initiative to get within 5 meters of the penguins; you must clean your shoes after disembarking from the boat and returning to the boat to avoid biological invasion, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, climate disasters have already had a serious impact on Antarctic ecology. As the Earth heats up, Antarctic glaciers are melting and becoming more fragile. Research shows that from 1997 to 2021, more than 40% of Antarctic ice shelves have shrunk significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nowadays, frequent human travel activities may make the Antarctic snow melt faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Last year, a paper published in Nature Communications pointed out that black carbon pollution at tourist arrival points in Antarctica may increase these area of ​​snowmelt. The burning of fossil and biomass fuels creates black carbon, which absorbs light and heats the atmosphere. If black carbon falls on snow, it melts faster. As a result, environmentalists loudly shouted: Please reduce unnecessary Antarctic travel and protect the natural ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Embarrassingly, many domestic companies that launch Antarctic tour projects promote one of the reasons for Antarctic tours is that &quot;some Antarctic glaciers are melting at an accelerating rate and are losing their The original natural beauty. The earlier you go, the less likely you will be able to see the most primitive Antarctic continent and retain the beauty and primitiveness that is about to disappear!&quot; However, the arrival of more and more tourists is exacerbating the melting of Antarctic ice and snow and destroying the beauty of Antarctica. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This does not mean that all Antarctic tours should be cancelled. Man and nature can coexist harmoniously. However, it is indeed necessary to speed up the use of clean energy in Antarctic tourism, limit the number of tourists, strengthen the supervision of Antarctic tourism, and strengthen the implementation of the Antarctic Treaty, so as to minimize the negative impact of human activities in Antarctica on the Antarctic ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[威马破产重整，车主面临“售后难”：购置电车须评估六大风险]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the National Enterprise Bankruptcy and Reorganization Case Information Network, WM Motor Technology Group Co., Ltd. has applied for bankruptcy and reorganization WM Motor&#39;s official Weibo issued a notification letter in response, saying that the company still has salvage value and hopes to actively save itself by adjusting corporate strategies, solving financial debt problems, and getting investors to participate in restructuring and development. However, according to feedback from many WM owners, in early 2023, WM supporting software frequently experienced failures such as &quot;unable to connect, network abnormality&quot; and so on. In response to this, WM Motor publicly responded: &quot;Currently, WM Motor&#39;s engine system has returned to normal, and we sincerely apologize for the inconvenience caused to everyone!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the current situation, if we cannot wait for the &quot;White Horse Rider&quot; &quot;Once WM Motor goes bankrupt, more than 100,000 car owners will face a &quot;complete shutdown&quot; of their vehicle systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main components of electric vehicles have changed from the engine and gearbox of previous fuel vehicles to three-electric systems. In the electric vehicle maintenance market, new energy vehicle-related product technologies and parts supply are all mastered In the hands of OEMs and EMC manufacturers, independent repairers rarely participate. This means that when electric vehicle companies such as WM Motor are eliminated due to factors such as fierce market competition, the after-sales service chain will be broken, and car owners will not be able to find corresponding substitutes in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of a Weimar owner is a typical example. The power battery of the WM EX5 car he purchased malfunctioned. When it was charged to 80%, it would automatically jump to 100%. When the remaining 20% ​​of power was used, the car would stop moving. Because it was still within the manufacturer&#39;s warranty period, the car owner drove the car to the Kuangshan store of Jinan Weima User Center for repair. It still has not been repaired in nearly half a year because the manufacturer did not provide spare parts. The car owner contacted the 4S store again, and the 4S store said that it could no longer operate and asked him to tow the car away and solve the problem himself. The car owner also complained to the manufacturer many times, but it has not been resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weima owners are facing &quot;after-sales difficulties&quot;, which reveals that electric cars are not as beautiful as the owners imagined. Due to strong policy support, China&#39;s electric vehicle industry has developed rapidly. The latest statistics released by the Ministry of Public Security show that the number of electric vehicles in China currently exceeds 18 million. However, with the rapid development of electric vehicles, there are still six major risks. In addition to the difficulties encountered by Weimar owners mentioned above, they also involve aspects such as cruising range, charging, vehicle safety, data and privacy, and assisted driving. When buying a car, car owners must not Not aware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some electric vehicle manufacturers deliberately exaggerate the cruising range of their vehicles in order to promote sales. According to a report by China Times in March this year, most new energy vehicle 4S stores marked the NEDC comprehensive working condition (driving cycle test) cruising range and did not mark the actual cruising range. Mr. Liu, an online ride-hailing driver, told a reporter from China Times that an electric car he mentioned in May 2022 had a range of 505 kilometers, but in actual driving, whether it was driving on the highway or in the city, , the cruising range can only reach about 300 kilometers, and in winter it only has more than 200 kilometers, and once it even &quot;slumped down&quot; on the highway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cruising range is not worthy of its name, and electric vehicles charge slowly, often taking six to eight hours to fully charge. This greatly affects the consumer experience. Especially when there is an urgent need for a car, long charging time will make consumers feel very inconvenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, electric vehicle companies have provided two options. One is the DC fast charging mode, which takes 1 to 1.5 hours. However, frequent use of fast charging mode will affect battery life. Therefore, current electric vehicles still mainly rely on AC slow charging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, some car companies provide battery swapping models, but the costs for car owners are high. At the same time, the investment cost of battery swapping stations is high and the number of built ones is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The safety of electric vehicles is another major pain point that consumers are concerned about. In recent years, there have been many accidents involving spontaneous combustion of electric vehicles, posing a serious threat to the life and property safety of car owners. Statistics from the emergency management department show that in the first quarter of 2023 alone, the spontaneous combustion rate of electric vehicles increased by 32%, with an average of 8 electric vehicles catching fire (including spontaneous combustion) every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the directions for the intelligentization of electric vehicles is digitization. Electric vehicles can not only collect the owner’s face data through the in-car camera, but may also collect information such as the owner’s place of residence, whereabouts, and consumption places. , once such data is leaked by car companies or stolen by hackers, it will cause more serious consequences. According to a notice issued by the Maine Attorney General&#39;s Office in August this year, Tesla&#39;s data breach in May affected more than 75,000 people, including records related to employees. The incident originated from &quot;internal Employee misconduct”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The application of assisted driving technology in electric vehicles will bring more problems. Some car companies refer to assisted driving technology as &quot;assisted autonomous driving&quot; or &quot;autonomous assisted driving&quot;. Sales staff will hype it up when promoting, beautifying it as &quot;autonomous driving&quot;. If there is an accident, it will become &quot;assisted driving&quot;. . The assisted driving technology used by many electric vehicles currently has a paradox in itself. It not only advocates liberating the driver, but also requires the driver to supervise and be ready to take over anytime and anywhere. If an accident occurs, how to divide the responsibilities between the driver and the car company? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the six major risks associated with electric vehicles may be improved with technological advancement, while others may remain unresolved for a long time. Therefore, when people buy electric vehicles, they must not be concerned about the risks promoted by car companies. &quot;Environmental protection&quot; (the degree of environmental pollution caused by batteries is not low) and &quot;intelligence&quot; are fully accepted, but it is still necessary to evaluate rationally and objectively before deciding whether to place an order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院印发《关于取消和调整一批罚款事项的决定》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259818]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to further optimize the business environment, the State Council recently issued the &quot;Decision on Cancellation and Adjustment of a Group of Fines&quot; ( (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;), 33 fines were canceled and adjusted in the fields of industry, information technology, housing and urban-rural construction, among which 16 fines were canceled and 17 fines were adjusted. If fine matters are canceled, the relevant fine provisions in relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be temporarily suspended from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot;; if fines are adjusted, the relevant fine provisions in the revised relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 16 fines canceled by the &quot;Decision&quot; include 2 from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 2 from the Ministry of Education, 5 from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, 3 from the People&#39;s Bank of China, and 1 from the National Forestry and Grassland Administration. , 1 State Post Bureau, 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention; 17 fines adjusted, including 1 Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 1 Ministry of Emergency Management, 13 National Press and Publication Administration, and 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention. These fines are mainly concentrated in areas closely related to the production and life of enterprises and the people. The purpose of cancellation and adjustment is to effectively reduce the burden on enterprises and the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cancellation and adjustment of fines involve a total of 7 administrative regulations and 6 departmental regulations. The &quot;Decision&quot; puts forward clear requirements for the legislative work after the cancellation and adjustment of fines. Relevant departments of the State Council must submit relevant administrative regulations modification plans to the State Council within 60 days from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot; and complete the modification and abolition of relevant departmental regulations. If departmental regulations need to be adjusted according to the revised administrative regulations, the modification and abolition must be completed within 60 days from the date of promulgation of the relevant administrative regulations. Considering that there is a 30-day period for soliciting opinions on the modification and abolition of departmental regulations, it is stipulated that if the modification or abolition of departmental regulations cannot be completed within the above period due to special reasons, it may be appropriately extended, but the extension period shall not exceed 30 days at most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Decision&quot; emphasizes that after the fines are cancelled, the relevant departments must study carefully in accordance with the law, strictly implement regulatory responsibilities, focus on strengthening supervision during and after the event, improve supervision methods, standardize supervision procedures, and improve the scientific and scientific nature of supervision. Simplicity and precision further enhance regulatory efficiency and provide strong support for promoting high-quality development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“丑小鸭”的生长：一所学校防治青少年抑郁的探索与思考]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259838]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 17:58:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/epeeemYXf9dkI727T4PbzTs2ff4ZarA2VMg8Hxh4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1578&quot; height=&quot;1106&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/epeeemYXf9dkI727T4PbzTs2ff4Z arA2VMg8Hxh4. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2023, girls confided and comforted each other on the playground of Ugly Duckling Middle School &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Did you want to come here on your own, or were you &#39;tricked&#39; by your parents?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Half and half. When I came here, I realized, hey, it&#39;s not at all what I thought.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the bright sun, more than a dozen buses and minibuses were parked here. The mountainside of Ruixing Village in Yiliang, Kunming. Hundreds of people filed in, lingering in the classrooms, student dormitories, book bars, and running tracks of this rural school, observing carefully, even the bathrooms painted with paint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visitors include principals, moral education directors, classroom teachers from all over the country, officials and entrepreneurs from the local education sector, social organizations engaged in family education and private innovative education, as well as some who “can’t figure it out” in their own families. Parents worried about their children. They were curious about how a school called &quot;Ugly Duckling Middle School&quot; could help a group of children who seemed to be surly, tired of studying, or even suffering from deep depression to blossom into a natural and brilliant life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these questions, the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; principal Zhan Danian always smiles and does not answer immediately. In the 13 years since he founded this school, various questions and controversies have continued, which he no longer thinks is strange. But he did not expect that the youth depression problem that he had deeply realized in running the school would actually trigger a strong response after launching the &quot;First Youth Psychological Safety Forum&quot; (jointly with the China Education Thirty Forum), and the reverberation continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 China Mental Health&quot; Blue Book released on October 10, 2023 shows that 40% of Chinese teenagers feel lonely, the depression detection rate among high school students is 40%, and the depression detection rate among junior high school students is 40%. is 50%, and the risk of mild anxiety among college students is 38%. Peng Kaiping, dean of the Academy of Social Sciences of Tsinghua University, once wrote an article pointing out that today&#39;s Chinese teenagers have &quot;four no&#39;s&quot;: no interest in learning, no interest in the real world, no ability to deal with the real society, and no interest in life. Therefore, the theme of this forum has been upgraded from the previously mentioned &quot;youth mental health&quot; to &quot;psychological safety&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BcDl53HOeKhBlcjWZsACyCKlrhO9mJTFm3q4LvX9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height= &quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BcDl53HOeKhBlcjWZsACyCKlrhO9mJTFm3q4LvX9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the psychology room of Ugly Duckling Middle School, teacher Li Guihong (middle) performs sand table psychotherapy for students. Some students also sit quietly and relax here&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhan Danian’s view, depression is just a symptom, and behind it are the flaws in the current educational ecology. &quot;The essence of education is to develop students&#39; personalities, rather than using a ruler to measure students. The best and most equitable education should be education that adapts to students&#39; personalities, so that every student&#39;s potential can be developed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have actually heard this argument too many times. The key is how to put it into practice. Therefore, in the &quot;wild education&quot; of the &quot;ugly duckling&quot;, is there really any experience that can be discovered and learned from to prevent and treat depression in teenagers? What kind of social and family symptoms are behind every depressed child? Are they definitely unsolvable? Our reporters went to Kunming and Yiliang to explore the possibility of dispelling the shadow of education under the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/cnGVQpHqsTRAN5BW8PNj5Om1pOjzY81isic8ZjO9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;545&quot; height= &quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/cnGVQpHqsTRAN5BW8PNj5Om1pOjzY81isic8ZjO9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 11:30 in the morning, the students of Ugly Duckling Middle School were having physical education class. Students in this school have about 3 hours of outdoor exercise time every day&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; It’s all my fault”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Pu Pu actually loves to laugh. But in the crowd, with her dark face, ponytail, and big black-rimmed glasses, she didn&#39;t often make a sound. On a 30℃ day, my body is still huddled in a collared sweater and a jacket. When you open your mouth, the sound coming out of the braces is very soft, like a porcelain bowl that is afraid of breaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I noticed her in class. In the Chinese class of teacher Juanjuan in the second grade of junior high school, Pu Pu raised her hand, which surprised me, who initially thought she would not want to speak. But two minutes later, she lowered her head and body, and closed her eyes, as if everything around her had nothing to do with her. This state of affairs occurs constantly in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s a reaction after taking medicine.&quot; Psychology teacher Li Guihong told me. When he first arrived at &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, Pu Pu had to take more than 20 pills of medication to treat mental illness at a time, but now the medication has been reduced by more than half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two years ago, Pu Pu was in the first grade of junior high school in Kunming, a middle school known for its academic performance. Like other branches of this education group, almost nothing is allowed here that is not related to study. It is strictly forbidden to move or talk during meals and lunch breaks. If you are &quot;disobedient&quot;, the dormitory aunt will record your name, deduct points, and scold you. Pu Pu once had his name recorded because he took a few minutes longer to take a shower. He got a little excited while chatting with his classmates at noon, so he was also recorded. &quot;The punishment is a slap on the palm, but it doesn&#39;t hurt. There is also running, which requires many laps.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t you think this kind of management is a bit strict?&quot; I asked her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t count. I broke the rules in the first place, and it&#39;s all my fault.&quot; She answered quietly in the rest area next to the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reading for a while, Pu Pu began to suffer from insomnia and developed delusional symptoms. &quot;Sometimes I feel happy, and sometimes I feel uncomfortable. When I feel uncomfortable, I can&#39;t control myself and scream loudly.&quot; She asked her parents to see a psychiatrist. Later, she was diagnosed with &quot;depression and anxiety disorder&quot; and was admitted to the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu Pu’s parents run a dental clinic and are very caring towards her. &quot;During the time I was hospitalized, my father was at work and my mother often stayed with me in the hospital.&quot; She had undergone MECT (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;non-convulsive electroshock&lt;/span>; ) and transcranial magnetism (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;physical device that stimulates brain nerves&lt;/span>;) treatments, except for dizziness and numbness, did not have much effect. Pu Pu dropped out of school. In the past two years, she gained weight due to medication and other reasons. Her heaviest weight was close to 70 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/TJoN8oef5Juq9tWKgF4rQvSNw2dkpGJCEAFagyfE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height= &quot;337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/TJoN8oef5Juq9tWKgF4rQvSNw2dkpGJCEAFagyfE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aerial view of the Ugly Duckling Middle School campus&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Bad moods still came up from time to time like a tide. When she couldn&#39;t stand it anymore, Pu Pu would hit her head against the wall, cry, and pinch her throat with her hands... More than once, she wanted to open the window and jump. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are other ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rolling up her sleeves, Pu Pu’s arms, from palm to elbow, were densely covered with new flesh that was a minute or two thicker than the original skin after twenty or thirty cuts with a knife, like a row. Light-colored thorns winding up. There are several more in the middle, which are longer, deeper, and redder in color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Does it hurt when you paddle?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No.&quot; She shook her head and smiled. &quot;Seeing blood relieves stress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those late nights when she couldn&#39;t get through it, patients she met while she was in the hospital sent her messages and asked her to try other methods, such as scratching paper, throwing stuffed toys, and picking at the wall. &quot;They also advised me not to think about (suicide) so much. Some (symptoms) are milder than yours, and some are more severe than yours. You will definitely get better slowly.&quot; After hearing these kind words of comfort, Pu Pu would stop. &quot;I actually don&#39;t believe what they said. But when I think about how hard it was for my parents to give birth to and raise me, I can&#39;t just give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still think that suffering from mental illness is all a matter of Is it my own problem?&quot; I asked her again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Well... I didn&#39;t adjust my mentality well. I used to have low self-esteem. I didn&#39;t like my skin being so dark. It turned out that my classmates at school called me &#39;black girl&#39;. I was unhappy and also I keep it in my heart.&quot; She raised her head and opened her eyes: &quot;But I am optimistic now. I don&#39;t think there is any problem with being black. And my mother said that there are many medical beauty methods now. If I want, I can also have whitening when I grow up. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year ago, Pu Pu was sent as an &quot;ugly duckling&quot;. &quot;She didn&#39;t like to laugh very much and couldn&#39;t integrate into the group.&quot; During the &quot;attack&quot;, she trembled all over and pulled her hair, causing two people to suffer. Only then can she be held back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Zhan Danian and Li Guihong said that adults need to pay attention to children&#39;s paddling and &quot;self-injury&quot;, but do not need to be too frightened. &quot;Some are seeking stimulation, some are subconscious, and some are emotional releases. They may want you to see it. What you have to do is to give them enough understanding and protection.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For various physical symptoms and stress In response, Li Guihong recorded her experience in the industry for more than ten years in a notebook, as well as some practices she learned from Liu Zhiyou, a special psychological consultant for &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot; and a Taiwanese brain science expert: when dealing with children with trembling hands and feet, first touch them gently. If they have violent behaviors such as hitting the wall, you can give them electrolyte water and touch other parts of the body. After the child calmed down a little, she also taught the student the &quot;Flat Throwing Kung Fu&quot;: half-squatting, slowly shaking both hands up and down. Sometimes she would also give the children some lemon slices, &quot;I said eating this will make them feel better quickly, and psychological suggestions can also work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CpuvdptotWQHlYpaDKBAVn7smjmQGGQ6cJciqfkk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/01/CpuvdptotWQHlYpaDKBAVn7smjmQGGQ6cJciqfkk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ugly Duckling Middle School Boys Dormitory&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During class time and after class in the afternoon, students will always enter the first floor in twos and threes. This psych room on the left. They hugged the big furry bears on the sofas and cushions; some would chat with &quot;Lao Li&quot; - this is their pet name for Li Guihong; some spent half an hour drawing mandoles in the cubicle. Luo (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A painting therapy invented by psychologist Jung&lt;/span>;). &quot;Old Li, why haven&#39;t my paintings been hung up?&quot; A child said, half coquettishly and half angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How about you draw a more interesting one? I will consider it later.&quot; Li Guihong secretly told me, asking whether this child is a student specializing in art. &quot;I have to give other children more opportunities.&quot; I suddenly remembered that when I visited the girls&#39; dormitory on the first day, there were several girls on the upper bunk with their legs curled up and their heads raised, painting, and one of them was Pu Pu. In the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, all greening and interior and exterior decorations are completed by students according to their own wishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one seems to regard this psychological room with warm colors as a therapeutic place. It has naturally become a transfer station, chat room and tea room for emotional flow. &quot;They are willing to come here for no particular purpose. They can relax and clear their minds. That&#39;s good.&quot; Li Guihong said. When encountering a child like Pu Pu who needs special treatment, if she is willing to chat, she and her colleague Yang Haoming will divide the work; if not, the first thing to do is still: give time and wait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Only when the child&#39;s emotions are relatively intense and several people have &#39;attacks&#39; at the same time, I feel a little powerless.&quot; She smiled, &quot;But there are other teachers who can take turns to deal with it, so don&#39;t be afraid.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/vMJ3G8t4amWuAREHAtZnY6sTReZXiQLvcCYK1bfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;297 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/vMJ3G8t4amWuAREHAtZnY6sTReZXiQLvcCYK1bfb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students are reading beside the bookshelf at the entrance of the classroom. Students can freely read and borrow books in the school’s public spaces &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The entire The world is sick, and so am I.&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Li Guihong&#39;s view, although Pu Pu&#39;s &quot;physical symptoms&quot; are severe, she is a very innocent, open and friendly child. &quot;If it weren&#39;t for taking too many pills, she would be in good condition. She is recovering well now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When some children first arrived, they were arrogant and said, &quot;Thinking that everything is other people&#39;s.&quot; It’s their fault. They often feel excluded and isolated from the entire world, and tend to avoid social interactions.” Some of these students may have already constructed or are forming their own worldview and set of behavioral logic. They are like big rocks on the cliff, shining brightly, but also easy to fall, and need the support of the big trees on the cliff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing that I wanted to chat with him in the military training class, Tian Lam’s eyes lit up as he shuffled slowly: “YES!” Later I learned that as long as there was no class, he would secretly happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering the large conference room on the first floor, only the two of us were left. Tian Lan sat down in an almost &quot;Ge You lying&quot; posture without any restraint. When faced with many questions, he would pause for five or six seconds before slowly spitting out his answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the topic involved emotions and &quot;depression&quot;, he seemed to be waking up from a dream, &quot;Then why are you looking for me -&quot; I thought the conversation was about to reach a deadlock, but he said again: &quot; This needs to be traced back all the way...even though I am only 14 years old, it has already run through my short life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan grew up in a provincial capital city in the south of the Yangtze River. A year or two before coming to the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, he dropped out of school for six months and was bored at home without ever leaving the house. Watching videos and reading novels. The longest time I stayed awake was more than fifty hours. He originally weighed 140 pounds, but lost dozens of pounds because he only had one meal in a day or two. &quot;It&#39;s not nutritious. Even my nails are only cut once a month.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unbeknownst to him, he refused to hear any sound at that time. He would explode whenever he heard a sound and would not let his father live at home. &quot;I just drove him away. They say &#39;filial piety comes first&#39;, but I actually beat my parents. I couldn&#39;t help it. After the beating, my mother cried, and I cried with her.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A psychiatrist was also found. Yes, come to see a doctor. Tian Lan didn&#39;t accept any of it. &quot;The questions they asked were very boring, and I couldn&#39;t see anything credible from them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Day and night are reversed, lifeless. At that time, Tian Lan&#39;s only thought was &quot;stay at home until the age of 18 and then die.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What happened before that? I asked him several times. He frowned and fell into memories, &quot;I can&#39;t tell.&quot; From childhood to junior high school, the memory puzzle was full of cracks. The description of the past is mixed with recognition, resentment, reflection, and more confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan’s father is a middle-level cadre of a state-owned enterprise, and his mother takes care of him full-time. The relationship with them cannot be said to be very bad, nor can it be said to be very good. When he was about 10 years old, his piano teacher scolded him fiercely because he made a mistake in practicing the piano, &quot;and even threw the milk out.&quot; After passing the level 10 piano test, he said, &quot;I never want to touch this thing again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just read it In the first year of junior high school, he was in a well-known foreign language school in the provincial capital, and his classmates seemed to be better than him. &quot;There were only 9 classes in the whole grade at that time, and I was in class 2109. But they said I was in class 10. Everyone was having fun, except me. I suspected that I had a neurological problem. Why can others socialize but I can&#39;t?&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan longed for a friend, but the result was zero. Then he didn&#39;t want to do his homework anymore. &quot;My mother said you can do whatever you want.&quot; He didn&#39;t go to school for a month. Man, completely wilted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Half a year after dropping out of school, he entered a local &quot;closed school&quot; under military management (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Special Training School&lt;/p>; span>;). &quot;Yes, it&#39;s like XX Academy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Strict control is not important. I hate the underworld.&quot; He emphasized. In Tian Lan’s description, the school is very popular (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Two sounds, meaning deceitful&lt;/span>;), &quot;teachers, gangsters&quot; They all bully others and hit them wherever they want. The boys&#39; class doesn&#39;t treat others as human beings. There are surveillance cameras everywhere just for parents to see. Even if they wipe their noses during assembly, they can be pulled to the stairwell.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first arrived at the closed school, my limb functions deteriorated a bit because I stayed at home for too long: my fingers were weak and my eyes couldn’t focus. After a few periods of military class, he heard two &quot;clicks&quot; from his knees and fell to the playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After five days like this, the instructor and classmates thought he was faking. &quot;I went to the village hospital to take a picture. I fractured my knee, and the doctor took a picture of my calf!&quot; He said with a &quot;bewildered&quot; expression. When he went to see the doctor for a follow-up visit, there were many teachers beside the car taking him to the hospital, but no one helped him pull the wheelchair or push him into the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The whole world is sick. I am also sick.&quot; He smiled habitually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How could you stay in such an environment for 8 months? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I later learned to tolerate it. Not long after I arrived, I complained to my dad and begged him to take me away. He just smiled. But you know, I have been in a closed school for a long time. , I even feel a little warm! I have found a little feeling of home.&quot; He himself couldn&#39;t believe this mentality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before and after the school was closed, he attended several other schools. Tian Lan was amazed at &quot;How come the world has become so weird in just over a year&quot;: &quot;Some schools are eager to learn all the contents of junior high school as soon as they are promoted from primary school to junior high school. Some even don&#39;t have enough time to go to the toilet and don&#39;t understand. Every day before the exam They all talked about test papers. Didn’t my mother tell the teacher at the new school that I had a fracture? The frostbite pustules on my hands left in the closed school have not gone away for a year. The teacher asked, didn’t you have a fracture? You were resting at home, so what are you doing? Will there be frostbite?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This heart is not completely dead. What Tian Lan wants to learn most is Go. His best result is amateur fifth-dan: it is no exaggeration to say that 99% of ordinary people are no longer his opponents in Go. &quot;You don&#39;t have to think about sixth-dan. I will be among the top three in provincial and municipal competitions. I think I have some talent. But what&#39;s the use of passing the exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yb5knYK1H5M5xPYAGDUsjuZwJWyvrG62KRQXEuVY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;297&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/01/yb5knYK1H5M5xPYAGDUsjuZwJWyvrG62KRQXEuVY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students decorate with brushes Girls dormitory &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He liked Liu Cixin and listened to &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; using podcast software when he dropped out of school , and love to read &quot;Supernova Era&quot; and many other short stories. &quot;Have you ever heard of &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;an open world role-playing game&lt;/span>;)? Others are just counting numbers (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Combat damage value)&lt;/span>;, I study the culture inside. I always fantasize about many strange things, those data and my imagination , formed many different worlds belonging to me...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He tilted his head and fell into a fugue again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of all the people, his cousin who was five months older than him had the greatest influence on him. My uncle and aunt were very strict with my cousin, but during the COVID-19 epidemic, the two brothers still had fun in the countryside of their hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The house in my hometown is big, with a mountain behind it. The top of the mountain was cut in half, and a slope protruded from the cliff. We cut down the weeds, built steps, and dug many holes. After the grass grew, we repaired it ourselves. Let&#39;s call it the &#39;Temple of Earth&#39;, haha. That&#39;s our &#39;Hundred Garden&#39;.&quot; He grinned for the first time in the two hours of chatting. &quot;There is a big pond in the back mountain. We use a big net to catch fish, and there are a lot of shrimps and crabs. There are many flowers, plants and trees on the path over the pond, which is fun.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the last time I saw my cousin, In his eyes, the other person has &quot;grown up&quot;, his voice has changed, and he is a little unfamiliar, &quot;We can&#39;t play together anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Guihong feels that Tian Lan&#39;s understanding of people and the world is narrow. &quot;But he is a child with a strong sense of justice and cannot hold a grain of sand in his eyes. So he will have his own expectations and requirements for the environment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is why Tian Lan feels that, compared to others, The &quot;ugly duckling&quot; whose place is already much better will still have situations where &quot;small groups&quot; &quot;bully the weak&quot; that he can&#39;t stand. Vice-principal Xiang Guoyue and life teacher Long Chengtong (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Long Ge&quot;&lt;/span>;) neither deny that they have a naughty personality and a bit of a tad There are indeed children in the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; who are addicted to the world. &quot;We will observe and deal with it, and we will also let each child face his own problems.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Lao Li said that I have problems with my emotions and emotional expression. I also feel that I am a little confused. As the saying goes , only after you have experienced it will you feel more... precious? I can&#39;t describe it.&quot; Tian Lan let out a long sigh. &quot;Anyway, I feel that my life is not worth it and I hope to do it all over again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ 471J7UgFwzxkHKyWZMNg9esZ9twVNQJ4swH9nKtU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/471J7UgFwzxkHKyWZMNg9esZ9twVNQJ4sw H9nKtU.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;256489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhan Danian at school&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;At an altitude of 1,800 meters, waiting for the flowers to bloom&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Children like Pu Pu and Tian Lan, in the Ugly Duckling Middle School in mid-October 2023, a total of There are more than seventy people. Some of them had mild or obvious symptoms of depression when they entered school, and some had already been diagnosed with depression or anxiety and took medication to enroll. There are also some &quot;problem students&quot; who may have nothing to do with &quot;depression&quot; but are troublesome to the original school or parents and difficult to discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Danian, the founder of &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, does not accept this labeling term. In his eyes, every child does not have any big problems. They just cannot adapt to the teaching methods and evaluation standards of traditional education, and encounter various obstacles in getting along with their families, teachers, and peers. &quot;I even feel that in the era of ChatGPT, these so-called &#39;problem children&#39; are more creative and more hopeful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1981, Zhan Danian, a native of Yiyang, Hunan Province, graduated from a normal college at the age of 26. Became the youngest principal in Taojiang County. During his tenure, the rural school that originally had just over a hundred students expanded into a medium-sized school with over a thousand students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after working in the system for nearly 20 years, Zhan Danian decided to resign. After that, he came to Yunnan and participated in the establishment of two private schools. Until 2011, he founded the Ugly Duckling Middle School with his wife Yang Liufang and several colleagues, and made it his lifelong ambition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My leaving the system has nothing to do with courage, but with personal choice.&quot; He emphasized again and again. &quot;Our educational environment places too much emphasis on &#39;picking the best and chasing the poor&#39;. Once the children do not do well, they seem to have no future. The value of education is to develop people, how can it become the elimination of people? I want to give myself and those who are not valued and The caring children find a way out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Danian&#39;s Mandarin has a strong Yiyang accent, and he once said with a smile that &quot;the voice software cannot recognize it.&quot; But this man with a face like Maitreya and a slightly bulging belly has become a powerful activist in innovative education. Over the years, he has blazed a path that seems to be a &quot;deviant path&quot; but is actually a &quot;passenger path&quot; that is extremely difficult to imitate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, students generally enroll for as little as 5 months and as long as more than two years, and will study courses from the first to the third grade of junior high school. Zhan Danian hopes that after they study here for about 10 months, their behavior and habits will return to normal and they can handle their interpersonal relationships normally, and then he will persuade them to return to their original school. &quot;After all, it is more convenient to go back to study with your parents. Its mission is not to let the children enter high school first, but to live a normal life or even survive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the year when the school was founded, Zhan Danian&#39;s good friend, Wang Yeju, deputy director of the Culture and History Committee of the Yunnan Provincial Committee of the CPPCC, named the school &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;. Many people couldn&#39;t understand it. Some freshmen also thought it was &quot;very earthy&quot;, but Zhan Danian felt like he had found a treasure: &quot;The duckling may be eaten by others, but the ugly duckling may be eaten by others.&quot; I will definitely be able to fly in one day!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of the so-called &quot;problem children&quot; are accompanied by social and psychological problems. But in the first few years, Zhan Danian and his colleagues did not discover and realize the seriousness of the problem. Until 2021, an internal psychological assessment at the school found that 71 of more than 90 students at the school were rated as &quot;severely depressed.&quot; He began to seriously examine this issue and spoke out many times on private accounts and other occasions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I want more people to understand teenage depression. Depression can be treated. But we should understand the voices of children more. They should not be marginalized.&quot; Before coming to Yiliang, he spoke on the phone Tell me solemnly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before traveling, I asked him to share a few &quot;cases&quot; of depressed students. He smiled and said, &quot;Who is the right person to talk about? You can talk to the children at will when you come. Each of their experiences can write a million-word novel.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late autumn season, from Kunming Less than an hour&#39;s drive later, we entered Yiliang County and walked upstream along the Nanpan River. After passing bougainvillea and bushes along the way, our noses began to be filled with the &quot;scent&quot; of chicken and duck feces and the smoke of burning straw all over the village. At the fork in the road, there is a sign indicating &quot;Ugly Duckling Middle School&quot; pointing in the direction of the destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original location of Ugly Duckling is located in the ancient town of Yiliang North, with convenient transportation. However, because the school building was in disrepair, more than two years ago, Zhan Danian led everyone to move the school to a new location more than 1,800 meters above sea level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As you step into the teaching building, you will be greeted by the wooden bars, bookcases and guitars hanging all over the wall in the corridor on the first floor. The wood is taken from local fir trees. The wood is not expensive, but it is tall and beautiful. &quot;The children built it together with us.&quot; Zhan Danian introduced. The camphor trees and geraniums outside the window, the coral cherry blossoms, Guanyin lotus, Green Princess, platinum philodendron on the windowsill, the layers of green in the pots are very pleasant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It may seem ordinary, but it has “superior” conditions that most schools in China cannot match: an average of more than 2,100 hours of sunshine per year. During the day in October, I feel slightly hot after just a few minutes with my back to the sun. Zhu Xiaomao, a visiting educator, couldn&#39;t help himself. He took three books as pillows and lay down directly on the ground in the playground. &quot;It&#39;s a waste not to lie down. Only a school with sunshine can truly warm people&#39;s hearts.&quot; Zhu Xiaomao lamented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/q3ntqxMMAWsWkelyuY6CHwcPdvtJ1WtIcSCfdPUa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;401&quot; height= &quot;267&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/q3ntqxMMAWsWkelyuY6CHwcPdvtJ1WtIcSCfdPUa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256490&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, in a psychology class at Ugly Duckling Middle School, students were expressing their views on the topic of &quot;Youth Sprout&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Morning jog in the morning, 40 minutes of physical education class in the morning, and 40 minutes of military training class in the afternoon. &quot;Every day we ensure at least three hours of outdoor exercise. , not including the children’s free time.” Zhan Danian said proudly, and Vice Principal Yang Liufang went on to introduce: “At noon in winter, the children often lie here (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The anti-corrosion wooden stage in the playground&lt;/span>;) is very comfortable for reading and chatting. The school will arrange for people to mop and clean these wooden boards so that they can &#39;lie down&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a piano in the corridor where students can play freely after class. The classrooms are concentrated on the second floor. There are only three classrooms for grades 7, 8, and 9. Each classroom is very spacious: the first half is the classroom, and the second half is separated by a hallway made of bookshelves. There are only one or two rows of tables for Student discussions and activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for the principal and his wife, Xiang Guoyue, Li Guihong and &quot;Brother Long&quot; who came to the school not long after the school was founded, the teachers are all young. Several times I mistakenly thought that the teachers were talking to students. &quot;There are not many traces of teachers here. There are no school uniforms or uniforms.&quot; Zhan Danian said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the class schedule written with a pen on the classroom wall is full of &quot;teachers&quot;: Juanjuan, Bobo, Zifu - the professor&#39;s nickname replaced the course name. The blackboard has also been replaced by a whiteboard covering almost the entire wall, smooth and oversized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;ugly duckling&quot; advocates comprehensive teaching. There are only three cultural courses here: liberal arts, science and English. Liberal arts teachers are responsible for teaching Chinese, history, and politics; science teachers are responsible for teaching mathematics, physics, and chemistry. &quot;Most of the children who come here have their self-confidence hurt, relationships destroyed, and even their personality disintegrated. If the subject teachers only have one or two classes a week to contact the students, they will not be able to get to know the students after a semester, and it is difficult to live up to our expectations. That kind of blending of lives. Only by contacting as many children as possible can we establish the &#39;relationship&#39; that education should have.&quot; Zhan Danian explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chinese language class of the second grade of junior high school, a classmate asked, &quot;Juanjuan, can we drive a &#39;small train&#39; today?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes!&quot; Next, the students They stood up one by one, like dominoes. After each person read a sentence of the ancient Chinese text &quot;Book of Thoughts with Zhu Yuan&quot; that they had just learned, they translated it themselves, and the next one did the same - this was a game that everyone enjoyed playing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hey, how did you steal someone else&#39;s carriage?&quot; Juanjuan sneered, but did not blame her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who is that? You just arrived today, right?&quot; She said to a slightly nervous freshman sitting in the back row, &quot;We have a &#39;freshman protection period&#39;, so you don&#39;t have to answer this question. I look forward to your performance in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, students use tablet computers to check information in almost every cultural class and then return them to the teacher; after class, they can use the classroom touch screen to enjoy music and watch movies. Watch short videos; and have the &quot;benefits&quot; of having free access to the Internet one or two nights a week - of course, on a tablet. Mobile phones are strictly prohibited from being used unless taking leave to visit relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Are you addicted to the Internet and can’t stand without your mobile phone?” No one seems to think so. After two cultural classes every afternoon, students not only participate in military training, but also have two interest classes and club activities: guitar, dance, vocal music, and basketball. No need to be fixed, you can do whatever you want. If you are really not interested, you can play cards, piano, read books, chat with people, hit sandbags, or walk on the playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 3rd, 13th and 23rd of each month are the &quot;street days&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;market day&lt; /span>;). The life teacher will take the students out of the school gate and go out to the market. &quot;Soy milk fried dough sticks, rice cakes, buckwheat cakes, scallion pancakes, biscuits and hawthorn rolls, hot and sour chicken feet, passion fruit flavor, there are all kinds of delicious things.&quot; Ji Guoer, a second-year junior high school girl, described to me, a glutton. It seems to have come out from the mouth. &quot;Sometimes on weekends, the teacher will take us to the county town to soak in hot springs, eat barbecue, hot pot, and go camping. It&#39;s fun.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/01/87mzFhHs2aAVvAn0lrtqpq7ngfD3U1EC1lnciydw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;538&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/01/87mzFhHs2aAVvAn0lrtqpq7ngfD3U1EC1lnciydw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256491&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students’ self-portraits on the corridor wall of the teaching building &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The creation of good relationships&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Education cannot be rushed . A good relationship is a good education.&quot; This is Zhan Danian&#39;s most well-known &quot;motto&quot; in the education circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A student who once studied at the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; described the &quot;Zhan style school management&quot; in his mind: &quot;I don&#39;t think you have any other tricks. Just don&#39;t punish those students who are prone to getting into trouble.&quot; Provoke them; then, just let them eat, drink and have fun.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Danian laughed loudly, &quot;You are very accurate. That&#39;s it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously Li Zhenxi, an education expert who emphasizes &quot;scientific management&quot;, always feels &quot;too mysterious&quot; every time he hears Zhan Danian emphasize &quot;understanding&quot;, &quot;trust&quot; and &quot;relationship is everything&quot;. Now he understands Zhan Danian more and more. &quot;Education cannot just regulate behavior, but should also pay attention to the soul. The &#39;ugly duckling&#39; treats children as human beings and focuses on everyone&#39;s personal dignity and spiritual freedom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children with &quot;problems&quot; in the eyes of adults , will also become the caregivers of each other&#39;s souls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, in addition to administrative classes and dormitory life classes, each freshman will be assigned a senior &quot;mentor&quot; to help them become familiar with campus life and overcome negative emotions in life. Some children don&#39;t eat, wash, or do laundry when they first arrive, and they don&#39;t listen to anything they say. The &quot;master&quot; will take them to the psychology room, but Lao Li Xiaoyang does not necessarily intervene immediately. Instead, the seniors will accompany them to play games. &quot;Some students are game masters, and some teachers are also very good at games, so we will give them He introduced that they can chat for a long time. Those who like to watch TV series, like two-dimensional comics and comics, and those who like singing and playing musical instruments will slowly get together...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Sqc4Q0JTj4fIrtsrkp9D6kpi2OdyCkXc8K3mkGpV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;538&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Sqc4Q0JTj4fIrtsrkp9D6kpi2OdyCkXc8K3mkGpV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256492&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Under the sun The book bar is the space where people stop most often. There are several pianos placed so that students can play freely during and after class&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The once most popular student club of the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; was the Psychology Club. On August 3, 2014, an earthquake occurred in Zhaotong, Yunnan. The day after the earthquake, Zhan Danian and several children drove more than 300 kilometers to deliver relief supplies to the affected villagers. However, he found that the psychology of children in disaster areas is in urgent need of intervention and counseling, and this is exactly where the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; students can focus. Soon, students who were completely unfamiliar with psychological counseling looked up earthquake information and asked the psychology teacher: How to help crying and desperate children in disaster areas? When we entered the disaster area for the second time, a group of half-grown children under the age of 15 were called &quot;teachers&quot; by a group of younger children. They played games and chatted about everyday things together, which brought them rare laughter. &quot;This is also an excellent self-education for our children.&quot; Zhan Danian was very pleased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, several teachers and students mentioned to me a boy named Luo Ting who was an “academic master”. &quot;I have experience living abroad, I have a good family background, and I am handsome, but I am not showy at all.&quot; Before coming to Ugly Duckling, Luo Ting studied in an international school and a public school in Shanghai. Due to his discomfort with school teaching and the epidemic, he stayed home for a long time. In the end, I just didn’t go to school at all. He didn&#39;t leave the door every day and didn&#39;t say a word, which made his grandfather, who had watched him grow up, very worried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arriving at the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; thousands of miles away, he felt that this school was &quot;quite different&quot;, but it was not &quot;love at first sight&quot;. In the first month or two, Luo Ting immersed himself in solving problems wherever he went, without talking to anyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know when he started playing the Pearl River piano in the corridor, and he seemed to be a different person. &quot;I studied for half a year when I was in the second grade of elementary school. I have been idle for four or five years. It is equivalent to starting from scratch and learning on my own.&quot; He did not seek quick results. He played &quot;Canon&quot; and &quot;Dance of Flowers&quot; according to the music scores he found. During the semester, classmates came over to listen from time to time, but he continued calmly. &quot;That kind of joy is difficult to express in words.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Luo Ting became best friends with Zhihan and Jiayu, who had similar interests. They will get together to talk about Sino-US trade and the Russia-Ukraine conflict. In the second semester of the third year of junior high school, several people formed a study group and used the precious &quot;exemption from military training&quot; time to study by themselves and prepare for the exam. &quot;In &#39;The Ugly Duckling&#39;, I also fell in love with running.&quot; Luo Ting said with a smile. &quot;Zhihan originally weighed more than 100 kilograms. After running, he lost 40 kilograms and became a legend in the school!&quot; Zhihan&#39;s &quot;Inspirational Run&quot; turned Luo Ting into a running expert. The school&#39;s track is close to a 125-meter lap. They run 40 laps every day and are almost &quot;unbeatable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ji Guoer is a carefree girl who is &quot;thick on the outside but delicate on the inside&quot;. While chatting, she looked away from time to time, and finally pointed to a figure beside the basketball hoop, &quot;Teacher Xiao Deng, I have a best friend over there, and she really wants to chat with you.&quot; So, Ji Guo and I Her best friend, He Man, walked around the playground arm in arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ji Guoer said that He Man liked to cry for a while, so she didn&#39;t ask so many questions and just made her laugh. &quot;I told her that you look ugly when you cry. She said you are so annoying. Haha, this trick works.&quot; Ji Guoer laughed heartlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What about the students who don&#39;t like to talk?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are all in the same life class and live under the same roof. Even those who don&#39;t like to talk will start talking after a long time. They have their own little secrets. If you talk to her every day, she will naturally come to you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She told me about her classmates with her fingers: Xiaoxing is generous and does not hold grudges; Jing Wen She likes reading and playing the piano; He Man is cheerful and has a good personality...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Did you just say that she loves to cry?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hey, as soon as she saw me crying, she put herself out again Hold back your tears and comfort me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We were happy together. But she became serious: &quot;Actually, people of our age are saving face. We don&#39;t want to appear weak, we want to be strong. Then we have to let them (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Classmates&lt;/span>;) slowly accept the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ji Guoer, who seems to be proactive, considerate to others, and able to point out other people&#39;s problems, can also be rude in the eyes of teachers and easily loses the boundaries of expression. . Xiang Guoyue said that adolescent children often show the characteristics of hedgehogs. The &quot;ugly duckling&quot; students&#39; personal will may have been suppressed in their original schools and families, and this will be reflected when they get here. Li Guihong, who has joined the school since 2011, originally felt that the children were &quot;unruly&quot; and would always use prank-like methods to announce their presence. &quot;School Zhan said that children should use a magnifying glass to see their strengths and reading glasses to see their weaknesses. So I also learned to appreciate them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In &#39;The Ugly Duckling&#39;, if you are talkative, you will be allowed to receive new classmates. If you can play the piano, try your best to play it; if you write a good article, it will be posted. We have a C poet who wrote an article about love and an article about life. Everyone can admire him... whether it is a theatrical performance or In the speech contest, the school requires everyone to appear on the stage, and they have to go on stage to do soy sauce. I will applaud you no matter what the performance is.&quot; Ji Guoer&#39;s words poured out like beans from a bag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes, there is Xiaoying.&quot; Long Jinying, a life teacher who graduated from the police academy, has just turned 20, and her long hair cannot stop her heroic spirit. During the few days of the interview, she was either cleaning up the potted plants she bought, or using a saw to cut wood strips and build flower stands. &quot;Xiaoying is so awesome. She helps you prepare medicines when you are sick, decorate and paint walls, and dance Dai dance during the Torch Festival. She can do it all! She is very good at dealing with children who have emotional outbursts and will let you go for a walk. She will talk to you again when you calm down. .&quot; Xiaoying in the minds of Ji Guoer and He Man seems to be the common &quot;idol&quot; of the girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FXAdGQ7EL1u9qNNPEzEj4kyufjey5KUhzOnecwsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height= &quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FXAdGQ7EL1u9qNNPEzEj4kyufjey5KUhzOnecwsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students having lunch&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; Send them to the ugly old duck&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;But capable people like Xiaoying and Xiang Guoyue also have times when they are not very motivated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Like Pu Pu and Tian Lan, although their parents have had disputes with them, they can generally calm down, accept their children&#39;s current situation, and cooperate with the school.&quot; Xiang Guoyue pointed out that the most difficult thing is The problem is that some parents send their children here because they hope that &quot;you will educate their children in their own way, only caring about the results and not caring about what is behind them&quot;; or they are not aware of their own problems and find it difficult to communicate; what&#39;s more, He almost doesn&#39;t care about his children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Children lack love in their hearts, but their parents seldom respond and even hurt them again and again. As a result, parents and children hurt each other. Some children are also forced to get involved in adult relationships. , learned violence, alienation and indifference.&quot; Li Guihong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feeling the importance of family education, Zhan Danian opened a parent class soon after the school opened. His private account has continued to spread educational concepts at a frequency of two messages a day for many years. Many parents gain spiritual strength from Zhan Danian&#39;s official account after their children become depressed, tired of studying, and stop communicating with their parents. Some will send their children here directly. But change does not happen overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Man, who has a big face and bright eyes, grew up in H City on the border between China and Vietnam. The image that impressed her most about her childhood was that her father took her to school on a motorcycle, while her mother was busy with the beauty salon business at night and sleeping during the day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she was transferred to Q City in the fourth grade, her father had no time to take care of her, so he found her old math teacher and paid her to come across town to be a &quot;nanny + tutor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From sixth grade to second grade, He Manwan changed schools five or six times. &quot;I was the vice-captain of cheerleading at the time and ranked first in running. The boys in the senior class added me on WeChat and QQ, and the girls in the same grade were unhappy with me and called me green tea. The students in the second grade of junior high school threatened me to pay protection money, so I had no choice but to fight for my life. There were a lot of gangsters running towards the back door. The teacher said I wasn&#39;t good at studying and wouldn&#39;t let anyone else play with me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She smoked in the corner and was reported. &quot;Actually, everyone smokes, but they only talk about me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She cried to her father, but it was useless. &quot;You didn&#39;t listen to me carefully.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Where&#39;s mom?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mom doesn&#39;t even know where my school is or where I live in the first semester of junior high school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She had swallowed about twenty pills of ibuprofen, all of which she had saved by going to the school infirmary when she had a cold. &quot;I can&#39;t even jump off the building. I&#39;m surrounded by railings and have no conditions. I just take medicine. Life is really meaningless. My mother told the teacher that I was obsessed with ghosts and deliberately scared them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She escaped from school again. open. In the end, he was caught by his parents and locked up in the underground garage of his hometown in H City for a night. &quot;Hit me with a wire, slapped me, choked me, and dragged me to wash my tattoos.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She returned to Q City. I went to work in a mobile phone store and was taken back by my parents. &quot;They just want to take me back. They have not participated in too many of my lives. I just want to escape.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking of which, a girl who took a few days off returned to school. , He Man looked at the gate with a hint of happiness: &quot;Many of our classmates often bring a big bag of plum potato chips, jelly, and pizza for us to eat when they come back from vacation. Some of them will bring a cup of milk tea for everyone in the life class, which is beautiful. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, Juanjuan asked her to be the monitor; Principal Yang asked her to receive visitors; Xiaoying would comfort her and listen to her. She caught up with the summer camp not long after she came here. &quot;We chatted on the playground from morning to night, and when it got dark, we watched movies and ate barbecue together...&quot; She originally thought that this would be the first time she called her parents after arriving at the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;. I cried, but ended up laughing the whole time. &quot;I used to be very attached to my ex-boyfriend. Lao Li said that I actually knew nothing about love. Haha. But I really understand. The outside world is unreal. Now I have learned to see people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of the course She fell behind too much, so at the age of 15, she retaken the second grade of junior high school in the &quot;ugly duckling&quot;. She was not in a hurry, and slowly began to sympathize with her father who always hated her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My grandparents’ hometown is not in Yunnan. After decades here, they are still not welcome in the town. Her father, who is over fifty, worked as an accountant in H City in his early years. In He Man&#39;s eyes, he is actually the most sensible person in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He is the most serious person in the family, but when he was a child, even a piece of candy was extravagant. He hated the family and felt it was unfair. He was the one who wiped the mess. So he hoped that I would make a difference. I can stay with you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before coming to &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, He Man went to Kunming to see a psychiatrist. &quot;The doctor said that the gap between your two generations is too deep. Anyway, my parents don&#39;t ask me about many things, and I don&#39;t tell them either. Sometimes I am naughty and just want to deliberately anger them.&quot; She paused and softened her tone. : &quot;My dad has diabetes, and I won&#39;t deliberately anger him anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ono&#39;s story, she and her mother are almost the only ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Today is the 136th day since I came to Ugly Duckling.&quot; As soon as she sat down, she clearly stated the day. Every day that passes, she will cross off a line on her calendar - &quot;It feels like one day closer to going home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike the other girls who can&#39;t wait to share, Ono&#39;s eyes and mouth are full of excitement. Take a look at it. She is good at art. Recently, she has contributed to the school&#39;s &quot;class culture&quot;, from the stairwells to the dormitory walls to the decorative paintings in the corridors. She is good at singing and dancing. But as if that wasn&#39;t enough to satisfy her cravings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She often hurts herself. She uses rulers, stones, gel pens to break them, and everything else. Her hands and legs are like fish scales.&quot; Li Guihong said that Pu Pu&#39;s self-mutilation is more of a This is a kind of emotional catharsis, and there is an additional intention of &quot;seeking attention&quot; in Ono&#39;s behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ono’s description, her mother felt that the divorce was because of her daughter, “so she always resented me with personal emotions.” From an early age, the more her mother did not allow her to do anything, the more she came to The more I want to do it. When they quarreled, the two always used vicious words to accuse each other, &quot;She said I was delusional. I said you should go and have a look, there must be something wrong with you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ono used to love giving to her mother Write a letter, write a WeChat, or handwrite a letter of a few hundred words, then take a photo and send it to &quot;Lao Li&quot;. &quot;Actually, she wants me to forward it to her mother. Some parents from other provinces may come three or four times. She thinks why her mother never comes. If she doesn&#39;t come, she doesn&#39;t love me. To realize it immediately is to love me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When we grow up, we will send those rebellious parents to a school called &#39;Ugly Duck&#39;, or &#39;Ugly Chicken&#39;, haha!&quot; Speaking of the suggestion when chatting with classmates , Ono shrugged and laughed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But her mother knows that she wants to buy &quot;Lolita&quot; clothes and loves to go to comic exhibitions, so she will fully support her. &quot;I&#39;m not a qualified daughter...I&#39;m sorry for my mother.&quot; Ono&#39;s eyes were a little red. She hopes that she will be independent soon and be able to earn money. &quot;I will give money to my mother when I go out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My biological father? I haven&#39;t seen him. He doesn&#39;t want me because I am a girl. Does he want to see me now? No.&quot; Maybe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, she had checked this place before coming here. The name of the school was weird. &quot;Live a happy and complete educational life...&quot; She murmured the school motto &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, which was quoted from the educator Zhu Yongxin, &quot;Can it be realized?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She refused to graduate from the third grade of junior high school. , hoping to leave as soon as possible, because there are a lot of fun things waiting for her outside. In her hometown, she went to KTV in the fourth and fifth grade of elementary school. “Those sisters who added WeChat are so beautiful.” They praised her that “she can sing and dance, can do makeup well, and won’t cause trouble.” Some adults also taught her “don’t care too much.” She found this life philosophy to be insightful and joyful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She hopes that Lao Li will communicate with her mother and let her go back. But her mother was worried. &quot;In Yiliang, we can cut off social ties between her and her hometown.&quot; Li Guihong said that she once gently reminded Ono that people in society are loyal, but small favors may be used to exploit minors. &quot;She is not yet able to listen to these principles, but we have to explain them to her bit by bit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/BYA0RMGelbZiZ46SxJFr4d0fM8KD2hJpXWFgFPnw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;545&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/BYA0RMGelbZiZ46SxJFr4d0fM8KD2hJpXWFgFPnw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256494&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 21, 2023, the first Youth Psychological Safety Forum Lecture On-site &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New educational philosophy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;With more individuality The story of Pu Pu and Ono, I left the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; who stayed for three days and headed to Kunming. Regarding adolescent depression, various special discussions have long been common, but the popularity of the first Youth Psychological Safety Forum held in Kunming from October 21 to 22 exceeded the organizers’ expectations. Active speakers, from writing notes to grabbing the microphone, to some rushing directly to the side of the stage, have to speak their minds &quot;with offense&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reader of Zhan Danian said that he had been studying well since childhood and had been attending the best local schools, but he had never been happy or had a sense of accomplishment. He was still confused when he was in his thirties; several teachers and parents brought Children were asked to seek help on-site for school bullying and mental illness problems; several teachers from different schools also suggested that they wanted to care for students, but were unable to do so. “We are also problem teachers, who will help us?!” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It not only shows that everyone has a huge desire to express themselves and their enthusiasm to solve problems, but also shows that many people, whether they are educators or parents, have psychological problems that need to be seen. Being diverted.&quot; One of the guests lamented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Minor Protection Law&quot; revised and implemented in June 2021 clearly stipulates: The education administration department should strengthen the mental health education of minors and establish a mechanism for early detection and timely intervention of minors&#39; psychological problems. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But inside and outside the forum, people discuss more about real-life problems that cause depression or are caused by depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Famous education expert Feng Enhong pointed out that what we face in building a defensive line of psychological safety education for teenagers is the overall loss of education in today&#39;s society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yu is the founder of the family education platform &quot;Youth is Different&quot;. He has conducted in-depth interviews with hundreds of primary and secondary school students who are depressed, tired of studying, struggling and desperate. Among the students who came to her for face-to-face and telephone consultation this year, the number that increased sharply was high school freshmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On the first day of their first year in high school, some children do their homework until 11 o&#39;clock at night. The teacher said, you are already in high school, do you still expect to sleep well? There are Beijing&#39;s &#39;Six Little Strong&#39; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Haidian Famous School&lt;/span>;) students asked me, why do I need to learn to the point of being word for word? This is a confusion of many children. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A student told Chen Yu that on the first day of school, the school mobilized like this: &quot;If you have grades, you have everything. The classmates sitting next to you are all enemies in the high school entrance examination room.&quot; She met I heard about a girl from a prestigious school in Shenzhen who got up to study at 4 a.m. and her period gradually stopped coming. She asked the girl, &quot;Does everything have to give way to grades? Are grades more important than body?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The girl said, yes. &#39;That&#39;s good, I don&#39;t have to worry about exams hitting my menstrual period anymore&#39; There is also a child who ranks first in grade in Liaoning who feels like he is &#39;like a thief who stole the emperor&#39;s crown&#39;, as if he was sitting on a high platform and would fall down if a gust of wind blew.&quot; Chen Yu concluded that children of this generation , get tired of studying earlier, take a longer break from studying, and find it more difficult to resume studying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“All the brilliant achievements of education are meaningless if a child suffers from reduced vision, lack of sleep, weak constitution, mental deformity, or even premature death!” Li Zhenxi exclaimed in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When students are prone to depression or are diagnosed, they will encounter completely different situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A child Chen Yu interviewed was ostracized by his classmates after he was diagnosed with depression, and his desk was filled with garbage and mineral water bottles. Later, the new class teacher invited her out to chat in a cafe. When school resumed, she held the little girl&#39;s hand and walked into the school. When she arrived at the door of the class, the whole class applauded to welcome her, and the child&#39;s psychology changed drastically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in a place in Jiangsu and Zhejiang, a school conducted psychological tests and evaluations for students approaching their third year of high school. &quot;The school said to some of the children that your current emotional state cannot adapt to the school&#39;s next studies.&quot; Expelled them from school. Many children with depression will also say that no teachers or students have contacted me since I returned home. They feel that I have been abandoned by this organization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Solution Where is the Tao? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Educator Yang Dongping’s answer is that the education department continues to introduce new policies to “reduce burdens”, but how to get rid of the long-term conflict between educational policies and educational reality, and the lack of vitality in quality education? There is only one answer: China needs a new educational philosophy and a top-down design from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He further proposed: We should reduce the number of teaching hours from the source, reduce the concentration of teaching and the difficulty of examinations, implement the all-subject teacher model in primary schools, and improve the educational ecology; cancel key schools, pilot subject stratification, and have It facilitates communication among students and reduces labeling or discrimination caused by the educational diversion system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When you respect your child as a person and get along with him, you will get a normal and healthy person; if you treat your child as a learning machine, you will get an object. &quot;Yang Dongping&#39;s powerful voice and Zhan Danian&#39;s simple language aroused strong resonance from the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Readers who visited Ugly Duckling Middle School and read Zhan Danian&#39;s account felt that &quot;problem children&quot; found themselves here and got to know life, and they could start anew. &quot;So, can an ordinary school become an &#39;ugly duckling&#39;? What would happen if normal children were educated in this way?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhan Danian has always emphasized that the ugly duckling middle school is a preventive one. Schools provide suitable education methods for children who cannot adapt to the traditional education system, rather than providing a methodology to solve their difficulties. &quot;All the crux of education we encounter today cannot be changed by a forum. But it can provide a way of thinking: Is there something wrong with our teaching and our family education? This is what these discussions and voices can do. Zhan Danian, who seems to be &quot;invincible&quot; in front of others, admits that he is often at a loss when faced with children with depression and other symptoms. There was once a mixed-race girl whose parents separated. One of her toes was wrapped with a rubber band until it became necrotic. Then the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; came and wanted to wrap another toe. I&#39;ve been here for several months and still haven&#39;t looked up, and progress is slow. &quot;We had no choice but to dissuade this child because it was beyond our capabilities and required the intervention of medical institutions.&quot; There was a rare sense of loss and powerlessness in Zhan Danian&#39;s tone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked Chen Yu, if the school environment is difficult to change and some parents are &quot;stubborn&quot; as the guests said, what advice would she give to the children she interviewed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I hope that the status quo of domestic vocational high schools and technical schools will change, so that ordinary people with skills can live a decent life. As long as a child has a little bit of sparkle, he will not be completely Deny yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A mother in Quanzhou once asked her for help: her son&#39;s IQ was slightly deficient, and she hoped that the child could keep up with the pace of his classmates&#39; studies, but the child was already tired of studying. Chen Yu learned that the boy liked raising pets very much, &quot;I said you follow me and imagine that on the street where you live, there is a seafood shop opened by your father, a photo studio opened by you, and a flower, bird, fish and insect shop opened by your child. Isn&#39;t it wonderful? She said, Teacher Chen, before others advised me to get a &#39;roll&#39;, I was very happy when I heard you say that.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the present moment, understand children and the times. It is particularly important. Every child brings his own food, grass and map. We must provide comprehensive support for the children and do not let them look around and feel lonely.&quot; Chen Yu used an analogy. &quot;A tutor who understands you, a trustworthy boyfriend/girlfriend, can be a fulcrum.&quot; If you are surrounded by people who have no support, I would tell them, stand up, and you will have a chance after you turn 18. Heal yourself and become your own nourisher. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before ending the interview with “The Ugly Duckling”, Pu Pu told me that she hoped to return to that “high-quality and strictly controlled” middle school to take the high school entrance examination because her uncle drove a taxi and was just in the first grade of junior high school. Her cousin has to do homework, take care of her two-year-old little brother, and cook for her uncle. If she grows up and has a good job, &quot;it can make her cousin less hard-working.&quot; He Man said that in the past, she and her father We quarreled, and now we talk about it every few days, why didn&#39;t dad send a message? Ono, who has been studying Japanese by himself and passed N2, wants to be an illustrator when he grows up, &quot;My mother supports me to study in Japan&quot;; Ji Guoer&#39;s mother hopes that she can I went to the police academy, “but I want to be a kindergarten teacher and teach children. Principal Zhan also thinks I can do it. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Reference: Zhan Danian’s private account, guest speaker at the first Youth Psychological Safety Forum. The names of the students in the article are pseudonyms. Intern reporter Yang Yuxi also contributed to this article. )&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[善缘丨台上台下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/Nle67mKR4B6FkOMYlKkteesTzDZ3VO6uK4rFizQR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1001&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Nle67mKR4B6FkOMYlKkteesTzDZ3VO6uK 4rFizQR. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256568&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brigitte Lin and Huang Meiyun, chairman of the Kao Kun Charitable Foundation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All the people gathered in this hall, all those who heard our message about Fu Da’s dementia You all have a good relationship because of the word &quot;fate&quot;. This good relationship began at an award ceremony more than 20 years ago. My husband and Professor Xin Shiwen, the former dean of Shanheng College, won awards at the same time. Therefore, Dean Xin and I had a close relationship. In 2018, I won the Xin Shiwen Award again. The dean awarded him the title of Honorary Academician of Shanheng College, and he became associated with the Chinese University from then on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My relationship with Dr. Zhao Xiaying began in the early days of the COVID-19 invasion. I discussed with my friend Jin Shenghua that we wanted to do our best for society in the COVID-19 battle. Shenghua introduced Dr. Lei Zhaohui and Dr. Zhao Xiaying to us. I knew each other and we became friends. During Christmas last year, we had afternoon tea at the Peninsula Hotel and heard Dr. Zhao discussing the Alzheimer&#39;s disease project with Shenghua. I thought it was urgent, so I took the initiative to participate in it, hoping to do my best to help promote this project. This charitable act enables people with invisible and mild dementia to prevent and delay their symptoms, alleviate the pain of themselves and their families, and reduce the burden on society. Dr. Zhao introduced me to Dean Mok Zhongtang of Shanheng Academy and Ms. Huang Meiyun (Mrs. Gao Kun), chairman of the Kao Kun Charitable Foundation. We hit it off in all aspects and soon promoted the brain degeneration project, and the good relationship continued from this Go down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fKBkxMNAJHPLlLJLOCBGNJXAZemQybB8FTsbONQC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fKBkxMNAJHPLlLJLOCBGNJXAZemQybB8FTsbONQC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256569&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brigitte Lin and Dr. Zhao Xiaying (left), and Dean Mok Chung-tang of Shanheng College of the Chinese University of Hong Kong. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After participating in the brain-smart care activity, I went to the hospital with neurologists Dr. Mo and Dr. Zhao After a few classes, I learned a lot of knowledge that I wouldn’t normally have access to. Do you know how much your brain weighs? Three pounds; do you know how many nerve cells there are in the brain? One hundred billion; each nerve cell is connected to thousands of other nerve cells through branches to form a communication network. The connections between these branches exceed one hundred billion points, and the entire connection forms a complex network. Did you know that one in ten people over the age of seventy has dementia? I have many friends who are in their seventies, eighties or nineties and have very bright minds. I like to get close to them. They have rich life experiences and the insights they have gained in life. Those treasures have a lot to learn from, so we must Take good care of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me tell you an interesting thing. Because I wanted to get close to the 90-year-old former superstar Sister Glenn, I went to watch the Beijing Opera with her. I was also curious about the ticketing of the opera. There were seven theatergoers, three of whom were 90 years old. One of the above, one of whom is ninety-nine years old, does not use crutches, does not use a wheelchair, does not have a caregiver, and walks in alone in a neat suit. Three people over ninety years old sing Peking Opera with amazing energy, and they are not even chatting. They speak freely without any scruples. I really can’t call them Mr. or Mrs. They live a free and easy life. During this time, everyone was joking and paired Sister Glenn and Jiujiu. I thought it was so cute. I raised my camera and shouted, &quot;Kiss me! Kiss me!&quot; Jiujiu generously kissed Sister Glenn on the face, and everyone clapped and applauded. hapiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2SjvLoqlT1cN4qPjbZZWN2sycGh0x5BoJde52tEA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2SjvLoqlT1cN4qPjbZZWN2sycGh0x5BoJde52tEA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256570&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As sponsor and project ambassador, Brigitte Lin at the launch ceremony of the &quot;Brain Intelligence Care&quot; service plan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am 68 this year and will be 69 in November. My memory and reaction Better than before I was sixty. I read, write, draw, sing, participate in positive social activities, and keep exercising every day. In addition to hiking, I play table tennis almost every day and occasionally do yoga. I am curious about everything in the world. The most important thing is Cultivating the ability to love is something I rarely did before I was sixty. Now I seem to be living another person&#39;s life. Turns out all of these are great remedies for brain degeneration. If sixty returned to zero and started over, I would be only eight years old now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having said so much, let’s get back to the subject. I would like to appeal to children over the age of sixty to actively sign up and test whether your brain is still as bright as before. If not, let us work together to fight back Alzheimer’s disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(This article is Brigitte Lin’s speech at the launch ceremony of Hong Kong’s “Brain-Smart Care” service plan)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违规的清滩养蛏：边滑“泥橇”边下农药]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259757]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73271&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70087&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bc8efa1ae6.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Razor Clam 1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bc8efa1ae6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256460&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Razor clams are a popular and affordable seafood. In order to increase the production of razor clams, some fishermen illegally use pesticides on the tidal flats to kill and drive away the natural enemies of razor clams on the tidal flats. Visual China|Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Ming is still waiting for an explanation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few months ago, many of the aquatic products in his fish pond suddenly died overnight, causing heavy losses. His fish pond is close to the seaside. Every time the tide rises on the first and fifteenth day of the lunar month, seawater is introduced into the pond to change the water. Three other farmer neighbors also suffered losses. They all changed the water on July 2, 2023 - the fifteenth day of the fifth lunar month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only fish pond farmers such as Liu Ming are asking for gifts from the sea, but there are also razor clam (commonly known as &quot;razor clam&quot;) farmers in the tidal flats one or two kilometers away. Liu Ming and others suspected that razor clam farmers put pesticides on the tidal flats, forming &quot;poisonous water&quot; after high tide. They were introduced into the fish ponds just in time for the water change, poisoning the aquatic products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Ming said that they have reported the case and there is no investigation result yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Different organisms have different constitutions. As long as the appropriate dosage is mastered, pesticides can kill and drive away the natural enemies of razor clams on the tidal flats without affecting the razor clams. Huang Biaowu, a senior experimentalist at the School of Marine Biology of Xiamen Marine Vocational and Technical College who has long studied razor clam cultivation, told Southern Weekend reporters that the method of raising razor clams using pesticides on tidal flats currently exists in some coastal areas of my country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The most common of these pesticides is triazophos, which is mainly used to control pests in fruit trees, cotton, and food crops. However, it is illegal to use it in razor clam cultivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The use of pesticides has increased the survival rate of a single razor clam species, but at the expense of biodiversity. The tidal flats are a transit point for millions of migratory birds around the world, and abundant shellfish are their food. At present, the residues, metabolic patterns and effects of pesticides on human health in razor clams have not been fully studied. Due to the difficulty of supervision and other reasons, this farming method has not been effectively managed in some coastal areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kill natural enemies without poisoning razor clams&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Razor clams are a popular affordable seafood. Huang Biaowu told Southern Weekend reporters that there are currently many kinds of razor clams on the market. The razor clams sold are basically aquaculture products, and there are two main methods: pond culture and tidal flat culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Early cultured razor clam seedlings were derived from wild seedlings, and wild razor clam seedlings were only produced in Zhejiang and Fujian, with limited quantities. More than ten years ago, after a breakthrough in artificial razor clam breeding technology, large-scale tidal flat farming methods emerged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73272&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70088&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d678c245b9.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Razor Clam 2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d678c245b9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256461&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;March 2022, Quanzhou, Fujian. In the morning, taking advantage of the lull in the tide, fishermen go to the tidal flats to salvage wild razor clam seedlings for sale. (Pictures and texts are unrelated) Visual China | Pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the promotion of raising razor clams on tidal flats, beach clearing drugs such as triazophos have also become popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rise and fall of the tide forms an intertidal zone thousands of meters wide, which is a treasure trove of biodiversity. In addition to razor clams, algae, snails, Abundant organisms such as shrimps, crabs, and small fishes also attract birds to feed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Biaowu explained that when the razor clam seedlings are first released, they cannot penetrate very deep into the soil and can easily become food for other organisms on the tidal flats. In severe cases, razor clam farmers may even lose the seeds. receive. Triazophos can kill crabs, snails, gobies and other natural enemies of razor clams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are many considerations in how to use triazophos and other drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Cheng, who once raised razor clams on the tidal flats, told Southern Weekend reporters that the traffic problem must be solved first. In the vast tidal flats, there are tens of thousands of acres of razor clam farms as far as the eye can see. If you cannot move with your feet alone, you will immediately fall into the mud. To do this, razor clam farmers ride on a homemade scooter-like tool called a &quot;mud sled.&quot; It is a long wooden board with slightly warped ends and a handrail in the middle. The driver can kneel on the board with one leg and push on the ground with the other leg, so that he can slide quickly on the mudflat. Four hundred years ago, it was the &quot;secret weapon&quot; used by the Qi army to defeat Japanese pirates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The dosage and area of ​​triazophos sprayed on the tidal flats need to be strictly controlled to achieve the purpose of killing natural enemies without poisoning razor clams. The razor clam breeding grounds are similar to field ridges, each about 150 meters wide, and the two stems are about 50 meters apart, making it easy for boating. The razor clam farmer tilts a 50-pound pesticide bucket behind the mud sled and moves forward in a straight line at a constant speed. The pesticide slowly flows out from the small eyes of the bucket, and it travels about 2 kilometers in an hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Cheng revealed that these triazophos were not purchased from the market. &quot;There are wholesalers who can directly contact them to deliver them to you.&quot; The time for spraying pesticides is usually before the spring tide. After the tide rises, the pesticides on the tidal flats will spread with the sea water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was this &quot;hidden rule&quot; of farming that made Liu Ming and others suspect that the sudden loss of their fish pond after the water change was related to the use of pesticides to raise razor clams. This is not the first time similar incidents have occurred locally. Farmers have even summed up their experience. Before changing the water, they first ask the people at the beach if they find dead fish to judge whether the sea water is &quot;toxic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local razor clam seedlings are sown in March and harvested in March of the following year. Because when the weather gets colder, there are fewer natural enemies of razor clams near the shore, so the spraying time lasts from March to September, usually at most twice a month. &quot;The smell of triazophos is very pungent and very irritating.&quot; Li Cheng said that once he put triazophos in the car, and the unpleasant smell did not dissipate for several days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to media reports, in 2018, Lao Wang, who had been raising razor clams for 18 years in Dafeng, Yancheng, Jiangsu, suddenly developed chest tightness, dizziness, and fatigue. Doctors found that the culprit was Lao Wang. The organophosphorus pesticide used by Wang can kill cockroaches (a small organism commonly known as &quot;sea leather&quot;) that destroy the growing environment of razor clams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to triazophos, Li Cheng also used two pesticides, dichlorvos and imidacloprid, which were also used to kill the natural enemies of razor clams, but triazophos was used in the largest amount. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Explicitly prohibited but difficult to supervise&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pesticides such as triazophos, dichlorvos and imidacloprid are not used in aquaculture in compliance with regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;An expert in the field of aquatic products and fishery drugs said in an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend that my country implements a white list system for aquaculture drugs. “The veterinary drugs for aquaculture in the white list have all undergone rigorous research on pharmacodynamics, toxicology, food safety and environmental impact, and have a relatively in-depth understanding of the effects of use and the rules of metabolic residues in aquatic products. Know.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chemical drugs outside the white list are not allowed to be used illegally. Pesticides such as triazophos used by razor clam farmers are not on the white list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There have been some studies on triazophos. An article published in 2007 by experts from the Zhejiang Provincial Institute of Marine Fisheries and other institutions mentioned that triazophos used in the process of raising razor clams can remain in edible tissues. Experimental simulation data shows that triazophos is present in razor clams. The accumulation and elimination speed in the drug are both fast. 24 hours after the drug was administered, the concentration of triazophos in the body reached 2.97mg/kg, and after 100 hours, it dropped to 0.021mg/kg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, my country has only set limits for triazophos in plant foods, and there is no standard to follow in aquatic products. Referring to the &quot;National Food Safety Standard Maximum Residue Limits of Pesticides in Food&quot; (GB 2763-2021), the maximum limit is 0.2mg/kg for fruits, and the minimum limit is 0.05mg/kg for cereals such as wheat and oats. The 24-hour data of the above study seriously exceeded the standard, but the 100-hour data did not exceed the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, because triazophos can easily cause excessive pesticide residues in vegetables, triazophos is not popular in vegetable planting. In 2013, the former Ministry of Rural Affairs stipulated that, Its use on vegetables is prohibited after December 31, 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some places have clearly banned the use of triazophos for raising razor clams. For example, in 2017, Yueqing City, Zhejiang Province, one of the main producing areas of wild razor clam seedlings, issued the &quot;Notice on Prohibiting the Use of Pesticides in Shallow Beach Breeding&quot;, which strictly prohibited the use of triazophos, dichlorvos, sodium pentachlorophenol, and cypermethrin in shallow beach breeding. , imidacloprid and other pesticides, and residents are encouraged to stop and report violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also cases of punishment. In 2017, law enforcement officers from the Ninghai County Fishery Administration and Fishing Port Supervision and Management Station in Ningbo, Zhejiang Province discovered that someone was using triazophos during the cultivation of razor clams and were fined 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, it is very difficult to regulate the use of pesticides such as triazophos. Some coastal farmers told Southern Weekend reporters that this breeding method has been secretive for many years. To avoid public notice, razor clam farmers usually spray pesticides late at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as 2014, Wang Songlin, chairman of the environmental organization &quot;Qingdao Marine Ecology Research Association&quot;, witnessed a group of razor clam farmers spreading triazophos on the tidal flats. The &quot;Razor Clam: China Offshore Breeding Assessment Report&quot; released by the Research Association in 2019 pointed out that the inconvenient transportation into the breeding tidal flat wetlands has brought many difficulties to supervision work. For example, people, vehicles, and ships cannot move forward on the muddy tidal flats, making it difficult for supervisors to locate evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73273&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70089&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/01/fb36a6570f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Razor Clam 3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fb36a6570f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256462&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In January 2023, farmers harvested razor clam seedlings in the tidal flat breeding area of ​​Yueqing Bay in Wenzhou, Zhejiang. (Pictures and texts are irrelevant) Visual China | Pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Inertial thinking in farmland management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Songlin said that not only razor clams, but also some economical shellfish For example, the tidal flat cultivation of variegated clams and the large-scale sea cucumber cofferdam breeding industry along the Yellow and Bohai Seas also have illegal use of chemicals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Sea Cucumber: China Offshore Pond and Cofferdam Culture Assessment Report&quot; released by the Qingdao Marine Ecology Research Association in 2019 mentioned that the cofferdam culture of sea cucumbers is abused The chemical problem is more serious. For example, in order to prevent and treat diseases, antibiotics are used illegally in the nursery stage; pesticides and herbicides are illegally used in the breeding process to clear ponds and kill sea cucumbers&#39; natural enemies; excessive amounts of alum and illegal use of formaldehyde may also be used in the processing and sales of sea cucumbers. , causing the aluminum content and formaldehyde in sea cucumbers to exceed standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Raising razor clams on tidal flats not only destroys biodiversity through the use of pesticides, but also causes the death of birds by erecting anti-bird nets. A newly published study by Princeton University associate researcher Liang Dan and others found that during the peak spring migration period of migratory birds in April and May 2021, anti-bird nets erected for razor clam farming in Xinghua Bay, Fujian and Yueqing Bay, Zhejiang More than 13,000 shorebirds were trapped, many of which are nationally protected species. The research team also found similar anti-bird nets in 17 other locations in Zhejiang and Fujian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liang Dan told Southern Weekend reporters that the above-mentioned tidal flats in the above two places specialize in breeding razor clam seedlings. The razor clam seedlings usually sprout from around November and grow until March or March of the following year. It can be harvested in April. If these bird-proof nets are removed immediately after razor clam seedlings are harvested in March and April, tens of thousands of birds migrating in spring can be saved, and part of the bird-proof nets can also be prevented from entering the sea and harming marine life. However, because it requires high labor costs to dismantle the nets on the tidal flats, the farmers will keep the nets on the tidal flats after selling the razor clam seedlings, waiting until typhoons to sweep away the nets in June or July. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In their natural state, razor clams are only part of the biodiversity of Hamada Wetland. To carry out aquaculture on legally protected natural tidal wetlands, Wang Songlin believes that fishermen have to accept the high natural mortality rate of razor clams - being predated by natural enemies and competing with other benthic animals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But it’s hard. Whether it is razor clams or sea cucumbers, the use of banned chemicals such as organophosphorus and pyrethroid pesticides in the breeding process reflects the farmers&#39; inertial thinking: managing natural tidal flats and coastal zones as farmland, and treating aquaculture products as a single type of &quot; crop&quot;. &quot;I asked an old couple who came back from spraying pesticides. They were very enthusiastic and said frankly that the beach is no different from a cotton field. To ensure a high yield of razor clams, other fish, shrimps, crabs, and shellfish must be killed with pesticides, and long-billed waterfowl must be driven away.&quot; Wang Songlin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is an old saying: &quot;April razor clams are plump and plump, so don&#39;t let Xishi&#39;s tongue down.&quot; April is the most plump season for razor clams, but it is not an eco-friendly time to eat them. . Because spring and autumn are also the peak seasons for migratory birds, reducing the interference from human activities such as spraying pesticides to clear the beach and firing cannons to drive away birds on natural tidal wetlands is of great significance to ecological protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How to resolve these contradictions, Yueqing City, Zhejiang Province advocates the use of boat cultivators, quicklime, bleaching powder, drying and other methods to clear beaches and ponds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Biaowu suggested that farmers return to the old method of pond farming. For pond culture, eco-friendly quicklime and Chinese medicinal materials can be used instead of triazophos in clear ponds. Raising razor clams in ponds requires fertilizer and water, which is equivalent to fertilizing crops. Raising razor clams in ponds can also use the tail water discharged from other fish ponds as fertilizer water to purify the organic matter rich in nitrogen, phosphorus and other organic matter in the tail water, turning waste into treasure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Liu Ming and Li Cheng are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄罗斯铝业公司创始人奥列格·德里帕斯卡：没有特斯拉汽车，大家还是会活下去的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259777]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mandarin Oriental Hotel is located on Wangfujing Street in Beijing, overlooking the Forbidden City. On the evening of October 25, 2023, in the luxurious conference hall box on the fifth floor, Oleg Deripaska, the founder of Rusal, was waiting for the visiting media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oleg Deripaska was once the founder of the world&#39;s largest aluminum company. In the interview, he claimed to be a &quot;Soviet-era physicist&quot; and graduated from the Physics Department of Moscow State University in his early years. After the collapse of the Soviet Union, academic funding dropped sharply, and there were no subsidies or grants, which made it impossible for him to continue physics research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving school, he and his colleagues established a trading company to export metals from Russia. Later, he used the first pot of gold he earned to acquire the third largest electrolytic aluminum plant in Russia, which became his The starting point of your career. Later, through asset merger, he established the world&#39;s largest aluminum company, Rusal. This company was listed in Hong Kong in 2015, becoming the first Russian company to be listed in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2018, the United States imposed sanctions on Deripaska and 23 other Russian tycoons and officials, and he was included in the United States&#39; Specially Designated Nationals List (SDN). After entering this list, the Office of Foreign Assets Control under the U.S. Department of the Treasury will freeze its property and property interests within the jurisdiction of the United States. U.S. citizens and entities located in the United States are generally prohibited from conducting any form of transaction or business with individuals or entities on the SDN list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This list affects not only the individuals or entities on the list, but also third parties with whom they do business. Transactions with entities on the list may result in violations of U.S. sanctions regulations, thereby Face legal consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oleg Deripaska was sanctioned by Australia, Canada, EU countries, the United Kingdom and other countries after the Russia-Ukraine conflict began. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1589&quot; height= &quot;1192&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Russian aluminum king Oleg Deripaska. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhou Yubo/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the purpose of your visit to China this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am a member of the Board of Trustees of Lomonosov Moscow State University. We visited BIT Moscow State University in Shenzhen , a joint university founded by Lomonosov Moscow State University and Beijing Institute of Technology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have opened an International Business School, as well as a School of Mathematics and Physics. Previously, Moscow State University held an international class. About twenty or thirty students from different countries came to Moscow State University to study mathematics and physics, and 30% of them were Chinese students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russian mathematics education is the best in the world, and we hope to promote such academic exchanges. At the same time, Chinese students can learn Russian, and Russian students can learn Chinese. We need to invest in transportation facilities and financial facilities, but we also need to invest in science education. Some scientific projects may not seem very important now, but in twenty or fifty years, they will become the key to the development of human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you view the current fluctuations in the ruble? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The problem of ruble fluctuations certainly exists because we now have a military conflict, but Russia’s settlement balance is still very powerful. As long as there are no major conflicts in the next two or three years, ruble fluctuations will not be a big problem, because Russia&#39;s resource industry is still quite good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of the year, you thought Russia needed to welcome more people from Investment from friendly countries, so what else can be done to promote cooperation between Chinese and Russian enterprises? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First, it takes time. The foundation of economic cooperation between the two countries is trust. We already have a foundation of trust. . Previously, 70% of Russian industry relied on European technology. Now it still takes time to transform, change our national standards, and cooperate with our friendly countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have a problem, you must solve it in time, and don&#39;t let it accumulate later. Entrepreneurs, including me, have raised this question before, why is Russia’s foreign trade so unbalanced? 80% comes from Europe and 20% comes from Asia. We need to find a balance. In the next two or three years, we will work hard to solve the problems that have not been solved before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, we must invest in infrastructure, not just logistics facilities, but also financial platforms. The financial platform is not just a settlement issue. The two countries have learned how to settle in their own currencies, but the debt market has not yet achieved the results we want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, the Russian automobile industry began to talk about import substitution, but they did not start to do it until the problems had arisen. Five or 10 years ago, it was unimaginable that the United States would do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the sanctions imposed on you by the United States seriously affected your life? Will it affect you psychologically? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a psychological point of view, I don’t think it has a big impact. I served in the army during the Soviet period and encountered even more severe situations. Since then, I have had a different attitude and understanding of danger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why were you sanctioned by the US Treasury Department? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2017, one of my companies was listed in London and successfully attracted US$2 billion in investment. Five months later, my company and I were included in the sanctions list. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They mentioned various excuses, but in fact there was no legal reason to put me on the sanctions list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One excuse is that at the Davos Forum in Dalian, I gave a speech that mentioned the establishment of a unified energy market in the East, but the real theme of my speech was to promote the development of nuclear energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, aluminum prices rose by 70%, and speculators made a lot of money. This goes to show that if you don&#39;t take into account the dangers and hope for a good partnership, sooner or later the dangers will materialize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height= &quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2021, in Washington, DC, the United States, the FBI searched several properties of Oleg Deripaska. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will sanctions affect the lives of you and your family? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For me personally, there is no impact at all. From a young age, I didn’t have many material needs. For others, especially if their children study abroad, the impact is quite large. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have been sanctioned very early. Have any friends come to you to ask for advice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have extensive experience in dealing with sanctions from Western countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My conclusion is to invest in countries that do not rely on the Western financial system. If there is an extreme conflict between any country and the United States, no one will abide by the law, and these real estate and projects will be taken away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you feel sad when your property is taken away? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To be honest, I don’t have any special feelings. I am not a person who cares about material things very much. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How can we not worry about being sanctioned?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Without independence, this will always be a problem. If you just lack certain supplies, you can still survive in five or ten years. I think the world is aware of this danger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is the independence you are talking about a kind of isolationism? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Oleg Deripaska: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course not. We are facing global problems, such as climate change, poverty, disease, etc. However, sanctions will not promote the development of a certain country. Only trust between countries, only economic cooperation and mutually beneficial development between countries can solve these global problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will Western sanctions make the sanctioned countries change their policies? Will not. Everyone would still be able to survive without Tesla cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, these sanctions will make us rethink our own development and fill some loopholes and shortcomings. For example, promoting the development of transportation and logistics, improving our financial market, and conducting settlement in local currency. We must build a new international security system and a new international relations system to avoid new crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous world was centered on the West, that is, all technologies and investments were initially determined by Western countries, which also led to many regional conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不清楚孩子上了什么学，回家陪读三年仅是一次情感弥补？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259687]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Downstairs where I work, there is a circle of shops, including restaurants, small supermarkets, fruit and vegetable shops, and morning stalls. The shop... is surrounded by an industrial park, and there is only one commercial place around. It is very lively here during meals and commuting, and these shops are running well. I have been working here since the building was built, and most of these shops have been operating here since the beginning, so I know many of the merchants and often chat with them while shopping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years ago, the proprietress of the Shaxian snack bar downstairs returned to Fujian to accompany her children in high school. Recently, I saw her when I was eating at a snack bar in Shaxian County, and asked, &quot;Are you back from studying with me?&quot; She said, &quot;Back!&quot; I asked again, &quot;Which university did your child go to after the college entrance examination?&quot; She scratched her head and answered. : &quot;I don&#39;t know!&quot; I asked: &quot;You have been studying with your child for three years, and you have achieved results after three years. You don&#39;t know what your results are?&quot; She still shook her head and said, &quot;I really don&#39;t know...anyway ...It seems to be from our side...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, I went to the small supermarket nearby to buy something. The small supermarket was run by a couple, they were from Anhui, and the male owner I am explaining to the hostess, don’t forget to transfer living expenses to the child. I asked, &quot;Is your child going to college?&quot; They nodded and said they just went to college this year. I continued to ask: &quot;Which university does the child go to?&quot; The male host lowered his head and thought for a moment, and said, &quot;I can&#39;t remember either.&quot; I looked at the hostess, and she said, &quot;Don&#39;t ask me, I can&#39;t either.&quot; I know...&quot; the male host interjected, &quot;He said he was in Chengdu... studying design... or something else...&quot; I couldn&#39;t help but be dumbfounded and joked: &quot;You two don&#39;t know what&#39;s important! You two only know how to transfer it to your children. Living expenses!&quot; They both looked at each other, not understanding what I was laughing at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, most couples or one spouse works outside the home and the children study in their hometown. If one spouse works outside the home, the life of the spouse at home will focus on the child&#39;s studies and spend time accompanying them to school. Both husband and wife work outside the home, and many people choose to go back to study with their children at some important stages and moments, such as the third year of junior high school, the third year of high school, etc. This is all in the hope that by accompanying them to study, they can help their children learn so that they can get into the ideal school. However, when I heard that the proprietress of a snack bar in Shaxian County accompanied her child to high school for three years and did not know what university the child finally went to, I thought that the effectiveness of accompanying him to study is questionable. It should be about the same whether he studies with him or not. , the three years of accompanying her were probably just an emotional make-up. When I heard that the couple in the small supermarket did not know the school and major their children were studying in, I was thinking that this seemed to be someone else’s business. The essence of university education is to pay for living expenses with your head covered. It is an education that is at a loss. invest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before yesterday, I called a water station downstairs and asked the store to send me a bucket of bottled water. The store responded that it could not be delivered, and there was no one in the store. The child was about to enter high school, and the wife went home to study with the child. If she wanted water, she would bring it herself. Originally, I could call another water station to have water delivered, but after the previous two experiences and my thinking, I immediately decided to go downstairs to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the water station and asked the shopkeeper: &quot;Why does your wife want to go home to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Then everyone is accompanying you, so it&#39;s impossible for us not to accompany you!&quot; the shopkeeper replied . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do when I go back to study with me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do, cook, wash clothes, supervise my children not to play with mobile phones...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Like this Is it interesting to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shop owner chuckled: &quot;We don&#39;t know about that... They say it&#39;s difficult to take the high school entrance examination now... I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t be able to pass...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not an educator myself , but I think there are some basic intellectual things that should be similar. I said to the shopkeeper, take the notes and I will tell you what time it is. I told him with my fingers: 1. Clarify your child&#39;s learning goals, which can be specific to which school he wants to attend, and understand the school&#39;s enrollment plan, enrollment requirements, and performance requirements. requirements and performance requirements as the program; 2. Maintain close contact with school teachers, understand the school’s learning progress and children’s learning situation, and solve possible learning problems in a timely manner. The basic problems should be grasped and the difficult problems should be overcome. ; 3. Your spouse should establish a good work and rest system, and supervise the child to balance work and rest during the learning process. When it is time to study and when it is time to rest, if you want the child not to play with mobile phones, first of all, she must not play with the mobile phone while the child is studying; 4. Don&#39;t use your emotional compensation as a moral standard to ask your children. Encourage your children to learn, but you must also respect your children&#39;s willingness to learn. 5. Caring for your children is long-term. It does not end when you enter high school in the future. Children are independent. However, your child&#39;s study and life are not independent. They are an expression of your family&#39;s common wishes and are closely related to your daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I finished speaking, and the shopkeeper also finished memorizing it, but he blinked, not knowing whether he understood or not. I told him that we would continue the discussion the next time I came to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading to your children is not just about doing laundry and cooking, nor is it as easy a job as sitting aside and playing with your mobile phone while asking your children to do homework and answer mock tests. What is the goal, what are the plans to achieve the goal, how to correct errors in the process of implementing the plan, how to achieve long-term emotional interaction after the plan is realized, how to make up for the failure of the plan, etc. These issues should be considered by the accompanying parents. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a fruit and vegetable shop downstairs. The proprietress of the fruit and vegetable shop also came back from school soon. I asked her: &quot;How did my child do in the exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She replied: &quot;I passed the exam. But the school is not very good, and the child has to repeat the year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked: &quot;Will you no longer accompany me during the repeat year?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said: &quot;I won&#39;t accompany you anymore. , I’ve had enough company, it’s up to him how he does in the next year’s exam, let him go!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s dinner time, people in the industrial park and people upstairs all come upstairs It&#39;s time to eat and consume, and the merchants are busy again. Looking at them being busy, I think about the children behind them who are still studying. I don’t know which universities, high schools or other places of study those children are in. I just hope that they will be healthy in body and mind and make progress every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a practitioner in Shanghai fruit industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦直播间卖假和田玉？谈谈玉的文化、国标及科学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After online anchor Li Jiaqi was accused by JD.com’s purchasing staff of forcing him to “choose one from two” and questioned the alleged monopoly, he went on a professional crackdown on counterfeiting Wang Hai also questioned whether the Hetian jade sold in Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast room was fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jade is a unique culture in China. The Chinese ancestors selected the &quot;beautiful stones&quot; from various stones. Jade is warm, shiny, meticulous and tough, so it is also considered by the Chinese to be benevolent and benevolent. Justice, wisdom, courage, and purity are the five moral qualities. Wearing jade has the effect of preventing evil spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese ancestors’ understanding of jade can be traced back to the Neolithic Age. Humans ground stone tools as tools for chopping and scraping, hunting, and cutting meat. Some ground stone tools showed a smooth and beautiful appearance, and humans began to have a preliminary understanding of jade. This also marks the beginning of the transition of human beings from material needs to spiritual needs. Archaeological research has found that in the late Neolithic Age, many jade products and jade ornaments appeared. At this time, the ancients had realized that jade and stone had completely different functions and aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 3000 BC, jade craftsmanship was separated from stone tool processing technology and became an independent craft category. Based on the production traces left on the jades unearthed from the Hongshan Cultural Site and the Liangzhu Cultural Site, experts have inferred that a rotating jade processing tool - a weight machine - had appeared at that time. This is no different in principle from the jade processing machines we see now. The Shang and Zhou dynasties were the growth stage of Chinese jade art. The scope of use of jade expanded, and the number and types increased significantly. However, the shapes were still very simple, with only sporadic decorations. Hotan jade also appeared in this era for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period, the art of jade carving developed. At that time, scholar-bureaucrats wore a series of jade ornaments all over their bodies. What reflected the spirit of the times at that time were a large number of jade pendants in the shapes of dragons, phoenixes and tigers, with complex and beautiful shapes and strong Chinese style and national characteristics. The jade pieces of the Tang Dynasty are all treasures. The craftsmanship was further developed and refined. The texture is warm and the luster is soft. Gold and jade complement each other, making them rich and elegant. In the Song Dynasty, jade gradually entered people&#39;s lives. Influenced by calligraphy and painting at that time, the style became more realistic and full of life. During the Ming and Qing Dynasties, jade art reached its peak, and various types of exquisite jade articles emerged in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The definition of real jade and non-real jade has long been reflected in the system of jade use in Chinese history. Hotan jade is the highest level of jade, it is real jade, and is used by emperors. After countless years, Hotan jade has just entered the folk world. The one that caused the controversy this time was Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing Wang Hai’s doubts, Yuanyang Jinlou, the owner of the cargo in Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, posted the appraisal certificates, including the National Jewelry and Jade Quality Supervision and Inspection Center (NGTC), Guangdong Gold and Silver Jewelry Testing Center Co., Ltd., National Gold and Silver Products Quality Inspection and Testing Center (Nanjing) Organization, Shenzhen Zhongdi Jewelry Testing Co., Ltd. These institutions are not without authority. So, what is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the question of whether it is fake. According to Wang Hai, GB/T38821-2020 stipulates that the appraisal certificate must have total mass and physical photos, and consumers received 18 appraisal certificates attached to the necklace. Not only are each 40g, but they are also photos of a shared necklace. , then it is suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the problem of counterfeiting is easy to solve, but what is difficult to solve is the second level problem, which is the standard issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standards used by these institutions are the national Hetian jade testing standards GB/T16552-2017 and GB/T16553-2017. This 2017 standard does not clearly stipulate the specific content of tremolite. As long as the main component is tremolite, it can be named &quot;Hetian Jade&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hai adopts another standard, namely GB/T 38831-2020. The GB/T38821-2020 &quot;Hetian Jade Identification and Classification&quot; launched in 2020 was developed by the State Administration for Market Regulation and China Released by the National Standardization Administration Committee, it is the latest national standard for the Hetian jade industry. The mineral composition of Hetian jade is described as: &quot;Mainly composed of tremolite, the secondary mineral can be actinolite, and can contain a small amount of calcite, diopside, pyrite, pyrite, chromite, and magnetite. , quartz, serpentine, chlorite, epidote, wollastonite, apatite and garnet, etc.&quot; According to this standard, the naming rule is: when the percentage of other minerals in the same piece of jade is less than 5%, Hetian jade can be named directly. When the percentage of other minerals is more than 5% (except black jade), if the other minerals contained are evenly distributed and the boundaries of the mineral particles are clear, use &quot;tremolite jade&quot; with a note indicating that it contains other minerals. For example: tremolite jade (including tremolite jade) carbonates). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, things are clear. Both standards are used in the industry. The 2017 standard is more relaxed, while the 2020 standard is more stringent. However, this standard is not mandatory and is only a recommended standard. Jade sellers adopted the loose standards introduced in 2017, saying that their items were Hetian jade; while Wang Hai, who fights against counterfeiters, adopted a stricter standard in 2020, saying that the jade sold by Li Jiaqi was fake and did not meet the standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, jade has been difficult to identify clearly since ancient times. What exactly is jade? In fact, many people don&#39;t understand. When we talk about what a thing is, it is actually a chemical question. Chemistry is the study of the composition of matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a chemical perspective, jade is actually a mixture. When we talk about gold, we refer to the material composed of gold atoms; when we talk about quartz, we refer to silicon dioxide; when we talk about ice, we refer to dihydrogen monoxide. Of course, minerals are mixed with other impurities, but in an abstract sense, these things are composed of single atoms or single compound molecules. But jade, in an abstract sense, is a mixture. For example, just like when we talk about Chinese medicinal soup and borscht soup, even in an abstract sense, it must be a mixture of multiple ingredients. Therefore, jade is a mixture, which is a mixture of two or more compounds and elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this concept, it is easier to understand jade. Jade has different chemical compositions, different colors, and different types. The chemical composition of jadeite is sodium aluminum silicate, the most representative of which is jadeite. The chemical composition of nephrite is hydrous calcium magnesium silicate, the most representative of which is Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Hetian jade has four main mineral components: silicon, aluminum, iron and magnesium. Silicon accounts for a large proportion of Hetian jade, and its main forms are calcium silicate (CaSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), magnesium silicate (MgSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), and sodium disilicate (Na&lt; sub>;2&lt;/sub>;Si&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;5&lt;/sub>;), etc.; the aluminum element is mainly albite (NaAlSi&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>; 8&lt;/sub>;), and also contains a small amount of aluminum silicate; iron mainly exists in the form of potassium ferroaluminate and iron silicate. It can be seen that Hetian jade has many ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charm of jade, its appeal to people in terms of look and feel, stems from this characteristic of jade&#39;s chemical composition. This has also caused various confusions in the naming, identification, and even price of jade. Some people say that the wholesale price of jade sold by Li Jiaqi is only a few dozen yuan. But then again, the wholesale price of tens of thousands of jade in those tourist attractions and jewelry stores may only be a few hundred yuan or less. This is the characteristic of the jade industry. As the old saying goes, &quot;Gold has a price, jade is priceless.&quot; This does not mean that gold is not as valuable as jade, and jade is a priceless treasure. It means that the price of jade has been confusing and confusing since ancient times, and the profits are often abnormally high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room is said to have the lowest price on the entire Internet. Consumers believe it, but there is a gap between their expectations and reality. In fact, if you really want to buy cost-effective jade, the live broadcast room is not a good place. Only knowledgeable people with instruments can identify, and only with the ability to identify can we negotiate a good price. Obviously, most consumers cannot do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>