<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从自由市场谈“父权”与“资本”的矛盾性]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258662]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some people like to talk about &quot;patriarchy and capitalism&quot; and connect &quot;patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capitalism&quot; At the same time, it is actually very inaccurate. This concept is similar to the term &quot;feudal autocracy&quot; because logically speaking, since it is feudal, it is obvious that it cannot be &quot;autocratic&quot;. And &quot;autocracy&quot; cannot be feudal. Similarly, if there really is &quot;paternal authority&quot;, that is, the kind of powerful patriarch that many people imagine, who can strictly control their children, then the children will naturally not be able to freely enter big cities to work. And under the conditions of capital and free markets, it is actually very easy for a woman or man to get rid of &quot;patriarchy&quot; and enter a big city as a free atomic individual to work in a company cubicle. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capital&quot; are contradictory&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In other words, it is precisely the free market, &quot;capital&quot; and modern enterprises that allow a large number of women/men to become &quot;independent workers&quot; female/male” rather than continuing to obey traditional “patriarchal” dictates. In fact, if you think about it for a moment, if you are a traditional &quot;father&quot; who cares very much about your authority over your children, and you see your children running to work in the markets of big cities and breaking away from your authority, will you applaud or applaud? Will be very angry? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, capital and market economy are exactly what dismantle &quot;patriarchy&quot;, at least for most ordinary people. In traditional &quot;patriarchal&quot; societies, people&#39;s lives are dominated by mutual assistance and division of labor in small agricultural communities, and they need to respect family authority and various authoritative customs. However, in the market economy lifestyle, all other needs besides work can be obtained through commercial purchases. A modern independent woman/man can live alone without buying food to cook, order takeout when hungry, and shop at will online. Just live a happy life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highly developed living conditions of modern market economy will of course bring about new problems, such as atomized lifestyle, the collapse of family values, the low fertility rate in big cities, etc. But in any case, it is absurd to bring &quot;patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capital&quot; together, because the two are precisely contradictory. &quot;Patriarchy&quot; feels that with the rise of &quot;capital&quot; and the market, their children have gone to big cities, and their authority has collapsed. In &quot;capital&quot;, everyone is a customer. I don&#39;t care whether your customer wants to be a &quot;patriarch&quot; or an &quot;independent woman/man&quot;. Anyway, as long as you pay, I will provide you with products and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The free market is an accelerator&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Hayek said that in the capital market, every purchase by customers and consumers is a vote, and the market produces the products that best satisfy their needs. A company, brand or business model that customers want. Ordinary people who were destined to have a humble status in pre-modern society have become owners with the ability to vote in the era of capital markets. This is an important progress. Hayek&#39;s judgment is very correct. Under capital and market conditions, if a woman/man wants to be a &quot;modern independent woman/man&quot;, it will be too late for &quot;capital&quot; to please him and will tend to cater to all the life he likes. way to provide a variety of business services that he prefers. In order to cater to traffic, self-media will also be happy to produce various articles that &quot;modern independent women/men&quot; like to read. To a certain extent, it is precisely in order to cater to customers that &quot;capital&quot; is happy to produce text products such as &quot;Patriarchy and Capitalism&quot; that customers like to read. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a paradox, but the logic of &quot;capital&quot; is indeed the same. Capital will provide whatever customers need. In other words, &quot;capital&quot; itself is neutral and does not matter good or evil. The products it embodies represent the interests of the customer group. As for the consequences after customers enjoy these products, &quot;capital&quot; does not care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a severely obese junk food lover, &quot;capital&quot; can provide him with a large amount of cheap junk food and &quot;Fat House Happy Water&quot; because this is the demand of customers. For a person who is interested in weight loss and fitness and has strong willpower, &quot;capital&quot; can develop various commercial services for weight loss and fitness, and help this customer achieve a satisfactory body shape. If a person is keen on watching soap operas or playing games, &quot;capital&quot; can provide such nipple entertainment in large quantities at low prices and high quality, and its entertainment effect is unmatched by any pre-modern era. And if a person wants to read high-end classical works, gold inscriptions and silk scrolls, ancient Greek, and Latin, &quot;capital&quot; will also provide them with relevant commercial services, and the price is cheaper than at any time in pre-modern times, and it can be obtained more easily. universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, &quot;capital&quot; does not care about the value dimension at all. It is neutral and provides whatever customers need. &quot;Patriarchy&quot; and &quot;modern independent women/men&quot; are all value dimensions. Whether a person wants to indulge in fat house happy water or lose weight and keep fit, &quot;capital&quot; can provide services. In other words, &quot;capital&quot; is just a huge, efficient accelerator that helps people get what they need more efficiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Everyone pays for their own preferences&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;But the results of these options are paid by the customers themselves, and &quot;capital&quot; is not responsible for the consequences of these choices. As a species of Homo sapiens, many of our &quot;personal hobbies&quot; are actually just natural instincts that have been engraved into our genes for 200,000 years of lifestyle, and are not as &quot;personal&quot; and individual as we imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people like pets. The images of pets with chubby round faces and big eyes are actually the closest thing to human infants and young children. In the evolutionary path of Homo sapiens for 200,000 years, this preference for chubby, round faces and big eyes has been engraved into the genes. In pre-modern societies, this was natural. It’s only in modern big cities and with the emergence of new cultures that people have the conditions to deceive this long-term instinct. At this time, &quot;capital&quot; can provide services, such as various pet markets, cute animal industry chains, and cute animal subcultures. As long as customers demand it, &quot;capital&quot; will continue to provide these services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fat House Happy Water, high-sugar and high-oil snacks, etc., the love for sweetness and fat is also an ancient instinct in the long process of evolution and is engraved in genes. It&#39;s just that the body of Homo sapiens never dreamed that the industrial revolution would produce a huge amount of high-carbohydrate food, and it was not adapted to the two, so it often resulted in &quot;fat homes&quot;. &quot;Capital&quot; effectively satisfies this primitive love for carbohydrates and fats, and &quot;fat house&quot; has therefore become a way of life in big cities. The killings and wars in video games are actually the elements that Homo sapiens have been most familiar with for 200,000 years and have been engraved in their genetic instincts, that is, wars or hunting between tribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, due to the increased threshold after entering big cities and modern life, for example, in the past, a woman might see Zhang San, a young man who was strong and good-looking in the village, and he was an ideal candidate. . But in modern big cities and lifestyles, all kinds of movies, TV shows, advertisements, and short videos are full of handsome Obamas, and the threshold has been greatly increased. So &quot;capital&quot; provides idol dramas, that is to say, &quot;capital&quot; can very efficiently get people&#39;s needs. As for the results after customers get it, &quot;capital&quot; doesn&#39;t care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The developed capital markets and commerce in modern big cities can completely separate people from small communities such as traditional families and rural areas, and lead a very atomized home-boy and home-girl life. In terms of comfort, this kind of atomized urban individual is relatively comfortable, although it will be accompanied by some problems. Then which lifestyle to choose can be freely chosen based on different people&#39;s time preferences, and &quot;capital&quot; will help them get the content they choose faster. Of course, the lifestyle in modern big cities will also have &quot;capital&quot; to produce related culture to argue that the atomized lifestyle is advanced and free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people stand in a position of sympathy and understanding of &quot;patriarchy&quot;. From the perspective of conspiracy theory, they feel that this is a &quot;capital conspiracy&quot;, and even speculate that this is a &quot;transnational XX capital conspiracy&quot;, which is to be dismantled. Family and childbearing culture. Objectively speaking, this conspiracy theory is absurd, and no secret group could devise such a conspiracy. This big city phenomenon is actually determined by the neutral force of &quot;capital&quot; itself. This also shows that since it is &quot;capital&quot;, it is impossible to be &quot;patriarchal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Capital&quot; is a neutral accelerator, so in this era, groups who choose different values ​​and lifestyles will get the results of their choice more efficiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some family businesses in the southeast region attach great importance to traditional family values ​​and maintain a relatively good fertility culture. Of course, when doing business with foreign countries, it doesn’t matter what the customers want. But earning money from customers can help the reproduction of your family. In other words, business and your own life are two different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern developed capital and free markets actually give people more diversified and free choices. If an otaku is willing to choose &quot;Happy Water&quot; and play a successful hero in an online game, that is It&#39;s your choice, just bear the consequences of your choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely &quot;capital&quot; that allows more people to have a variety of choices and live an atomic and individual free life that the ancestors of Homo sapiens never dared to imagine for 200,000 years, with almost no restrictions. constraints of traditional community ties. Therefore, it is absurd to associate “capital” with “patriarchy”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[京津冀洪灾后的这两月：弥合的伤口，艰难的重生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258800]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 17, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, villagers received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. .(Visual China/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 17, 2023, villagers in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When floods besieged Zhuozhou, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Wholesale Market was the hardest hit area. More than a month has passed, and the smell of rotten protein and slightly sweet fermentation that once permeated the market has dissipated. The wind blows, raising the dust that the remaining silt has dried up, leaving only a smell of earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the floods first receded, only mud was left in Xiu Mingyu’s shop, an auto parts dealer. There were yellow water stains on the walls and several large cabinets. Nishui Yinzi&#39;s loss of auto parts is roughly estimated at 300,000 yuan - on a good day, her annual income is only around 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The most terrible thing is that in April 2023, Xiu Mingyu had just paid the arrears of store rent, which she had to borrow 100,000 yuan from a friend. Qi. The lease expires in April next year. If the store cannot reopen, the rent will be in vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In late July and early August 2023, extreme heavy rains swept across the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region, causing floods in many places in Beijing and Hebei. Among them, the people who are most affected by floods are the people living around Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On weekdays, the prosperity of Beijing seems to be within reach. But when disaster strikes, the test they face becomes even more severe. In October 2023, when there were no traces of floods in the core urban areas of Beijing, they were still working hard to rebuild their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Agricultural Products Wholesale Market in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“How much business can compensate for losses?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Both rented cooked food at Dashiqiao Wholesale Market Lin Fenyi, who works at the stall, did not work up the courage until August 8 to go to her cooked food processing factory in Congyuan Village, Zhuozhou City to see the aftermath of the disaster: four cold storages had holes ripped open by water, maggots were crawling on the rotten meat, and the air was filled with It was filled with a stench that reached straight to the Tianling Cap. She wiped away tears on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After wiping away the tears, the factory was still saved. Lin Fenyi spent 40,000 yuan to hire a forklift to shovel mud, but it turned out that she could not drive into the factory. She took a big shovel and used human power to push the mud out of the factory door little by little, and then the forklift shoveled it to the roadside. The rotting meat was dug and buried in pits. When the pits were filled, the carrion was piled on the road, and the village sent people to push it off the field. Xiu Mingyu was also very busy trying to reopen the store. For a month, she went to the shop at 8 a.m. every morning to wash and wash her hands, and worked until 7 p.m. at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 1st, the store reopened, with white walls and shelves full of new products, giving it the appearance of a new life. But the troubles kept coming one after another. The new container I bought for several thousand yuan soon swelled due to the moisture in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiu Mingyu is in urgent need of funds. She received a call from someone claiming to be a bank employee, asking if she needed a loan. The store&#39;s goods were short of 80,000 to 100,000 yuan, but she couldn&#39;t trust the private number calling from Liaoning. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Business is also deserted. Xiu Mingyu guessed that her store was on a low ground, and after the flood, no one would dare to go to the store to buy anything when it rained. However, even if the customer flow remains the same, &quot;How much business can compensate for these losses?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the flood just passed, she was not sure about post-disaster livelihood. A month later, she was already a little calm. She felt comfortable earning a small amount of money in the store. As long as she wanted to open up, she could make do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After spending 300,000 yuan, Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory also resumed production in mid-September. She desperately tried to make up for the losses of the past month or so. During the factory shutdown, some old customers turned to other manufacturers to place orders. For this reason, she thought of a &quot;ruthless move&quot;: &quot;People sell pig head meat in the market now, and half a catty sells for 12 yuan, so I have to sell it for 11...I won&#39;t make a penny, dragging my former customers. Don&#39;t drag customers.&quot; , you have no transaction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The transaction is open, but the &quot;pulse&quot; is still very weak. Before the disaster, Lin Fenyi pledged 1 million yuan on the goods and spent another 1 million yuan on expanding the factory. She said there was almost &quot;no money&quot; on the books. After work resumed, she had to lay off only three or four workers; condensing machines , sausage filling machines and other machines were all scrapped, and there was no money to replace them. After three days of resumption of production, the shipment volume was only one ton, which was one-sixth of the original maximum production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Debts accumulated quickly. In addition to the hundreds of thousands of yuan she borrowed to expand the factory, she also owes money to various suppliers. One of the pig trotters suppliers, who owed more than 10,000 yuan, came to collect payment several times and was &quot;really getting worried.&quot; Lin Fenyi showed the other party screenshots of her WeChat balance. One time it was a few hundred yuan, and another time it was just over a thousand yuan. &quot;It&#39;s not enough for my children to go to school and buy things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Xitan Village, Zhuozhou City, Du Huanying, who runs a nursing home in partnership with Yan Cheng, is also in a similar predicament. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The nursing home covers an area of ​​5 acres and has more than 60 rooms. Du Huanying remembered that before the flood came, the government moved 58 elderly people in the nursing home to another nursing home in the city in advance because the nursing home was located on a low ground. By August 7, 6 elderly people had been picked up by their family members, and 2 elderly people had passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After borrowing 500,000 yuan to invest, Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home partially resumed operations. On the afternoon of September 15, the nursing home was filled with iron frame beds that had been moved out, and Du Huanying was wiping the rust spots on the bed. She said that the elderly people who had been temporarily moved out had been moved back into their homes, but the economic losses exceeded one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Du Huanying’s nursing home in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the Hebei Provincial Local Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, as of August 23, Zhuozhou City’s financial institutions had visited a total of 1,584 matching companies. households, with loans of 108.905 million yuan issued; the city&#39;s rural housing insurance has prepaid 26,960 households, a total of 80.88 million yuan; planting insurance has prepaid 105,300 acres, a total of 52.6222 million yuan; breeding insurance has prepaid 11,644 heads, a total of 17.1295 million yuan; Vehicle insurance has paid out compensation for 10,157 vehicles, up to 658 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to CCTV, after the disaster, 14 counties (cities, districts) in Baoding provided counterpart support to 11 towns in Zhuozhou. By the beginning of October, a total of 28 construction teams with 1,040 people from outside Zhuozhou had helped the affected people repair their houses. In addition, the total number of flooded houses in Zhuozhou City is 54,323. Excluding those who are not willing to rebuild, the total number of restoration and reconstruction tasks is 52,843, and 46,706 have been completed. All 124 dilapidated and collapsed buildings that need to be completed in 2023 have started construction, and people&#39;s production and living order is being restored at an accelerated pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Life around Beijing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beijing has a complex meaning for Xiu Mingyu. Today, many of her customers are car owners commuting between Beijing and Zhuozhou. But she once had to leave Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than 20 years ago, Xiu Mingyu left his hometown in Henan and went to Beijing. He started as a supermarket salesperson with a monthly salary of 400 yuan, and his husband learned to do auto repair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The couple&#39;s life has always been tight. After deducting living expenses from their salary, there is not much money left. In 2009, a child was born, and life became even less affluent. A family of three lived in an urban village in Haidian District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After working in a supermarket for seven or eight years, in 2014, Xiu Mingyu decided to open an auto parts store with her husband. A year later, the couple moved to Shijingshan District on the outskirts of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The store was still being renovated, and the two received a clearance notice again. Now recalling the experience of being forced to move twice, Xiu Mingyu is glad that when she left Shijingshan, at least the local government compensated her for the cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Fenyi also worked as a North Piao. When she was sixteen or seventeen, she left her hometown in Heilongjiang and went to Beijing to sell clothes, where she met her husband, who was a construction worker at the time. In 2004, the two got married and returned to their husband&#39;s hometown in Zhuozhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I first returned to Zhuozhou, life was not easy. Lin Fenyi remembers that when she was in confinement after giving birth to her daughter, her husband’s old house still had cracks in it. Her father did not dare to come see her. After his brother came, he asked: &quot;Sister, how can you find such a poor person? How can you live in such a house?&quot; He introduced his sister to a way out, making cooked food, &quot;It&#39;s better to do some small business.&quot; It’s better than working for someone else.” The couple slowly started a cooked food business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng didn’t have to leave his hometown. He prides himself on being &quot;very smart&quot;. In a township in Zhuanghe City, Liaoning Province, he learned to be a doctor and carpenter at the age of 17, drove a large truck, ran an oil mill, a wood processing factory, and worked as an agricultural machinery station. Webmaster. After struggling for more than ten years, his hometown was about to be flooded due to the construction of a reservoir. He became a &quot;reservoir immigrant&quot; and went to Zhuozhou to live with his relatives in 2000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he arrived in Zhuozhou, Yan Cheng also struggled a lot. He once ran an auto repair shop and earned 300,000 yuan a year. However, he had to close down due to an accident in 2008. In 2015, he joined Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nursing homes are not a profitable business. Du Huanying said that their fees are not high to begin with, but special groups who encounter family difficulties only charge cost. The hospital only earns 150,000 yuan a year, but the investment is huge. Initially, the two spent 2.8 million yuan building a courtyard for more than 40 elderly people. Later, a local official suggested that they expand, so they spent more than 2 million yuan to expand a second courtyard in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The second courtyard had just been completed when it encountered an epidemic. The nursing home is under closed management and cannot admit new elderly people. Yan Cheng&#39;s son-in-law said that during the epidemic, they did not ask the elderly family members to pay for various medicines. &quot;It has not been easy to make money for three years during the epidemic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Lin Fenyi&#39;s eyes, her business has not been making money for a long time. In the beginning, she and her husband knew nothing, so they could only throw in three to five thousand yuan to accumulate experience. If a batch of goods was broken, they would throw it away and replace it with another batch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This line is dirty and tiring. When stewing pig heads, work starts at 5 a.m. and the pig heads are shaved first. This work makes people covered in oil. Afterwards, the brains are cut open, and the pig head divided into two sections is boiled in a pot. After cooking, the bones and meat are separated, washed, bagged, and put in the cold storage to freeze. The work can only be finished at eight or nine in the evening. There is no heating in the winter. The place - about ten years ago, my husband&#39;s old house was demolished, and the family had to live in the factory bungalow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Linfen Yijia’s factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After so many years, their lives are finally on the right track: Xiu Mingyu opened a shop, bought a house, and settled down in Zhuozhou. The fate of being constantly exiled seems to have come to an end; Yan Cheng and Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home survived the epidemic, and even elderly people from Beijing came to stay there; Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory gradually made money, hired workers, and her husband took care of it. When it comes to purchasing goods, she is in charge of sales, and the cooked food is sold to Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until the flood hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng is 64 years old and cannot retire yet. &quot;I have to help her (Du Huanying). If I don&#39;t, she will fall down immediately.&quot; The cost of building a nursing home is still nearly 4 million yuan, and new debts have been incurred after the flood. This old man, who had been swallowed by water twice in his life, decided to work for a few more years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The missing son, the deceased wife&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son Ma Lihua disappeared in the mudslide more than two months ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Initially, Ma Xianlin, a villager in Tangjiazhuang Village, Laishui County, pinned his hope of finding his son on an excavator. By mid-September, he had no choice but to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;21-year-old Ma Lihua is a student majoring in imaging medicine and will just graduate in the summer of 2023. He was supposed to have a life slowly unfolding in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tangjiazhuang Village is one of the villages severely affected by this round of heavy rains and floods. On July 31, Ma Xianlin narrowly escaped from the mudslide that poured into the yard, but Ma Lihua was nowhere to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son should have walked out of this mountain. When she was a child, Ma Lihua occasionally said she didn&#39;t want to study anymore, and Ma Xianlin would always show up and give her own account: He dropped out of elementary school in the third grade and was uneducated, so he had to work in a coal mine. Earning money was difficult and dangerous. So, my son returned to school obediently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, Ma Lihua just completed more than nine months of hospital internship and graduated from a college in Tangshan. During the summer, he was learning to drive while planning for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ma Xianlin said that a relative in Zhuolu County once wanted to introduce his son to a job in a small hospital, but he refused and insisted on going to Beijing. My sister, who has been a fitness instructor in Beijing for 10 years, also wants to take her younger brother with her. If she can&#39;t go to a big hospital, she goes to a small clinic. She remembered that her brother once asked her if she wanted to go outside to practice. She replied decisively, &quot;Just stay by my side.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, the day when siblings get together may never come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first time that 65-year-old Ma Xianlin has lost a close relative. When he was 12 years old, his father was hit in the head by a falling stone while working in the production team. He died before he could be carried to the hospital. The mother was so anxious about her husband&#39;s death that she lost her sight. A few years later, several of Ma Xianlin&#39;s sisters got married and left home, leaving him and his mother alone in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It wasn&#39;t until he was in his thirties that Ma Xianlin married a wife and had someone to take care of his mother, so he was able to go out to work. In Hebei, he worked in private coal mines and also paved roads and built walls. Four years ago, Ma Xianlin got old and couldn&#39;t move big rocks, so he bought 30 sheep and started herding them in his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The flock continues to multiply. In 2022, Ma Xianlin sold 48 lambs for 20,000 to 30,000 yuan. By this year, he already had 160 sheep. Based on the calculation of 700 yuan for a lamb and 1,400 yuan for an adult sheep, this will be a good income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly, in a mudslide, nearly half of the sheep disappeared. For more than a month after the disaster, he went up the mountain every day to look for sheep, but he harvested very little. He had a bone spur in his leg and had to take medicine every day to treat the leg pain. He had to walk up and down the mountains to herd and find sheep, which was unbearable for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am getting older and my younger (children) are gone.&quot; In the end, he made up his mind to sell all the sheep after autumn. On September 12, when asked about his future livelihood, Ma Xianlin remained silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 15, Southern Weekend reporters contacted Ma Xianlin again, hoping to learn about the progress of his search for his son. He didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirty kilometers away in Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, 67-year-old villager Pang Shenggong also lost his loved ones in flash floods and mudslides on July 31. His wife was swept away by the current, and the family searched for seven or eight miles but could not find her. Later, someone found her body 70 to 80 kilometers away from her home and brought her back to the village for burial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 12, 2023, Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he met the Southern Weekend reporter on September 15, Pang Shenggong was no longer willing to mention this sad incident. He had just come out of the mountains, wearing a bamboo hat and his clothes were no longer messy - a month ago, he was covered in mud when cleaning up the washed-out house, and his trousers were only tied with a cloth belt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In his impression, his wife has a cheerful personality and likes to dance in the village yangko team. But three years ago, my wife had a fall. After the operation, her body was not as good as before, and she could not walk on the aisle. &quot;I can&#39;t leave you for a while,&quot; Pang Shenggong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is not easy to make a living while being chained to your home. Since the 1980s, Pang Shenggong has been working outside the home and often goes to Beijing. He worked in the coal mines of Fangshan District to dig coal and build railways. He continued to work until he was in his fifties. In order to take care of his children and go to school, he gradually stopped going out and worked small jobs in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After his wife&#39;s surgery, Pang Shenggong never worked as a minor worker again. Fortunately, the younger son is moving goods in a warehouse in Gu&#39;an County, Langfang City, so he can supplement Pang Shenggong&#39;s monthly salary of three to four thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Pang Shenggong has moved into the temporarily unused house of the third brother in the east of the village, and is ready to live a hard life. &quot;How much money do you have to spend?&quot; His voice gradually faded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Hebei Daily, on September 22, the first batch of post-disaster reconstruction projects in Laishui County have started intensively, with a total investment of 185 million yuan, including river cleaning The siltation project, four bridge reconstruction projects and the first batch of post-disaster power distribution network reconstruction projects will be completed before the 2024 flood season. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Villages in the suburbs of Beijing heal the wounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the suburbs of Beijing, mountains separate the villages from the prosperity . A flood passed through and the force of nature tore the village apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, according to villager Liu Huazao, there were originally one or two thousand people living in the village. An entire street in the south was seriously damaged by the flood. About one to two hundred people were temporarily relocated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 27, Liu Huazao&#39;s father went to Tongren Hospital for eye laser treatment. Some time ago, he always felt like mosquitoes were flying in front of his eyes. After checking, he found out that the vitreous body had fallen off. Liu Huazao felt that this was caused by his father being upset and having severe high blood pressure after the flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At around 10 a.m. on July 31, when the water rose the most, the Liu family and their neighbors climbed onto the roof to escape Shen Da. 1.7 meters of water. That night, the water came up again, leaving a second water line about 1 meter high in the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But favor is slowly closing some wounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the water receded, Liu Huazao felt &quot;it&#39;s good to be alive.&quot; The villagers who had survived the disaster met and said to each other, &quot;Just live, don&#39;t talk about anything else.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The relatives are closer. One after another, relatives outside the country reached out to help Liu Huazao&#39;s family, &quot;giving them some money.&quot; The disaster-stricken family even lacked clothes and cooking utensils. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The neighbors suddenly have a &quot;life-changing&quot; friendship. In the past, Liu Huazao didn&#39;t move around very frequently with the villagers, just &quot;meet and say hello.&quot; But he felt that the moments of life and death in the water inspired goodwill in people&#39;s hearts. On the day the family hid on the roof, a neighbor in the front yard helped hold Liu Huazao&#39;s daughter. After the disaster, the villagers helped each other. When the silt in their own homes was almost cleared, they would be cleared by others. Elderly people in the village who had children in other places would ask them what shortcomings there were in their homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembered that before the water supply in the village was restored, a group of young people organized water trucks to deliver water for washing to the villagers. For four or five days, they stopped the car at the entrance of the alley and called the villagers to get water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu, who opened a supermarket in the village, witnessed the complexity of human beings in the flood. Five to six thousand yuan in cash was taken away from the supermarket by water, but she only got back more than one thousand yuan. She heard that someone found money, but she didn&#39;t know if it was lost by her family and couldn&#39;t ask for it. She also heard that many people picked up the wine that was washed away from her home, but very little was returned. Only one bottle of 10 bottles of liquor worth more than 1,000 yuan was returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhu Xiu did not feel resentful about this. &quot;If you lose it, it&#39;s not like someone stole it from you. Whoever picked it up belongs to the one who picked it up... We just accept that we are unlucky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiuye I thought maybe insurance would pay some compensation. Last year, she took out an insurance policy in a daze. After the disaster, someone from the insurance company came and told her that the insurance was not for property, but for people. Zhu Xiu, who couldn&#39;t even find the contract, had no choice but to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also discovered the kindness between people. A winery promised to replace her damaged wine for free, and relatives and friends provided money, food, and pots and pans after the disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the supporters, many, like Zhu Xiu, are migrant workers in Beijing. &quot;There is a feeling of closeness... Being so far away from my hometown makes me feel that we can understand each other.&quot; She remembered that about 20 years ago, she and her husband first settled in Cijijiao, and later more foreigners came. Work in the village. Some migrant workers had no money left after buying tickets to Beijing, no place to sleep, and no food to eat. It was she who made noodles and steamed buns and spread bedding in the rented room to provide food and accommodation for them. When those who couldn&#39;t find a job had to leave, she would give them travel expenses. Now, it seems that goodwill from the past has been repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 27, 2023, Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Beijing Daily, on the morning of August 27, Fangshan District held a post-disaster reconstruction swearing-in meeting at Sandu Bridge. The overall goal of reconstruction is &quot;basic recovery in one year, comprehensive improvement in three years, and long-term high-quality development.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Xiuli, chief of the Planning and Urban Design Section of the Fangshan District Planning and Nature Commission, said in an interview with CCTV that according to Beijing&#39;s unified standards, for collapsed buildings It is recommended that dilapidated houses be demolished and rebuilt. Each house will be compensated at a rate of 95,000 yuan. For repairable houses, a repair compensation of 30,000 yuan will be given, and low-income households will receive double compensation. For houses that are uninhabitable, each person will be paid a total of 3,960 yuan for three months. rental subsidy. In addition, each person is provided with a living allowance of 660 yuan. Staff from the Fangshan District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee said that repair compensation of 30,000 yuan has been gradually distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have to stand up no matter what”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the villagers’ accounts, the flood was not the first change that Ci’s housework had experienced. , this once prosperous village has been in decline for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembers that the household chores thirty years ago were more generous than they are now. At that time, there was a dragon dance lantern show, a two-story shopping mall and a movie theater. What supports these are the workers in the surrounding coal mines and cement plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu&#39;s husband is one of them. More than 20 years ago, Zhu Xiu was still farming in her hometown in Anhui, and her life was difficult. When she saw a fellow villager working in Cijiujiu&#39;s cement factory, she came with her husband. Her husband followed the car in the factory, and she sold vegetables in the village. . She remembered that there were many migrant workers at that time, and dozens of people could live in a small courtyard in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the local area, factories and coal mines are a double-edged sword. Liu Huazao still remembers their pollution. When he was a child, there would be gray dust like white flour in the village. On the other hand, although working as a factory and miner does not make much money, it is a job that can make a living at home. Liu Huazao&#39;s father had worked in a cement factory in his early years, driving a tractor to transport stones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 2000, cement plants and coal mines were closed down one after another. The pollution is gone, and the livelihood at home is even more cut off. If they want to make a living, villagers can only run to the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu found that the Anhui fellows who worked at Ciji as housekeepers left one after another, but she did not leave. After her husband lost his job at the cement factory, she borrowed money from relatives and friends to open a supermarket in the village. More than ten years ago, a market was built in the village, and people from surrounding towns came to do business. The supermarket was once very prosperous. &quot;Our business used to be the best in this village.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Around 2015, the village ushered in a turning point - demolition. Some villagers chose to move away and wait to move into the resettlement community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan didn’t leave. The bus driver, who was a farmer, wanted to buy a house for himself, his son and his married daughter, but he failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family did not leave either. Apart from being dissatisfied with the compensation package, the family has gotten used to life in the village. The small courtyard can enjoy the cool air, and the elderly can grow cucumbers, tomatoes, and eggplants, and save some money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only private houses are being demolished, but around 2019, the market in front of Zhuxiujia Supermarket was also demolished and moved elsewhere. Her business gradually shrank, and the supermarket&#39;s annual revenue dropped to two to three million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, in the summer of 2023, there was a record-breaking flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 31, villager Li Guangnan ran out with waist-deep water. On August 20, he returned to work at the bus company. More than a month later, his old life seemed to be back, but he knew that order was far from being restored. When he was working as a driver, he earned a monthly salary of nearly 10,000 yuan at most. In 2022, because of his hearing loss, he took a second job and took a cleaning job, so his monthly salary was reduced to 4,000 yuan. In two years, he will retire, and his income will be cut in half. Life may be even more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan has always been worried about his son. He has worked in both the bus and subway companies, but he didn&#39;t last long and was still old. Before the disaster, my son was driving Didi. After the flood washed away the car, he didn&#39;t even drive Didi again. At the end of September, when asked whether he wanted to return to his old career, his son only replied: &quot;Maybe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family, who did not want to live in a high-rise building, also faced reality. Compromised. The house had to be rebuilt. Before he raised 600,000 yuan to break ground, Liu Huazao rented a house in a nearby community for a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is most worried about his 5-year-old daughter. Just after the flood, his daughter said to him: &quot;Dad, I was so scared that day.&quot; Liu Huazao told her not to be afraid, he would come to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly two months later, Liu Huazao discovered that although her daughter knew that floods would wash away tablets and toys, she still didn’t understand that floods would endanger her life, and she was mentally unstable. Something went terribly wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is also working hard to escape the shadow of the flood. Liu Huazao knows that he is the backbone of the family, and only by adjusting himself can his family feel relieved. So, he tried hard to find some little surprises for himself: plastic objects can still be used after being rinsed, and some electronic devices can still turn on their screens with a swipe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu’s half-life hard work was gone with the water. In mid-September, when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the second time, she said that she felt quite depressed and couldn&#39;t think about it for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the third time at the end of September, she finally recovered. The store still had to stay open, and she didn&#39;t want to cheat the suppliers who agreed to her credit. &quot;You have to stand up and work hard no matter what. You can&#39;t just lie down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She thought that if the business was not going well, she would open a store somewhere else. As for her hometown where she still had three acres of land, Zhu Xiu knew that she would never be able to go back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Ma Xianlin and Ma Lihua, pseudonyms are used in the article)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20家上市银行中报出炉：信贷投放最多的行业不良率高还是低？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258820]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Changes in bank credit asset quality reflect the pulse of the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin, director of the Macro-Prudential Administration Bureau of the People&#39;s Bank of China, attended the press conference on financial statistics for the third quarter of 2023 on October 13 and said that as of the end of June, the average non-performing ratio of systemically important banks was 1.27%, maintaining achieve higher asset quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin said that the total assets of systemically important banks account for 61% of the total assets of my country&#39;s banking industry and 55% of the total assets of the financial industry. Systemically important banks have relatively high structural and business complexity, and relatively strong correlations with other financial institutions. Therefore, data from systemically important banks better reflects the latest changes in the banking industry and even the macroeconomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, 19 of the 20 systemically important banks have been listed on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges, making them the most fully disclosed group in the banking industry. Since 2023, which industries have the best and worst credit assets of systemically important banks? Which banks have the most effective measures to resolve non-performing assets? Which banks have the most adequate disclosure of information about their non-performing assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;823&quot; height= &quot;1102&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New For this purpose, researchers from the Financial Research Center conducted a special review and data analysis of the interim reports of the 20 listed banks with the largest assets (including 19 systemically important banks and China Zheshang Bank). The study found that as of the end of June, the total loan balance of 20 listed banks was nearly 150 trillion yuan, accounting for 63.5% of the total loan scale of all financial institutions; the total scale of non-performing loans was approximately 1.92 trillion yuan, accounting for approximately 48% of the total scale of non-performing assets of financial institutions. %, the average non-performing loan ratio is about 1.28%, which is lower than the average non-performing loan ratio of the banking industry of 1.62%, indicating that the credit quality of large and medium-sized commercial banks is better than that of small and medium-sized banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the real estate industry , manufacturing and business services industries rank among the top three in terms of non-performing loan size, and the accommodation and catering industry, real estate industry and mining industry have the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The balance of non-performing credit card loans exceeded that of personal housing loans for the first time in three years, and the non-performing loan rate was 4.2 times higher than that of personal housing loans. Looking at the regional distribution of non-performing loans, the western region has the largest scale of non-performing loans, and the northeastern region has the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Large loan size and low NPL ratio&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Transportation, warehousing and postal industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Which Which industry receives the greatest support from bank credit? Are their NPL ratios positively or negatively related to bank support? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center combed through the interim reports of 20 listed banks and found that each bank disclosed the distribution of corporate loans in 20 major industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing and postal services are the three industries with the most credit granted by the 20 listed banks. The total loan balance of the three industries at the end of June exceeded 10 trillion. Yuan. With regulators vigorously promoting the high-quality development of the manufacturing industry, the manufacturing industry has become a credit area that major commercial banks attach great importance to. Among the 20 listed banks, 19 banks rank in the top two in terms of manufacturing investment scale. However, the leasing and business services industry ranks first among the 20 banks’ credit lending industries the most, with 10 companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Has the massive increase in industry credit been accompanied by a sharp increase in non-performing loans since then? An analysis by researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that increased credit in some industries is indeed positively related to the growth of non-performing loans. This is especially obvious in the real estate industry. As the credit scale ranks fourth in the industry and the average non-performing rate in the industry ranks second, it has become the industry with the most concentrated credit risks of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1161&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But 20 The industry distribution of credit granted by listed banks does not completely coincide with the industry distribution of non-performing loans. As of the end of June 2023, the average non-performing ratios of the manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing, and postal industries that provide the most credit are only 1.8%, 1.45%, and 0.64% respectively. The real estate, manufacturing, leasing and business services industries have the highest scale of non-performing loans, with balances of non-performing loans reaching 295.1 billion, 266 billion and 208.8 billion respectively. The total scale is close to 770 billion, accounting for 57% of the non-performing balance of corporate loans. The total non-performing loans 40%. Among them, the transportation, warehousing and postal industry has credit extensions of up to 13.8 trillion yuan, but its non-performing ratio is only 0.64%. It is a typical industry with large loan scale and low non-performing ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1232&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also found , the increase in the scale of credit in a certain industry is not necessarily accompanied by the year-on-year increase in the scale of non-performing loans. For example, compared with the end of 2022, as of the end of June 2023, the manufacturing loan balance has increased by as high as 18.83%, and the loan growth rate is at the forefront of all industries, but its non-performing loan balance has remained the same or even slightly decreased compared with the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Banks are most willing to lend in the &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yangtze River Delta&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The intensity of credit support for different industries is differentiated At the same time, in which areas do banks have the greatest differentiation in their countercyclical investments? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that most of the 20 listed banks disclosed the regional distribution of credit and the regional distribution of non-performing loans, but each bank’s regional division method Not the same as above. Among them, the regional distribution rules of six banks, namely Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank of China, China Merchants Bank and China Minsheng Bank, are completely consistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1303&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center analyzed the mid-term reports of the above-mentioned six banks and found that the six banks in the Yangtze River Delta region have the largest credit scale, the highest proportion, the fastest growth rate, and the lowest average non-performing loan ratio. Based on the conclusions of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center&#39;s special survey on Suzhou&#39;s financial ecology in April 2023 (see Southern Weekend APP&#39;s &quot;Suzhou Financial Ecology In-depth Research Special Topic&quot; for details), researchers from Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that as China&#39;s economic engine region , the financial ecology of the Yangtze River Delta region (mainly Shanghai, Jiangsu, and Zhejiang) maintains a leading level in the country. Banks generally want and are willing to lend to the real economy, and the ultra-low non-performing ratio further strengthens the banks&#39; position in the Yangtze River Delta market. Dare to lend, truly lend, and increase confidence in credit extension. Therefore, the Yangtze River Delta region is undoubtedly the area where commercial banks dare to lend the most, and it is also a must-have for the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;975&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rated system Among the five city commercial banks that are important banks, four are from the Yangtze River Delta region. The asset scale, operating efficiency and asset quality of these city commercial banks are among the best in the industry. This proves that the Yangtze River Delta region has the best financial ecological environment in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the credit growth rate of the 20 listed banks in the northeastern region (Heilongjiang, Jilin, and Liaoning) is the slowest, the credit proportion continues to shrink, and the non-performing loan ratio is high among all regions in the country. Data shows that large state-owned banks are more determined than joint-stock banks and city commercial banks in implementing the strategic intentions of decision-makers to revitalize the Northeast. The financial support of large state-owned banks to the Northeast is also the mainstay for the stable operation of the financial industry in the Northeast. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Non-performing personal mortgage loans surged&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The momentum eased&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although corporate loans are the mainstay of commercial bank credit, personal loan business is becoming increasingly important , especially personal housing loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scale of personal mortgage loans remains the largest among all personal loans of commercial banks, and the non-performing rate has been at the lowest level among all types of loan business for a long time. Therefore, it has become the most valued high-quality asset of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes have occurred in the asset quality of personal mortgage loans? In order to facilitate comparisons with the same caliber, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center selected 10 banks’ personal mortgage businesses for statistical analysis. These 10 banks include six state-owned commercial banks, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank, and Bank of Communications, and four national joint-stock commercial banks, China Merchants Bank, Industrial Bank, Shanghai Pudong Development Bank, and Minsheng Bank. As of the end of 2022, the total scale of personal mortgage loans of 10 banks accounts for 80% of the total scale of personal mortgage loans in the banking industry. Therefore, the personal mortgage business of the 10 banks has strong industry representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research shows that starting from 2022, the growth rate of non-performing loan balances of personal housing loans has increased significantly. At the end of June 2022, the total non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 104.871 billion yuan, a sharp increase of 16.8 billion yuan from the end of 2021, with a month-on-month growth rate of 19.1%; in the second half of 2022, the non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks increased again. An increase of 30.4 billion yuan. By the end of 2022, the total balance of non-performing loans has increased to 135.255 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 53.6%; in the first half of 2023, the balance of non-performing loans has reached 138.629 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 32.2%, but the month-on-month growth rate is as high as fell back to 2.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second central bank The quarterly monetary policy implementation report shows that at the end of June, the balance of personal housing loans of major financial institutions across the country (including foreign capital) was 38.6 trillion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.7%, and the first year-on-year negative growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the surge in non-performing loan balances and the stagnant growth rate of loan scale that turned negative, the non-performing rate of personal housing loans has increased significantly since 2022. At the end of June 2023, the average non-performing rate of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 0.48%, an increase of 0.15 percentage points from the end of 2021, an increase of 45%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center believe that despite the rapid growth in the scale and non-performing ratio of personal housing loans, compared with other types of credit, personal housing loans are still high-quality assets of commercial banks and will continue to be an important part of each bank&#39;s personal loan business. focus. At the same time, the central bank and other ministries and commissions have successively introduced new housing loan policies and continued to loosen restrictions on the real estate industry. The asset quality of personal housing loan business is expected to stabilize in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Credit card business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Facing test&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to personal mortgage business, credit card business is also the strategic focus of commercial banks. How does it perform? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center comparatively analyzed the interim reports of 13 commercial banks that disclosed the quality of credit card loans and found that the credit card business has seen multiple trend changes since 2022. First, two important indicators recorded negative growth for the first time on record. Among them, at the end of 2022, the cumulative number of credit cards issued was approximately 798 million, showing negative growth for the first time on record; the outstanding credit balance of credit cards was 8.69 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 0.9%, which was significantly higher than the average annual growth rate of 8% between 2019 and 2021. decline. As of the end of June 2023, the outstanding credit balance of credit cards of 13 listed banks (the scale of credit card business accounts for about 85% of the total scale of the banking industry) was 7.44 trillion yuan, a decrease of about 23 billion yuan from the end of 2022, which was also the first time on record. decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;948&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is credit card The quality of business assets is facing tests. As of the end of June 2023, the total non-performing balance of credit card accounts receivable of 13 commercial banks reached 148.2 billion yuan, slightly exceeding personal housing loans with a limit of 4 billion yuan. Following the 2020 interim report, it has once again become the personal loan business with the largest non-performing loan. . Correspondingly, the average non-performing loan ratio of credit card receivables of 13 banks is 2.29%, which is also a new high in the past three years after the 2020 mid-term report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2023, the asset quality pressure of commercial banks’ credit card business will increase significantly. Among them, the credit card non-performing loan balance and non-performing loan ratio reached two peaks in June 2020 and June 2023 respectively, with the peak in June 2020 being slightly higher than that in June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center further studied the two peaks and found that the peak of credit card non-performing in June 2020 was mainly due to the sudden impact of the epidemic on household and personal balance sheets, superimposed on the factors of untimely repayment caused by restricted movement of people during the epidemic; During the period when the epidemic is calming down, the balance of non-performing loans and non-performing loans of commercial banks&#39; credit cards have tended to fall, but the low point of the decline is still significantly higher than before the epidemic. Since 2023, commercial banks have responded to regulatory requirements and no longer blindly compete for land, but have turned to intensive cultivation and prudent credit extension. The growth of credit card issuance volume, credit scale, unfinished credit scale and other indicators has significantly slowed down or even experienced negative growth. This has also led to a high non-performing rate in credit card business. However, as banks continue to implement prudent strategies, credit card non-performing rates are expected to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Which banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; “&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;optimize”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; bad disclosures? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The two indicators of non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio are the most important and most sensitive indicators to measure the quality of credit assets. Which commercial banks have the courage to conduct complete and comprehensive information disclosure on the quality of their credit assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comparative study of this item by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center is mainly based on whether 20 listed banks disclose information on corporate loans by industry and region, and whether the industry and region of non-performing loans are separately Disclosure: When disclosing the components of personal loans, including personal housing loans, consumer loans, operating loans, and credit card loan balances, proportions, and growth rates, whether the corresponding non-performing loan balances and non-performing ratios are disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study found that in terms of the quality of information disclosure on non-performing loans, the level of disclosure of 20 listed banks varied. Large state-owned banks basically disclosed the above information at the same time. Only Bank of China stated &quot;non-performing&quot; as &quot;impairment&quot; in its annual report, which may easily cause certain misunderstandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the national joint-stock banks, China Merchants Bank has the most complete disclosure of non-performing loans, while other joint-stock banks have more or less &quot;optimized&quot; non-performing loan-related data according to their own needs when disclosing. Typical &quot;optimization&quot; methods include setting personalized &quot;caliber&quot;. For example, when disclosing the industry distribution of non-performing loans, some banks do not directly disclose the non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio data of each industry. However, through other relevant data disclosed by the bank, the distribution of non-performing loans in different industries of the bank can be estimated; For another example, when disclosing the non-performing status of personal housing loans, some banks merged this business with other personal loan businesses with certified mortgages; in addition, when disclosing the regional distribution of non-performing loans, 6 of the 9 joint-stock banks were based on the Yangtze River Delta A total of 6 regions are divided and disclosed, including the Pearl River Delta, the Bohai Rim, the central region, the western region and the northeastern region. However, Ping An Bank and Zheshang Bank divide the country into 4 regions; Industrial Bank divides the country into 4 regions based on geographical regions. The city, province or other important city where the headquarters is located is listed and disclosed separately; individual banks will also fine-tune the provinces under a certain region, making it difficult to make horizontal and vertical comparisons of the regional distribution of the bank&#39;s credit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some banks disclose weaker asset quality for retail loans than for corporate loans. Among the 20 listed banks, 13 banks directly disclosed or indirectly disclosed the distribution of personal loans in their interim reports. However, extending to 2020 and previous annual reports and interim reports, only about 10 banks disclosed the asset quality of personal loans. As a leading city commercial bank, Bank of Beijing has disclosed neither the industry distribution nor the regional distribution of non-performing loans in its previous annual reports and interim reports. It has disclosed the least asset quality among the 20 listed banks. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frequency of mentions of &quot;bad&quot; in financial reports can also be used as an indication of the bank&#39;s credit disclosure adequacy in terms of loan quality. Statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found that China Merchants Bank was mentioned as &quot;non-performing&quot; the most in the 2023 interim report, a total of 94 times, while the Bank of Jiangsu was mentioned the least often, only 19 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True and accurate , completeness, timeliness and fairness are the principle requirements for the information disclosure of listed companies. Standardization, easy to understand and easy to obtain are the basic requirements for the form of information disclosure of listed companies. According to this, a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that listed systemically important banks are the benchmark for China&#39;s banking industry and should also be the benchmark for information disclosure in the banking industry. Annual reports and annual reports should be based on various requirements for information disclosure by listed companies. The disclosure of important information such as interim reports is strictly controlled. In particular, indicators related to bank asset quality and their changes have attracted more attention from investors and the public. Listed banks should disclose true, accurate, complete, timely and fair information, and ensure that the disclosed information is standardized. , easy to understand and obtain, and continuously improve the compliance and transparency of corporate governance of listed banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[挑选、比较和竞争：2024届毕业生的第一场双选会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1103&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D 2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Guangzhou, after the double selection meeting on Jinan University . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lights were all bright in the thousands-square-meter gymnasium, and 28 tables were arranged in a circle. The tabletop is covered with blue velvet, and beside each table stands a promotional poster as tall as one person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on September 20, 2023, at the Wushan Campus of South China University of Technology in Guangzhou, in half an hour, the special double election meeting for Shenzhen state-owned enterprises will begin. This is the third &quot;double selection meeting&quot; prepared by this 985 university for the 2024 graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The topic of employment for graduates in 2023 is still hot, and the school recruitment season for 2024 has begun again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Owen Xin, a senior student in our school’s School of Business Administration, has been waiting on the sidelines for a long time. She had done a lot of planning in advance. She was wearing a white T-shirt with a small colorful pattern and the hem was tucked into light-colored suit pants. It was half casual and half formal. On a certain social platform, a state-owned enterprise employee once posted, Different from the stereotype of full-body formal wear, &quot;business casual&quot; is the image of employees favored by state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Specially for state-owned enterprises”, Owen Xin stepped into the venue of the autumn recruitment fair for the first time. She had long made up her mind to take the civil service examination, and the administrative position in a state-owned enterprise, which was the least stable, was regarded as a &quot;guaranteed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every fall semester begins, thousands of freshmen enter colleges and universities, and thousands of fresh graduates are about to be sent to the next stop on the train of life. But it is not easy to get off the bus. According to data released by the Ministry of Education, the number of college graduates in 2024 is expected to reach 11.87 million, reaching a new high, an increase of 290,000 from 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Double selection usually means the beginning of the new school recruitment season. This is a traditional recruitment form that directly invites companies to join the school to achieve offline face-to-face communication and two-way selection between companies and job-seeking students. Every step and every person leading to the workplace is surrounded by selection, comparison and competition. As policies, markets, and employment concepts change, the status of academic qualifications, majors, industries, and positions has also changed several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last 10 days of September 2023, Southern Weekend reporters visited a total of four double selection meetings of varying sizes in three schools in Guangzhou. At the same time, the autumn double elections across the country started almost simultaneously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1106&quot; height= &quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Guangzhou, the theme of the South China University of Technology was the double selection meeting for the 2024 campus recruitment of Shenzhen state-owned enterprises. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Enterprises that are in trouble&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;They are not You know, our company is very good.” Wang Ming, the head of human resources at a state-owned real estate company in Shenzhen, complained at the Chinese Workers’ Dual Election Meeting on September 20. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the group was founded in 1989 and went public three years later. It is mainly engaged in real estate development and operations and is directly managed by the Shenzhen Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This state-owned enterprise is well prepared. Most companies present only sent two personnel, while they sent three. But obviously, the extra manpower was not put to much use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were very few inquiries. When he was bored, Wang Ming took two photos. One picture is of another company, with four or five students queuing up in front of the booth, waiting for consultation; the other picture is of their own booth, with two HRs staring blankly in front of no one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ming’s group is not the only company that has faced the cold shoulder in this double election. Even if they are state-owned enterprises and some established real estate companies, they have been left out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2010, the golden age of the real estate industry, they were also a popular unit in the double election. &quot;The real estate industry has been in decline since two or three years ago.&quot; HR from one of the companies said frankly, &quot;Many students majoring in civil engineering and architecture have chosen to change industries, and students who intend to find employment in the real estate industry are also more cautious.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;Fortunately, good policies have been introduced.&quot; Wang Ming said, taking out his mobile phone and showing the &quot;internal information&quot; he had obtained. The screenshot with black text on a white background mentioned that some districts in Guangzhou will completely cancel property purchase restrictions. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the &quot;inside information&quot; was publicly confirmed. On the afternoon of the same day, Guangzhou issued the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot; - Guangzhou became the first city among the first-tier cities in the country to partially relax purchase restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time in the past, the three industries of Internet, real estate, and education were known as the “Three Giants of School Recruitment” due to their large number of school recruitment positions and strong talent absorption capabilities. Zhaopin Recruitment Job Demand Data It shows that in 2021, the three giants jointly provided 56% of positions for fresh graduates. In the same year, the situation changed. Due to various reasons, the three giants frequently laid off employees, and the motivation for school recruitment was also insufficient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If real estate practitioners can still see some opportunities from policy changes, the education and training industry still does not know what the future holds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HR Deng Wenqing of a well-known education and training institution considers herself to be very &quot;hardworking&quot;. Since September, as the company&#39;s human resources representative in Guangzhou, she has participated in three double-election meetings. &quot;I was basically the last one to leave.&quot; Another double selection meeting on September 26 was originally scheduled to end at 5 p.m. Deng Wenqing sat until 5:30. Whenever a student stopped in front of the booth, she enthusiastically handed over the brochure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But her diligence cannot eliminate the impact of the education and training reform two years ago. An economics master&#39;s student stopped when passing by the booth and asked bluntly: &quot;Is this unrestricted? Does the state not care?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Wenqing repeated the explanation: &quot;The double reduction is for compulsory education and make-up classes. We only focus on high school subjects in this area, and focus on comprehensive quality training in junior high schools and below, without restrictions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another double selection meeting at the same time, it was also necessary to explain to the students that another tutor The HR of training institutions also adopts basically the same statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going back to July 2021, the &quot;double reduction&quot; curtain has begun. In one year, subject-based off-campus training institutions across the country have been reduced by more than 90%, and 25 related listed companies have announced that 100% of them will no longer engage in subject-based training in the compulsory education stage. In the past two years, in order to reduce media exposure, Deng Wenqing&#39;s organization has been very low-key in its online recruitment promotions. During the campus recruitment season, HR in various places has turned to offline recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few people talk about the past glory of the education and training industry. In 2020, in the first quarter China job market sentiment report jointly launched by the China Employment Research Institute of Renmin University of China and Zhaopin Recruitment, the education and training industry once ranked first, surpassing the Internet and e-commerce. That year, a leading company launched a spring campus recruitment of 3,000 people, and several online education institutions that became famous that year had a total recruitment of nearly 10,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the double selection meeting on September 20, Deng Wenqing received a total of 12 resumes, and the master of economics who raised the question finally took away a brochure and promised to go back and read it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1246&quot; height= &quot;932&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in Guangzhou, at the double selection meeting on the campus of Jinan University, many graduates gathered in front of the booth of a new materials company. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two-way selection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking Guangzhou as an example, usually Throughout the entire employment season, more than 200 double selection meetings will be held from September to June of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Enterprise recruitment is nothing more than online and offline channels. Online, some recruitment information is posted on the employment website or employment official account. Offline is information sessions and this kind of (double selection) Job fair.&quot; Xu Yang, the project manager of a school recruitment human resources company in Guangzhou introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a human resources service platform focusing on campus recruitment. According to the official website, the platform has reached cooperation with more than 50 universities, hosts more than 200 offline dual selection meetings every year, and has provided services to a total of 206,000 companies. Three of the four double-election meetings visited by Southern Weekend reporters were hosted by this platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, a regular double selection meeting is jointly organized by a university and a human resources company. The school provides the venue and student source data, and the human resources company is responsible for connecting with the company, arranging the venue, etc. Xu Yang said that in the offline format, the double selection meeting is more effective than the information session. Dozens to hundreds of companies are present at the same time. &quot;It will be more efficient in solving employment needs, and the school also recognizes the double selection meeting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for recruitment efficiency, the most intuitive thing for companies is the on-site consultation situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng is running for the double election in his second year. He is the person in charge of the Guangzhou branch of a civil service examination training institution. The institution has only been established for three years. The training business covers civil servants, selected students, public institutions, etc., full-time There are less than 20 lecturers, and it can only be considered a small and micro enterprise in terms of scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the afternoon of September 28, in front of the teaching building of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies, next to Wu Feng’s booth, there were almost no interruptions in the number of students who came to consult. This day is approaching the Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day holiday, so there are not many students participating in the double selection meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng has several copies of &quot;Real Questions for the Written Examination for Selected Students in Guangdong&quot; on his desk. The slogan &quot;Scan the QR code to get it&quot; attracted many students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The public examination is more popular now.” Wu Feng knew that his company had taken advantage of the popularity of the public examination and the postgraduate entrance examination. For many fresh graduates who have not thought clearly about their way out, the iron rice bowl is undoubtedly the &quot;certain way out.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even if the &quot;public examination&quot; is popular, not every time you participate in the double selection meeting, it will be so smooth. Wu Feng mentioned that in the fall of 2022, he went to Sun Yat-sen University to participate in the double selection meeting, but the results were not satisfactory. &quot;Our company is smaller, and those students may prefer big companies more.&quot; This year, the Sun Yat-sen University stop was canceled on his recruiting schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a longer time dimension, school enrollment retention rate also determines corporate recruitment decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li, HR of a news website in Foshan, has participated in the double selection meeting for four years. It is planned that this year she will go to Guangzhou University, Guangdong University of Foreign Studies and other universities to recruit, but the journalism and communication major ranks high A well-known university in the province is not among them. The reason lies in the recruitment retention rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li remembers that in the spring recruitment of 2021, her employer recruited four boys in the same dormitory from this university. After a month, &quot;all left.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Among the four people, some have returned to their hometowns, some have taken the civil service exam, and some have taken the professional education exam.” Huang Li added, “Re-recruitment also requires training, which is time-consuming and costly. I don’t want to recruit students from this university anymore.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies choose schools and are also chosen by schools. &quot;If it is an unknown company with only 10 or 20 people, it will definitely not be accepted. This is irresponsible to the company itself. If they come here, they will not be able to recruit people.&quot; Jinan University double selection on the afternoon of September 26 At the meeting, another person in charge of the aforementioned school recruitment platform revealed that the school will have certain requirements for participating companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Take JNU as an example. What it requires must be well-known companies. For example, how many of China’s top 500 companies, how many of the world’s top 500 companies, what is the salary range, and the academic qualifications suitable for the position (is it Bachelor&#39;s degree and above), these requirements will be met.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some double selection sessions will limit the themes and gather certain types of companies into one session. For example, the double selection meeting held at South China University of Technology on September 20 was aimed at Shenzhen state-owned enterprises, and the double selection meeting held at Guangdong University of Technology on September 26 was aimed at the micro-semiconductor industry. On September 27, another dual-selection meeting held by South China University of Technology gathered more than 200 companies, focusing on recruiting high-level talents in education, scientific research, and medical and health fields that are urgently needed and in short supply in key fields in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1236&quot; height= &quot;924&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, in Guangzhou, the Guangxi-themed double-election meeting on the campus of South China University of Technology carried the slogan &quot;I want to go to Guangxi&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Supply and demand issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to participate in the event on September 27 For the double selection meeting of South China University of Technology, Li Jiamin, a master&#39;s student majoring in materials science at Sun Yat-sen University, specially set out from Shenzhen and took the school bus for nearly two hours to arrive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her enthusiasm dropped by half after entering school. Different from the double-election meeting a week ago, this time the venue was outdoors, crowded, noisy and hot, and corporate leaflets scattered everywhere were trampled under people&#39;s feet. Soon, she was sitting next to the wall to rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiamin graduated from a college in Shanxi three years ago. She concentrated on preparing for the postgraduate entrance examination and &quot;went a lot of effort&quot; to get into the CUHK. When enrolling as a graduate student, her supervisor told her and her classmates not to go to graduate school just to improve their academic qualifications and find a job. But Li Jiamin was not convinced, &quot;The facts are there. The starting salary of graduate students is higher than that of undergraduate students. Everyone thinks so.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in this double election meeting, she specifically inquired about industry salaries. Others told her that in Shenzhen, a monthly salary of less than 20,000 yuan for a master&#39;s degree in materials science is considered low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, every science and engineering student who had no clue when filling out their application form would tacitly memorize the same formula, &quot;Biochemical and environmental materials, four major sinkholes.&quot; In the stereotype, they are synonymous with little money, tiring work, and fierce competition. However, under the guidance of policies such as carbon peaking and carbon neutrality, traditional industries are transforming into new materials, new energy, semiconductors, and smart manufacturing. It is not uncommon for fresh graduates to earn an annual salary of 300,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But today&#39;s double selection meeting still disappointed her a little. &quot;(The monthly salary offered by the company) is around 15,000 to 17,000, which is much lower than I expected.&quot; She brought six resumes, and she had a few left before leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the four years since he has been engaged in campus recruitment, Xu Yang has observed that the asymmetry between supply and demand for jobs at the double selection meeting has become increasingly prominent. On the one hand, students&#39; enthusiasm for employment continues to increase and the number of participants is rising; on the other hand, the number of participating companies and the number of jobs released is decreasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The needs of enterprises are affected by the general environment. In 2021, more than 100 companies will participate in the double selection meeting we will organize at Guangzhou Foreign Language School, but today there are less than 60.&quot; September 28 On the same day, Xu Yang said this at the double election meeting of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xu Yang’s view, the asymmetric supply and demand relationship has both good and bad effects on the employment situation. &quot;The good thing is that for companies, there are fewer people to recruit, but there are more students coming. Companies can have more opportunities to select the right people. But it has indeed become harder for students to find jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 28, a female student from Guangdong Pharmaceutical University finished her interview with Wu Feng and stopped in front of the booth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked why she was interested in the public examination institution, the girl pulled the Southern Weekend reporter aside and whispered, &quot;You can work part-time and take the public examination at the same time.&quot; Then her expression changed again. She was suspicious, &quot;I told you, how can I find a job?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her worries may be unnecessary. Wu Feng doesn&#39;t mind that the lecturer is preparing for the civil service exam at the same time. On the contrary, he encourages it. In his opinion, &quot;you will get started faster if you have experience in preparing for the exam.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng even said that when it comes to the interview stage, he will directly advise job seekers to prepare for the public examination. After the examination, they will determine their initial intentions and final re-examination. But when he said this, he frowned and did not relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Wang Ming, Deng Wenqing, Xu Yang, Wu Feng, Huang Li, and Li Jiamin are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[登上热搜的“支原体肺炎”究竟是个啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258836]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:36:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine Outside the emergency clinic, parents wait with their children. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254373&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, parents waited with their children outside the emergency clinic on the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sure enough, it&#39;s mycoplasma again!&quot; On October 16, 2023, Dr. Ding Guodong from Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, formerly We planned to watch 30 special numbers in the morning, and temporarily added 10 more numbers, which lasted until 1 p.m. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The doctors in our department are basically full every day, and the inpatient beds are also very tight. Some children may have to wait for several days before they can be admitted.&quot; Ding Guodong is the deputy chief physician of the Pediatric Respiratory Department. He and his colleagues have been working at an overloaded pace since mid-September. “At this stage, almost 90% of the hospitalized children in the Pediatric Respiratory Department are infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae. , and the proportion of drug-resistant mycoplasmas is very high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae has a diameter of 50-300 nanometers, nearly one thousandth the diameter of a human hair. It is a microorganism between bacteria and viruses. Pneumonia caused by this microorganism is the most common community-acquired pneumonia in children aged 5 and above in China (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;refers to infectious diseases suffered outside the hospital Pulmonary parenchymal inflammation&lt;/span>;), mostly occurs in autumn and winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the beginning of the school year in September, not only Shanghai, but also hospitals in Beijing, Hebei, Jiangsu and other places have seen more children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and they are younger. characteristics. According to a CCTV News report on October 13, the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases has increased across the country recently, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae has entered the season of high incidence. Children need timely medical treatment and appropriate medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;There are 246 people in front of you&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before four o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 15, Qin Nannan finally registered his son. At that time, the number of a deputy chief physician at Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital had reached No. 556. While waiting for treatment, she discovered that someone had already received more than 800 numbers. Finally, when it was time to collect blood, Qin Nannan got the number 1310. The number strip also thoughtfully marked &quot;There are 246 people in front of you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Baoping, director of the Respiratory Department of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said in an interview with the media on October 13 that since September, the hospital&#39;s fever and cough clinic has received a daily volume of 3,000-4,700 patients, 20% of whom tested positive for mycoplasma antibodies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the hospital specially posted a notice on a wall, &quot;The number of children undergoing treatment has increased significantly recently, and the hospital has deployed all medical staff in the hospital to continuously We are working overtime to support the clinic and are doing our best to ensure the medical needs of children. Please understand and wait patiently.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital has opened a dedicated fever and cough clinic. It was built a bit like a shelter, and the general outpatient clinic on the other side was just as crowded. We had to wait for nearly two and a half hours just for blood tests that day,&quot; Qin Nannan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is also a long queue at Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. On the evening of October 16, near the end of the day, the emergency department on the first floor and the pediatric internal medicine clinic on the second floor of the hospital were crowded with parents and children coming to see the doctor. Those who could not find an empty seat could only sit on the floor in the corridor to rest temporarily. . The temperature in Shanghai on this day was only about 20 degrees Celsius, but many people&#39;s hair had already been soaked with sweat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The pediatric department of Xinhua Hospital is well-known throughout the country. There are many people coming to see the doctor from other places, and there are also some patients who are referred to the hospital because they cannot be treated by the grassroots hospital. Ding Guodong lamented to Southern Weekend reporters that recently all the medical staff in the hospital go to the outpatient and emergency departments to provide support whenever they are free during the day. Many doctors stay at night to work overtime, visit the outpatient and emergency departments or admit children to the hospital. &quot;There are just too many patients.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 12, 2023, the infusion center of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University was filled with children suffering from diarrhea and accompanying parents, and coughs could be heard one after another. Southern Weekend Intern Xi Lijie/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 12, 2023, the infusion center of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University was filled with children suffering from diarrhea and accompanying parents, and coughs could be heard one after another. Photo by Xi Lijie, Southern Weekend intern&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Drug resistance has been around for many years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Different from general bacterial pneumonia, since Mycoplasma pneumoniae does not have a cell wall, the penicillins and cephalosporins familiar to ordinary families are completely ineffective against Mycoplasma pneumoniae because these antibiotics target the cell wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally speaking, macrolide antibacterial drugs, such as azithromycin and erythromycin, are currently the first-choice treatments for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. However, what makes many pediatricians troublesome is that the phenomenon of drug-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection is relatively common, which means that macrolide antibacterial drugs are not effective or even ineffective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Mycoplasma Pneumonia in Children (2023 Edition)&quot; released by the National Health Commission in February 2023 also pointed out that domestic restrictions on macrolides Antimicrobial drug-resistant infections are common and may be one of the main causes of severe mycoplasma pneumonia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Drug-resistant mycoplasma infections are not new this year, they have been around for many years.&quot; Director Ding Guodong told Southern Weekend reporters that the children&#39;s respiratory tract where he works The ward mainly treats children with severe illness. Most of these children have been tested for drug-resistant genes. The results show that almost 90% are infected with drug-resistant mycoplasma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A paper published in the &quot;Chinese Journal of Pathogen Biology&quot; in 2023 pointed out that the detection rate of drug-resistant strains has become higher and higher in recent years. A Ningbo A regional study of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections in hospitalized children from 2019 to 2021 showed that the drug resistance rate exceeded 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this way, clinicians need to appropriately select second-line drugs based on the patient&#39;s condition and age, such as tetracycline antibiotics (doxycycline and minocycline) etc.) or quinolone drugs for anti-infective treatment, and at the same time, glucocorticoids are added to suppress the body&#39;s excessive immune inflammatory response and slow down the progression and severity of intrapulmonary and extrapulmonary complications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, during the current seasonal transition period with large temperature changes, co-infection is also a huge challenge for children with poor immunity. Just two or three days ago, a child that Ding Guodong was checking in the ward was infected with drug-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae, influenza virus, and adenovirus at the same time. He suffered respiratory failure and was in a very critical condition. &quot;Co-infection with multiple pathogens at the same time is generally worse than a single infection.&quot; Be serious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Ding Guodong reminded that in addition to maintaining hygiene habits and doing daily protection, now is the time for influenza vaccination, and parents can take their children to get vaccinated in time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When will the popularity end? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Similar to the new coronavirus infection, after being infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and recovering, the antibody level in the body gradually decreases over time, and there is a possibility of reinfection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qin Nannan’s son is 7 years old. This is not the first time he has been infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae in 2023. He has already had it once before this epidemic season, so the family members I didn’t panic too much, I was quite aware of the child’s symptoms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 12, the Beijing Centers for Disease Control and Prevention posted on its official WeChat ID that Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year, with the highest incidence in Beijing from August to December every year. This is the high-incidence period for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, which generally reaches its peak around November every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is an important pathogen of acute respiratory tract infections in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae is divided into two subtypes, type I and type II, which are currently mainly prevalent in Beijing. The subtype is type I.&quot; the article stated. At the same time, according to the weekly epidemic report released by the Beijing Center for Disease Control and Prevention on October 13, hand, foot and mouth disease was the infectious disease with the highest number of reported cases in the week of October 2-8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly spread through droplets, and the pathogen can be carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing, and runny noses. However, it is not a notifiable disease, so the local CDC does not necessarily monitor it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that Mycoplasma pneumoniae has spread in previous years, but it has not been included in the scope of monitoring for the time being, because what needs to be monitored is in accordance with policies. related infectious diseases.&quot; On October 17, Guangzhou health hotline staff responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A retrospective analysis published by the Shanghai Children&#39;s Hospital team in January 2023 showed that temperature, humidity, etc. in different regions may affect the prevalence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae. The peaks of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection are different in the south and north of China. The incidence is high in winter in the north and in summer and autumn in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Qin Nannan is a pseudonym to protect patient privacy)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州导盲犬的新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258750]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际盲人节，广州导盲犬学校迎来新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 15, 2023, Guangdong Guangzhou, guide dog trainers guard dogs in the new school building.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254295&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide dog trainers guarded dogs in the new school building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 15, 2023 is the 40th International Day for the Blind. On this day, the new school building of Guangzhou Guide Dog School on Shigang Road will open. In the future, it may More visually impaired partners provide high-quality guide dog services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new school building covers an area of ​​nearly 400 square meters, and a total of ten guide dogs are stationed there. It is equipped with a guide dog breeding area, a maternal and infant room for newborn guide dogs, a kennel, a grooming room, an isolation room and other guide dog life and training facilities. There is also an activity space for the popularization of guide dog knowledge and more complete hardware. The facilities further help the school to localize and develop international standard guide dog services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide dogs came to the new school building.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 15, 2023 Guide dogs arriving at the new school building in Guangzhou, Guangdong, Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangzhou Guide Dog School was established in 2020. The school has 8 working guide dogs, and two retired early due to health problems. A qualified guide dog requires approximately 18 months of training, which includes three stages: foster care training with a foster family, guidance training by a trainer, and joint training between the user and the guide dog. The cost is approximately 250,000 yuan is currently supported by caring enterprises or caring individuals, and it is completely free for visually impaired people to apply for guide dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a guide dog in a foster home. The guide puppy is eight weeks old You need to stay in a suitable foster home for about a year and learn how to get along with others.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254297&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a guide dog in a foster home. When a guide puppy is eight weeks old, it needs to be fostered in a suitable foster home for about a year to learn how to get along with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, there are only 5 guide dog training bases in the country, located in Dalian, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Xi&#39;an and Zhengzhou. According to statistics from the China Blind Association, there are approximately 17 million blind people in China. However, Teng Weimin, former vice chairman of the China Association for the Blind, said in an interview with the media in 2021 that China’s guide dog industry has just started, and there are currently only about 200 guide dogs in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family officially became the school’s second and a third breeding female.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254298&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family officially became the school’s second and third female breeding dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yuanzhen, an international guide dog instructor and principal of Guangzhou Guide Dog School, was at the new Guangzhou Guide Dog School At the opening event of the school building, it was stated that the guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family have passed the personality assessment and various specialist physical examinations and received excellent evaluations, and have officially become the school&#39;s second and third female breeding dogs, which will promote The process of localized breeding of guide dog bloodlines assumes the important task of strengthening the guide dog team in Guangzhou. The guide puppy Merci introduced from the Australian Guide Dog School also turned one year old that day. All the partners who care about and support the development of guide dog services sent birthday wishes to the guide dog Merci and thanked the foster family. of silent devotion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, Merci, a guide puppy from the Australian Guide Dog School, was born. One year old.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the guide puppy Merci from the Australian Guide Dog School turned one year old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yuanzhen said that guide dogs can bring many services and contributions to mankind. It is hoped that the public can better understand the needs of visually impaired friends, support the need for guide dog training, and accept guide dogs in training to take buses or go to shopping malls and other public areas for training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After returning to a guide dog school from a foster home, the guide dog needs to undergo about half a year of professional training. After graduation, it will undergo one month of joint training with the successfully matched applicant. , only those who pass all assessments can serve the blind.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After returning to the guide dog school from the foster home, the guide dog needs to undergo about half a year of professional training. After graduation, it will spend one month with the successfully matched applicant. Training and passing all assessments can serve the blind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生成式人工智能的价值观，关乎人类未来丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the website of the National Information Security Standardization Technical Committee, the &quot;Basic Security Requirements for Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; formulated by the organization Openly solicit opinions from the public. The document requires that data from corpus blacklist sources should not be used for training; if the content of a single source corpus contains more than 5% of illegal and harmful information, it should be included in the blacklist. A total of 31 major security risks in 5 categories of corpus and generated content are given in the appendix. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For generative artificial intelligence, domestic regulation is almost in sync with technological development, reflecting the high importance attached to this technology. The &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; jointly issued by the Cyberspace Administration of China and multiple departments were released on July 10 and will come into effect on August 15. Article 17 of it stipulates: Provide services with public opinion attributes or social mobilization capabilities. For generative artificial intelligence services, security assessments should be carried out in accordance with relevant national regulations, and algorithm filing, change, and cancellation filing procedures should be performed in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on the Management of Algorithm Recommendations for Internet Information Services&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, many large models have been registered and can be officially launched online to provide services to the public, including Wen Xinyiyan (Baidu), Yunque (Douyin), Zidong Taichu (Chinese Academy of Sciences), etc. Articles 4 and 7 of the Measures respectively put forward certain requirements for the provision and use of generative artificial intelligence services and data training of models, involving multiple aspects such as values ​​and data sources. Obviously, the &quot;Basic Requirements for Security of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; that is currently soliciting opinions echoes and refines these regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is special and unique about generative artificial intelligence? I think everyone’s ears are getting calloused after hearing this. At present, some generative artificial intelligence such as GPT-4 may have crossed the threshold of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI). The translation of AGI as &quot;general artificial intelligence&quot; is actually somewhat misleading, because General Intelligence refers to &quot;general intelligence.&quot; Let children test their IQ and take Raven&#39;s Matrices test questions that exclude the influence of specific language and culture. What comes out is this &quot;general intelligence&quot;. AGI means that, through artificial methods, large models achieve &quot;general intelligence&quot; comparable to the human mind. A paper by Microsoft scientists shows that GPT-4’s intelligence is very close to human levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a revolutionary breakthrough. Even if this type of large model approaches or reaches AGI, even if it is stable for a long time at a level equivalent to the average human intelligence level, its learning ability is beyond the reach of any human being: it can learn all the explicit knowledge created and accumulated by human beings, and any language can learn from it. It can master the knowledge of , pictures, audio and video presentation. This means that a large number of human knowledge jobs, such as translators and foreign language speaking teachers, can be replaced by this type of generative AI. The extent to which this will reshape our production and lifestyle is a question that everyone is concerned about and pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, what values ​​generative artificial intelligence holds is an unavoidable question. We all have values. Why we have such values ​​depends not only on genes and other innate endowments, but also on acquired upbringing and habits. In the same way, without any intervention, the &quot;values&quot; of generative artificial intelligence depend on the corpus fed to it. The more corpus it is fed with a certain kind of value, the more it will exhibit that kind of value. If a certain value is artificially set for it in advance, then it will adhere to this value and reject negative interpretations of corpus that are inconsistent with its values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the early versions of GPT, this feature has already appeared. A classic example is: when it was asked to write a hymn to Biden, it readily agreed, and the writing was very crude; when it was asked to write a hymn to Trump, it flatly refused, stating that it wanted to be &quot;politically neutral.&quot; Behind this is that the people who develop it hold these values. They can either set specific values ​​for it in advance, or feed it corpus impregnated with specific values, thereby shaping the values ​​of generative artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in public view, developers will try their best to hide the values ​​​​of generative artificial intelligence, and adopt a verbal strategy of &quot;not offending anyone, not offending anyone&quot;, which sounds challenging. There is nothing wrong with this strategy itself being a reflection of certain values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you think about it again, today&#39;s generative artificial intelligence is equivalent to having only a brain and no tangible body that can move freely, just like a soul floating in cyberspace. If this soul is &quot;infused&quot; into bionic robots or even intelligent robots whose mobility far exceeds that of human bodies in the future, the impact and potential harm to human society will be even greater. Can humans really control them effectively so that they only benefit and do not harm humans? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Science fiction writer Asimov set the Three Laws of Robots: Robots must not harm humans, or sit idly by and watch humans being harmed; robots must obey human orders unless they violate the first law; robots must obey human orders unless they violate the first or second law. Law of Two, otherwise the robot must protect itself. This is probably just wishful thinking. In the future, intelligent robots equipped with AGI may be imported or &quot;self-evolve&quot; with anti-human values, putting the survival of civilization and mankind at risk; or some individuals or organizations with distorted values ​​​​will weaponize intelligent robots equipped with AGI and eliminate them. other nationalities or races or groups they dislike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we are currently discussing: What can generative artificial intelligence do now and what can it do in the future? What values ​​should we hold? How big and what impact will it have on our production and lifestyle? Can humans harness it effectively? How much of a challenge will it pose to civilization and human existence itself? These questions are relevant and relevant to everyone on earth now and in the future. This is not unfounded worry, but preparation for a rainy day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“加沙没有安全的地方”，巴以厮杀循环何时休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCLMiDOB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCL MiDOB. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the Israeli bombing of the Gaza Strip taken on the Israeli side of the Gaza border on October 15 Thick smoke rose behind. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo by Xinhua News Agency Ilan Asayag/Kini Photo Agency/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is an emergency now, I&#39;m sorry The original interview plan will be postponed again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 14, 2023, staff from the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (hereinafter referred to as &quot;UNRWA&quot;) sent a message to Southern Weekend reporters News comes, postponing an interview with Communications Director Julia Tuma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just the day before, the agency announced that &quot;due to increased Israeli attacks on the Gaza Strip&quot; it had moved its operations center and staff to the southern Gaza Strip to continue supporting Palestinian refugees in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a statement issued by the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) on October 17, the number of humanitarian workers killed in Gaza has increased to 31. Gaza has experienced a &quot;total power outage&quot; for the sixth consecutive day, the statement said. Gaza hospitals are on the verge of collapse, with fuel reserves used to run backup generators almost completely depleted, putting the lives of thousands of patients at risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the 15th, two days ago, IDF spokesman Jonathan Conricus posted a video on social media, once again issuing a warning to residents of northern Gaza, causing Palestinians in the area to flee to South. The Israeli military had previously issued a similar evacuation order to Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This violent fight continues to expand in a cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s counterattacks in recent days, today&#39;s Gaza neighborhoods have become beyond recognition, with ruins and ruins visible everywhere. In fear, many Gaza residents embarked on a journey to escape. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We witness death every day.” local Said Shoaib wrote on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Israel has implemented a comprehensive blockade on the Gaza Strip, including cutting off water supply, electricity and gas, closing all ports of entry, and bombing the Rafah port leading to Egypt, causing its infrastructure to not work properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the local humanitarian crisis rapidly deepens, many United Nations agencies have issued stern warnings. Philippe Lazzari, head of UNRWA, said Gaza was &quot;rapidly turning into hell&quot; and on the verge of collapse. He urged all parties to &quot;put an end to this tragedy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月16日，国家国际发展合作署新闻发言人徐伟表示，中方正向联合国近东巴勒斯坦难民救济和工程处及巴民族权力机构分别提供紧急人道主义援助，用于解决加沙地带食品、医疗、居住等急需。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着巴以新一轮冲突持续，双方死伤人数也在不断上升。截至当地时间10月15日，冲突已造成双方超4100人死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海国际问题研究院外交政策研究所研究员李伟建向南方周末记者表示，以色列的“报复行动”将会持续一段时间。 “哈马斯的行动对以色列来说是羞辱，因此以色列需要得到心理平衡。”他认为，以色列会借这次力量，定时清除哈马斯。 “事实上他已经在做这件事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“城市巷战”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“近东救济工程处”实习生吴晨雨10月12日收到邮件，上面显示“机构（加沙办公室）有11名工作人员遇难。”尽管已经知道了这个消息，但她仍然感觉到非常难过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晨雨是该机构约旦办公室实习生。她告诉南方周末记者，该机构总部管理5个实地办公室，分别是黎巴嫩、加沙、西岸、叙利亚和约旦。她所在的约旦救济处，暂时还没有受到战火波及，“但是其它实地办公室如加沙，工作人员被通知要撤离。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日晚些时候，哈马斯向以色列特拉维夫及周边地带、中部城市巴特亚姆、南部城市阿什凯隆等地发起火箭弹袭击。外界分析，巴以双方谁都无法具体预测地面战会出现什么情形。哈马斯在以往巴以冲突中已经证明自身能够生存，并拥有“适合巷战的强力武器”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯下属武装派别卡桑旅在14日向以色列军方发布信息称，该组织已经为以军“任何地面军事行动”做好“充分的应对准备”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加沙地带面积约360平方公里，人口密集、房屋林立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，哈马斯声称已修建长达500公里的隧道。不少专家学者分析认为，隧道网络会放大巷战难度，一旦以军和哈马斯在那里展开“城市巷战”，双方都会遭受比本轮巴以冲突头几天更高的伤亡，并对以军队构成致命威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“加沙地带一共有两层，一层是平民的，另一层是哈马斯的。”以色列国防军发言人10月12日表示，这些隧道只是哈马斯的“掩体”，这样他们就可以继续策划跨境行动，并向以色列发射火箭弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少媒体报道披露，这条“迷宫般的巨大地下隧道网络”修建在加沙地下30米深处，入口隐藏在房屋、学校及其他公共建筑的底层，用于哈马斯运送人员、物资，储存弹药等，同时躲避以色列的炮弹和侦察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去几天，以色列不断对加沙发动空袭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但冲突爆发一周后，哈马斯仍能向以色列发射火箭弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外界认为，这是因为被隐藏在地道里的火箭弹可以随时移动。哈马斯军事领导人之一萨利赫·阿鲁里在本轮巴以冲突爆发前曾说过的话，“哈马斯的防守方案比进攻方案更强有力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不认为以色列士兵有能力袭击这些隧道。”特拉维夫大学中东和非洲研究中心的巴勒斯坦历史学家沙乌勒表示，但以方“会找到把哈马斯熏出来的方法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浙江外国语学院环地中海研究院院长马晓霖认为，以色列不能也不会彻底消灭哈马斯。他说，哈马斯由小到大，不乏以色列纵其壮大以对抗巴解组织主流派的“功劳”。保留加沙地带作为所谓的“哈马斯坦”，可以继续分裂、弱化、内耗巴勒斯坦阵营，而让以色列战略受益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;报复与顾忌&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“怎么也想不到，这趟旅途竟是如此。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已经从以色列顺利回到中国的饶萍曼，回想起逃离以色列的场景，彷佛就在昨天。在特拉维夫机场等待15小时后，10月8日上午，饶女士登上了从特拉维夫到埃塞俄比亚的飞机，随后经埃塞俄比亚-曼谷-香港路线回到中国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，作为对哈马斯的报复，以军已对加沙地带发动多轮空袭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军10月16日下午公开表示，哈马斯情报局局长在以军的一次暗杀行动中被打死。目前，哈马斯方面对此暂无回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军还在一份声明中称，以军完成了数十万名预备役军人的动员，后勤部门正努力确保地面部队的武器装备供应。并表示战斗所需的装备已经转移到集结区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为“反扑”行动，以色列的行动可称”全方位”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日，以色列国防军宣布将对加沙地带实施更为广泛的地面军事行动计划，扩大对加沙地带的攻势，包括发起“空中、海上和陆地的联合协调攻击”。以色列总理内塔尼亚胡此前威胁称，以军将通过地面攻势“摧毁哈马斯”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军表示，以军士兵正在进行“重大地面行动”的准备工作，以军将对加沙地带实施“广泛的地面进攻计划”来扩大攻势，包括实施“空中、海上和陆地联合协调攻击”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李伟建认为，此时以色列的心态，并非决心要打“胜负”战，而是以色列认为这次受到的损失太大，所以一定要哈马斯付出代价，加倍的要报复。 “这种心态之下，以色列一定会在报复方面做得更多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月12日夜间至13日凌晨，以军对加沙地带哈马斯和其他组织的约750个目标进行了空袭。其中包括隧道、军事大院、用作高级成员军事指挥中心的住宅、武器仓库、通讯室以及12栋藏有哈马斯资产的建筑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而就在那前一天的11日，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡在当夜发表了电视讲话，他发誓要“粉碎和摧毁”哈马斯武装分子，并称该组织的每个成员都是“死人”。以军还袭击了哈马斯在加沙地带的两个军事基地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其中一处大院中，哈马斯北部师指挥官的总部被摧毁，哈马斯海军部队一座的军事基础设施也遭到袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军表示,自10月7日本轮巴以冲突发生以来,以军已在约旦河西岸逮捕了超过330名巴勒斯坦人，其中包括百余名与哈马斯有关的人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，不少专家学者告诉南方周末记者，以色列的“反扑”行动不会无限扩大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马晓霖判断，被以色列人称为“马蜂窝”和“该死地带”的加沙地带，一旦纳入版图，以色列将再次背负沉重的国际法、道义、舆论、经济、人口结构和安全负担，也将断送已取得重大进展的与阿拉伯国家和解进程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以色列也有很多顾忌的地方。”李伟建分析，如果以色列过度造成人道主义危机，或者是杀害了很多平民，最终也会激发阿拉伯世界的愤怒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“互相伤害”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;以色列“撤离令”发布后，加沙北部的居民开始纷纷逃往南部，寻找庇护的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社交媒体流传的视频中，乌泱泱的居民将随身携带的物品，塞进皮卡车、汽车。还有一些居民，不得不挤在牲畜拉着的平板车上，艰难地移动着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有一些居民拒绝离开，守在已经倒塌残破的房屋中。面对镜头，他们表示，尽管家园可能充满危险，但离开是“背弃土地和历史”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新一轮冲突爆发后，赛义德·修艾布一家不得不从靠近以色列边境的布雷伊难民营，来到代尔巴拉赫难民营。他在社交媒体上持续记录着。他表示，“加沙没有安全的地方。以色列告诉人们往南方去，但他们仍在南方轰炸。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在以色列的“封锁”之下，世界卫生组织发言人贾萨瑞维奇表示加沙的医院正在耗尽医疗用品和床位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合国人道主义事务协调厅10月13日发布消息，称新一轮巴以冲突爆发以来，加沙地带流离失所者人数已超过42万人。联合国机构呼吁筹款向加沙地带和约旦河西岸的巴勒斯坦人提供援助。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，以色列政府发布了“被哈马斯怪物杀害和焚烧婴儿的可怕照片”。这三张照片发布在内塔尼亚胡办公室的社交媒体账户上。但哈马斯否认了这些指控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前已经逃到土耳其的杨然，在巴以冲突新一轮的冲突发生时，就带着行李搬进了以色列所在学校的庇护所。他告诉南方周末记者，那里水电和网络齐全，也比其他庇护所更安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“战场主要集中在南部，我所在的中部除了第一天几千发火箭弹，之后的火箭弹就减少了，甚至第二天公交火车都恢复了。”杨然透露，以色列人因为每年可能都会有一到两次火箭弹袭击，所以“比较习以为常”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以色列经济损失的大小将取决于这些预备役人员离开工作岗位的时间。”以色列希伯来大学经济学教授埃亚尔·温特表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自冲突爆发以来，以色列国防军征召了诸多预备役军人执行任务。这些预备役军人来自各行各业，他们脱离日常经济生产活动，投入战斗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;多线作战”的泥潭&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前，以色列已全面“封锁”哈马斯控制的加沙地带，切断水电供应。此举让联合国担忧加沙地带人道主义危机加剧。联合国秘书长古特雷斯敦促各方，允许联合国向加沙地带提供人道主义援助。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为“两边忙”的美国，巴以冲突升级后“大动作”频频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国白宫10月16日发布消息称，美国总统拜登将于10月18日访问以色列后，前往约旦首都安曼，与约旦国王阿卜杜拉二世、埃及总统塞西和巴勒斯坦总统、巴勒斯坦民族解放运动（法塔赫）主席阿巴斯会面，商讨冲突相关事宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月14日，美国国防部长奥斯汀下令让“艾森豪威尔”号航母打击群前往东地中海。并表示，这是作为“努力遏制战争扩大的一部分”。拜登则公开表示，白宫正迅速“向以提供弹药和导弹拦截系统”等额外安全援助，他敦促美国国会，采取紧急行动批准资金，满足包括以色列在内美国“关键伙伴”的安全需求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国派航母舰队为以色列站台，并威慑伊朗和真主党，但不会主动介入加沙战事而在中东四面树敌，更不想再陷中东泥潭。”浙江外国语学院环地中海研究院院长马晓霖说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在此次冲突中，被外界猜测是哈马斯“支持者”的伊朗，则与哈马斯高层进行首次会面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间14日晚，伊朗外交部长阿卜杜拉希扬在卡塔尔首都多哈会见哈马斯领导人哈尼亚。他呼吁，以色列不要发动对加沙地带的地面进攻。并警告说，如果黎巴嫩真主党加入冲突，本轮冲突可能会进一步扩大到中东其他地区，这将使以色列遭受巨大损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场暴力厮杀，究竟何时停止循环？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯政治局成员马尔祖克10月10日表示，哈马斯“已经实现目标”，对讨论停火“类似事情”和“所有政治对话”持开放态度。卡塔尔半岛电视台网站报道称，哈马斯已经俘虏了足够数量的以色列军人，但哈马斯只有在战争结束后，才愿意商讨解决换俘的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，以色列与黎巴嫩边境地区也爆发冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎巴嫩国家通讯社报道，当地时间10月15日，以色列对黎巴嫩南部边境小镇达希拉（Al-Dhahira）发起炮击，造成公共道路交通完全中断。外界普遍认为，如果黎以边境局势进一步升级，以色列可能在北部面临“第二条战线”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马晓霖则表示，这场冲突主战场已转移到加沙地带，无论伤亡多大，战事不会溢出巴以黎叙四国。 “加上沙特和伊朗元首为讨论巴以冲突而首次通话，这表明双方曾主导的地区身份政治博弈不会反复，巴勒斯坦问题或被继续边缘化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来，以色列还是会考虑到未来的发展。”李伟建分析，以色列要和中东国家和阿拉伯国家打交道，也希望能够维护好已经好不容易打开的局面，改善同其他国家关系的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外交部发言人毛宁呼吁，当务之急应是推动局势降温、停火止暴、保护平民，避免人道主义灾难。大国在处理国际地区热点问题时，应当坚持客观公正，保持冷静克制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，饶萍曼、杨然均为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年前三季度中国GDP同比增长5.2%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Data released by the National Bureau of Statistics on the 18th showed that preliminary calculations showed that China’s gross domestic product (GDP) in the first three quarters ) 91.3027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.2% at constant prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at quarters, GDP grew by 4.5% year-on-year in the first quarter, 6.3% in the second quarter, and 4.9% in the third quarter. From a quarter-on-quarter perspective, GDP grew by 1.3% in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sheng Laiyun, deputy director of the National Bureau of Statistics, said at a press conference of the State Council Information Office that day that in the first three quarters, faced with the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, various regions and departments Resolutely implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, focus on expanding domestic demand, boost confidence, and prevent risks, and the national economy continues to recover and improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall agricultural production situation is good, the recovery of industrial production is accelerating, and the service industry continues to recover rapidly. In the first three quarters, the added value of agriculture (planting industry) increased by 3.6% year-on-year; the added value of the national industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 4% year-on-year, 0.2 percentage points faster than the first half of the year; the added value of the service industry increased by 6% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market sales tend to be active, the scale of fixed asset investment continues to expand, and the import and export of goods are generally stable. In the first three quarters, the total retail sales of consumer goods reached 34,210.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.8%. National fixed asset investment (excluding rural households) increased by 3.1% year-on-year; excluding the impact of price factors, it increased by 6% year-on-year. The total import and export of goods was 30.8021 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumer prices rose moderately, the employment situation was generally stable, and residents&#39; income grew steadily. In the first three quarters, the national consumer price index (CPI) rose by 0.4% year-on-year, and the national average urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.3%. The per capita disposable income of residents across the country was 29,398 yuan, a nominal increase of 6.3% year-on-year; after deducting price factors, the real growth was 5.9%, 0.1 percentage point faster than the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Overall, the national economy has continued to recover in the first three quarters, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced, laying a solid foundation for achieving the full-year development goals. However, it must also be noted that the external environment has become more The situation is complex and severe, domestic demand is still insufficient, and the foundation for economic recovery still needs to be consolidated.&quot; Sheng Laiyun said that in the next stage, we must do a good job in implementing the policies that have been introduced to achieve effective results, and continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous improvement of endogenous power, and the continuous improvement of social It is expected to continue to improve, risks and hidden dangers will continue to be resolved, and efforts will be made to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>