<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《鲁颂》，一位国君的换脸术：把老谋深算打扮成雄才大略]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261428]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Book of Songs is divided into three parts: Fengya Song, and the Song is divided into Zhou Song, Lu Song and Shang Song. This is Common sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An interesting thing is that &quot;Song of Lu&quot; does not praise the great Duke of Zhou, the first king of Lu. The object of its praise is a figure who is already unfamiliar to most people today, Duke Xi of Lu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Duke Xi of Lu is indeed worthy of careful observation: in a situation where big powers are competing for hegemony, how should a king of a medium-sized country preserve or even develop his country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gong Xi of Lu was the son of Duke Zhuang of Lu. He reigned for 33 years, which was considered a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Duke Xi of Lu came to the throne, the State of Lu experienced serious turmoil. At that time, the king of Qi was Duke Huan of Qi, the leader of the Five Hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period. Duke Huan of Qi helped the state of Lu quell the civil strife. Duke Xi of Lu also followed Duke Huan of Qi, and the politics of Lu State returned to the track of smooth operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of Duke Huan of Qi, there was no overlord in the Central Plains, and the power of Chu State continued to expand northward. The Chu State was a barbarian that was looked down upon by all the Central Plains countries. The Lu State was a state of etiquette and the representative of the Central Plains countries. It should be expected that the Chu State should look down on the Chu State. However, Lu Xigong showed a very open mind and hooked up with the Chu State without any psychological barriers. He wanted to use the power of Chu State to deal with Qi State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, the second of the Five Hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period, Duke Wen of Jin, appeared. The Jin State in Shanxi began to actively intervene in the affairs east of the Taihang Mountains. The two great kingdoms of Jin and Chu were competing for hegemony. It was unpredictable who would win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State of Wei was relatively close to the State of Jin. At that time, the State of Wei had also surrendered to the State of Chu, so Duke Wen of Jin took action against the State of Wei. The situation is obvious. After taking care of the Wei State, they are likely to come to take care of the Lu State. What&#39;s more, Duke Xi of Lu also sent a nobleman to help the Wei State defend the city. This means that the Lu State has put itself on the opposite side of the Jin State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gong Lu Xi came to show off again and killed the nobleman who was sent to Weiguo. He said to Jin: This man secretly led troops to help Chu, so I killed him. It shows that Lu State has no hostility to Jin State. He also sent people to say to the Chu State: This man did not fight well and did not help the Chu State in the war, so I have him executed. In this way, Duke Xi of Lu withdraws in time, and no one is offended by me. You two great countries should fight quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Battle of Chengpu, Jin defeated the Chu army. Duke Xi of Lu also knew who he should side with and quickly hugged Jin&#39;s thigh. The State of Jin felt that he was so active and set an example for other countries, so it also gave Lu Xigong generous rewards: the country that originally stood in the wrong team would be punished and had to cede part of its land. The Jin State could not take all of this land for itself, so some of it was given to the Lu State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Duke Xi of Lu was a monarch who had no great talent or strategy, but had keen vision, soft body, scheming or, to put it worse, cunning, and was very good at profiting from the cracks in the power struggle. This is the impression provided to us by &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interesting thing is that the image of Lu Xigong in &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; and the image of Lu Xigong in &quot;The Book of Songs·Song of Lu&quot; do not look like the same person at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only four poems in &quot;Song of Lu&quot;, but two of them, &quot;Panshui&quot; and &quot;Zhen Gong&quot;, are very long, especially &quot;Zhen Gong&quot;, with a total of nine chapters and 120 lines. The longest chapter in the entire Book of Songs. Both poems talk about one thing, which is the victory of Lu over &quot;Huaiyi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The name Huaiyi literally means the people living outside the Chinese civilization circle in the Huaihe River Basin. During the Spring and Autumn Period, Huaiyi was not a very powerful force, but it should not be underestimated. It was enough to pose a considerable threat to the small countries in the Central Plains. If Duke Huan of Qi wants to be the overlord, he has the obligation to maintain the security of small countries, so he has organized international coalition forces many times to attack Huaiyi. The State of Lu was a country with medium strength, and Duke Xi of Lu followed Duke Huan of Qi closely, so of course the State of Lu was involved in all the actions of the State of Qi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the record of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;, and what do we see from &quot;Song of Lu&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, &quot;Song of Lu&quot; is a supplement to &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. We know that the State of Lu benefited greatly from these actions. He obtained a lot of land, and Lu took advantage of it. He followed Qi, but Qi drove away Huaiyi in the northeast of Mount Tai. Qi could not occupy the area, but the territory of Lu and Huaiyi The land we live in is originally connected together, so you can take it for yourself without any hesitation. The State of Lu also obtained a lot of treasures. It is said that &quot;the Yuan Dynasty turtle and elephant tusks bribed the Southern Jin Dynasty&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, &quot;Song of Lu&quot; is also a distortion of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. Because there is no trace of Duke Huan of Qi in &quot;Song of Lu&quot;. All these victories were achieved under the wise leadership of Duke Xi of Lu. &quot;Panshui&quot; praises Duke Xi of Lu, and contributes an idiom that is very commonly used in later generations, &quot;Yun Wen Yun Wu&quot;, he is really capable of both literature and martial arts. &quot;Zhen Gong&quot; is even more remarkable. It uses extremely flamboyant words to describe how Duke Xi of Lu was so talented and brilliant in martial arts that he conquered all the barbarians in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, &quot;Lu Bang is the constant protector of the East.&quot; Who can maintain the stability of the Eastern world? This is our country of Lu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;Rong and Di are cheats, and Jingshu is punishment, so I dare not accept it.&quot; To put it simply, all the thorns in the world were beaten by our Duke Xi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, &quot;No one can fail to obey, it is the credit of Marquis Lu&quot;. The reconstruction of the order of the world depends on us Marquis Lu; The country can only say &quot;promise&quot; respectfully. You are so right. It is really like the red sun rising in the east, and the state of Lu feels like Duke Xi of Lu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the Duke of Lu Xi in &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;, this Duke of Lu is completely different. Here, today we can easily see that &quot;Song of Lu&quot; was a propaganda text at that time, and it was full of water, but the people of Lu at that time believed that it was really a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, as mentioned before, Duke Xi of Lu was by no means a mediocre king, but his forte was not brilliance and strategy but scheming. However, the image of talent and strategy has a Charisma type. The charisma of a charismatic personality is the ideal persona for a monarch, while the image of being cunning and calculating is more suitable for staff rather than a monarch. Therefore, &quot;Song of Lu&quot; never mentions his real strengths and only talks about the abilities he does not have. In human history, it is very common to use false advantages to cover up one&#39;s real advantages to confuse others, and to use small stains to attract attention and make people ignore big stains. These situations are very common and deserve special attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医院儿科人满为患背后：儿科医生为何长期缺乏？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261471]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 23:00:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, there has been an outbreak of respiratory infections in children, and the Xiaoye Clinic of the Department of Internal Medicine of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital was crowded. At 1 o&#39;clock in the morning on November 25, the electronic horizontal screen call number of Xiaoye Clinic of Internal Medicine has reached 1200, and this is the third batch of 1200 numbers that day. In other words, the clinic received more than 3,000 child patients that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone said on Weibo that his nephew was infected with influenza A and had a high fever. At 5 o&#39;clock in the morning, his parents drove to Beijing Maternal and Child Health Hospital, but the registration queue was over 400. He really didn&#39;t dare to wait, so he went A fully self-funded children&#39;s hospital also had a two-hour wait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pediatric hospitals are full due to seasonal reasons, but a more long-term factor is the lack of pediatricians. According to data from the National Health Commission, there are 228 children&#39;s hospitals in China, with 2.22 beds per 1,000 children, and the number of pediatric practitioners in medical institutions is 230,000, which has doubled from 2012. Based on this data, it can be calculated that the number of pediatric practicing (assistant) physicians per 1,000 children is 0.92. Although there is a big improvement, there is still a certain gap between the number of pediatric practicing (assistant) physicians per 1,000 children in developed countries such as the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insufficient training of pediatricians is one of the reasons for this situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, in order to broaden the professional scope, the Ministry of Education adjusted the &quot;Catalogue of Undergraduate Majors in General Colleges and Universities&quot;. The major of pediatrics was no longer set up separately, but was merged and adjusted into the major of clinical medicine. Since then, major universities no longer offer undergraduate majors in pediatrics, and only some universities recruit and train pediatric talents in the name of clinical medicine (pediatrics). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the problem of lack of doctors in pediatrics became increasingly prominent, 18 years later, in 2016, the then National Health and Family Planning Commission and the Ministry of Education jointly announced that they would support eight universities including China Medical University and Chongqing Medical University in organizing pediatric education programs. Undergraduate major in science. According to the plan of the Ministry of Education at that time, it is necessary to train about 5,000 general medical talents at the grassroots level each year to engage in the diagnosis and treatment of common diseases such as pediatrics, and strive to have at least one university in each province (autonomous region, municipality) by 2020 to organize undergraduate courses in pediatrics. Professional Education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Medical science lasts five years. According to the annual enrollment plans of the first eight universities that have resumed recruiting undergraduate majors in pediatrics, in 2021, the number of graduates in the undergraduate major in pediatrics will be about 1,000. It is also unlikely that the number of graduates in 2021 and 2022 will increase significantly. Therefore, there is still a process of accumulation in terms of the number of targeted pediatric talents. Moreover, being a doctor requires the accumulation of experience. It may take ten or even twenty years for this group of medical graduates to truly become experienced pediatricians who can act independently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, if the series of problems faced by pediatrics in reality are not improved, these undergraduate pediatric students will also choose to change majors when taking the postgraduate entrance examination. In fact, in order to change the shortage of pediatric doctors, the National Health Commission has even resorted to giving extra points in the medical qualification examination to alleviate the pediatric manpower shortage. But even such a policy cannot attract talents into pediatrics. There are approximately 800,000 medical graduates in China every year, of whom 22,000 will become doctors, but only more than 300 will eventually choose to go to pediatrics. According to the &quot;White Paper on the Current Situation of Pediatric Resources in China&quot;, the number of pediatricians lost in my country is 14,310, accounting for 10.7% of the total number of pediatricians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, targeted training of talents cannot quench the thirst for nearness. The fundamental reason is that pediatrics has the characteristics of high occupational risks, low remuneration (compared to doctors in some other professional fields), many conflicts between doctors and patients, long working hours, and heavy workloads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children are prone to crying when they feel uncomfortable; they are also prone to crying when they are afraid of pain or pain during treatment. When a child is sick, it is very easy for adults to lose control of their emotions. When encountering brutal parents, they will often make noises and even beat up doctors and nurses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chain of internal discrimination among doctors, many doctors from other specialties look down on pediatricians and call them &quot;pediatricians.&quot; In fact, pediatrics is even more complex than adults. Unlike adults, children are less cooperative and resistant to doctors. In addition, children have limited expression skills and will make more mistakes in consultation, which will increase the risk of misdiagnosis by doctors. In order to avoid misdiagnosis, doctors will prescribe more tests, which in turn will lead to misunderstandings and complaints from parents. Therefore, pediatrics has many doctor-patient disputes and high risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shortage of pediatricians has resulted in long waiting times for pediatricians and high pressure on doctors. During the peak season of respiratory diseases in winter, a pediatrician may even see more than 100 children a day. Some hospitals that offer pediatrics temporarily limit the number of patients and close clinics in order to reduce the burden on doctors. Due to staff shortages, many hospitals do not open pediatric emergency rooms at night, on holidays and weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s just busy and hard work. As long as the salary can keep up, there will be people doing it. However, the salary of Chinese pediatricians is not high compared to other popular departments. Compared with some departments&#39; &quot;large prescriptions and large examinations&quot;, pediatric auxiliary examinations are less, and medication must be used more cautiously. The benefits are naturally less, and the exhausting work cannot keep up with those departments with high treatment fees. Some people said that in the hospital where they work, there are only three doctors in the pediatric department working in shifts, 300 times a day. They go at 7 am and come back at 7 or 8 pm. Although many people will say that doctors are benevolent, doctors are also ordinary people who also have worries about life, income, and money. Naturally, income is a consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a consensus within the medical community: &quot;Golden ophthalmology, silver surgery, crying for father and mother in pediatrics, never go to the emergency department.&quot; There are some differences in different versions. For example, one version has the &quot;Golden Oncology Department&quot;, but the only constant is that you cannot go to pediatrics or emergency department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market means and economic means are the immediate solutions to this problem. In view of the high pressure and heavy workload of pediatrics, the price of pediatric services should be adjusted in a market-oriented manner, and adaptive reforms should be carried out in the hospital&#39;s salary system. Establish a salary distribution incentive mechanism based on work intensity and outpatient needs to better reflect market demand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 40 years of market-oriented reform, society has recognized that more work brings more rewards. There will not be too much pressure on relevant government departments to adjust the prices of pediatric medical services and the salary standards of pediatricians. Of course, no matter what, there will always be voices of doubt and criticism, but in order to attract and retain outstanding pediatric talents, ensure the sustainable development of the pediatric industry, and ensure the healthy growth of children, the right things should be done, even if there is a certain amount of pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国空间站全身照首次发布]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261489]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/28/14e6c006572aa1a234aa0ca2a754352b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;309&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/28/14e6c006572aa1a234aa0ca2a754352b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259886&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shenzhou 16 crew held a high-definition camera before returning to the ground and took a panoramic photo of the space station assembly taken by flying around the spacecraft. It was released for the first time at a meeting between the manned space project delegation organized by the Hong Kong SAR government and the media. This is the first time that my country has acquired a full-view image of the space station assembly in orbit with the Earth as the background, and it is also the first set of full-configuration working photos of the Chinese space station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dce95985ddc945836bb0791b28b5d54a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;777&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dce95985ddc945836bb0791b28b5d54a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259883&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shenzhou 16 astronauts take panoramic images of the space station assembly&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/4943574ee444ab717dd2a5d1f3d46662.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;777&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/4943574ee444ab717dd2a5d1f3d46662.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Shenzhou 16 astronauts took panoramic images of the space station assembly&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/28/b4e6663a4206f905c7d96b24e85fde62.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;777&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/b4e6663a4206f905c7d96b24e85fde62.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259885&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shenzhou 16 astronauts took panoramic images of the space station assembly&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[当以开放心态正确引导爱玩游戏的孩子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261469]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When it comes to electronic games, many parents and teachers must be furious. Playing electronic games for their children is like attracting a scourge. . In order to prevent children from playing games, they resorted to all possible means in a battle of wits and courage. Some parents sent their children to a certain school and used electric shock therapy, causing many injuries and disabilities. In this context, I think it is very necessary to clarify the nature of video games and rectify the name for children who love games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is the nature of animals and humans to love games. Scholar Schiller said that people are real people only in a state of play. In the game state, people are fully relaxed and free. In the game, you will invest your creativity and thoughts infinitely, bursting out with endless vitality. In order to play games, many children have used their great creativity to learn English and strategies on their own. Games are not only a form of entertainment, but also a platform to express personality and showcase talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is undeniable that games have many beneficial functions. The famous futurist Jane McGonigal believes that games have four major characteristics: goals, rules, feedback systems and self-involvement, which can greatly enhance players&#39; happiness. Of course, games can also cultivate children&#39;s teamwork spirit, enhance children&#39;s awareness of rules, and improve children&#39;s concentration and innovation abilities. Therefore, we should see that games, while entertaining, can also provide a positive impact on children&#39;s all-round development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to tell you a fact: the AI ​​technology revolution that started to explode last year completely originated from games. The ChatGPT team, which is now leading the global AI revolution, also said in the interview that their development ideas come from games. More than ten years ago, I myself was an addicted gamer. Fighting monsters and leveling up is a very boring, hard and tiring job. Many of us looked at online guides and made a small program to automatically defeat monsters. From now on, in the game, when you hang up and sleep, you will automatically defeat monsters and level up. This can also be said to be a simplified version of AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s more interesting is that according to Zhihu netizens: for at least 20 years after the birth of 3D graphics cards, 99% of graphics cards were dedicated to games, and 1% were used for movies and graphics. Gamers around the world have created a graphics card market worth hundreds of billions of dollars, and the stock of hundreds of millions of graphics cards has supported technological progress over the past few decades. Scientific computing such as AI is just a free ride after the game industry matures. It can be said that the outbreak of AI is just a by-product of the game industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This wave of AI technology revolution has had a profound impact on mankind. The prosperity of the game industry promoted the development of graphics cards and other technologies, providing the foundation for subsequent scientific computing and AI technologies. Although the development of AI originated from games, its applications have involved many fields such as medical care, education, and transportation, and have produced profound changes in human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the immersive experience and interactive mechanisms brought by video games are also changing fields such as education and medical care. More and more educators are trying to use video games to increase students&#39; participation and motivation. In terms of medical rehabilitation, virtual simulation systems based on video games also show great application prospects. It can be said that electronic games are not only changing the way of entertainment, but will also profoundly affect all aspects of human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we cannot simply regard games as a negative form of entertainment, nor can we generally oppose children&#39;s participation in games. On the contrary, we should fully realize the positive aspects of games and guide children to develop various abilities in games. In this information age, games are not only a form of entertainment, but also a way of learning and innovation. Through games, children can learn important abilities such as teamwork, problem solving, and creative thinking, laying a solid foundation for future development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The younger generation has grown up in a video game environment. This new form of entertainment and competition is no different from traditional sports. To be fair, many traditional sports are not inferior to e-sports in terms of cultivating endurance, collaboration, and adaptability. We cannot simply characterize new things as &quot;curses&quot;, but should understand and accept video game culture with an open and inclusive mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we cannot ignore the problems existing in games, such as addiction and over-consumption. How to guide and play the positive role of games is a topic worthy of further study. Parents and teachers need to guide their children to participate in games while also focusing on cultivating their good gaming habits and self-control abilities. Moderate gaming is good for children&#39;s physical and mental health, but overindulgence may have a negative impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, video games are not a curse, but a rich and colorful form of cultural expression and entertainment. We should look at games with an open mind. Through correct guidance, children who love games can not only find fun in games, but also cultivate various beneficial abilities and lay a solid foundation for future development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a college teacher in Zhejiang Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江一煤矿发生事故，造成11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261491]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 19:33:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 14:40 on November 28, an accident occurred in Shuangyang Coal Mine affiliated to Shuangyashan Mining Company. Preliminary judgment Caused by impact of ground pressure. As of 18:20, 11 people were killed in the accident. Cause of the accident is under further investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[画家罗一平：“边界对中国画的发展约束特别大”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261456]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wenzhou Feng Gong Temple is a Qing Dynasty building facing south and north. Modern architecture, located in the ancient village of Huangpu, Guangzhou. Visitors walking through the granite strips will enter the landscape space under the hard top of the mountain and the low straight ridge. An artist is painting on a long table, and on the wall is a large completed landscape. This is 68-year-old Luo Yiping, who has used this ancient ancestral hall as a studio for ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1b19dc0539.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;336&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1b19dc0539.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Luo Yiping&#39;s work &quot;Region·Non-Region (1)&quot;. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping has multiple identities. He is a painter, professor, critic and curator. He has taught at the Central Academy of Fine Arts and Sun Yat-sen University. Later he served as the director of Guangdong Museum of Art. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping is considered a rare &quot;scholar-type painter&quot; in the art world. In an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend in 2007, Luo Yiping, who teaches at Sun Yat-sen University, published a series of books called &quot;Images in Art History.&quot; &quot;Rather than reading their pictures, it is better to say that I am reading my own desires and will.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After many years, Luo Yiping remembers this discussion. It was his most important academic achievement at Sun Yat-sen University, and he interpreted thousands of Western paintings from his own perspective. Images in the history of contemporary art, as well as images of landscapes, figures, flowers and birds in the history of Chinese art. He said at the time: &quot;I don&#39;t think the essence of art is divided into East and West, but the expression tools of art are definitely different. This is not determined by personal subjective thoughts, but by differences in ethical habits and cognitive habits.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, Luo Yiping presided over the &quot;Art Creation Laws, Talent Growth Laws and Thousand Talents Research Plan&quot;, which was applied by the China Artists Association. To this end, he drafted a questionnaire to be distributed to members of the National Artists Association. As a result, he discovered something that worried him: the boundaries of artists now seem to be more &quot;firm&quot; than in the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;They will frame it with a symbol or image. This unintentionally creates a clear boundary between traditional ink and contemporary ink, each playing its own role.&quot; Luo Yiping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fan Di&#39;an, chairman of the Chinese Artists Association, said: &quot;At present, the biggest issue in the development of Chinese painting is how to look at the relationship between tradition and contemporary times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping did not answer this question directly. He painted many new works. In November, Luo Yiping completed his most important solo exhibition in 2023, &quot;One Yuan Returns to the Beginning - Luo Yiping&#39;s Ink Works Exhibition&quot; hosted by the Guangdong Museum of Art and the Guangdong Artists Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6aa87222e5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;784&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6aa87222e5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Luo Yiping&#39;s work &quot;Jing·Not Jing (1)&quot;. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The exhibition consists of four parts: &quot;Mountain · Non-Mountain&quot;, &quot;Region · Non-Region&quot;, &quot;Jing · Non-Situation&quot; and &quot;Word · Non-Word&quot; The exhibition hall is composed of exhibition halls that display Luo Yiping&#39;s landscape works and boundary concepts in recent years. In Luo Yiping&#39;s works, Fan Di&#39;an said that he saw that boundaries are not constraints, but also provide the possibility of breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The homogeneity of ink painting is too serious”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In May 2023, Luo Yiping created while listening to Tchaikovsky A large painting of 18 meters was made. It has been his habit for many years to pair classical music with large paintings. Music guides the painter&#39;s emotions, while large-scale landscapes test the painter&#39;s creative &quot;momentum&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What exactly is a landscape painting that is different from others? Over the past few decades, these works, ranging from large landscape paintings to landscape sketches, have not lacked appeal and literary interest, but they are still considered by critics to have the shadow of famous artists such as Huang Binhong, Pan Tianshou, and Lu Yanshao. Luo Yiping doesn&#39;t care about these external comments, but hopes to &quot;push open a door.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The paintings I have seen and the books I have read over the years flow into the eight-foot rice paper through the end of the pen. In the dense pen and ink, the traditional landscape &quot;disappears&quot; on Luo Yiping&#39;s scroll. &quot;Yes. This 18-meter-long scroll now hangs in the &quot;Mountain·Feishan&quot; exhibition hall. The image of the mountain appears faintly, but it is no longer so &quot;mountain-like&quot;. Luo Yiping uses an uncertain long and short lines and thick and light ink color blocks to show the atmosphere of the mountains, trying to draw the viewer into the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The painting theory of the Tang and Song Dynasties required that Chinese paintings should be &quot;visible, feasible, travelable, and habitable.&quot; Luo Yiping pointed to the broken lines in his landscape, &quot;Is this mountain beautiful? I can&#39;t tell.&quot; &quot;Does this mountain have space for us to enter? No.&quot; &quot;Does this mountain have the cultural atmosphere of a gathering of literati in pavilions and pavilions? No. &quot;This mountain has only bare lines. Do you want to live here forever? It will definitely not attract interest.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Traditional ink painting has strict regulations. &quot;What opinion do I want to express in a Chinese painting? Is there a mountain in front or behind it? Should there be a pavilion on the mountain?&quot; These are settings.&quot; Likewise, this regulation affects the people who view the paintings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This time, the spatial image that is most valued in traditional landscapes has been &quot;lost&quot; by Luo Yiping. Viewers of the painting are never able to enter the mountains, and can no longer find familiar directions and specific spaces. In the end, they can only &quot;see with non-mountain eyes.&quot; This is exactly the effect Luo Yiping expected. People who look at paintings can see their own desires and wills, just like they did in the past. Among the horizontal and vertical thick and thin lines and thick and light ink dots, follow along and let your emotions blend into the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/23b202d7ae.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/23b202d7ae.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259851&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Luo Yiping&#39;s work &quot;Mountain·Not Mountain (V)&quot;. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yin Shuangxi, deputy editor-in-chief of &quot;Art Research&quot; of the Central Academy of Fine Arts, once said: &quot;He is a scholar, and the paintings are not just about his theory. It also reflects his memory of landscape painting images. A painter’s possession of the feeling of pen and ink is always the most important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping was born in Jiangxi. He started painting in elementary school, then went north to study and received a doctorate degree from the Art History Department of the Central Academy of Fine Arts. Later he taught in Guangzhou for many years. For many years, he has always insisted on &quot;having nothing in mind&quot;, which means that there should be no settings and regulations in mind, and he should break away from fixed ideas and methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After this painting, many problems seemed to be solved at once. Luo Yiping told Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, there was a clear boundary between contemporary art and mainstream art: &quot;The boundary has a very strong restriction on the development of Chinese painting. Once it passes a little bit, it is not classified as Chinese painting because it crosses the boundary. This is Artificially setting up barriers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What Luo Yiping is worried about is that &quot;the homogenization of ink painting is too serious. If you learn from Huang Binhong, you will be Huang Binhong, and if you learn from Lu Yanshao, you will be Lu Yan Shao emphasizes foundation rather than development... Every ancient person actually has his own present. When every ancient person moves forward, the biggest issue he considers is the present.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping showed the questionnaire to Southern Weekend reporters. In the questionnaire, he asked more than 9,000 Chinese artists more than 600 questions, ranging from national ideology to the current development status of Chinese art to the artists&#39; personal family lives. Regarding the laws of art, the anxiety of faults, and the establishment of an evaluation system... On August 6, 2021, Luo Yiping decided to put everything aside for a short time and no longer consider these issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he felt that there was nothing else in his mind, only the &quot;emotion&quot; that existed faintly. He wanted to pour out this emotion into his unforgettable works. This was how it was born. Luo Yiping found &quot;unprecedented passion&quot;: &quot;When you break through this boundary, you can gain greater freedom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;There is an either-or barrier between traditional art and contemporary art. ”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In February 2010, Luo Yiping served as the director of the Guangdong Museum of Art. Two years later, at the Sixth Asian Art Museum Directors Forum, Luo Yiping once again felt some kind of discourse “pressure”. At the roundtable meeting, some art museum directors from East and South Asia suddenly &quot;attacked&quot; and hoped to cancel the forum later because &quot;the force that promotes the development of Asian art is not art museums, but curators.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As one of the participants at the time, Luo Yiping replied that he partially agreed with the curator’s opinion and decided to hold the first Asian Curated Exhibition in September 2013 The forum even proposed four sections of content. &quot;This is a temporary decision, including the time and topics of the forum,&quot; Luo Yiping told Southern Weekend reporters. &quot;I remember the scene was quiet.&quot; Luo Yiping then added that the forum would also invite directors and curators from the world&#39;s top museums People discussed &quot;Asian consciousness and Asian experience&quot; together, and the vote was passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soon, curators from important art museums including the Tate Modern in the UK, the Metropolitan Museum of Art in the US, and the Museum of Modern Art in New York, I received an invitation letter from China. This invitation lists the guests who will participate in the forum, although some people have not yet been invited. As a result, all the replies Luo Yiping received were &quot;participate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This was already ten years ago. Luo Yiping told Southern Weekend reporters that various opportunities have contributed to this largest curator forum in the world so far. Luo Yiping said that this is the first and currently only forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping believes that the crisis faced by Chinese artists in the 21st century began in the late 20th century. Chinese artists suffered two impacts. One was the coercion of Western culture; Another is the change in the communication environment. &quot;For the outside world, mainly Asian contemporary art faces the European and American-centered art structure. Do we need to get rid of the Western system model and establish a new Asian artistic image? If so, how to achieve it?&quot; said the above-mentioned curator. At the forum, Luo Yiping said in a speech on the topic of &quot;Asian Consciousness and Asian Experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2017, Luo Yiping, who has retired, also prepared for the China Centenary Comics Exhibition held at the National Cartoon Museum of Belgium. At first, they encountered the familiar &quot;prejudice&quot; in Belgium, where the other party &quot;popularized&quot; comics, explained art and other basic content, but was unwilling to disclose the curatorial plan. In the subsequent long-term and powerful communication, the original &quot;assist in organizing the exhibition&quot; became &quot;leading in organizing the exhibition&quot;, and the plan to only show the &quot;revolutionary&quot; side of Chinese comics was replaced by a more comprehensive plan proposed by Luo Yiping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For many years, Luo Yiping has served as a visiting professor at the Repin Academy of Fine Arts in Russia, and has also been the chairman of the China Committee of the Asian Artists Alliance for 17 years. He told Southern Weekend reporters To put it bluntly: &quot;Chinese traditional landscape paintings have not received much attention in the world. The Japanese converted Chinese ink paintings into Japanese paintings during the Meiji Restoration era. When Europeans and Americans see Chinese paintings, they do not think they are Chinese paintings, but think they are Japanese paintings.&quot; Painting. Our traditional art has really little international influence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There is an either-or barrier between traditional art and contemporary art.&quot; After completing the 1.7 million-word project report, Luo Yiping realized that one of the core issues in Chinese painting is &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;cultural definition&quot;, which &quot;restricts the possibility of Chinese artists looking at art from a more comprehensive perspective.&quot; Sexuality has caused Chinese artists to be unable to deny themselves like Picasso and Matisse, Western artists in the 20th century, and lack a more tolerant and forward-looking vision.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Yiping told Southern Weekend reporters that Chinese painters can of course &quot;put traditional language into a contemporary context to speak.&quot; In the work &quot;Region · Non-Region&quot; in Hall 2, Luo Yiping breaks the traditional ink landscape pattern and uses traditional brush and ink to organize the space, frame, and structure common in contemporary art works. In order to get closer to contemporary patterns, he added &quot;color&quot; to black and white ink to express the postmodern sense of &quot;absurd dislocation&quot;. In some works, Luo Yiping added elements of Western artists&#39; works to the ink that was originally a traditional landscape, realizing the &quot;juxtaposition&quot; of traditional ink and contemporary art, and also used contemporary painting materials to integrate them into the ink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Hall 3, &quot;Jing·Feijing&quot;, Luo Yiping also brought installation art, with huge paintings reflected in the pillar mirrors. In Hall 4&#39;s &quot;Word · Fei Yan&quot;, Luo Yiping used 38 round landscape paintings to chase the ancient — the ancient — literati fun -sketch -abstract -abstract, reproduced the path from tradition to contemporary, no confrontation, and no confrontation. Not compromise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/44292696a2.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 270 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/44292696a2.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259852 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Luo Yiping&#39;s &quot;Words · Fei Yan&quot;. The interviewees confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At first glance, these works are Chinese painting, but they are full of contemporary atmosphere and feeling. During the curatorial, after watching the exhibition, Ren Rong, a German Chinese artist, believed that Luo Yiping&#39;s works were &quot;the purest contemporary art, and it was non -westernized, breaking the traditional landscape space.&quot; Those more harsh critics, no one denied that Luo Yiping&#39;s works were ink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the past, Luo Yiping mentioned in an interview with a reporter from the Southern Weekend: &quot;What the author wants to do? Is it torn one by one? &quot;Sixteen years later, his works&quot; seduced &quot;and&quot; tear &quot;the barriers to Chinese paintings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[曹保平：我并不迷恋愤怒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261458]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-28 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https: /// Feedx.net &quot;style =&quot; color: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href =&quot; https://feedx.run &quot;style =&quot; Color: Orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小区电梯放露骨广告背后：业主自治权难落实丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261479]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the &quot;Xiaoxiang Morning News&quot; report, a citizen in Changsha reported that the elevator in their residential complex was covered with stickers on three sides. The &quot;home massage&quot; advertisement, the advertising images and slogans are very &quot;explicit&quot; and uncomfortable. It also arouses the curiosity of children and worries the owners. After the owners complained, the property management company removed two advertisements. The remaining advertisement looked relatively normal, but after scanning the QR code on the advertisement, there were still pages featuring a large number of sexy &quot;physical therapists.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding these marginal advertisements, staff from the property management company said that if the owner feels there is something wrong with the advertisement, he needs to provide evidence that it is an illegal advertisement. Whether it is illegal or not is up to the government. This incident quickly aroused heated discussion, which made people think: Is it true that any advertisement can be placed as long as it does not violate regulations? Do the owners have a say in what advertisements are placed in the community? Furthermore, who does community advertising revenue belong to? How should it be allocated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These issues are actually very clear in law. Article 271 of the Civil Code stipulates that owners “enjoy the right to co-own and jointly manage the common parts other than the exclusive parts” of the building. The &quot;Property Management Regulations&quot; also stipulate that owners have the right to know and supervise the use of shared parts of the property, shared facilities and equipment, and related sites. Elevators, public activity venues, etc. are all shared by the owners of the community. In some communities, parking lots are built using roads, sites, etc. shared by the owners, and are also owned by the owners. Since these common parts are shared by the owners, the owners should naturally have the right to decide how to use them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to legal provisions, whether public locations such as elevators in a community can be used for advertising is a matter decided jointly by the owners and requires a vote by the owners. If the owners vote to place advertisements, they can also authorize the property management company to carry out specific operations. After all, it is unlikely that the owners will vote on whether every advertisement can be placed. However, even if the property management company is authorized to operate advertising spaces, it cannot do whatever it wants. When deciding what advertisements are acceptable, the views and feelings of the owners should be taken into consideration. Advertisements that the majority of owners think are inappropriate should be removed as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After solving the problem of whether it can operate, the next step is who owns the operating income and how to distribute and use it. In some communities, the owners&#39; shared portions are used for operations, and the income gained is considerable. &quot;Qianjiang Evening News&quot; once reported that a community with 15 residential buildings in Hangzhou has an annual operating income of about 1 million yuan, and some communities have an annual income of more than 4 million yuan. Advertisements in elevators, entrances, garages, etc. are an important source of income for the community. In addition, there are parking fees, business rent, venue rent, etc. Express lockers, self-service vending machines, etc. in the community need to pay rent. Some communities even charge entrance fees for telecom operators to set up base stations in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These operating income should naturally belong to the owners. According to the provisions of the property management regulations, these operating income should be mainly used to supplement special maintenance funds, and can also be used according to the decision of the owners&#39; meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in reality, many property companies often forget that they are only entrusted by the owners to provide property services, and instead regard themselves as the managers of the community. Many property companies arbitrarily add business projects in public places of communities or increase charging standards without consulting the owners. Some time ago, property companies in many residential areas in Nanjing installed electronic billboards in elevators without the consent of the owners. Previously, some residential properties added express delivery cabinets, takeout cabinets, etc. without the consent of the owners. Disputes caused by property management companies arbitrarily increasing parking fees in residential areas occur from time to time in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to not respecting the rights of owners on whether and how to operate the jointly owned parts, the actual operating income of many communities is also unclear. Some property companies announce operating income every year, but they only announce a total amount, which is divided into several major items such as parking fees and advertising space rentals. As for the details of each income, they are rarely announced, and of course few owners study it in detail. This leaves a lot of room for the property management company to operate. Some property companies rent out business buildings shared by owners in the community to their affiliated companies at low prices. The affiliated companies do not even charge for advertising in the community, but for unrelated companies, the charges are even higher than the market price. More importantly, some of the income may go directly into the pockets of the property management company, rather than being used as public operating income for the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The root cause of the constant disputes over community property management is that the property management company oversteps its authority and regards itself as the owner of the community and the manager of the owners. The fundamental solution to the problem lies in implementing the autonomy of community owners and allowing them to truly have the right to choose property management companies. Only then can property management companies truly change their roles and become service providers to all property owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[财富管理榜：29家最活跃金融机构，谁更用心看护您的财富？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261448]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wealth management is one of the core businesses of the global financial industry. It is one of the blue ocean markets where financial institutions are increasing competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Calculated in terms of personal financial assets, China has become the world&#39;s second largest wealth management market. As of the end of 2022, my country&#39;s wealth management market has reached 118.49 trillion yuan, a year-on-year growth of 8.7%. Among them, the total scale of bank financial management and insurance asset management accounts for nearly 62%. At the same time, the huge potential of the wealth management market has attracted financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the wealth management market heats up and competition intensifies, regulatory agencies have issued new regulations one after another. In particular, the central bank, together with relevant departments, issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Regulating the Asset Management Business of Financial Institutions&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;commonly known as the &quot;New Asset Management Regulations&quot;&lt;/ span>;) is continuing to reshape the asset management market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The wealth management business in 2023 will not be easy. The lack of high-quality assets, the turmoil in the financial target market, and residents&#39; financial management deposits and regular deposits are all testing banks and insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to select evaluation objects? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the huge market temptation, increasingly strict supervision and unfavorable market environment, the competition between my country&#39;s commercial banks and insurance institutions in wealth management in 2023 How is the strength? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, the People&#39;s Bank of China announced the list of domestic systemically important banks. The People&#39;s Bank of China mainly evaluates and identifies systemically important banks from four dimensions: size, relevance, substitutability and complexity. Rated commercial banks are divided into different groups based on their scores. In addition to meeting minimum capital requirements, reserve capital and countercyclical capital requirements, banks in each group should also meet different additional capital requirements. Among them, core tier-one capital has the strongest loss-absorbing capacity and is the core indicator for measuring the comprehensive strength and risk compensation capabilities of commercial banks. It is also an important foundation for the operation and development of the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to statistics from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center, as of the end of June 2023, the total assets of the 20 systemically important banks reached 260 trillion yuan, accounting for the total assets of my country&#39;s commercial banks. About 3/4 of the assets; in the first half of 2023, a total net profit of 1.04 trillion was achieved, accounting for approximately 83% of the total net profit of my country’s commercial banks in the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the 20 most representative domestic systemically important banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also included nine major life insurance companies in the list for evaluation. The total original insurance premium income of the nine companies from January to October 2023 is approximately 1.8 trillion yuan, accounting for approximately 3/4 of the total original insurance premium income of the life insurance industry during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the main force in the wealth management market, how can commercial banks and insurance institutions seize the high ground? Can you provide high-quality wealth management products and services? To this end, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has constructed a wealth management index system to comprehensively evaluate the wealth management competitiveness of financial institutions in the banking and insurance industries. The results of the &quot;Wealth Management Ranking&quot; are intended to provide investors with a decision-making reference and provide useful reference for financial institutions to improve their competitiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank list: Six dimensions&amp;nbsp;Eighteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the wealth management business of twenty commercial banks, Southern Weekend The New Finance Research Center conducts a combined qualitative and quantitative assessment from six dimensions, and assigns appropriate weights to eighteen sub-indicators. The total weight of these qualitative and quantitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/67cc569e2b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2529&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/67cc569e2b.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The above main dimensions are now &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;analyzed&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and explained&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(1)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Wealth management scale&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and capability&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; : Maximum weight&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are 8 secondary indicators under wealth management scale and capability, with a total weight of 35%, accounting for half of the weight of all qualitative and quantitative indicators. Therefore, this dimension is the most important consideration in measuring the competitiveness of commercial banks’ wealth management. Among them, as the basis and prerequisite for carrying out wealth management business, there are five indicators related to the retail business of commercial banks, including: retail customer scale, personal deposit balance and its growth rate, total assets under management of retail customers and its growth rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, in order to gain insight into the profitability of the wealth management business of commercial banks, the fee and commission income generated by related businesses and their growth rate are also important measurement indicators. However, given that my country&#39;s wealth management market has not formed unified regulations for the wide range of businesses included in wealth management, and various commercial banks have inconsistent definitions of wealth management fees and commissions, this list uses the quantitative indicators of each bank&#39;s net fee and commission income and Whether to publish qualitative indicators of data related to wealth management business income to roughly assess the bank&#39;s wealth management profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To sum up, the scale of wealth management embodies the basic scale, competitiveness and profitability of commercial banks’ wealth management business, and is the most important dimension to measure the level of wealth management. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The scale of financial management business: embodies the &quot;two strengths&quot; of financial management products&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are 4 secondary indicators under the scale dimension of financial management business, with a total weight of 16%. Since the &quot;New Asset Management Regulations&quot; were officially implemented in 2022, major commercial banks have basically completed the net-value transformation of their wealth management business, and have established wealth management subsidiaries to undertake the design, development and operation of their wealth management products. Wealth management subsidiaries have thus become the core pillar of wealth management for commercial banks. This list uses four indicators, including the issuance scale and growth rate of wealth management products, net profit of wealth management subsidiaries and its growth rate, to consider the strength of each commercial bank&#39;s wealth management business, and also reflects the market competitiveness of each bank&#39;s wealth management products after the wealth management market is standardized. and the risk-resistance ability of wealth management products after the net-worth transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(3)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Private banking business: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Tinjian’s comprehensive service capabilities&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are three secondary indicators under the private banking business dimension, with a total weight of 12%. In order to attract high-net-worth customers, each bank has deployed private banking business, strengthened the construction of comprehensive private banking services, and enhanced the core competitive advantages of private banking business. This list uses three indicators: the number of private banking customers, the scale of private banking customer assets under management and its growth rate to measure the competitiveness of each bank&#39;s private banking business, thereby demonstrating the comprehensive service capabilities and level of each bank at the top of the pyramid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;(4)&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Wealth service capabilities: consider professionalism and initiative&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are three secondary indicators under the wealth service capability dimension, with a total weight of 7%. Different from the above-mentioned wealth management scale and wealth management business capabilities, wealth service capabilities mainly consider the professionalism of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business and their &quot;customer-centered&quot; proactive service awareness and capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, commercial banks should promptly explain the fluctuations in wealth management and financial management business income, continue to accompany customers and maintain high-level service capabilities; on the other hand, Commercial banks should attach great importance to the construction of wealth management teams, establish a wealth management talent training system, regularly organize various trainings, continuously improve the professional knowledge and service levels of financial management practitioners, and enhance the professionalism of wealth management business from both the company and client sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who wins the bank ranking? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The bank list of the 2023 wealth management list shows that Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, China Merchants Bank and Agricultural Bank of China occupy the top three. With its comprehensive capabilities and comprehensive strength in wealth management, ICBC ranked first with a total score of 77.40. China Merchants Bank relied on its leading edge in private banking to overtake state-owned banks and rank second on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking of Banks (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28 /d67de23e50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2237&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/d67de23e50.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, among the four major state-owned banks, the wealth management business of the four major industrial and agricultural banks, China Construction Bank, has strong economies of scale advantages and ranks high overall. Specifically, ICBC ranks first in wealth management scale, net fee and commission income, and overall ranking first; Agricultural Bank of China ranks among the top three in the list because it has the largest retail customer scale, personal deposit scale, and wealth management product scale; China Although the bank leads among the four major banks in terms of the growth rate of personal deposit balances and the growth rate of net fees and commissions, its number of retail customers and its efforts in financial investor education, professional talent team building, and the popularization of financial knowledge are China Construction Bank lost a lot of points due to lack of information disclosure, and finally ranked seventh; China Construction Bank&#39;s wealth management scale and financial business scale are comparable to ICBC, but the scale growth rate and net profit performance of its financial business have become its biggest loss points. Ranked only eighth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2023, although the trend of joint-stock bank residents&#39; deleveraging and deposit regularization has eased, the issuance of financial products and net worth performance have still continued the downturn in 2022. The market conditions have had an impact on the overall bank financial management business. In the first half of 2023, although the growth rate of wealth management scale of China Merchants Bank was negative, it ranked first among joint-stock banks and ranked second overall because its wealth management scale and private banking business performed much better than other joint-stock banks; Ping An Bank&#39;s wealth management scale ranked second among Ranked third among joint-stock banks, ranked first in net profit growth rate of wealth management subsidiaries, ranked first in growth rate of total assets under management of private banks, and disclosed the most complete and detailed information related to wealth management. Its comprehensive ranking surpassed some major state-owned banks and The leading stock bank ranked fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among city commercial banks, except for wealth service capabilities, Bank of Ningbo ranks first in all other indicators. Therefore, it ranks first among city commercial banks and has also been promoted to the comprehensive ranking. Fifth; Bank of Beijing and Minsheng Bank did not fully disclose information related to wealth management, and many key indicator data were not disclosed in the 2023 interim report, which seriously affected their scores and rankings, so they were at the bottom of the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Dimension analysis, wealth management scale and capability dimensions embody the basic scale, competitiveness and profitability of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business. Overall, state-owned banks have a relatively large base in wealth management business, strong ability to attract personal deposits, and excellent profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scale dimension of financial management business highlights the competitiveness of financial management products of various banks after the financial management market is standardized, and the risk resistance ability of financial management products after the net-worth transformation. Overall, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks perform well in terms of scale of financial management business. Some leaders are no smaller than state-owned banks and have good growth rates, highlighting the opportunities for latecomers to overtake in new business areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The private banking business dimension further reflects the capabilities and level of each bank in high-end wealth management services. Generally speaking, state-owned banks have a large private banking customer base and a large scale of managed private banking customer assets, and the private banking business of city commercial banks is also gradually speeding up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The wealth service capability dimension presents the professionalism and &quot;customer-centered&quot; initiative of commercial banks&#39; wealth management business. Overall, the era of wealth management has arrived, and all banks are allocating resources to this line. Each type of bank has perfect cases in this dimension. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insurance list: Five dimensions&amp;nbsp;Sixteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Aiming at the wealth management competitiveness of 9 leading life insurance companies, We conduct a combined qualitative and quantitative evaluation from three dimensions, and assign appropriate weights to the fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of these qualitative and quantitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After adding up the above three scores, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team ranked the total score from high to low to construct the 2023 Wealth Management Ranking Life insurance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking and Life Insurance Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/1aeaf2f52f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2073&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/1aeaf2f52f.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management Ranking and Life Insurance Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The relevant dimensions are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(1) Channel building capabilities. There are 8 secondary indicators under the channel construction capability dimension, with a total weight of 40%. The construction of various channels is the basic ability of life insurance companies to engage in wealth management business and even the entire life insurance business, and it is also the most important influencing factor. Most of the life insurance companies evaluated have large agent teams and various distribution channels. They have strong sales capabilities and can reach a large number of customer groups, which helps attract customer groups to participate in wealth management business and increase the wealth management customer base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to more accurately consider the comprehensive strength of the nine life insurance companies in channel construction, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team evaluated individual insurance agent channels and bancassurance channels respectively. Quantitative indicators such as the channel’s premium income, new business value, and 13-month and 25-month premium/policy continuation rates are supplemented by qualitative evaluations of distribution channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2) Wealth management scale and capabilities. There are five secondary indicators under this dimension, with a total weight of 25%. Life insurance companies support the development of insurance liability business through wealth management business. Therefore, the scale of assets managed and invested by life insurance companies and their rate of return have become two important dimensions for measuring the wealth management strength of insurance companies. This list uses indicators such as third-party asset management scale, investment asset scale, total investment income and rate of return as quantitative indicators of the competitiveness of the wealth management business of the nine life insurance companies, and the adequacy of wealth management-related information disclosure as the nine life insurance companies. A qualitative indicator of the importance a company places on its wealth management business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(3) Business collaboration capabilities. Major life insurance companies attach great importance to business synergy, which is also an important starting point for strengthening the competitive advantages of related products and services. As competition in the wealth management market becomes increasingly fierce, life insurance companies can form a &quot;moat&quot; by building their own &quot;ecosystem&quot; through multi-business collaboration. Therefore, this list specifically considers the measures and achievements of nine life insurance companies in building ecosystems such as comprehensive health and comprehensive pension, and encourages insurance companies to provide differentiated services to customers through the &quot;insurance + service&quot; model, thereby highlighting relevant life insurance companies comparative advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why does the champion not dominate the rankings in one indicator? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The life insurance list of the 2023 wealth management list shows that Ping An Life, China Life and Taiping Life are among the top three. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the fourteen secondary indicators in the life insurance rankings, Ping An Life is not particularly conspicuous, only in the adequacy of information disclosure and the &quot;insurance + service&quot; model. It received the highest score among the two secondary indicators of category, and none of the other 12 quantitative indicators ranked first. However, in-depth analysis found that most of Ping An Life&#39;s indicators performed at the mid-to-upper level, with very few indicators clearly lagging behind. Specifically, among the twelve quantitative indicators, Ping An Life ranks second in five and third in four. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although China Life is the &quot;king&quot; in premiums in the life insurance industry, it implements more stringent statistics in the two key indicators that reflect the renewal rate. In terms of information disclosure and information disclosure, its scores on related indicators lagged behind those of its peers, dragging down its overall score and ultimately ranking second with a gap of 1.6 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taiping Life ranks first in terms of third-party asset management scale and 25-month premium/policy continuation rate, but its total investment return rate The two indicators of new business value and bancassurance channel lag behind peers, dragging down the overall ranking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wealth Management Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28 /75a5eb9098.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1188&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/75a5eb9098.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259838&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wealth Management List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of wealth management scale and capabilities, the larger the asset management scale, the higher the investment business returns, the stronger the ability to allocate large-scale assets, and the stronger the wealth management retail business will be. China Life and Ping An Life have obvious advantages in this indicator, with investment assets and total investment income significantly ahead of other life insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of channel construction capabilities, China Life’s number of agents in the individual insurance channel, premium income from the bancassurance channel, premium income from the individual insurance channel, and new innovations from the individual insurance channel All four indicators of business value ranked first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The business synergy dimension score shows that each of the nine life insurance companies has its own characteristics. For example, Sunshine Life focuses on the four core needs of family customers such as health care, pension planning, children&#39;s education and wealth management, and concentrates resources to create a multi-level &quot;insurance + service&quot; ecological service system covering the entire family life cycle; Taikang Life Insurance has cooperated with Taikang The layout of the early and high-density high-end retirement communities has formed a positive interaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The list also shows that the life insurance industry will continue to bottom out in 2022. Against the background of lower bank deposit interest rates, bank financial losses, and increased volatility in equity products such as stocks, life insurance products with higher interest rates have been highly sought after for more than half a year, and even experienced a pulse peak effect for a time. However, the rebound momentum is affected by various internal and external factors, and the overall performance throughout the year is unsatisfactory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Especially with the reduction of interest rates in the second half of the year and the implementation of the regulatory authorities&#39; &quot;unification of reporting and banking&quot; regulations, (for details, see Southern Weekend&#39;s &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.infzm.com/contents/259167&quot;>;How come the bancassurance business is deformed all year round when there are large accounts and small accounts?&lt;/a>;》) The competitiveness of product rates has decreased and the handling fees of bancassurance channels have dropped significantly. . The once hot-selling scene of life insurance products has returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth mentioning that the bancassurance channel is one of the important channels for many life insurance companies. The &quot;unification of reporting and banking&quot; will definitely have a long-term impact on the wealth management business of each life insurance company and test the coping capabilities of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江一煤矿发生事故，已有多人失联]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:43:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At around 15:00 on November 28, an impact occurred at the Shuangyang Coal Mine of Heilongjiang Longmei Shuangyashan Mining Co., Ltd. Ground pressure roof accident. The reporter learned from various sources that as of 16:00 on November 28, it was initially understood that many people were lost in the accident and related rescue work was in progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:55:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[MH370乘客家属索赔案开庭，此前已对马航等相关方提起多轮诉讼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-28 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was held in Chaoyang, Beijing The District People&#39;s Court holds a hearing. Photo provided by People&#39;s Vision&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2637cede22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 27, 2023, the compensation case for the family members of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was opened in the Chaoyang District Court in Beijing. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 27, 2023, the compensation case filed by the families of Malaysia Airlines MH370 passengers was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not a single lawsuit. More than 40 family members independently sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties. The defendants include Malaysia Airlines (old Malaysia Airlines) and Malaysia International Airlines Berhad. (New Malaysia Airlines), Boeing Company, Rolls-Royce Holdings Limited, Allianz Insurance Group, etc. The trial will last from November 27 to around December 5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter learned that on the first day of the trial, the plaintiff and defendant had not yet entered the cross-examination phase, and Malaysia Airlines had not submitted new evidence, and they were all going through the legal process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly ten years after the accident, can this air crash come to a legal end in China? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Lost lawsuits in the United States and Malaysia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first lawsuit against the MH370 incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past ten years, the families of MH370 passengers have traveled to China, the United States and Malaysia, and have filed multiple rounds of lawsuits against Malaysia Airlines and other related parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;MH370&#39;s departure point is Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, and its destination is Beijing, China. There are no transfers or stops during transportation. For this type of international air transport incident, the main international treaties to refer to for the attribution of civil jurisdiction are the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1929 and the &quot;Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Air Transport&quot; formulated in 1999 Convention (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Montreal Convention&quot;&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the latter sets the compensation standards for civil aviation accidents and has the effect of priority application. China, the United States and Malaysia are all parties to the Montreal Convention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 33 of the Montreal Convention stipulates that a claim for damages may be brought at the plaintiff&#39;s option to the carrier&#39;s domicile, principal place of business, or the principal place of business where the contract is concluded. , destination and, in certain circumstances, the passenger’s fixed and permanent residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This means that in the MH370 air crash case, both Malaysia and China have jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, from the beginning of 2016 to March 7, Chinese family members sued Malaysia Airlines and related parties in the United States, Malaysia and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the lawsuits in the United States are mainly divided into two categories. One is a claim against Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies based on the Montreal Convention, and the other is a claim against the aircraft manufacturer Boeing. The company filed a product liability lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hao Junbo, a lawyer who has represented the families of an air crash in transnational litigation, told Southern Weekend reporters that the United States has the highest air crash compensation standards in the world, so worldwide, If an air crash occurs in almost any country, as long as the plane has a connection point with the United States, such as an engine or parts manufactured by an American company, attorneys from various countries will strive to prosecute the case in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Senior international aviation lawyer James Healy-Pratt wrote in 2021 that based on the jury’s recognition of unlimited compensation for bereavement, etc. Considering all these factors, the average amount of compensation awarded by American courts for air crash victims is the highest in the world, reaching US$5.2 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Hao Junbo said: &quot;In recent years, the possibility of foreign air crashes being tried by U.S. courts is very low, and they are generally dismissed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2018, the judge of multidistrict litigation in the United States ruled as forum non conveniens (&lt;em>;forum non conveniens&lt;/em>;) (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The principle of forum non conveniens means that after a court accepts a foreign-related case, it considers the many inconvenient factors in the trial of the case and believes that it is more convenient for the court to hear the case in other jurisdictions, thus giving up the case. The court dismissed all lawsuits arising from the disappearance of MH370 on the grounds of jurisdiction (&lt;/span>;), and the court believed that Malaysian courts were more suitable to hear these cases. The family chose to appeal, and in 2020, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit upheld the original verdict and dismissed all the family&#39;s lawsuits in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2017, 15 Chinese family members sued the Malaysian government, the Malaysian military and the Malaysian Civil Aviation Authority for &quot;negligence&quot; in Malaysia, demanding disclosure. the truth. In 2018, a Malaysian court ruled against the family due to insufficient evidence. In addition, from 2016 to 2020, the cases brought by family members against Malaysia Airlines and the Malaysian government in Malaysia were also lost due to insufficient evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The trial will not be affected by the outcome of foreign litigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The domestic litigation of the MH370 case can be traced back to 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced in 2015 that Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 crashed and it was presumed that all people on board were killed, Malaysia Airlines subsequently announced a compensation of 2.52 million to the families of each MH370 crash passenger. Yuan Yuan, but asked the family to give up pursuing responsibility against the Malaysian government, Malaysia Airlines, Malaysian military, and Boeing Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, nearly two-thirds of the families refused to sign the settlement agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, some family members who did not sign the agreement went to the Beijing Railway Transport Court to sue Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia Airlines International Berhad, Boeing Company, and Rolls-Rolls— Royce Holdings plc, Allianz Insurance Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In March 2016, the Beijing Railway Transport Court announced that it had filed and accepted 36 civil claims for compensation from passengers involved in the crash of Malaysian Airlines flight MH370. At the end of 2017, the Beijing Railway Transport Court held a pre-trial meeting on the case, which was later designated by the Beijing High Court to be under the jurisdiction of the Beijing Chaoyang District Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, almost all family members who lost cases abroad returned to Chinese courts to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Qihuai, a lawyer representing some of the family members, said in a previous interview that for more than nine years, the court has actively promoted reconciliation between the two parties, and the family members and Malaysia Airlines and insurance companies have More than half of the cases are waiting for the parties involved to reconcile. As of March 2021, 89 families have refused to settle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Previously, the lawsuits filed by the families of Chinese passengers involved in the crash were not supported by the courts in the United States and Malaysia. Will this result affect domestic litigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the relevant provisions of the judicial interpretation of the Civil Procedure Law, for cases where both Chinese and foreign courts have jurisdiction, one party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court, while the other party will file a lawsuit in the foreign court. If a lawsuit is filed in a Chinese court, the domestic court may accept the case. After the judgment, if a foreign court applies or the parties request a domestic court to recognize and enforce the judgment or ruling made by a foreign court on the case, it will not be allowed, unless otherwise provided for in an international treaty jointly concluded or acceded to by both parties. In addition, if a foreign court&#39;s judgment or ruling has been recognized by a domestic court, and the party files a lawsuit in a domestic court with the same dispute, it will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A civil litigation law scholar who does not want to be named to the south weekend reporter that in general, even if the civil case of civil cases in foreign countries takes effect, it needs to be in Domestic applications should also be applied for recognition and execution to intermediate courts with jurisdictions in China. The courts were reviewed and approved to recognize its effectiveness and issue an enforcement order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;&quot; For civil cases defeated abroad, there is no need to apply for execution first. Second, as long as there is no special regulations, the parties can still prosecute the same facts and cases in China. &quot;The aforementioned scholar told the Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; China and Malaysia have signed a bilateral judicial assistance treaty, that is, the &quot;Treaty of the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Malaysian Government on Criminal Judicial Assistance&quot;, but the bilateral treaty agreement The content is criminal case, and the judicial judgment of civil disputes has not been considered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This means that the results of MH370 passengers&#39; families in foreign countries did not affect the trial of the Chinese court in the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to CCTV news reports, the civil compensation amount raised by passengers is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. A large part of the compensation costs are mental damage comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>