<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[高标准对接国际经贸规则，“应聚焦数字经济领域的制度型开放”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6t2GGa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6 t2GGa. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Yangshan Deep Water Port is also an important part of the free trade zone. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The top priority this year is to align with international high-standard economic and trade rules and promote high-level and comprehensive Institutional opening. It is necessary to test the system for the country and steadily promote the pressure test of institutional opening such as rules, regulations, management, and standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 30, 2023, Gong Zheng, Deputy Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee and Mayor Said this at the meeting of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone Promotion Leading Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June, the State Council issued &quot;Several Measures on Piloting Conditional Free Trade Pilot Zones and Free Trade Ports to Align with International High Standards and Promote Institutional Opening&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Several Measures&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the Shanghai Municipal Government issued an implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;, stating that &quot;in one year, we will focus on promoting trade in goods, trade in services, digital trade, temporary entry of business personnel, and optimizing Various pilot measures in the business environment and other aspects have been implemented.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone align with international high-standard economic and trade rules? What progress has been made? What are the current obstacles? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to this topic, Southern Weekend reporters exclusively interviewed Peng Delei, dean of the School of Law at East China University of Science and Technology and researcher at the Lingang-East China University of Science and Technology Free Trade Zone Innovation Research Institute. He has been paying attention to related topics since 2019, and Published many articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is still room for institutional innovation in the digital economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The State Council will issue &quot;Several Measures&quot; in June 2023. What is its importance? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In September and November 2021, China formally applied to join the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) and The Digital Economic Partnership Agreement (DEPA) demonstrates China’s determination to further deepen domestic reforms and expand high-level opening up to the outside world. The introduction of &quot;Several Measures&quot; marks the beginning of my country&#39;s formal alignment with international high-standard rules such as CPTPP and DEPA in terms of substantive content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thirty-three articles of &quot;Several Measures&quot; are mainly based on the CPTPP rules. Some provisions are also reflected in the content of DEPA, such as DEPA Article 2.6 for six-hour customs clearance of express cargo, etc. Trade facilitation measures. This shows that the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has relatively mature conditions to apply these rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that in practice, Shanghai has been at the forefront of the country in terms of facilitation of trade in goods. Recently, Shanghai has also highlighted this in the implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once mentioned that compared with international high standards such as CPTPP and DEPA According to the rules, there is still room for further expansion in the scope of the digital economy content in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;. How should we understand it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are two rules related to digital trade in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;, one is about online consumer protection, and the second is about Software source code disclosure issues. However, CPTPP Chapter 14 E-Commerce (Digital Trade) covers 18 items, and each item also contains different amounts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;non-discriminatory treatment of digital products&quot;, that is, any Party grants digital products created, produced, published, contracted, represented or first commercialized in the territory of another Party. Treatment of products, or treatment of digital products whose authors, performers, producers, developers or owners are persons of another Party, shall not be less favorable than the treatment it accords to other similar digital products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, there is a rule in the CPTPP regarding the &quot;location of computer facilities&quot;: No Party shall require a covered person to use or set up computing facilities in the territory of that Party as part of carrying out activities in its territory. Conditions of business. Each party will also consider the issue of data security, so the CPTPP adds an exception to this rule, that is, nothing in this article shall prevent a party from achieving legitimate public policy objectives, which leaves a certain amount of time for each party to policy space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the premise of protecting national security, more systematic considerations are needed on how to further align with international high-standard rules on non-discriminatory treatment of digital products and the location of computer facilities in the future. These provisions are also key provisions in DEPA, and they have an important impact on digital economic activities such as digital trade. Of course, this also provides space for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to be implemented first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is in line with international high standards in the field of digital economy , what are the advantages? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with other domestic free trade pilot zones, at present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone mainly undertakes the function of institutional innovation. We should take the lead in aligning with international high-standard rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there are many high-standard international rules. Taking CPTPP as an example, it covers 30 chapters including investment, e-commerce, and environment. If the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone wants to benchmark every chapter at this stage, I think it will be difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the conditions of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, it is more advantageous to actively benchmark DEPA and focus on institutional opening up in the field of digital economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the industrial foundation for the development of digital trade in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is unmatched by other pilot free trade zones. Shanghai is an international economic center, financial center, trade center, shipping center and technological innovation center. Trade The foundation is mature, and the newly established Lingang New Area in 2019 is also actively exploring the construction of an international data port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Article 84 of the newly revised &quot;Legislative Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee shall, in accordance with the authorized decision of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, formulate the Pudong New Area &quot;Regulations, implemented in Pudong New Area&quot;, which also provides a legal basis and guarantee for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to carry out pilot trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone should promote China’s accession in the field of digital economy High-standard economic and trade agreements provide practical support. What are the main obstacles faced at this stage? How to break through? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone actively benchmarks against DEPA, which has overall significance for China to join DEPA. The extent to which the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has adapted to DEPA and the problems it has encountered can provide an experience reference for China in subsequent negotiations to join DEPA. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is still in the exploratory stage in the process of connecting with CPTPP and DEPA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in terms of cross-border data flow, national security must be taken into consideration, and risk assessment and prevention and control must be done when aligning with international high-standard rules. What risks are faced by the free flow of data, how big the risks are, and what impacts they will bring, definitely require more detailed and systematic consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can break through from two entry points and gradually expand the scope of docking. First, we can consider learning from the negative list approach and research and develop an important data catalog. If this type of data is in the directory, the management specifications need to be stricter; otherwise, they can be relatively loose. Secondly, some qualified companies can also be allowed to pilot cross-border data flows. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“We attach great importance to the construction of a digital trust environment”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the establishment of the Lingang New Area, some explorations have been completed in promoting institutional opening up in digital trade. What are the highlights? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, the &quot;About Supporting Lingang New Films&quot; issued by the Lingang New Area Management Committee and the Shanghai Municipal Commerce Commission on August 30 Implementation Plan for the District to Deepen High-level Institutional Opening and Promote Innovative Development of Trade in Services (hereinafter referred to as the “Implementation Plan”). This is a comprehensive plan for the development of service trade in the Lingang New Area and has breakthrough significance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; proposes specific measures for the safe and orderly flow of data and the innovative development of digital trade. For example, a data supervision sandbox pilot was launched to promote the implementation of a number of cross-border data cooperation projects such as electronic invoices and digital identities. The data supervision sandbox is equivalent to piloting some supervision measures on a certain subject in a region, and then judging whether it is suitable for promotion based on feasibility and effect. The implementation of electronic invoices and digital identities can improve trade efficiency and reduce business operating costs. These measures are actually the content of DEPA and are also the specific actions for Lingang New Area to align with international high-standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Lingang New Area is also relatively advanced in the construction of digital infrastructure, such as the layout and construction of international communication submarine cable facilities, as well as the new National (Shanghai) Internet Exchange Center and international Internet dedicated channels. Construction etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the field of digital trade, Lingang New Area can take the lead in the future What international high-standard economic and trade rules should we try? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In terms of benchmarking DEPA, there are two aspects that can be tried first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen cooperation among digital enterprises. DEPA’s chapter on “Cooperation with SMEs” mentions that “Parties shall engage in digital SME dialogue. The dialogue may include the private sector, non-governmental organizations, academic experts and other stakeholders from each Party”. It is recommended to establish cooperative organizations or conduct regular forums to promote exchanges between small and medium-sized enterprises and Chinese and foreign-funded enterprises, and the demands of foreign-invested enterprises in China can also be reflected through this mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the cross-border data flow issues that digital investors are concerned about, on the premise of ensuring national security, it can also solve the worries of foreign investors investing in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to strengthen mutual recognition of digital enterprises. Article 4.2 of DEPA states that “Parties shall endeavor to mutually recognize the data protection trust marks of other Parties as an effective mechanism to facilitate cross-border information transfers while protecting personal information.” After mutual recognition of information and security is completed, if both parties need to conduct data flow or transactions, many procedural requirements can be reduced and costs can be saved, which is equivalent to establishing a white list for each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Chinese-funded companies have previously been awarded the Data Protection Trust Mark (DPTM) by the Singapore Infocomm Media Development Authority. It is used to certify businesses that have deployed data protection measures to demonstrate that their operations comply with Singapore’s Personal Data Protection Act. Similarly, Article 12 of my country’s Personal Information Protection Law also contains relevant statements, which is to promote international exchanges and cooperation in personal information protection and promote mutual recognition of personal information protection rules and standards with other countries, regions, and international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The cross-border flow of data is considered a basic prerequisite for digital trade. What is the current practice in this regard in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The cross-border flow of data in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is generally governed by the Data Security Law, National Security Law and Personal Information Protection Law. operating within the framework. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I communicate with the practical community, I feel that they attach great importance to the construction of a digital trust environment. The digital trust environment includes network security, personal privacy protection, etc. For example, in the process of digital trade, it is necessary to ensure that large-scale data leaks or cyber attacks cannot occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai has made a lot of efforts in developing digital trade. For example, the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; mentioned that the Lingang New Area will build the country&#39;s first digital trust pilot zone. In addition, in July this year, the Standing Committee of the 16th Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress publicly released the full text of &quot;Shanghai Provisions on Promoting Data Circulation and Transactions in Pudong New Area (Draft)&quot; to solicit opinions from the society. The overall context and value concept of this consultation draft is to strengthen the use of data. In the past, many policies emphasized the protection of data. If data can be fully utilized, it will help promote the development of the data economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Business environment assessment indicators benchmark against international standards&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has been piloted and has achieved many results. In your opinion, what is the most important outcome? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the most important thing is to implement the “pre-establishment national treatment plus negative list management system” for foreign investment. This concept was proposed with a certain background, mainly based on some demands and paradigms put forward by the United States on investment access during the bilateral investment negotiations between China and the United States at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at first, we didn’t know whether these two systems could be implemented, so we first tried them in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. In 2013, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone piloted the first negative list for foreign investment access. Years of trying have since provided many helpful experiences. Therefore, by the promulgation of the Foreign Investment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China in 2019, the &quot;pre-establishment national treatment plus negative list management system&quot; was officially written into law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two systems have been implemented from pilot to legal form and implemented nationwide, achieving the effect that the experience of the Pilot Free Trade Zone can be replicated and promoted, reflecting the pioneering spirit of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. mission to try. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Free Trade Pilot Zone Key Work List (2023)&quot; issued by the Ministry of Commerce -2025), specifically requires the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to strive to create a world-class business environment. What can be done in this regard? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone attaches great importance to the construction of business environment. For example, the Lingang New Area is actively benchmarking against the World Bank&#39;s newly released business environment project concept document in May this year, namely the B-READY project. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as I know, Lingang New Area invites accounting firms to conduct business environment assessments every year. Not long ago, my colleagues and I went to Lingang New Area to participate in a seminar on the business environment. We talked about the three chapters of B-READY: dispute resolution, bankruptcy and labor. For example, online arbitration can be used Facilitate and improve the business environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the new version of the World Bank’s business environment assessment indicators includes content related to digital trade, that is, the digital trade restrictions index. In the future, China may also include restrictions on digital trade as part of its business environment assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 is the tenth anniversary of the establishment of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. Next The free trade pilot zone promotion strategy will be vigorously implemented. How do you think it should be improved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At this stage, my country’s overall goal requirements for the improvement strategy of the free trade pilot zone can be summarized into three aspects. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it is necessary to improve the alignment with international high-standard economic and trade rules. Currently, it is mainly based on DEPA and CPTPP; second, it is necessary to improve the level of market access, focusing on increasing investment and service trade. Large stress test; third, reform system integration and collaborative innovation should be improved, focusing on strengthening cross-department, cross-field, and cross-industry overall coordination, and enhancing the systematicness, integrity, and coordination of pioneering trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海自贸试验区十周年：对接世界，做制度创新的“试验田”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5 GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. 2095, Jinjing Road, Jinqiao Development Zone, Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, is the office of Volvo Construction Equipment Investment (China) Co., Ltd. This area is home to many automobile manufacturing and parts companies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of this century, Jinqiao, as the first national export processing zone, attracted Volvo to open an assembly plant here. By 2012, Volvo Construction Equipment signed a memorandum of understanding with the Shanghai Municipal Government to establish its regional headquarters in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the office, Zhan Xu, director of Volvo Construction Equipment, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that for the company at that time, it was like a young man starting to make life plans. He had many ideas, but met a bottleneck. &quot;The place where I live is an electronics factory, can I only be a factory boy and factory girl for the rest of my life?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Xu described that the establishment of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone solved the hesitation of &quot;this young man&quot;, &quot;It tells all companies what Pudong, Shanghai and even China will develop into.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2015, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was expanded to include the Lujiazui Financial Area, Jinqiao Development Area, and Zhangjiang High-tech Area, in addition to the four special customs supervision areas including the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone. In August 2019, the country&#39;s only new free trade pilot zone was unveiled in the Lingang area of ​​Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 29, 2023 is the tenth anniversary of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. Over the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has been a pioneer in testing systems and exploring new paths for the country, and has also become an important driving force for Shanghai&#39;s economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;White Paper on the 10th Anniversary of the Construction of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone&quot;, as of the end of 2022, Pudong New Area has established a total of 18,691 new foreign-invested projects, with a cumulative registered foreign capital of US$217.274 billion, and a cumulative paid-in foreign capital of US$74.994 One hundred million U.S. dollars. Pudong New Area will achieve a regional GDP of 1.6 trillion yuan in 2022, creating 1/74 of the GDP with an area of ​​1/8000 of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering a new stage, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is facing new expectations. The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed to &quot;implement the strategy of improving the free trade pilot zone.&quot; At the same time, China is applying to join the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement (DEPA). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency on September 26, 2023, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, recently issued important instructions on further promoting the construction of the free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that on the new journey, based on a comprehensive summary of ten years of construction experience, we must deeply implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy, bravely be a pioneer in forging ahead and overcoming difficulties, and work in a wider field and Carry out deeper exploration and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Responsive to all requests, no disturbance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“If there is no free trade pilot zone Without support, a lot of business may be done overseas. With the establishment of the pilot free trade zone, we have one more way to go. Since the pilot free trade zone wants to engage in innovation, companies will feel that they might as well come to the government to talk.&quot; Zhan Xu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2018, Volvo Construction Equipment became the first company in the Pilot Free Trade Zone to realize cross-border settlement of offshore trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend learned from the Jinqiao Management Committee that at that time the customer ordered two sets of engineering equipment produced in South Korea from Volvo Construction Equipment. The transaction and transportation occurred overseas, and the fund settlement (receipt from overseas customers, The two processes of payment to Korean factories) are carried out in the free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his early years, Zhan Xu ran through industrial and commercial windows and dealt with the government for a long time. &quot;In the past, we participated in policy briefings, but now we attend more research meetings. Many ideas for institutional innovation in the free trade pilot zone came from the enterprise side.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that in the past, enterprises went to The government mostly consults on policies. Now when companies encounter problems, the government helps bring relevant people over and everyone sits down to discuss solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talking about the changes brought about by the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, Zhan Xu spoke highly of the reform of the commercial system. &quot;All the approval procedures have been simplified. One trip is required for each matter, and sometimes there is no need to make a trip at all. This not only saves manpower and costs for the company, but also plays a great role in stimulating corporate vitality and improving corporate confidence.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to a press conference held by the Shanghai Municipal Government on September 15, 2023, in the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has deepened the reform of the commercial system around the entire life cycle of enterprises and innovatively carried out &quot;separation of licenses and licenses&quot; and &quot;post-licensing&quot; Pilot projects such as &quot;license reduction&quot; and &quot;one industry, one license&quot; have issued more than 5,000 comprehensive industry licenses in 31 industries. The average approval time has been reduced by nearly 90%, application materials have been reduced by nearly 70%, and form-filling elements have been reduced by more than 60%. %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has also taken the lead in implementing the registered capital subscription system, the business entity registration confirmation system, the market quasi-operation commitment immediate entry system, innovating business entity exit mechanisms such as simple cancellation, and continuously reducing institutional transaction cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We respond to requests and don’t disturb anything.” Wu Haixia, CEO of Xingbei Group, expressed similar feelings to Zhan Xu when recalling the company’s process of building Shanghai Free Trade No. 1 Life Technology Industrial Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia told Southern Weekend reporters that when the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was officially launched, the company had just arrived at the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone to acquire the land. As the first biomedical entrepreneurial park in the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone, we will encounter many new situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free Trade No. 1 currently plans to build three phases of the park. About 150 companies have settled in the first and second phases of the park. Wu Haixia said that biopharmaceutical companies have different building height requirements from other companies. With the help of the management committee, the maximum floor height of the first-phase park was only 24 meters, and by the third-phase park, it can reach 50 meters. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, at that time, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone implemented a comprehensive land use reform pilot in the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone. This reform is also very attractive to the biomedical industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Several Opinions on Comprehensive Land Use Planning and Land Management in the Bonded Area of ​​the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone&quot; that came into effect on November 20, 2016 (valid until November 19, 2021), encourages The land uses are compatible, and the land use types are mixed with two or more uses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Several Opinions&quot; stated that factors such as spatial layout, industrial integration, building compatibility and traffic environment should be comprehensively considered, and functional guidance requirements for comprehensive land use in the bonded area of ​​the free trade pilot zone should be put forward, and the planning of mixed comprehensive land use should be clarified Type of use, proportion, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The land used by biopharmaceutical companies is generally based on the ratio of 1/3 office, 1/3 R&amp;D, and 1/3 production. But strictly speaking, office and R&amp;D cannot be located on industrial land. .With comprehensive land use reform, it can better meet the needs of the biomedical industry.&quot; Wu Haixia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;System innovation can reduce costs for enterprises&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhan Xu has been in foreign-funded enterprises for 27 years. In his view, whether a multinational company chooses to stay in one place for development depends on whether it can do more business and whether the market is good; second, whether there are risks in operation and whether the rules are clear; third, whether there is any institutional innovation. , which is an important factor in promoting high-quality development of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the above-mentioned press conference that of the 302 free trade pilot zone system innovations replicated and promoted at the national level, nearly half were originated from Shanghai or were simultaneously piloted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Hongming Supply Chain Co., Ltd. is an enterprise established nearly 30 years ago. Since 2006, it has gradually transformed from a traditional logistics enterprise into a digital supply chain enterprise, currently mainly engaged in integrated circuits, medical equipment and other industries. Provide supply chain services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you walk into Hongming&#39;s office at No. 899 Dangui Road, Pudong New Area, you can see two rows of unmanned workstations. Intelligent robots are completing actions such as identifying and entering waybills and automatically filing customs declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the adjacent office, Bai Li, senior manager of Hongming Customs Management Department, told Southern Weekend reporters that the company&#39;s transformation has benefited from many innovative measures in the customs supervision system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baili gave an example. A domestic factory purchased a piece of equipment from abroad. When a screen of the piece of equipment failed, the past practice was for the factory to place an order overseas and go through customs clearance, tax payment, and international transportation. Waiting for the process, it may take a week for the new screen to arrive at the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In a mature manufacturing process, the assembly line machines are lined up one after another. If this one breaks, all the others behind it will be broken.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Started in 2006 , Hongming has opened bonded warehouses in areas such as Waigaoqiao, which is equivalent to putting this screen at the &quot;doorstep&quot;, saving the time and cost incurred by the original &quot;ordering from overseas&quot; model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But as the size of transactions increases, companies need a more cost-effective approach. &quot;In order to serve factories in ten places across the country, a company needs to put 10 screens, which incurs the cost of 10 screens. So, can it only put 5 screens?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone Launched The special customs supervision model for the circulation of bonded goods between regions has solved the most troublesome problem of the national circulation of bonded goods in the industrial supply chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now bonded goods between free trade pilot zones can flow quickly and freely, and the data and information flow sent by enterprises are sent to the regulatory authorities, replacing the traditional paper documents between the regulatory authorities of the two places. Circulation.&quot; Bai Li said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hongming has established 24 industrial supply chain logistics centers in 14 cities across the country. This model now covers all its logistics centers, effectively reducing inventory costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned press conference introduced that the institutional innovation achievements of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone and the Lingang New Area are mainly reflected in four aspects: focusing on the supply of innovative institutions required for industrial development and enhancing new driving forces for high-quality development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the biopharmaceutical industry, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone took the lead in piloting the medical device marketing authorization holder system (MAH) in December 2017. Eligible medical device registration applications in the Pilot Free Trade Zone People can apply for a medical device registration certificate individually and then entrust production to an enterprise with qualifications and production capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free Trade No. 1 is the first biopharmaceutical business park in China that meets MAH requirements. Wu Haixia said that Free Trade One has built the country&#39;s first CDMO platform with industrial park attributes and built 6 production lines. The CDMO platform can provide enterprises with services in research and development, small trials, pilot trials, animal experiments, human trials, registration and approval and other processes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia said that generally speaking, the investment in a production line is more than 10 million yuan. In the past, companies had to wait about 2 years from application to finally getting the certificate, during which the production lines were idle. The economic investment of the enterprise has not been maximized and time has been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that under the MAH system, companies can share production lines, &quot;which can reduce costs, improve utilization, and release huge dividends.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 5, 2018, Shanghai The Food and Drug Administration issued an announcement &quot;Expanding the pilot reform of the city&#39;s medical device registrant system to the entire city.&quot; Starting from June 1, 2021, the revised &quot;Regulations on the Supervision and Administration of Medical Devices&quot; will be officially implemented, and the medical device registrant system will be fully implemented across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Haixia also suggested that the whitelist system for biomedical research and development supplies and special imported items should be further promoted and improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that as &quot;raw materials&quot; for biomedical research and development, special items such as microorganisms, human tissues, biological products, blood and their products have been planned to be imported in recent years with the development of the industry. However, special items may carry risks of various infectious diseases, and Shanghai Port is extremely cautious about related imports and exports. The rapid development of the biomedical industry has put forward higher demands for rapid customs clearance of special items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant systems will be gradually implemented in Shanghai starting from 2020, but there are still few open parts. It is hoped that the free trade zone can accelerate the implementation of this system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Make full use of the legislative power of Pudong New Area&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with other free trade pilot zones, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone was established the earliest, and Pudong The new district has the unique advantage of “legislative power”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 10, 2021, the 29th meeting of the Standing Committee of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress voted and adopted the &quot;Decision on Authorizing the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee to formulate regulations for the Pudong New Area&quot;. Authorize the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee to formulate Pudong New Area regulations based on the practical needs of Pudong&#39;s reform and innovation, in compliance with the provisions of the Constitution and basic legal and administrative rules, and implement them in Pudong New Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This unique advantage played an important role when Hongming participated in an institutional innovation in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Hongming and the Pudong Integrated Circuit Industry Association reported that the company&#39;s application for exemption from compulsory product certification (i.e. &quot;CCC exemption&quot;) took a long time, resulting in the failure of equipment parts to be delivered to semiconductors in time. Problems with the production plant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem Hongming encountered at that time was that the normal CCC exemption required about 2 working days to be issued, but the supply chain after-sales maintenance service needed to be provided 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. The support of the original policy was not enough It can no longer meet industrial needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bai Li raised a pen and made several gestures on the table. &quot;For example, a fuse is very small, but once it blows, the entire machine stops.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, traditional CCC exemptions are for upstream and downstream enterprises in the industry, and the supply chain companies themselves do not have development applications. permissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baili believes that supply chain companies as chain owners are not only familiar with goods and products, but also have the clearest understanding of the flow of the entire supply chain. If the main unit of the innovation chain can apply, the supervision will be upgraded from point supervision to chain supervision, and the entire flow of goods will be clearly visible where it comes from and where it goes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the promotion of Pudong Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, Hongming took the lead in piloting the convenient channel for CCC exemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main contents of the pilot include allowing rapid certification through &quot;self-declaration, automatic certification, and integrity supervision&quot;; through process reengineering, the 5-working-day manual approval will be transformed into a &quot;zero-wait&quot; automatic system Release. At the same time, the restriction that logistics trading enterprises cannot be the subject of CCC exemption applications has been broken, expanding the scope of CCC exemption subjects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2022, Hongming and regulatory authorities will continue to improve processes and systems. &quot;By 2023, companies and associations feel that they can combine the legislative power of Pudong New Area to fix the pilot policies and promote them.&quot; Bai Li said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1, 2023, the country&#39;s first CCC exemption management measure &quot;Several Provisions on Exemption from Compulsory Product Certification in Pudong New Area, Shanghai&quot; was officially implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Pudong Market Supervision Bureau described that one of the main innovations in the management measures is that according to relevant regulations, logistics trading companies cannot be the applicant for CCC exemption. With the approval and authorization from the General Administration of Pudong, supply chain enterprises that clearly provide services to key industries can be applicants for CCC exemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the fourth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 16th Shanghai Municipal People’s Congress held on July 24, 2023, the Municipal Development and Reform Commission mentioned that it would take the opportunity to make full use of the Pudong New Area’s legislative power to base itself on its own Based on the practical needs of reform and innovation in the Pilot Trade Zone and Lingang New Area, we will study and formulate a number of policies and measures in terms of strengthening the innovation engine, high-level institutional opening, reform system integration, and urban governance modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Innovative intellectual property protection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Promoting institutional innovation in the field of intellectual property is also the first step for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to align with international high-standard economic and trade rules such as CPTPP and DEPA. important aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 10th anniversary press conference of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone held by the Shanghai Municipal Government on September 15, Shen Weihua, deputy director of the Municipal Commerce Commission, said that the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is under the guidance of the Ministry of Commerce and other national ministries and commissions. and support, focus on the provisions of post-border management systems such as trade in goods, trade in services, digital trade, intellectual property rights, and government procurement in CPTPP and DEPA, and study reform measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Chao, Executive Deputy Director of Pudong New Area, introduced at the press conference that in the 10 years since the construction of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, a high-level intellectual property protection system has been improved, including the implementation of rapid patent pre-examination, patent implementation investigation, etc. &quot; &quot;Quick Protection&quot; system, shortening the invention patent authorization cycle from 3 years to 3 months, exploring the implementation of a punitive compensation system for intellectual property infringement, and taking the lead in building an international intellectual property protection highland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2021, the Shanghai Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Rights Protection Mutual Aid Fund was launched. This is the country’s first market-oriented intellectual property rights protection mutual aid fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the Lingang Market Supervision Bureau took the lead in establishing the non-profit social organization &quot;Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Exchange Promotion Center&quot; and used the center as a platform to operate funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Zhenhua, director of the Lingang New Area Intellectual Property Exchange and Promotion Center, told Southern Weekend reporters that the fund was launched in the Lingang New Area mainly because the new area has institutional innovation soil, coupled with the agglomeration of cutting-edge technologies and key industries. There is a need for intellectual property protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他指出，随着新片区企业参与国际经济贸易程度的深入，面临的国际知识产权竞争愈发激烈，许多企业由于在人才、资金、信息等方面基础薄弱，在国际竞争中往往处于劣势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在此背景下，基金的落地完善了临港新片区多元化知识产权维权体系，有助于在临港新片区形成长效的市场化运作维权互助机制，为产业创新发展保驾护航。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前基金成员单位达到近180家，覆盖临港新片区重点产业领域，资金规模近130万。 2022年启动了基金扩充计划，根据理事会年费管理办法进行管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，所谓市场化，就是在政府引导下，坚持企业“自发组织、自主管理、自治运营”，基金的募集、管理、使用等都通过市场化机制解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为全国首创，基金没有成熟的经验可供借鉴。冯振华说，遇到问题、调查研究、解决问题，这个循环一直伴随着基金成立和运行的整个过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“临港新片区企业的真实需求就成为了基金成立的最重要标准。”该中心介绍，筹备小组在密集调研了近50家企业后，确定了基金成立和运行的基本思路，即“公益性与市场化相结合，知识产权与重点产业相链接，体系建设与纠纷应对相平衡”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立以来，基金帮助临港新片区企业成功应对知识产权纠纷并提供维权资金支持案例2起，提前介入知识产权纠纷提供咨询超过15次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临港新片区一家从事创新型医疗器械研发和生产的公司在上市过程中，遭遇了全球医疗器械行业巨头的专利狙击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，除了企业自身积极应对之外，基金发挥了重要的维权援助功能，协调多方专家智库资源予以纠纷应对指导，提供维权资金支持，同时也为公司提供知识产权咨询，帮助其进一步完善知识产权布局，降低经营风险，最终在专利无效案中胜诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冯振华看来，未来自贸试验区在知识产权方面还可以关注以下问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是让企业了解国际经贸规则，提前做好准备以便应对潜在的知识产权风险；二是主动融入国际高标准经贸规则体系，甚至通过先试先行探索经验来影响经贸规则；三是平衡中国技术创新和产业发展与国际规则中知识产权相关规定适用的关系；四是关注新技术、新业态为知识产权相关规则适用带来的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大胆试、大胆闯、自主改&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月18日，南方周末记者在沃尔沃建筑设备的仓库里看到一台大型的绿色的再制造发动机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在场的工作人员介绍，这台发动机是全国首单“重点行业再制造产品进口试点”货物，是公司向瑞典订购的，于9月1日抵达仓库，后续将交付客户用于售后。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了让货物快速到达工厂，浦东海关提供了门到门查检服务。现场查检主要是确保单货相符，以及进口机器设备的相关参数、性能等是否与申报内容相符，确保商品既通得快、走得顺，又管得住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，中国在政策层面对进口再制造产品按照旧机电产品进行管理。 “如一缔约方采取或维持措施禁止或限制旧货的进口，则该缔约方不得将这些措施适用于再制造货物。”詹旭现场念了一段CPTPP关于再制造产品的内容。他表示，从国际规则来看，再制造产品是允许进口的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6月1日，国务院印发《关于在有条件的自由贸易试验区和自由贸易港试点对接国际高标准推进制度型开放的若干措施》，第一条就是“支持试点地区开展重点行业再制造产品进口试点”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在詹旭看来，这次针对再制造产品的制度创新产生了多赢的结果。企业拓宽了业务空间，自贸区增加了贸易种类，同时与国际高标准规则接轨。此外，对打通国内国际双循环，达成低碳减排目标等也有重要意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了保障首单试点进口货物顺利通关，上海海关提前介入，全程参与，研究制定了专项监管方案和应急预案。由企业所属地浦东海关负责联系企业，做好企业的事前指导、再制造产品的通关监管等工作，通过专窗受理申报、“门到门”查检等服务措施，确保重点行业再制造产品进口高效、安全通关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么叫做制度创新？因为这个改变不是领导批个条子，而是要讲出个所以然，要大家坐下来研究。”詹旭说，改变这条规则涉及哪些部门、各自要做出怎样的变化、规则改变后的监管和推广要怎么处理等问题都要研究清楚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年来，詹旭对自贸区的理解也在发生变化。他最初觉得，自贸试验区是在上海出台税收优惠等方面的政策。过了一段时间，他开始理解，设立自贸试验区不是在一个地方搞特殊化，而是针对一些特殊的问题进行试点，然后全面铺开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其实原来没想到那么宏大的层面。过去觉得，自贸试验区是不是在解决招商引资的问题？后来我慢慢体会到，自贸试验区是要对接国际标准，把解决方案放在国际视野去综合考虑。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“浦东发布”介绍，上海自贸试验区提早谋划落实上述《若干措施》试点任务，目前已取得了积极进展，初步形成了一批制度创新成果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了率先开展再制造产品进口试点，成果还包括持续优化金融创新业务审批服务，瑞士再保险集团子公司瑞再企商保险申请增资支持个人保险业务拓展，10日内即获批准等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月30日，上海市委副书记、市长龚正在中国（上海）自由贸易试验区推进工作领导小组会议上说，“十年来，上海自贸试验区大胆试、大胆闯、自主改，充分发挥了开路先锋、示范引领、突破攻坚的作用，彰显了全市经济增长极和发动机作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来，要更好发挥高水平改革开放&#39;试验田&#39;作用，在制度创新上取得更大突破。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会：赛场内外，同样精彩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257774]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of 17:00 on September 27, 2023, the Chinese delegation It is far ahead in the medal list of the Hangzhou Asian Games, with a total of 124 medals, including 69 gold medals, 39 silver medals, and 16 bronze medals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Li Bingjie, who won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final, showed her medal.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final championship Li Bingjie displays her medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will be held from September 23 to October 8, 2023, with a total of 15 competition days. The competition events of this Asian Games include 40 major events, 61 sub-events, and 481 minor events. It is the Asian Games with the largest number of events. It is worth noting that non-Olympic events, as the distinguishing mark of the Asian Games from the Olympic Games, mostly originate from traditional folk sports activities and have a deep public base and strong regional characteristics. This Asian Games has added new non-Olympic sports such as skateboarding, break dancing, and e-sports, which not only increases the enjoyment of the games, but also demonstrates the diversity and inclusiveness of Asian sports culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the e-sports events of the Hangzhou Asian Games kicked off at the Hangzhou E-sports Center in China.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports events The tournament kicked off at the Hangzhou E-Sports Center in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind every game and every medal is the sweat and hard work of the players. The Hangzhou Asian Games brought unlimited passion to the Asian region and demonstrated the elegance of Asian sports on a global scale. However, the Asian Games is not just about the medals, it is also exciting both inside and outside the stadium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 22, 2023, the Hong Kong, China delegation attended the welcome and flag-raising ceremony and officially stationed in the Asian Games Village in Hangzhou.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, the Hong Kong delegation from China attended Welcome and flag-raising ceremony, officially stationed in Hangzhou Asian Games Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 22, 2023, Fok Qigang, head of the Hong Kong Asian Games delegation, accepted media interviews at the welcome and flag-raising ceremony.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On September 22, 2023, Fok Qigang, head of the Hong Kong Asian Games delegation, was interviewed by the media at the welcome and flag-raising ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the host Chinese delegation entered the venue to the music of &quot;Singing the Motherland&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 23, 2023, the host Chinese delegation Enter the stage to the music of &quot;Singing the Motherland&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Hangzhou Asian Games is the second international sports event held by China after the Chengdu Universiade. It is also an important window to showcase China&#39;s image in the new era. Like the Chengdu Universiade, domestic and foreign sports audiences can enter the venues and watch the fierce competitive events at close range. Swimming, basketball, table tennis, etc. are the most popular sports in the first week of the competition. Southern Weekend reporters saw at the venue that many enthusiastic spectators would arrive at the ticket gate two or three hours in advance to wait for admission. On the Internet, discussions about athletes&#39; competitive skills, figures, and even appearance and temperament remain high among Asian Games-related categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 20, 2023, an Asian Games-themed light show will be staged every night on the Qiantang River.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every night there is an Asian Games themed light show on the Qiantang River. The picture was taken on September 20, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, a fan of swimmer Wang Shun displayed a poster of her cheering for Wang Shun at the swimming pool.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 24, 2023 , a fan of swimmer Wang Shun displayed a poster of her cheering for Wang Shun at the swimming pool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, the Asian Games swimming events were held fiercely in the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, the Asian Games swimming event was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center The central swimming pool is in full swing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the host city of the 19th Asian Games, Hangzhou has also done its best to let athletes and spectators from afar feel the enthusiasm of the organizers. The Asian Games-themed light show on the banks of the Qiantang River lights up on time every night, attracting many tourists to watch. The overall environment, accommodation conditions and food arrangements of the Asian Games Village were praised by the athletes and Asian Games technical officials. The canteen of the media center was also praised by foreign media workers during the live broadcast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Uzbek veteran Chusovitina saluted the audience with her right hand touching her heart after completing the vault.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Uzbekistan veteran Chusovitina saluted the audience with her right hand touching her heart after completing the vault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Imaddin, a media person from Saudi Arabia, said that the only regret of this Asian Games is that &quot;seeing that October 8 is the closing ceremony, the day of the Asian Games It ended too soon.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 26, 2023, players from the Chinese table tennis men&#39;s team and the Korean team were interviewed by the media after the game.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 26, 2019, players from the Chinese men&#39;s table tennis team and the Korean team were interviewed by the media after the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“三星堆”在香港]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 22:34:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[多家企业放弃，森林碳汇为何不香了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/UBXtPOqKCGqqORVOY0LYq9xP53SFURKTDpdBA5nv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;869&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/UBXtPOqKCGqqORVOY0LYq9xP53SFURKTDpdBA5nv . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Purchasing forest carbon offsets was once a &quot;fast lane&quot; for companies to achieve their carbon neutrality goals. However, many companies have recently announced that they will abandon this approach and focus more on their own carbon emission reductions. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nongjian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Forests are no longer humans&#39; friends in reducing carbon emissions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early September 2023, the famous American climate reporter David Wallace Wells lamented in a commentary article about forest fires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wildfires that are raging across Canada this summer are burning not only forests, but also the forest carbon offset projects behind them. Along with the thick black smoke, the carbon collected through photosynthesis is released, turning the forest into a huge carbon source. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The forest carbon offset project is an important carbon credit. By purchasing carbon credits to offset one&#39;s own carbon emissions, it was once a &quot;fast lane&quot; for companies to achieve their carbon neutrality goals, and was especially popular among households &quot;difficult to reduce emissions.&quot; Such as the petroleum industry, aviation industry, etc. However, in recent years, carbon offset projects, especially forestry carbon offset projects, have been increasingly questioned and even accused of &quot;greenwashing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, the international oil company Shell announced that it would abandon its US$100 million annual carbon offset plan because the current &quot;carbon offset&quot; projects failed to meet the company&#39;s quality standards. Bloomberg New Energy Finance pointed out in its &quot;Long-term Carbon Offset Outlook&quot; report that due to concerns about reputational risks from purchasing low-quality carbon credits, globally, corporate carbon offset quotas will drop by 4% in 2022 compared with 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are forest carbon offset projects becoming less popular? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Carbon dioxide is not a “first-class, first-class” exchange relationship&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The fundamental reason for the doubt lies in the limitations of the forest’s “emission reduction principle”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The carbon dioxide absorbed by forestry carbon sinks and the carbon dioxide emitted into the atmosphere from fossil fuel burning are not in a &quot;one-to-one&quot; interchange relationship. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) specifically distinguishes between two &quot;carbon cycle&quot; models: the long carbon cycle (or slow carbon cycle) and the short carbon cycle (or fast carbon cycle). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The carbon in the long carbon cycle is mainly stored in the lithosphere, that is, in fossil fuels that have been fixed over millions of years. If this part of carbon is not mined and burned, it generally does not participate in the carbon cycle in the atmosphere. Because the process of storing carbon compounds underground is slow, the &quot;long carbon cycle&quot; may take thousands to tens of thousands of years to complete a cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carbon in the short carbon cycle is stored in vegetation and soil. The cycle of carbon is short, and the time depends on the lifespan of the plant, usually within 100 years: plants absorb carbon dioxide through photosynthesis - the plant dies or is destroyed by animals. , fungi or microorganisms decompose – the carbon is returned to the atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;short carbon cycle&quot; and the &quot;long carbon cycle&quot; in nature rarely overlap and do not overlap. Using &quot;tree planting to absorb carbon&quot; to absorb the carbon released through the extraction and burning of fossil fuels is an artificial equal replacement between the two systems, which does not comply with mathematical logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The principle of carbon absorption by planting trees is photosynthesis, but it is worth noting that only forests in the growth stage have strong carbon absorption capabilities. After trees gradually grow into old trees, their metabolism slows down and even dies. will no longer apply to carbon sequestration projects. Therefore, the general cycle of afforestation carbon sink projects is 20-60 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the carbon sink during this period was also unstable. During the growth period of trees, forests may be damaged or even die due to pests, diseases, fires, or logging, and the forest will transform from a &quot;carbon sink&quot; to a &quot;carbon source.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most prominent issue is the wildfire problem. Since 2015, wildfires in California, USA, have destroyed six forest carbon offset projects and released 5.7 million to 6.8 million tons of carbon dioxide back into the atmosphere. In the 2021 fires, forest offset projects purchased by Microsoft and BP were also burned, putting a lot of pressure on the company&#39;s &quot;climate performance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, a research result published in the magazine &quot;Nature&quot; even showed that under the dual impact of logging and forest fires, the tropical rainforest in the southeastern Amazon has become a carbon source and is no longer a source of carbon. exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of global warming, the risk of wildfires in forestry carbon sink projects has further increased. Analysis by WRI shows that the global forest fire rate has almost doubled over the past 20 years. The United Nations Environment Program predicted earlier in 2023 that the number of extreme wildfires worldwide would increase by 30% by 2050 and by 50% by the end of the century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if people can ensure that the forest carbon sink project will not be interrupted, there may not be so much land in the world. Switzerland, for example, recently struck carbon offset deals with Peru and Ghana, and even a country as small as Switzerland would likely require an area nearly equivalent to the entire island of Puerto Rico to grow trees. The four major oil and gas companies - BP, Eni, Shell and Total Energy - will need to plant trees on an area more than twice the size of the UK if they are to achieve their 2050 net zero target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An Oxfam report estimates that achieving the carbon reductions companies are committing to today would require an area roughly five times the size of India and more than all farmland on Earth combined. Similarly, another &quot;Land Gap&quot; report (Land Gap) released in 2022 by a total of 20 scientists from many countries showed that to achieve the climate commitments of various governments, an area equivalent to four Indias is required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large amounts of land required may also trigger negative impacts on ecosystems. The IPCC’s land use report states that “Afforestation activities may exacerbate risks to biodiversity, water and food security if deployed on naturally forest-free land.” Recently, it was reported that a bluecarbon company based in Dubai, United Arab Emirates, would purchase 10% of Liberia&#39;s land to develop carbon offset projects, triggering international concerns about the livelihood of local residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some companies have realized the risks of carbon offset projects and have pledged to abandon this path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2022, EasyJet, the British airline, was the first company to announce that it would abandon its carbon offset plan and announced that it would increase investment and develop direct emission reduction technologies, such as developing hydrogen fuel and optimizing operating efficiency. EasyJet said it expects these direct emission reduction technologies to reduce the company&#39;s carbon emissions by 78% by 2050, while the remaining 22% of carbon emissions will rely on carbon capture technology. In June 2023, France&#39;s Nestlé announced that it would no longer use carbon offsets to achieve the company&#39;s carbon neutrality goal and would &quot;commit to investing in projects that can truly bring emission reductions to the supply chain and operations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Protect forests and benefit local people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment reviewed and approved the &quot;Greenhouse Gas Voluntary Emission Reduction Trading Management&quot; Measures (Trial)&quot; means that the national voluntary greenhouse gas emission reduction trading market is about to restart, which also includes projects such as forestry carbon sinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since mid-2022, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has made a series of statements regarding the CCER (China Certified Voluntary Emission Reduction) project, indicating that the restart button has been pressed on CCER approval, which has also triggered domestic carbon emissions reductions. Credit development. Forestry carbon sinks have shown explosive growth in the past year. Since February 2023, at least 30 forestry carbon sink projects have been implemented. Many companies have made plans in advance and signed contracts with local forestry companies in areas rich in forestry resources to develop forest land into carbon sinks, hoping that once CCER is restarted, transactions can be carried out (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/230498&quot; title=&quot;&quot;Air can also be sold for money&quot;: overheated forestry carbon sink&quot;>;&quot;Air can also be sold Selling money”: overheating forestry carbon sink&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long run, whether the forest carbon sink has achieved &quot;additional&quot; emission reduction effects, ensured the durability of the carbon reduction effect, and can withstand third-party verification is still a core issue. The low-carbon think tank Yike Dual Carbon Center recently released a report &quot;It&#39;s an Opportunity and a Risk. What Does Carbon Offsetting Mean to Enterprises?&quot; 》Provides suggestions on how companies should choose appropriate carbon offset projects: try to protect intact or basically intact forests, with the main task of protecting forestlands and surrounding biodiversity and ecosystems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the new version of the CCER methodology, updated provisions are also made for the emission reduction verification, approval and verification agencies of forest carbon sequestration projects, placing more emphasis on the verifiable attributes of the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the authors of the aforementioned &quot;Land Gap&quot; report also mentioned that the focus of forest carbon credit development should be on preventing the felling of ancient, virgin forests and benefiting local residents and communities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the topic of abandoning forest carbon offsets is a protracted debate about &quot;Carbon Dioxide Remove (CDR)&quot;. CDR includes measures to remove carbon dioxide from the atmosphere in a broad sense. At this stage, it mainly refers to traditional methods such as forest carbon sinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, CDR technology may be expanded to capture carbon directly from the air and store it long-term on land, oceans or caves. In its latest Sixth Assessment Report, the IPCC made policy recommendations on CDR for the first time, believing that if the goal of controlling global warming to 1.5°C is to be achieved, large-scale CDR applications will be inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But CDR technology other than “planting trees” is even more controversial. Therefore, the IPCC also emphasizes that any carbon removal method cannot replace deep emission reduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[双节有奖征集丨归与游，我的城市印记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:58:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival meets the National Day, which is another double festival of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rare double holiday allows us to go home for reunion and travel together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From small towns in rural counties to bustling cities, from hometowns to tourist destinations;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They have all left you with unforgettable memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it the lake where you hung out as a child? Or the street shop you often visit after get off work? Or is it an unforgettable street scene while traveling? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Participate in the double-section discussion and share your city imprint with us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have prepared for you &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekly Cultural and Creative &quot;One Moon&quot; Mid-Autumn Festival gift box, &quot;Presence&quot; T-shirt, Southern Weekend APP membership&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; and other peripheral gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Leave a message in the comment area to get a chance to win the lottery, &lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com/iJC2nEr1/&quot;>; Click here to enter the draw now&lt;/a>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to get lucky draw opportunities? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1. Post a comment in the comment area below during the event to get 1 lucky draw opportunity (once a day) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2. High-quality user comments that are selected and displayed will receive 1 lucky draw opportunity (each selected comment Updated daily)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;3. Participate in the double-day sign-in event on the APP and you can also get lucky draw opportunities and sign-in activities Time: September 29th to October 6th&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;4. Share &lt;a href=&quot;https ://h5s.infzm.com/iJC2nEr1/&quot;>;Lottery activity page&lt;/a>;You can get 1 lucky draw opportunity (once per day)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[民政部派出调查组对中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会开展全面调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257780]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:30:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to reports from the masses and media reports, the &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Relief Project&quot; of the China Children&#39;s Charity Relief Foundation &quot; and other related issues, the Ministry of Civil Affairs attaches great importance to it and urges the China Children&#39;s Charity Aid Foundation to take its responsibilities and safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the families involved in accordance with the law and regulations. Recently, the Ministry of Civil Affairs has dispatched an investigation team to the foundation to conduct a comprehensive investigation and resolutely investigate and correct violations of laws and regulations. The investigation and handling status will be announced to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运电竞首金的夜晚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257770]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of September 26, 2023, at the Hangzhou E-sports Center, the first gold medal in the e-sports event of the Asian Games is about to be Birth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/l55WaYzpvo4oY49Bk4ggdvshvJ6j6U1gU216Ynp2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/l55WaYzpvo4oY49Bk4ggdvshvJ6j6U1gU216Ynp2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yang Yiqing was interviewed by the media while holding a banner to support the players&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Afternoon 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;6&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;00&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are still 3 hours left before the game, and the media box is already half full , everyone knows what this gold medal means - the first gold medal in the Asian Games e-sports event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There seems to be no suspense about the outcome of the competition. Since the Honor of Kings World Champions Cup was held in 2019, no team outside China has won the championship. Experienced reporters come to the scene not to watch the game, but to see the status of the players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of a reporter from an e-sports magazine, among the seven e-sports events in the Asian Games, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; is not very competitive, but it has the largest number of domestic players among the seven events. The most well-known game was the first to reach the finals in the schedule, so this game has a deeper historical significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games, the Chinese team won the championship in the &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; event, but it was an exhibition match. Today&#39;s gold medal is legal.&quot; Two-time Asian Games winner The gap is reflected in his experience. In 2018, he could not go through the media channel, but this year he can. &quot;It&#39;s just a different channel, but the feeling in his heart is different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mtxJzBlptUba9tQDzUY2CxCjyQJtOJtAGhyJVYRV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mtxJzBlptUba9tQDzUY2CxCjyQJtOJtAGhyJVYRV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 26, 2020, in the final of the Asian Games version of the e-sports e-sports King of Glory in Hangzhou, Chinese team player Luo Siyuan (middle) competed in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Hta0j2IyEs9mbBDeSefhhvw88OzzOuJ2YaogipQK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Hta0j2IyEs9mbBDeSefhhvw88OzzOuJ2YaogipQK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports King of Glory Asian Games version finals, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team 2-0 and won the championship&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1pm&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;7&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;00&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Inside the venue, the rehearsal for the finals has begun. Outside the venue, the official licensed merchandise retail store of the Hangzhou E-Sports Center is taking final orders before the audience enters. In addition to mascot items like other projects, souvenirs surrounding e-sports projects also include categories co-branded with game IPs, which “sell out very quickly.” When faced with the question of why there are so few e-sports souvenirs in e-sports venues, the young The counterman replied, &quot;Mascot badges are basically hard to buy. There are hundreds of them a day and they are sold out in the morning. The popular character badges were sold out two days ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prepare for the finals, the warehouse I urgently restocked the goods the night before and replenished a batch of souvenirs through all the channels I could find, including the Gongsunli badges of &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; that had already been sold out, but I couldn&#39;t wait for the final audience to enter. &quot;Before the third place match in the afternoon. It’s all sold out.” Brother Cabinet’s tone was filled with regret, “We are not fully mentally prepared.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are not many e-sports peripherals left for the final audience, “The badges are sold out, the magnetic books The irons are sold out, the keychains are sold out, the card sets of Li Bai and Shangguan Wan&#39;er are sold out, and Gongsunli&#39;s are sold out. This character is very popular, and there are only two of her bookmarks left.&quot; The cabinet brother thinks they belong to the contestants. Hobbies drive consumption. He heard from the audience that the character commonly used by contestant Xu Bicheng (ID: Yinuo) is Gongsun Li. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Brother Cabinet’s job is to sell goods, he was also puzzled by the purchasing power of the audience. He opened the stationery gift box on the shelf nearby, “The gift box contains 4 items, notebook, pen, Exclusive bookmarks and sticky notes are priced at 208 yuan. I thought no one would buy them at first, but they have almost sold out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/cD1FMIJlvjfDI1M24YTRNBk6a04y1YojTNWhkdRM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;724&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/27/cD1FMIJlvjfDI1M24YTRNBk6a04y1YojTNWhkdRM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games Electronics The final of the Asian Games version of Honor of Kings, players from the Chinese team (right) and the Malaysian team in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;PM 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;7&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;30&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The audience is about to enter. Without enough time to wait for the store manager&#39;s reply, another counter girl in the franchise store went to the warehouse and moved the remaining seal keychains, which belonged to the characters Da Qiao and Xiao Qiao. As soon as they were put on the shelves, a male spectator took away all the three Daqiao keychains. Seeing this, the counter girl stuffed the Xiaoqiao keychains she wanted to put on the shelf back into the box, &quot;Hide some first, otherwise there will be no more.&quot; Things are sold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More spectators crowded into the hall at the entrance. Seven cosplay game character actors were invited to stand in the center of the hall for a group photo. People waiting for the group photo volunteered at the venue. There was a long queue behind the audience, and almost every audience member who came through the door stopped to identify the characters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gathered crowd made it easy for media reporters to find the people they wanted to interview. A media from Hubei wanted to interview fans of the Wuhan eStarPro team. Two players from this team were selected for the national team, namely Luo Siyuan (ID: Huahai) and Sun Linwei (ID: Tanran). Young girl Yang Yiqing was chosen as the interviewee from the crowd. She was easily identifiable as she was wearing the uniform of the eStarPro team and carrying a bag of support materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the camera, Yang Yiqing enthusiastically praised the positive value of the players, &quot;I want to say something about Luo Siyuan. He has taken on the responsibility of captain and has always been very responsible, very determined, and very diligent in training.&quot; , led the team members to help the team win so many championships, I think they represent the spirit of perseverance and hard work.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eStarPro team has won 8 championships in previous competitive competitions. Regarding tonight&#39;s championship, the mentality of fans is much better than that of the media. Yang Yiqing said: &quot;Player Sun Linwei has just celebrated his 20th birthday. I am also here to wish him the first gold medal at the age of 20.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The support materials brought by Yang Yiqing include banners and small flags, which are spontaneously produced by the players or their team&#39;s fan clubs. A few days before the finals, each support club chose to distribute the materials at the Intime Department Store at the intersection away from the e-sports center. The materials with the personal photos of the players were to express their stance, and all the players of the national team were printed to show the pattern. The biggest one is Xu Bicheng’s (ID: Yinuo) Zebra Paradise Support Club. They set up a display area directly in the atrium on the first floor of the shopping mall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the game started, each company’s support materials competed in a round. When the venue’s cameras scanned the auditorium, the fans held up their banners high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/sBFZOTT3mdSIpJs8yAHJQQbm0uApeUfFLuBic1qZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/sBFZOTT3mdSIpJs8yAHJQQbm0uApeUfFLuBic1qZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;E-sports souvenir shelves in Hangzhou E-sports Center&#39;s licensed merchandise retail store&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Yangxin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;In the evening 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;8&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;30&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The auditorium is filling up one after another , the warm-up music before the game was played loudly on the field, and the DJ chose a RAP version of &quot;Good Luck&quot;. In fact, the spectators who can come to the game are very lucky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tickets for the Asian Games e-sports events will go on sale on August 14, 2023. It is the only event where ticket purchase qualifications are determined by drawing lots, and it is also the most expensive event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no statistical data on the winning rate of single-game tickets, but according to the official blog of the Hangzhou Asian Organizing Committee, there are at least 5 million users who apply to purchase tickets for e-sports events, and the maximum number of spectators for each game is no more than 4,000 people. Among them, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot;, &quot;League of Legends&quot; and &quot;Dota2&quot; are particularly popular. On September 23, the official ticket purchase system released some tickets again, and the tickets for these three projects were almost sold out in seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/dcoHGEW6YFq4faY2Qrf8rKvKsntTDWLjJTae8Xbu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/dcoHGEW6YFq4faY2Qrf8rKvKsntTDWLjJTae8Xbu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hangzhou E-sports Center licensed merchandise retail store, spectators waiting for the replenishment of e-sports souvenirs&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Yangxin/Picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Night&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;19&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;47&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Live broadcast , the just-concluded 19th Asian Games Hangzhou Honor of Kings Asian Games version finals, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team and won the Honor of Kings Asian Games version championship, winning the first gold medal in e-sports. It was also the Chinese sports team’s first victory in this Asian Games. The 48th gold medal won. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final between the Chinese team and the Malaysian team lasted two rounds, and each round was won with an absolute advantage, taking about 15 minutes each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the award ceremony, the faces of several Chinese contestants appeared on the big screen one by one, with tears faintly flashing. When the emcee picked up the medal and hung it up for Lin Heng (ID: Nuanyang), Chi Xiaoming (ID: Ming) next to him lowered his head in misunderstanding, then stood up quickly, revealing a trace of his nervousness. Xu Bicheng also showed nervousness. Facing the cheers of the audience, he raised his right hand and scratched his head unconsciously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After exiting, the six contestants passed through the mixed interview area. The long passage was filled with reporters and volunteers. A small blackboard was erected at the media entrance, &quot;The mixed interview area is full.&quot; Several young people who had just won the award dispersed and expressed their excitement at the moment to the microphones and cameras swarming in front of them. Jiang Tao (ID: Adou) finished his speech and was about to leave when he was stopped by a bunch of voices. Dozens of reporters immediately surrounded the place where he stopped. Only the one with the loudest voice could get the right to ask questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last question was grabbed by a female reporter: &quot;What do you want to say to our audience?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I did it, and I believe you can do it too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After saying this, Adou walked towards the exit accompanied by the team manager. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[减持“新规”从严落实！沪深交易所进一步明确破发、破净、分红不达标条件]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257772]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 19:37:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the China Securities Regulatory Commission launched the &quot;new regulations&quot; on shareholding reduction, the market is in urgent need of detailed rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued relevant notices clarifying some of the constraints in the new regulations on shareholding reduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission’s requirements for share reductions on August 27 show that controlling shareholders and actual controllers of companies whose shares are broken, broken, or whose dividends do not meet the target are not allowed to reduce their shareholdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the requirements were issued, many listed companies announced the early termination of their shareholding reduction plans. Taking the Shanghai Stock Exchange as an example, the controlling shareholders, actual controllers, directors, supervisors, and senior executives of 35 companies terminated their shareholding reduction plans in advance, and the &quot;key minority&quot; personnel of 18 companies voluntarily promised not to reduce their shareholdings in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the market has also raised through various channels a series of implementation standards issues such as how to judge relevant conditions and what methods to limit shareholding reduction. To this end, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges have conducted systematic and in-depth research to refine relevant implementation standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice issued by the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges clarified the standards for breaking the issue, breaking the net or failing to pay dividends, clarifying the scope of the secondary market holding reduction, clarifying whether the conditions are met during pre-disclosure, etc., responded to market concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;You can reduce your holdings only if you cannot break the stock price or break the net price for 20 consecutive days&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As we all know, a stock price break means the stock price is lower than the issue price when it was first issued. To avoid artificial manipulation, a break here means that the closing price of the stock on any of the 20 trading days before the announcement of the shareholding reduction plan is lower than the stock issuance price at the time of the initial public offering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the Shanghai and Shenzhen exchanges require that the stock price does not break for 20 consecutive trading days before they can reduce their holdings. This article is applicable to the controlling shareholders, actual controllers and persons acting in concert at the time of the initial public offering of the listed company; if the issuer discloses that it has no controlling shareholder or actual controller, it applies to the largest shareholder at the time of the initial public offering. and its actual controllers and persons acting in concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Net-breaking means that the stock price is lower than the net assets per share. The notice shows that the so-called net loss here refers to the closing price of the stock on any of the 20 trading days before the announcement of the shareholding reduction plan is lower than the net assets per share at the end of the most recent fiscal year or the most recent financial accounting report period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Senior market insiders pointed out, “In order to improve the accuracy and timeliness of judgment, two comparison benchmarks are set (for the net breaking situation), namely the latest financial report and the audited annual report for the most recent year. , the holdings can be reduced only if the net is not broken. Same as the break, twenty trading days are also selected, and the holding can be reduced only if the net is not broken.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to ensure the comparability of prices, the net is broken and the net is broken. All adopt the backward re-weighting calculation method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market participant said, &quot;This notice strictly identifies the circumstances in which holdings cannot be reduced. For example, for breaking the stock and breaking the net, it is not simply that the stock is not broken or the net is not broken on a certain day as the conditions for reduction, but It is required to not break the stock price or net profit for 20 consecutive trading days. This can prevent controlling shareholders and actual controllers from manipulating the stock price to cooperate with the reduction of holdings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Excluding fiscal years with negative net profits&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Dividends that do not meet the standard include two types of situations: one is that there is no dividend for three years; the other is that the accumulated amount of dividends over the three years does not reach 30% of the three-year average annual net profit. The year of judgment is the fiscal year for which the audited annual report is disclosed. It is worth noting that fiscal years in which net profits are negative are not included. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some special circumstances in the calculation of whether dividends meet the standards. For example, if there are losses for three consecutive years but profits are distributed because the accumulated undistributed profits are positive, if according to the natural algorithm, the average annual net profit for three years is negative, a small amount of dividends can meet the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, one or two years in the past three years have been profitable, and the remaining years have suffered losses and the losses have been huge, resulting in a negative average annual net profit in the past three years. According to natural calculations, a small amount of dividends may be appropriate. Achievable standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid such a situation, this time it is stipulated that the loss-making years will be excluded from the calculation standard, and only the dividend amount and average annual net profit of the profitable years will be calculated. According to this standard, if there are losses in the last three years, there are no years that can be calculated, and the standard cannot be met, and the shareholding cannot be reduced; if the cumulative net profit in the last three years is negative, the loss-making years will be eliminated, and the dividends for the remaining profitable years will reach 30%. Only then can we reduce our holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of industry insiders, in fact, the elimination calculation method and standards are more stringent, basically achieving the effect that controlling shareholders and actual controllers of loss-making companies are not allowed to reduce their holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Block transactions are included in the scope of secondary market holding reductions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges pointed out that according to general understanding, the secondary market refers to centralized bidding transactions and block transactions. If other methods of reduction are achieved through the above two methods or are similar to them, they should also be implemented with reference to the same standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This notice also adds pre-disclosure requirements for large transactions. The current holding reduction rules do not force major shareholders to disclose in advance before reducing their holdings in large-scale transactions. In order to prevent controlling shareholders and actual controllers from reducing their holdings through large-scale transactions without meeting the conditions, new rules for large-scale transactions have been added this time. The pre-disclosure obligation requires them to pre-disclose 15 trading days in advance with reference to the regulations on centralized bidding, and to make disclosures during and after the event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysts believe that &quot;this move further improves the transparency of shareholding reduction and facilitates small and medium-sized investors to understand the holding reduction arrangements of controlling shareholders and actual controllers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of disclosure requirements , when the shareholding reduction plan is disclosed in advance during the start-up stage of the shareholding reduction, the controlling shareholder and actual controller should determine whether the conditions that prohibit the shareholding reduction are met. If it is met, it cannot be disclosed; if the conditions for shareholding reduction are met, the shareholding reduction plan can be disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Strengthen supervision of violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What will be done if relevant entities violate relevant regulations? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that exchanges can take self-regulatory measures according to their rules, including self-regulatory measures, disciplinary sanctions, trading restrictions, etc. The China Securities Regulatory Commission may impose administrative penalties or take regulatory measures in accordance with the Securities Law and the Certain Provisions on the Reduction of Shareholdings by Shareholders, Directors, Supervisors and Senior Management of Listed Companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from past cases, the exchange has taken disciplinary actions and restricted trading measures for serious violations. The China Securities Regulatory Commission also imposed severe fines and heavy penalties. For example, Shanghai Yingyi violated pre-disclosure requirements and reduced its holdings of WuXi AppTec shares and was fined 200 million yuan; Yu Fanyi and others violated regulations by reducing their holdings of Wole Home shares, and their illegal gains were confiscated and severely punished. A fine of more than 30 million yuan was imposed; the Shenzhen Stock Exchange issued a notice of criticism and disciplinary sanctions to the shareholders of Xtest Testing on the day they announced the illegal reduction of holdings. The company&#39;s shareholders promised to repurchase the excess reduction of shares and hand over the illegal gains. The relevant measures have been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in recent cases, parties that have illegally reduced their holdings have repurchased the shares that have been illegally reduced. It is expected that stock repurchases will also become one of the important measures to punish violators and will never be allowed. The offender benefits from the violation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, the Shanghai Stock Exchange will further strengthen the supervision of shareholding reduction behaviors: First, it will improve the transparency of information disclosure of shareholding reductions. For pre-disclosure announcements of shareholding reductions, it is required to fully explain whether the conditions for shareholding reductions are met. The second is to strengthen the monitoring of holding reduction behaviors, strengthen transaction supervision, and promptly discover illegal holding reduction behaviors. The third is to do a good job in rule consultation and policy interpretation, and guide listed companies to ensure the first compliance level in the disclosure of information on shareholder reductions; the fourth is to take regulatory measures in a timely manner, and in the case of suspected violations, send letters to inquire, Telephone reminders and other measures will be taken to verify that violations are involved, and disciplinary sanctions will be implemented quickly and strictly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shenzhen Stock Exchange stated that it will also further strengthen supervision work: First, improve the supervision of information disclosure of shareholding reductions. For pre-disclosure announcements of shareholding reductions, it is required to fully explain whether the conditions for shareholding reductions are met. The second is to improve the functions of the shareholding reduction monitoring system, strengthen transaction supervision, and detect violations in a timely manner. The third is to take regulatory measures in a timely manner. For suspected violations, measures such as sending letters to inquire and calling reminders will be adopted as soon as possible to verify that violations are involved, and disciplinary sanctions will be implemented quickly and strictly. maintain behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中共中央政治局召开会议 审议《关于二十届中央第一轮巡视情况的综合报告》 中共中央总书记习近平主持会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257776]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 19:46:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on September 27 to review the &quot;About the First Round of Inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China&quot; Comprehensive Report. Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting held that the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core attaches great importance to inspection work, regards inspections as a strategic institutional arrangement to promote the party&#39;s self-revolution and comprehensively and strictly govern the party, and has made a series of major decisions and arrangements. The first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee adhered to integrity and innovation, promoted the concreteness, precision and normalization of political supervision, and released a clear signal that comprehensive and strict governance of the Party is always on the road, and the Party&#39;s self-revolution is always on the road. Practice has proved that inspections are an effective way to discover and promote solutions to problems, and we must continue to make efforts and advance in depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting pointed out that from the inspection, party building and comprehensive and strict party governance in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance, and sports have been strengthened, and new results have been achieved in various tasks, but there are also some problems. It is necessary to pass on the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere to the end, urge the inspected party organizations, especially the main responsible comrades, to take on their responsibilities, carry out rectifications strictly and practically, and implement the inspection rectification and learning in the new era of Xi Jinping The education on the theme of socialism with Chinese characteristics should be combined to deeply understand the decisive significance of the “two establishments” and resolutely achieve the “two maintenances”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting emphasized that we should take the inspection and rectification as an opportunity to further strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership, urge the inspected party organizations to improve their political positions, conscientiously perform the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Party Central Committee, and continuously enhance the core functions and functions of state-owned enterprises. Core competitiveness, consolidating the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, increasing the efforts of financial enterprises to serve the real economy and national strategies, and promoting high-quality development. It is necessary to coordinate development and security, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, take effective measures to prevent and resolve major risks, and firmly maintain the bottom line of safety. It is necessary to promote the in-depth development of comprehensive and strict party governance, tighten the responsibilities of the party committee (party group) secretary as the first responsible person, the members of the leadership team with &quot;one post and two responsibilities&quot;, and the supervision responsibilities of the discipline inspection and supervision agencies, and highlight the strengthening of the &quot;top leaders&quot; at all levels. We will strengthen the supervision of corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, in-depth rectification of the &quot;four styles&quot;, deepen the use of cases to promote reform and treatment, and promote the integrated promotion of those who do not dare to corrupt, those who cannot corrupt, and those who do not want to corrupt. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. It is necessary to make full use of the inspection results, deepen reforms, improve systems, promote source control, and promote treatment of both symptoms and root causes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other matters were also considered at the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家长花50万为自闭症儿子“经络重构”：业者涉嫌诈骗+非法行医丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257730]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of medical news has attracted attention. According to &quot;Shangguan News&quot;, the three-year-old son of Mr. Wang from Changshu was diagnosed with autism two years ago and has been seeking medical treatment to no avail. In the first half of this year, Mr. Wang came into contact with an organization that claimed to be able to cure autism, and joined a WeChat group with nearly 500 people. There is a &quot;warm atmosphere&quot; in the group, and group members often share successful treatment cases. Over time, Mr. Wang couldn&#39;t help but be moved, so he signed a &quot;Modern Traditional Chinese Medicine Technology Meridian Conditioning Service Agreement&quot; with this organization called &quot;Qiawei&quot; and gritted his teeth and paid 503,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after eight times of &quot;conditioning&quot; from this institution, the child still showed no improvement. He reported this situation in the WeChat group, but was directly kicked out of the group chat. Mr. Wang&#39;s experience is not an isolated case. Another child who purchased &quot;conditioning&quot; services also did not improve. According to media reports, what this institution has done has been suspected of fraud, and its fraud methods have also been packaged in multiple layers. Upon closer inspection, it can be described as a nested &quot;pig-killing plate&quot;, but it is wrapped in seemingly ordinary medical services. In the service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, this organization invented a wonderful and mysterious story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;therapy&quot; called &quot;Meridian Reconstruction&quot; itself is very similar to the Taoist art of &quot;opening up the two meridians of Ren and Du&quot;, and this organization has added another layer of packaging to it: &quot;using clustered pressure wave technology&quot; &quot;Modern technology&quot; filter creates the so-called &quot;integration of diagnostic indicators of Western medicine and syndrome differentiation methods of traditional Chinese medicine&quot;. It looks amazing, but also has some black humor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the treatment details of the &quot;conditioning service&quot;, the staff member held the child&#39;s arm with one hand and held a pistol-like instrument terminal in the other hand, moving it back and forth on the child&#39;s arm. As can be seen in the video, Mr. Wang&#39;s child was quite frightened and impatient during the treatment process. The true efficacy of this &quot;conditioning service&quot; is probably self-evident. The image of the staff holding &quot;pistols&quot; is very reminiscent of the Yuzhang Academy-style &quot;electric shock therapy&quot;. So, how is it different from &quot;science pretends to be magical and technology makes ghosts&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this organization has also played a long-standing quasi-MLM scam, which even includes the method of &quot;killing pigs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Qiawei Health&quot; carefully sets up the rhetoric of &quot;public welfare treatment&quot; and &quot;commercial treatment&quot;, which not only creates an image of &quot;public welfare and charity&quot; on the surface, but also artificially creates &quot;scarcity&quot; anxiety, step by step Inducing Mr. Wang to spend money: Spend money to buy &quot;commercial treatment&quot; so that you don&#39;t have to wait for &quot;public welfare treatment&quot;. At the same time, they also lost no time in letting the &quot;medical care&quot; appear in the group chat and talk about the &quot;miraculous curative effect&quot;, which is very similar to the classic &quot;medical care&quot; scam performed in the movie &quot;I am not the God of Medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Wang, who was eager to treat patients, finally fell under the psychological offensive of &quot;enthusiastic patients&quot;. There were five other families who signed the agreement with Mr. Wang in this scam. The WeChat group chat where you could see various successful cases every day was forcibly disbanded shortly after the payment was made. This method, which is exactly the same as telecommunications fraud, can be called an alternative &quot;pig-killing plate&quot;, but the target has changed from &quot;investment/marriage&quot; to medical services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 266 of the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that whoever defrauds public or private property, if the amount is particularly huge or there are other particularly serious circumstances, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than ten years or life imprisonment, and shall also be fined or have property confiscated. Mr. Wang paid exactly 503,000 yuan in &quot;treatment fees,&quot; which exceeded 500,000 yuan, meeting the standard of &quot;extremely large amounts&quot; in the &quot;Interpretation of Several Issues Concerning the Specific Application of Laws in Handling Criminal Cases of Fraud&quot; of the two top governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the suspected criminal behavior of this institution may go beyond what happened to Mr. Wang and others in this report, and it deserves further investigation by the police and medical supervision departments: This is a qualified and legal medical institution. ? Is the treatment performed a legal medical treatment that has been proven to be safe and effective? Are the people performing the treatment qualified to practice medicine? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, as reported by the media, the staff did say &quot;approved by the state,&quot; then this is a blatant use of public power to endorse themselves, and may also be suspected of forging, altering, and buying and selling official documents of state agencies. Certificates and seals; at the same time, the main business of &quot;Qiawei Health&quot; registered with the Industrial and Commercial Bureau is &quot;health consultation&quot; and &quot;health care&quot;, and may not be qualified to practice medical treatment. In this way, it is suspected of illegal medical practice; the expensive &quot;treatment&quot; &quot;The cost&quot; far exceeds the reasonable price range for &quot;consultation&quot; and &quot;health care&quot;. This is another out-and-out price fraud and is suspected of being illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the medical community still has not yet reached a completely clear consensus on the pathology, symptoms and treatment options of autism. The range of autism symptoms is also very wide, and different patients may need completely different treatment plans. There is no such a one-size-fits-all so-called &quot;meridian reconstruction&quot; therapy, and it is difficult for formal treatment to achieve a once-and-for-all effect. &quot;Qiawei Health&quot; took advantage of the information asymmetry of the patients&#39; families to carefully design such a scam, and almost every aspect was suspected of illegal crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the &quot;service categories&quot; of this institution, the list of &quot;difficult and complicated diseases&quot; advertised by it actually includes &quot;stroke, rheumatoid, ankylosing spondylitis, and ALS.&quot; &quot; and &quot;a total of 21 diseases&quot;, which seems a bit &quot;surprising&quot; to the outside world. As far as ALS is concerned, how can Qiawei Health be able to treat this rare disease that the world&#39;s top medical scientists are still trying to challenge? If it&#39;s true, I&#39;m afraid the world owes them a Nobel Prize in Medicine and Physiology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, &quot;Qiawei Health&quot; has been suspected of multiple illegal and criminal acts, including fraud. The public department should conduct an in-depth investigation into its illegal and criminal facts, seriously investigate its civil and criminal responsibilities, and compensate the victims. financial losses to the victims’ families and combat similar medical scams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>