<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[五年间，千亿债务“削峰”：地方化债的镇江样本]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258822]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/NTydygQiWy1Aa7n58WpDWSaGYxFYkXRNWBLwCKW4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1800&quot; height=&quot;1201&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NTydygQiWy1Aa7n58WpDWSaGYxFY kXRNWBLwCKW4. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the past few decades, Zhenjiang’s economy has mainly relied on heavy industries such as chemicals. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This year, the feeling is very obvious. Mainstream financial institutions have begun to do business in Zhenjiang.” A financial leasing company An employee told Southern Weekend reporters that due to risk control reasons, the company had not done business in Zhenjiang for several years, but this year it allowed it to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, the scale of Zhenjiang’s debt has continued to rise, and it was even once called the “four major Internet celebrities” in the market’s urban investment debt issues, together with Zunyi, Xiangtan, and Dalian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Enterprise Early Warning Data, if the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt + urban investment platform interest-bearing debt)/GDP, Zhenjiang’s debt ratio has increased from 105% in 2018 to 121% in 2020 . In the past three years, its debt ratio has been higher than that of the other 12 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high debt ratio has increased financial pressure in Zhenjiang, and financial institutions have also been deterred, and most have chosen to reduce their business volume in Zhenjiang. However, in 2023, Zhenjiang’s local debt situation showed obvious signs of improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An obvious signal is that two urban investment companies in Zhenjiang have just received AAA entity ratings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 13, 2023, the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission issued a document stating that Zhenjiang Industrial Investment Holding Group Co., Ltd. and Zhenjiang Urban Investment Holding Group Co., Ltd. have both obtained AAA subject credit ratings, realizing the credit construction of Zhenjiang City. A historic breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the highest credit rating of Zhenjiang’s urban investment companies was AA+. Among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu Province, Lianyungang, Suqian and Zhenjiang have no urban investment companies with AAA credit ratings. Obtaining an AAA rating means that the financing difficulty of the urban investment platform is reduced and the cost is reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After the debt situation eased this year, our bank reopened the credit line to a city investment platform in Zhenjiang.” A person who works at a city commercial bank in Jiangsu revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the city investment company had previously Risk point: His bank had suspended credit to the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu Province, Zhenjiang’s GDP ranked fourth from the bottom. Although it is located in southern Jiangsu, its economy is far away from Wuxi, Changzhou and Suzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did Zhenjiang, a relatively weak economy, resolve hundreds of billions of debts? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“There are more difficulties than expected, and the challenges are greater than expected”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang is located at the intersection of the Yangtze River and the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal, guarding the north-south hub, and is connected with Nanjing, Changzhou, Taizhou and Yangzhou border on each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Jiangsu Statistical Yearbook and the seventh national census data, Zhenjiang covers the smallest area among the 13 prefecture-level cities. Among the population distribution across Jiangsu Province, only Zhenjiang has a permanent population of less than 4 million. In other words, Zhenjiang has the least land and the least people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1983, Zhenjiang became a provincial municipality. In the past few decades, Zhenjiang&#39;s economy has mainly relied on heavy industries such as chemicals. According to the Zhenjiang Municipal Economic and Social Development Bulletin, from 2013 to 2017, the total output value of Zhenjiang heavy industry accounted for more than 80% of the total output value of designated industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2016, in order to protect the ecological environment, Jiangsu Province began to deploy special actions to reduce backward chemical production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the Zhenjiang Municipal Government, in 2017, the city shut down a total of 53 chemical companies, exceeding the provincial target (6 companies). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For backward and excess production capacity, we must resolutely eliminate those that should be eliminated.” In January 2019, Bu Xiaofang, then director of the Zhenjiang Municipal Economic and Information Technology Commission, introduced that in 2018, the city shut down 44 chemical companies, a total of 44 chemical companies were shut down in the past two years. Nearly half of chemical companies have been shut down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under environmental protection regulations, Zhenjiang’s economy has entered a period of pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, its annual fixed asset investment fell by 26.5% compared with the previous year, and private investment fell by 30.4%. In terms of industries, investment in the secondary industry dropped by 28.9%, of which industrial investment dropped by 27.9%; investment in the tertiary industry dropped by 24.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also this year, Zhenjiang’s GDP growth rate was 3%, ranking last among the 13 prefecture-level cities. Its GDP growth rate was 9.3% in 2016 and 7.24% in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2019 Government Work Report introduced that in the past year, the three indicators of Zhenjiang’s GDP, total retail sales of consumer goods, and fixed asset investment have failed to meet the goals set by the People’s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then mayor of Zhenjiang City, Zhang Yefei, said in his government work report, &quot;Looking back on 2018, there were more difficulties and greater challenges than expected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people in northern Jiangsu In cities, chemical industry is also an important industry, so why does it have less impact on economic growth than Zhenjiang? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An economist in Zhenjiang told Southern Weekend reporters that unlike the northern Jiangsu region, the Yangtze River flows through Zhenjiang. In the past, many chemical companies were located in areas closer to the Yangtze River. In the past few years, the Yangtze River Under the Great Protection Strategy, environmental protection management has become more stringent, and many chemical companies have had to close down or move away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The upgrading of industrial structure requires a buffer period.” The scholar analyzed that compared with other cities in southern Jiangsu, Zhenjiang’s high-tech enterprises and advanced manufacturing enterprises are small in scale and lack core leading enterprises, which will lead to local The capacity for economic development is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, after the new leadership team of the Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government took office, Zhenjiang’s development philosophy also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Zhenjiang will never repeat extensive growth in pursuit of speed, never engage in ‘numbers games’ in pursuit of political achievements, will never borrow blindly for image projects, and will never sacrifice the ecological environment in pursuit of economic interests. .&quot; In January 2019, Zhang Yefei, then mayor of Zhenjiang City, said in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the chemical industry was shut down and reorganized, a large amount of debt burdened by the vigorous development of urban construction in previous years was still accumulating, which put pressure on Zhenjiang&#39;s finances of low revenue and high debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2017, the Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s work report stated, “In the past five years, the urban area has completed a total of 290 billion yuan in urban construction investment.” In comparison, Zhenjiang’s general public budget revenue in 2017 was 28.4 billion yuan. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, urban investment debt also increased rapidly. According to the Enterprise Alert, from 2013 to 2017, the interest-bearing debt of Zhenjiang Urban Investment Platform increased from 122.1 billion yuan to 350.3 billion yuan, an increase of 187%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee inspection team inspected the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee and found that during a certain period, &quot;the municipal Party committee did not do enough research on debt control, economic layout, major projects, and urban construction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee wrote in the inspection and rectification report that in view of the inadequate management of government investment projects, it was made clear that all government investment projects must be managed by the municipal party committee and municipal government through unified decision-making, and a series of documents were issued to build a System system for completion acceptance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Municipal finance has completely returned to &#39;food finance&#39;&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Economic growth has slowed down, a large amount of money has been invested in urban construction, and there is rigid payment pressure on the finance. Zhenjiang&#39;s local debt problem has gradually exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2018, Zhenjiang City’s budget implementation in the first half of the year revealed that the scale of municipal fiscal maintenance and operation expenditures has increased year by year. In 2018, municipal department budget arrangements for personnel, operations and business project expenditures were close to 3.4 billion yuan. &quot;Under the development trend of large total operating expenditure, high proportion, and rapid growth, municipal finance has completely returned to &#39;food finance&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Food finance&quot; refers to the fiscal revenue of the first-level government, which is only enough to maintain the salaries of personnel in government agencies and institutions, as well as basic daily operations. In 2018, Zhenjiang City’s general public budget revenue was 12.6 billion yuan. 3.4 billion yuan, equivalent to 27% of the general public budget revenue that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang’s 2018 budget execution report stated that incremental financial resources are limited, and the balance of fiscal revenue and expenditure in recent years has mainly relied on revitalizing existing stocks, coordinating funds, and replacing financial resources. However, there is less and less room to absorb incremental expenditure through existing financial resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News reported that on January 18, 2019, Lou Qinjian, then Secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, pointed out that “Zhenjiang City has weak links in supervision of key areas, and the government’s hidden debt risks are prominent. , and there are even corruption issues.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, Zhenjiang’s debt situation became known to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Zhenjiang, debts are mainly concentrated in various urban investment platforms, and government debt is still controlled under the limit. If you look at the debt scale of Zhenjiang Urban Investment alone, it is much lower than that of Suzhou, Wuxi, Changzhou and other places, and is not outstanding in Jiangsu Province. The key issue is the debt ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang’s debt ratio is much higher than that of other cities in Jiangsu. According to the aforementioned calculation method, in 2013, its debt ratio was only 41.71%, and in 2020 it reached 121%. If the debt ratio is too high, it means that the local comprehensive financial resources are difficult to repay debts, and cannot even guarantee the existence of debts, which is prone to risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the urban investment debts in Guizhou, Yunnan and other places are concentrated at the county level. But in Zhenjiang, urban investment debts are mainly concentrated in municipal platforms. The enterprise warning notice shows that in 2022, the interest-bearing debt of Zhenjiang&#39;s top four municipal urban investment platforms will be 207.5 billion yuan, and the interest-bearing debt of all urban investment platforms in Zhenjiang will be 340.5 billion yuan, accounting for 61%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation is also related to Zhenjiang’s economic structure. Zhenjiang has jurisdiction over 3 districts and 3 county-level cities. The economic aggregate of county-level cities is higher than that of municipal districts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past few years, Zhenjiang City has not been as prosperous as the counties (county-level cities) below. Mainstream financial institutions would rather do business in the counties (county-level cities) than invest in the cities. Platform operation.&quot; Wang Li, who works for a financial leasing company in Shanghai, and whose major customers are mainly urban investment companies across Jiangsu, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to alleviate financing pressure, Zhenjiang Urban Investment Platform began to issue a large number of non-standard products. Compared with bank loans and bonds, non-standard financing issuance costs are higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism Industry Group (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism&quot;) is 100% owned by the Zhenjiang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission and is a municipal urban investment platform. Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism&#39;s bond prospectus shows that in 2017, its non-standard financing scale was only 2.8 billion yuan, and by 2020, it had climbed to 11.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Zhang Huan has spent tens of millions of yuan purchasing non-standard products from urban investment companies in various places. He told Southern Weekend reporters that around 2016, he purchased non-standard products in Zhenjiang, and the interest rate was less than 7%. However, at that time, the income from urban investment bonds in Guizhou, Yunnan and other places was higher, and non-standard products in Zhenjiang were not easy to sell. &quot; In order to persuade me to buy, the agent would give me some rebates, such as buying 1 million and getting 10,000 back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee of a financing intermediary company told Southern Weekend reporters that the highest coupon rate for non-standard products in Zhenjiang was around 9%. The employee said that at first Zhenjiang’s district and county urban investment platforms were issuing such products, probably because of the difficulty in financing, but later they were concentrated on municipal platforms with larger assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Support from provincial governments&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, the Jiangsu Provincial Government and the Zhenjiang Municipal Government began to solve the urban investment debt problem before the risk occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2019, news leaked out of the market that the China Development Bank would replace Zhenjiang’s implicit debt at a cost of 20 billion yuan a year for 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of that year, Zheng Zhijie, the former president of the China Development Bank, said at a forum, &quot;Zhenjiang has problems with high repayment pressure and high costs. Zhenjiang also wants to extend the term and reduce the current financial burden. I also We participated in the talks, but the Zhenjiang News plan was not approved by the Ministry of Finance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, when talking about how to resolve the existing debt, Finance Minister Liu Kun stated that he would insist that the central government would not bail out. Who is responsible for borrowing money, so that &quot;whose family&#39;s children will be cared for&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the CDB’s plan was not passed, Jiangsu Province began to increase its debt support for Zhenjiang. The specific methods were to increase the scale of special bonds, reduce the financing pressure of urban investment platforms, and avoid relying on high-interest non-standard product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special bonds of municipal and county governments are issued by provincial governments on their behalf. After counting the budget implementation status of various regions in Jiangsu, it can be found that the scale of special debt in Zhenjiang in 2019 increased by 34.6 billion yuan compared with the previous year. Among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu, Zhenjiang is the place with the largest increase in the scale of special debt. In 2020, the scale of Zhenjiang&#39;s special bonds increased by 42.5 billion year-on-year, also exceeding other regions in the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the large-scale issuance of special bonds, the scale of Zhenjiang government debt has changed accordingly. According to data such as Zhenjiang City&#39;s budget implementation, Zhenjiang City&#39;s government debt scale was 109.7 billion yuan in 2019, which is not outstanding in the province. In 2021, the debt will rise to 191.8 billion yuan, second only to Nanjing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Zhenjiang also replaced high-cost hidden debts by issuing replacement bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2019 financial accounts of Danyang City and Dantu District under the jurisdiction of Zhenjiang, the replacement of hidden debts was mentioned. According to the final accounts report of Danyang City, the government bonds issued by Jiangsu Province in 2019 totaled 5.3 billion yuan, of which 1.4 billion yuan were replacement bonds, accounting for 26%. The replacement bonds were used to repay the existing implicit government debt of platform companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dantu District also revealed in its final accounting report that it issued 679 million yuan of existing replacement bonds to repay existing hidden debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In response to financial and debt risks, we have taken measures such as curbing growth, adjusting structure, and reducing costs. The total amount of government debt and costs have ‘double decreased’.” Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s 2021 Work Report wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Enterprise Early Warning Data, Zhenjiang’s urban investment interest-bearing debt increased by 200 million yuan year-on-year in 2021, with little change; in 2022, urban investment’s interest-bearing debt was 340.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 9.7 billion Yuan. In other words, the debt scale of Zhenjiang’s urban investment platforms has been controlled and is trending down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many urban investment practitioners in Jiangsu told Southern Weekend reporters that the most critical factor in Zhenjiang’s debt-oriented development is the financial and policy support from Jiangsu Province. For a long time, Jiangsu&#39;s GDP has ranked second in the country and has strong economic strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the Lianyungang government shows that on May 27, 2022, the north-south paired assistance meeting between Wuxi and Lianyungang was officially held. For more than 20 years, Lianyungang has been supported by Zhenjiang. For Zhenjiang, withdrawing from assistance can alleviate some of the financial pressure. In addition, changing Lianyungang&#39;s sponsor from Zhenjiang to Wuxi also requires coordination from provincial government departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Zhenjiang also has professional cadres handling debt matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Zhou Kai, then vice president of Bank of Jiangsu, was transferred to deputy mayor of Zhenjiang City. Previously, he worked at China Construction Bank Jiangsu Branch, Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu for more than 20 years. According to the official website of the Zhenjiang Municipal Government, Zhou Kai is in charge of the local financial regulatory bureau, the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, municipal state-owned enterprises, etc., and assists in being in charge of the Finance Bureau. The deputy mayor must also be nominated by the Organization Department of the Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reduce financing costs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Jiangsu Province issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Regulating the Investment and Financing Behavior of Financing Platform Companies&quot;, requiring guidance for financing platform companies to gradually reduce trust and capital costs. management plans, financial leasing, private equity funds and various non-standard products issued on local trading venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to replacing hidden debt with bonds, Zhenjiang also received assistance from banks to increase credit and reduce financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang Communications Industry Group (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zhenjiang Communications Investment&quot;&lt;/span>;) wrote in the bond prospectus , with the coordination and support of government resources, since 2020, the total amount of corporate bank credit has increased, high-interest non-standard financing has been cleared to a greater extent, the debt composition and financing costs have been better improved, and financing costs have decreased by 0.84% ​​compared with 2019. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analyzing bond prospectuses, Southern Weekend reporters found that between 2020 and 2023, the top four urban investment platforms in Zhenjiang in terms of asset size have all seen sharp declines in non-standard financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the one with the largest scale reduction is Zhenjiang Communications Investment. In March 2020, the amount of non-standard financing in Zhenjiang was 15.3 billion yuan, accounting for 25.86% of the total financing scale; in March 2023, the amount of non-standard financing was 5.555 billion yuan, accounting for 10% of the total financing scale. Compared with three years ago, it dropped by 9.745 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Lin works at a municipal urban investment platform in Zhenjiang. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the company had cleared away other high-cost non-standard products, except for short-term emergency financing, which could only be done after filing. According to the person from the above-mentioned financing intermediary company, there are currently no non-standard products for the public in Zhenjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, many places in Jiangsu have announced the upper limit of financing interest rates for urban investment. Several people from Zhenjiang&#39;s urban investment platform told Southern Weekend reporters that the upper limit of Zhenjiang&#39;s external financing costs is 6.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, this interest rate is at a medium level in Jiangsu Province. A staff member of an urban investment platform in Nanjing told Southern Weekend reporters that the local urban investment financing limit is 4.2% (five-year LPR), which is almost the strictest regulation in Jiangsu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to people from the above-mentioned financing intermediary companies, some urban investment platforms in Jiangsu can issue fixed financing products with interest rates of up to 7%-8%. &quot;Actually, the upper limit of issuance cost is 6.699%.&quot; Zhang Lin said that if the red line of 6.7% cannot be reached, &quot;lower cost financing must be achieved.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2022, the Zhenjiang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission issued a document stating that for high-cost financing projects that meet or exceed the financing cost control price determined by the municipal government, the &quot;High-cost Debt Management Approval Form&quot; must be filled out one by one in advance 》, after the enterprise implements the internal decision-making procedures, it can be carried out after being reviewed by the Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, reported to the leaders of the municipal government for approval, and reported to the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision for filing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned Nanjing Urban Investment person also revealed that if the cost of a financing reaches 5%, the district will advise you not to do it. If there is real financial pressure, the district will coordinate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhenjiang City State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission’s document also mentioned that it is necessary to clarify the mutual insurance quotas of enterprises based on the financing needs and affordability of relevant enterprises, implement total amount control, and prevent cross-conduction of debt risks and unlimited extension of debt chains. In principle No guarantee shall be provided in excess of the mutual insurance limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, the mutual guarantee situation among Zhenjiang municipal-level urban investment companies has not been optimistic, with Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism being the most serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Its bond prospectus shows that as of the end of March 2020, the issuer’s external guarantee balance totaled 16.7 billion yuan, accounting for 97.93% of net assets. The company provides relatively large amounts of external guarantees, mainly to state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Recovering economic losses of nearly 1.6 billion yuan”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the basis of specifying the upper limit of financing costs, Zhenjiang and other places in Jiangsu are further reducing financing intermediary fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2019, the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee wrote in a report on the progress of inspections and rectifications that it is necessary to further standardize the decision-making and operating procedures of financing projects, strictly control intermediary agency service fees, formulate intermediary agency service management methods, and adopt intermediary Institutional access system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incorporate the intermediate business expenses in the credit link into the total cost and determine them together, require all municipal industrial groups to register their accounts in detail, and eliminate the payment of financing and financial advisory fees to third-party non-financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Some urban investment platforms are controlled by intermediaries, and there is no way around them.” Li Yu has worked in many financial leasing companies. He told Southern Weekend reporters that intermediaries generally have a close relationship with the leaders of urban investment companies. Internet, &quot;Even if the cost is low, urban investment will not do business with you, you must go through an intermediary.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu said that after the intermediary participates, it will push up the financing cost. For example, if 6% of the cost can be financed, the final cost will be 8%, and the middle 2% will be between the intermediary, urban investment, and investors. divided into. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission stated that since the launch of a special rectification of corruption issues in the financing field in January 2022, the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision of Zhenjiang City, Jiangsu Province has filed a total of 22 cases and investigated party members and cadres, including those at the county level. With 3 cadres, nearly 1.6 billion yuan in economic losses were recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the special rectification, the Zhenjiang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision comprehensively reviewed the financing business of platform companies at the municipal, county and township levels in the past ten years, focusing on and verifying financing projects whose comprehensive financing costs significantly exceeded the market interest rate. , sorting out financing projects with major doubts such as illegal payment of intermediary fees and abnormal comprehensive financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it was discovered that a number of fund &quot;brokers&quot; were involved in cross-regional financing business and obtained high intermediary fees, as well as bribing platform company officials. A total of 10 fund &quot;brokers&quot; were investigated and punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu revealed that this year, government staff from a certain place in Jiangsu came to a financial leasing company where he previously worked and demanded the return of funds that were higher than the upper limit of financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, urban investment platforms across Jiangsu are very sensitive to financing costs. In October, at a financing negotiation meeting of a certain urban investment company in Jiangsu, Southern Weekend reporters saw an executive repeatedly negotiating with bank staff, hoping that the other party could reduce the channel fee of 3‰. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now when the person in charge of an urban investment company goes to the government for a meeting, the first thing he reports is not the current status of the company’s operations, but the situation of debt repayment.” A Zhenjiang urban investment practitioner said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Li’s view, Zhenjiang Urban Investment’s debt has not been significantly compressed, but the internal debt structure has been well adjusted, non-standard financing has accounted for a low proportion, and the debt can survive stably. “What financial institutions value most is Or debt stability.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Li’s company has conducted statistics and found that the number of new financial leases in Jiangsu in 2022 dropped by 40% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, governments at all levels in Zhenjiang have also revitalized state-owned assets to relieve financial pressure. In 2018, Zhenjiang City&#39;s state-owned capital operating income was only 568 million yuan, and it reached 4.854 billion yuan in 2020, mainly coming from property rights transfer income at the municipal level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the number of high-quality state-owned assets is limited and this income is difficult to sustain. In 2022, state-owned capital operating income will drop to 585 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, with the help of the provincial government and financial institutions, Zhenjiang has improved its debt structure by curbing the increase in debt and replacing high-interest debt. Coupled with the recovery of financing intermediary fees and the establishment of financing cost ceilings and other control measures, the debt ratio has been steadily reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, the Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s work report revealed that in 2022, in response to financial debt risks, the government will strengthen the concept of “debt reduction is also political achievement” and further promote “redundancy reduction” and “peak reduction”. Four plans, annual goals and tasks were fully achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in 2019, the Ministry of Finance established a local government debt risk rating mechanism, dividing debt risks into red (debt rate ≥ 300%), orange (200% ≤ debt rate &lt; 300%), yellow There are four levels: (120% ≤ debt ratio &lt; 200%) and green (debt ratio &lt; 120%). &quot;Going off the red&quot; refers to the debt risk level that leaves the red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, in response to issues related to Zhenjiang’s chemical debt, Southern Weekend reporters called the Zhenjiang Municipal Finance Bureau, but the other party declined the interview request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Wang Li, Zhang Lin and Li Yu are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张之洞为何再三邀请他北上？陶福祥与张之洞的“岭学流传中原”计划]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/uAHKaAKt8pPKk3GxEarg8QaVt3xFpc5kh1mEol60.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;759&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/uAHKaAKt8pPKk3GxEarg8QaVt3xFpc5kh 1mEol60. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait of Tao Fuxiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Taken from &quot;Portraits of Scholars in the Qing Dynasty&quot;/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early days of Zhang Zhidong&#39;s supervision of Hubei, he proposed that &quot;Lingxue spread to the Central Plains&quot; He said that in order to attract scholars from Guangdong Xuehaitang to go north, he particularly valued Tao Fuxiang (alias Chunhai), a disciple of Lingnan scholar Chen Li. Ruan Yuan, governor of Guangdong, founded Xuehaitang. After the mid-Qing Dynasty, the status of &quot;Lingxue&quot; rose rapidly. Xuehaitang does not have a mountain director, but elects many scholars as &quot;seniors&quot;. Zhang Weiping, Tan Ying, Zhu Ciqi, Chen Li, Zou Boqi, etc. have all served as seniors. In the seventh year of Guangxu&#39;s reign (1881), Zhang Shusheng, the governor of Guangdong and Guangxi, petitioned the court to &quot;compliment and commend&quot; two great Lingnan scholars, Zhu Ciqi and Chen Li, and both of them were awarded the title of &quot;Fifth Rank Minister&quot;. When Zhang Zhidong was in charge of Guangdong, he founded Guangya Academy. One of his purposes was to inherit the academics of Xuehaitang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuehaitang attaches great importance to &quot;simple learning&quot;, and Chen Li, a native of Panyu, inherited and developed Ruan Yuan&#39;s academic tradition. Scholars during the Qianjia period focused on textual research, while the official ideology promoted Zhu Xi, forming an opposition between Sinology (textual research) and Song Dynasty (righteousness). Chen Li followed the current situation and put forward the slogan of &quot;reconciling the Han and Song Dynasties&quot;, and the &quot;reconciliation theory&quot; was gradually affirmed by the mainstream. Zhang Zhidong&#39;s &quot;Encouraging Learning&quot; written in 1898 emphasized that &quot;old learning is the body and new learning is the application&quot;, which is also a &quot;reconciliation theory&quot; and is in the same vein as Chen Li in terms of thinking and methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Li&#39;s &quot;Study Notes of Dongshu&quot; was once popular all over the world. Wen Tingshi quoted Weng Tonghe as saying that Emperor Guangxu &quot;placed this book on his desk and read it daily.&quot; Yuan Chang, a disciple of Zhang Zhidong, expressed his admiration for Chen Li many times in his diary. In the seventh year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, Yuan Chang &quot;read Mr. Chen&#39;s &quot;East School Reading Notes&quot; and found out that everything he said was profound, practical and feasible, and now Mr. Hu is stable.&quot; Mr. Anding Hu was Hu Yuan, a famous scholar in the Song Dynasty. In the fourteenth year of Guangxu (1888), Yuan Chang called Chen Li and Zeng Guofan together, &quot;the only recent sages can be called Zeng Wenzheng and Chen Panyu.&quot; He called Chen Li &quot;Chen Panyu&quot; without a name, and was compared with Zeng Guofan and highly praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this, Zhang Zhidong had met Tan Zongjun, the son of Tan Ying, and Gui Wencan, a disciple of Chen Li. In 1871, Pan Zuyin and Zhang Zhidong launched an elegant gathering at Nagarshu Temple in the capital. Gui Wencan and Tan Zongjun were both guests. Zhang Zhidong wrote to Pan Zuyin, saying that Gui Wencan&#39;s attainments in Confucian classics were &quot;really unattainable.&quot; Chen Li was highly praised by important officials in the court, and Gui Wencan played an irreplaceable role. In the fourth year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, on Chen Li&#39;s 70th birthday, Zhang Zhidong wrote a couplet to congratulate him on his birthday. The couplet said: &quot;Living late and taking care of the elderly will make the world admire your virtue; sharp thinking and thinking are the teachings of scholars.&quot; Although he had never met Chen Li, he I highly admire Chen Li&#39;s academic practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of the 15th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, Zhang Zhidong moved from Guangdong and Guangxi to Huguang, and planned to build Lianghu Academy based on the model of Guangya Academy. The following year, Zheng Zhitong (also known as Bo Geng), who was appointed to teach economics at Lianghu Academy, died suddenly, which made him turn his attention to Lingnan scholars. Zheng Zhitong (1831-1890), a native of Zunyi, Guizhou, was the son of the famous scholar Zheng Zhen. In his early years, he served as an assistant to Zhang Zhidong in Sichuan academic affairs, and was later hired as the branch of Guangya Bookstore. In Zhang Zhidong&#39;s mind, the best candidate to succeed Zheng Zhitong was Tao Fuxiang, Chen Li&#39;s disciple and Liang Dingfen&#39;s teacher. From this, Zhang Zhidong launched his &quot;relentless pursuit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Third Collection of Stele Biographies·Biography of Tao Fuxiang&quot; says: &quot;Wen Xiang moved to Lianghu to supervise Lianghu and set up Lianghu Academy. Yue Yue thanks the sick and returns home.&quot; The wording is simple. The process of Zhang Zhidong insisting on asking Tao Fuxiang and Tao to resign repeatedly, taking care of Zhang&#39;s face to go north for a short period of time, and then resolutely returning to Guangzhou can be seen in the telegrams exchanged between Wang Bingen and Tao Fuxiang this year, which are now in the Institute of Modern History of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. They can be attributed to Tao Fuxiang. Add footnotes to the biography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Bingen, courtesy name Xuecen, was born in Huayang, Sichuan. Zhang Zhidong was a protégé of Zhang Zhidong when he was an academic and political scholar in Sichuan. He had been an official in Guangdong for a long time and was promoted by Guangya Bookstore at that time. On the third day of February in the 16th year of Guangxu, Zhang Zhidong sent a telegram to Wang Bingen: &quot;Since Bo Geng (Zheng Zhitong) is gone, there is no one to teach economics in Lianghu Academy, except Tao Chunhai, who is filial, honest, elegant, upright and pure. He is qualified to occupy this seat and look forward to future generations.&quot; Invite me to Hubei for a total of 800 gold to repair the fire. The situation of dividing the religion here is different from that of Guangya. There is no need to invite another mountain leader. He has more power and a more respectable appearance. The appointment will be sent as soon as it is accepted.&quot; (&quot;Modern History Collection of the Qing Dynasty&quot;) &quot;Copy of the Nominee&#39;s Manuscript&quot;, Volume 2, Volume 41, Page 26, the following quotations are only registration numbers and page numbers) Confucian classics were the core of the culture of the day. Lianghu Academy does not have a mountain director. After teaching by division, he has the status of subject leader and has greater power. Zhang Zhidong was afraid that Tao Fuxiang would care about his reputation, so he explained it this way. &quot;Yuan Ya Duan Chun&quot; is not only an evaluation of Tao Fuxiang, but also Zhang Zhidong&#39;s criterion for hiring Confucian classics teachers. At that time, there was a saying that &quot;a Confucian teacher is a teacher of people&quot;. Confucian teachers should not only have profound knowledge, but also have noble conduct and be able to teach all living beings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Fuxiang (1834-1896), courtesy name Chunhai, also known as Ailu, was born in Panyu, Guangdong. He studied under Chen Li when he was young. Thousands of volumes. Zhang Zhidong supervised Guangdong and was appointed as the headmaster of Guangya Bookstore. In the spring semester of the 17th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign (1891) at Lianghu Academy, apart from classics, there was also a shortage of history teachers. Zhang Zhidong asked another student of Chen Li, Lin Guogeng. Lin Guogeng, courtesy name Yang Bo, was born in Suishi Township, Panyu County. He could write poems at the age of nine and entered Haitang as a college graduate. He and his younger brother Lin Guozan both made outstanding achievements in history. Chen Li called the two brothers &quot;Erlin, the treasure of the country&quot; also&quot;. Lin Guogeng was elected as the senior student of Xuehaitang in the eleventh year of Guangxu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Fuxiang did not want to go north, so he said goodbye in the telegram: &quot;Fuxiang regards the museum as his home. It has now been opened. The scattered disciples have moved in and it is difficult to prepare it for the time being. There are funerals in summer and autumn, so it is not convenient to travel far.&quot; (Volume 66, page 711) The school he opened has opened and the students cannot be dismissed. Moreover, there are funerals at home in the summer and autumn, so it is difficult to accept the invitation from Hubei. Ten days later, Zhang Zhidong Power Generation Wang Bingen analyzed the reasons for Tao Fuxiang&#39;s resignation. In addition to opening a bookstore and teaching apprentices, he also served as the headmaster of Guangya Bookstore, the senior of Xuehaitang, and the head of Jupo Jingshe. He had a high status and a good income. . Zhang Zhidong replied to Wang Bingen and promised to find a way to do this. He said hello to Li Hanzhang, the current governor of Guangdong and Guangxi, and reserved three part-time jobs for him. &quot;Even if the two seniors, Jupo and Xuehai, come to Hubei Province, they can still hold concurrent positions. Tao is the leader of Guangdong middle school scholars. These two places must not belong to others. When I take a seat in the bookstore, I should entrust Li Xiaoshuai (Li Hanzhang, also known as Xiaoquan) ) As usual, I sincerely agree to come, and the appointment letter will be sent on the same day.&quot; (Volume 41, page 391) In Zhang Zhidong&#39;s mind, after Chen Li died, Tao Fuxiang became the &quot;leader of Guangdong middle school scholars&quot;. In order to please Tao Fuxiang, he did not hesitate to I begged Li Hanzhang, the successor governor of Guangdong and Guangxi, to reserve a part-time job for Tao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to impress Tao Fuxiang and Lin Guogeng, Zhang Zhidong sent a telegram to Wang Bingen: &quot;Tao and Lin are not lonely when they come to Hubei. They both hope to be invited to come. From then on, Ling Xue It is said that in the Central Plains, Tao and Lin will also be happy if they think about it.&quot; (Volume 41, page 398)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhidong hired Tao Fuxiang with such a low profile that he only had to visit the thatched cottage three times in person, which made Tao feel Sorry, I had no choice but to come up with a compromise, which was to teach in Hubei for three months and then return to Guangzhou on the grounds of &quot;burial&quot;. Tao Fuxiang spent three months in Wuchang to determine the scale and curriculum of the Confucian classics teaching at Lianghu Academy, and then returned to Guangzhou. Before leaving, Zhang Zhidong asked Tao Fuxiang for a &quot;substitute&quot;. Tao Fuxiang recommended Wang Guorui, a fellow sect member from Panyu, but Wang seemed to have failed to make the trip in the end. When Lin Guogeng first received the invitation, he declined on the grounds of his father&#39;s old illness (Volume 66, page 714). He was eventually persuaded to teach history at Lianghu Academy. In 1892, he passed the Jinshi examination and was awarded the title of editor of the Hanlin Academy. He left Hubei. . Liang Dingfen, a disciple of Chen Li, once served as the supervisor of the Lianghu Academy and was Zhang Zhidong&#39;s main assistant in handling academic affairs in Hubei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuehaitang attaches great importance to practical learning. One of the seniors, Zou Boqi (from Nanhai), has profound research on optics and surveying. He once presided over the surveying and mapping of Nanhai County maps, which was the beginning of the modern method of surveying and mapping local chronicles and maps in my country. Luo Zhaocang, a disciple of Zou Boqi and a native of Nanhai, specialized in surveying and mapping. He was recruited by Zhang Zhidong to survey and map rivers in Hubei, and stayed at Lianghu Academy to teach. After that, Zhang Zhidong hired many Guangdong scholars to go north, including Confucian classics teacher Yang Yufang (Nanhai), Confucian classics teacher Ma Zhenyu (Shunde), and arithmetic teacher Tang Jinzhu (Huaxian). Tang Jinzhu majored in actuarial science and was hired by Zuo Zongtang to teach at the Fujian Shipbuilding School. Xuehaitang inherited the orthodox classics and history of the Qing Dynasty, and had many disciples who were also good at practical studies (surveying, mapping, arithmetic, etc.). This was the main factor why they were favored by Zhang Zhidong. In 1905, Zhang Zhidong and Yuan Shikai suspended the imperial examination, and academics entered a new era. The so-called &quot;Lingxue spread to the Central Plains&quot; was rarely mentioned. Today, there are still many people who know Chen Li, but few know Tao Fuxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数字人“入职”企业，主打“不知疲倦”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/BADHEzQtsMAcF3e3m8E5OUM4qs74EoClsS3SbwS0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1249&quot; height=&quot;832&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/BADHEzQtsMAcF3e3m8E5OUM4qs74E oClsS3SbwS0. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 8, 2023, the closing ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the digital torchbearers &quot;set the trend&quot; &quot;From far to near, ran into the closing ceremony and extinguished the main torch. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Hangzhou Asian Games, a giant digital human torchbearer walked across the Qiantang River through the city. Run towards the venue and light the main torch. The hyper-realistic virtual digital human Lili made his film and television debut in the TV series &quot;Under the Stranger&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the digital people on the screen, more digital people &quot;join&quot; companies and work with humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concepts of virtual people, digital people, and virtual digital people are often used interchangeably on the market, and the industry has not yet formed a unified understanding. Generally speaking, virtual people refer more to purely digital images without real-person entities in reality, while digital people include virtual images without real-person entities, as well as digital &quot;doppelgangers&quot; of real people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital humans have anthropomorphic or human-like appearance, behavior or thinking ability, but have no physical entities and only exist in virtual space. Because of its characteristics of freely customizing appearance, absolute obedience to orders, and tirelessness, it carries the perfect imagination of human beings to overcome the limitations of the mortal body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, in addition to Digital Human technology companies and film and television animation companies, those engaged in the production of digital humans, domestic and foreign Internet giants, when laying out the metaverse, have without exception chosen digital humans and launched their own digital products. Human creation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As digital human suppliers flourish, who is paying the bill for digital humans? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From ten thousand yuan to one million yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Common digital people can be divided into cartoon images, two-dimensional characters, realistic or hyper-realistic figures in appearance. People; in terms of driving methods, they can be mainly divided into real-person driven and AI-driven; in terms of functional positioning, they can be divided into performing arts digital people and service-oriented digital people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different types of digital people will also have large differences in technical routes and production costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The accuracy of the digital human model is mainly determined by the number of faces.” Shen Jianyou told Southern Weekend reporters. He was born in 1995 and works as a marketing manager at Guangzhou Virtual Power, a company that provides inertial motion capture technology and virtual digital human production services. Most of the company&#39;s employees are born in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Jianyou explained that modeling a cube only requires six faces, but the model usually involves complex curved surfaces, and more faces are needed to ensure the smoothness of the model. Ordinary cartoon dolls have a small number of modeling faces and do not involve the production of complex clothing, hair, etc. The closer to real-life hyper-realistic models are, the more complicated the production is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complexity of the model is related to the real-time driving effect. Shen Jianyou gave an example. The facial expression of a cartoon model is mainly the opening and closing of the eyes and mouth, while the facial expressions of a humanoid model usually have 52 sets of model deformation parameters. In other words, the subsequent workload and production costs are determined from the moment the customized image is determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A set of digital humans that can be driven in real time costs at least tens of thousands of yuan, including digital human image customization, motion capture equipment and virtual anchor systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Jianyou said that due to the different usage scenarios of customized digital humans, the specific cost must be determined based on customer needs. The cost of producing a hyper-realistic digital human like Liu Yexi&#39;s is in the millions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Zikang, CEO of Chuangyi Technology, which produced Liu Yexi, once told the media that in the first half year of launching Liu Yexi, the cost investment in R&amp;D, manpower and technology was about one million levels, and the cost of the first Liu Yexi short video Up to hundreds of thousands of dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter consulted Alibaba Cloud sales as a customer and learned that through Alibaba’s digital star-making service, it costs about 50 RMB to design a set of virtual digital human assets that are adapted to real-person intelligent driving and multiplexed in multiple scenarios and ports. Ten thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the cost of customizing digital humans is not low, most of the customers Shen Jianyou comes into contact with in the market are still B-side, especially in the fields of cultural tourism, education, and government exhibition halls. Occasionally, there are those with higher budgets. C-side customers are coming. &quot;For example, some anchors who don&#39;t want to show up or want to maximize their own advantages.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, many personal virtual anchors at Station B use Live2D models (two-dimensional animation effects), also known as the anchor&#39;s &quot; leather case&quot;. To make a &quot;leather case&quot;, you need to complete the character drawing and then make it into a Live2D model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some painters will provide some exquisite public vertical paintings. For exclusive characters, you need to make an appointment with the painter, and the price ranges from a hundred yuan to a thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A company that provides Live2D model production has launched a regular model production package priced at 666 yuan, and the most expensive package does not exceed a thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After having the model, you can complete the motion capture of the face and hands with the help of the camera. The live anchor can operate the model in the live broadcast screen through facial expressions and hand movements in front of the computer to achieve preset expressions. and simple actions, but the model cannot move freely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A virtual anchor at Station B said that if the anchor himself has the ability to take over the work of painters and modelers, the cost of live broadcast is only the hardware investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The birth of digital actors&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among digital actors, digital artists with exquisite production and versatile talents are the most eye-catching and the most expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Their image and appearance fully cater to the market aesthetics, and they have a distinctive personality and identity label since their debut. For example, Luo Tianyi and A-SOUL who are good at singing and dancing, Liu Yexi, a blogger who is good at makeup and catching monsters, AYAYI and Ling_Ling, KOL bloggers who specialize in fashion, and Tianyu, a digital figure in the ancient style track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital artists who gain attention by relying on their &quot;face&quot; and &quot;personality&quot; mean that they have to continue to invest in high production costs and stable operating capabilities. The lack of either will make digital artists become a lackluster actor on the Internet. An &quot;empty shell&quot; that no one cares about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the way digital artists monetize is no different from traditional artists, mainly through brand activities, business endorsements, performances, etc. Compared with the two, digital artists have fewer exposure opportunities, a weak fan base, and limited visibility and market appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years, there have been numerous cases of real-person celebrities’ “collapse” affecting brand image, and many brands have begun to cooperate with digital artists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Angie, born in 2020, is a virtual idol under the Dongtu Universe. She is a girl next door with short neck-length hair and clean makeup. The works on the Douyin account tend to record daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years after its debut, Axi has established cooperative relationships with brands such as Zhong Xuegao, Yadi Changhua, Chery, Xiaomi, OPPO, and Qiandu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhong Xuegao, the brand manager, replied to Southern Weekend reporters that cooperation with digital person Axi is a new exploration and attempt to achieve brand innovation, shorten the distance with young consumers, and enhance the interaction between consumers and enterprises. feel. The advantage of digital human endorsement is that it can adapt to the characteristics of the brand for secondary creation and customize the image and content in line with the brand&#39;s tone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lili, the first hyper-realistic digital human under Alibaba Entertainment Group, has successfully participated in film and television dramas and has become a veritable &quot;digital actor&quot;. In the play, Lili plays the role of Erzhuang, a girl who has no limbs and can only walk and control electromagnetic waves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The head of the Lili team gave a written reply to the Southern Weekend reporter. Initially, there were eight versions of Lili’s image. Finally, the current version was selected based on user research. It is sweet and cute but also a little cool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene that reflects Lili&#39;s &quot;acting skills&quot; is Erzhuang&#39;s fantasy of being greedy when he hears food from others. Alibaba said that this was due to the director&#39;s &quot;training&quot;, and the best effect was tested in Lili&#39;s extreme expressions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the shooting plan of director Xu Hongyu, the role of Er Zhuang was originally completed with traditional special effects, and was later replaced by a digital human plan. The head of Lili&#39;s technical team said that compared with traditional special effects, the digital human solution can reduce production costs by 80%, mainly saving the cost of original painting settings and IP asset creation; AI technology has shortened the post-production cycle by 40%, and the crew More choices and possibilities in less time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Yong, CTO of Alibaba Entertainment Group, revealed to the media that after the broadcast of &quot;Under the Stranger&quot;, Lili&#39;s performance in the drama attracted several directors to inquire about digital human technology solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Science fiction film director Qiao Fei also paid attention to Lili&#39;s performance in the TV series, but he believed that from the perspective of the big screen presentation effect, the film narrative has extremely high requirements on the actors&#39; tiny expressions and movements, and subtle performances are hidden. It contains a wealth of information, but the level of delicacy of digital human performance is far from ideal. &quot;What real people can do easily, it costs a lot to hand it over to AIGC.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Qiao Fei&#39;s view, digital human actors only provide a technical alternative similar to traditional special effects production. Unless digital people can accumulate IP value, they will have the same brand spillover benefits as celebrity artists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vLH9Sds1AvaEOKfHLMtuWaQ9l1SmOVUwru5A42vh.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vLH9Sds1AvaEOKfHLMtuWaQ9l1SmOVUwru5A42vh.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After a real person wears facial capture and motion capture equipment, it can drive the digital human image to make the same movements in real time. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Maiquan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Surge in demand for virtual live broadcasts&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Digital human production companies receive more demand from brand digital human image customization or digital human IP in a certain project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seyou Technology, founded in 2014, is the technology provider of digital humans for the Hangzhou Asian Games. After obtaining the image of the digital human from the Asian Games, Shiyou Technology&#39;s goal is to make the digital human move, and use AR technology to complete the visual image output of the digital human running and igniting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Chong came to Shiyou Technology in 2016 as the head of marketing. In the early days, her customers mainly came from the field of radio and television, customizing real-time interactive virtual hosts. In 2018, the increased requirements for visual teaching materials in the education field brought a large demand. After 2019, the epidemic forced various industries to move online, and brand virtualization Demand for live streaming has surged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a brand’s investment ratio tilts towards online, in order to better achieve brand exposure, companies often customize a set of digital human images. Shiyou Technology has provided customized services for brand image digital people and IP-based virtual digital employees for companies such as JD.com, Tmall, Haier Brothers, and Suning.com. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, Jinpai officially announced its first digital employee-Dongfang Jin, who also serves as the company&#39;s brand ambassador. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongfang Jin, who made his debut, was wearing a red Tang suit, black suit pants and black leather shoes. He was holding a paper fan and had a tall and tall figure. This digital human model is technically supported by Guangzhou Fantuo Digital Innovation. Fantuo Shuchuang is a company specializing in digital exhibition hall design. Fantuo Digital&#39;s 2022 financial report shows that the digital human project is its new business, accounting for only 2% of total revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Lilan, the person in charge of the Dongfangjin project, told Southern Weekend reporters that digital people are a way for brands to increase communication with users, such as participating in marketing activities and conducting Q&amp;A interactions with consumers in the holographic warehouse of corporate exhibition halls. . &quot;When visiting a company, there will still be dedicated experience specialists to receive consumers, involving a series of tasks such as accommodation, guidance, explanations, etc. This is something that digital people cannot replace.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Lilan will later be responsible for Dongfangjin&#39;s marketing For event or content operation work, Fantuoshu Creation provides technical support to partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within Jinpai, the Dongfangjin project is a typical project of digital transformation. &quot;The content and budget of the (Dongfangjin) project have been determined. Compared with some marketing activity projects, the budget of this project is not high.&quot; Liu Lilan said that if subsequent content operators have new needs, they will still increase the budget. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Sun Never Sets&quot; Live Broadcast Room&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, you can often see this video on short video platforms: rows of workers in the office There were no real people in the seats, there was a screen on each table, and the anchor on it kept introducing the products. The person in the video reminded that the anchors on the screen are all digital people and can work for you 24 hours a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tireless digital people hit the pain points of practitioners in the live broadcast industry. Below the video, there are multiple messages asking how to purchase such a digital anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;service-oriented digital humans&quot; launched by various digital human technology manufacturers are digital human images driven by AI that can be separated from real people and can serve content output fields such as news broadcasting, live broadcasting, and customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You only need to provide pictures or videos, and AI will automatically simulate and reproduce a 2D digital image that is almost the same as a real person. Enter text or voice, and AI can allow the digital person to make mouth shapes and expressions that fit the content. and action. Some AI digital people can even freely convert the voices of multiple countries to achieve a perfect fit of mouth shape and smooth and natural movements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter’s search found that leading domestic cloud vendors have also launched similar AI digital human products, such as Baidu Cloud, Tencent Cloud, Alibaba Cloud, Huawei Cloud, iFlytek, JD.com, Volcano Engine, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of these platforms provide monthly subscription services. Ordinary users can use the built-in public models, voices, actions, etc. on the digital human generation platform. After entering the background, they can edit and generate short videos of the digital human just like editing text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the iFlytek Smart Production Platform as an example. The price of an ordinary member is 399 yuan per month. Users with high-frequency production needs can purchase an exclusive membership for 2,999 yuan per month. Tencent Intelligent Video provides non-members with a five-minute digital human broadcast experience per month. The most expensive professional membership is only 598 yuan a year, and enjoys 30 minutes of digital human video and 600 AI paintings per month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters consulted in the name of customers and found that due to different rules of live broadcast platforms, digital live broadcasts are still difficult to achieve across multiple platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud Digital Human mainly provides digital human anchors within the Taobao ecosystem. Alibaba Cloud Sales introduced that Taobao supports digital human anchors, and the traffic allocation for real anchors and digital human anchors is treated equally. Hangzhou Qianxun and Nanjing Silicon Foundation also cooperated to launch digital human anchors to make up for the problems of limited energy and high cost of real anchors. Digital humans self-broadcast in stores late at night and during non-prime time periods, extending the live broadcast time and improving the effectiveness of the anchors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businesses are eager to use AI anchors to create a live broadcast room where the sun never sets. In the view of some platforms, this is damaging to the live broadcast ecosystem. The pre-sales customer service of Volcano Engine stated that the digital human live broadcast service has not yet been launched, and &quot;Douyin does not allow digital human live broadcasts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Douyin, some bloggers also reported the risk of &quot;account ban&quot; caused by using digital live broadcasts. Some are because the platform determines that digital live broadcasts are recorded broadcasts, and some are due to the use of public models. Despite this, some digital live broadcast merchants are still instructing merchants on how to avoid triggering platform account suspension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters anonymously consulted two Douyin users who had purchased Digital Man’s live broadcast. One user said that Digital Man’s live broadcast had zero sales in the first week, and the other pointed out that Digital Man’s live broadcast room could not attract people. Real users watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Fei pointed out that the greatest value of live broadcast is that it can bring companionship to the audience. The audience can capture a lot of emotional information from the real anchor, but digital people cannot provide it, which is why digital people cannot retain the audience. reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But digital people still have certain advantages in batch output content. Shen Jianyou gave an example. For short video operators, they have to process a large amount of video content every day. Shooting and cutting videos takes up a lot of time and energy. Digital short videos only need to replace the text content to quickly generate video files, which improves Work efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多专家谈罗威纳犬咬伤女童：“关键在管理人，其次才是管理狗”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258846]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 23:06:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the vicious dog bit the girl, the dog owner was taken criminal coercive measures. (Visual China /Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/74c490000c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/74c490000c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the vicious dog bit the girl, the owner of the dog was subject to criminal coercive measures. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 16, 2023, a 2-year-old girl in Chongzhou, Chengdu, Sichuan was attacked by a black Rottweiler in the community The attack resulted in multiple bites all over the body, contusions and lacerations on the right kidney, and fractured ribs on the right side. After the incident attracted widespread attention, on the evening of October 17, the Chongzhou City Joint Investigation Team issued a situation report. At about 3 o&#39;clock on October 17, the owner of the black Rottweiler arrived at the case. The police have opened a case for investigation into the incident and taken criminal coercive measures against Tang, the owner of the black Rottweiler dog, in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that Rottweiler, as a large working dog, is often used by military and police departments for riot control and inspection. In many cities, including Mianyang, Hangzhou, Shanghai, Guangzhou, etc., it is listed as a restricted or banned breed; but in Chengdu, it does not appear in the list of 22 breeds of violent dogs that are banned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Each city has a different definition and understanding of fierce dogs. Some cities think that large dogs are fierce dogs, and some cities think that they are aggressive dogs. They are fierce dogs, so the banned breeds vary in each city.&quot; Zhang Yongbing, secretary-general of the Sichuan Pet Association, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the opinion of &quot;Hai Shi&quot; (screen name), a member of the China Rottweiler Club (CKURK), in this incident, the black Rottweiler The owner should bear most or even all of the responsibility: large dogs like Rottweilers must not &lt;span>;wear&lt;/span>; a leash when walking the dog, &quot;just like a driver driving without a seat belt.&quot; In addition, Haishi also mentioned that this kind of anti-riot dog with strong strength and strong bite ability also needs scientific feeding from dog owners. &lt;/span>; “A working dog like the Rottweiler, which ranks high in obedience and intelligence, needs stability first. The first step it takes out of the house is to &lt;span>;wear&lt;/span>; it properly. Leash.&quot; Haishi emphasized that &quot;the key to raising large dog breeds in cities is to manage people, followed by dogs.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many interviewees said that incidents of fierce dogs injuring people in the city are not isolated cases. Although regulations regulating dog-raising behavior in various cities stipulate that dogs should use leashes when leaving the house and dogs must not be abandoned, the effect of law enforcement is still limited. How to regulate the uncivilized dog-keeping behavior in daily life has become a challenge for the current refined urban management. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The list of prohibited dogs varies greatly from place to place&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 1, 2010, the &quot;Chengdu Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; were officially implemented. The regulations stipulate that dog-raising households in restricted areas are limited to one dog per household; individuals are prohibited from raising aggressive dogs and large dogs; dog owners are not allowed to abuse or abandon dogs. In addition, the regulations also stipulate that when dog owners take their dogs out of the house, they should put the dogs in a dog cage, a dog bag, or be led by a person with full capacity for civil conduct using a dog leash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the first city in the country to enact dog-raising regulations, Chengdu has continued to use this management regulation for the next 13 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Zhang Yongbing found that 13 years later, this document had a lot to add and improve. For example, among the banned breeds, Zhang Yongbing suggested updating the list of banned aggressive dogs based on the dog’s personality and aggression. In addition, community property management can also play a greater role in stopping uncivilized dog-raising behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the national laws and regulations database and found that after 2020, various places have intensively introduced dog breeding management regulations in the form of local regulations. However, not all cities have introduced similar management regulations, and different places have different approaches regarding the types of dogs that are prohibited and how to hold owners accountable for uncivilized pet-raising behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the number of dogs owned by residents, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Hangzhou, Shenzhen and other cities have stipulated that each household in the management area is limited to one dog. However, Shenzhen stipulates that those who keep two or more dogs must &quot;comply with the relevant conventions of the community or residential area where they are located, and provide proof of consent from the neighborhood committee or property owners committee&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cities such as Beijing, Hangzhou, Changsha, Wuhan, Xi&#39;an and other cities have included the Rottweiler dogs in Chongzhou that are prohibited from raising by individuals. , but in cities such as Shenzhen in Guangdong, Xiamen in Fujian and Guangyuan in Sichuan, they are not included in the list. In the list of prohibited dogs in some cities, dog breeds such as Bernese Mountain Dog, Akita Dog, Chinese Pastoral Dog, and Jugui also appear; but in other cities, the above dog breeds are not on the list of prohibited dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What kind of protection should be taken when taking aggressive dogs and large dogs out? Cities such as Beijing, Chongqing, Xi&#39;an, Shenzhen, and Zhuhai stipulate that dog owners need to add extra protection to their dogs. Wear a muzzle, but Chengdu has not made more detailed regulations on the need for large and violent dogs to wear muzzles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although most dog-raising regulations do not allow dog owners to abandon dogs, based on the analysis of the regulations, whether various places should pursue abandonment and how to punish them, The scales are also different:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangyuan City does not stipulate the punishment for abandoned dogs; Hangzhou stipulates that abandoned, lost and confiscated dogs shall be punished by the city The dog authorities handle the matter uniformly; Chongqing, Qingdao and other cities stipulate that abandoning dogs will be punished with fines; Jinan stipulates that individuals who abuse or abandon dogs will be fined not less than 2,000 yuan but not more than 20,000 yuan, and those who indulge or drive dogs to intimidate Anyone who harms others or harms others will be punished in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Public Security Administration Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. Those suspected of committing crimes will also be held criminally responsible in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;May 2021, Beijing, a Rottweiler dog at the Pet Carnival event. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8870cf9b93.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/18/8870cf9b93.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999 ;&quot;>;In May 2021, a Rottweiler dog was seen at the Beijing Pet Carnival event. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;City dog ​​regulations have weak penalties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Many interviewees believe that although different cities have different regulations on dog raising, there are more practical reasons that lead to uncivilized dog raising behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Wei, director of the Jiangsu Provincial Zoological Society, told Southern Weekend reporters that he prefers to understand the entire incident from the perspective of the industrial chain. He believes that the current management model that distinguishes restricted areas from non-restricted areas has caused many problems. &quot;The management intensity of restricted and non-restricted areas in our country is very different. The problems of free-range breeding, disorderly breeding, and non-vaccination in rural areas are serious. Many (dog) vicious injuries occur in rural areas; breeding households have serious problems with dogs. It&#39;s just improper management&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>; or even malicious abandonment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, domestic breeding is still stuck in the &quot;treating pets as economic &quot;animal&quot; stage and are bred and raised extensively. “For dogs, three to fourteen weeks is generally a critical period for their socialization, but most breeders do not have the ability and awareness to help puppies for sale establish good behavioral habits so that they can adapt to living with people in the future. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Jie, director of the Shanghai Gongyi Law Firm, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that the treatment of the dog owner Tang was not based on the relevant dog owner. Instead, Tang was held legally responsible based on the crime of negligence causing serious injury in the criminal law. &quot;As the manager of dogs in the city and also the handler of injury cases, the public security department has the right to decide whether to intervene in such cases.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Yongbing believes that due to the limited manpower of law enforcement agencies, the current urban dog management regulations are not like a preventive measure. Relevant departments often only intervene after problems occur. In actual operation, it is still difficult to have some mandatory measures to deal with the uncivilized dog-raising behavior of citizens, and it is easy for loopholes in supervision to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The intensity, difficulty and cost of law enforcement are all too high.&quot; Chen Jie believes that the current dog-raising regulations in various places impose penalties for uncivilized dog-raising behavior. It is not too serious, which means that this is an act that requires citizens to be conscious and self-disciplined. &quot;A person who can raise a dog shows that he has certain financial ability and cultural accomplishment, and can also abide by the rules. But at present, there are still many aspects that deserve vigilance and attention.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Chen Jie, Du Fan and many other &lt;span>;interviewers&lt;/span>; believe that in addition to local dog-raising regulations, there is more to regulating the dog-raising behavior of urban residents. It requires the cooperation of multiple forces in the city to establish a refined management dog breeding system. In addition to the public security department, it also requires the participation of different forces such as market supervision, property management, and dog owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Compared with catching and beating dogs that may occur after the incident, the source of the aggressive dogs is more suspicious.&quot; Du, President of Wuhan Small Animal Protection Association Fan Xiang, a reporter from Southern Weekend, analyzed that if dog owners can continue to purchase aggressive dogs that are prohibited by city dog-raising regulations from the market, it will be difficult to prevent such tragedies from the source. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Yongbing suggested that in addition to dog owners learning the corresponding management systems before raising dogs, property companies currently restrict some behaviors of dog owners in the community. More can be done. &quot;They (property companies) should also conduct some professional training and learning, such as how to identify the type of dog, how to stop an attacking dog, and stop the uncivilized dog-raising behavior of some owners who do not listen to persuasion, etc.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;After discovering an ownerless or aggressive dog, the property company can report it to the public security organ for disposal, but they do not have the power to kill it. According to the tort liability code of the Civil Code &quot;The property management company has the obligation to ensure safety in the community. If a resident is injured by a domestic dog or a stray dog ​​in the community, the property management company, as the relevant responsible party, must also bear the liability for supplementary compensation.&quot; Chen Jie proposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从自由市场谈“父权”与“资本”的矛盾性]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258662]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some people like to talk about &quot;patriarchy and capitalism&quot; and connect &quot;patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capitalism&quot; At the same time, it is actually very inaccurate. This concept is similar to the term &quot;feudal autocracy&quot; because logically speaking, since it is feudal, it is obvious that it cannot be &quot;autocratic&quot;. And &quot;autocracy&quot; cannot be feudal. Similarly, if there really is &quot;paternal authority&quot;, that is, the kind of powerful patriarch that many people imagine, who can strictly control their children, then the children will naturally not be able to freely enter big cities to work. And under the conditions of capital and free markets, it is actually very easy for a woman or man to get rid of &quot;patriarchy&quot; and enter a big city as a free atomic individual to work in a company cubicle. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capital&quot; are contradictory&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In other words, it is precisely the free market, &quot;capital&quot; and modern enterprises that allow a large number of women/men to become &quot;independent workers&quot; female/male” rather than continuing to obey traditional “patriarchal” dictates. In fact, if you think about it for a moment, if you are a traditional &quot;father&quot; who cares very much about your authority over your children, and you see your children running to work in the markets of big cities and breaking away from your authority, will you applaud or applaud? Will be very angry? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, capital and market economy are exactly what dismantle &quot;patriarchy&quot;, at least for most ordinary people. In traditional &quot;patriarchal&quot; societies, people&#39;s lives are dominated by mutual assistance and division of labor in small agricultural communities, and they need to respect family authority and various authoritative customs. However, in the market economy lifestyle, all other needs besides work can be obtained through commercial purchases. A modern independent woman/man can live alone without buying food to cook, order takeout when hungry, and shop at will online. Just live a happy life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highly developed living conditions of modern market economy will of course bring about new problems, such as atomized lifestyle, the collapse of family values, the low fertility rate in big cities, etc. But in any case, it is absurd to bring &quot;patriarchy&quot; and &quot;capital&quot; together, because the two are precisely contradictory. &quot;Patriarchy&quot; feels that with the rise of &quot;capital&quot; and the market, their children have gone to big cities, and their authority has collapsed. In &quot;capital&quot;, everyone is a customer. I don&#39;t care whether your customer wants to be a &quot;patriarch&quot; or an &quot;independent woman/man&quot;. Anyway, as long as you pay, I will provide you with products and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The free market is an accelerator&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Hayek said that in the capital market, every purchase by customers and consumers is a vote, and the market produces the products that best satisfy their needs. A company, brand or business model that customers want. Ordinary people who were destined to have a humble status in pre-modern society have become owners with the ability to vote in the era of capital markets. This is an important progress. Hayek&#39;s judgment is very correct. Under capital and market conditions, if a woman/man wants to be a &quot;modern independent woman/man&quot;, it will be too late for &quot;capital&quot; to please him and will tend to cater to all the life he likes. way to provide a variety of business services that he prefers. In order to cater to traffic, self-media will also be happy to produce various articles that &quot;modern independent women/men&quot; like to read. To a certain extent, it is precisely in order to cater to customers that &quot;capital&quot; is happy to produce text products such as &quot;Patriarchy and Capitalism&quot; that customers like to read. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a paradox, but the logic of &quot;capital&quot; is indeed the same. Capital will provide whatever customers need. In other words, &quot;capital&quot; itself is neutral and does not matter good or evil. The products it embodies represent the interests of the customer group. As for the consequences after customers enjoy these products, &quot;capital&quot; does not care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a severely obese junk food lover, &quot;capital&quot; can provide him with a large amount of cheap junk food and &quot;Fat House Happy Water&quot; because this is the demand of customers. For a person who is interested in weight loss and fitness and has strong willpower, &quot;capital&quot; can develop various commercial services for weight loss and fitness, and help this customer achieve a satisfactory body shape. If a person is keen on watching soap operas or playing games, &quot;capital&quot; can provide such nipple entertainment in large quantities at low prices and high quality, and its entertainment effect is unmatched by any pre-modern era. And if a person wants to read high-end classical works, gold inscriptions and silk scrolls, ancient Greek, and Latin, &quot;capital&quot; will also provide them with relevant commercial services, and the price is cheaper than at any time in pre-modern times, and it can be obtained more easily. universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, &quot;capital&quot; does not care about the value dimension at all. It is neutral and provides whatever customers need. &quot;Patriarchy&quot; and &quot;modern independent women/men&quot; are all value dimensions. Whether a person wants to indulge in fat house happy water or lose weight and keep fit, &quot;capital&quot; can provide services. In other words, &quot;capital&quot; is just a huge, efficient accelerator that helps people get what they need more efficiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Everyone pays for their own preferences&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;But the results of these options are paid by the customers themselves, and &quot;capital&quot; is not responsible for the consequences of these choices. As a species of Homo sapiens, many of our &quot;personal hobbies&quot; are actually just natural instincts that have been engraved into our genes for 200,000 years of lifestyle, and are not as &quot;personal&quot; and individual as we imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people like pets. The images of pets with chubby round faces and big eyes are actually the closest thing to human infants and young children. In the evolutionary path of Homo sapiens for 200,000 years, this preference for chubby, round faces and big eyes has been engraved into the genes. In pre-modern societies, this was natural. It’s only in modern big cities and with the emergence of new cultures that people have the conditions to deceive this long-term instinct. At this time, &quot;capital&quot; can provide services, such as various pet markets, cute animal industry chains, and cute animal subcultures. As long as customers demand it, &quot;capital&quot; will continue to provide these services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fat House Happy Water, high-sugar and high-oil snacks, etc., the love for sweetness and fat is also an ancient instinct in the long process of evolution and is engraved in genes. It&#39;s just that the body of Homo sapiens never dreamed that the industrial revolution would produce a huge amount of high-carbohydrate food, and it was not adapted to the two, so it often resulted in &quot;fat homes&quot;. &quot;Capital&quot; effectively satisfies this primitive love for carbohydrates and fats, and &quot;fat house&quot; has therefore become a way of life in big cities. The killings and wars in video games are actually the elements that Homo sapiens have been most familiar with for 200,000 years and have been engraved in their genetic instincts, that is, wars or hunting between tribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, due to the increased threshold after entering big cities and modern life, for example, in the past, a woman might see Zhang San, a young man who was strong and good-looking in the village, and he was an ideal candidate. . But in modern big cities and lifestyles, all kinds of movies, TV shows, advertisements, and short videos are full of handsome Obamas, and the threshold has been greatly increased. So &quot;capital&quot; provides idol dramas, that is to say, &quot;capital&quot; can very efficiently get people&#39;s needs. As for the results after customers get it, &quot;capital&quot; doesn&#39;t care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The developed capital markets and commerce in modern big cities can completely separate people from small communities such as traditional families and rural areas, and lead a very atomized home-boy and home-girl life. In terms of comfort, this kind of atomized urban individual is relatively comfortable, although it will be accompanied by some problems. Then which lifestyle to choose can be freely chosen based on different people&#39;s time preferences, and &quot;capital&quot; will help them get the content they choose faster. Of course, the lifestyle in modern big cities will also have &quot;capital&quot; to produce related culture to argue that the atomized lifestyle is advanced and free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people stand in a position of sympathy and understanding of &quot;patriarchy&quot;. From the perspective of conspiracy theory, they feel that this is a &quot;capital conspiracy&quot;, and even speculate that this is a &quot;transnational XX capital conspiracy&quot;, which is to be dismantled. Family and childbearing culture. Objectively speaking, this conspiracy theory is absurd, and no secret group could devise such a conspiracy. This big city phenomenon is actually determined by the neutral force of &quot;capital&quot; itself. This also shows that since it is &quot;capital&quot;, it is impossible to be &quot;patriarchal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Capital&quot; is a neutral accelerator, so in this era, groups who choose different values ​​and lifestyles will get the results of their choice more efficiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some family businesses in the southeast region attach great importance to traditional family values ​​and maintain a relatively good fertility culture. Of course, when doing business with foreign countries, it doesn’t matter what the customers want. But earning money from customers can help the reproduction of your family. In other words, business and your own life are two different things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern developed capital and free markets actually give people more diversified and free choices. If an otaku is willing to choose &quot;Happy Water&quot; and play a successful hero in an online game, that is It&#39;s your choice, just bear the consequences of your choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely &quot;capital&quot; that allows more people to have a variety of choices and live an atomic and individual free life that the ancestors of Homo sapiens never dared to imagine for 200,000 years, with almost no restrictions. constraints of traditional community ties. Therefore, it is absurd to associate “capital” with “patriarchy”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[京津冀洪灾后的这两月：弥合的伤口，艰难的重生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258800]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 17, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, villagers received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. .(Visual China/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/389c90cd00.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 17, 2023, villagers in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province received disaster relief materials donated by all walks of life. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When floods besieged Zhuozhou, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Wholesale Market was the hardest hit area. More than a month has passed, and the smell of rotten protein and slightly sweet fermentation that once permeated the market has dissipated. The wind blows, raising the dust that the remaining silt has dried up, leaving only a smell of earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the floods first receded, only mud was left in Xiu Mingyu’s shop, an auto parts dealer. There were yellow water stains on the walls and several large cabinets. Nishui Yinzi&#39;s loss of auto parts is roughly estimated at 300,000 yuan - on a good day, her annual income is only around 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The most terrible thing is that in April 2023, Xiu Mingyu had just paid the arrears of store rent, which she had to borrow 100,000 yuan from a friend. Qi. The lease expires in April next year. If the store cannot reopen, the rent will be in vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In late July and early August 2023, extreme heavy rains swept across the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region, causing floods in many places in Beijing and Hebei. Among them, the people who are most affected by floods are the people living around Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On weekdays, the prosperity of Beijing seems to be within reach. But when disaster strikes, the test they face becomes even more severe. In October 2023, when there were no traces of floods in the core urban areas of Beijing, they were still working hard to rebuild their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/461ad7fd7e.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Xinfadi Dashiqiao Agricultural Products Wholesale Market in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“How much business can compensate for losses?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Both rented cooked food at Dashiqiao Wholesale Market Lin Fenyi, who works at the stall, did not work up the courage until August 8 to go to her cooked food processing factory in Congyuan Village, Zhuozhou City to see the aftermath of the disaster: four cold storages had holes ripped open by water, maggots were crawling on the rotten meat, and the air was filled with It was filled with a stench that reached straight to the Tianling Cap. She wiped away tears on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After wiping away the tears, the factory was still saved. Lin Fenyi spent 40,000 yuan to hire a forklift to shovel mud, but it turned out that she could not drive into the factory. She took a big shovel and used human power to push the mud out of the factory door little by little, and then the forklift shoveled it to the roadside. The rotting meat was dug and buried in pits. When the pits were filled, the carrion was piled on the road, and the village sent people to push it off the field. Xiu Mingyu was also very busy trying to reopen the store. For a month, she went to the shop at 8 a.m. every morning to wash and wash her hands, and worked until 7 p.m. at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 1st, the store reopened, with white walls and shelves full of new products, giving it the appearance of a new life. But the troubles kept coming one after another. The new container I bought for several thousand yuan soon swelled due to the moisture in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiu Mingyu is in urgent need of funds. She received a call from someone claiming to be a bank employee, asking if she needed a loan. The store&#39;s goods were short of 80,000 to 100,000 yuan, but she couldn&#39;t trust the private number calling from Liaoning. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Business is also deserted. Xiu Mingyu guessed that her store was on a low ground, and after the flood, no one would dare to go to the store to buy anything when it rained. However, even if the customer flow remains the same, &quot;How much business can compensate for these losses?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the flood just passed, she was not sure about post-disaster livelihood. A month later, she was already a little calm. She felt comfortable earning a small amount of money in the store. As long as she wanted to open up, she could make do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After spending 300,000 yuan, Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory also resumed production in mid-September. She desperately tried to make up for the losses of the past month or so. During the factory shutdown, some old customers turned to other manufacturers to place orders. For this reason, she thought of a &quot;ruthless move&quot;: &quot;People sell pig head meat in the market now, and half a catty sells for 12 yuan, so I have to sell it for 11...I won&#39;t make a penny, dragging my former customers. Don&#39;t drag customers.&quot; , you have no transaction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The transaction is open, but the &quot;pulse&quot; is still very weak. Before the disaster, Lin Fenyi pledged 1 million yuan on the goods and spent another 1 million yuan on expanding the factory. She said there was almost &quot;no money&quot; on the books. After work resumed, she had to lay off only three or four workers; condensing machines , sausage filling machines and other machines were all scrapped, and there was no money to replace them. After three days of resumption of production, the shipment volume was only one ton, which was one-sixth of the original maximum production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Debts accumulated quickly. In addition to the hundreds of thousands of yuan she borrowed to expand the factory, she also owes money to various suppliers. One of the pig trotters suppliers, who owed more than 10,000 yuan, came to collect payment several times and was &quot;really getting worried.&quot; Lin Fenyi showed the other party screenshots of her WeChat balance. One time it was a few hundred yuan, and another time it was just over a thousand yuan. &quot;It&#39;s not enough for my children to go to school and buy things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Xitan Village, Zhuozhou City, Du Huanying, who runs a nursing home in partnership with Yan Cheng, is also in a similar predicament. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The nursing home covers an area of ​​5 acres and has more than 60 rooms. Du Huanying remembered that before the flood came, the government moved 58 elderly people in the nursing home to another nursing home in the city in advance because the nursing home was located on a low ground. By August 7, 6 elderly people had been picked up by their family members, and 2 elderly people had passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After borrowing 500,000 yuan to invest, Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home partially resumed operations. On the afternoon of September 15, the nursing home was filled with iron frame beds that had been moved out, and Du Huanying was wiping the rust spots on the bed. She said that the elderly people who had been temporarily moved out had been moved back into their homes, but the economic losses exceeded one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab5c15a579.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Du Huanying’s nursing home in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the Hebei Provincial Local Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, as of August 23, Zhuozhou City’s financial institutions had visited a total of 1,584 matching companies. households, with loans of 108.905 million yuan issued; the city&#39;s rural housing insurance has prepaid 26,960 households, a total of 80.88 million yuan; planting insurance has prepaid 105,300 acres, a total of 52.6222 million yuan; breeding insurance has prepaid 11,644 heads, a total of 17.1295 million yuan; Vehicle insurance has paid out compensation for 10,157 vehicles, up to 658 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to CCTV, after the disaster, 14 counties (cities, districts) in Baoding provided counterpart support to 11 towns in Zhuozhou. By the beginning of October, a total of 28 construction teams with 1,040 people from outside Zhuozhou had helped the affected people repair their houses. In addition, the total number of flooded houses in Zhuozhou City is 54,323. Excluding those who are not willing to rebuild, the total number of restoration and reconstruction tasks is 52,843, and 46,706 have been completed. All 124 dilapidated and collapsed buildings that need to be completed in 2023 have started construction, and people&#39;s production and living order is being restored at an accelerated pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Life around Beijing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beijing has a complex meaning for Xiu Mingyu. Today, many of her customers are car owners commuting between Beijing and Zhuozhou. But she once had to leave Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than 20 years ago, Xiu Mingyu left his hometown in Henan and went to Beijing. He started as a supermarket salesperson with a monthly salary of 400 yuan, and his husband learned to do auto repair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The couple&#39;s life has always been tight. After deducting living expenses from their salary, there is not much money left. In 2009, a child was born, and life became even less affluent. A family of three lived in an urban village in Haidian District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After working in a supermarket for seven or eight years, in 2014, Xiu Mingyu decided to open an auto parts store with her husband. A year later, the couple moved to Shijingshan District on the outskirts of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The store was still being renovated, and the two received a clearance notice again. Now recalling the experience of being forced to move twice, Xiu Mingyu is glad that when she left Shijingshan, at least the local government compensated her for the cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Fenyi also worked as a North Piao. When she was sixteen or seventeen, she left her hometown in Heilongjiang and went to Beijing to sell clothes, where she met her husband, who was a construction worker at the time. In 2004, the two got married and returned to their husband&#39;s hometown in Zhuozhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I first returned to Zhuozhou, life was not easy. Lin Fenyi remembers that when she was in confinement after giving birth to her daughter, her husband’s old house still had cracks in it. Her father did not dare to come see her. After his brother came, he asked: &quot;Sister, how can you find such a poor person? How can you live in such a house?&quot; He introduced his sister to a way out, making cooked food, &quot;It&#39;s better to do some small business.&quot; It’s better than working for someone else.” The couple slowly started a cooked food business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng didn’t have to leave his hometown. He prides himself on being &quot;very smart&quot;. In a township in Zhuanghe City, Liaoning Province, he learned to be a doctor and carpenter at the age of 17, drove a large truck, ran an oil mill, a wood processing factory, and worked as an agricultural machinery station. Webmaster. After struggling for more than ten years, his hometown was about to be flooded due to the construction of a reservoir. He became a &quot;reservoir immigrant&quot; and went to Zhuozhou to live with his relatives in 2000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he arrived in Zhuozhou, Yan Cheng also struggled a lot. He once ran an auto repair shop and earned 300,000 yuan a year. However, he had to close down due to an accident in 2008. In 2015, he joined Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nursing homes are not a profitable business. Du Huanying said that their fees are not high to begin with, but special groups who encounter family difficulties only charge cost. The hospital only earns 150,000 yuan a year, but the investment is huge. Initially, the two spent 2.8 million yuan building a courtyard for more than 40 elderly people. Later, a local official suggested that they expand, so they spent more than 2 million yuan to expand a second courtyard in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The second courtyard had just been completed when it encountered an epidemic. The nursing home is under closed management and cannot admit new elderly people. Yan Cheng&#39;s son-in-law said that during the epidemic, they did not ask the elderly family members to pay for various medicines. &quot;It has not been easy to make money for three years during the epidemic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Lin Fenyi&#39;s eyes, her business has not been making money for a long time. In the beginning, she and her husband knew nothing, so they could only throw in three to five thousand yuan to accumulate experience. If a batch of goods was broken, they would throw it away and replace it with another batch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This line is dirty and tiring. When stewing pig heads, work starts at 5 a.m. and the pig heads are shaved first. This work makes people covered in oil. Afterwards, the brains are cut open, and the pig head divided into two sections is boiled in a pot. After cooking, the bones and meat are separated, washed, bagged, and put in the cold storage to freeze. The work can only be finished at eight or nine in the evening. There is no heating in the winter. The place - about ten years ago, my husband&#39;s old house was demolished, and the family had to live in the factory bungalow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/e71a2c79cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 13, 2023, Linfen Yijia’s factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After so many years, their lives are finally on the right track: Xiu Mingyu opened a shop, bought a house, and settled down in Zhuozhou. The fate of being constantly exiled seems to have come to an end; Yan Cheng and Du Huanying&#39;s nursing home survived the epidemic, and even elderly people from Beijing came to stay there; Lin Fenyi&#39;s factory gradually made money, hired workers, and her husband took care of it. When it comes to purchasing goods, she is in charge of sales, and the cooked food is sold to Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until the flood hit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Cheng is 64 years old and cannot retire yet. &quot;I have to help her (Du Huanying). If I don&#39;t, she will fall down immediately.&quot; The cost of building a nursing home is still nearly 4 million yuan, and new debts have been incurred after the flood. This old man, who had been swallowed by water twice in his life, decided to work for a few more years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The missing son, the deceased wife&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son Ma Lihua disappeared in the mudslide more than two months ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Initially, Ma Xianlin, a villager in Tangjiazhuang Village, Laishui County, pinned his hope of finding his son on an excavator. By mid-September, he had no choice but to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;21-year-old Ma Lihua is a student majoring in imaging medicine and will just graduate in the summer of 2023. He was supposed to have a life slowly unfolding in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tangjiazhuang Village is one of the villages severely affected by this round of heavy rains and floods. On July 31, Ma Xianlin narrowly escaped from the mudslide that poured into the yard, but Ma Lihua was nowhere to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The son should have walked out of this mountain. When she was a child, Ma Lihua occasionally said she didn&#39;t want to study anymore, and Ma Xianlin would always show up and give her own account: He dropped out of elementary school in the third grade and was uneducated, so he had to work in a coal mine. Earning money was difficult and dangerous. So, my son returned to school obediently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, Ma Lihua just completed more than nine months of hospital internship and graduated from a college in Tangshan. During the summer, he was learning to drive while planning for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ma Xianlin said that a relative in Zhuolu County once wanted to introduce his son to a job in a small hospital, but he refused and insisted on going to Beijing. My sister, who has been a fitness instructor in Beijing for 10 years, also wants to take her younger brother with her. If she can&#39;t go to a big hospital, she goes to a small clinic. She remembered that her brother once asked her if she wanted to go outside to practice. She replied decisively, &quot;Just stay by my side.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, the day when siblings get together may never come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first time that 65-year-old Ma Xianlin has lost a close relative. When he was 12 years old, his father was hit in the head by a falling stone while working in the production team. He died before he could be carried to the hospital. The mother was so anxious about her husband&#39;s death that she lost her sight. A few years later, several of Ma Xianlin&#39;s sisters got married and left home, leaving him and his mother alone in the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It wasn&#39;t until he was in his thirties that Ma Xianlin married a wife and had someone to take care of his mother, so he was able to go out to work. In Hebei, he worked in private coal mines and also paved roads and built walls. Four years ago, Ma Xianlin got old and couldn&#39;t move big rocks, so he bought 30 sheep and started herding them in his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The flock continues to multiply. In 2022, Ma Xianlin sold 48 lambs for 20,000 to 30,000 yuan. By this year, he already had 160 sheep. Based on the calculation of 700 yuan for a lamb and 1,400 yuan for an adult sheep, this will be a good income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly, in a mudslide, nearly half of the sheep disappeared. For more than a month after the disaster, he went up the mountain every day to look for sheep, but he harvested very little. He had a bone spur in his leg and had to take medicine every day to treat the leg pain. He had to walk up and down the mountains to herd and find sheep, which was unbearable for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am getting older and my younger (children) are gone.&quot; In the end, he made up his mind to sell all the sheep after autumn. On September 12, when asked about his future livelihood, Ma Xianlin remained silent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 15, Southern Weekend reporters contacted Ma Xianlin again, hoping to learn about the progress of his search for his son. He didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirty kilometers away in Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, 67-year-old villager Pang Shenggong also lost his loved ones in flash floods and mudslides on July 31. His wife was swept away by the current, and the family searched for seven or eight miles but could not find her. Later, someone found her body 70 to 80 kilometers away from her home and brought her back to the village for burial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/d0dd0d3c48.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;254368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 12, 2023, Xiamingyu Village, Laishui County, Hebei Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he met the Southern Weekend reporter on September 15, Pang Shenggong was no longer willing to mention this sad incident. He had just come out of the mountains, wearing a bamboo hat and his clothes were no longer messy - a month ago, he was covered in mud when cleaning up the washed-out house, and his trousers were only tied with a cloth belt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In his impression, his wife has a cheerful personality and likes to dance in the village yangko team. But three years ago, my wife had a fall. After the operation, her body was not as good as before, and she could not walk on the aisle. &quot;I can&#39;t leave you for a while,&quot; Pang Shenggong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is not easy to make a living while being chained to your home. Since the 1980s, Pang Shenggong has been working outside the home and often goes to Beijing. He worked in the coal mines of Fangshan District to dig coal and build railways. He continued to work until he was in his fifties. In order to take care of his children and go to school, he gradually stopped going out and worked small jobs in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After his wife&#39;s surgery, Pang Shenggong never worked as a minor worker again. Fortunately, the younger son is moving goods in a warehouse in Gu&#39;an County, Langfang City, so he can supplement Pang Shenggong&#39;s monthly salary of three to four thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Pang Shenggong has moved into the temporarily unused house of the third brother in the east of the village, and is ready to live a hard life. &quot;How much money do you have to spend?&quot; His voice gradually faded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Hebei Daily, on September 22, the first batch of post-disaster reconstruction projects in Laishui County have started intensively, with a total investment of 185 million yuan, including river cleaning The siltation project, four bridge reconstruction projects and the first batch of post-disaster power distribution network reconstruction projects will be completed before the 2024 flood season. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Villages in the suburbs of Beijing heal the wounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the suburbs of Beijing, mountains separate the villages from the prosperity . A flood passed through and the force of nature tore the village apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, according to villager Liu Huazao, there were originally one or two thousand people living in the village. An entire street in the south was seriously damaged by the flood. About one to two hundred people were temporarily relocated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 27, Liu Huazao&#39;s father went to Tongren Hospital for eye laser treatment. Some time ago, he always felt like mosquitoes were flying in front of his eyes. After checking, he found out that the vitreous body had fallen off. Liu Huazao felt that this was caused by his father being upset and having severe high blood pressure after the flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At around 10 a.m. on July 31, when the water rose the most, the Liu family and their neighbors climbed onto the roof to escape Shen Da. 1.7 meters of water. That night, the water came up again, leaving a second water line about 1 meter high in the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But favor is slowly closing some wounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the water receded, Liu Huazao felt &quot;it&#39;s good to be alive.&quot; The villagers who had survived the disaster met and said to each other, &quot;Just live, don&#39;t talk about anything else.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The relatives are closer. One after another, relatives outside the country reached out to help Liu Huazao&#39;s family, &quot;giving them some money.&quot; The disaster-stricken family even lacked clothes and cooking utensils. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The neighbors suddenly have a &quot;life-changing&quot; friendship. In the past, Liu Huazao didn&#39;t move around very frequently with the villagers, just &quot;meet and say hello.&quot; But he felt that the moments of life and death in the water inspired goodwill in people&#39;s hearts. On the day the family hid on the roof, a neighbor in the front yard helped hold Liu Huazao&#39;s daughter. After the disaster, the villagers helped each other. When the silt in their own homes was almost cleared, they would be cleared by others. Elderly people in the village who had children in other places would ask them what shortcomings there were in their homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembered that before the water supply in the village was restored, a group of young people organized water trucks to deliver water for washing to the villagers. For four or five days, they stopped the car at the entrance of the alley and called the villagers to get water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu, who opened a supermarket in the village, witnessed the complexity of human beings in the flood. Five to six thousand yuan in cash was taken away from the supermarket by water, but she only got back more than one thousand yuan. She heard that someone found money, but she didn&#39;t know if it was lost by her family and couldn&#39;t ask for it. She also heard that many people picked up the wine that was washed away from her home, but very little was returned. Only one bottle of 10 bottles of liquor worth more than 1,000 yuan was returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhu Xiu did not feel resentful about this. &quot;If you lose it, it&#39;s not like someone stole it from you. Whoever picked it up belongs to the one who picked it up... We just accept that we are unlucky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiuye I thought maybe insurance would pay some compensation. Last year, she took out an insurance policy in a daze. After the disaster, someone from the insurance company came and told her that the insurance was not for property, but for people. Zhu Xiu, who couldn&#39;t even find the contract, had no choice but to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also discovered the kindness between people. A winery promised to replace her damaged wine for free, and relatives and friends provided money, food, and pots and pans after the disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the supporters, many, like Zhu Xiu, are migrant workers in Beijing. &quot;There is a feeling of closeness... Being so far away from my hometown makes me feel that we can understand each other.&quot; She remembered that about 20 years ago, she and her husband first settled in Cijijiao, and later more foreigners came. Work in the village. Some migrant workers had no money left after buying tickets to Beijing, no place to sleep, and no food to eat. It was she who made noodles and steamed buns and spread bedding in the rented room to provide food and accommodation for them. When those who couldn&#39;t find a job had to leave, she would give them travel expenses. Now, it seems that goodwill from the past has been repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/de8e950d6d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 27, 2023, Cijiajia Village, Fangshan District, Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Jiang Bowen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Beijing Daily, on the morning of August 27, Fangshan District held a post-disaster reconstruction swearing-in meeting at Sandu Bridge. The overall goal of reconstruction is &quot;basic recovery in one year, comprehensive improvement in three years, and long-term high-quality development.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Xiuli, chief of the Planning and Urban Design Section of the Fangshan District Planning and Nature Commission, said in an interview with CCTV that according to Beijing&#39;s unified standards, for collapsed buildings It is recommended that dilapidated houses be demolished and rebuilt. Each house will be compensated at a rate of 95,000 yuan. For repairable houses, a repair compensation of 30,000 yuan will be given, and low-income households will receive double compensation. For houses that are uninhabitable, each person will be paid a total of 3,960 yuan for three months. rental subsidy. In addition, each person is provided with a living allowance of 660 yuan. Staff from the Fangshan District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee said that repair compensation of 30,000 yuan has been gradually distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have to stand up no matter what”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the villagers’ accounts, the flood was not the first change that Ci’s housework had experienced. , this once prosperous village has been in decline for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao remembers that the household chores thirty years ago were more generous than they are now. At that time, there was a dragon dance lantern show, a two-story shopping mall and a movie theater. What supports these are the workers in the surrounding coal mines and cement plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu&#39;s husband is one of them. More than 20 years ago, Zhu Xiu was still farming in her hometown in Anhui, and her life was difficult. When she saw a fellow villager working in Cijiujiu&#39;s cement factory, she came with her husband. Her husband followed the car in the factory, and she sold vegetables in the village. . She remembered that there were many migrant workers at that time, and dozens of people could live in a small courtyard in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the local area, factories and coal mines are a double-edged sword. Liu Huazao still remembers their pollution. When he was a child, there would be gray dust like white flour in the village. On the other hand, although working as a factory and miner does not make much money, it is a job that can make a living at home. Liu Huazao&#39;s father had worked in a cement factory in his early years, driving a tractor to transport stones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 2000, cement plants and coal mines were closed down one after another. The pollution is gone, and the livelihood at home is even more cut off. If they want to make a living, villagers can only run to the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu found that the Anhui fellows who worked at Ciji as housekeepers left one after another, but she did not leave. After her husband lost his job at the cement factory, she borrowed money from relatives and friends to open a supermarket in the village. More than ten years ago, a market was built in the village, and people from surrounding towns came to do business. The supermarket was once very prosperous. &quot;Our business used to be the best in this village.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Around 2015, the village ushered in a turning point - demolition. Some villagers chose to move away and wait to move into the resettlement community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan didn’t leave. The bus driver, who was a farmer, wanted to buy a house for himself, his son and his married daughter, but he failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family did not leave either. Apart from being dissatisfied with the compensation package, the family has gotten used to life in the village. The small courtyard can enjoy the cool air, and the elderly can grow cucumbers, tomatoes, and eggplants, and save some money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only private houses are being demolished, but around 2019, the market in front of Zhuxiujia Supermarket was also demolished and moved elsewhere. Her business gradually shrank, and the supermarket&#39;s annual revenue dropped to two to three million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, in the summer of 2023, there was a record-breaking flood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 31, villager Li Guangnan ran out with waist-deep water. On August 20, he returned to work at the bus company. More than a month later, his old life seemed to be back, but he knew that order was far from being restored. When he was working as a driver, he earned a monthly salary of nearly 10,000 yuan at most. In 2022, because of his hearing loss, he took a second job and took a cleaning job, so his monthly salary was reduced to 4,000 yuan. In two years, he will retire, and his income will be cut in half. Life may be even more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Guangnan has always been worried about his son. He has worked in both the bus and subway companies, but he didn&#39;t last long and was still old. Before the disaster, my son was driving Didi. After the flood washed away the car, he didn&#39;t even drive Didi again. At the end of September, when asked whether he wanted to return to his old career, his son only replied: &quot;Maybe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Huazao&#39;s family, who did not want to live in a high-rise building, also faced reality. Compromised. The house had to be rebuilt. Before he raised 600,000 yuan to break ground, Liu Huazao rented a house in a nearby community for a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is most worried about his 5-year-old daughter. Just after the flood, his daughter said to him: &quot;Dad, I was so scared that day.&quot; Liu Huazao told her not to be afraid, he would come to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly two months later, Liu Huazao discovered that although her daughter knew that floods would wash away tablets and toys, she still didn’t understand that floods would endanger her life, and she was mentally unstable. Something went terribly wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is also working hard to escape the shadow of the flood. Liu Huazao knows that he is the backbone of the family, and only by adjusting himself can his family feel relieved. So, he tried hard to find some little surprises for himself: plastic objects can still be used after being rinsed, and some electronic devices can still turn on their screens with a swipe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhu Xiu’s half-life hard work was gone with the water. In mid-September, when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the second time, she said that she felt quite depressed and couldn&#39;t think about it for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when she met the Southern Weekend reporter for the third time at the end of September, she finally recovered. The store still had to stay open, and she didn&#39;t want to cheat the suppliers who agreed to her credit. &quot;You have to stand up and work hard no matter what. You can&#39;t just lie down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She thought that if the business was not going well, she would open a store somewhere else. As for her hometown where she still had three acres of land, Zhu Xiu knew that she would never be able to go back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Ma Xianlin and Ma Lihua, pseudonyms are used in the article)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20家上市银行中报出炉：信贷投放最多的行业不良率高还是低？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258820]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Changes in bank credit asset quality reflect the pulse of the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin, director of the Macro-Prudential Administration Bureau of the People&#39;s Bank of China, attended the press conference on financial statistics for the third quarter of 2023 on October 13 and said that as of the end of June, the average non-performing ratio of systemically important banks was 1.27%, maintaining achieve higher asset quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin said that the total assets of systemically important banks account for 61% of the total assets of my country&#39;s banking industry and 55% of the total assets of the financial industry. Systemically important banks have relatively high structural and business complexity, and relatively strong correlations with other financial institutions. Therefore, data from systemically important banks better reflects the latest changes in the banking industry and even the macroeconomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, 19 of the 20 systemically important banks have been listed on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges, making them the most fully disclosed group in the banking industry. Since 2023, which industries have the best and worst credit assets of systemically important banks? Which banks have the most effective measures to resolve non-performing assets? Which banks have the most adequate disclosure of information about their non-performing assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;823&quot; height= &quot;1102&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/KU05QNvacT2454pc07mF5N96XaXW9ba7BNOE2Bht.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New For this purpose, researchers from the Financial Research Center conducted a special review and data analysis of the interim reports of the 20 listed banks with the largest assets (including 19 systemically important banks and China Zheshang Bank). The study found that as of the end of June, the total loan balance of 20 listed banks was nearly 150 trillion yuan, accounting for 63.5% of the total loan scale of all financial institutions; the total scale of non-performing loans was approximately 1.92 trillion yuan, accounting for approximately 48% of the total scale of non-performing assets of financial institutions. %, the average non-performing loan ratio is about 1.28%, which is lower than the average non-performing loan ratio of the banking industry of 1.62%, indicating that the credit quality of large and medium-sized commercial banks is better than that of small and medium-sized banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c1xyT4WmIiFkCsZMbpjnzE0OzRXIqazCqTH9Y9t8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the real estate industry , manufacturing and business services industries rank among the top three in terms of non-performing loan size, and the accommodation and catering industry, real estate industry and mining industry have the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The balance of non-performing credit card loans exceeded that of personal housing loans for the first time in three years, and the non-performing loan rate was 4.2 times higher than that of personal housing loans. Looking at the regional distribution of non-performing loans, the western region has the largest scale of non-performing loans, and the northeastern region has the highest average non-performing loan ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Large loan size and low NPL ratio&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Transportation, warehousing and postal industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Which Which industry receives the greatest support from bank credit? Are their NPL ratios positively or negatively related to bank support? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center combed through the interim reports of 20 listed banks and found that each bank disclosed the distribution of corporate loans in 20 major industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing and postal services are the three industries with the most credit granted by the 20 listed banks. The total loan balance of the three industries at the end of June exceeded 10 trillion. Yuan. With regulators vigorously promoting the high-quality development of the manufacturing industry, the manufacturing industry has become a credit area that major commercial banks attach great importance to. Among the 20 listed banks, 19 banks rank in the top two in terms of manufacturing investment scale. However, the leasing and business services industry ranks first among the 20 banks’ credit lending industries the most, with 10 companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Has the massive increase in industry credit been accompanied by a sharp increase in non-performing loans since then? An analysis by researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that increased credit in some industries is indeed positively related to the growth of non-performing loans. This is especially obvious in the real estate industry. As the credit scale ranks fourth in the industry and the average non-performing rate in the industry ranks second, it has become the industry with the most concentrated credit risks of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1161&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vgPrJUQ2nLXiSlObE8Fzc7N5dSltXXMiOjja0SgM.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But 20 The industry distribution of credit granted by listed banks does not completely coincide with the industry distribution of non-performing loans. As of the end of June 2023, the average non-performing ratios of the manufacturing, leasing and business services, transportation, warehousing, and postal industries that provide the most credit are only 1.8%, 1.45%, and 0.64% respectively. The real estate, manufacturing, leasing and business services industries have the highest scale of non-performing loans, with balances of non-performing loans reaching 295.1 billion, 266 billion and 208.8 billion respectively. The total scale is close to 770 billion, accounting for 57% of the non-performing balance of corporate loans. The total non-performing loans 40%. Among them, the transportation, warehousing and postal industry has credit extensions of up to 13.8 trillion yuan, but its non-performing ratio is only 0.64%. It is a typical industry with large loan scale and low non-performing ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1232&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/iOEc7BaPZJefEo0xqN46JDitJsV7XWfvxsIa9v4v.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also found , the increase in the scale of credit in a certain industry is not necessarily accompanied by the year-on-year increase in the scale of non-performing loans. For example, compared with the end of 2022, as of the end of June 2023, the manufacturing loan balance has increased by as high as 18.83%, and the loan growth rate is at the forefront of all industries, but its non-performing loan balance has remained the same or even slightly decreased compared with the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Banks are most willing to lend in the &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yangtze River Delta&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The intensity of credit support for different industries is differentiated At the same time, in which areas do banks have the greatest differentiation in their countercyclical investments? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that most of the 20 listed banks disclosed the regional distribution of credit and the regional distribution of non-performing loans, but each bank’s regional division method Not the same as above. Among them, the regional distribution rules of six banks, namely Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank of China, China Merchants Bank and China Minsheng Bank, are completely consistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1303&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DRt8TJKTWZsm2BkrO7sNFMTtJRxM7xsin7DSFAwD.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center analyzed the mid-term reports of the above-mentioned six banks and found that the six banks in the Yangtze River Delta region have the largest credit scale, the highest proportion, the fastest growth rate, and the lowest average non-performing loan ratio. Based on the conclusions of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center&#39;s special survey on Suzhou&#39;s financial ecology in April 2023 (see Southern Weekend APP&#39;s &quot;Suzhou Financial Ecology In-depth Research Special Topic&quot; for details), researchers from Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that as China&#39;s economic engine region , the financial ecology of the Yangtze River Delta region (mainly Shanghai, Jiangsu, and Zhejiang) maintains a leading level in the country. Banks generally want and are willing to lend to the real economy, and the ultra-low non-performing ratio further strengthens the banks&#39; position in the Yangtze River Delta market. Dare to lend, truly lend, and increase confidence in credit extension. Therefore, the Yangtze River Delta region is undoubtedly the area where commercial banks dare to lend the most, and it is also a must-have for the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;975&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Dur70kGK5CVsiHXWbzgWexz8143TqmT8O493XNQ2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rated system Among the five city commercial banks that are important banks, four are from the Yangtze River Delta region. The asset scale, operating efficiency and asset quality of these city commercial banks are among the best in the industry. This proves that the Yangtze River Delta region has the best financial ecological environment in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the credit growth rate of the 20 listed banks in the northeastern region (Heilongjiang, Jilin, and Liaoning) is the slowest, the credit proportion continues to shrink, and the non-performing loan ratio is high among all regions in the country. Data shows that large state-owned banks are more determined than joint-stock banks and city commercial banks in implementing the strategic intentions of decision-makers to revitalize the Northeast. The financial support of large state-owned banks to the Northeast is also the mainstay for the stable operation of the financial industry in the Northeast. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Non-performing personal mortgage loans surged&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The momentum eased&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although corporate loans are the mainstay of commercial bank credit, personal loan business is becoming increasingly important , especially personal housing loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scale of personal mortgage loans remains the largest among all personal loans of commercial banks, and the non-performing rate has been at the lowest level among all types of loan business for a long time. Therefore, it has become the most valued high-quality asset of commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes have occurred in the asset quality of personal mortgage loans? In order to facilitate comparisons with the same caliber, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center selected 10 banks’ personal mortgage businesses for statistical analysis. These 10 banks include six state-owned commercial banks, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Postal Savings Bank, and Bank of Communications, and four national joint-stock commercial banks, China Merchants Bank, Industrial Bank, Shanghai Pudong Development Bank, and Minsheng Bank. As of the end of 2022, the total scale of personal mortgage loans of 10 banks accounts for 80% of the total scale of personal mortgage loans in the banking industry. Therefore, the personal mortgage business of the 10 banks has strong industry representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research shows that starting from 2022, the growth rate of non-performing loan balances of personal housing loans has increased significantly. At the end of June 2022, the total non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 104.871 billion yuan, a sharp increase of 16.8 billion yuan from the end of 2021, with a month-on-month growth rate of 19.1%; in the second half of 2022, the non-performing balance of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks increased again. An increase of 30.4 billion yuan. By the end of 2022, the total balance of non-performing loans has increased to 135.255 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 53.6%; in the first half of 2023, the balance of non-performing loans has reached 138.629 billion yuan, a year-on-year growth rate of 32.2%, but the month-on-month growth rate is as high as fell back to 2.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/xRkvb8zHmC6C3DeBwVYm8OZgI2258FRbjRTPtyvC.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second central bank The quarterly monetary policy implementation report shows that at the end of June, the balance of personal housing loans of major financial institutions across the country (including foreign capital) was 38.6 trillion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.7%, and the first year-on-year negative growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the surge in non-performing loan balances and the stagnant growth rate of loan scale that turned negative, the non-performing rate of personal housing loans has increased significantly since 2022. At the end of June 2023, the average non-performing rate of personal housing loans of 10 listed banks was 0.48%, an increase of 0.15 percentage points from the end of 2021, an increase of 45%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQmLmbhwYwxG4bFDzfczeQ3Sx8h5E3JKG42Jh7Lw.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center believe that despite the rapid growth in the scale and non-performing ratio of personal housing loans, compared with other types of credit, personal housing loans are still high-quality assets of commercial banks and will continue to be an important part of each bank&#39;s personal loan business. focus. At the same time, the central bank and other ministries and commissions have successively introduced new housing loan policies and continued to loosen restrictions on the real estate industry. The asset quality of personal housing loan business is expected to stabilize in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Credit card business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Facing test&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to personal mortgage business, credit card business is also the strategic focus of commercial banks. How does it perform? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center comparatively analyzed the interim reports of 13 commercial banks that disclosed the quality of credit card loans and found that the credit card business has seen multiple trend changes since 2022. First, two important indicators recorded negative growth for the first time on record. Among them, at the end of 2022, the cumulative number of credit cards issued was approximately 798 million, showing negative growth for the first time on record; the outstanding credit balance of credit cards was 8.69 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 0.9%, which was significantly higher than the average annual growth rate of 8% between 2019 and 2021. decline. As of the end of June 2023, the outstanding credit balance of credit cards of 13 listed banks (the scale of credit card business accounts for about 85% of the total scale of the banking industry) was 7.44 trillion yuan, a decrease of about 23 billion yuan from the end of 2022, which was also the first time on record. decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;948&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qXTZyLm4Jp5VkvruSTMPMIke1OrjoVv0qlP6trKz.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is credit card The quality of business assets is facing tests. As of the end of June 2023, the total non-performing balance of credit card accounts receivable of 13 commercial banks reached 148.2 billion yuan, slightly exceeding personal housing loans with a limit of 4 billion yuan. Following the 2020 interim report, it has once again become the personal loan business with the largest non-performing loan. . Correspondingly, the average non-performing loan ratio of credit card receivables of 13 banks is 2.29%, which is also a new high in the past three years after the 2020 mid-term report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2023, the asset quality pressure of commercial banks’ credit card business will increase significantly. Among them, the credit card non-performing loan balance and non-performing loan ratio reached two peaks in June 2020 and June 2023 respectively, with the peak in June 2020 being slightly higher than that in June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qvLU5C5MBUN8RwU1n1rx3wRdeUZ27SX1hjcSuiRj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Researchers from the Financial Research Center further studied the two peaks and found that the peak of credit card non-performing in June 2020 was mainly due to the sudden impact of the epidemic on household and personal balance sheets, superimposed on the factors of untimely repayment caused by restricted movement of people during the epidemic; During the period when the epidemic is calming down, the balance of non-performing loans and non-performing loans of commercial banks&#39; credit cards have tended to fall, but the low point of the decline is still significantly higher than before the epidemic. Since 2023, commercial banks have responded to regulatory requirements and no longer blindly compete for land, but have turned to intensive cultivation and prudent credit extension. The growth of credit card issuance volume, credit scale, unfinished credit scale and other indicators has significantly slowed down or even experienced negative growth. This has also led to a high non-performing rate in credit card business. However, as banks continue to implement prudent strategies, credit card non-performing rates are expected to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Which banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; “&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;optimize”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; bad disclosures? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The two indicators of non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio are the most important and most sensitive indicators to measure the quality of credit assets. Which commercial banks have the courage to conduct complete and comprehensive information disclosure on the quality of their credit assets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comparative study of this item by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center is mainly based on whether 20 listed banks disclose information on corporate loans by industry and region, and whether the industry and region of non-performing loans are separately Disclosure: When disclosing the components of personal loans, including personal housing loans, consumer loans, operating loans, and credit card loan balances, proportions, and growth rates, whether the corresponding non-performing loan balances and non-performing ratios are disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study found that in terms of the quality of information disclosure on non-performing loans, the level of disclosure of 20 listed banks varied. Large state-owned banks basically disclosed the above information at the same time. Only Bank of China stated &quot;non-performing&quot; as &quot;impairment&quot; in its annual report, which may easily cause certain misunderstandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the national joint-stock banks, China Merchants Bank has the most complete disclosure of non-performing loans, while other joint-stock banks have more or less &quot;optimized&quot; non-performing loan-related data according to their own needs when disclosing. Typical &quot;optimization&quot; methods include setting personalized &quot;caliber&quot;. For example, when disclosing the industry distribution of non-performing loans, some banks do not directly disclose the non-performing loan balance and non-performing ratio data of each industry. However, through other relevant data disclosed by the bank, the distribution of non-performing loans in different industries of the bank can be estimated; For another example, when disclosing the non-performing status of personal housing loans, some banks merged this business with other personal loan businesses with certified mortgages; in addition, when disclosing the regional distribution of non-performing loans, 6 of the 9 joint-stock banks were based on the Yangtze River Delta A total of 6 regions are divided and disclosed, including the Pearl River Delta, the Bohai Rim, the central region, the western region and the northeastern region. However, Ping An Bank and Zheshang Bank divide the country into 4 regions; Industrial Bank divides the country into 4 regions based on geographical regions. The city, province or other important city where the headquarters is located is listed and disclosed separately; individual banks will also fine-tune the provinces under a certain region, making it difficult to make horizontal and vertical comparisons of the regional distribution of the bank&#39;s credit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some banks disclose weaker asset quality for retail loans than for corporate loans. Among the 20 listed banks, 13 banks directly disclosed or indirectly disclosed the distribution of personal loans in their interim reports. However, extending to 2020 and previous annual reports and interim reports, only about 10 banks disclosed the asset quality of personal loans. As a leading city commercial bank, Bank of Beijing has disclosed neither the industry distribution nor the regional distribution of non-performing loans in its previous annual reports and interim reports. It has disclosed the least asset quality among the 20 listed banks. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frequency of mentions of &quot;bad&quot; in financial reports can also be used as an indication of the bank&#39;s credit disclosure adequacy in terms of loan quality. Statistics from researchers at Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found that China Merchants Bank was mentioned as &quot;non-performing&quot; the most in the 2023 interim report, a total of 94 times, while the Bank of Jiangsu was mentioned the least often, only 19 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/J7abSO8kN5QkX9C1NLM6v82mZMTFhd5f379OI0nj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True and accurate , completeness, timeliness and fairness are the principle requirements for the information disclosure of listed companies. Standardization, easy to understand and easy to obtain are the basic requirements for the form of information disclosure of listed companies. According to this, a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that listed systemically important banks are the benchmark for China&#39;s banking industry and should also be the benchmark for information disclosure in the banking industry. Annual reports and annual reports should be based on various requirements for information disclosure by listed companies. The disclosure of important information such as interim reports is strictly controlled. In particular, indicators related to bank asset quality and their changes have attracted more attention from investors and the public. Listed banks should disclose true, accurate, complete, timely and fair information, and ensure that the disclosed information is standardized. , easy to understand and obtain, and continuously improve the compliance and transparency of corporate governance of listed banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[挑选、比较和竞争：2024届毕业生的第一场双选会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1103&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/nuifKPmtNwPXYFAsfecCAyNOTckvwqHubxbDX1D 2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Guangzhou, after the double selection meeting on Jinan University . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lights were all bright in the thousands-square-meter gymnasium, and 28 tables were arranged in a circle. The tabletop is covered with blue velvet, and beside each table stands a promotional poster as tall as one person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on September 20, 2023, at the Wushan Campus of South China University of Technology in Guangzhou, in half an hour, the special double election meeting for Shenzhen state-owned enterprises will begin. This is the third &quot;double selection meeting&quot; prepared by this 985 university for the 2024 graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The topic of employment for graduates in 2023 is still hot, and the school recruitment season for 2024 has begun again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Owen Xin, a senior student in our school’s School of Business Administration, has been waiting on the sidelines for a long time. She had done a lot of planning in advance. She was wearing a white T-shirt with a small colorful pattern and the hem was tucked into light-colored suit pants. It was half casual and half formal. On a certain social platform, a state-owned enterprise employee once posted, Different from the stereotype of full-body formal wear, &quot;business casual&quot; is the image of employees favored by state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Specially for state-owned enterprises”, Owen Xin stepped into the venue of the autumn recruitment fair for the first time. She had long made up her mind to take the civil service examination, and the administrative position in a state-owned enterprise, which was the least stable, was regarded as a &quot;guaranteed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every fall semester begins, thousands of freshmen enter colleges and universities, and thousands of fresh graduates are about to be sent to the next stop on the train of life. But it is not easy to get off the bus. According to data released by the Ministry of Education, the number of college graduates in 2024 is expected to reach 11.87 million, reaching a new high, an increase of 290,000 from 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Double selection usually means the beginning of the new school recruitment season. This is a traditional recruitment form that directly invites companies to join the school to achieve offline face-to-face communication and two-way selection between companies and job-seeking students. Every step and every person leading to the workplace is surrounded by selection, comparison and competition. As policies, markets, and employment concepts change, the status of academic qualifications, majors, industries, and positions has also changed several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last 10 days of September 2023, Southern Weekend reporters visited a total of four double selection meetings of varying sizes in three schools in Guangzhou. At the same time, the autumn double elections across the country started almost simultaneously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1106&quot; height= &quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/4wWcEH5Zs4GaAgWB8hTaoLK5fs6suv19ltDQOTDQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Guangzhou, the theme of the South China University of Technology was the double selection meeting for the 2024 campus recruitment of Shenzhen state-owned enterprises. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Enterprises that are in trouble&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;They are not You know, our company is very good.” Wang Ming, the head of human resources at a state-owned real estate company in Shenzhen, complained at the Chinese Workers’ Dual Election Meeting on September 20. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the group was founded in 1989 and went public three years later. It is mainly engaged in real estate development and operations and is directly managed by the Shenzhen Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This state-owned enterprise is well prepared. Most companies present only sent two personnel, while they sent three. But obviously, the extra manpower was not put to much use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were very few inquiries. When he was bored, Wang Ming took two photos. One picture is of another company, with four or five students queuing up in front of the booth, waiting for consultation; the other picture is of their own booth, with two HRs staring blankly in front of no one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ming’s group is not the only company that has faced the cold shoulder in this double election. Even if they are state-owned enterprises and some established real estate companies, they have been left out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2010, the golden age of the real estate industry, they were also a popular unit in the double election. &quot;The real estate industry has been in decline since two or three years ago.&quot; HR from one of the companies said frankly, &quot;Many students majoring in civil engineering and architecture have chosen to change industries, and students who intend to find employment in the real estate industry are also more cautious.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;Fortunately, good policies have been introduced.&quot; Wang Ming said, taking out his mobile phone and showing the &quot;internal information&quot; he had obtained. The screenshot with black text on a white background mentioned that some districts in Guangzhou will completely cancel property purchase restrictions. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the &quot;inside information&quot; was publicly confirmed. On the afternoon of the same day, Guangzhou issued the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot; - Guangzhou became the first city among the first-tier cities in the country to partially relax purchase restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time in the past, the three industries of Internet, real estate, and education were known as the “Three Giants of School Recruitment” due to their large number of school recruitment positions and strong talent absorption capabilities. Zhaopin Recruitment Job Demand Data It shows that in 2021, the three giants jointly provided 56% of positions for fresh graduates. In the same year, the situation changed. Due to various reasons, the three giants frequently laid off employees, and the motivation for school recruitment was also insufficient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If real estate practitioners can still see some opportunities from policy changes, the education and training industry still does not know what the future holds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HR Deng Wenqing of a well-known education and training institution considers herself to be very &quot;hardworking&quot;. Since September, as the company&#39;s human resources representative in Guangzhou, she has participated in three double-election meetings. &quot;I was basically the last one to leave.&quot; Another double selection meeting on September 26 was originally scheduled to end at 5 p.m. Deng Wenqing sat until 5:30. Whenever a student stopped in front of the booth, she enthusiastically handed over the brochure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But her diligence cannot eliminate the impact of the education and training reform two years ago. An economics master&#39;s student stopped when passing by the booth and asked bluntly: &quot;Is this unrestricted? Does the state not care?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Wenqing repeated the explanation: &quot;The double reduction is for compulsory education and make-up classes. We only focus on high school subjects in this area, and focus on comprehensive quality training in junior high schools and below, without restrictions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another double selection meeting at the same time, it was also necessary to explain to the students that another tutor The HR of training institutions also adopts basically the same statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going back to July 2021, the &quot;double reduction&quot; curtain has begun. In one year, subject-based off-campus training institutions across the country have been reduced by more than 90%, and 25 related listed companies have announced that 100% of them will no longer engage in subject-based training in the compulsory education stage. In the past two years, in order to reduce media exposure, Deng Wenqing&#39;s organization has been very low-key in its online recruitment promotions. During the campus recruitment season, HR in various places has turned to offline recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few people talk about the past glory of the education and training industry. In 2020, in the first quarter China job market sentiment report jointly launched by the China Employment Research Institute of Renmin University of China and Zhaopin Recruitment, the education and training industry once ranked first, surpassing the Internet and e-commerce. That year, a leading company launched a spring campus recruitment of 3,000 people, and several online education institutions that became famous that year had a total recruitment of nearly 10,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the double selection meeting on September 20, Deng Wenqing received a total of 12 resumes, and the master of economics who raised the question finally took away a brochure and promised to go back and read it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1246&quot; height= &quot;932&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZNG7TVhz66mAOhmQdv116Q8TSI1419OqX1BnAGIj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in Guangzhou, at the double selection meeting on the campus of Jinan University, many graduates gathered in front of the booth of a new materials company. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two-way selection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Taking Guangzhou as an example, usually Throughout the entire employment season, more than 200 double selection meetings will be held from September to June of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Enterprise recruitment is nothing more than online and offline channels. Online, some recruitment information is posted on the employment website or employment official account. Offline is information sessions and this kind of (double selection) Job fair.&quot; Xu Yang, the project manager of a school recruitment human resources company in Guangzhou introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a human resources service platform focusing on campus recruitment. According to the official website, the platform has reached cooperation with more than 50 universities, hosts more than 200 offline dual selection meetings every year, and has provided services to a total of 206,000 companies. Three of the four double-election meetings visited by Southern Weekend reporters were hosted by this platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, a regular double selection meeting is jointly organized by a university and a human resources company. The school provides the venue and student source data, and the human resources company is responsible for connecting with the company, arranging the venue, etc. Xu Yang said that in the offline format, the double selection meeting is more effective than the information session. Dozens to hundreds of companies are present at the same time. &quot;It will be more efficient in solving employment needs, and the school also recognizes the double selection meeting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for recruitment efficiency, the most intuitive thing for companies is the on-site consultation situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng is running for the double election in his second year. He is the person in charge of the Guangzhou branch of a civil service examination training institution. The institution has only been established for three years. The training business covers civil servants, selected students, public institutions, etc., full-time There are less than 20 lecturers, and it can only be considered a small and micro enterprise in terms of scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the afternoon of September 28, in front of the teaching building of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies, next to Wu Feng’s booth, there were almost no interruptions in the number of students who came to consult. This day is approaching the Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day holiday, so there are not many students participating in the double selection meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng has several copies of &quot;Real Questions for the Written Examination for Selected Students in Guangdong&quot; on his desk. The slogan &quot;Scan the QR code to get it&quot; attracted many students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The public examination is more popular now.” Wu Feng knew that his company had taken advantage of the popularity of the public examination and the postgraduate entrance examination. For many fresh graduates who have not thought clearly about their way out, the iron rice bowl is undoubtedly the &quot;certain way out.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even if the &quot;public examination&quot; is popular, not every time you participate in the double selection meeting, it will be so smooth. Wu Feng mentioned that in the fall of 2022, he went to Sun Yat-sen University to participate in the double selection meeting, but the results were not satisfactory. &quot;Our company is smaller, and those students may prefer big companies more.&quot; This year, the Sun Yat-sen University stop was canceled on his recruiting schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a longer time dimension, school enrollment retention rate also determines corporate recruitment decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li, HR of a news website in Foshan, has participated in the double selection meeting for four years. It is planned that this year she will go to Guangzhou University, Guangdong University of Foreign Studies and other universities to recruit, but the journalism and communication major ranks high A well-known university in the province is not among them. The reason lies in the recruitment retention rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Li remembers that in the spring recruitment of 2021, her employer recruited four boys in the same dormitory from this university. After a month, &quot;all left.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Among the four people, some have returned to their hometowns, some have taken the civil service exam, and some have taken the professional education exam.” Huang Li added, “Re-recruitment also requires training, which is time-consuming and costly. I don’t want to recruit students from this university anymore.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies choose schools and are also chosen by schools. &quot;If it is an unknown company with only 10 or 20 people, it will definitely not be accepted. This is irresponsible to the company itself. If they come here, they will not be able to recruit people.&quot; Jinan University double selection on the afternoon of September 26 At the meeting, another person in charge of the aforementioned school recruitment platform revealed that the school will have certain requirements for participating companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Take JNU as an example. What it requires must be well-known companies. For example, how many of China’s top 500 companies, how many of the world’s top 500 companies, what is the salary range, and the academic qualifications suitable for the position (is it Bachelor&#39;s degree and above), these requirements will be met.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some double selection sessions will limit the themes and gather certain types of companies into one session. For example, the double selection meeting held at South China University of Technology on September 20 was aimed at Shenzhen state-owned enterprises, and the double selection meeting held at Guangdong University of Technology on September 26 was aimed at the micro-semiconductor industry. On September 27, another dual-selection meeting held by South China University of Technology gathered more than 200 companies, focusing on recruiting high-level talents in education, scientific research, and medical and health fields that are urgently needed and in short supply in key fields in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1236&quot; height= &quot;924&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/qtrfGww6PZYUh5QeAOt4dU8buB8BgmmdxraDhFZQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, in Guangzhou, the Guangxi-themed double-election meeting on the campus of South China University of Technology carried the slogan &quot;I want to go to Guangxi&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Supply and demand issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to participate in the event on September 27 For the double selection meeting of South China University of Technology, Li Jiamin, a master&#39;s student majoring in materials science at Sun Yat-sen University, specially set out from Shenzhen and took the school bus for nearly two hours to arrive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her enthusiasm dropped by half after entering school. Different from the double-election meeting a week ago, this time the venue was outdoors, crowded, noisy and hot, and corporate leaflets scattered everywhere were trampled under people&#39;s feet. Soon, she was sitting next to the wall to rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiamin graduated from a college in Shanxi three years ago. She concentrated on preparing for the postgraduate entrance examination and &quot;went a lot of effort&quot; to get into the CUHK. When enrolling as a graduate student, her supervisor told her and her classmates not to go to graduate school just to improve their academic qualifications and find a job. But Li Jiamin was not convinced, &quot;The facts are there. The starting salary of graduate students is higher than that of undergraduate students. Everyone thinks so.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in this double election meeting, she specifically inquired about industry salaries. Others told her that in Shenzhen, a monthly salary of less than 20,000 yuan for a master&#39;s degree in materials science is considered low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, every science and engineering student who had no clue when filling out their application form would tacitly memorize the same formula, &quot;Biochemical and environmental materials, four major sinkholes.&quot; In the stereotype, they are synonymous with little money, tiring work, and fierce competition. However, under the guidance of policies such as carbon peaking and carbon neutrality, traditional industries are transforming into new materials, new energy, semiconductors, and smart manufacturing. It is not uncommon for fresh graduates to earn an annual salary of 300,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But today&#39;s double selection meeting still disappointed her a little. &quot;(The monthly salary offered by the company) is around 15,000 to 17,000, which is much lower than I expected.&quot; She brought six resumes, and she had a few left before leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the four years since he has been engaged in campus recruitment, Xu Yang has observed that the asymmetry between supply and demand for jobs at the double selection meeting has become increasingly prominent. On the one hand, students&#39; enthusiasm for employment continues to increase and the number of participants is rising; on the other hand, the number of participating companies and the number of jobs released is decreasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The needs of enterprises are affected by the general environment. In 2021, more than 100 companies will participate in the double selection meeting we will organize at Guangzhou Foreign Language School, but today there are less than 60.&quot; September 28 On the same day, Xu Yang said this at the double election meeting of Guangdong University of Foreign Studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xu Yang’s view, the asymmetric supply and demand relationship has both good and bad effects on the employment situation. &quot;The good thing is that for companies, there are fewer people to recruit, but there are more students coming. Companies can have more opportunities to select the right people. But it has indeed become harder for students to find jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 28, a female student from Guangdong Pharmaceutical University finished her interview with Wu Feng and stopped in front of the booth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked why she was interested in the public examination institution, the girl pulled the Southern Weekend reporter aside and whispered, &quot;You can work part-time and take the public examination at the same time.&quot; Then her expression changed again. She was suspicious, &quot;I told you, how can I find a job?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her worries may be unnecessary. Wu Feng doesn&#39;t mind that the lecturer is preparing for the civil service exam at the same time. On the contrary, he encourages it. In his opinion, &quot;you will get started faster if you have experience in preparing for the exam.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng even said that when it comes to the interview stage, he will directly advise job seekers to prepare for the public examination. After the examination, they will determine their initial intentions and final re-examination. But when he said this, he frowned and did not relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Wang Ming, Deng Wenqing, Xu Yang, Wu Feng, Huang Li, and Li Jiamin are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[登上热搜的“支原体肺炎”究竟是个啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258836]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:36:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine Outside the emergency clinic, parents wait with their children. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254373&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, parents waited with their children outside the emergency clinic on the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sure enough, it&#39;s mycoplasma again!&quot; On October 16, 2023, Dr. Ding Guodong from Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, formerly We planned to watch 30 special numbers in the morning, and temporarily added 10 more numbers, which lasted until 1 p.m. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The doctors in our department are basically full every day, and the inpatient beds are also very tight. Some children may have to wait for several days before they can be admitted.&quot; Ding Guodong is the deputy chief physician of the Pediatric Respiratory Department. He and his colleagues have been working at an overloaded pace since mid-September. “At this stage, almost 90% of the hospitalized children in the Pediatric Respiratory Department are infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae. , and the proportion of drug-resistant mycoplasmas is very high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae has a diameter of 50-300 nanometers, nearly one thousandth the diameter of a human hair. It is a microorganism between bacteria and viruses. Pneumonia caused by this microorganism is the most common community-acquired pneumonia in children aged 5 and above in China (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;refers to infectious diseases suffered outside the hospital Pulmonary parenchymal inflammation&lt;/span>;), mostly occurs in autumn and winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the beginning of the school year in September, not only Shanghai, but also hospitals in Beijing, Hebei, Jiangsu and other places have seen more children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and they are younger. characteristics. According to a CCTV News report on October 13, the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases has increased across the country recently, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae has entered the season of high incidence. Children need timely medical treatment and appropriate medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;There are 246 people in front of you&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before four o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 15, Qin Nannan finally registered his son. At that time, the number of a deputy chief physician at Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital had reached No. 556. While waiting for treatment, she discovered that someone had already received more than 800 numbers. Finally, when it was time to collect blood, Qin Nannan got the number 1310. The number strip also thoughtfully marked &quot;There are 246 people in front of you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Baoping, director of the Respiratory Department of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said in an interview with the media on October 13 that since September, the hospital&#39;s fever and cough clinic has received a daily volume of 3,000-4,700 patients, 20% of whom tested positive for mycoplasma antibodies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the hospital specially posted a notice on a wall, &quot;The number of children undergoing treatment has increased significantly recently, and the hospital has deployed all medical staff in the hospital to continuously We are working overtime to support the clinic and are doing our best to ensure the medical needs of children. Please understand and wait patiently.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital has opened a dedicated fever and cough clinic. It was built a bit like a shelter, and the general outpatient clinic on the other side was just as crowded. We had to wait for nearly two and a half hours just for blood tests that day,&quot; Qin Nannan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is also a long queue at Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. On the evening of October 16, near the end of the day, the emergency department on the first floor and the pediatric internal medicine clinic on the second floor of the hospital were crowded with parents and children coming to see the doctor. Those who could not find an empty seat could only sit on the floor in the corridor to rest temporarily. . The temperature in Shanghai on this day was only about 20 degrees Celsius, but many people&#39;s hair had already been soaked with sweat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The pediatric department of Xinhua Hospital is well-known throughout the country. There are many people coming to see the doctor from other places, and there are also some patients who are referred to the hospital because they cannot be treated by the grassroots hospital. Ding Guodong lamented to Southern Weekend reporters that recently all the medical staff in the hospital go to the outpatient and emergency departments to provide support whenever they are free during the day. Many doctors stay at night to work overtime, visit the outpatient and emergency departments or admit children to the hospital. &quot;There are just too many patients.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of October 12, 2023, the infusion center of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University was filled with children suffering from diarrhea and accompanying parents, and coughs could be heard one after another. Southern Weekend Intern Xi Lijie/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1f4273c3b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of October 12, 2023, the infusion center of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital Affiliated to Capital Medical University was filled with children suffering from diarrhea and accompanying parents, and coughs could be heard one after another. Photo by Xi Lijie, Southern Weekend intern&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Drug resistance has been around for many years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Different from general bacterial pneumonia, since Mycoplasma pneumoniae does not have a cell wall, the penicillins and cephalosporins familiar to ordinary families are completely ineffective against Mycoplasma pneumoniae because these antibiotics target the cell wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally speaking, macrolide antibacterial drugs, such as azithromycin and erythromycin, are currently the first-choice treatments for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. However, what makes many pediatricians troublesome is that the phenomenon of drug-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection is relatively common, which means that macrolide antibacterial drugs are not effective or even ineffective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Mycoplasma Pneumonia in Children (2023 Edition)&quot; released by the National Health Commission in February 2023 also pointed out that domestic restrictions on macrolides Antimicrobial drug-resistant infections are common and may be one of the main causes of severe mycoplasma pneumonia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Drug-resistant mycoplasma infections are not new this year, they have been around for many years.&quot; Director Ding Guodong told Southern Weekend reporters that the children&#39;s respiratory tract where he works The ward mainly treats children with severe illness. Most of these children have been tested for drug-resistant genes. The results show that almost 90% are infected with drug-resistant mycoplasma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A paper published in the &quot;Chinese Journal of Pathogen Biology&quot; in 2023 pointed out that the detection rate of drug-resistant strains has become higher and higher in recent years. A Ningbo A regional study of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections in hospitalized children from 2019 to 2021 showed that the drug resistance rate exceeded 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this way, clinicians need to appropriately select second-line drugs based on the patient&#39;s condition and age, such as tetracycline antibiotics (doxycycline and minocycline) etc.) or quinolone drugs for anti-infective treatment, and at the same time, glucocorticoids are added to suppress the body&#39;s excessive immune inflammatory response and slow down the progression and severity of intrapulmonary and extrapulmonary complications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, during the current seasonal transition period with large temperature changes, co-infection is also a huge challenge for children with poor immunity. Just two or three days ago, a child that Ding Guodong was checking in the ward was infected with drug-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae, influenza virus, and adenovirus at the same time. He suffered respiratory failure and was in a very critical condition. &quot;Co-infection with multiple pathogens at the same time is generally worse than a single infection.&quot; Be serious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Ding Guodong reminded that in addition to maintaining hygiene habits and doing daily protection, now is the time for influenza vaccination, and parents can take their children to get vaccinated in time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When will the popularity end? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Similar to the new coronavirus infection, after being infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and recovering, the antibody level in the body gradually decreases over time, and there is a possibility of reinfection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qin Nannan’s son is 7 years old. This is not the first time he has been infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae in 2023. He has already had it once before this epidemic season, so the family members I didn’t panic too much, I was quite aware of the child’s symptoms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 12, the Beijing Centers for Disease Control and Prevention posted on its official WeChat ID that Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year, with the highest incidence in Beijing from August to December every year. This is the high-incidence period for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, which generally reaches its peak around November every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is an important pathogen of acute respiratory tract infections in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae is divided into two subtypes, type I and type II, which are currently mainly prevalent in Beijing. The subtype is type I.&quot; the article stated. At the same time, according to the weekly epidemic report released by the Beijing Center for Disease Control and Prevention on October 13, hand, foot and mouth disease was the infectious disease with the highest number of reported cases in the week of October 2-8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly spread through droplets, and the pathogen can be carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing, and runny noses. However, it is not a notifiable disease, so the local CDC does not necessarily monitor it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that Mycoplasma pneumoniae has spread in previous years, but it has not been included in the scope of monitoring for the time being, because what needs to be monitored is in accordance with policies. related infectious diseases.&quot; On October 17, Guangzhou health hotline staff responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A retrospective analysis published by the Shanghai Children&#39;s Hospital team in January 2023 showed that temperature, humidity, etc. in different regions may affect the prevalence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae. The peaks of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection are different in the south and north of China. The incidence is high in winter in the north and in summer and autumn in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Qin Nannan is a pseudonym to protect patient privacy)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州导盲犬的新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258750]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>