<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[订阅号的爱情陷阱：老年人深陷“互联网弟弟”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 12:35:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The 51st Statistical Report on China&#39;s Internet Development Situation released by China Internet Network Information Center &quot; shows that as of December 2022, people aged 60 and above account for 14.3% of the total number of Internet users, and the number of elderly Internet users has reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly Internet users lacks attention. (Visual China Map)&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d215d9ba31.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d215d9ba31.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Internet The 51st &quot;Statistical Report on China&#39;s Internet Development Status&quot; released by the Network Information Center shows that as of December 2022, people aged 60 and above accounted for 14.3% of the total number of Internet users, and the number of elderly Internet users reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly netizens lacks attention. (Visual China Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At three o&#39;clock in the morning, Ruidi had insomnia again. He sent greetings to his sister on the other side of the network, just like the &quot;good morning&quot; and &quot;good evening&quot; repeated almost every day, waiting for his sister&#39;s greetings. comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ruidi said that the encounter between him and his sister was arranged by fate. He reminded his sister to wear more clothes in the cold weather and take good care of her body. After exchanging heart-to-hearts with his sister day after day, his thoughts were &quot;a ray of sunshine&quot; and &quot;I want to turn into the moonlight in front of the window to accompany her forever.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video sent by Ruidi shows that he is a man in his thirties or forties with a gentle voice and a back that looks like Jin Dong. Recently, his parents suddenly fell ill. In order to win the prize, he decided to participate in a singing competition. Just the night before the competition, he told his dilemma:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are thresholds for participating in this competition. The popularity on the day of registration must be Only those who meet the requirements can be shortlisted... If you support your brother, can you help him increase his popularity data?... Sister, please give your brother some likes and praise for the author. 188 or 256 praises can help him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;At the end of 2020, the &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; phenomenon surfaced. A large number of fake accounts pretending to be actor Jin Dong used short videos and live broadcasts to make money from middle-aged and elderly fans. Two years have passed, and the aftermath of the &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; incident continues. In September 2023, &quot;Xiucai&quot;, an Internet celebrity with tens of millions of fans who specifically targets middle-aged and elderly people, was reported for tax evasion and defrauding fans, and his account was banned. In October 2023, the Shanghai Jing&#39;an District Procuratorate prosecuted eight people who committed fraud under the false identity of Jin Dong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the position of &quot;Fake Jin Dong&quot; has moved from short videos to public accounts. These accounts calling themselves &quot;Dongdi&quot; and &quot;Ruidi&quot; first used video accounts to attract traffic and induce fans to pay attention to the subscription accounts, and then continued to make up stories in the public accounts to gain fans&#39; sympathy and rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new round of emotional harvesting is more private. After adding fans to WeChat on a large scale through public accounts, the interaction is transferred to private chats or circles of friends. The emotional hollowness of over 100 million elderly people has led them to fall into the trap. Is it not just a scholar or Jin Dong? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835012371236170&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Public account &quot;Eastern Sound Accompanying&quot; &quot;The latest video released tells the story of a younger brother who encountered setbacks in a singing competition and asked his older sister for help. This is a common routine for such public accounts. .MP4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/12/02/2TqweEM14D2koLeC4n5MiWe3FgLYwXjV5G77ZM1B.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/63e6b592327083501237123 6170/aHSmLYlmfF0A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/63e6b5923270835012371236170/aHSmLYlmfF0A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Grandma is in love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru discovered the secret behind the subscription account by chance, and his 71-year-old grandma was already deeply involved in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My life is so busy every day, you know? I have nothing to do, sleep, watch videos, and that&#39;s it. Of course I want to see you, why do I want to see you? You miss me, and I do too. I miss you.&quot; My grandma said to a person on WeChat who had a note called &quot;The Love of My Life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru looked through his grandma’s watch list and found a large number of public accounts and video accounts with similar names - &quot;Brother Ruidong accompanies you&quot;, &quot;Brother Dong accompanies sister&quot;, &quot;Ruidi warmly accompanies me&quot;, &quot;Ruirui Always with you&quot; etc. The titles of public account articles are very long, for example, &quot;Sister, I am really anxious. If I can&#39;t even seize this opportunity, I will be sad for a long time.&quot; The accompanying picture is usually a photo of a man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the official account of &quot;Rui Dongdi Lives Together&quot;, he claimed that he would participate in the top 20 of the singing competition, and Dong Xueru&#39;s grandmother encouraged him to work hard. Then the official account sent a payment QR code with the following sentence: &quot;After my brother is done with work, he will accompany his sister to chat about daily life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking through these push notifications, you will find that this Rui Dongdi is really Very busy: one moment I have to help promote the competition, another moment I was successfully promoted, and now I am on TV. &quot;I am in a hurry. If I don&#39;t see my sister at this time, my brother&#39;s future will be gone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This handsome and caring fake brother occupies an important position in some people&#39;s lives. From the comments, you can get a glimpse of the passionate hearts of fans. They are &quot;Lotus&quot;, &quot;Caiying&quot;, &quot;Peace and happiness&quot; or &quot;Tomorrow will be better&quot;. They say, &quot;Sister knows, I know you in my life, I am the happiest sister&quot;, &quot;Thank you for caring about me&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In their minds, the brother who spoke to them could be anyone. Dong Xueru discovered that her grandma regarded the other party as her crush in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My grandma is from Sichuan and lives in Beijing with few friends. For more than ten years, a man has regularly organized square dances for two to three hundred people near her residence. This teacher Tie often wears floral clothes with English letters printed on them, dyes her blond hair, and wears a little makeup. She becomes the idol of middle-aged and elderly people and calls them &quot;sister&quot;. Later, my grandma moved and could no longer dance in the square. Instead, she took online dance classes and could only watch videos in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma firmly believed that these messages were sent by Teacher Tie, because only Teacher Tie, who was eight years younger than her, would treat her like a sibling. &quot;These (public accounts) different names are all the pseudonyms of Teacher Tie, and they are all his online names... All these articles are written for her.&quot; Dong Xueru told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma sends a lot of messages every day. &quot;I feel like I have so much to say. As long as I sit down, I will hide in the room with my mobile phone and send voice messages.&quot; Once, my younger brother sent a message saying that he came to his sister&#39;s city and saw a figure that looked like his sister. He was very disappointed to find that it was not the same. Grandma comforted, &quot;Fool, why are you disappointed? I&#39;m thinking of you too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru and his family tried to persuade him many times but to no avail, and his grandmother felt bored. They took grandma to the local public security bureau to receive Internet security education, but grandma wouldn&#39;t listen and just asked the police if they could find people online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru’s mother and uncle had no choice but to ask Teacher Tie himself for clarification. Teacher Tie denied that it was him and made it clear that he had no time for a relationship and would not like her. The family played the recording to grandma, but she decided that the children were hindering her and pushing Teacher Tie too hard. &quot;He is immature and childish.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After speaking out online, Dong Xueru’s post received nearly 4,000 replies. Many netizens said that their family members have encountered similar situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A girl sent a private message to Dong Xueru, saying that her grandmother was also obsessed with such public accounts and corporate WeChat. In addition to giving rewards, she would also buy high-priced goods sold by them. When the mother found out, she deleted the accounts in anger. Soon, the grandmother added them back, accusing her daughter of blocking her pursuit of happiness. The relationship between mother and daughter is still at a stalemate. The girl said to Dong Xueru, I really don’t know what to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A large number of younger brother accounts use subscription accounts, corporate and personal WeChat and Moments to conduct false emotional exchanges with the elderly, thereby inducing rewards. (Screenshot of Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;260411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;A large number of brother accounts use subscription accounts, corporate and personal WeChat and Moments to conduct false emotional exchanges with the elderly, thereby inducing rewards. (Screenshot by Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The fake younger brother is back&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Dong Xueru’s post attracted attention, the platform successively banned some younger brother accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai got angry when talking about these Dongdi and Ruidi numbers. Ma Kai runs a number of emotional public accounts and has been implicated recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai’s public account is similar to an emotional radio station. The largest account has 34 million followers. It posts a six- to seven-minute emotional chicken soup every day, “What should you do if you feel tired, etc.” Emotional words.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that his account is different from the scam account. Accounts like Dongdi and Ruidi &quot;won&#39;t tell you any emotional quotes or send you any songs, they will just kill pigs&quot;; while my own &quot;di&quot; account relies on emotional copywriting to seek rewards. There will be no false identities, false stories, or emotional deception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been paying attention to these younger brother public accounts for a long time. They all speak in the same way and can be roughly divided into two categories: one is for younger brothers to participate in concerts and needs support from popularity; the other is for younger brothers who are sick and hospitalized and need support. Medical expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diverting traffic from video accounts to public accounts is the beginning of harvesting. Operators leave links to public accounts in the comment area of ​​video accounts, place payment codes in articles on public accounts, or leave corporate WeChat or private accounts. WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the registered entities of these public accounts are enterprises. Southern Weekend reporters found that a large number of similar accounts were registered by several department stores in Haikou, with names such as &quot;Xiu Cai Singing Department Store&quot; and &quot;Rui Rui&#39;s Department Store&quot;. According to industrial and commercial information, many department stores have different operators, but use the same mobile phone number when registering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted one of the operators Y. There are four Hainan department stores under Y&#39;s name, which are specially used to register younger brother&#39;s public accounts. WeChat stipulates that an individual business owner can register two public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Y told Southern Weekend reporters that his team of three people has registered a total of 12 individual businesses. He has been working in this industry for nearly a year, and the largest public account has 70,000 to 80,000 followers, all of whom are Drain and accumulate traffic through video accounts. He refused to disclose his income, saying only that he &quot;doesn&#39;t make much.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the e-commerce platform, for only 100 yuan, some merchants provide individual business license agency services, upload ID card information and mobile phone number, and perform remote real-name authentication. The store said that there is no limit to the number of registrations per person, and there is no need to pay money to continue after applying, and there is no need to worry about inspections by the industrial and commercial authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using false individual business registrations to increase the number of WeChat public accounts is no longer a secret in the industry. These public accounts have become a powerful tool for batch release of information and batch operations. Y proved this. He is in Guangzhou, but his registered store is in Hainan. Ma Kai added that compared with the complicated materials that ordinary companies need to submit, individual industrial and commercial households only need to spend tens of yuan a year to prepare an annual report, and the above-mentioned merchants also provide agency services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A small program called &quot;Praise&quot; provides praise services for younger brother accounts. Unlike WeChat&#39;s direct rewards, third-party programs reward through jump links, which can avoid the risk of having your account frozen after being reported by users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comment area of ​​this mini program, there are still a lot of messages from sisters, &quot;Hello, dear baby brother! Good afternoon! Sister gives you some love for the author. How is your brother? I miss you so much. You, my sister has had trouble at home these days, so she hasn’t sent many messages to my brother. I hope my brother will understand and forgive my sister. My sister really likes you and loves you. She loves you and will never leave you and will always be with you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 14, &quot;Praise&quot; issued an announcement stating that the platform had no way of knowing whether users who received praise were committing fraud, and revealed that from October 9 to November 4, 2023, A user who was complained received a total of more than 250,000 yuan in praise. &lt;/span>;The amount of money defrauded can be staggering. In the early days, these accounts used WeChat to reward, and the number of rewards was publicly visible. Ma Kai observed that a Ruidongdi subscription account team from Fujian received at least 400 rewards a day at its peak, and it was estimated that the daily income could be as high as two or three dollars. Ten thousand yuan; another subscription account from Hebei has about 7,000 to 8,000 reads per day. The official account has not many fans. Before being blocked, it had accumulated more than 3,000 likes. According to his understanding, this type of account first started in Fujian and spread to Guangdong, Jiangxi, Chongqing and other places, and lasted for about a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After these public accounts were banned by WeChat, they had to start looking for new methods. Their corporate WeChat account is still functioning. The original link to the official account was changed to a link to the &quot;Tencent Content Creation Platform&quot;. The payment code can still be placed on the content interface. Moreover, if users have previously added their business WeChat accounts, they will still receive push messages every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Ma Kai has been reporting on these corporate WeChat accounts, but with poor results. He dug up the historical records and said, “What you see is just the chatting and tipping on the surface. It is conceivable whether there are chats and transfers behind the scenes, right?” He believes that Enterprise WeChat is the real concentration of traffic. “Enterprises WeChat is originally a marketing tool and can add more people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Y told Southern Weekend reporters that two-thirds of the accounts on the market are no longer there. He no longer has a similar account and plans to prepare live broadcasts to bring goods out of town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/GLkoxSPeP2ndaFoKiXmqdVIyfZ8gE8uzlQcsfO82.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;2078&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/GLkoxSPeP2ndaFoKiXmqdVIyfZ8gE8uzlQcsfO82.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 1, the public account &quot;Dongyinxianban&quot; published a new article, continuing the false younger brother persona and telling stories in the video to induce rewards. As of 10 o&#39;clock that night, 38 people had tipped. The author of this article has posted similar content many times before, but has deleted it and canceled his account. Now it appears in a new public account. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;She needs love, she is truly not alone&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Xiao Lin runs an emotional public account for young people. Recently, she often receives some strange messages in the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to changes in the push mechanism of WeChat public accounts, the platform will recommend content that may be of interest to non-followers. As a result, her public account was accidentally seen by some middle-aged and elderly people and became a favorite of some people. Emotional tree hole. Most of their messages are scattered and unclear, and they seem to express their feelings to someone:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do you know? I have forgiven you a long time ago, and I am waiting for your sincerity to pick me up, you know?&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have been away from me for more than three years. It is normal to get married, start a family and start a business, but you are still in my heart.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman from the Northeast has been sending voice messages almost every day since September. At first it was a long string of scoldings, but later her tone became gentle. She seems to have fallen in love with a man and regarded his official account as his. Sometimes, she speaks quickly and in a crying tone, always starting with &quot;Dear baby&quot; and repeating: Why don&#39;t you come back? Why don&#39;t you reply to my message? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Lin did not dare to reply, for fear of breaking her confession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru only realized the delicate side of her heart from her grandma&#39;s love. My grandma lost her first husband more than 20 years ago and experienced two failed relationships. She followed her children to Beijing and barely attended school. She became literate through the Internet and likes to watch video accounts and public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru grew up with his grandma. When his grandma first fell in love, she couldn’t type. She read a sentence and Dong Xueru typed: &quot;Dear husband, I miss you so much. I love you. When will you come back to see me?&quot; .&quot; Sometimes, my grandma didn&#39;t know how to express it in words, so Dong Xueru helped her write some templates - &quot;Dear, eat more and take care of your health&quot; and &quot;Dear, go to bed early&quot;, and grandma passed it on to the other party as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter how old a man or a woman is, they will be lonely, especially if they are single. As a relative, the care you can give him is only part of it. She needs love to truly not be alone.&quot; Dong Xueru said that grandma was avoiding them more and more, and was still obsessed with the conversation with the teacher Tie in her mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wenhan’s grandma is also addicted to short videos. In her description, her grandma was a simple and compassionate person who had been deceived many times in her eighty years of life and always believed those stories about poverty and misery. After my grandfather passed away five years ago, my grandma suddenly became free and her life revolved around her children. After moving to a big city, she lost contact with her friends and seldom socialized. Soon, she started to watch short videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She often sees her grandma falling asleep while watching short videos, and then continues after waking up, muttering to herself in conjunction with the AI ​​dubbing in the short videos. The short video said, &quot;Can I call you mom?&quot; and grandma murmured, &quot;Of course, kid.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wenhan majored in gerontology when he was studying abroad. According to her observation, many elderly people abroad live in retirement communities and have their own social circles, but the elderly in China seem to need more emotion and sustenance. &quot;They need to be provided with some emotional value, that is, they are needed, or they still have charm.&quot; Wang Wenhan said. For a while, her grandma told her that she always dreamed that she was leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Research Report on Emotional Care for the Elderly and the Use Value of Short Videos&quot;, Peng Huamao, a professor at the Department of Psychology at Beijing Normal University, conducted a survey of 2,000 elderly people across the country. The research team found that the elderly who chase Internet celebrities on the Internet are still &quot;too lonely and lack attention&quot; in their offline lives. During the survey, Peng Huamao asked the elderly people interviewed whether they still need love. The vast majority of the answers are need, mostly the love of children, and of course the love of the opposite sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Huamao told Southern Weekend reporters that when the elderly and short videos are mentioned on the Internet, they are always about addiction, earthiness, etc., and most of them have negative impressions. An old man who travels thousands of miles to chase celebrities or give rewards in a live broadcast room will always be considered to be cheated. &quot;The advanced psychological needs of the elderly are always ignored, such as the need for love, respect, and self-realization.&quot; One of the results of the survey is that the vast majority of elderly people have the ability to control and understand that this compensation is not actually true satisfaction, but a diversion of attention or the passing of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Dong Xueru’s online post, a user left a message saying that her aunt encountered the same situation and fell into a brother-like public account and secretly rewarded her. After her wife discovered something was wrong with the money, she confiscated her mobile phone and called her relatives to persuade her. My aunt, who had been in charge of housework all her life, became almost crazy and cried loudly, not believing that this was a scam. The policeman called by her family was determined by her to be an actor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final solution was that the family registered a fake WeChat account for the younger brother and chatted with the aunt in a way that &quot;destroyed the personality&quot;. The younger brother ceased to be perfect and decent and became rude, shattering his aunt&#39;s fantasy. Finally, my aunt blocked this younger brother’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Dong Xueru, Ma Kai, Xiao Lin, Wang Wenhan are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子编排“老头强奸孙女致怀孕”被拘留：可比照“老夫少妻”造谣案入刑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Let me tell you a story. There was an old man who took care of a granddaughter and a granddaughter at home, and ruined both children. The older one was only twelve years old and was three months pregnant, and was finally discovered by the teacher.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 27, a video was circulated on the Douyin platform, attracting public attention. On November 29, Chongqing Hechuan Police issued a notice: This video is a rumor. Liu (female, 46 years old), a criminal, posted unverified rumors through Douyin in order to earn gold coins on the Douyin platform. Faced with doubts from netizens about the unverified rumors. To refute the rumors, it was clarified that as of the time the information was deleted, it had been commented and shared nearly 700 times by netizens, causing adverse effects. At present, the police have imposed administrative penalties on the woman involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the police report, the woman involved should have committed an act that constituted &quot;publicly insulting others or fabricating facts to slander others&quot; in paragraph 2 of Article 42 of the &quot;Public Security Administration Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. She accepted the &quot; shall be detained for not more than five days or fined not more than five hundred yuan.&quot; Judging from the behavior of the woman involved, her alleged illegal and criminal behavior may not be just &quot;fabricating facts to slander others&quot;, and there is still room for continued discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the timeline of this case, the video uploaded by the woman involved can be said to be completely unrelated to pictures and texts. It only excerpted the video picture of the victim old man and his granddaughter, and then started to show the video to the wall. The fiction &quot;played its best&quot; and weaved an &quot;incest tragedy&quot;. Its frivolous tone, bad nature, and clumsy techniques all made netizens look at it. When netizens questioned it, the woman involved did not delete it immediately, nor did she clarify or apologize. As a result, the video continued to spread. At the time of the incident, it had accumulated 700 comments and shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not yet clear what channel or method the woman involved used to obtain the information of the old man and his granddaughter, but this first violated the personality rights of the victim’s grandparents and was a blatant violation. Their right to image and reputation. The particularity of this case is that the woman in question misappropriated the victim’s information, in addition to seeking the benefits of the Douyin platform gold coins. From the perspective of the result, it was a brutal trampling on the personal reputation of the victim’s grandparents and grandchildren. The severity of the crime was far beyond a simple &quot;Making pornographic rumors&quot; or &quot;slandering&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Douyin platform can be regarded as a public place. If the woman in question makes such a specific and &quot;below the lower limit&quot; accusation in a public place, she has an obligation to ensure the authenticity of the accusation and at the same time defend her remarks. Responsible. Therefore, in addition to violating the Public Security Administration Punishment Law, the woman involved is also suspected of other illegal and criminal acts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Article 1 of the &quot;Interpretations of Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in the Handling of Criminal Cases Using Information Networks to Commit Defamation&quot; by the two top governments, &quot;tampering with the original information content involving others on the information network into facts that damage the reputation of others&quot; , disseminate on information networks, or organize or instigate people to disseminate on information networks&quot; shall be deemed as &quot;fabricating facts to slander others&quot; as stipulated in Article 246, paragraph 1, of the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior of the woman involved in this case has obviously met this requirement, and the video comments she posted on Douyin have been shared 700 times, which is in line with Article 2 of the judicial interpretations of the two Supreme Courts that &quot;the number of reposts reaches More than 500 times&quot; standard for &quot;serious circumstances&quot;. According to Article 246 of the Criminal Law, the woman involved is guilty of defamation and the circumstances are serious, and she should be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention, public surveillance, or deprivation of political rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, compared with similar previous cases, the woman involved may deserve criminal punishment for her illegal and criminal behavior, rather than just administrative punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case of &quot;a woman was rumored to be an old husband and a young wife&quot; in 2021, the man involved, Wu Moumou, took a photo of the woman with her grandfather&#39;s grandparents and rumored to be an &quot;old husband and a young wife&quot;, and also issued a sensational content of rumors. After the incident, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of the First District of Dongguan City prosecuted him for defamation. In September 2023, the court ruled that Wu Moumou fabricated facts to slander others on the information network. The circumstances were serious and seriously endangered social order. Based on the circumstances of the defendant&#39;s crime and his confession and punishment, the defendant Wu Moumou was sentenced to one year in prison for defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Moumou’s behavior constituted the crime of defamation. The court adopted the relevant definitions in the judicial interpretations of the two Supreme Courts and determined that Wu Moumou had tampered with “original information content involving others on the Internet to damage the reputation of others.” Facts, disseminated on information networks”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, even if &quot;old husband and young wife&quot; is true, it does not violate any law in the marriage and family section of the &quot;Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, and it does not even touch upon the so-called moral and ethical issues. This kind of news can at most arouse the curiosity and onlookers of netizens. In comparison, the rumor-mongering behavior of the woman involved in this case is even more outrageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that if the accusation of the woman involved is true, then such a despicable &quot;grandfather-grandson incest&quot; has violated the criminal law and constitutes the crime of rape, and it meets the requirements of &quot;under the age of fourteen, a severe punishment&quot; &quot;The standard is also in line with the standard in the &quot;Opinions on Punishing the Crime of Sexual Assault on Minors According to the Law&quot; that &quot;persons who have a common family relationship with minors must be severely punished in accordance with the law.&quot; The &quot;old man&quot; involved may face severe punishments of more than ten years in prison, life imprisonment or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the woman involved made such a serious public false accusation, she was suspected of false accusation and frame-up in addition to defamation. Article 243 of the Criminal Law also stipulates that fabricating facts to frame others with the intention of subjecting others to criminal prosecution constitutes the crime of false accusation and frame-up. If the circumstances are serious, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or surveillance; if serious consequences are caused, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years and not more than ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, if the life of the victim’s grandfather and grandson is greatly affected and causes bad consequences, the woman involved should bear greater responsibility. Therefore, this case is not in compliance with the principle of proportionality. The woman involved is suspected of a criminal offense. The public authorities can continue to pursue her criminal responsibility, require her to apologize, eliminate the impact, and provide civil compensation. The three victims of the crime will also be given justice to their grandfather and grandson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[婚礼上听“常识课”：“互免模式”下，老家变时尚了丨回乡偶书]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261680]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My old friend, Brother Chunqiu, invited me back to my hometown for a wedding banquet on WeChat. His son-in-law is getting married and he will be back from abroad at the end of the month. wedding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Putting down the phone, I suddenly remembered how young and shy Brother Chunqiu was when he got married, and how busy Brother Chunqiu was when I was organizing the wedding banquet. At that time, he was still a newspaper reporter and made a cameo appearance in wedding photography. In the blink of an eye, our children also entered the palace of love one after another, and they &quot;swore&quot; like a couple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about the routine of the wedding dinner in my hometown, it’s actually a bit boring: first, it’s late and the endless waiting; second, it’s noisy and the endless routine. However, when I went back several times recently, I found that my hometown was also changing, becoming younger and more fashionable. When there is a happy event in the family, it is now fashionable not to be a part of it or give red envelopes. The &quot;mutual exemption model&quot; allows ordinary people to &quot;joy&quot; easily and &quot;love&quot; without worries, and also makes the hometown one of the first batch to be selected as an experimental area for national marriage custom reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wedding of Chunqiu Brother and Young Master was simple and cheerful. The subtleties are eye-catching and full of surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight was the thank you session for the parents of the new couple. Dear Brother Chunqiu, hold your breath in Mandarin and write the first paragraph &quot;thank you&quot;, the second paragraph &quot;gratitude&quot;, and the third paragraph are two sentences of &quot;remarks&quot;, specially given to your son and daughter-in-law: In a sea of ​​more than one billion people, you meet and get to know each other. Meet and fall in love. I hope you will cherish the fate of thousands of miles and thousands of years, and respect, understand and help each other. As parents of newlyweds, I would also like to remind you: First, always be kind and help those in need around you in a timely manner; second, always be grateful and never forget to care about those who help us... The true marriage between a Jiangsu boy and a Hunan girl is For the love of &quot;rivers and lakes&quot;, I look forward to you riding the wind and waves and being proud of the &quot;rivers and lakes&quot;! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These golden expressions are enough to be provocative. At the wedding scene, the parents of the newlyweds simultaneously hung up the red couplets of &quot;Always Be Kind&quot; and &quot;Always Be Grateful&quot;. The eight big characters attracted the attention of the entire audience. , the banner of &quot;Swordsman Jiangsu and Hunan&quot; was unfolded, which pushed the atmosphere of the night to a new climax. In an instant, many people switched to &quot;hilarious mode.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most ceremonial part was the &quot;tribute moment&quot;, the high-profile appearance of the groom&#39;s 99-year-old grandmother. The old man came from out of town, more than 4 hours&#39; drive away, to wish the newlyweds a long and happy life. The bride and groom made a special trip to hand over red envelopes and shouted in the old man’s ears: Grandma, may you be healthy for a long time! Happy for a long time! ! This was the fourth time the old lady attended her grandson&#39;s wedding, but it was the first time she received a blessing red envelope from the couple. She smiled like a child. According to reports, the red envelope is a lucky number: 999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is interesting is the on-site blessing from Professor Zhu of Shanghai University Hospital: I am a cardiologist and have been dealing with the &quot;heart&quot; all my life. On this special day, I returned to my hometown and said a few words from my heart: First, in a small family, new people must be loyal to each other and care for each other. Entering the marriage hall today means the beginning of firewood, rice, oil, salt, pots and pans. In the future, small families will inevitably encounter small difficulties and setbacks. You must be patient! Second, in the workplace, you must be open-minded when it comes to professional matters, have perseverance in sticking to your post, and be enthusiastic about your colleagues! The third is to be kind and filial to your relatives, friends, parents, and elders in your hometown, and pay more attention to the details - your parents do not ask you to make much contribution, but there are overseas video calls every now and then, and they are sent to the family group every day. A smiling face is enough! As long as you have love, we can rest assured in our hometown! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wedding is the highlight moment for the newlyweds. The protagonists of the wedding are the groom and the bride, their growth background, love story, and future vision. However, the protagonists are not necessarily the highlights of the scene. The family or friends of the newcomers, those characters who appear in supporting roles, can sometimes surprise and win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This wedding is full of positive energy, without clichés, not preachy, and down to earth. The only bad thing was that people ended up forgetting a few dishes and a few glasses of wine. Some people say that marriage is a school that teaches people to tolerate, understand, and share. Then, the wedding may be the &quot;first lesson of school&quot;, a lesson in life, life, and respect for the elderly. At the end of the day, it’s all common sense lessons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a Jiangsu media person)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; Share what you see, hear and think about the countryside. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS: &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿拉伯的劳伦斯：传奇、神话和现代中东诞生记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwoPm87.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;715&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwo Pm87. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Thomas Edward Lawrence&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in 1920, in a private house in Westminster Abbey, London, T.E. Lawrence was immersed in writing his war memoirs. After being expelled from the Paris Peace Conference a year ago, this famous World War I hero was struggling with persistent depression. Only writing could temporarily pull him out of the swamp of despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The silence was broken by a ringing sound. It was a call from Whitehall in London - the other party was Winston Churchill, who was to be the Colonial Secretary. He wanted to invite Lawrence to assist him in handling Middle Eastern affairs. This controversial figure who was reduced to a &quot;political pariah&quot; five years ago due to his defeat in the Middle East battlefield has made a comeback and is trying to figure out how to deal with the mess of the British Empire in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;World War I&quot; has ended, the Ottoman Empire has been dismembered, and peace has not come: In Palestine, conflicts between the Zionists supported by the British and the local Arabs quickly intensified, and eventually escalated to Bloody conflicts; even more serious was the outbreak of a full-scale anti-British uprising in Iraq, an oil-producing area controlled by the British, and tens of thousands of people died in bloodshed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The allies are not having a good time either - in the desert of Transjordan, Prince Abdullah from the Hashemite family has been ferociously attacking the French who control the Syrian region. A few months ago, the French had just used force to seize this territory from Faisal, another prince of the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 1919, the Paris Peace Conference, which had been wrangling for half a year, came to an end. The Middle East, divided among the victors, is filled with hatred, bloodshed and conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite Lawrence&#39;s rejection, Churchill had no intention of giving up. This extraordinary man, who would go on to become one of the most important statesmen of the 20th century, knew that Lawrence of Arabia was the key to unraveling this mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two unconventional &quot;political pariahs&quot; are about to work together to shape the history of the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1913, Lawrence (second from right) and British archaeologist Leonard Woolley participated in archaeological operations at the ancient Hittite city Carchemish in the Ottoman Empire. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Smart &quot;illegitimate son&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; He is an Irish nobleman and a mistress eloped. crystallization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In order to avoid social pressure, Lawrence&#39;s parents&#39; surnames were anonymous to avoid living in the countryside and frequently moved, and they almost did not communicate with the surrounding neighbors. It wasn&#39;t until the education and future of the five sons that he had moved to the lively Oxford County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the eyes of the teacher, the boy is very smart, quiet, likes books, but is keen on prank. He especially likes to play games that test his extreme survival endurance, such as not drinking water, eating, and sleeping, and he can always persist in fainting. The principal of Oxford Public School recalled: Lawrence and boys of the same age are very different. There are quite some ancient Greek -Gepai style, &quot;I don&#39;t care about the joy and pain of the flesh.&quot; , Especially obsessed with the Middle Ages Cavaliers literature, interested in military history and archeological. During the holiday, he would ride a bicycle to explore the monuments of England with his friends, and also went to the Ashmorin Museum in Oxford as an assistant. He was later admitted to the main history of Jesus College of Oxford University. During college, he rode 2400 miles to inspect the ancient castles and military relics in Europe, and went to the Mediterranean all the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In January 1909, in order to understand a academic case in the medieval military history, he went to Syria to investigate. Under the scorching sun, he set off from Berut, passed through the Lebanese mountains, and arrived in northern Palestine; returned to Berut three weeks later, and then went north to continue to be more difficult archeology. After returning, he wrote the thesis &quot;The Influence of the Crusades of the 12th Century on the European Military Architecture&quot; and won the highest first prize of Oxford. In addition, it is awarded a scholarship for graduate stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1910, the British Museum launched the archeological excavation of the Calkimish ancient city site in Turkey and Syria today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence served as the junior assistant, and soon became the person in charge of the excavation site and managed more than two hundred local workers. He did well. He usually used Arabic to chat with workers, visited and visited their family, and recorded their folklore, the structural relationship between the family and the tribes, and their political views. Workers also have a good opinion of this young European, because he really respects their customs and culture, and is willing to accept money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It can be said that at the time, there was no better understanding of Westerners in the Syrian region than Lawrence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Karkimish, Lawrence and a 13 -year -old Syrian teenager are inseparable and very close. This young man who was called Darhm in his memoir, the real name, Saishmad, dedicated the war memoir &quot;SA&quot; to &quot;SA&quot;. Dahom was smart and handsome, with two deep dimples on his face, and he laughed innocently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the curiosity of scholars, Lawrence has made real appreciation and respect for near -East culture in contact with local society. He began to reflect on the proud imperialist consciousness of Western&#39;s proud imperialism on the West. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a scholar who really penetrates into the hinterland of Syria, Lawrence has clearly seen the general trend of the Ottoman Empire collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, the Ottoman Empire, which ruled the Arabian Peninsula for more than four centuries and across Asia, Africa and Europe, had entered the dusk and was known as the &quot;European sick husband.&quot; With the rise of nationalism and the development of international trade around the world, more and more domestic and foreign challenges faced by Ottoman. In the outside, the strong European strengths are constantly eating its territory and sovereignty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eavznh9ps2iktoaaruyacubk02ldofh1.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;735&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eavznh9puk8ps2iktoaCubk02ldofh1.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259971&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In November 1917, the British Egypt expeditions broke through the Ottoman army&#39;s defense line and captured the Palestinian region; in December, the British entered Jerusalem &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; ( Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Inside the empire, the power to promote reform and demand modernization has always existed. In 1908, a group of young officers, known as the &quot;Young Turkish Party&quot;, launched a coup, forcing Hamid II to restore the Constitution of the Parliament. In 1913, the party&#39;s nationalist radicals in charge of power and established a centralized dictatorship system with the &quot;three oligarchs&quot; as the core. They adjusted the reform plan into the implementation of modernization, defending Islam and Pan -Turkicism in order to fight for the united empire&#39;s territory in the territory of the empire. Each group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in a huge empire with a multi -language multi -ethnic group and the society that constitutes abnormally complicated, it is impossible for any reform program to appease all groups: the secular efforts have greatly irritated the traditional Muslims with a large number of people. ; Advocating pan -Turkicism, and other ethnic groups of non -Turkish people, such as the Arabs and Armenians, are born with the heart ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this moment, young archaeologists are drunk. And love. When he was determined to invest and study the ruins of the ancient city in the next four or five years, the bad news came: the project funding of the British Museum has been exhausted, and the excavation work must be suspended until there are new funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But there is another opportunity to work: funded by a foundation, a special team of the Royal Workers in the UK wants to conduct an archeological adventure of the desert area in southern Palestine. Ask if they are interested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence and his companions readily accepted. &quot;Fang Mo&quot; in the south of Israel today, according to the Old Testament, it is the last place where the ancient Jews ran away from Egypt and the wild in the wilderness under the leadership of the prophet Moses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Smart as Lawrence, he soon guessed that the adventure operation under the name of the foundation was actually a secret military geographic exploration. At that time, the British troops occupied the buffer belt of the Suez Canal and the Sinai Peninsula, and the relationship with the Ottoman Empire was always nervous. By the outbreak of the &quot;World War I&quot;, because they were worried that once the Ottomans forth with Germany, they would attack the Egypt and seize the canal. The situation of the desert area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The British Captain Stuart Newkom was responsible for this operation. He has a good opinion of this Oxford scholar who does not care about enjoying, stunning endurance, and even being abused, and is particularly impressed by his quirk. In general, Lawrence is a very shy person, but once someone attempts to attempt He will become resolute and bold to obstruct or fool him. On the way to find a deserted adventure, because of the surveillance and obstruction of the Ottoman military police everywhere, Lawrence showed this kind of breakthrough ability with children&#39;s prank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the &quot;World War I&quot; broke out, he brought Lawrence into the British army&#39;s military intelligence agency in Cairo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 28, 1914, the Austro -Hungarian Empire Emperor Chu Dihinan and his wife were assassinated in Sarajewo, and the First World War broke out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; October, Lawrence, who was just 26 years old, was sent to the Geography Department of the General Staff of the UK as a map painter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Senior military and political officials in the empire, this arrogant young man is still sloppy, freely scattered, indifferent to various rules and regulations. In his eyes, these senior officials were all silly forks in the abdomen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because a general wanted to make a report with an identity report to himself, Lawrence was dramatically promoted as a big lieutenant. But what he longed for was to show his skills at the front line. Lawrence is less than 1.65 meters tall and lower than the British Army&#39;s lowest standard, so the only opportunity to go to the front line is where he needs his special talent -the Middle East battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 2, 1914, the Ottoman Empire eventually joined the Allies and officially participated in the war. On December 15, Lawrence came to Cairo with a French carboat and reported to the military intelligence unit led by Newkom. At this time, the hustle and bustle of Cairo was an important transit hub of the personnel and supplies in the &quot;World War I&quot;. Hundreds of thousands of British colonies from India, Australia and New Zealand opened from here to the European battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/of9gtmleihfgx1qvqgiyxmtijzqwhszCT3R.JPG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;632&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/of9gtmleihfgx1qvqgiyxmtijzqwhszct3r.jpg =&quot; 259969 &quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In 1918, Lawrence led in Drac and launched the most fierce attack on the Hanzhi Railway. The picture shows Lawrence view the destroyed train &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Million cracks of &quot;European sick husband&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;/h4>; P>; In the British intelligence agency in Cairo, one of Lawrence&#39;s work content is to write a report describing the topographic and cultural and ethnic composition of the Osman Empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The experience of deepening Syrian society for many years has allowed Lawrence to see the countless cracks inside this old empire -in the huge territory of the Turkish people&#39;s heyday in the past, there are a lot of The ethnic group of the war to the relationship; they were originally full of resentment with the rulers of Turkish, and the war made this hatred deeper. In this empire, the largest population is the Arabs who believe in Islam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1908, the modern and secular reforms promoted after the youth Turkish Party came to power, which angered Hussein Ibn Ali, a religious and political leader in controlling the Hanzhi region of the Arabian Peninsula. He is the leader of the famous Hashim family, the prophet Muhammad&#39;s direct descendants, and has been guarding the Macata Holy Land for generations. As the &quot;saint&quot;, Hussein is one of the most lofty religious leaders in the Islamic world and has a strong influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the Ottoman Empire joined the &quot;World War I&quot;, the relationship between the two sides became more deteriorating. Hussein, a religious leader launched the so -called &quot;jihad&quot; propaganda launched by the official, remained silent; the Ottoman Empire asked him to send troops to assists in the Suez Canal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, in February 1914 before the outbreak of &quot;World War I&quot;, Abdullah took the opportunity to visit Cairo to visit the British Egypt Governor Kirinner. Sexual question: If the Arabic uprising erupts in the Hanzhi area, how will Britain react. Kinsona carefully avoided it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the official participation in the Ottoman Empire in November 1914, Kicinsner, who became the British Minister of the British Army, immediately sent a secret electricity to Cairo, so that the old Sottoz faction and Abdullah secretly secretly Contact, to find out Hussein&#39;s true attitude. This time, Hussein recovered cautiously that he would maintain neutrality, but at the same time hinted that if the British provided external aid and ensured that he would not interfere with the internal affairs of Arabia, he might lead his followers to launch an uprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This makes Kicinsner very happy. He wrote to Hussein&#39;s letter- &quot;From today, we will be friends with noble Arabs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Knowing it After these secrets came to the letter, Lawrence felt like &quot;Shenqi&quot; -after Cairo, he has been studying the possibility of launching the Arab uprising in the Syrian region. The Middle East battlefield is relatively lacking from European roads and obtained resources. Therefore, Lawrence believes that the United Kingdom needs to adopt a unconventional war, that is, the use of the social, ethnic contradictions and divisions in the internal social, ethnic contradictions and divisions of the Ottoman Empire. Undested Turkey&#39;s rule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5tnegpf03MPRBRXWBRSHTN9q7q15L7J7ypg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;743&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5TNEGPF03MPRBUQRXWBRSHTN9q7q15L7J7YPZ.JPG&quot; data- &quot;>; 259973&quot;>; &lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In 1919, the Fergal (front row) and Lawrence (second right of the second row) during the Paris time in Paris and &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;(visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The uprising of the heavy contract &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; From July 1915 to January 1916, Hussein and the British senior commissioner in Egypt Henry Mike Mahong (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; that is, &quot;McMahon Line&quot; deliner &lt;/span>;) secretly comes to bargain to bargain. Several Arab nationalist secrets in Syria also secretly contacted Hussein in secret, hoping to jointly launch the uprising to resist the Turks, providing support from the United Kingdom, and using him as a spiritual leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But what Hussein finally decided to fall to the United Kingdom was a rumor -at the time, it was rumored that Constantinople intentionally abolished him and let the leader of the Zaid family replaced. On May 6, 1916, Jemalpatha, one of the &quot;three oligarchs&quot; of Ottoman, executed 21 Arab nationalists in Damascus. Hussein sent his son Fasal to say love and was rejected and intimidated. This has made him more aggravated of the restlessness of future destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In these secret communication, the British assured Hussein: If he led the army to assist the British Middle East war, after the war, the British would assist him to establish a place between Egypt and Persia, but It does not include the Arab Empire in Kuwait, Aden and the Syrian coast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Mcma Hong also inserted an inconspicuous condition in the letter: these commitments enabled only when &quot;Britain can be freely decided, not endangering the interests of its allies France&quot;. Among them, part of Palestine&#39;s part of the part was not talked about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When France learned that Britain and Hussein were talking about secrets, they immediately proposed their rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In January 1916, a &quot;amateur politician&quot; from a nobleman, a &quot;amateur politician&quot; named Mark Sicks and the French diplomat Franvo George-Pipo reached a war in London Later the draft of the Middle East vision, which was later officially signed in Peter Geller in Russia, which is known as the &quot;Socker-Portrak Agreement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据这份秘密协定：独立的阿拉伯国家被大致限制在阿拉伯半岛的荒漠里，法国直接控制大叙利亚，英国则占领产油的整个伊拉克；另有两块飞地，侯The north of the Hanzhi kingdom ruled by Saiyin, all areas of the remaining inland are &quot;semi -independent areas&quot;, are indirectly controlled by Britain and France; Palestine is a &quot;international co -management area&quot; and will be jointly shared by Britain, France, and Russia. manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How is this series of &quot;oolong&quot; incidents become the factual facts step by step in the acquiescence, and historians are still arguing for this. In short, the British government&#39;s contradictory documents signed with the Arabs and French respectively will laid the roots of the turbulence of the Middle East in the future of the Middle East, so it will push Lawrence to the classical tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 5, 1915, in the Holy Land, Micatriga, Hussein Ibn Ali climbed into a tower in the palace, and fired a shot with a Turkish fortress in the city in the city. . On the same day, his two sons Ali and Ferobar took the lead in acting, and 1,500 Arabian knights fired on McDIC&#39;s pair. After that, Hussein&#39;s followers launched an attack in the Turkish base in Hanzhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hussein issued a declaration to Muslims around the world: publicly condemned the Turkish authorities to &quot;persecute and slaughter the Arab nationalists, deviate from Islamic spirit&quot;, and announced that the Arabian Empire was separated from the Ottoman Empire. He was self -proclaimed as the king of the Kingdom of Han. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The famous &quot;Arab uprising&quot; in the modern history of the Middle East broke out and officially opened on the stage with Lawrence as the main character. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Find the &quot;Rabbit&quot; who is looking for the prophet and holding the king &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;The hotness of the Arabian Peninsula is like a sharp sword with a sheath, which makes us open.&quot; October 16, 1916 In the morning light of the day, when Lawrence accompanied the British Eastern Culture Secretary to the important port Gada, who was controlled by the Hussein uprising, he recorded this moment in the diary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before embarrassed Han Zhi, he had designed a new direction for the Arabic uprising, and the positioning of the role of himself- &quot;Looking for the unknown master soul for the uprising, and measured him The ability to advance the uprising to the goal I envisioned. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Hussein launched the first shot, and after a month of bloody alley war, the insurgents and the Ottoman army entered the stalemate stage. Moreover, the prestigious righteousness of the Melizer&#39;s sacred guardian is not as expected -it aroused a wider ethnic uprising on the Arabian Peninsula and did not respond in Syria and other regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence believes that the core of the problem is the lack of a leader. Unlike Western political culture, the Arab uprising is not a clever politician, but a prophet, &quot;not intelligent, not judgment, not political wisdom, but can ignite the passion of the desert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When his chief and the leaders of the rebels discussed the details of the cooperation, Lawrence looked for the opportunity to carefully observe Hussein&#39;s four sons: the eldest son Ali, the second son Abdullah, the three sons Ferza Er and young son Zair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He first met the three princes except Fasal: Abdullah was happy, and he blessed early because he was greedy for enjoyment. Sad and exhausted, there is no obvious ambition, and it is easy to be affected by the people around him. As for Zael, he is only 20 years old. people. Lawrence concluded that they could not be the kind of &quot;armed prophets that wins in the revolution in history&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Until Lawrence rode a camel 100 miles, crossed the regions controlled by multiple hostile tribes, and saw Fergal, who was stationed in the desert oasis with another tribal soldier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I felt at the first glance when I saw him, this is the person I came to the Arabian Peninsula, the person who will bring the Arab uprising to bring a full glory.&quot; Ferobasal was thin and long, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, and there was a one. The strange and quiet, the passion and the rhetoric when they speak, the iron -like determination revealed behind the words has deeply attracted Lawrence. This was what he couldn&#39;t find in the other three princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence was still walking around in his camp for a long time, chatting with soldiers with fluent Arabic. He found that the more than 6,000 people summoned by Fasal include almost all the tribes in the western Hanzhi. Although they just lost a battle, their morale rose and had unwavering confidence in victory. It was Fasal who united them and always encouraged them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The more he is firm, the more firm Fergar is the &quot;prophet&quot; he want The trip made Lawrence the first foreigner to observe the battlefield in the Arabian Peninsula. When returning to Yanbu and other ships back to Cairo, he wrote a report of 15,000 words in five days and made two important judgments: one is that Britain only sent a small number of troops to Hanzhi region; the other is that the real &quot;prophet&quot; of the leadership uprising is fee. Sal, not the British familiar Abdullah. He also pointed out that the only way to cooperate is that the British must accept the way of fighting the Arabs and adjust their strategy and expectations accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This report of Lawrence basically changed the British policy to the Arabian Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the huge bureaucracy of the British Empire, many smart ideas are buried every day. After writing a report in Cairo&#39;s office for nearly two years, Lawrence slowly found the rules of the game. He was very good at using the bureaucratic system and faction to achieve his own goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After returning from Han Zhi, under the dazzling operation of Lawrence, through memo, reporting, and reporting, intentionally guided, bypassing and even destroying &quot;obstacles&quot;. In the end It was adopted and obtained green lights from the senior management of military and political from Egypt to London. Soon, Cryon, director of the Arabian Arab Arabian Arabia, informed Lawrence: He would send him to the Arabian Peninsula to serve as a temporary liaison officer around Fasal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The superiors and colleagues were happily sent away this &quot;arrogant and self -sophisticated, stinky, and hairy rabbits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ev9bygqfq730yztxt16fkkgadylvQicw4kpj.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;704&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ev9shs7bygq730yztXt16FKKGADYLVQICW4KPG&quot; data-key = &quot;259970&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; In 1921, Churchill (in the front row) and Lawrence (fourth right of the second row) &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/ Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become the &quot;Son of Desert&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In December 1916, when Lawrence was the British liaison officer, he came to Fergar&#39;s camp again and was The suggestion was put on a pure white robe of the Ferga La. During the entire war, he lived with the soldiers of the Arab tribe as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Arab tribal camp, the typical day spent the day: Early morning, an Imam wake up the camp with prayer, and then the long breakfast time. Every morning, anyone can come to Fasal to sing unjust, petitions, and fixed disputes. During the day, most of his time he was eating, drinking tea, and chatting with staff and tribal leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence himself has always been known for his irritability and strictness, but he realized that these long -time and aimless chats are the way Arabs deal with war and peace. Fergaal united these loose tribes and clan around him with this as a adhesive. During the entire operation, he also acts as a mediation arbiter between the tribes, listening, suggestions, and coaxing if necessary, and often paid for the reconciliation of both parties in the interests of interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the uprising, almost all British military advisers who have been sent to Hanzhi are very scornful for the fighting power of the Arabs. Lawrence also agreed, but after fighting with them, he came to an important point: he could not measure the European war standards to measure the Arabs, and it was difficult to organize and train them into European combat forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are really good at guerrilla warfare, coupled with the geographical environment, the mobility is strong. In the war, when the force and weapons and weapons were obviously not as good as the enemy, the weak party should not be connected to the other person&#39;s positive short soldiers, but &quot;floating around like the air.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the first day of the uprising, whether it is Hussein and his followers, or British, they have taken the second Holy City McDIC in Islam as the main goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Danaor believes that the correct strategy is to abandon McDonaline where the heavy soldiers guard, so that the Ottoman army stays there almost infinitely, so that they can barely maintain the supply line. The rebels were captured. In the end, he convinced the insurgents to transfer the strategic focus to harassment and destruction of the area along the Hanzhi Railway. While forcing Tujun to send heavy soldiers to defend the railway, it has to bear continuous maintenance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Arab uprising, the new goals and new strategies set by Lawrence make the situation reverse, the blow has become effective, and the casualties have decreased significantly. During the &quot;World War I&quot;, the guerrilla warfare that the Arabic uprising continued to launch effectively delayed the operation of the Ottoman army and helped the cooperation country to eventually defeat the Ottoman Empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ru2VLCM0Z8CZJ9I6SEMMLQYNW01DMZSL.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;769&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ru2vlcm0z8czj9i6semmlqynw01dmzsl.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;259976&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Lawrence (left) and American traveler and journalist Lovil Thomas in Arabia &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become a legend -attack Avaspa &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The Aqaba Bay is located east of Sinai Peninsula and west of Arabia. It is a bay in the north of the Red Sea. The port of Yakha is at the end of its northern part. From the plan, it is an ideal assembly place for attacking southern Palestine from Egypt. Entering 60 miles east is the Hanyan Railway on the Arabian Peninsula on the Arabian Peninsula. In the future of the Middle East War, this is the strategic place of offensive and defensive offensive and defensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1914, Lawrence was also an archaeologist at the British Museum, who had an adventure at Aikepa Bay. From the port of Aqaba to the inland, there are steep mountains that are rising altitude, followed by inland deserts. The only passage from the port of Akaba to the inland is the canyon, where the Ottomans built a network system composed of bunkers and trenches along the line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Britain and France have their own abacus for how to deal with this obvious strategic position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of January 1917, with the cooperation of Lawrence&#39;s contact and the British army, Fasal led his tribal army to seize the important port Wosh in the middle of the Red Sea. The French representatives began to lobby Britain to attack and control Avas Caska, so that the British Egyptian Expeditionary Force launched the British Egyptian Army in the right wing. Another more secretive motivation is to suppress the Arab uprising with a momentum of the momentum in Hanzhi and command them to cooperate as needed. If they do not accept it, they threaten the support of weapons and gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence has always opposed Fasal&#39;s plan to attack Avas. He knew the abacus of the contract: if the Arabs were only cooperated with the British and French attacks, Aikepa would become their &quot;death trap&quot; and finally fell empty -handed. To this end, he did not hesitate to risk the &quot;crime of betrayal&quot; and disclosed the British -French secrets to Fergal in February 1917. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On the other hand, if the Arabs control the port of the northernmost point of the Red Sea themselves, once the uprising troops are fighting in the Syrian region north, the material supply line can be greatly shortened, from the original 300 -mile to 60 miles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 1917, the boss Cryon issued a secret order from Cairo to Lawrence: Do not let the Arabs appear in Aasha. He understood his subtext -Cright&#39;s letter to a general was more clear: given the importance of Avaspa to Egyptian defense, the British must firmly control the sea port city after the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April of that year, when Lawrence asked a dozen Turkish prisoners of war sent by the British army, Lawrence got a new information: the Aqaba garrison just changed, and the number of people rarely exceeded 100 people, and from Asia The road between Ma&#39;an Town, the Hanye Railway hub in the inland, has only 200 natives stationed in Ma&#39;an Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence quickly made a bold adventure decision -before the British and French army dyed Avha, the United Desert tribal forces convened an Arab armed forces, and then turned over the mountains and rolled the mountains. At the end of Ma&#39;an Town, the Port of Akhapa. Through the victory that the Arabs strived to minimize the influence of European strong forces in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is also Lawrence&#39;s bold and most famous military operation in &quot;World War I&quot;. He used his lightly described excuses to stuff other British officers around him and his boss far away from Cairo. &quot;So, no matter whether there is or not or not, go to his own way.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Lawrence and 45 Desert Warriors set off from Vosh, with gold coins worth 20,000 pounds and some re -guns, riding camels into the Hul Desert in the Northeast inland, and planned to go to the Hostert Tribe deep in the desert to recruit soldiers. And encouraged the Syrian tribe to go north and liberate Syria&#39;s front station for the uprising army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They stayed in the Waldisir Han Oasis who entered the Syrian area. More and more tribal representatives came to discuss with the insurgents and join the Arab independence cause. When Lawrence accepted a round of tribal feasts, his guilt was getting deeper and deeper. He knew that after being deceived -after winning, the contract country would inevitably betray the Arabs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under a extremely complicated painful mentality, he made a suicide adventure -go north to Syria alone, detour 400 miles in the enemy, and arrive in the outskirts of Lebanon and Damascus northward. Potential uprising allies, including tribal leaders and urban Arab nationalists. At that time, Damascus was located in the Joint Command of the Ottoman Army and the German Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a desert oasis, he saw the lofty prestige Emir (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; The nobility of the Arab world &lt;/span &lt;/span >;) Nuri Salad. When the old chief who was at the depths of the desert took out a bunch of copywriting copies of the document that contradicts each other and asked him exactly what the British promised, Lawrence had to recommend the closest choice date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The old chief was persuaded, and Lawrence was ashamed. &quot;I used lies to make a reputation for myself and become the leader of the fraud group.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence said he really woke up With the motivation to survive. &quot;I vowed to spare no effort until they brought the final victory to the Arabs, asking for respect for the Arabs, and negotiating a fair and reasonable solution. Only by protecting the troubled times in front of me in the future . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Swamp -like situation, Whenever Lawrence&#39;s most incredible courage, ingenuity and endurance are stimulated. The legendary battle during the &quot;World War I&quot; -attacking the battle of Avas Caska -it happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 18, 1917, Lawrence and the &quot;Legendary Desert Samurai&quot; Oda Abu Toy led the 500 camel cavalry from the Wadisir Han to march southwest. When they arrived in Bell, they found the footprint of the Ottoman army -the most important water well in the desert march was blown up, and the goal of the uprising army was Avaspa. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence commanded and led the Arabs to put on a god -level ecstasy array -as early as ten days ago, when he went north to Syria, he made a pavement and brought a local team to bomb. Destroy a small bridge on the Hanzhi Railway north of Damascus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 21, he led 100 soldiers to Amman on the railway 150 miles north, and quickly destroyed a railway culvert and then returned quickly. In the south of Syria, the insurgents launched a series of guerrilla warfare. This made the Turkish troops unable to find the law at all, and had to diversify their troops and follow them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A good news came: a team they sent a few days ago had just captured and destroyed the Turkish military base, Fuvila, and the road from the inland to Avasaka was basically basically. Open. When they hurriedly bypassed Ma&#39;an Town and rushed to Aikeha, there was news of bad news: On the morning of the same day, about 500 Ottoman soldiers rushed to Fvira to increase their troops. at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After thinking about it, Lawrence made a decision: must actively find and annihilate Ottoman reinforcements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the dawn on July 2, in a narrow road south of Fvira, they found an enemy who was sleeping. After cruel killing, they finally killed 300 people and 160 captives. . However, when the prisoners of war revealed that Ma Anzhen defended the emptiness, the tribal warriors from the bandits shouted, and wanted to take the opportunity to loot the rich transportation hub. Lawrence tried to persuade and promised to give them more compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When they moved west along the highway, they passed through the empty Turkish fortress and trenches -this proves that Lawrence has not been recognized by the boss. &quot; We will attack from the inland. In all their large defensive industries, there is no trenches and no posts are facing inland. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; After two days of stalemate, the troops led by Lawrence are almost not bloodless blades. The ground won the port of Yakha. The next day, he went to Egypt again, traveled through the camel through the 150 -mile desert to the Suez Canal, and informed the British to quickly add reinforcements and transport food and other supplies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On July 10, 1917, Lawrence, who had been &quot;missing&quot; for more than two months, wore a sloppy Arabic robe and suddenly appeared in the Cairo office of the British intelligence agency. Within a few days, his heroic deeds spread in the senior management of Egypt and London. As the Western Front war was unfavorable and the French army was changing, the victory of the British in the Middle East battlefield was particularly exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the general public, this is a legend of lonely heroes that can arouse endless romantic imagination -a young, blue -eyed British officer wearing a alien robe, riding a camel, and a single shot deep into the horse. In the hinterland of the enemy, secrets to meet and strive for potential conspirators, walking around in the middle of the people who want to be smoked, they may be sold and executed at any time. Then, the hero led the tribal warriors, who made a conspiracy and won a series of incredible victory with less victory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The British Egyptian commander Wengate proposed to the senior management of London: Lawrence awarded the highest military honor in Britain -Victoria Cross.很快，他被提拔为上校，并提名授予三等骑士爵位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一回，桀骜不驯的劳伦斯却谦卑恭顺地接受了——官方的认可和荣誉也可以成为一种强有力的工具，去影响军事高层的决策，以实现他在沙漠里发下的誓言：突破法国人所设的“红线”，把战火一直烧到叙利亚，让英国人帮助阿拉伯人解放叙利亚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;站在新任英国埃及远征军总司令埃德蒙·艾伦比面前，他描绘了一番激动人心的战况和未来前景。随即，艾伦比给帝国总参谋长威廉·罗伯逊拍去一份洋溢着乐观情绪的电报。最终，这位视西线为重中之重的总协调人答应给中东增兵5万，用于巴勒斯坦战场的攻势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是阿拉伯大起义的一个关键转折点。撬动齿轮的人，正是劳伦斯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在高层要求下，这位“当红炸子鸡”写下了供海外作战军官参考的经验总结，是为《二十七条建议》。他最重要的心得是：抛弃英国人的习惯，让自己完全沉浸到当地环境，要熟悉“当地的家庭、氏族和部落、朋友和敌人、水井、山丘和道路”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006年，美国对伊拉克发动军事行动，美军总司令戴维·彼得雷乌斯将军就命令高级军官们阅读《二十七条建议》，向劳伦斯学习如何赢得伊拉克本地的人心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/2GoBfcYcaBhBupnkcwvtvyN6jtzDWoOVshoucg6i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;717&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/2GoBfcYcaBhBupnkcwvtvyN6jtzDWoOVshoucg6i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;骑着骆驼的劳伦斯&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被污损的英雄&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1917年10月起，一些接近劳伦斯的人发现他处于安静的沮丧状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从担任阿拉伯大起义的英方联络官，他一直过着高度紧张的生活，就像一个伟大的演员，马不停蹄地进行“惊险表演”。这在智力、体力、精神上都是巨大的消耗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更主要的原因，是越来越升级的杀戮。在《智慧七柱》里，他记录下第一次近距离处决一个人，然后他病倒了。起初，他带领阿拉伯人四处打游击战，尽量避免杀戮无辜。一次伏击行动中，他们抓住了一个撞见他们的牧童，劳伦斯把他绑在树上，以防他去给土军通风报信，战斗结束撤离前，再把他释放。随着战争越来越紧张、残酷，他已经顾不上很多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等到亚喀巴战役的富维拉峡谷之战结束，他用极为诡异、凄美的文字描写了在月光下看到几百具被剥走衣服的土耳其士兵的尸体，看上去年轻、白皙、宁静，令人心生悲悯，“于是我把他们全都摆放整齐，一个一个地摆好。我自己也很疲惫，渴望成为这些宁静的人中的一员，而不是回到山谷高处那群没有片刻安宁、吵闹、苦痛的暴徒当中去。那些人还在为战利品而争。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对越来越频繁的杀戮，他似乎越来越冷漠，越来越无动于衷。但在给牛津密友的信里，他倾吐说：“我希望噩梦结束，我能够醒来，重新活过来。杀人，杀土耳其人真是太可怕了”，“我知道自己已经干过这种事情几百次，如果可以的话，还要再干几百次”，“我在这场游戏里撑不了多久了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上司克莱顿已经注意到这位最得力干将的精神状态，他承认对劳伦斯的状态非常担忧，“我们会尽快把他撤下来的，不要继续让他冒险，但时间还没有到，因为现在还需要他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年11月，为配合埃及远征军对巴勒斯坦的攻势，劳伦斯带着一名护卫去勘查叙利亚境内铁路枢纽德拉附近的情况时，他被奥斯曼的一支部队逮捕了，然后被押到当地总督那里。劳伦斯谎称自己是高加索一个山地民族的平民，这个民族以皮肤白皙、眼珠浅色著称，且免于兵役。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后是他整部回忆录里最恐怖的场景，劳伦斯用了整整五页的篇幅描述自己所遭受的暴行细节——他先是被土耳其总督施以弥漫着血腥气息的暴力性侵；然后被四个士兵鞭打，接着是被刑讯军官反复踢打；他又被拖回总督的房间。后来他被扔在一个庭院里，一个亚美尼亚人过来为他清创、包扎。这群人随后扬长而去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天微亮时，劳伦斯清醒过来，跌跌撞撞地走出镇子。在一个骆驼商人的帮助下，他找到了同伴，然后讲述一个“通过贿赂和计谋逃脱敌人魔掌的欢乐故事”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们发现：从德拉回来后，劳伦斯身上的一些东西变了，他更加孤傲冷漠。从那以后，这个过往胆大包天的人给自己组织了一支50人的精锐卫队，时刻陪伴在他身边。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10个月后，等他率领阿拉伯战士再次回到这座铁路城镇，他带着复仇的火焰下令进行了一场血腥大屠杀，共有四千多人丧生，史称“塔法斯屠杀”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德拉事件给劳伦斯留下的精神创伤是永久性的——“一战“结束后，对被他视为忏悔神父般的存在的萧伯纳夫人，他倾吐了内心的被污损感和强烈的自我憎恶，“那件事”之后，他发誓从此“弃绝过体面的生活”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7QS17IxA1tkbMuvRygpq9jt1YSkqDU2uuPS7uUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;747&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7QS17IxA1tkbMuvRygpq9jt1YSkqDU2uuPS7uUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1962年电影《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;越缠越多的乱麻：贝尔福宣言，魏茨曼和劳伦斯&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1917年11月，英国埃及远征军顺利地突破奥斯曼军队防线，攻占巴勒斯坦地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，劳伦斯已得知一个将使未来局面越发乱成一锅粥的消息：英国政府内阁在10月底初步通过了支持犹太复国主义者在巴勒斯坦建立“民族家园”的《贝尔福宣言》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“锡安主义”，我国一般称之为“犹太复国主义”，是一种犹太民族主义思潮，号召散居世界各地的犹太人返回故国——巴勒斯坦，重建犹太国家，复兴犹太民族。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到19世纪末，欧洲出现新一轮反犹太主义浪潮后，犹裔奥地利记者西奥多·赫茨尔提出了现代犹太复国主义的理论和纲领，并于1897年举行第一次锡安主义代表大会，创建世界锡安主义组织。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1916年底，英国新首相大卫·劳合·乔治上任，他和外务大臣贝尔福都是锡安主义运动的同情者，并和该运动核心人物、著名化学家哈伊姆·魏茨曼有交往。除宗教同情之外，这也有现实政治的考量：“一战”陷入僵持后，交战双方都意识到犹太复国主义者的广泛影响，都希望得到他们的帮助；但德国碍于巴勒斯坦地区是盟友奥斯曼帝国的领地，无法许诺过多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年10月31日，英国政府内阁通过支持性决议，随之而生的《贝尔福宣言》正式宣布：支持锡安主义者在巴勒斯坦建立犹太人“民族之家”，条件是不伤害当地已有民族的权利，但是政治权利除外。当时巴勒斯坦仍然是奥斯曼帝国领土，犹太人只是当地的少数民族。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《贝尔福宣言》是大英帝国的中东政策和以色列建国史上一个重要文件。它促成了巴勒斯坦托管地的建立，这后来成为以色列和巴勒斯坦领土，所以宣言也被视为是导致巴以冲突的一个原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在8个月前，劳伦斯在《阿拉伯公报》上发表了一篇对叙利亚现状的分析。他谈及了导致该地区四分五裂的原因，包括部落、民族、宗教之间种种矛盾，以及任何外来者企图把自己的意志强加于叙利亚，必将面临诸多挑战。劳伦斯还指出：巴勒斯坦南部对犹太复国主义运动者怀有莫大仇恨，包括穆斯林和基督徒，近来事态更是加剧了这种天生仇恨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，这篇文章写于两年前，劳伦斯完全预见到了未来中东地区的无数动荡、冲突和不安。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年2月，这篇文章引起了一位名叫威廉·耶鲁的美国驻中东代表的特别兴趣。这位年轻的前美国石油巨头雇员一心想让自己国家参与到中东事务中来，他于是去拜会劳伦斯，想得知更多相关情报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会面时，劳伦斯堪称毫无保留，甚至还透露了阿拉伯起义军下一步的军事行动目标。他还预言了《贝尔福宣言》的后果：“如果的确在巴勒斯坦建立了一个犹太国家，只能是通过武力来建立，并且要在充满敌意的人群当中通过武力维持下去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有传记作者分析认为：劳伦斯是有意为之，他是想通过耶鲁去影响并引导加入协约国不久的美国政府，进而采纳他所认可的、对叙利亚和巴勒斯坦的政策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而威尔逊总统在1919年的巴黎和会上无甚作为。直到第二次世界大战后，美国彻底取代英国成为世界头号霸主，同时接手其在中东的势力，成为现代以色列建国后最坚实的盟友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《贝尔福宣言》的公布，连同被曝光的《赛克斯-皮科协定》，在阿拉伯世界点燃了愤怒之火。在开罗，一向温顺的埃及穆斯林民众爆发了群体性抗议行动。叙利亚流亡者也越来越担心未来将有一个犹太国家会强加给巴勒斯坦地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汉志国王侯赛因在阿拉伯半岛的最大对手伊本·沙特借此发起新一轮舆论猛攻。伊本·沙特来自控制内志地区的沙特家族，代表着伊斯兰教复古主义势力——瓦哈比教派。他一直有雄心一统阿拉伯半岛。他对外宣称：侯赛因国王是西方基督教的傀儡。但事实上，他本人也依赖于大英帝国殖民分支英属印度的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿拉伯世界的强烈反弹，让英国大为不安。他们向侯赛因施压，要求他公开表态支持。克莱顿则要求劳伦斯去向费萨尔做劝说工作，尽管劳伦斯一直反对英国政府和犹太人之间的协定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年3月，在英国人的陪同下，由魏茨曼带队的“犹太复国主义委员会”对埃及、巴勒斯坦地区进行访问。在埃及，他向英国人、流亡的叙利亚人展开魅力攻势，一再表达犹太复国主义事业的善意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该年6月4日，魏茨曼又亲自到亚喀巴拜访费萨尔。会面气氛十分融洽，魏茨曼甚至带上了阿拉伯头巾；费萨尔则避免做出任何实质性承诺，推说一切决定权都在他父亲那里。劳伦斯找借口避开了，不管上司如何来电施压。他已判定：英国人强加的和谐，只会使得费萨尔和老侯赛因在阿拉伯世界遭到更大的反对声浪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10天后在埃及，他还是见到了魏茨曼。这位世故练达的犹太政治领袖很清楚：和阿拉伯起义领袖是否能达成谅解，关键就在于这位娃娃脸的小个子英国军官。高手过招，也生出了惺惺相惜——劳伦斯也很佩服魏茨曼的玲珑手腕，一面相当成功地消解了阿拉伯人的担忧，一面又用另一套言辞激发犹太人的斗志。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个聪明人达成一个共识——如果犹太人希望能在巴勒斯坦建立一个“民族家园”，就必须先让英国人打赢这场战争，这也就意味着他们应该先支持阿拉伯人的起义。魏茨曼还主动提出一项颇具诱惑力的“支持”：让国际犹太复国主义运动组织来资助阿拉伯独立事业，包括资金、武器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏茨曼的魅力攻势取得了成效，他说服了大多数曾因《贝尔福宣言》而对巴勒斯坦未来感到担忧的英国官员，让他们相信：在巴勒斯坦，犹太社区可以和人口占多数的阿拉伯人在政治上和经济上共同生活、和谐相处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让上司们高兴的是，劳伦斯对犹太复国主义运动似乎不再那么抵触。但他也没有这么天真。在一份秘密报告中，他犀利地指出了这位犹太领袖的真实愿景——“50年之后犹太人将完全控制巴勒斯坦，而当前的目标是犹太人在英国幌子之下控制巴勒斯坦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1930年代，希特勒在德国上台后，纳粹党徒对犹太人进行惨绝人寰的种族大屠杀，摧毁了欧洲多数犹太族群，犹太复国主义运动因此高涨，于1948年达到顶峰。当年5月14日，现代以色列正式建国，魏茨曼为首任总统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一切比劳伦斯预见的还早了20年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;徒劳的最后一搏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年7月，劳伦斯开始策划耽搁许久的阿拉伯起义军北上叙利亚作战。随着事态发展，他越发清楚一个道理：只有在阿拉伯人自己解放的地区，他们的独立才能得到保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在劳伦斯万般促成之下，安曼和约旦河以西聚集起一支由阿拉伯部族武装、阿拉伯北方军士兵、英法顾问和专门的炮兵、装甲车单位组成的混合部队，人数为几Thousands of people.一同到场的，还有重要的起义领袖：费萨尔、奥达，以及沙拉昂在内的主要部落酋长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大战前夕，传来一个令人心碎的噩耗——劳伦斯在卡尔基米什时期的伙伴、爱人达霍姆，那个有着灿烂笑容的叙利亚少年死于一场肆虐于叙利亚北部的伤寒疫情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《智慧七柱》的扉页上，他写下一首献给达霍姆的情诗：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我爱你，故我将这千军万马掬于手中/在繁星灿烂的天空里写下我的心愿，去为你赢来自由…/当我长驱直入，你的眼睛将因此熠熠生辉…/你的微笑令其（死神）妒从悲起，抛下我，将你掳走，囚入他死寂的幽冥。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对劳伦斯而言，对达霍姆的爱，是他为阿拉伯人赢得自由和独立的最初动力。当梦想即将实现，爱人已逝，一种巨大的痛苦和虚空感把他压倒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争还在继续。 1918年9月，劳伦斯从英军司令部得到命令：让阿拉伯人彻底切断德拉以南的铁路线，但不可以北上冲向大马士革，以配合英军在约旦河西岸的北上行动。他们也转达对费萨尔的暗示：如果阿拉伯人在这个关键时候保持忠诚，将会得到很好的补偿，甚至将会允许他在大马士革建立一个政府。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得到政府的口头保证后，劳伦斯在德拉一带领导、发动了对汉志铁路最凶猛的袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月27日，在德拉附近那个给劳伦斯留下过严重创伤的名叫塔法斯的村镇，他和阿拉伯部队看到了一支撤退下来的同盟国军团留下的暴行：到处是残缺不全的尸体，姑娘和妇女们则裸露着带血污的身体，显然是被奸杀；在一堵矮墙上，倒着一具被刺刀穿透的裸身孕妇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯随后下令：不接受任何俘虏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;屠杀进行了一整夜，延续到第二天，共有四千多名被俘的同盟国士兵死于杀戮，是为“一战”中著名的“塔法斯屠杀”。次日清晨，劳伦斯进入德拉镇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位英军将领率部稍晚赶到这里，他目睹的是肮脏、野蛮和残忍，阿拉伯战士如何折磨、打劫医护列车上痛苦呻吟着的土耳其病员，“任何一个普通的文明人都无法忍受这样的惨景”。当他向劳伦斯控诉时，劳伦斯平静温和地告诉他：这就是阿拉伯人的“战争观念”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过德拉之战，奥斯曼军队已经全线崩溃。艾伦比将军给费萨尔发来热情洋溢的贺信说：“我向殿下表达我的祝愿，以及我对于您部队伟大成就的诚挚祝贺……多亏了我们的共同努力，现在土军正全线溃退。”他随后下令：把首先攻入大马士革的荣誉留给费萨尔的军队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年10月3日，在大马士革维多利亚饭店，英军总司令艾伦比和费萨尔会面了。劳伦斯充当翻译。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦比将军宣布：阿拉伯人作为参战国的地位，得到协约国承认；在叙利亚独立问题上，费萨尔没有选择，法国将成为保护叙利亚的“宗主国”；费萨尔作为侯赛因国王的代表，“将拥有叙利亚的管辖权”，但是“在法国的指导和财政支持下”，且他的管辖权“仅限于叙利亚内地”，不包括巴勒斯坦和黎巴嫩；法国将给费萨尔配一名联络官，他将与劳伦斯一同工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯和费萨尔惊呆了。费萨尔一开始激烈反对，但在艾伦比的施压下，最终只得屈从。在疲惫和失望中，劳伦斯转而向将军告假。将军最终同意了。次日，他离开了大马士革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;谈判桌上的溃败&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年12月，巴黎和会召开之前，英国首相劳合·乔治与法国总理乔治·克里孟梭用了五分钟就中东愿景达成一致意见：英国人控制美索不达米亚和巴勒斯坦；法国人则有权处置叙利亚。除了《赛克斯-皮科协定》的基本结构被确定外，他们还大大超越了它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴黎和会上，身着阿拉伯长袍的劳伦斯担任费萨尔的顾问，为阿拉伯独立事业继续奔走，以翻译身份参与演讲和谈判，组织新闻发布会以及引导报纸舆论。这给同在会场的著名历史学家阿诺德·J·汤因比留下难以磨灭的印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，恼怒万分的克里孟梭去英国代表团那里告了劳伦斯一状，并把这个年轻人叫来当面训斥。有“猛虎”绰号的法国总理劈头盖脸地问：“劳伦斯上校，你知道自从十字军东征以来，法国在叙利亚就有利益吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯回答：“是的。我知道。但是叙利亚人打败了十字军，我们永远不会忘了这一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克里孟梭被驳得哑口无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个饱受折磨的灵魂。我觉得劳伦斯在巴黎时已经意识到，尽管他在阿拉伯事业上取得了很多成功，但仍没有赢得胜利。”汤因比写道. “这让劳伦斯很苦恼，但痛苦并没有消磨掉他的幽默感，他有点伟大，还有点调皮。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英法的勾兑，摧毁了劳伦斯发下誓言为之奋斗的理想——阿拉伯人的民族独立。而对大英帝国的大人物们，“英雄劳伦斯”已经成为一个麻烦。在一份备忘录上，他们称其为“有害影响”，“很大程度上是我们与法国在叙利亚问题上麻烦的根源”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯最终被剥夺了参加巴黎和会的资格，同时被禁止在会议上协助费萨尔。他输掉了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，他仍做出一个堪称了不起的努力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年12月巴黎和会前夕，在他促成下，作为阿拉伯世界代表的费萨尔和犹太复国主义运动领袖魏茨曼拟定一份联合声明，宣布双方的合作意愿.其中第四条为：“应采取一切必要措施，鼓励和促进犹太人向巴勒斯坦大规模移民”，然后是一个关键性条件句——该协定“仅在叙利亚区独立的情形下有效；如果不满足这个条件，就完全无效。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，费萨尔还友好地谈到阿拉伯人和犹太人之间的“种族亲缘关系和古老纽带”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴勒斯坦地区，水火不容的阿拉伯人和犹太复国主义者也曾携手起来想建立一个阿拉伯-犹太人的联合国家。然而，劳伦斯的努力真有现实可能性吗？ ——如果他在1918年成功了，一个独立的泛阿拉伯国家会因此诞生吗？如果历史如费萨尔和魏茨曼之间协议的那样发生了，阿以/巴以会彼此和谐地相处吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为和劳伦斯相隔一个世纪的后人，我很难乐观——纵观中东现代史，每回出现和解的曙光，都会有极端势力发起针对性的暗杀、破坏行动。在遇害者名单上，有侯赛因次子、约旦首任国王阿卜杜拉，埃及总统萨达特，推动“以土地换和平”的以色列总理拉宾……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现代中东的诞生——划定疆域、拥立国王之人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1919年秋的巴黎和会上，失去劳伦斯帮助后，费萨尔不得不接受法国人给出的条件。等回到大马士革，他发现自己被谴责为向欧洲帝国主义出卖祖国的叛徒。他转而利用民众的愤怒，于1920年撕毁了与法国人的协议，发动一场宫廷政变，自立为大叙利亚国王。同年4月，叙利亚被托管给法国。 7月，法国在麦塞隆战役中获胜，费萨尔流亡英国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，历史走向了另一条轨迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;控制了叙利亚地区的法国也没有好日子过——阿卜杜拉从外约旦对他们发动持续、凶狠的进攻。让英国人头痛的则更多：在巴勒斯坦地区，巴勒斯坦人和犹太定居者之间的冲突不断升级；在美索不达米亚，反英起义揭竿而起，到处都是流血和对抗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年，前海军大臣温斯顿·丘吉尔复出，后在劳合·乔治内阁转任殖民大臣。他向被打入冷宫的劳伦斯发出邀约，请他担任中东事务部负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;心灰意冷的劳伦斯推说自己忙于写回忆录，对政治再无过问的兴趣。丘吉尔于是再三保证：在即将召开的开罗会议上，授予他几乎完全自由的权力，以帮助英国重新塑造中东棋盘上属于英国的那一部分。劳伦斯答应了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他对一位传记作者透露：1921年3月的开罗会议只是走了一个过场，他和丘吉尔在会前“不仅确定了会议将审议哪些问题，还确定了将会达成何种决议”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据决议，英国将它所控制的两块前奥斯曼帝国领土交给哈希姆家族。双方同意：费萨尔王子成为美索不达米亚新国家国王，即伊拉克王国；他的兄长阿卜杜拉王子则统治约旦河以东、由部分巴勒斯坦组成的新国家，即今天的约旦王国. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这基于劳伦斯一直为之奋斗的两个想法：首先，阿拉伯人必须获得对自己土地的控制权。其次，被赋予这种权力的阿拉伯人，是起义领袖哈希姆家族成员：侯赛因国王和他的儿子们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯的努力，为中东地区带来一段时间和平，也部分兑现了他对阿拉伯人在大起义时的承诺。一般认为：在1921年的开罗会议上，劳伦斯的作用大过了丘吉尔——最终，他真的成为了在中东地区划定疆域、拥立君王的那个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在安纳托利亚地区，前奥斯曼将领穆斯塔法·凯末尔带领土耳其民族主义者，把所有企图瓜分者打得落花流水。 1923年，他和协约国签订条约，确定了现代土耳其的疆域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南方，汉志国王侯赛因拒绝接受中东的现实政治，即使劳伦斯也无力说服。他的顽固和反复无常，最终让英国政府感到厌烦。老对头伊本·沙特利用了这一矛盾，于1924年带领瓦哈比战士逼近麦加。在众叛亲离之下，侯赛因避难塞浦路斯，后到新约旦首都安曼和次子阿卜杜拉团聚。 1931年6月，侯赛因去世，安葬于耶路撒冷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赢家伊本·沙特吞并汉志后，建立沙特阿拉伯王国。 1927年，英国人宣布承认其独立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过短暂的和平后，新的动荡又开始了。 1946年，法国人最终被迫放弃大叙利亚地区，但又从中分割出一个新国家——黎巴嫩。 1958年，伊拉克民族主义者发动军事政变，推翻了亲英政权，费萨尔独子费萨尔二世被处决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年代，西方殖民主义时代落下了帷幕。因为拥有占全世界六成的石油资源，中东如同被咒诅一般，继续成为地缘政治中最不安宁的角落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“当死神追上了我”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1921年，当劳伦斯在为丘吉尔奔走效力时，他给一位朋友写信说：“阿拉伯人就像是我翻过的一页，续集是我很讨厌的东西”。一战后，他一直患有严重的创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）,不断受到噩梦惊扰，多次陷于严重的抑郁，甚至萌生过自杀的念头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年起，劳伦斯根据笔记和回忆，重写自传，完成战争回忆录《智慧七柱》。他用手摇印刷机印了8本，分赠好友。后应公众的强烈要求，他做出妥协，在1926年出版了该书的删节版，同时又发行了大众版《沙漠中的起义》，后者取得了市场成功。劳伦斯把版税全部捐给慈善组织，并拒绝有生之年再版《智慧七柱》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他再也无法回归到一个学者的往日生活。 1922年，结束了在英政府殖民部的任职后，他化名约翰·休姆·罗斯，以普通列兵的身份加入英国皇家空军，但很快就被新闻界所发现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他又改名为托马斯·爱德华·肖，继续在军队服役，逃避对他穷追不舍的报界和公众。在生命的最后十多年，他过着离群索居的生活，用各种借口推掉朋友们的邀请，即使是最亲近的朋友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成为伊拉克国王的费萨尔跟劳伦斯后来又见过两次，一次是1925年，面对曾经并肩作战的生死之交，劳伦斯无所适从，二人一度相顾无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1933年费萨尔访英时再次提出要见劳伦斯，劳伦斯态度消极，后来费萨尔不得不借助军方的命令，才得以见到“列兵肖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1935年5月13日，劳伦斯骑着摩托车，去博文顿军营发一份电报。回程途中，遭遇一起交通事故。在部队医院昏迷六天后，于5月19日清晨去世，时年46岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“二战”阴云逼近，正陷于“困惑岁月”的丘吉尔前来悼念，写下一段政治家才有真正共鸣的悼词：“在我眼中，他是我们时代最伟大的人物之一……我担心，不管我们多么需要，像他这样的人都永远不会再有了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考书目及资料：《智慧七柱》T·E·劳伦斯著；《阿拉伯的劳伦斯：战争、谎言、帝国愚行和现代中东的形成》斯科特·安德森著；《交游录》阿诺德·J·汤因比著；Clio数字化历史博物馆网站。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[无尽的纷争：雷颐的2023年读书小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261708]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Making reading and writing a career, of course I will not finish reading in 2023 Few books. If we could sum up this year&#39;s reading and thinking with one title, the most appropriate one would be the title of one of the books: &quot;Endless Conflict.&quot; Real-life conflicts and wars have triggered &quot;reading circles&quot; from the international to the domestic, or Talk about the huge disputes in the intellectual and ideological circles. I hope this kind of dispute will bring about more profound discussions and thoughts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Zhu Zheng: &quot;Shi Ling New Collection&quot;, Huacheng Publishing House, June 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Mr. Zhu Zheng is a great editor, literary and historical figure who &quot;emerged&quot; after the reform and opening up. He was mainly an editor at first, and later a writer. Editing and writing, writing and editing, complement each other, making him a master of literature and history. His essays often have the sharpness of essays, but also contain many historical facts that essays lack. &quot;Shiling New Collection&quot; released by Huacheng Publishing House collects his main essays from 1987 to 2021. It is only a little over 200,000 words, but each chapter is based on solid historical materials. These dozens of essays form part of contemporary cultural history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Richard Pipes: &quot;Russia under the Old Regime&quot;, Democratic Construction Press, May 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Russia is a big country across Europe and Asia. The &quot;Soviet Union&quot; with Russia as the main body was once one of the two superpowers in the world and had an impact on the world. Tremendous influence. Such a huge country was formed not long ago. It is not a European country, but it is not an Asian country either. Its unique culture and vast territory have formed its own governance model, political and economic systems. &quot;Russia Under the Old Regime&quot; combs through the evolution of Russia from the 9th century to the 1880s, providing a clear description and in-depth analysis of the complex history. Only by understanding its past can we have a deeper understanding of its present and future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Lin Huihuang: &quot;Portrait of Huacun: Peasant Life in Transformation China&quot;, Oriental Publishing House, August 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Beautiful Countryside&quot; is a major rural construction project promoted by the country and an important step in targeted poverty alleviation. &quot;Flower Village&quot; was originally an ordinary village, but after it was selected as a demonstration site for beautiful rural construction, the social ecology underwent major changes and a large amount of project funds were instantly received. &quot;Portrait of Hanacun: Peasant Life in Transformation China&quot; takes real rural areas as examples and discusses some common problems encountered in the development of Chinese rural areas in case studies. By telling the stories of different farmers, the author explores different themes, including farming, working, mechanical farming, crop planting adventures, farmhouse entertainment, agricultural industrialization, rural governance, rural revitalization, etc. The core question is that most of these project funds are used for major issues that county and township governments are interested in, rather than major issues that farmers are really interested in. Why is this? What is the mechanism that creates this situation? The author&#39;s questions are thought-provoking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Walter Isaacson: &quot;The Biography of Kissinger&quot;, CITIC Publishing House, September 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2018, CITIC Publishing House published &quot;Kissinger: The Idealist&quot; by American historian Ferguson, which provided an in-depth analysis of Kissinger&#39;s early thoughts. Research, I have written book reviews, and I have gained some understanding of Chi&#39;s early thoughts, which I didn&#39;t know much about before. This year, CITIC Press released &quot;Kissinger&#39;s Biography&quot; by the famous American biographer Isaacson. What interests me is still Kissinger&#39;s early experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Kissinger is a Jewish refugee who fled Germany to the United States with his family in 1938 when he was 11 years old. Previously, he was discriminated against and persecuted in the German city of Fürth, which he found incomprehensible at a young age. The city of Fürth is not big. Except for the Jewish children, almost all the people in the city are members of the &quot;Hitler Youth&quot;. He and his brother were standing on the street and saw them wearing uniforms, singing in lines and marching in neat steps. They didn&#39;t understand why they couldn&#39;t right to participate. On the contrary, he and his brother were ridiculed and ridiculed everywhere, and soon they were no longer allowed to go to the swimming pool, dance, or teahouse... More and more places had &quot;Jews prohibited&quot; signs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After immigrating to the United States, his parents worked for others and their income was not high. After one year of high school, Kissinger had to switch to &quot;night school&quot;. Work during the day and study at night. His job was to work in a shaving brush factory run by a relative, wearing thick rubber gloves and squeezing the solution and water out of the brushes. The weekly salary was 11 US dollars, and he was later upgraded to a delivery person, responsible for delivering goods, and the weekly salary increased to 30 US dollars. Colleagues recalled that he was often absent-minded at work, reading or doing night school homework whenever he had the chance. His early experiences were quite &quot;inspirational&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The painful childhood experience had an unforgettable impact on him. “For Kissinger, the Holocaust destroyed the link between God’s will and historical progress—a core belief of Judaism and its most important contribution to Western philosophy. For believing Jews, history The meaning of should be understood from its connection with God’s will and heavenly principles. But after witnessing the evil deeds of the Nazis, Kissinger abandoned his Jewish faith. While studying at Harvard, the young student began to focus on academic aspects Explore other ways of finding historical meaning.&quot; His inner academic &quot;module&quot; was always European rather than American. He was fond of Kant, Hegel, Metternich, and Dostoevsky, but never I have expressed my appreciation for the archetypal figures who represent American creativity, such as Mark Twain, Jefferson, and Franklin. His childhood experience formed his basic idea: the pursuit of order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1588&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;260431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[US] Perry Miller: &quot;Endless Conflict: American Intellectual Life from the Revolution to the Civil War&quot; , Oriental Publishing House, July 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In recent years, Oriental Publishing House has planned and published the &quot;American Civilization Classics Translation Series&quot;. Qian Mansu, the editor-in-chief of the series and a researcher at the Institute of Foreign Languages, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, is a graduate of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences after the reform and opening up. The first batch of students studying in the United States studied the history of American civilization at Harvard University. This series of books is well-selected, and &quot;Endless Conflict: American Intellectual Life from the Revolution to the Civil War&quot; is one of them. Published in 1965, this book won the 1966 Pulitzer Prize for History. It is Miller&#39;s next grand work on the history of American thought after &quot;American Spiritual Life: The Seventeenth Century&quot; and &quot;American Spiritual Life: From Colonies to Provinces&quot; . This book was published nearly a year ago and has become a classic after the test of time. In this book, Miller attempts to grasp the religious roots of American culture and explain why the spirit of religion and the spirit of freedom, which are often opposed to each other elsewhere, are almost integrated in the United States. The contradiction and conflict between religion and secularity is a global problem. In the era of globalization, can the history of more than a hundred years ago be enlightening? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 09:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[六名中国公民被绑架杀害？海外华人华侨要团结以自保]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 11, 2023, the Philippine police discovered multiple tools in succession near a construction site in Laihu Bay. The remains are suspected by the police to be the six Chinese citizens who were kidnapped on October 30: including Mr. Zeng and his wife who are presidents of local Chinese charity organizations in the Philippines, brother Zeng and his wife, and brother Zeng’s teenage son. son, and one person remains unidentified. On November 28, the Philippine police confirmed the identities of four corpses, including Mr. Zeng’s two brothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, vicious cases involving overseas Chinese have occurred in some overseas countries: In May 2023, a Chinese couple died naked in a Bali hotel; in 2023, a Chinese student was murdered in Thailand on &quot;3·31&quot;... …In addition to these brutal cases, the criminal system of the warlords in northern Myanmar is basically tailor-made for the Chinese people. The number of Chinese people they have killed and the seriousness of their crimes are really too numerous to describe. Recently, the &quot;Ming Family&quot; in northern Myanmar, which specializes in telecommunications fraud, has reached the end of its rope and is about to be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the country&#39;s economic development, foreign economic, trade and cultural exchanges have increased, and Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Opportunities are always accompanied by challenges, and contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure one&#39;s personal and property safety, as well as legal rights, has become increasingly important. Examples of self-security and collective security for overseas Chinese can be found in the Korean community living in North America and the Jewish community scattered around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea has a small population, and even fewer people live in the world. However, a small number of Korean immigrants (mainly immigrants from South Korea) became a bright spot in the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; in 1992: After the U.S. police temporarily gave up protecting communities of color, a small number of Korean immigrants united and armed themselves for self-defense , took up arms to defend the community, resisting the onslaught of thugs, and held on until the National Guard entered the city to quell the violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For decades, Koreans have deeply felt the importance of external unity. Their overseas immigrants have strengthened internal unity, taking advantage of North American citizens&#39; gun-carrying laws to arm themselves for self-defense and strengthen their martial spirit. Therefore, even though the 1.65 million Korean immigrants only account for 0.5% of the U.S. population, North American residents know that Koreans are not easy to mess with and they dare to use guns in critical moments. Therefore, the thugs of the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; were unable to capture the strongholds held by Korean armed forces, so they looted Chinese stores because the Chinese generally lacked the ability to defend themselves at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before World War II, the Jewish community was known for being disunited, disorganized, shrewd and philanthropic, and gentle and cowardly. It is said that there are 12 branches of Judaism since ancient times. There are so many factions and small groups below. The Jews who run banks are greedy for money and are unwilling to help others. Therefore, few people are willing to help them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to better integrate into European society, the Jews not only accepted many Western living habits, but also tried to avoid confrontation when they had conflicts with the indigenous peoples. Therefore, various European ethnic groups have long scorned the military value of the Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During World War II, the Holocaust in Nazi Germany nearly annihilated European Jewry, which changed the spirit, character, and psychology of some Jews. After the war, some Jews reached several consensuses:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, they must build their own country and make it strong, rather than just being nomads in the world. When conflicts involving the Jewish community occur again, it cannot only rely on money, but also on the state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it is still necessary to maintain the simultaneous existence of Jews in various parts of the world to spread the risks of survival in case one country is defeated and the entire race is annihilated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, money alone is not enough. To survive, you must have the ability to defend yourself. The two words &quot;wealth and strength&quot; are indispensable. If we are not rich, we cannot afford advanced weapons and equipment and cannot build a strong army, so we cannot be strong; if we are not strong, we cannot maintain wealth for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, Jews have self-defense groups in many communities around the world. Especially in North America, we make full use of local laws and policies to conduct paramilitary training and have a considerable number of foreign reserve soldiers. On October 7, 2023, just hours after the war in Gaza broke out, a large number of Jewish young people from North America and Australia flew to Israel to join the war, with a total number of tens of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through arduous efforts, the Jews have changed to a certain extent the customs of their ethnic group, which were previously fragmented, fighting among themselves, and trying to undermine each other (but there is still a clear distinction between their modern factions and the &quot;ultra-Orthodox&quot;). It not only engages in &quot;hiding troops among the people&quot; around the world, but also forms an underground intelligence network connecting the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, Israel is a miniature country with a population of only a few million, and its intelligence agency &quot;Mossad&quot; does not have sufficient funds (like the CIA). Especially in the early stages of construction and development, it can be said that there is little money to be had, and even poverty can lead to poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1960, the Nazi war criminal Eichmann was captured; in the 1970s, the &quot;Black September&quot; terrorist organization was hunted around the world. &quot;Mossad&quot; can only send out a small range of troops, and the budget is tight. Each person only has a few dollars per day for food, and cannot afford to live in a hotel or buy a car. They move around the world and live in old houses provided by local Jews. Some of them don&#39;t even have beds and can only make beds on the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With that little activity fund, not only can’t I afford a restaurant, I can’t even afford takeout. I had no choice but to give the money to the local Jewish contacts, who would buy ingredients from the mall on their behalf and cook the food themselves. It is simply impossible for a &quot;Mossad&quot; agent to drive an Aston Martin sports car as elegantly as in spy movies. The vehicles used in many operations were all old cars borrowed from local Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the grass-roots teams in the early days when Koreans and Jews established their own power networks in the world, the number of Chinese people and wealth they have around the world is really much stronger. But it is a pity that Chinese expatriates with huge wealth cannot even effectively protect their personal safety and property safety. Malicious anti-Chinese and crimes against Chinese expatriates occur frequently around the world. As for the large number of violent crimes against Chinese people mentioned above, many Chinese gangsters were involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is really regrettable and heartbreaking. The reason is that there is still internal strife among overseas Chinese and there is serious internal friction in their strength. Some Chinese friends in North America vividly told me how they tried to undermine each other in business, criticized each other culturally, and even colluded with &quot;Ghost Cap&quot; (foreign police) to punish each other. The speaker was very excited, beaming, and dancing. When he was excited, his saliva sprayed into my face. This is really heartbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure their personal and property safety, as well as their legal rights, has become increasingly difficult. The more important it is. The basis of all this is first of all the unity of the ethnic group. In this regard, we should really think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[甘肃酒泉市肃北县发生5.0级地震]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:17:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China Seismological Network officially determined: December 01, 22:55 in Subei County, Jiuquan City, Gansu Province ( A magnitude 5.0 earthquake occurred at 39.30 degrees north latitude and 97.27 degrees east longitude, with a focal depth of 9 kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height= &quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1701443803135-0&quot; data-mce-width =&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔚来“朋友圈”再扩容，车企为何统一换电？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261667]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 battery swap stations around the world .Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 power swap stations around the world. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following Changan Automobile (000625.SZ), NIO (09866.HK, NYSE:NIO) has made another success with its battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Geely Holding) and NIO officially signed a strategic cooperation agreement on battery swapping in Hangzhou. The two parties will work on battery swapping standards and battery swapping technology. , carry out comprehensive cooperation in various fields such as battery swap service network construction and operation, battery swap model R&amp;D and customization, battery asset management and operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the agreement, in the future, the two parties will create two major battery swap standard systems for &quot;private cars&quot; and &quot;commercial vehicles&quot; through the &quot;co-investment, co-construction, sharing, and co-operation&quot; model to promote vehicle-end , station end, battery end, and operation end are connected and coordinated to expand the scale of the battery swap network to meet users with different needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, NIO founder Li Bin revealed in an internal speech to all employees that in addition to Changan Automobile, there are 4-5 potential partners currently being negotiated. In other words, more car companies may join NIO&#39;s &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei, the expert committee of the China Automobile Dealers Association, told Southern Weekend reporters that the expansion of the &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping has a strategic significance higher than the practical level, and it will have a limited effect on improving their respective revenue in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the initial cooperation between the parties is exploratory and may start with operating vehicles such as online ride-hailing. &quot;If the results are good, it may be upgraded to more important models or high-value models.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are only two roads in front of you&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news &quot;NIO lost 76.4 billion in five and a half years&quot; appeared on Weibo&#39;s hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2018 to 2022, NIO’s net profits attributable to the parent company were -23.328 billion yuan, -11.413 billion yuan, -5.611 billion yuan, -10.572 billion yuan and -14.559 billion yuan respectively. In the first half of 2023, NIO&#39;s net profit attributable to its parent company continued to suffer a loss of 10.926 billion yuan, with a cumulative loss of 76.4 billion yuan in 5.5 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although at the recent Guangzhou Automobile Industry Development Conference, NIO co-founder and president Qin Lihong emphasized that &quot;NIO will never go bankrupt, and it is impossible for it to go bankrupt.&quot; But it is undeniable that Weilai has invested too much in “peripheral products” and its sales have declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Li Bin’s internal speech to all employees was also on the hot search. He said that the road to battery replacement is very difficult, but it is difficult and the right thing to do. &quot;Everyone thinks of battery replacement as Amazon doing cloud services in 2003, as well as Alibaba, Tencent, Microsoft, etc. They have suffered losses for many years. Only then did we finally achieve success.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NIO and NIO’s battery swap are always accompanied by controversy. The construction of a service system with power exchange as the core is regarded as the main reason for NIO&#39;s losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, NIO will deploy a total of 2,300 power swap stations in 2023. As of November 28, NIO has built 2,184 power stations around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the cost of each generation of NIO&#39;s three generations of power swap stations is slightly different, if based on a rough calculation of the 3 million yuan cost of each power swap station stated by Qin Lihong at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show, NIO&#39;s power swap performance will be The cumulative investment has exceeded 6.5 billion yuan. This does not include additional expenses such as venue rental, personnel operations and electricity expenses. Based on NIO’s goal of adding 1,000 battery swap stations in 2023, the cost of building the stations alone will be as high as 3 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Fei, NIO’s vice president in charge of NIO Power, revealed at a press conference in March that the battery swap station had to serve 50-60 orders per day to achieve breakeven. At that time, NIO’s battery swap station averaged 35 orders per day. -36 orders. The implication is that Weilai is still in the loss-making stage when it comes to battery replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei believes that NIO positions itself as a luxury brand and provides services such as battery replacement and user rights to make up for the lack of product and brand power. It has indeed played a very good role in brand building in the early stage. However, as investment increased, its sales volume did not increase significantly, but instead became a huge burden. &quot;Keeping it has limited use, just throw it away. It&#39;s a pity.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only two ways in front of Weilai, either to sell more cars and dilute the power exchange network construction from within. or introduce more car companies to participate in NIO’s power swap network to create a scale effect and alleviate financial difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Weilai has already had clues about opening up the battery swap business. At the China Electric Vehicles 100 People Forum held in April 2023, Li Bin said that &quot;the battery swap service has reached the stage where it can be exported to the outside world.&quot; He hoped that other companies can share and build charging and swap infrastructure with NIO, and revealed that there are already Car companies are discussing this matter with NIO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu, honorary chairman of the Society of Automotive Engineers of China, told Southern Weekend reporters that as the current battery swap model has not yet found a profit model, there are only more battery swap stations and a more convenient energy replenishment experience. Only then can more users be willing to buy battery-exchange models, thus forming a positive cycle. NIO&#39;s cooperation with Geely, Changan and other automobile manufacturers will help promote the battery swap model on a larger scale, improve the overall operating efficiency of the battery swap model, and may solve the commercialization problem of battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Or start from online car-hailing services&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The battery swap model laid out by NIO does have many advantages. For example, it only takes less than 5 minutes for car owners to replace the battery at the battery swap station. However, the disadvantage is that the battery swap model still faces problems such as high website construction costs, uncertain commercialization models, and inconsistent industry standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, there are several companies on the market that are trying to lay out the power swap model, but the construction of power swap stations is independent of each other. Since 2020, relevant national departments have continued to promote the formulation of standards for battery swap stations and battery packs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 World Power Battery Conference, Xin Guobin, Vice Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, revealed an important signal. Currently, a battery replacement technology standard system is being studied and compiled to promote battery replacement battery size, battery replacement interface, Standards such as communication protocols are unified. At the same time, relevant departments have also entered into the inspection process for the national battery replacement station standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu believes that each car company has different models and batteries. In the context of cooperation, battery swapping may require a transition period to improve the versatility of the battery swapping network. &quot;However, it can force companies to make better efforts in standardization, which is of key significance to the structural adjustment of the battery swap model.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some people question that unified battery swap operation management may affect Wei Come to the battery swapping experience of existing users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike NIO’s battery swap model, most car companies are betting on high-voltage fast charging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 800V high-voltage fast charging platform is currently regarded as the most likely technology path. In 2019, Porsche launched the Taycan, the world&#39;s first 800V high-voltage platform model. Automobile manufacturers such as BYD, Xpeng, Great Wall, Geely Jikrypton, etc. have all begun relevant layouts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the long term, 800V will be an opportunity to reshape the battery industry,” Li Bin said at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show. “But no company has yet been able to reduce the cost of 800V to close to that of the current 400V. or a slightly higher level.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei also believes that high-voltage charging costs are high and is currently mainly used in relatively high-end models. It is unlikely that the technology will be transferred to low-end models in the short term. In addition, the layout of high-voltage charging piles is still imperfect, and an absolute advantage over the battery swap model has not yet been established in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Liu Jinliang, CEO of Yiyi Internet Technology Co., Ltd., signed the power exchange cooperation with NIO on behalf of Geely Yifang this time. He has led Geely&#39;s travel business in recent years, and has been responsible for Caocao Private Car, Yao Travel and other sectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei said that online car-hailing may be the first area of ​​cooperation between the two parties. Due to cost control, operating vehicles such as taxis and online ride-hailing vehicles mostly use lithium iron phosphate batteries. The batteries are used frequently, so the demand for battery replacement will be higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海底捞“科目三”爆火，有创意还是“辣眼睛”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chatting is not as good as dancing. Making oneself feel comfortable is everyone&#39;s talent...&quot; In Haidilao, watch Dancing seems to be more important than chatting and eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Haidilao has made a splash again with the launch of the &quot;&lt;strong>;Subject 3&lt;/strong>;&quot; dance service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;Subject Three&quot; is not the &quot;Subject Three&quot; of the driver&#39;s license assessment, but a dance that mainly consists of waving hands, twisting hips and half-crotch feet. The music above, the magical dance steps, and the exciting scenes have made the business of many Haidilao stores become booming. Some customers enjoy it: &quot;The fatigue of the day is healed here&quot; &quot;Haidilao can cure social fear&quot; &quot; The boys are so handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &lt;strong>;&quot;Dance&quot; must be reversed&lt;/strong>;, and Haidilao&#39;s &quot;Subject Three&quot; has also caused a lot of controversy. Some customers complained that &quot;the dancing is tacky and noisy&quot; and &quot;it feels uncomfortable to bring children here to eat.&quot; Accompanying the controversy are the feelings of Haidilao employees themselves: “There is no reward commission”, “It’s hard to refuse customers’ requests”, “It’s really embarrassing inside”, “It’s meaningless”, and even a young man from a store in Changxing County, Zhejiang&lt; strong>;I was admitted to the hospital with a bone bruise due to skipping &quot;Subject Three&quot;&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating with atmosphere, singing and dancing to entertain is not Haidilao’s exclusive program. For example, Chongqing Hot Pot Factory is called “Sheniu Hot Pot Restaurant” by customers. Behind the &quot;local flavor social shake&quot;, &quot;fancy decoration&quot; and &quot;grandstanding&quot; is the fierce competition in the catering industry. While trying to acquire customers at a low cost, they also want to speed up breaking out of the circle. However, no matter what, service comes first, and the core of a restaurant should be Still taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Under the sea &quot;Subject Three&quot; became a hit, what do you think? Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数据安全榜：谁在尽心倾力守护您的金融隐私？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:07:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In today’s digital age, financial privacy security is greatly testing everyone’s A financial institution also affects everyone&#39;s most sensitive nerves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But accidental events often produce extraordinary panic and associations. In November 2023, some financial institutions experienced successive risk incidents at home and abroad, and even encountered hackers, and their core data was leaked or hijacked. The incident triggered deep thinking in the financial and technological circles: How can we do our best to protect users’ financial privacy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, regulators attach great importance to the security of national financial data and personal financial information, and have successively introduced a series of regulatory specifications aimed at establishing a system that covers all financial data. Life cycle safety management system mechanism. Among them, the protection of personal financial information has become an important part of the security management of financial data life cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively evaluate the data security strength of the banking and life insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a survey on 20 systemically important commercial banks and 9 mainstream life insurance companies. Conduct systematic evaluation. Consistent with the construction logic of the indicator evaluation system of the wealth management list, green finance list, and digital finance list, the quantitative and qualitative indicators of the data security list account for 70% of the weight, and external expert review and media factors each account for 15% of the weight. In view of the differences in relevant information disclosure rules and actual disclosure situations between banks and insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed quantitative and qualitative indicator systems for data security in the banking and life insurance industries based on the key disclosure points of each bank and insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the strict data security standards of each bank and insurance institution under evaluation, and the rare data security accidents so far, this list focuses on the above-mentioned bancassurance institutions’ The strategic importance of data security, the transparency of information disclosure and the effectiveness of data security work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bank ranking indicator system: the most important performance in four dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banking industry data security ranking The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the evaluation indicator system are divided into four dimensions: organizational construction, institutional processes, technical tools and effectiveness, and include five secondary indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1151&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the banking industry data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Organizational construction&lt;/strong>; refers to the organizational structure of commercial banks in terms of data security. The research team of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center considered the number of relevant responsible departments disclosed by commercial banks. The weight of this indicator accounts for 10%, reflecting the importance commercial banks attach to data security and information protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;System process&lt;/strong>; refers to the degree of standardization of the process of building a data security system for commercial banks. Standardized institutional processes are an important cornerstone and guarantee for commercial banks to build data security systems. Under this dimension, we mainly examine the number of relevant systems and normative documents on data security of commercial banks, divided into two secondary indicators: the number of its own relevant systems and the number of normative documents related to supplier management, with a total weight of 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among them, supplier management refers to when a commercial bank collects, transmits, stores, filters, analyzes, exchanges, and shares all data belonging to the bank. , a management mechanism for effective risk identification, assessment and effective control of relevant external partners. At present, most commercial banks do not pay enough attention to data security when conducting annual reviews of various suppliers. For suppliers who have access to sensitive bank data, once the supplier has security vulnerabilities or misbehaves, it is likely that the information security and data security of commercial banks will be threatened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to encourage commercial banks to pay more attention to the management of suppliers in terms of data security, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has disclosed the relevant supplier management systems disclosed by commercial banks. The number of documents is included in the indicator system, accounting for 10% of the weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Technical tools&lt;/strong>; are a core part of the network security system. This indicator directly reflects the commercial bank&#39;s ability to protect data and privacy and the effectiveness and reliability of data security protection. In view of the fact that the research and evaluation of relevant technical tools in the data industry has been very systematic, we use the number of certification systems disclosed by each commercial bank to determine the bank&#39;s technical strength in data security. The weight of this indicator is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Performance indicators&lt;/strong>; account for 30% of the weight, which is the largest single indicator dimension and the only qualitative indicator to fully reflect the Results-oriented data security ranking evaluation logic. This indicator has a significant impact on the data security evaluation results of commercial banks. For commercial banks that have information security incidents, customer personal information leaks, major IT system failures and other incidents in 2023, we will warn the relevant commercial banks by reducing their scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It needs to be emphasized that in order to encourage commercial banks to increase the transparency of information disclosure in the field of data security and reduce information asymmetry, we have not disclosed relevant information for some banks. In the case of indicator data, the relevant indicator will be given the lowest score. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Data Security&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Big banks dominate the top three&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank data security list shows that Agricultural Bank of China ranks first, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. . The comprehensive scores of the three major banks all exceed 70 points, showing significant advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China has obtained 51 various certifications related to data security, far more than any other bank. The bank was the first among major state-owned banks to issue the &quot;Data Security Management Measures (Trial)&quot; and established a comprehensive data security management system based on this. At the same time, the bank adheres to the &quot;minimum necessary&quot; principle, conducts mining and applications within the scope and authority of reasonable use of data, and encrypts sensitive customer information to maximize data security and privacy and avoid leakage and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking of Banks (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2273&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among joint-stock banks, Ping An Bank and China Merchants Bank ranked fourth and fifth respectively on the list, performing relatively well. Ping An Bank insists on using safe and available tools and technologies for data integration, including using security umbrella technology to automatically desensitize data and automatically protect sensitive groups, and ensure the independence and security of analysis scenarios through data safe houses. The bank&#39;s credit cards use a self-developed privacy computing platform to accurately identify external and debit card customers, effectively reducing customer acquisition costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance ranking indicator system:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Three dimensions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;7&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Sub-indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance is a typical data-intensive industry, with a large amount of personal information, market information and transaction information. Regulators attach great importance to data security in the life insurance industry. Since 2023, regulatory agencies have issued regulatory documents such as the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Consumer Rights Protection in Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Network and Data Security Management in Third-Party Cooperation&quot;, requiring life insurance institutions to establish a consumer personal information protection mechanism. And carry out self-examination and rectification of data risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How is the performance of life insurance institutions? Based on public information such as financial reports, ESG or CSR reports, official announcements, and public reports disclosed by the nine life insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a quantitative analysis of the nine life insurance companies from the three dimensions of data security, internal governance, and external review. and qualitative evaluation, and set up 7 sub-indicators, each with a weight of 10%, and the total weight of quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center integrated expert review scores and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) to build a life insurance data security ranking indicator system . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of data security ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1379&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Life Insurance Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the data security dimension, the emphasis on data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by the number of times &quot;data security&quot; or &quot;data privacy&quot; is mentioned in ESG reports, and the effectiveness of data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by whether major information security incidents occurred in the past year. . The judgment of this indicator is based on the description of major information security events in the annual report or ESG report. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the internal governance dimension, life insurance institutions are qualitatively evaluated based on three indicators: whether to set up an independent data security department, whether to formulate a data security protection system, and whether to conduct an annual information security review. Implementation of internal data security work. The total weight of the above three indicators accounts for 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The external review dimension qualitatively evaluates the acceptance of life insurance institutions in the professional field of data security based on two indicators: whether the App has violated user privacy issues and whether it has obtained ISO/IEC27001 certification. Level of recognition. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Insurance ranking: China Life wins the championship, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;AIA Taikang ranks among the top three&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance data security list shows that China Life leads AIA Life to take the first place with an advantage of 1.59 points, and AIA Life ranks second. The comprehensive scores of both life insurance companies exceeded 80 points, 8 points ahead of the third place Taikang Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1186&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Looking at the scores of quantitative and qualitative indicators, China Life, China Pacific Insurance, AIA Life and Taikang Life all scored over 60. This shows that they perform better overall in multiple dimensions such as data security, internal governance and external review. In the end, China Life won the championship due to its high scores in both external judges&#39; scores and media factor scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life proposed a comprehensive &quot;Technology China Life&quot; strategy as early as 2012, and has continued to increase investment in data security for 11 years. As one of the first batch of pilot financial institutions, China Life took the lead in the industry to migrate and put into production the Xinchuang database of key business systems, achieve 100% distributed architecture transformation of key business systems, and successfully build a new self-controlled distributed cloud architecture digital base. The company also proposed and built the first data center in the domestic life insurance industry and a high-standard underground computer room that obtained T4 certification. In addition, the company has also successfully developed a safe, green and elastic China Life Hybrid Cloud using internal private cloud and external public cloud resources, which integrates computing, storage and containers to significantly improve data security and computing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also found that although the life insurance institutions at the bottom have not yet experienced major information security incidents, they have shortcomings in internal governance and external review obvious. For example, 4 institutions under evaluation did not set up independent data security departments, 2 institutions did not conduct annual information security audits, and the apps of 3 institutions were accused of infringing on user privacy, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that life insurance institutions at the bottom of the list urgently need to pay more attention to the construction and improvement of data security systems, and at the same time adopt more stringent and transparent policies. In the face of public concerns, the public&#39;s information disclosure standards should be strengthened through practical and effective measures to enhance public trust in the data security of life insurance institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的多重面孔：一轮夜空悬，千片秋江月]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261635]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In history, there are few Chinese poets like Li Bai. It attracted much attention during the era in which he lived. Topics, legends, and stories about him were widely circulated when he was alive, and they did not decrease with his death, but became more abundant and mysterious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A scholar did not take the imperial examination, but was recruited to the Jinluan Palace; a commoner did not have the merits of building a large scale, but was favored by the emperor; a person who intended to clarify the troubled times, He was killed by Changliu Yelang; a man who once scattered more than 300,000 yuan a year ended up with nothing in his later years; a poet fought with people in Chang&#39;an City; a Hanlin scholar who was waiting for an imperial edict, drank freely with his craftsmen; A man with lofty ideals who is &quot;willing to serve as the Prime Minister&quot; is keen on refining elixirs and collecting herbs; a madman who looks down on the powerful is excited when facing the common people&#39;s wild rice...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Faced with this prototype that combines many contradictions, people are puzzled and determined to &quot;understand&quot; him. People not only want to understand him, but also &quot;use&quot; him, either to support themselves, to self-explain, to self-comfort, to self-liberate, or to use the past to satirize the present, or to make use of topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does Taibai look like? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No photos or videos can answer the question of Li Bai&#39;s true face. For guessing about Li Bai&#39;s appearance, we can only rely on sporadic descriptions in historical materials and the poet&#39;s autobiography to seek clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The senior poet He Zhizhang exclaimed that Li Bai was &quot;relegated to a fairy&quot; when he first met him. Taoist master Sima Chengzhen commented on Li Bai that &quot;the Jun family has immortal Taoist bones, which can travel with the gods to the eight extremes&quot;. There are many documents written about Li Bai&#39;s contemporaries like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed in &quot;Books with Han Jingzhou&quot;: &quot;Although the body is less than seven feet, his ambition is ten thousand.&quot; The ancients said that tall people are like Zhuge Liang and others are all &quot;eight feet long&quot;, and the seven-foot-long man is only of average height. Even though Li Bai was majestic and magnificent, he was not tall and mighty. He should be a small man. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s fanboy Wei Hao described Li Bai in the preface to &quot;The Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; as having &quot;bright eyes, trembling like a hungry tiger, sometimes belted, The romance is brewing.&quot; His friend Cui Zongzhi&#39;s poem &quot;Gift to Li Twelve Bai&quot; also described Li Bai&#39;s &quot;eyes that illuminate people&quot;. It can be seen that Li Bai&#39;s eyes are indeed bright and special. Li Bai calls himself a &quot;savage&quot;, and the &quot;hungry tiger&quot; is seeing his state of breaking through the restraints, which is in sharp contrast with the &quot;or time belt&quot; below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Tang Dynasty, there have been many portraits of Li Bai left. Although Li Bai&#39;s true appearance has disappeared with history, some characteristics of Li Bai&#39;s image can be directly appreciated from the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the poems of Song Dynasty poets Rao Jie and Chen Shidao, we can know that the Tang Dynasty painter Zhou Fang once painted the image of Li Bai. In Zhou Fang&#39;s writings, Li Bai is a scholar wearing a black gauze hat and a white silk robe, which is highly consistent with the dress of most scholars in ancient times. Wusha was originally a skullcap commonly worn by the people, but it was not until the Ming Dynasty that it became an official hat. The white silk robe, made of white ramie, became the mainstream of fashion in the mid-Tang Dynasty, and people even became obsessed with this kind of clothing. Li Bai&#39;s own description is different from the image in the painting: &quot;Wrapped in grass and covered with black gauze scarf, upside down with purple fur.&quot; ​​He said that he often wore &quot;purple fur&quot;, which was different from the &quot;white fur&quot; described by Zhou Fang &quot;. However, among the many paintings depicting Li Bai&#39;s image in later generations, most painters chose the &quot;black gauze and white gauze&quot; clothing feature. It can be said that Zhou Fang&#39;s &quot;portrait&quot; of Li Bai became a &quot;sample&quot; for later painters to create Li Bai&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stele gallery of the Li Bai Memorial Hall in Jiangyou, Sichuan contains the &quot;Kuangshan Taibai Statue Stele&quot; and &quot;Li Bai Statue Stele&quot; painted by the famous Northern Song Dynasty painter Li Gonglin. The former depicts Li Bai when he was studying in the mountains, clothed in cloth, carrying a bamboo stick, and high-spirited. Many subsequent images of young Li Bai originated from this. In the latter&#39;s prime, Li Bai had a round face, plump ears, and an enlightened, joyful and peaceful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Chanting Picture&quot; is the most representative image painting of Li Bai in existence, and was written by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai. Liang Kai had a willful and informal personality of &quot;hanging over the wall with his gold belt and leaving his job&quot;. Coupled with his fondness for wine, it can be said that he and Li Bai cherished each other. In the painting, Li Bai is wearing loose clothes similar to Taoist robes, and his hair style depicted in burnt ink is slightly tilted back, as if he is reciting a poem in front of the moon. With a few strokes, he captures the subtle moment when Li Bai is reciting a poem, from his head to his head. The feet are almost in one go. The modern painter Zhang Daqian painted many paintings of Li Bai in his life, most of which were based on the shapes in Liang Kai&#39;s &quot;Li Bai Xingyin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2874&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260278&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&#39;s Songs&quot; by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai is now in the Tokyo National Museum. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng used &quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; to express the feelings of the literary people. In the painting, Li Bai is supported by two chamberlains. The servant&#39;s clothes are gray, his eyes are submissive, and his posture is like hiding and peeping. Li Bai wears a bachelor&#39;s scarf on his head, a white bachelor&#39;s coat, cinnabar-colored boots and a belt, with bright colors and a sense of nobility. His beard is flowing, his eyes are open, and he is half drunk and half awake. This portrait is reminiscent of Li Bai, who &quot;got drunk in the palace and made Gao Lishi take off his boots&quot;, revealing his arrogant freedom and boldness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; by Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng, now in the Shanghai Museum. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is said that in the Ming and Qing Dynasty warehouses of the Forbidden City in Beijing, the Nanxun Hall has a particularly impressive collection of calligraphy and paintings, including more than ten small portraits of Li Bai and Du Fu. It is unknown when these small portraits were painted, and the people in the paintings are far from the stereotypes. Du Fu is not the common thin image, but a dark and fat man. Although Li Bai has a fair complexion, he does not have much beard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Taibai Hall in the Li Bai Memorial Hall is home to a bronze statue created by Li Xiangqun, a professor at the Academy of Fine Arts of Tsinghua University. The poet&#39;s slender body stands upright in the hall, with his head raised to the sky, his raised chin and beard fluttering, his lips slightly parted as if he wants to speak. The most special thing is that his eyes are blurred. After the statue was exhibited, it was recognized by the cultural and art circles, and was accepted by young people. However, some people over the age of sixty expressed great confusion about the lack of eyes and the freehand treatment, and some even protested. It can be seen that the folks in Taibai&#39;s hometown have an irreplaceable affection for Li Bai. The image of Li Bai created by tradition has been deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, and it seems that he should be what people imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, author Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;relegated immortal&quot; with &quot;a proud waist&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am a madman in Chu, Feng Ge laughs Confucius.&quot; &quot;A life of arrogance and misery is not harmonious, and kindness and help are a good matchmaker.&quot; &quot;Arrogance&quot; is not only a self-constructed trait of Li Bai in his poems, generations of creators tell Li Bai&#39;s stories, and they are also happy to express it. this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed that &quot;An Neng can crush my eyebrows and bend my waist to serve the powerful, making me unhappy?&quot; He just said that his character was incompetent. Dai Wei&#39;s &quot;Shu Pu&quot; of the Song Dynasty said: &quot;People in the Tang Dynasty said that Li Bai could not bend his body because he had a proud waist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If there are changes in character, there are also bending and stretching changes. , but the physical &quot;arrogance&quot; cannot be changed, which pushed Li Bai&#39;s arrogance to absolute status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;People believe that Li Bai is anti-secular at heart and an anomaly of the times. From inducing the foot of Gao Lishi to take off his boots, to having the prime minister grind his ink, and the concubine holding an inkstone, from riding a donkey into the county government office to fishing for ao at sea, all kinds of extreme deeds are unparalleled in ancient and modern times, both at home and abroad, among which &quot;the strong man taking off his boots&quot; is the most representative. sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The notebook novels of the Tang and Five Dynasties, &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, &quot;Youyang Miscellanies&quot; and &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; all record this story. The difference is that only &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; records that Li Bai was slandered and retaliated by Gao Lishi because of this incident. In &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s behavior of asking Gao Lishi to take off his boots was severely denied by Xuanzong. In the former, Li Bai was directly kicked out by the emperor after he asked to take off his boots. The emperor asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots, which was criticized by the emperor as &quot;he is a poor man&quot;. The former statement has been almost forgotten except for the adoption in &quot;Old Book of Tang&quot;. In subsequent stories, Gao Lishi taking off his boots has become an established fact. Perhaps, the repressed people want to take this opportunity to make a fool of themselves and feel happy by spitting out the blockages in their chests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the notebook novels related to Li Bai in the Song Dynasty, there are also some fictional stories that are almost exaggerated but vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai in Zhao Lingchou&#39;s &quot;Hou Zhenlu&quot; is like a famous scholar in the Wei and Jin Dynasties:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Li Bai visited the prime minister in the Kaiyuan period and sealed a board with the title: &quot;Li Bai, a fisherman on the sea.&quot; The prime minister asked: &quot;Sir, when you go to the sea to catch a giant turtle, what do you use as a hook and line?&quot; Bai Said: &quot;The wind and waves let go of one&#39;s emotions, and the universe controls one&#39;s ambitions. Use the rainbow as a thread and the bright moon as a hook.&quot; He also said, &quot;What can be used as bait?&quot; Bai said, &quot;Take the unloyal husband in the world as bait.&quot; Prime Minister Chang Ran . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shu&#39;s &quot;Qing Suo Gao Yi&quot; writes that Li Bai rode a donkey into the county government office while drunk:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: regular script, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zai said: &quot;Who are you, how dare you be rude?&quot; Taibai said: &quot;Begging for a confession.&quot; When Zai ordered the confession, Taibai did not write his name, but said: &quot;I once got a dragon scarf to wipe my saliva. The emperor holds a spoon, a strongman cleans his boots, and a noble concubine holds an inkstone. I am allowed to walk on horseback in front of the emperor&#39;s gate, but I am not allowed to ride a donkey in Huayin County?&quot; Seeing this, the prime minister was shocked. He stood up and thanked him and said, &quot;I didn&#39;t know that Hanlin was here, so he failed to greet me. &quot;Wanting to stay, Taibai ignored him and rode off on the donkey again. &lt;p>; The warriors and the ministers took off their boots and knotted their socks.&quot; Holding the inkstone and grinding the ink were all performed by Yang Guozhong, which fulfilled the theory that Concubine Yang, as the &quot;king&quot;, could not hold the inkstone and grind the ink for the ministers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously, people&#39;s imagination of Li Bai does not stop at the image of a &quot;madman&quot;. What is more thorough than describing Li Bai&#39;s &quot;smiling man&quot; is &quot;relegating an immortal&quot; to Li Bai. &quot;With his identity firmly established, he came from heaven and returned to heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;About Li Bai&#39;s life and death, from the legend of &quot;Chang Geng entering a dream&quot; to &quot;catching the moon and riding a whale&quot;, it has a profound impact on later generations of creators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;, which blurs the boundaries between feature films and documentaries, is the last work of Dutch director Ivens. It tells the story of his pursuit of wind and Chinese culture. course. Evans walked out of Méliès&#39;s moon mouth and walked on the moon&#39;s surface. In addition to chatting with Chang&#39;e, he also saw Li Bai on the earth through a small hole. Li Bai was lying drunkenly on a small boat, chanting, &quot;If you don&#39;t see me, the bright mirror in the high hall will have sad white hair, and the morning will be like blue silk and it will turn into snow at dusk.&quot; Suddenly a huge moon shadow appeared on the water, and Li Bai wanted to wrap his hands around it, turn over and fall into the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai goes boating with wine on a moonlit night in Evans&#39; film &quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historical materials mostly record that Li Bai died of illness. Bai Juyi wrote a poem &quot;Li Bai&#39;s Tomb&quot;. Although it does not explicitly refer to catching the moon and drowning, &quot;Li Bai&#39;s tomb by the quarrying river&quot; &quot;This sentence is quite fascinating. By the late Tang and Song dynasties, poems and articles on Li Bai&#39;s death had been extensively discussed, such as Hong Mai&#39;s &quot;Essays of Rong Zhai&quot;: &quot;It is said in the world that Li Taibai was quarrying stones in Dangtu. He was drunk and boating in the river. He looked down and took some stones in the shadow of the moon, and drowned. Therefore, there is a catching platform on the ground.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stars and the moon depend on each other. Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; said that Li Bai was born because his mother dreamed that Chang Geng was pregnant, so he was named Bai, the word is too white. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the writing of Zhang Dachun, a contemporary Taiwanese writer, the origin of this name for Li Bai is his devout identity. &quot;Li Bai in his childhood has already Knowing that he is a star who has fallen into the mortal world, looking at his parents from this point of view is just a tool that God had to borrow to cultivate him in this mortal life; looking at his brothers from this point of view is only a matter of ten years. A companion who accompanies children in spring and autumn.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As a star, it emits fairy sounds. The guest&#39;s heart is not abiding, and the lingering sound is silent.&quot; Zhang Dachun With this sentence, Li Bai is identified as a person who is like a passer-by in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fake Taoism and true Confucianism? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Part of Li Bai&#39;s story immortalizes Li Bai, while another part of Li Bai&#39;s story increasingly highlights his mortal qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The inspirational legend of &quot;an iron pestle ground into a needle&quot; was recorded in &quot;Fangyu Shenglan&quot; by Zhu Mu of the Song Dynasty. This story shows that Li Bai&#39;s talent is not innate. It is not something that comes from a dream, but is accumulated through hard study. The genius in the eyes of the Tang people was so down-to-earth in the eyes of the Song people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tu Long of the Ming Dynasty wrote Li Bai&#39;s family life in the legendary &quot;Cai Hao Ji&quot;, describing his wife Xu Xiang&#39;e and son Bo Qin, showing Li Bai as a husband With his father, he released the aloof poet into the secular life. This was unheard of in operas of the Yuan Dynasty, and the theme did not appear again in operas of the Qing Dynasty. However, contemporary literary and artistic works often depict Li Bai&#39;s relationship with his hometown and relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is interesting is that the emphasis on Li Bai&#39;s entry into the world and the image of him as a man of lofty ideals who made great achievements are almost overwhelming in today&#39;s literary and artistic works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai stood at the entrance of the altar. When he stepped onto the altar, he broke with yesterday. Yesterday was the life of the human world. In the life of the human world, he Pursuing: &#39;I am willing to serve as an assistant to make the country peaceful and the people peaceful, and the country peaceful.&#39; He wants to be Guan Zhong, Lu Zhonglian, Zhuge Liang, Xie An, Jiang Ziya... &#39;Abandoning the world&#39; means abandoning all these.&quot; Jiangyou writer Wang Huiqinghua said She completed the novel &quot;Li Bai&quot; with more than 700,000 words in 2018. She attributed the reason why Li Bai entered Taoism to avoid being hunted by Li Linfu&#39;s minions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Taixuan, who presided over the ceremony, quoted a famous line from &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; to warn Li Bai: &quot;If you want to avoid punishment, it is better to abandon the world.&quot; But Li Bai knew that he most What is difficult to do is to give up the world. Li Bai in the novel once said to the grass-roots sage Zhang Xu when he was young: &quot;Confucius said, &#39;Heaven moves vigorously, and a gentleman should constantly strive for self-improvement.&#39; I don&#39;t believe there is no such thing.&quot; It is completely Confucian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The chapter &quot;Li Bai: The Gambler&quot; in Bei Mingyu&#39;s novel &quot;A Guest from Chang&#39;an&quot; is written more straightforwardly, &quot;Li Bai said a lot of things that flattered others in his life. The scenes and words are all based on the Taoist&#39;s realistic outlook on life of &#39;for my own use&#39; - in order to realize his ideal of becoming a high official, there is nothing he cannot do. But as he gets older, he becomes more and more attached to the silly pursuits of Confucianism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was young, he thought of himself as the roc in Zhuangzi&#39;s works. He once again mentioned it in his last work &quot;Song on the Road&quot;: The great roc flies to inspire the eight descendants, and the sky destroys the power. Not good. The remaining wind is stirring for eternity, and the fusang is hanging on the stone gauze. Later generations will pass this on, who will cry when Zhongni dies? Bei Mingyu lamented: &quot;Since he was young, he has firmly believed that this big bird that shakes eight generations and stirs the world is himself. He has a high and far direction, but he is in the middle. According to Zhuangzi&#39;s carefree , It’s good to fly, it’s good to fold, so just fold. However, Li Bai thought of Confucius in such a tragedy. ... Li Bai spent his life seeking immortality, and when he was about to die, he found that he was still with him in the end. Confucius stands together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&quot; premiered in 1991 and has been performed for more than 30 years. It can be called a classic of Beijing People&#39;s Art Theater. The play is based on Li Bai&#39;s more than sixty years of life, and chooses the five or six years in his later years to form the background of the whole play. It also expresses the secular side of Li Bai&#39;s hesitation between &quot;official&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;. Screenwriter Guo Qihong pointed out in Li Bai&#39;s character introduction: &quot;&#39;Piaoran Taibai&#39; seems to be the consensus of people all the time, but I think it is not always the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing People&#39;s Art In the drama &quot;Li Bai&quot;, Pu Cunxin plays Li Bai. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The play opens with the scene of Li Bai coming to the throne for King Yong. Li Bai carried &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; and &quot;Li Sao&quot; with him. Taoist friend Wu Yun teased him, thinking Using Zhuangzi&#39;s free and easy mind to complete Qu Yuan&#39;s tragic career is the opposite. Li Bai responded with a smile: &quot;If you walk south, you will reach the north; if you walk north, you will reach the south!&quot; After Yelang was released, Li Bai was about to enter Taoism with his wife, but the day before, he encountered Guo Ziyi&#39;s visit and faced the opportunity to serve in the army. , 60-year-old Li Bai decided to change his mind and joined Guo Ziyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai-related works launched in 2023, represented by the animated film &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot; and the musical &quot;Journey into the Wine&quot;, all chose not to write poetry. Xian Taibai dwells too much on the free and easy dance, but instead pushes a lonely and frustrated Li Bai in front of the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/730e64747a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/730e64747a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the musical &quot;Let&#39;s Enter the Wine&quot;, Zheng Yunlong plays Li Bai. Photo courtesy of the show&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Li Bai in &quot;Jinjinjiu&quot; came to Beijing, he did not see the emperor, but instead saw Gao Lishi and Yang Guifei, who complained sadly Di said to Li Bai, don&#39;t take it seriously, he and she are just playthings in this palace. The play ends with Li Bai leaving Chang&#39;an in despair and returning to his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In-depth attention to Li Bai&#39;s inner world and life pursuits originated from the drama &quot;Caishiji&quot; written by Jiang Shiquan of the Qing Dynasty. Previously, composers in various dynasties paid much attention to the description of Li Bai&#39;s character. Jiang Shiquan was very dissatisfied with this and was eager to rectify Li Bai&#39;s name. This dissatisfaction is also a kind of dissatisfaction he has with his own identity. The two people have very similar experiences. They both became famous, were praised by the rulers of the dynasty, entered the Imperial Academy, but were not reused, and neither wanted to live as just a scholar. Down the line, they all grow old as literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jiang Shiquan once expressed in an article that when future generations read his works, they will say that he is an excellent poet. This kind of short-sightedness is so short-sighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, how would Li Bai view himself? This biggest mystery may never have a clear answer. Only the revolving lantern of history continues to rotate, gradually illuminating different aspects of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Part of the content of this article is referenced from: &quot;Born to Be Talented: Biography of Li Bai&quot;, &quot;The Foundation and Trajectory of the Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s Image&quot;, &quot;The Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s Image in Paintings&quot;, &quot;Research on Li Bai Stories in Tang and Song Note Novels&quot;, &quot;Li Bai-themed Operas of the Yuan, Ming and Qing Dynasties&quot; Research&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>