<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[回故乡之路丨月是故乡明⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OHl0geXE8w.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OH l0geXE8w. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;203155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xiaochen 4x/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was born in Liling, Hunan. Since I left when I was very young, I have always regarded Pingxiang, Jiangxi, as my hometown. When I first heard that the capital of Anhui Province was called &quot;Hefei&quot;, I was as surprised as I was when I learned about the history of Pingxiang. Although this coal city in western Jiangxi is called &quot;Pingxiang&quot;, in fact, it has become a well-known industrial and mining city at home and abroad as early as the late Qing Dynasty with the rise of Anyuan Coal Mine; it is not only the birthplace of the Chinese workers&#39; movement, but also the autumn harvest. Why was the origin of the uprising named &quot;Pingxiang&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn’t it just Pingxiang? There are also many cities in China with interesting names. For example, the capital of Hebei Province is called &quot;Shijiazhuang&quot; and the famous porcelain capital of Jiangxi is called &quot;Jingdezhen&quot;. In the 1970s, a flood in the upper reaches of the Huaihe River washed out Henan Province. A prefecture-level city was named &quot;Zhumadian&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is either a town, a village, or a store. It is conceivable that most of these place names come from its history. But the combination of these two Chinese characters &quot;Hefei&quot; makes people feel strange. A cross talk once joked that it was &quot;two fat men sleeping&quot;. Later I learned that it got its name because it is located where the two Fei rivers in the north and south merge into Chaohu Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Anhui, or the first time to Hefei, was in May of 1993, when the flowers were blooming. At that time, I was still working in Pingxiang City. The two places were separated by more than a thousand kilometers. Because of the inconvenient transportation, Hefei felt like a distant existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent two full days on that trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set off early in the morning the day before. After taking the green train for most of the day, I first arrived in Nanchang and stayed at a small hotel near the long-distance bus station. The next day, I took a bus before dawn. Genius 1 bus bound for Hefei. Then, the car passed through countless villages and towns. The road was uneven and had potholes from time to time. After a day of bumps, the bones were falling apart. Lunch seemed to have been served at a roadside shop in Huangmei County, Hubei Province. It was probably the driver&#39;s personal designated restaurant. The food didn&#39;t look clean, and there was a strange taste in the mouth. This is nothing, the worst part is going to the &quot;bathroom&quot;. Although the car stopped twice during the journey, both times it stopped in the wilderness of Qianbuba Village and Hoububa Store; those two places were blocked. The sheds called &quot;public restrooms&quot; were only one person high and had no doors. The passengers were self-conscious at first and lined up at a distance, but the male compatriots who couldn&#39;t wait went to look for trees or grass that could provide shelter. To solve the problem, our female compatriots could only guard the toilet. The dirty floor in the toilet and the flying mosquitoes and flies made me retching uncontrollably. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order not to go to the toilet, I didn’t dare to drink a sip of water or take a sip of food along the way. By the time I arrived in Hefei, it was already dark and I was so hungry that my chest was touching my back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that terrible experience, I did not dare to return to my hometown. It was not until three years later that a railway was built between Hefei and Nanchang, and I began to return to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, this special line was not included in the national railway system and was only a local railway between Anhui and Jiangxi provinces. It starts from Hefei&#39;s West Railway Station, passes through Feixi, Lujiang, Shucheng, Tongcheng, Qianshan, Susong, and Wangjiang in Anhui Province, passes through Huangmei in Hubei Province, and then crosses the Yangtze River and enters Jiujiang and Yongxiu in Jiangxi Province. , and finally arrived in Nanchang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I do remember that the first time I boarded that southbound train was one morning at the end of 1996. At that time, our financial situation was still very difficult, and all we bought was a seat ticket. When my husband and I got into the car carrying large and small bags, we were surprised to find that there were very few passengers in the car. Although some people started to get on along the way, they were always sparse and there were so many empty spots that people could even lie down and sleep. Looking out the window at the rolling mountains, the sleeping fields under the winter sun, and the fleeting simple farmhouses, I felt mixed feelings. Fortunately, I no longer have to endure the pain of long-distance buses where I dare not even take a sip of water. Switching to a spacious and comfortable train, the time is shortened by nearly half. What is worrying is that there are too few passengers and the passenger flow is so small. Volume, let alone making money, whether the cost can be maintained is a question, and the economies of Anhui and Jiangxi provinces are still underdeveloped. If they are always losing money, can this train be saved? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This train arrived at the terminal, Nanchang, in the evening. Since there were no more trains to Pingxiang that day, we had to stay in Nanchang for one night. I remember we chose a hotel called &quot;Da Guangming&quot; on Zhanqian Road. &quot;Da Guangming&quot; is a small hotel. The rooms are poorly furnished and there is no separate bathroom. A very funny thing happened in &quot;Great Light&quot; that day, and even today, twenty-six years later, I still remember it fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While packing the luggage the next morning, my husband suddenly discovered that an envelope containing 3,000 yuan in cash was missing! The door was locked and the windows were bolted, so it was impossible for outsiders to come in and steal. But after searching every corner of the room, as well as the corridors and public toilets outside, nothing was found. My husband then went downstairs to find the waiter, and soon a hotel security guard came up. He said that only the two of us lived on the entire floor that day, and even if it fell on the corridor, it would not be picked up by anyone. What he meant was that the envelope could only be left in the room. So, in front of him, I took off the quilt cover, lifted the sheets, took out the items in the box one by one, and rummaged through them again, but there was still nothing. At this time, my husband made a request to him, &quot;Maybe I accidentally dropped it into the toilet when I was convenient and it was washed away. Can you take me to the sewer to have a look?&quot; The man did not refuse. He agreed, &quot;It is possible. Not long ago, a traveler dropped a watch and found it in the sewer. There were not many people staying in the hotel last night, and the water from the sewer should still be accumulated downstairs. I will take you Go down and look for it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a glimmer of hope, we followed him downstairs. He took out an iron rod with a hook from a corner, led us around to the small courtyard behind the hotel, and opened two The iron plate, underneath is the sewer. He bent over and rolled up his sleeves, completely ignoring the stench coming from the sewer. He held the iron rod and carefully raked it back and forth little by little. After raking it out three or four times, he still found nothing. He smiled at us apologetically: &quot;Nothing either!&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;If I really can’t find it, I can only admit that I am unlucky. We left &quot;Da Guangming&quot; sadly, took the train back to Pingxiang, and stayed at Dadi&#39;s house at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That year, my eldest brother was allocated a new apartment. This money was originally a gift to him, but unexpectedly something unexpected happened, so he had to owe it first. Unexpectedly, when my husband went to bed at night, he took off the black woolen jacket and something fell from his sleeve, and it was not the envelope containing the money! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for how the envelope slipped into the sleeves, there is no way to verify it; he didn’t even notice it when he was getting dressed, and he didn’t even notice when he put it all the way around, which shows that he doesn’t care about such trivial matters in life. He is a careless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While I was blaming his Madaha for giving me a false alarm, I was also full of guilt for the Da Guangming Hotel. Think about it, in the middle of winter, I had to dig out the gutter early in the morning, and I still looked unhappy when I left. I always thought that the money was lost in the hotel, and I even suspected that the waiter had picked it up! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the Daguangming Hotel and the tall security guard have been deeply engraved in my mind. Even after our economic conditions improved, I still chose to stay in &quot;Da Guangming&quot; every time I was in transit from Nanchang. Once, my son had a high fever in the middle of the night, but I did not panic and gave him medicine calmly because I believed that this hotel would definitely lend a helping hand if needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years later, this Anhui-Jiangxi line was integrated into the national railway network. The trains from Hefei to Nanchang were also extended from Nanchang to Guangzhou, and a pair of trains to Dongguan were also added. There are many trains to choose from, but both trains depart from Hefei at noon or evening, and arrive in Nanchang either in the evening or in the middle of the night; and the train from Nanchang to Hefei departs in the early morning, either in the middle of the night or in the early morning. When traveling between Hefei and my hometown, I still have to stay one night in Nanchang. I have been riding this kind of train for more than ten years, so I have stayed at the Daguangming Hotel no less than forty times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I don’t have a good impression of Nanchang Railway Station. Every time I leave the station, there will be a number of people holding signs to solicit guests to stay in the hotel, and they will keep pestering you; in front of the station When dining in a small restaurant, if you don&#39;t agree on the price in advance, sometimes you will be charged an exorbitant price, and you will have to consider yourself unlucky if you get ripped off, because those people are very rude and seem to be ready to use their fists at any time. Fortunately, this hotel prevented us from being too disappointed in this city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 2010, my journey back home changed again: Hefei opened two direct trains to the southwest, one to Kunming and one to Nanning; Both trains pass through my hometown. The former departs in the morning and arrives in the evening, while the latter departs in the morning and arrives in the evening. The time it takes to reach Pingxiang does not exceed twelve hours. From then on, my journey back to my hometown suddenly became very smooth. I no longer needed to change trains midway. I only had to buy a sleeper ticket, get on the train from Hefei after dinner, and sleep all the way to Pingxiang in time for breakfast the next day; or I was still in Hefei in the morning, and before the sun went down, I came to the streets of Pingxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the convenient transportation, the number of times I return to my hometown has naturally increased. It used to be once or twice a year, but now it has become several times. Something happened at home. I got a call the day before and I arrived early the next morning. It used to be difficult to meet my classmates and friends from my hometown, but now it is easy to meet once or twice a year. Whenever there is a school anniversary or class celebration event, as long as I can spare the time, I will rush back to join in the fun. , although I have been away from home for more than 20 years, my former classmates and friends have miraculously recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Spring Festival, my husband and I went back to our hometown to visit my mother. When we purchased tickets online, we unexpectedly discovered that the train from Hefei to Kunming suddenly disappeared; the train to Nanning was also absent. Pingxiang stopped. But at the same time, I was even more surprised to find that there is a high-speed rail connection between Hefei and Nanchang! Moreover, the high-speed rail departs six times a day, and the whole journey takes just over two hours! Then, I also discovered that the passenger train that used to operate between Anhui and Jiangxi had also returned, but it had also changed from the earlier green train to a motor train, and the time was greatly shortened to two hours and forty minutes! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 12 noon on the fifth day of the Lunar New Year, my husband and I boarded the train. Looking at the wilderness and farmhouses passing by outside the window, my mood suddenly returned to the unstoppable excitement I felt when I first took the train back to my hometown twenty-six years ago. In my impression, the speed of the green train at that time was only 60 kilometers per hour, and in order to prevent thermal expansion and contraction, there were gaps at the joints of each section of the rail. When the wheels passed by, a clear and audible &quot;thumping thump&quot; would be emitted from underneath the train. The sound of &quot;thump, thump, thump&quot; is especially loud when people are quiet at night; and now the speed of high-speed trains has reached more than 200 kilometers per hour. People sitting on the train can no longer hear the sound of wheels hitting the rails. It is so smooth that even the water in the cup can&#39;t be heard. It didn&#39;t move at all. As you can imagine, the rails today are obviously seamless. There are only twenty-six years before and after. Twenty-six years is not a long time, but it is enough to give birth to a generation. It is only a blink of an eye. In the past twenty-six years, China&#39;s railway transportation has indeed undergone earth-shaking changes. . In terms of speed alone, there used to be only local trains or express trains, but at the beginning of the 20th century, there were express trains and direct trains. By the 2008 Olympic Games, the first intercity high-speed rail line appeared between Beijing and Tianjin. The municipalities have implemented high-speed rail and public transportation, and it only takes half an hour to travel to and from each other. In terms of color, in the past, local trains were always green, while in the transition to express trains, there were red and blue. Later, high-speed trains and high-speed trains were all white. Now, high-speed trains have spread all over the country, and only Anhui Province has done so. Arrive at Shishitong High Speed ​​Rail. So, I discovered that the colors of the cars have been adjusted again: except for the high-speed trains, all ordinary passenger cars have returned to the previous green color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Green is the color of spring, which makes you feel refreshed and full of vitality. Of course, the bigger change is that today&#39;s rail transit has switched from burning coal to using electricity. This is a change of the times. It has not only become faster, but also cleaner and more environmentally friendly! So, I am guessing what kind of new energy will be used to drive high-speed rail and high-speed trains in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I searched on the Internet with great interest and found out that the high-speed railway between Nanchang and Hefei was officially opened to traffic this year, that is, in January 2022. I was earlier. One of the passengers who enjoys this benefit. There were not many passengers on the train that day. Just like the first time I took the local railway, most of the seats were empty. But I no longer have the worries I had back then, because the reason why there are so few passengers this time is not due to passenger volume, but due to the COVID-19 epidemic. Everyone is responding to the government’s call and trying not to travel if possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-speed rail not only greatly shortens the time compared to ordinary trains, but the convenience of transfer is also a major advantage. I have transferred at Tianjin West Railway Station in a municipality directly under the Central Government, and at Bengbu South Railway Station in a prefecture-level city. Both times I could transfer without leaving the station. This time, the train entered Nanchang West Station. We got off the train and followed the &quot;Convenient Transfer&quot; signs to get on the elevator of the station&#39;s overpass. We crossed the overpass and entered the waiting room directly. Because there are as many as 26 high-speed trains running from Nanchang West to Pingxiang North every day, we only stayed at the station for a short time and completed the transfer easily. An hour later, we ended our journey back to our hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about it, all this is incredible: from Hefei, between the Jianghuai River and the Huaihe River, to Pingxiang, the coal capital of western Jiangxi, the trip used to take two days and one night, but now it only takes four hours. Such speed was something I couldn&#39;t even dream of before. Many people have watched &quot;Water Margin&quot; and know that Dai Zong, the magical Taibo in it, can travel a thousand miles in a day and eight hundred miles at night. Everyone thinks that is just a myth. But with China&#39;s high-speed rail now, why does it take one day to travel a thousand miles? Two or three hours is enough! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the journey back to my hometown can be said to be a kind of enjoyment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次历届最火的迷笛音乐节，和乐迷遭遇的65起盗窃案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:50:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The classic scene widely circulated at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival: lifting a wheelchair man. The picture comes from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic image that has been widely circulated at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival: lifting a wheelchair man. The picture comes from the official Weibo of the Midi Music Festival&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After witnessing the two classic scenes of &quot;Mud Fight&quot; and &quot;Lifting a Wheelchair Brother&quot;, Liu Rui could have brought this exclusive experience of the Midi Music Festival with him Looking back, I ended my annual music pilgrimage with joy, but I didn&#39;t expect that an unexpected theft incident at the last moment destroyed almost all the &quot;beautiful things in this world&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This senior music fan, like many of his friends, has had a habit of going to music festivals during the National Day holiday for many years, but none of his previous experiences were as exciting as this one in Nanyang, Henan. Unforgettable: &quot;I have heard of things being thrown away at music festivals before, but it was not as serious as this time. This time it is too exaggerated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, &quot;Central Plains Midi&quot; in Nanyang, Henan &quot;Music Festival&quot; has been on the hot search topic list many times. Among them, according to reports from many music fans on social platforms, a large-scale property theft occurred in the Midi camping area on October 3. Videos and pictures provided by music fans showed that local villagers broke into the Midi camp and brazenly &quot;ransacked&quot; tents. , many computers, mobile phones, musical instruments and other valuables were confiscated. &quot;It&#39;s outrageous that my home has been moved away after I went to the bathroom. It was already an open robbery.&quot; A music fan told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the Nanyang Municipal Public Security Bureau. A police officer surnamed Lu responded: &quot;We are still registering the lost items of music fans. The specific situation needs to be contacted by the Municipal Public Security Bureau.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, the official Weibo of the Midi Music Festival announced that the local police received a total of 73 reports and implemented 65 theft cases. After investigation by the public security organs, some thieves have been captured and detained, and some property has been recovered. On the same day, the WeChat public account &quot;Nanyang Radio and Television Station&quot; issued a notice saying that based on the current registration situation of music fans, 79 ID cards and 3 computers have been returned , 17 mobile phones, and the remaining items are being verified and contacted. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Because of the rain, few people live in the camping area&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is the first time Nanyang has hosted the Midi Music Festival, which will be held for four days from September 29th to October 2nd. In order to hold this music festival, the local government opened a large open space in Huangshan Village on the outskirts of the country, planted a large lawn, and named it &quot;Green Field Monologue.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It rained for three days during the four-day music festival.” Liu Rui said that outdoor music festivals like Midi usually provide open spaces for music fans to bring tents for camping. At noon on September 29, the camping area was officially opened to music fans. However, during the past few days of the music festival, except for the sunny weather on September 30, it continued to rain for the other three days. After setting up their tents, many music fans only use them to rest during the day and choose to stay in hotels in the city and take a shower at night. For the sake of convenience, many people do not carry their luggage with them, but put it directly in the tent as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that the camping site is divided into three areas: A, B, and C. Among them, Area C where he is stationed is located inside. The theft was not serious. He only lost his power bank, The relatively low-value items such as power strips did not call the police. However, thefts in areas A and B near the exit, especially near the fence, are very serious. &quot;It seems that Shenzhen music fans put their things on the wall and suffered heavy losses.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to him, he had not heard of any &quot;lost things&quot; in the days before the festival. On the last morning, he returned to After setting up camp, many people found their belongings missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have a (music fan) organization, and we all camp together.” Wu Siqi is from Shenzhen, and this is her fourth MIDI tour. She recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that because of the rain, she only stayed in the tent for one night on the second night, and stayed in the hotel the rest of the time. She put her luggage in the tent and zipped it up. On the evening of October 2, I was in a very excited mood after watching the performance and found nothing unusual. When I returned to the camping area from the hotel on October 3, I found that the zipper of the tent had been opened, many belongings were missing, and some items were scattered beside the tent. It was obvious that There are signs of being picked up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After verification, she lost a mobile phone, several bank cards, some cash, and some souvenirs. &quot;They should have come in by climbing over the wall.&quot; Wu Siqi said that music fans can get a bracelet on site after purchasing tickets. There are staff on duty at the entrance, and they can enter and exit freely with the bracelet. &quot;There are people watching the entrance, and the security on the wall inside is poor.&quot; She said that the wall at the music festival venue is about two meters high and is not guarded by security guards, making it easier to climb over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wu Siqi communicated with friends from Shenzhen, they all suffered varying degrees of loss. She saw videos and pictures taken by music fans. Some people climbed over the wall and jumped into the camping area, while others were rummaging through tents in the camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Music fan Liu Ling lost her laptop, headphones, power bank, and goods used to set up a stall. When she went to the police station to call the police, she met a stall owner who claimed that more than 80,000 yuan worth of goods was missing. In order to find her lost items, she joined three music fan support groups. Each group has four to five hundred people, all of whom said they had lost their belongings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Liu Ling’s first time to participate in a large outdoor music festival. She had not graduated from college yet, so she took the green train from Guangzhou to Nanyang for more than ten hours. &quot;My family doesn&#39;t know about this yet. I&#39;m still in school now, and it costs a lot,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Another classic scene &quot;Mud Fight&quot;. Picture from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/06/8202470098.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ 8202470098.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Another classic scene &quot;Mud Fight&quot;. The picture comes from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Multiple suspects have been arrested&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;After the incident, some netizens posted on social media that during the music festival, someone was broadcasting , once released the information that no one wanted the tents after the music festival, which played a misleading role. In response, the Organizing Committee of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival stated in an announcement on October 5 that on the morning of October 4, netizen Chen illegally posted false information that &quot;the event has ended and the scene must be cleaned up,&quot; causing nearby villagers to Taking advantage of the chaos, there were many cases of property being stolen in camping areas. The announcement also revealed that Chen, who published misleading and false information, has been arrested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t know what his mentality is, why would he send such a message?” Liu Rui said that on the second and third days of the music festival, he discovered that someone was “picking up” the moisture-proof mat. Within the acceptable range, &quot;I just want to pick up some small advantages.&quot; The turning point came on the penultimate night of the show, when items from the tent began to be stolen on a massive scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that he had participated in many music festivals before and had property stolen from time to time. He had even heard of gangs of thieves committing collective crimes, but nothing like this at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival. exaggerate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stealing is stealing. We do believe that a lot of things have been stolen from the entire camp.&quot; Wu Siqi said that she saw some netizens on the Internet excusing the villagers, thinking that what happened in Nanyang Midi The disgraceful incident was not considered theft, but the villagers &quot;took&quot; some items abandoned after the event. She believed that this argument completely ignored the facts, &quot;They are just denying the facts, and this is not acceptable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Siqi said that her trip to Nanyang Midi originally left her with very good memories, but the final encounter ruined these experiences. She said that due to the continuous rain, some music fans&#39; plans to camp outdoors were scrapped. The organizers provided free accommodation for some music fans who could not find a hotel temporarily. They caught a cold after being exposed to the rain. They could also receive free brown sugar at the music festival. Ginger tea. Details including transportation connections and other details are also in place, and the favorability level was once full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also had some contact with local residents. When she went to the city for a stroll during the music festival, the citizens she met were very enthusiastic, because it was difficult to take a taxi, and she also encountered well-meaning passengers and drivers who &quot;crash&quot; &quot;Give them a ride.&quot; &quot;I felt very warm and moved. As a result, when I returned to the camp on the last day, I found that my house had been robbed and stabbed.&quot; Wu Siqi said that the experience of these few days was magical, &quot;It immediately took me back from Utopia. It exposed the reality and made me see the dangers of society.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Kun is a music fan born in the 1970s. Due to the weather, he has been staying in the hotel, but he still witnessed the final &quot;fantasy&quot; scene. &quot;It feels like the mentality of fellow villagers who steal pumpkins, or overturn the fruit cart on the highway, and grab the fruit.&quot; He said that at first, it was just the mentality of taking advantage of it, &quot;picking up&quot; some worthless things, but later people saw that the advantage had been taken away. People picked them up and simply coveted the items in the tent. In the end, the situation intensified and turned into &quot;looting&quot; with open fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, a Southern Weekend reporter called the Midi Music Festival Organizing Committee. A person in charge said that the police have been called and detailed registration work has been done for fans who have lost their belongings. The public security organs have A special work team has also been set up for this collective theft case, and many suspects have been arrested so far. &quot;We compared the recovered items with our registration information at the scene, and have now returned some of the fans&#39; items. We also later learned that one of the netizens, Chen, spread false information on the Internet after the night of the 2nd. The message indicates that the event is over, and no one wants many things. Let everyone pick them up. At present, Chen has been arrested by the public security organs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Encountering a &quot;Black Swan&quot; in investment promotion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Midi The music festival is an original music festival founded by Beijing Midi Music School. It is a music festival IP with a long history in China and has a deep foundation of music fans. In recent years, Midi Music Festival has frequently moved out of first-tier cities and been held in third- and fourth-tier cities in the mainland, which also has box office appeal. However, the arrival of the Midi Music Festival in Nanyang is an initiative of the Nanyang local government to attract investment and attract traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to local media reports, in May 2023, leaders of the Wolong District Committee of Nanyang City led a team to Beijing Midi Music School to discuss cooperation. The leaders of the Wolong District Committee said that Wolong District has sufficient development space and activity scenes. , hoping that both parties will promote cooperation, jointly ignite urban vitality, release industrial potential, highlight cultural charm, and inject more young forces into Wolong District&#39;s &quot;urban growth&quot;. The person in charge of Midi Music School said that Wolong District has a beautiful natural environment and broad prospects for the development of the cultural tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 2, the person in charge of Beijing Midi Music School said in an interview with Nanyang Daily that this music festival was very successful and set a box office record for the 47th Midi Music Festival in 30 years. , the number of live audiences also broke the previous record. There were more than 20,000 viewers on the eve of the music festival, and the number of viewers was close to 40,000 every day for the other three days. All tickets for the music festival were sold out in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, Southern Weekend reporters called the Wolong District Culture and Tourism Bureau of Nanyang City. The staff on duty at the bureau did not provide any more information about the music festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that because there are more restrictions in big cities, the trend of large-scale outdoor music festivals developing in third- and fourth-tier cities is very obvious. Local governments choose to cooperate because of the considerations of attracting investment and developing tourism; From the perspective of music fans, it is also a good choice to travel to different cities and experience the customs of different regions while attending music festivals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the music festival ended on October 3, but the National Day holiday has not yet ended. Previously, the usual practice was that many music fans would choose to continue visiting the city where the music festival was held for a few days, and then return Make return arrangements. &quot;So many people come here to eat, drink and play, which can boost the economy.&quot; Liu Rui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liu Rui’s view, before the theft incident, the entire event was actually very successful and basically met the organizer’s expectations. He said that because the lawn of the music festival had just been laid not long ago, after continuous rain, the entire venue was muddy, and it turned into a large-scale &quot;mud war&quot;, which became a scene that went viral on major social platforms and short video platforms; in addition, A young man in a wheelchair from Hebei was lifted up by many music fans to pay tribute at the music festival, and it became a classic scene that moved many netizens. These many factors have caused the 2023 Nanyang Midi Music Festival to frequently fail to appear, attracting attention from the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It turned out that everything went smoothly, but I didn&#39;t expect that something like this happened.&quot; Liu Rui felt sorry for Midi and Nanyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Liu Rui, Wu Siqi and Liu Ling are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特诺奇蒂特兰沦亡五百年祭丨古国多少事⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Flying from Atlanta to Mexico City, the scenery changes three times: first, from the flat and fertile southern plains of the United States to the sea and sky. over the Gulf of Mexico, and then crosses the Gulf of Mexico at a 45-degree angle, then enters the warm and tropical northern coast of Mexico, and finally reaches the rugged central Mexican plateau, which is the starting point of the northern end of the long volcanic belt that forms the Central American isthmus. The Pacific Ocean and the Atlantic Ocean connect the two continents of North and South America. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be clearly seen from the plane window that the moist air from the Gulf of Mexico is blocked at the northern foot of the Central Plateau, forming a continuous cloud belt, and finally turns into rainfall and moistens the northern coast again. The central plateau, with an average altitude of nearly 2,000 meters, is cloudless and the sun is scorching; there is little vegetation on the ground and it is very dry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The flight arrived over the Valley of Mexico, where the capital Mexico City is located, with an altitude of 2,240 meters, ranking eighth among the highest capitals in the world. Historically, this place was called Tenochtitlan. The precious precipitation from the central plateau gathered here and once formed continuous mountain lakes. It prospered as a result, and it perished five hundred years ago as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;City of the Gods&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Although Mexico is the largest country in Central America, it has the Gobi Desert that stretches to North America in the west and the warm and comfortable Baja California Peninsula, and Yucatan in the east The peninsula has lowland jungles and savannahs, as well as alluvial plains and swamps on the north and south coasts. The topography is very rich, but its country name comes from the almost isolated Valley of Mexico (Valle de México) on the central plateau. This is because when the Spanish came to this area in the early sixteenth century, the most powerful city-state Tenochtitlan was located in this valley. Later it became the capital of the colonists: Mexico City, and &quot;Mexico&quot; became the entire The name of the colony - &quot;x&quot; in Spanish is pronounced as &quot;h&quot;, and the Chinese transliteration of &quot;Mexico&quot; comes from this. If it is pronounced in English, it becomes &quot;Mexico&quot;, which does not match the local place name. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Valley of Mexico is actually a basin. The basin with an altitude of 2,200 meters is surrounded by volcanoes with an altitude of 5,000 meters, which is insurmountable. Therefore, there are no outflow rivers here, and all the rainfall meltwater completely flows to the bottom of the valley, forming a rare large mountain lake in history - Lake Texcoco. Its water area reaches 5,400 square kilometers, and it is the largest freshwater lake in my country, Poyang Lake. about 1.7 times. Due to strong evaporation, the water depth of Lake Texcoco changes greatly throughout the year, forming a wetland around the lake that is repeatedly submerged and then exposed. This is very similar to the Tonle Sap Lake (&lt;span style) reported by this edition in October this year. =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Cambodia: The Trisolaran World of Tonle Sap Lake&quot;&lt;/span>;). This wetland around the lake is a rare livable place in the vast plateau. Primitive agriculture was developed here, making it one of the important birthplaces of ancient Mesoamerican civilizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mexico Valley Location Map&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to archaeologists Excavations have shown that humans lived here 12,000 years ago, and the city was formed around 1200 BC. The specific location was on the west bank of Lake Texcoco, on the western outskirts of today&#39;s Mexico City - China at that time was still in the late Shang Dynasty. The Wuding and Zhongxing periods. The city was later destroyed by a volcanic eruption on the west side of the lake. The people migrated to the east coast of the lake and settled in a mountain depression called Teotihuacan by later generations, creating an ancient city with a thousand-year civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ruins of Teotihuacan are Mexico&#39;s first World Cultural Heritage and a must-see for travelers. I went to visit it on the second day after arriving in Mexico City. The main landscape is a north-south central axis of the city called &quot;Yellow Springs Avenue&quot;, with dense Mesoamerican-style trapezoidal pyramid buildings on the east and west sides. The two largest pyramids are almost equally tall according to visual inspection, but the Moon Pyramid located at the north end of the avenue is higher, so the Sun Pyramid located on the east side of the middle of the avenue is actually taller. The base of the latter is square with a side length of about 225 meters. The top of the remaining tower is about 64 meters high. Originally, there was a magnificent temple built on the top platform, but since the entire ancient city was abandoned 1,200 years ago, the temple has been completely lost. Now it is impossible to know which god this temple was built for. , and it is not clear what the exact height of this pyramid was in its heyday. What we can determine is that it was built around 100 AD using 3 million tons of boulders without metal tools, livestock for transport, or vehicles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中美洲原住民修筑金字塔的想象图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;我于1月中旬来到这里，胖嘟嘟的本地游客们穿着短袖顶着烈日排着长队等待攀登太阳金字塔：塔分四层，每一层都要重新排一次队，才能最终走完248级台阶登上塔顶平台，估计全程需要花2个小时。我叹了口气，放弃了世界第三大金字塔打卡计划，转而爬上了台阶陡峭的月亮金字塔，打开一罐激浪，一边平缓呼吸，一边俯视眼前的黄泉大道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的意思是“众神之城”，它和“黄泉大道”“太阳金字塔”“月亮金字塔”一样，都是后人对这座千年古城的臆测——由于特奥蒂瓦坎文明没有留下语言文字，石头本身又不会说话，历史学家并不掌握它的来龙去脉，只知道它是起源于公元前200年的城邦文明，全盛时代大约有20万以上人口，于公元八世纪前衰亡，只留下了令后人叹为观止的宏伟建筑与精美石雕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1446&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特奥蒂瓦坎遗址是墨西哥首批世界文化遗产，图为从月亮金字塔俯瞰黄泉大道。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的第一拨后人是托尔特克人——后人并非后代，而是后来之人。托尔特克人在西北方不远的图拉建立了新的城邦，而将这座空寂无人却令人敬畏的废墟命名为特奥蒂瓦坎，意思是众神建造之地：他们显然无法相信这座中美洲最为宏大的古都是由人类自己建造的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的第二拨后人是阿兹特克人，他们给古城的中轴线起了“黄泉大道”的名字，又把最大的两座金字塔命名为太阳和月亮金字塔。他们认为宏伟的金字塔群是天神为先王建造的陵墓，而这些死去的先王正是支撑太阳运行的潜在动力——这是基于一种从特奥蒂瓦坎到托尔特克再到阿兹特克一以贯之的独特世界观，也就是世界的存续维系于人类的献祭：以人的生命滋养世界的运行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人便是这篇故事的主角，特诺奇蒂特兰的缔造者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;湖中之国&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;特诺奇蒂特兰如今往往被称为“阿兹特克帝国”，这个名称从“阿兹特克”到“帝国”其实都不太妥当。先说“阿兹特克”（&lt;span>;Aztec&lt;/span>;），这是传说中来自墨西哥西北部的一个游牧族群，他们沿着荒凉的墨西哥高原南迁，最终抵达水草丰茂的墨西哥谷，在此定居下来，成为托尔特克人的附庸。托尔特克文明消亡后，他们与当地其他族群经过长期融合，构建了三个主要城邦之间的联盟，使用共同的语言，自称为墨西加人（&lt;span>;Mexica&lt;/span>;），也就是住在墨西哥谷中的人，形成了民族认同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拿中国来做类比的话，这就相当于黄帝与炎帝两大部落结盟，构建了民族认同，其后代自认为炎黄子孙，又以所居住的中土而自称为中国人——这里的“炎黄子孙”和“中国人”可以大致对应“阿兹特克”与“墨西加人”两个概念。但我们如果把中国称为“炎黄国”显然不太妥当，因为“炎黄”是故老相传的上古神话；同理，“阿兹特克”也是存在于远古神话中的族群，将现实中的墨西加人国度称为“阿兹特克国”同样并不恰当。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再说“帝国”，刚才提到，这其实是三个城邦之间的松散联盟，并不存在一个大一统的帝国。因此，所谓“阿兹特克帝国”，其实就是墨西哥谷中由特诺奇蒂特兰主导的城邦联盟。这些原住民自称为墨西加人，自认为是阿兹特克人的后裔，他们建立的文明，如今叫做阿兹特克文明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特诺奇蒂特兰还原图，上方为东。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么特诺奇蒂特兰是怎样一个城邦呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传说当年阿兹特克人南迁时得到神谕，要寻找一只叼着蛇停在仙人掌上的鹰，那里便是他们新的繁衍之地。当他们经过长途跋涉到达特斯科科湖西岸的一座沙洲时，果然见到了这番景象，便在沙洲上定居下来，并根据酋长特诺奇的名字将沙洲命名为特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人建造了三条长堤，从北、西、南三个方向连接沙洲与湖岸，又在沙洲与湖心之间建了一条长堤，用来隔绝浪潮和来自大湖对面的攻击；他们从西岸引来山泉水，经长堤向沙洲供水饮用；由于火山灰中富含矿物质的缘故，特诺奇蒂特兰周边土壤非常适合耕种，他们以玉米为主粮，也种南瓜、豆类和苋菜；他们还发明了一种叫做奇南帕（&lt;span>;chinampa&lt;/span>;）的浮岛农业，有点类似我国长江中下游流域的圩田，从湖底取淤泥造田，用木桩和柳条固定，形成肥沃的人工岛，扩大种植面积；美洲大陆没有马、牛、羊这些家畜，特斯科科湖里也没什么鱼，他们主要饲养狗、兔和鸡鸭来获得蛋白质，做饭的方式是在石板上烤&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>;因为阿兹特克文明尚处于青铜时代，没有铁锅；他们铺设了排污系统，在管道接口处还会放一口大缸，污水中的垃圾沉淀在大缸里，定期派人清除；他们实施斯巴达式的全民军事教育，而贵族和富人则可以学到文化知识；由于没有铁，他们的武器是黑曜石做的矛、剑以及箭镞——黑曜石是墨西哥的“国石”，是火山熔岩冷却凝结后形成的一种天然玻璃，显然并不十分耐用，我从墨西哥带回的黑曜石匕首回到上海第一天就被儿子把玩时摔断了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;黑曜石箭簇&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人将见证神谕的地方定为城邦的中心——在他们看来，这里也是当仁不让的宇宙中心——在此建立他们的神庙。这座神庙后来被西班牙人捣毁，用拆下的石料在其前方建造了墨西哥第一座天主教堂，用于镇压异教徒的“邪灵”，那就是今天的墨西哥城主教座堂（Catedral Metropolitana）。 457年后，市政工人偶然挖出了阿兹特克神庙的重要遗物：月亮女神石像，墨西哥政府遂决定拆掉遗址上方的建筑物，全面发掘这座大神庙，让阿兹特克人的神祇重见天日。于是，我们今天得以在墨西哥城市中心的宪法广场北侧同时看到两座比邻而居的世界文化遗产，西侧是巴洛克风格的主教座堂，东侧是半露天的特诺奇蒂特兰大神庙遗址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宪法广场古已有之，早在阿兹特克时代这里就是大神庙旁边的大型露天市场。西班牙人能把异教徒的首都夷为平地，却没有办法把一座广场摧毁成原始森林，于是就留了下来，作为主教座堂门前的中央广场。到了&lt;span>;1821&lt;/span>;年，为了庆祝墨西哥独立后颁布迪亚兹宪法，这里被命名为宪法广场。政府曾经筹划在广场上建一座独立纪念碑，这事儿由于财政原因只打了个地基就黄了。西班牙语里的&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;地基&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;叫&lt;span>;zócalo&lt;/span>;，于是这里就被首都各界群众半写实半嘲讽地称为&lt;span>;Zócalo&lt;/span>;广场。没想到后来墨西哥其他城市的中央广场也跟着首都叫这个名字，结果&lt;span>;Zócalo&lt;/span>;这个词在墨西哥西班牙语中竟成了中央广场的意思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;大神庙嵌套模型&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大神庙的主体建筑是一座类似特奥蒂瓦坎太阳金字塔的四层梯形平台，体量上则大为缩水——毕竟特诺奇蒂特兰这座湖畔沙洲的承载能力有限。平台上方原本有两座祭坛，分别用于祭祀阿兹特克人的太阳神暨战神以及雨神，但早已毁于西班牙人之手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;貌似无甚可观？非也。这座神庙的独特之处在于：它外层包内层，里里外外一共包了六层——也就是说，从内到外一共有七座神庙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是怎么回事呢？原来特诺奇蒂特兰是一个尚武的城邦，控制着周边其他原住民城邦与部落。每当君主逝世，下一任统治者都会开展一场加冕战争，重新获得各个属地的忠诚。一旦他再次控制局面，天下布武，就会要求各邦各部派人来到特诺奇蒂特兰参与修建神庙，从基座开始砌个梯形金字塔外墙，把上一代君主修建的神庙包起来，将外墙封顶后形成一个新的平台，重新修建新的双祭坛神庙。这座新神庙的竣工标志着新一代君权的确立，可以视为“国之大事，在祀与戎”的墨西哥版诠释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么一来，大神庙层层嵌套，越修越大。运用简单的工程学原理就可以判断：这种“套娃“工程的土方量是呈立方关系增长的，对于国力消耗极为巨大，也是不可持续的。特诺奇蒂特兰立国近二百年，建造了七层这样的大神庙，所耗费的人力物力，并不亚于太阳金字塔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么这世世代代修建的一系列大神庙用来干什么呢？以活人为牺牲，向天神献祭祈福——简单说来，就是杀人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;查克是人与神之间的信使，用于供奉人心。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;嗜血文明&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人自认为是太阳的后裔，相信日出是太阳神战胜黑暗的结果。他们认为世界已经毁灭过四次，如今正处于太阳神与黑暗群神的第五次较量之中，太阳神需要子民为他提供滋养，那就是人血。因此，阿兹特克人不分男女，从小就习惯于使用尖锐的龙舌兰刺在耳垂、舌头、胸膛乃至生殖器采血祭神，祭司则从自己的太阳穴蘸血作画，敬献给太阳神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，采血祭祀只是个人行为，比采血更神圣的祭祀仪式是公开的活人献祭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已故美国考古学家Patricia R.Anawalt曾在其论文《对阿兹特克人祭的理解》中开章明义地说过：“用活人作祭品，无论在新大陆还是在旧大陆都出现过。这样的例子不仅在中美洲找得到，在美索不达米亚、埃及和中国也都找得到。所不同的是阿兹特克的人祭早已为人所知，而对旧大陆的古老文化的认识则是最近的事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以我国为例，上世纪二十年代末启动的安阳殷墟发掘工作让我们得以了解殷商时期的大规模活人献祭，仅殷墟一地发现的人祭尸骨即达到3684具。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而阿兹特克人的人祭行为在西班牙征服者的渲染之下更让人触目惊心，考古挖掘的新发现则证明西班牙人的记载并非对于失败者的一味抹黑。比如，墨西哥考古学家曾在大神庙附近意外挖出大批骷髅头骨，它们并不像一般的万人坑、乱葬岗，而是朝着同一个方向整齐地排成三维矩阵。经过清理，考古学家奇怪地发现，所有头骨两侧都有破洞，显然是被人为凿穿的。最后当整片遗址发掘完毕，大家才明白是怎么回事：原来这里曾经是一个三十多米长、四米多高的五排石架，架子上插着许多木梁，木梁上穿着成排的头骨——正如西班牙人的记载。后来这里被泥土掩埋，木梁朽坏，便形成了地下头骨矩阵。考古学家用阿兹特克人的语言将这片遗址命名为“骷髅之墙”，挑选了三具头骨用木梁串起来，展示于大神庙后侧的博物馆中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结合文字记录与考古发掘成果，如今已经可以大致还原大神庙的活人献祭：在广大国民的围观之下，被献祭的人牲在大神庙前列成长队，一个个被带上四层平台，仰面躺在双祭坛前的人牲石上；由主祭司手持黑曜石匕首切开人牲的胸膛，掏出尚在跳动的心脏，供奉给太阳神；尸体沿石阶扔下基座，由次一级的祭司将其首级割下，剥去头皮，在头骨两侧钻孔后穿在刚才提到的骷髅架上；人牲的四肢被肢解，交还给他们的提供者，躯干则被遗弃，人牲的鲜血会和玉米饼和在一起作为与神灵沟通的食物，以至于西班牙人来到大神庙时，首先注意到的就是石阶上积累近两百年的血迹和它散发的浓重气味。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;911&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;马利亚贝奇亚诺手抄本中展示的阿兹特克人祭场面&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人宰杀的人牲数量相当惊人，常被引证的是1487年的记载，在4天里屠杀了201个400人，也就是80400人。不过这个数字不太可靠，因为当时特诺奇蒂特兰的人口总共也才20万人。考虑到阿兹特克人所说的“400”其实是虚指，意为大量，比如作为大地女神最小儿子的战神就曾经杀死他的400个哥哥成为主神，那么这条记录的意思也许只是杀害了201批人牲。历史学家含糊地把这4天内的受害人数削减到两万人——饶是如此，这也是一个惊人的数字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于上文提到人牲的“提供者”，这涉及墨西哥谷的地缘政治。阿兹特克人近乎狂热地使用活人献祭来维持太阳东升西落，祈求农业风调雨顺，在一片干旱粗粝的高原上维续这座湿地城邦的有限农业资源。但他们并不想耗费自己的人力资源，因此热衷于四出征讨，获得战俘以供祭祀。后来周围部落都被打服了，不愿继续作战，甘心每隔八个月向特诺奇蒂特兰上缴一次贡品。但阿兹特克人依然不肯收手，继续发动其“荣冠”战争，也就是没有宗教、政治、领土和经济诉求，纯粹为了获得人口用于献祭的战争，类似原始部落“猎头族”的行为，最后演变为各个臣服部落定期向特诺奇蒂特兰献出人口，供其屠杀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了上述常规的人祭方式，还有两种特殊的人祭值得一提：一是为了献祭太阳神暨战神，更为“高端”的祭品是俘获的敌国将领，他被绳索拴在一块大石头上无法逃脱，使用羽毛棒与手持狼牙棒和盾牌的本族武士搏斗。如果他能够连胜四人，再与一个左撇子武士搏斗获得胜利，就可以重获自由——当然，这纯属赤裸裸的欺负人；二是为了献祭雨神，使用的祭品是儿童——阿兹特克人相信儿童在祭祀过程中流下的眼泪将会变成灌溉农田的雨水而带来丰收。作为一个父亲，我就不详述这项祭祀的过程了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;由两条蛇交织而成的雨神面具，绿松石代表水&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，大神庙博物馆里还陈列着千奇百怪的牺牲：美洲豹、美洲狮、狼、鳄鱼、白鹭、琵鹭，甚至还有大量的石刻头骨——这些或许意味着阿兹特克人正在走出蒙昧，逐步取代野蛮的活人献祭。可惜的是，随着一群现世神祇的降临，他们不再有机会继续演进了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;石骷髅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;天外飞仙&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“201个400人”活人献祭后5年，哥伦布抵达加勒比海地区，开始在古巴建立殖民地。西班牙人花了27年站稳阵脚，然后于1519年2月15日派出一支由11条船、550人和16匹马组成的远征船队前往今天的墨西哥，这支船队的首领叫做埃尔南·科尔特斯（Hernán Cortés），被墨西哥人视为史上第一大恶人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科尔特斯首先在尤卡坦半岛东岸的Cozumel岛登陆补给，那里现在是加勒比海邮轮之旅中最重要的港口之一。然后他率领船队沿着尤卡坦半岛向西绕行，被沿途的原住民视为天神下凡：原住民没有见过马，也没有见过骑兵，所以认为骑兵是长着四条腿能够移动如飞的神怪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科尔特斯知道自己人单势孤，无法与人数超过五百万人的整个原住民阵营相抗衡，但他很快发现，这个阵营并非铁板一块，而是由特诺奇蒂特兰主导的三城联盟，统治着一群弱小的部落，对抗墨西哥谷以东的两个敌对城邦。特诺奇蒂特兰的敌国们深知其嗜血本性，坚决不肯屈服；特诺奇蒂特兰的属国们则长期匍匐于其暴政之下，不断付出供品和人牲，同样叫苦不迭。于是，科尔特斯明智地与这两个城邦结盟，共同对付特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在特诺奇蒂特兰这边，阿兹特克人非常崇敬统治墨西哥谷的前辈托尔特克人，全盘接收了托尔特克人的世界观。根据托尔特克人的神话传说，他们离开了墨西哥中部高原，在墨西哥湾下海前往东方追寻羽蛇神——中美洲多个文明所供奉的主神，并将于1519年跟随白色皮肤的羽蛇神从东方回归墨西哥谷。所以，当国王蒙特祖马二世听说一群“漂浮的城堡”从东方蹈海而来，在墨西哥湾登陆，他的第一认知是：神灵回归人间了！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特诺奇蒂特兰大市场还原模型&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1519年11月8日，科尔特斯带着人数微不足道的远征军以及六千名原住民盟友在中部高原绕了两个几字形的大弯后从特斯科科湖南岸经长堤进入特诺奇蒂特兰，见到了这座闻名已久的水上圣城，也是当时世界上人口最为稠密的都市之一。他被当作天神一般受到了蒙特祖马二世的隆重接待，被安置于国王父亲的宫殿。大约半年多以后，也许是阿兹特克人看出了西班牙人的野心，也许是西班牙人有意识地捣毁阿兹特克神像，双方发生了冲突，意图息事宁人的蒙特祖马二世在谈判中被科尔特斯扣为人质，随后在双方各执一词的混乱中受伤致死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年后的1521年5月，对特诺奇蒂特兰的地形与弱点已经了如指掌的科尔特斯带着九百名西班牙援军和十万名土著盟军卷土重来。天下苦阿兹特克久矣！过去的属国纷纷反戈一击，形成了墙倒众人推的态势。阿兹特克人孤军奋战，在错综复杂的河网中凭据一座座浮岛、一栋栋房屋负隅顽抗。 93天之后，整座岛城被夷为平地，特诺奇蒂特兰灭亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联盟的中枢败亡后，整个墨西哥都被西班牙轻松控制。殖民者将这里命名为Nueva Espana，意为“新西班牙”。又过了三百年，到了1821年，墨西哥才获得独立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;国家宫壁画展示西班牙殖民者攻破特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;尾声&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;从墨西哥城机场坐地铁五号线进城，需要在La Raza站换三号线。 La Raza是个换乘大站，差不多相当于北京的东直门站或者上海的龙阳路站，转趟车得步行五六分钟。每次经过这里，我都会在漫长的甬道中部逗留片刻，细细观赏路边玻璃柜里陈列的变形金刚全家福，仿佛被拉回到了九十年代的少年时光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在五百年前，生活在这里的阿兹特克人也像卡通片中的地球人一样迎来了在技术层面足以对他们形成降维打击的变形金刚：西班牙人。只是，现实中并不存在像汽车人那样博爱仁慈的救世主。他们最终退缩到大湖中央的特诺奇蒂特兰，被冷酷无情的威震天所率领的霸天虎们屠杀殆尽，烟波浩渺的大湖也被这些天外飞仙抽干，成了今天持续下沉的墨西哥城。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克文明就这样完结了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[智力残障女性被标“18.8万，交钱结婚”：婚姻介绍还是人口贩卖？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日有博主发文，称某短视频平台主播发布的征婚视频引人不适，引发舆论关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个网名叫“才哥（全国相亲)”的“婚介主播”长期在短视频平台发布相亲信息，明码标价彩礼价格。被介绍相亲女性中有多位是智障人士，视频中不乏“18.8万，交钱结婚”这种令人严重不适的内容。网友怀疑，该网红是个公开明码标价的人贩子。该主播则表示他们是“正规婚介”，有需求可以到线下婚介所相亲，交完彩礼另付2万元介绍费就可以把人领走，“先结婚后恋爱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事掀起舆论波澜，不少网友认为这是“人口贩卖”。 10月4日晚间，云南省弥勒市政府工作人员告诉《上游新闻》称已关注到此事，当地已经成立多部门组成的工作专班，分组对此事进行核查。细审这起事件，除了令人不适之外，更显露出一些深层次问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，这起事件带来的最大问题是，如此短视频婚介存在哪些法律与道德上的破口？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚姻应该遵循自愿原则。 “自愿”应理解为可以自主表达，有完全民事行为能力，可以做出有法律效力的意思表示。然而，残障人士的情况比较特殊，是否可以行使完全民事行为能力登记结婚，需要分情况看待。如果残障人士只是肢体残疾而不影响辨认自己行为，则具有完全民事行为能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而如果残障人士是精神方面的残障，那么还可以细分为“不能完全辨认自己行为”的限制民事行为能力人，以及“不能辨认自己行为”的无民事行为能力人。限制民事行为能力人只能独立实施纯获利益的民事法律行为，或者与其智力、精神健康状况相适应的民事法律行为，其他的情况与无民事行为能力人一样，需要由监护人来代为行使民事权利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，监护人是否有权代替残障人士行使民事权利，做出登记结婚的重大决定？在这起事件中，“婚介主播”的短视频多遵循“年龄＋智力状况＋广告语＋彩礼”的套路，明晃晃打出“相亲”“闪婚”的广告字眼，一开始就冲着“收钱结婚”去的。残障人士在此期间有无机会表达自己的真实意愿？或者，婚介方与监护人是否会征询残障人士的意见？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些问题的答案当然是大有疑问的。尤其是在有利益驱使的情况下，监护人未必会尊重残障人士的真实意愿。甚至于从人性角度来讲，监护人面临“丢掉一个累赘，收到一笔大钱”的真实激励。在这条婚介产业链上，残障人士成了最没有话语权的相关方，沦为婚介方与监护人的摇钱树。这有悖于起码的人伦道德，也存在法律上的疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2021年的“河南省泌阳县55岁男子娶20岁智障女子”事件中，当事女性父亲的所作所为曾经引发巨大争议。作为智障女儿的监护人，父亲与继母一手做主“包办”了这场“婚姻”。事后官方调查组的结论是，两人同居不违法，但不能办理结婚证。这个案例就显示，类似“婚姻”的法律效力是存疑的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，“人口贩卖”的疑云在事件中挥之不去，尤其是与“彩礼”结合到一起的时候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这名“婚介主播”在接受音频采访时表示，“正常的女孩子彩礼在15万以上，最低也得10多万”“我们要拿两万的服务费”“一对一服务，过来一个成功一个”“两星期内领好证把老婆带回去”。诚如网友所言，挂着彩礼名号的“明码标价”，确实令人直接联想到人口贩卖。这不仅是观感上的不适，也同样涉嫌真正的违法犯罪行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不论这位“婚介主播”多么强调自己的“合法合规”，“拿到彩礼两星期内领证”的操作怎么看怎么都像是变相的人口贩卖，“来一个成功一个”的表述更是让人完全看不到残障女性在其中的发言权，这在根本上已经违背了《中华人民共和国民法典》中“婚姻自愿原则”的法律条文，唯一可以作为补丁的就是监护人的同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;监护人的意见真的就可以代表残障人士的自主意愿吗？这是存疑的。同时，十多万的高额彩礼，最终可以用来改善残障女性的婚后生活吗？这笔钱最终会落到谁的手里，也是不问可知。如果监护人“收钱给人”，那么这无异于银货两讫的人口贩卖，退一步讲也是不折不扣的强迫婚姻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更有甚者，类似“婚介产业”还开发了针对残障女性的“细分赛道”。因为容易被操控，他们甚至还可以“反复回收”残障女性。 “买家”在结婚生子之后还可以“退回媳妇”，然后再“介绍”给下一家去怀孕生产，“婚介所”从中再收取一笔佣金，这又无异于直接倒退回已经进入历史垃圾堆的“生育奴隶制”了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚姻的基础应该是爱与道德，而不是买卖与算计。但如果加入残障人士这个特殊变量，买卖婚姻甚至买卖人口的性质就加倍地凸显出来。面对如此明目张胆的“标价征婚”，有关部门理应拿出不亚于“泌阳事件”的严肃态度，追查其合规性，保障残障人士合法权益，维护婚姻家庭价值观，不能让残障人士成为一手交钱一手交货的现代奴隶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[读《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》的乐趣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk9rrT15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk9rrT15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;村上春树和他的新著《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（CFP图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本作家村上春树喜欢收藏，其中一样他收藏的东西就是古典音乐唱片，特别是黑胶唱片，早前出版的《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》，就是写他所收藏的唱片精选。在这本把书的开本做成跟唱片封套一样的小书里，他说自己在过去60年来，在世界各地逛唱片店，买回来的旧唱片有过万张，他特别挑选一些最喜欢的，写一下喜欢的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上开宗明义说，这书“充其量就是一本个人偏好与兴趣的书，不具任何系统性、实用性目的，没有&#39;这张是这首曲子的必听盘！&#39;之类的推荐意图”。这书就像早前《村上T》的延续，读者很喜欢村上春树，想知道他穿什么的衣服，也想知道他听什么的唱片，如此而已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，古典音乐的每首曲子都有无数的录音版本，不同的指挥、乐团、演奏时间，甚至是同一首乐曲但不同的录制压制技术，都令每个唱片版本独一无二。在今天浩瀚的各个串流音乐平台，也只有不同录音版本的冰山一角。读村上这书的时候，总会有：啊！原来这首曲子还有这个版本，真想找来听听的冲动。不过，想要按图索骥把书里介绍的唱片找回来，很不容易，毕竟村上在书里介绍的唱片，很多都是上世纪五六十年代的产物，要么在旧唱片店里碰运气，也可到著名的唱片交易网站discogs寻宝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上说他挑选唱片都是个人偏好，也因此有不少古典乐迷对他的选择都有意见，但讲到明底个人偏好，自然各人所见所喜都有不同。就像村上自己说他不太喜欢钢琴家布伦德尔（Alfred Brendel），但布伦德尔本来就有很多人喜欢。喜欢哪个版本、哪个指挥，很多时候都是和自己的经验有关，而村上跟著名指挥小泽征尔是好朋友，他就自然更偏好小泽征尔的版本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在个人经验之外，另一个原因就是对乐曲诠释的偏好，有些时候音乐家对乐曲的演绎手法都很有特色（甚至到了哗众取宠的程度），乐迷不埋单（或反过来很喜欢）的原因也相对容易可以说出来。举个例吧：马勒的第七交响曲，如果听克伦佩勒（Otto Klemperer）的版本（跟大部分版本比较，全曲长了差不多20分钟），那种极度缓慢的风格，感觉就像看着远处的火车驶进月台，火车逐渐靠近但又总是永远没到达似的，有人说这是一种张力，但我自己就很不喜欢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论怎样，村上在写这些乐评的时候，始终有他独到的手法，让读者即使只是在读村上的古典唱片短评，也一样有读村上春树文字的乐趣。就如他说钢琴家古尔达（Friedrich Gulda）跟维也纳爱乐（阿巴多指挥）录制的莫扎特第25号钢琴协奏曲，听起来“有一种像是在大阪乌龙面店吃清汤乌冬面般不可思议的安心感”；又或是Thomas Beecham爵士指挥海顿的第94号交响曲，总是有种“风度翩翩的旧时代英国绅士印象，就连第二乐章的&#39;惊愕&#39;（surprise）部分，惊吓方式也是稳健又高雅，这种程度的惊吓就连端着茶杯的妇女也不会吓到红茶溢出来”。这些比喻，非常独到，非常的村上春树。莫扎特也好，古尔达也好，怎会想过自己的作品，竟然变成了一碗大阪的清汤乌冬？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，回到一个重要问题：现在听古典音乐，为何还要听黑胶唱片？又或者更大的疑问是：黑胶唱片怎么会起死回生？黑胶唱片的回归，是人类发展史上其中一个最励志的故事。明明已给时代淘汰，笨重又脆弱，承载量少得可怜，但事实证明：只要有价值，哪怕满满缺点，还是有存在的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上春树在《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》中说，听黑胶唱片是“那种只要悉心对待，就会有所回应的东西”。在一切都是数位的年代，付出和回应早已变成非常公式的交换，什么都是一个按钮换来一个反应，失去了用心付出所换来的满足。就像你再小心温柔地轻触手机上的串流音乐平台、播放乐曲，播出来的音乐，也绝对不会有任何分别（所以实际上我们也自然不会怎样温柔地轻触手机）。 “有所回应”的特质在现今冰冷的世界已经变得稀有，也因此才会令黑胶唱片在今天复兴起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听黑胶唱片，从买唱片到播放，每一步都讲求“悉心对待”的付出。其中之一是音响播放，无论是听黑胶唱片还是听串流平台，本来就是深似海的学问。像最基本的唱盘、前级后级功放（音讯扩大机）、喇叭，或唱盘所用的唱头和唱针、连接设备的线材和接头，甚至是唱盘上放唱片的唱片垫，全部都讲究。村上春树也说，音响是个“行有余力才能培养的兴趣，这也是没办法的事，只能有此觉悟”。话虽如此，只要不是买几百元货色、只有外表的那种一体化播放唱盘，简单一套像样的入门音响设备，价钱其实也是亲民的，并且已经可反映出黑胶唱片的珍贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是音响设备，买（和找）黑胶碟也是讲求付出的活动。像在欧美等地方，不同社区都有救世军、乐思会等卖二手旧物的店，在这些旧物店里，总会有个角落，放满一箱箱的旧唱片，如果有负责任一点的店员（或是整齐一点的物主），都会把唱片分类放好。这个时候，慢慢蹲下来，把唱片逐张翻一翻、看一看，每一张都是未知，随时遇上心头好。这些旧唱片，很多时候都只是十元八块的价钱，便宜到不得了。跟一般旧唱片店不一样，这些旧物店都是非牟利的，负责人既无暇慢慢定价，也通常没有内行人一样懂得行情，了解货品的价值。所以，很容易在这些旧物店找到宝藏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在旧物店买到的唱片，唱片的状态不一，通常要花更多时间来好好清洁，有时也会买到损毁了的唱片，这些都没法避免，只好在买的时候再仔细检查看看。但像村上春树所说，即使是旧的唱片，只要用心去清洁（清洁唱片也一样有学问），清洁前后的播放音质，还是有显著的分别，至少唱针不会在播完唱片之后积起一堆尘垢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较之下，专卖旧唱片的商店，很多时候都对唱片做基本的清洁，并清楚标明唱片的状态、品相，相应地，定价也会相应地昂贵。比较世界各地不同的唱片店，日本的唱片店，往往是最整齐和最清洁的。难怪好朋友焦元溥老师说，他去日本的中古唱片店，每一次进去就是7个小时，每次都是天光逛到天黑。听他的分享，无论是精神还是财力，都是非常大的付出，当然每次也是换来大丰收吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大城府：泰国那一抹“永恒的微笑”丨古国多少事⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;暗红色的海洋&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如今无论从曼谷考山路包车，或者坐火车约一个小时，当可以远眺到尖塔和金碧辉煌的路牌时，浓厚的历史气息就会扑面而来——坐落于湄南河冲积平原上的大城府，地处暹罗湾潮汐线上方，这个四面被湄南河、华富里河、巴塞运河环绕而形成独特的岛城，有水道通向南方的暹罗湾，可通中国与东南亚诸国，又紧扼北方素可泰的出海门户，成为中、印、欧的地理连接点，更造就了它在贸易、军事、外交上得天独厚的条件：14至18世纪，发达的水陆交通和耀眼的佛教建筑让它的名声享誉东南亚乃至整个亚洲，甚至被目为东南亚最大最美丽的城市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199733&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玛哈泰寺的佛像与遗迹&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1350年，湄南河西岸的罗斟（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今华富里&lt;/span>;）政权首领拉玛铁菩提（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ramathibodi I，乌通王&lt;/span>;）战胜泰国第一个封建王朝素可泰王朝，罗斟与河东岸素攀政权暹国合并，建立阿瑜陀耶王朝，中国史籍称“暹罗”。当曼谷还是名不见经传的小渔村时，阿瑜陀耶王朝定都之地，已是一座繁华“大城”——旅泰华人认为此城最大，故称“大城府”，连王朝都亦称“大城王朝”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在历史文献中，大城府被称为“天堂”，鼎盛时期人口约有100万，三座王宫、超过2000座镀金尖塔式庙宇和4000多尊镀金佛像，让这里处处金碧辉煌；历33位国王、延世417年的王朝，将佛教文化送上巅峰。大城王朝中后期时，明人张燮还在他的《东西洋考》“暹罗条”里写：“其土下湿，气候岚热不齐，民悉楼居，楼密联，槟榔片藤系之甚固，藉以藤席，竹簟寝处其间。王宫高九丈余，以黄金为饰，雕缕八卦，备极弘丽。”16世纪开始，大城府的声名远播欧陆，1512年葡萄牙人首抵此处，大城府逐渐在17世纪成为贸易中心，欧洲各国使节纷至沓来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说几百年前大城府的主色调是金色，而今这里，武断一点而言，市中心只有红褐与焦黑两种颜色：红褐色是建筑早已蒙尘的砖块，烈日烤灼、风雨侵蚀，让凹凸不平的地面与墙面，一起化为一片暗红色的海洋。大城府的诸多古刹，乍看之下是吴哥窟的翻版，但仔细鉴赏之后就能发现，与多用大石块构成的吴哥诸寺不同，这里多用红砖；没有吴哥窟雕花墙壁、百转千回长廊，这里却衍生出许多大城王朝时期独有的建筑风格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗卡雅苏塔寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Lokaya Sutha&lt;/span>;）已经不能被称作“寺”，一片蔓生荒草中，巨大卧佛裸露在自然中接受朝拜；建于1491年的帕西桑碧寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Phra Si San Phet，三王庙&lt;/span>;）残存的三座白色锡兰式佛塔一字排开，已成大城府地标：1492年，为供奉父兄骨灰，拉玛铁菩提二世在寺中兴建两座佛塔，开启了泰国用佛塔存放国王骨灰的丧葬习俗，1529年拉玛铁菩提二世驾崩，其子又修建一座佛塔。而今时光还没有把它们摧毁殆尽，旁边历代国王依次修筑的许多小塔虽然破损严重，却依然壮观高耸，如同肃穆的卫兵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;帕西桑碧寺以东，即是以正居院中的宏伟佛塔而闻名的拉嘉布拉那寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Ratchaburana&lt;/span>;）。这座高棉样式的佛塔原本为泰式，系九世王替两位争夺王位继承权决斗而死的兄长举行火葬而建：1424年，因陀罗阇王去世，骑大象自相残杀的两个王子死后，三子从彭世洛南下继承王位，成为波隆摩罗阇二世（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat II&lt;/span>;），建设这座寺庙存放兄长骨灰。穿过如同大三巴一样只剩一面墙壁的大门，四周全是支离破碎的佛像与围墙，仿佛突然掉进遥远的古代。似一根玉米一样的主塔上，楞状塔饰层层叠叠；四周环绕四座锡兰式小塔，乃城中保存最为完整的高棉风格佛塔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城中最古老的寺院则在护城河外东南角，崖差蒙空寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Yai Chaiyamongkho&lt;/span>;）为1357年乌通王为纪念王朝诞生而建，与城内充满沧桑感的废墟式庙宇不同，这里随处可见重建的痕迹，却并不让人觉得突兀，甚至还不如佛塔披挂的黄绫与斑驳的红砖给人的视觉反差强烈。长达28米的洁白卧佛是这里的标志，身披黄色袈裟安详侧卧在白花花的炙热阳光下，淡泊地注视周围饱经风霜的土地与河流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爬上锡兰式主塔，内部有八座佛像，更令人难忘的是一种混合的奇怪味道充溢其间，硝烟夹杂腐败植物的味道，更多的是人体臭气，让人难于呼吸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;柴瓦塔那兰寺，佛像的背影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;繁荣的黑暗倒影&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在游人绝迹之时，崖差蒙空寺的卧佛周遭，徒留一片历经岁月洗涤过后的宁静——主塔四周，许多无头佛像静默着，似乎并不想诉说它们所经历的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿瑜陀耶的名字来源于印度史诗《罗摩衍那》中罗摩的诞生地及凯旋归来后的登基之地阿约提亚（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ayodhya&lt;/span>;），梵语意为“不可战胜之城”或“永恒胜利之城”，但这名字一如谶语：作为继高棉帝国之后第二个东南亚“超级大国”，当大城王朝达到鼎盛时期之时，它与缅甸之间的战争也绵延展开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一切辉煌总有一个终结。 1766年，觊觎大城府已久的缅甸王孟驳率军围城14个月之后，炸塌城墙攻入城中，在15天的烧杀抢掠之后，三万人沦为俘虏，大城府几乎被夷为平地。不可战胜之城却在战乱中破败——这个泰王国历史上持续时间最长的朝代，带着它所有的风华，在1767年戛然而止，只有十几座“洗尽铅华”的寺庙遗迹——红砖上多见黑色火烧污渍，佛像也被火焰熏得黧黑，沉默不语伫立城中，为大城王朝的黄金时代聊作见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府，红的对面是黑。拉嘉布拉那寺之南，玛哈泰寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Mahathat&lt;/span>;）据说是缅甸军队攻打泰国的首要目标：这座始建于1374年即二世王波隆摩罗阇一世（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat I&lt;/span>;）统治时期的寺院曾拥有10余处僧院、立有如丛林般的200余座佛塔，如今寺院正中只剩巨大方形塔基，小塔亦多严重倾斜，摇摇欲坠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;柴瓦塔那兰寺的成排无头佛像&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府诸寺，很多“排排坐”的佛像，无一例外都没有头，地上墙角会“惊现”一双石雕佛脚，抑或一只巨大佛手，观之十分“后现代”。也许正因如此，许多游客喜欢屈膝躲在佛像后，将自己的头从佛像破损的颈口伸出来拍照。其实，那些玛哈泰寺中的佛像与佛塔，身镀黄金，或体内藏有金叶，引得缅军将佛像斩首，或以大火焚烧，令黄金与石头分离，热胀冷缩造成佛像头部、手脚断裂，留下残肢断臂的满目疮痍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大城府如同圆明园。阳光给柴瓦塔那兰寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Chaiwatthanaram&lt;/span>;）的高塔涂上金黄，让红砖拥有了狞厉之美，带人回到战火纷飞的时代。当红已变成黑，浮屠兀自伫立，斑驳佛塔、破烂砖墙、黝黑佛像、浩大古迹，毫不留情地掩盖了繁华与覆灭，只有残留的文献与口述的故事世代相传，岁月亦如过眼云烟——盛世的繁荣也会成为幻灭的倒影，一如柴瓦塔那兰寺中，夕阳里高坐于几乎坍塌的基座上的佛像，那恒久的落寞背影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;军队入侵之际，佛寺尽毁，刀落之处，如作家翁达杰语，“菩萨意味深长的巍峨法相倒向地面，坠入土中”。在漫长的时光中，一颗佛头被千年菩提之根紧紧包裹，环绕的枝蔓将它缠绕于其中，形成了树包佛头的奇观，亦是玛哈泰寺最著名的“永恒微笑”。如同吴哥窟中塔布伦寺景色的“终局”一样，东南亚树木的绞杀现象会让植物最终取代寄主，但而今佛像仍在菩提树中闭目微笑，不着一语，仿佛看尽王朝风云变幻，那是一种与事件万物同在、超乎生死的神奇气度，让人们可以一直站在它面前，注视它很久很久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玛哈泰寺的树包佛头奇观&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千千万万人用时间将大城府筑起，大城府又在光影里注视着这千千万万人生成的世界。大城王朝覆灭后，郑信将泰国都城南迁近百公里至吞武里，历经仅15年的吞武里王朝后，1782年曼谷王朝定都曼谷，在新的土地上书写繁华，大城府则愈发淡出人们的视线了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两百余年光阴倏然而过，如今这里更像一个充满乡村气息与休闲氛围的小镇。遗址公园内，草坪、绿树、水塘，一派田园风光；当地人会铺张席子随意野餐，或者租下传统服饰，模仿在此取景的热门电视剧《天生一对》，在遗址中拍照。红与黑的遗址紧挨着新建的民居与寺庙，残砖败石中烟火水乳交融，有种穿越时空的错愕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;邦芭茵夏宫草坪的大象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府与曼谷之间，始建于17世纪的邦芭茵夏宫（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bang Pa-In Summer Palace&lt;/span>;）是泰国最大最美的王室行宫，19世纪经曼谷王朝的拉玛四世、五世国王下令修复后，泰国、中国、缅甸、哥特诸式建筑风格俱全；更有典型泰式“三尖顶”的金色水上皇亭，粉蓝、淡紫、纯白的建筑群颇为小清新，搭配上做成可爱象群的热带绿植，邦芭茵夏宫挥别了浓烈的红与惨烈的黑，洋溢着一个新的时代的清爽之绿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运女篮铜牌赛上演朝韩对决，韩国以93比63获胜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258150]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿在防守韩国队球员。本场比赛她16投11中，交出了一份27分9篮板3助攻1盖帽的成绩单。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253069&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿在防守韩国队球员。本场比赛她16投11中，交出了一份27分9篮板3助攻1盖帽的成绩单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月5日，杭州第19届亚运会女子篮球铜牌争夺战在杭州奥体中心体育馆举行。韩国队以96比63胜朝鲜队，夺得该项目铜牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;朝韩女篮在小组赛的遭遇战中，韩国女篮凭借整体出色发挥，以81比62击败了朝鲜女篮，取得了比赛的胜利。 10月5日的比赛虽然只是铜牌争夺战，依旧是一场极具关注度的比赛。有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿缺阵对战中国女篮的半决赛之后，此番再度对阵韩国队复出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，作为神秘且很少外出参赛的朝鲜女篮，站到四强的高度，体现出了她们顽强拼搏的体育精神。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253070&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，作为神秘且很少外出参赛的朝鲜女篮，站到四强的高度，体现出了她们顽强拼搏的体育精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队17号球员朴津阿持球起跳射篮。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253071&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队17号球员朴津阿持球起跳射篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝韩双方球员在比赛中拼抢。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253072&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝韩双方球员在比赛中拼抢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从开场的热身和训练状态就可以看出朝鲜女篮的复仇决心。朴津阿在首节比赛中的效率非常之高，不仅有持球得分，在助攻和篮板上都有出色表现。在攻防两端，朴津阿都有盘活球队的能力，朝鲜队21比15领先第一节。然而进入第二节，朝鲜队的失误非常多，投篮命中率也出现下滑。韩国队中锋朴智修在第二节下半段也有非常出众的表现，不知不觉拿下了17分。半场结束前，韩国队将比分锁定在40比33，压力来到落后的朝鲜队一边。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，在观众席上为朝鲜队加油助威的观众。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253073&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，在观众席上为朝鲜队加油助威的观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，韩国队球员朴智修突破朝鲜队球员的防守。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253074&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，韩国队球员朴智修突破朝鲜队球员的防守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队12号球员芦淑英带球突破。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253075&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队12号球员芦淑英带球突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队教练对球员进行指点。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253076&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队教练对球员进行指点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下半场，朝鲜三分钟内将比分追至40平，随后两队中锋各中一个中投，42平。接着朴津阿和队友内外呼应连续出现问题，比赛以44比61朝鲜队落后进入第四节。第四节成了韩国队的表演时刻，尤其是韩国队老将金丹菲不声不响拿到21分，更是以三分球8中5把全队三分球带到25中13。全场比赛还剩三分半钟的时候，韩国队已经84比51领先33分。朝鲜扔进压哨超远三分，比分定格在93比63，朝鲜女篮以30分之差不敌韩国女篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，比赛结束后，韩国队球员合影留念庆祝。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253077&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，比赛结束后，韩国队球员合影留念庆祝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;打满全场的朝鲜队球员朴津阿虽然拿到全场最高的27分，但双方的账面实力差距太大，面对韩国队全场27中14的三分球，显得杯水车薪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欧洲公厕为什么很少且收费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258137]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;厕所看似小事，却也是社会必需之物，很多时候可以反映出一个社会的历史与当下，中外概莫能外。每个去欧洲旅行过的人应该都体会过厕所之困。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲各国普遍公厕很少，往往方圆几公里或许才能找到那么一个，所以欧洲有找厕所的APP，相比之下，中国找厕所的功能，都被地图APP涵盖了，不是一个热门功能，不能单独撑起一个APP。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了少，欧洲的厕所还要收费。很多欧洲国家例如英国、荷兰、德国等地方，使用公厕都是要付钱的，比如德国的高速服务区或是商场配套的厕所，多数都要收费。就连快餐店、商场、火车站、麦当劳、肯德基的厕所也都是要收费的。比如在德国科隆，麦当劳里面的厕所也要收费。再比如，波兰一家肯德基就贴出告示：店内厕所只提供给顾客，没有消费收据的人如果想使用厕所需付费30兹罗提（约合53元人民币）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收费的形式也五花八门，有专人坐在门口收费，有投币后闸门转动，有些是相信自觉，放一个小费盘。有些店，是厕所门有密码，而密码打印在购物小票上。德国的百货商场中并非每一楼层都设有洗手间，一般在最顶层的餐馆层附近，使用洗手间一般免费，但如果有清洁工人在，一般都要留下0.3欧元左右的小费。如果是在旅游区，还会贴心地提供汇率转换，各国货币明码标价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲厕所的收费，并不便宜，上一趟洗手间少则0.3欧多则2欧的费用。 1欧元等于7.7元人民币，相当于两块钱到15块钱之间，即便收入高些，在欧洲上个厕所也是真不便宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲作为全球最富裕的地区之一，也是“社会福利”最完善的地区，为什么很少有免费的公厕？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是因为历史。在欧洲的许多城市，比如英国伦敦、瑞典斯德哥尔摩、法国巴黎，都有街边半开放的露天厕所。它能包裹住下半身，但只能男性使用。这些露天小便池，在当地的使用频率非常高。这种奇怪的街头小便池在欧洲有近200年的历史了。这也反映了欧洲缺公共厕所是有历史渊源的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个历史路径就导致，人们未必把公共厕所视为一种政府义务。实际上，欧洲很多地方的公厕基本是私营化了的。既然如此，就按市场思路解决问题。厕所要定期保养、维修，还需要请人清洁，欧洲国家多为发达国家，人工成本高，这都造成了厕所的维护费用很高，商家不愿意把它放入一揽子服务中，而是单独收费提供。欧洲的咖啡馆、小酒吧等营业性场所的私人厕所，承担一些公共厕所的作用，当然得先消费再如厕。欧洲人也习惯了付费使用公厕，或者去咖啡店买杯咖啡，顺便解决内急问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲各国情况还不完全相同，在高税收高福利的丹麦，政府就认为，上公厕自由是政府必须达标的一项公共服务。所以，在人口不多的首都哥本哈根市区，公厕的数量足、环境好，还免费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，中国厕所也曾收费。 1970年代后期至1980年代末期，经济发展起来了，中国各城市相继开始建设较高档次的公厕，实现了水冲和机械抽运。公厕等级提高了，成本随之上升，部分城市公厕开始收费，以缓解公厕建设管理资金短缺的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了20世纪末，随着经济的进一步发展，中国人对厕所的要求开始变高，新建住宅小区，厕所从一卫增至两卫。但是，公共厕所的免费，并没有那么早。像青岛这样的中游城市，直到2008年5月1日，公共厕所才实行免费开放，到现在不过15年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;免费公厕，说到底还是政府有钱了。经过改革开放的多年积累，特别是加入WTO后，经济飞速发展，房地产腾飞，地方政府依靠土地财政获得了充裕的资金，才有能力把公共厕所的成本全部承担下来。所以，中国的免费公厕，主要是经济发展的结果。收费与不收费，必然与经济状况息息相关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厕所收费，本质上还是一个政府财政收入和政府公共服务范围的问题。如果说欧洲的公厕情况非常糟糕，那是因为历史、文化、习俗原因，社会也发展出各种替代形式，人们也与之适应。某些国家，免费公厕的福利从未出现，自然也不会有太大的感觉。但如果从免费再次返回到收费，会产生不一样的感知了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[粉黛花海迷人眼丨指尖华夏⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the golden autumn, and Naluhua is in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province Domestic pink grass has entered its best viewing period, and the sea of ​​flowers is like a &quot;pink ocean&quot;, attracting tourists to come to watch, play and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists play among the Nalu flowers and flowers in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;772&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[济南城投公司一次性售1341套现房，房从哪来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女篮夺冠，带妆打球的李梦砍下全场最高分]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/9Ybm20M4OciGBen6wKO9BuY6uLwbmNJORLc4inaX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9Ybm20M4OciGBen6wKO9BuY6uLwbmNJORL c4inaX. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women&#39;s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, China The team defeated the Japanese team 74-72 and won the championship. Chinese team player Li Meng won the gold medal at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 5, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games In the women&#39;s basketball final of the Asian Games, Wang Siyu scored a layup in the last 10 seconds. The Chinese women&#39;s basketball team defeated the Japanese women&#39;s basketball team with a score of 74-72 and successfully defended the Asian Games women&#39;s basketball championship. This is also the seventh time that the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team has won the Asian Games gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this fierce duel, Wang Siyu scored 14 points, Li Meng 17 points, Li Yueru 13 points and 9 rebounds, and Han Xu scored 10 points and 8 rebounds. After the game, Li Meng, who was once called the &quot;main scorer&quot; by Yao Ming, became a hot topic because of his makeup and brave play style. She wrote on her personal social media, &quot;This year is a year of harvest. I keep challenging and making breakthroughs. Basketball will always be my love and pursuit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the 28-year-old Li Meng, this is off the court. A year of constant turmoil is also a year of full harvest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before the women&#39;s basketball finals, the Women&#39;s National Basketball League (WNBA) officially announced the league&#39;s best rookie lineup. Li Meng, who played for the Washington Mystics last season, was selected. In this regard, she said in an interview, &quot;Thank you everyone for your recognition of me. It is not easy for everyone to recognize your ability in a foreign country. This is also a preliminary goal achieved. As I said, I am satisfied and adjusted. Have a good attitude and leave the rest to time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/nVE3Hvb9Zav9UdVjRfon5E64p8ZlBJl1RgUhmvN5.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/nVE3Hvb9Zav9UdVjRfon5E64p8ZlBJl1RgUhmvN5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253081&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 11, 2023, in Seattle, USA, during the 2023 WNBA regular season, the Washington Mystics defeated the Seattle Storm 71-65. Washington Mystics player Li Meng (left) broke through in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Li Meng officially Joined the WNBA team Washington Mystics and became the ninth women&#39;s basketball national player in history to land in the WNBA. Among the current Chinese women’s basketball players, four players including Han Xu, Li Yueru, Yang Liwei, and Li Meng have realized their WNBA dreams. As early as 2019, the Minnesota Lynx offered an olive branch to Li Meng, but because the national team still had a series of games at that time, she ultimately gave up the opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Washington Mystics official website recorded Li Meng’s outstanding performance in 34 games in his first season in the WNBA: averaging 5.6 points, 1.1 rebounds and 1.0 assists per game. As a player from China, Li Meng leads all rookies in three-point shooting percentage, hitting a total of 44 three-pointers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Washington Mystics general manager Mike Thibault said of Li Meng: &quot;She is the leading scorer of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team and an excellent outside player who has the ability to help the ball with her excellent three-pointers. The team opens up the space.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Same words were said by Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and former NBA superstar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/P1tI2RAa6wA6jgwdOPgOOw0Wp8gUNSGI97O58L3H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/P1tI2RAa6wA6jgwdOPgOOw0Wp8gUNSGI97O58L3H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women’s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese team player Li Meng (front right) shot a shot during the game&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2022 Women&#39;s Basketball World Cup, Li Meng averaged 16 points per game and was the highest scorer on the team, although she ended up missing due to illness. Able to participate in the semi-finals and finals, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team still won the silver medal. Yao Ming said in an interview after the game, &quot;The results achieved this time can be said to exceed expectations, but the growth of a team certainly does not happen overnight. In fact, many people on the team began to emerge 10 years ago, such as the main scorer. Li Meng already achieved good results when he participated in the World Youth Championship in the National Youth Team.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Meng started playing basketball at the age of 5. At first, he was rejected by the coach because he was too young and was difficult to coach. At her mother&#39;s insistence, she started practicing dribbling on the sidelines. There is a competitive side to her character. She could not grab the ball from the coach&#39;s hand. After being pointed out, she dared to &quot;fall to the ground and grab it&quot; and she actually hit the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ST1n4DyBXt93N6XobeOyOo1g3u4AHmZt4G1mcNti.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ST1n4DyBXt93N6XobeOyOo1g3u4AHmZt4G1mcNti.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253082&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women&#39;s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese team player Li Meng (left) communicated with teammate Han Xu&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 5, she didn’t know what basketball could bring to herself, she just thought it was fun. &quot;But when you get in touch with it slowly, you like it and it turns into love, and it continues to this day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, young Li Meng became a blockbuster at the U17 Youth World Cup Basketball Tournament. At that time, the Chinese team finished third, and at the age of 15, she won the tournament&#39;s Most Valuable Player (MVP) title by averaging 15.4 points and 6.2 rebounds per game, becoming the first player in Chinese history to win this honor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no smooth road. Li Meng, who has just emerged, has been plagued by injuries from ruptured anterior cruciate ligaments in both legs. Injuries have always been a problem that every athlete has to overcome, but for the teenage Li Meng, it was indeed a solid blow. &quot;Actually, it was okay after the first injury, but after the second injury, I started to think about whether this path would not be suitable for me.&quot; She told her mother that she wanted to go to school, but the coach felt it was a pity and rushed Come to persuade. After months of arduous recovery, she was able to return to competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2012 to 2013, Li Meng landed in the WCBA. In his rookie season, he averaged 14.7 points, 3.9 rebounds and 1.5 assists per game, and was awarded the Rookie of the Year. In the following years, she was always the top scorer in the WCBA. However, due to her personal characteristics of strong offense and weak defense, she missed the 12-man national team roster led by Maher and missed the 2016 Rio Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/B2KEJKf7PkXLw1WLrhShsBHJDFvy3Wu6Vv61me5s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;632&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/B2KEJKf7PkXLw1WLrhShsBHJDFvy3Wu6Vv61me5s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253079&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2022, in the 2022 Women&#39;s Basketball World Cup finals in Sydney, Australia, the Chinese team lost to the United States and won the runner-up. Chinese team player Li Meng took photos with fans after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the reason why Li Meng was eliminated, he was still a football player at the time Xu Limin, the team&#39;s assistant coach, explained, &quot;Because of Li Meng&#39;s defense (weakness), she was eliminated at the last minute of the Rio Olympic selection, which was a huge blow to her.&quot; Xu Limin was later promoted to the head coach of the women&#39;s basketball team. He specifically approached Li Meng to emphasize the defensive issue, &quot;If you want to be the world&#39;s top athlete, you must be both offensive and defensive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Meng took this advice to heart. By the time of the Tokyo Olympics, she had become an indispensable main player of the women&#39;s basketball team. She said, &quot;In the past, my physical strength may have been 50% on offense and defense, but now my physical strength on defense can reach 80%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because With her outstanding physical fitness and all-round performance on the court, Li Meng is called the &quot;LeBron Dream&quot; by fans, and LeBron James has been her idol for many years. &quot;His professionalism, technology, leadership, and psychological quality, He is a role model among players and I have been learning from him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/z3MVMri8BnHbR8sfbwcAdzgTJyMnaK6oKafkG00P. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/z3MVMri8BnHbR8sfbwcAdzgTJyMnaK6oKafkG00P.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;253080&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 2, 2023, in the 2023 Women&#39;s Basketball Asian Cup finals held in Sydney, Australia, the Chinese team won Defeated Japan 73-71 and won the championship. Chinese team player Li Meng (right) makes a layup during the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months ago, the Asian Cup final , it was still the Chinese team against the Japanese team, and the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team also won the championship with a two-point advantage, returning to the top of Asia. This is also the first time that the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team has won the Asian Cup after 12 years. Li Meng also contributed important goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At several important moments in Li Meng&#39;s 2023, she mentioned &quot;Always be the best version of yourself and never give up.&quot; We have reason to believe that she will uphold this belief and lead the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team to face the Paris Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：澎湃新闻、新华社、中新网、《新京报》等。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>