<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[大V控诉综艺节目装修“翻车”：普通人装修要踩多少坑？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260540]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The master stood in front of the door, and several dazzling haloes of light shone on the metal round door, and then, The door slides open to one side, and the owner steps in. The lights above his head light up in sequence with the owner&#39;s steps. In the middle of the room, there is a square box. The electric door of the square box opens automatically, revealing a private space equipped with a large-screen TV and a bed. The owner can rest here, watch movies and play games without being disturbed. The lights in the room can change color according to the mood of the owner. Sometimes it is bright white, and sometimes it turns to warm orange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who has ever dreamed of science fiction would want to own such a cool cyberpunk-style house. Well-known digital blogger Li Jieling is also one of them. Therefore, when he saw the designer&#39;s plan, he immediately decided to participate in the decoration variety show &quot;Miracle Renewal Home&quot; and spend more than one million to renovate his house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the design is beautiful, but it is not that easy to implement. Recently, Li Jieling posted on Weibo, complaining that the decoration was &quot;overturned&quot; and cost a huge amount of money, but it was far from achieving the results he expected. According to the articles, photos, videos and other information published by Li Jieling, as well as the contract he signed with the decorator, the electric door is 150,000 yuan, the lighting system is 185,000 yuan, and the black square device is 290,000 yuan, plus design fees, transportation and installation fees Waiting for miscellaneous charges, the total charge for these three major items is 730,000 yuan, plus the decoration in other places, the total cost exceeds one million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after spending such a large amount of money, we did not get very good results: the electric door only has a simple sliding function, and the promised cool effect was not realized at all; the electric door of the square box opened the door, stretched out the chair, etc. There are also many problems with the structure. Firstly, the gaps are too large to form a complete whole, and the appearance is not beautiful enough. Secondly, the operation is very slow and the sound is loud; only the lighting system can pass the test. Due to the huge gap with psychological expectations, Li Jieling finally refused to take over the house and continue to record the program, and asked the decorator and program owner to make rectifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been many programs on new house decoration and old house renovation, which have attracted many viewers. Many people like to watch house building and decoration programs, hoping to provide some inspiration for their own decoration, or simply to see how other people&#39;s homes look like when decorated. But this is not the first time Li Jieling has &quot;overturned&quot; and caused complaints. The last time that the internet went viral was the &quot;Million Dollar Red Brick House&quot; on the show &quot;Dream Renovator&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old man Du from rural Gansu Province hoped that the program team would help him transform his old house into a modern, western-style and exquisite small foreign-style building. As a result, a designer from Beijing designed the house into a &quot;red brick rough house&quot;. There are exposed red bricks and cement everywhere, as well as hollow brick walls. This cost more than 1.32 million. As soon as the program aired, it aroused strong complaints from netizens. However, some people defended the designer, believing that the designer&#39;s work is actually compatible with the environmental style of the northwest countryside, has considerable artistic quality, and has no problem with practicality. Du Laobo and netizens find it difficult to accept it. In fact, it is influenced by traditional concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe the designer has his own ideas, and this work is also very &quot;modern&quot;. However, when designing, constructing, and decorating, we receive money and are entrusted by others. Shouldn&#39;t we respect the client&#39;s ideas first? ? At the beginning of the design, the designer should communicate with the client in detail about the requirements. Even if the designer has his own ideas, he should obtain the client&#39;s understanding and consent during communication. He should not completely follow his own ideas and &quot;open the blind box&quot; for the client after the construction is completed. At that time, the work was done, and making changes would be a major undertaking, if not impossible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the situation Li Jieling encountered was different from that of Mr. Du. In Li Jieling&#39;s case, there was no problem with the design. In fact, Li Jieling agreed to participate in the show only after she was satisfied with the designer&#39;s plan. But what I didn&#39;t expect is that the ideal is plump, but the reality is very skinny. When the cool design is implemented in reality, not only the effect is greatly reduced, but even the basic beauty is difficult to achieve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the decoration program, the effect was not satisfactory, which attracted the attention of netizens and could be corrected. For example, the house of Mr. Du in Gansu received strong criticism after the program was broadcast. The program team responded that the renovation would continue to be improved and the program team would bear half of the renovation costs. Judging from the follow-up program that was broadcast later, the results after the transformation were quite acceptable. As for the situation Li Jieling encountered this time, because Li Jieling himself is a big V and has a strong influence on social media, he has the capital to bargain with the decorator and the program team. The other party currently agrees to complete the renovation before the Spring Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What should ordinary people do if they encounter such a situation? In reality, house decoration is really a matter of luck. The decoration market is a mixed bag, and homeowners often have to work hard to achieve satisfactory decoration results. Disputes arising from decoration quality are endless. How do ordinary people avoid pitfalls when decorating? Even if you choose a regular decoration company, the decoration company may outsource the specific work to the decoration team; even if you sign a decoration contract with clear agreements on the decoration effect, construction period, etc., and there are breach of contract clauses, all kinds of wrangling will inevitably happen. Li Jieling&#39;s experience further reflects the many pitfalls faced by ordinary people in decoration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿童肺炎支原体高发，囤积阿奇霉素不可取]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260550]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 10:07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[世界最大地下水漏斗补漏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/cbcc4f6c12.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 13/cbcc4f6c12.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A deactivated shallow water in Zhangzhuang Village, Nanpi County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province Weeds have grown over the well. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Linsong grinned, with two rows of yellow teeth clearly visible, &quot;Everyone knows which village we are from when we go out. The fluoride content in the groundwater is too high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High concentrations of fluoride can damage the ameloblasts of the tooth germ, causing the enamel to turn yellow. Wujiafang Village is located in Wumaying Town, Nanpi County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province. It entered the coverage of the East Route Project of South-to-North Water Diversion a few years ago. To drink &quot;Yangtze River water&quot;, the villagers no longer need to use yellow teeth as &quot;ID cards&quot;. A big lock is also hung on the deep machine well house in the village, which will only be used during the busy farming season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many Hebei villages, water from the Yellow River is used for farmland irrigation. The &quot;one reduction and one increase&quot; measure of reducing overexploitation of groundwater and increasing water supply through multiple channels is to control the groundwater funnel - a funnel-shaped concave surface formed by the large-scale exploitation of deep groundwater, the water level drops, and the surrounding groundwater flows toward the center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Groundwater funnels can cause ground subsidence, which can damage railways, buildings, underground pipelines, and even endanger embankment safety. Since the 1960s and 1970s, the &quot;Tianjin-Cangzhou-Hengshui-Dezhou Deep Composite Funnel&quot; has gradually connected into a piece, with the largest area in the world. According to an article published by Zhang Zhaoji and others from the Key Laboratory of Groundwater Science and Engineering of the Ministry of Natural Resources in 2022, the most serious plot in Cangzhou, located in the center of the funnel area, has sunk by a total of 2.5 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the Ministry of Water Resources and other four ministries and commissions issued the &quot;Action Plan for the Comprehensive Control of Groundwater Overexploitation in North China&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot; Action Plan&quot;&lt;/span>;), which proposed that by 2035, we will strive to fully achieve a balance of groundwater extraction and replenishment, and gradually fill the deficit of over-exploitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the Ministry of Water Resources announced at a press conference that through nearly five years of governance, the trend of year-by-year decline in groundwater levels has been fundamentally reversed, and the short-term goals of the &quot;Action Plan&quot; have been exceeded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in July 2023, Hebei Province’s 2022 annual audit work report (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the audit report&lt;/span>;) warned : 11 cities and 16 counties have problems such as water abstraction without a license, water abstraction exceeding the license, and slow progress in shutting down water intake wells; 6 cities and 2 counties have problems such as unfinished consumption of river water, and arrears of 3.175 billion yuan in South-to-North Water Diversion fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hebei’s agricultural water accounts for 55%, of which about 70% is used to irrigate winter wheat. Managing winter wheat irrigation well is the key to suppressing groundwater exploitation. Now is the season for winter wheat to be irrigated with overwintering water. Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that Hebei Province has strictly controlled new wells, shut down old wells, and actively transferred water in recent years. Behind the problems reported in the audit are difficulties in water intake supervision, lagging small water conservancy projects, and water shortages. Problems such as the backward payment system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Strictly control new wells&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wells are the connection between people and groundwater, but in Hebei, it is difficult to drill new wells. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country implements a water abstraction licensing system, and drilling wells requires approval. In 2017, Hebei designated prohibited/restricted mining areas. No new water wells are allowed to be dug in the prohibited mining areas, and hierarchical approval is required in the restricted mining areas. In 2018, the &quot;Hebei Province Water Drawing License Management Measures&quot; was revised to transfer the approval authority for groundwater drawing licenses to the provincial level. In 2022, the restricted mining area will increase by more than 36,000 square kilometers, equivalent to 2.5 times the area of ​​Cangzhou City. Hebei also stipulates that when digging new wells in restricted mining areas, &quot;1 minus 2&quot; must be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the purpose of drilling a well is only for personal use, the policy still leaves a loophole. The &quot;Hebei Province Water Drawing Permit Management Measures&quot; stipulates that units or individuals who draw small amounts of water for household purposes and scattered free-range or captive livestock and poultry for drinking are exempt from applying for a water drawing permit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to understand this category? When Southern Weekend reporters inquired about drilling wells in a personal capacity, Peng Ping, a staff member of the water resources department of a water conservancy department in Hebei Province, explained that there are two main requirements: first, the wells should only be used for personal use and not for business purposes; second, do not drill. It&#39;s too deep, &quot;even if it&#39;s twenty or thirty meters away,&quot; it cannot touch the deep water layer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deep water generally refers to the water below the aquiclude layer, which is a rock formation with extremely weak water permeability. Shallow groundwater can be replenished through surface water systems, but deep groundwater is generally buried more than 50 meters deep and replenishes slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to dig a deep water well, &quot;you need the approval of the county government, and then report it to the city and provincial governments in turn.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the water license approval ledger regularly published by the Hebei Provincial Department of Water Resources and found that 50 or 60 companies were approved within two days, and the vast majority were companies, factories, schools and other legal entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under heavy pressure, some people still take risks. The audit report reported that there is a problem of unlicensed water abstraction in some areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late September, Southern Weekend reporters consulted more than a dozen well-drilling teams in the Cangzhou area and surrounding areas about drilling wells. A well-drilling worker in Langfang claimed that he was providing water to some chemical plants in Langfang that did not have water extraction licenses. Drilled a well. Another well-drilling worker in Tianjin also said that when he digs wells for customers, he does not ask them to show their water permission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Closing old wells&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to strictly controlling new wells, Hebei has also begun to close or reduce water production for old wells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wangjiakou Village, Chenzui Township, Qingxian County, Cangzhou, Southern Weekend reporters found a locked red brick well house with an area of ​​more than ten square meters. A shiny sign was nailed to the outer wall: Shut down the well. Private activation is strictly prohibited. Through the holes in the iron door, one can see the electricity meter and gate on the brick wall, as well as the wellhead where the pump is installed on the ground. The wires have accumulated a thick layer of dust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/f9b8547100.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/f9b8547100.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In late September 2023, the door of a deep motor-shaft well house in Wangjiakou Village was locked, and the scene inside the room could still be seen through the small hole in the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the vast farmland outside the well house, there is a red iron &quot;fire hydrant&quot; every other section of the road - this was once the outlet of underground pipes, which transported deep well water It was transported from the well house to the field and is now abandoned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Hebei Daily&quot; report, as of the end of August 2022, more than 230,000 water wells have been shut down in the province, including urban domestic and industrial water wells and rural domestic water wells in the South-to-North Water Diversion receiving areas. According to the 2023 Hebei Provincial Water Conservancy Work Conference, by the end of 2022, the comprehensive management tasks of 5.97 billion cubic meters of groundwater overexploitation in Hebei Province have been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a county in southern Cangzhou, a staff member of the agricultural department told Southern Weekend reporters that there were originally more than 9,000 wells in the county, but now the deep wells have been sealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even so, the audit report still pointed out that the closure of water wells has been slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Hebei Province Groundwater Management Regulations&quot;, in the deep groundwater funnel area, agricultural irrigation wells that draw deep groundwater must also be shut down as planned. However, Southern Weekend reporters saw that there are still many villages that rely on deep water wells, and the closure period is unknown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of September, Wu Linsong was watering the bottom moisture needed before sowing winter wheat. Southern Weekend reporters saw that sections of yellow plastic floor cages were assembled into a long pipe of tens of meters. One end was connected to a red faucet at the edge of the field, and the other end was flowing with clear groundwater. Wu Linsong adjusts the position of the water outlet from time to time to irrigate along the diagonal line of the field. More than 70 kilometers away, Jinliuzhuang Village, Qingzhou Town, Qing County, Cangzhou City, is also using deep machine-driven wells for irrigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a3ca232ea3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a3ca232ea3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Linsong’s fields are still irrigated with groundwater. To do this, he needed to lay dozens of meters of yellow ground cages and constantly move heavy pipes. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Peng Ping explained that deep machine wells are currently closed seasonally. If there is water in the river that can be used when farming, you cannot use the water from the well. Otherwise, you can use the water from the well. &quot;There will be no hard shutdown.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those water wells dug illegally, their concealment makes supervision more difficult. Excluding the house and electricity meter, the above-ground construction part of the deepwater well is not large, and the height of the pump is less than knee-high. Shallow wells are even more inconspicuous, with their mouths not as wide as city manhole covers and only ankle-high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a water conservancy bureau in a county in Hebei Province said that the grassroots water conservancy department is limited by establishment and does not have sufficient manpower. Sometimes there are only about 40 people in the water affairs bureau at the county level, and only a small part of them are involved in water administrative law enforcement. They can only go to the fields from time to time to inspect the sealing and water withdrawal status of wells, and whether there is a water withdrawal permit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insufficient capillaries and difficulty in digestion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In farmers’ perception, warm river water is more suitable for irrigating fields than cold groundwater. For example, Wang Gui, a villager in Wangjiakou Village, Qingxian County, feels that the corn cobs produced this year are indeed longer than last year. However, Wang Gui couldn&#39;t tell whether it was because water from the Yellow River had been diverted into the dry river in recent years or because of increased precipitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a07e37bd49.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a07e37bd49.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Hebei, a drought-ridden country with little rainfall, the amount of watering directly affects crop growth. The corn field on the left side of the sweet potato field is irrigated normally and is growing well; the corn field on the right side is stunted because the owner of the field goes out to work and relies on the sky for water. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hebei Province Water Resources Bulletin&quot; shows that in 2022, Hebei Province&#39;s cross-basin water diversion volume reached 4.128 billion cubic meters, accounting for 22.6% of the total water supply. According to Southern Weekend reporters, in rural Hebei, the &quot;Yangtze River water&quot; from the South-to-North Water Diversion mainly replaces domestic water, while most of the river water extracted for irrigation is diverted from the Yellow River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most farmers are in favor of closing wells if they can use nearly free river water for irrigation. The China Rural Research Institute of Tsinghua University once surveyed 270 farmers in Hengshui, Hebei Province, on their evaluation of groundwater overexploitation control measures. For the measures of filling and sealing wells, the farmers&#39; favorable rate was only 61%; but for the South-to-North Water Diversion Project and the Yellow River Water Diversion, the favorable rate was only 61%. As high as 91% and 95% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of diverting water from the Yellow River is lower than that from the Yangtze River, only a few cents per cubic meter at the end of the field. A staff member of the agricultural department of a county in Cangzhou also told Southern Weekend reporters that the county government will transfer water unplanned for irrigation in 2024. This transaction was led by the water conservancy department and paid by the county finance, costing millions of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that many villages still cannot use external water for irrigation. The main reason is the lack of water conservancy facilities to divert water to the fields, even if the river is just a few kilometers away from the village. The terrain of some villages is one or two meters higher than the surrounding areas, and water from the surrounding water systems cannot be diverted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/69b364a145.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/69b364a145.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the fields of Wangjiakou Village, the corn has just been harvested, leaving a bare land waiting for wheat to be sown. A red cast iron faucet stands on its own, connected to the deep shaft not far away. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Qing, a groundwater research expert at an institute affiliated to the Ministry of Water Resources, explained that Hebei’s rural areas are vast and there are no ready-made urban water conservancy facilities like Beijing and Tianjin. Han Qing compared rivers, ditches and ponds in rural areas to &quot;capillaries&quot; in the last mile. &quot;When external water is transferred to some areas with flat or high terrain, supporting pipe network projects must be provided to supply it. Provincial and county governments must Everyone has to invest, and it won’t be possible for several years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of building rural water conservancy projects is not small. Public information shows that in Qing County, Cangzhou alone, nearly 100 million yuan will be invested in water conservancy projects related to the comprehensive management of groundwater overexploitation in 2023, including channel dredging, reconstruction of water culverts, and new control valves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Finances at all levels are very difficult now, and it would be good to be able to pay wages.&quot; Du Yun, head of the water affairs department of a county in Hebei Province, said, &quot;There is really no way to complete all the water diversion projects at once. We can only Do our best to improve.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For farmers who cannot use water from the Yellow River, can they use the &quot;Yangtze River water&quot; from the South-to-North Water Diversion in their home tap pipes for irrigation? This alternative would be prohibitively expensive and currently not a possibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Jiansheng, former director of the Institute of Hydrogeology and Environmental Geology of the Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters that the fundamental reason why some areas still rely on groundwater is that the cost of replacement surface water sources is too high. &quot;According to current cost calculations, the cost of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project to reach the irrigation plots in the central and eastern Hebei Plain is as high as 5-6 yuan per cubic meter. The cost of water use is impossible to bear unless the government provides high water source replacement subsidies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The cost of water from the South-to-North Water Diversion Project is much higher than that of water diversion from the Yellow River, and local governments are not active in consuming it. A report from the Audit Office shows that 6 cities and 2 counties have unfinished tasks of absorbing river water and are in arrears with water fees of 3.175 billion yuan for the South-to-North Water Diversion Project. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Accurate measurement, say goodbye to flood irrigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether it is groundwater or external water transfer, many experts believe that moderate charging of water fees can cultivate farmers&#39; awareness of water conservation and can also provide support for construction and maintenance. Provide funding for rural water conservancy projects. However, water fee pricing needs to be cautious to ensure food security, take into account farmers&#39; affordability, and not increase agricultural production costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Wenlai, a researcher at the Institute of Agricultural Resources and Agricultural Zoning of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, said, &quot;Agricultural water prices are higher based on full cost, which is difficult for farmers to accept. Even if they are charged based on maintenance costs, they still face difficulties. This cost The burden should be reasonably shared by the state, local governments and farmers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without accurate measurement, there is no rigorous water price system. Water charges for urban residents generally include water resources charges, water company costs and sewage treatment charges, which are measured through water meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most farmers in Hebei still have unclear accounts of their irrigation water consumption. For the use of groundwater, it is common to convert electricity bills into water bills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/bdadd4bd45.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/bdadd4bd45.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In a well house in a village, villagers take the meter counts of their own water usage to settle their electricity bills. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are seven or eight deep machine-operated wells in Wujiafang Village, and Wu Shucai is the manager of two of them. Villagers called him when they wanted to irrigate, and he went to the telephone pole outside the well house and wrote down the numbers on the electric meter. The old and new figures are subtracted to determine the villagers&#39; electricity consumption, which is then converted into electricity bills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the basis of normal electricity prices, some villages will &quot;increase the price&quot; to subsidize the personnel who manage the wells. Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that the electricity charges for water wells in each village are different, ranging from 0.31 to 1 yuan per kilowatt hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using groundwater requires paying electricity bills, while using surface water is almost free. Villagers don’t even know whether the water they use comes from thousands of miles away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Gui did some calculations and found out that irrigating the ground with well water is billed according to the electricity consumption of deep wells. The price of electricity per kilowatt hour is 1-1.5 yuan. The water cost for growing one acre of wheat is It costs more than one hundred yuan. He spent more than 1,000 yuan to buy a diesel pump. The cost of pumping water from the river was only about 2 yuan in gas money, which was almost negligible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/d3c25b3f0b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/d3c25b3f0b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;With the diesel pump, Wang Gui pumps water from the river for irrigation at almost free cost. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some rural areas have begun to try metering. Water meters are installed on the water wells in Nansong Village, Lugongbao Town, Renqiu City, and the water conservancy department can remotely monitor whether anyone is secretly taking water. The village party secretary of Nansong Village told Southern Weekend reporters that during severe droughts, the villagers can apply to the water conservancy department for temporary use of motorized wells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Peng Ping’s view, establishing an accurate metering system will help the water conservancy department grasp more accurate water consumption. &quot;In the past, it was all estimated. For example, 50 cubic meters of water was used to water one acre of land, and then the estimate was based on the area of ​​cultivated land. But if it had just rained, you might have only poured 40 cubic meters of water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Shi Jianshe reminded that the installation of metering devices was based on Beijing’s experience, and the long-term effects may not be ideal. “Wellhead metering measures require large investments and are difficult to maintain. If farmers do not understand them, they will cause a lot of damage.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Beijing announced that it would implement metering and charging for 30,000 agricultural wells in the city within three years. In June 2023, the Beijing Municipal Water Affairs Bureau held an open tender for &quot;Construction of Agricultural and Rural Water Use Control and Standardized Management Models for Different Purposes&quot;. The purpose was to solve the problems of vulnerable, broken, stolen and inaccurate measurement of agricultural water metering facilities. Supplement and improve agricultural water use statistics and improve the level of agricultural irrigation water supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Jianshi suggested that the implementation of accurate wellhead metering can overcome the idea of ​​flood irrigation, and should be gradually promoted on the basis of the stable operation of the pilot, such as reasonable water use with subsidies and no charges, special water use with moderate charges, and wasteful use of water. High charges for sexual water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/14b3e5248a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/14b3e5248a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the China Agricultural University Experimental Station in Wuqiao County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province, Professor Wang Zhimin began researching water-saving agriculture in the 1980s. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, Han Qing has been paying attention to groundwater levels in Hebei. After analyzing the data from thousands of observation sites, he gave an extremely positive evaluation: &quot;The mining volume has decreased significantly, and the deep water has basically shown a rebound trend. Due to the hysteresis of land subsidence, the subsidence has not stopped, but the degree is also gradually increasing. Reduced. Generally speaking, the management of groundwater overexploitation areas is moving in a good direction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shijian Province reminds that after the balance of groundwater extraction and replenishment is achieved in the future, groundwater will not be unusable at all, and the water level will be restored. It may lead to secondary salinization, urban underground engineering immersion and other problems. It is necessary to reasonably and appropriately arrange the extraction and utilization of groundwater according to the needs of suitable water level control to maintain the optimal groundwater level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Wu Linsong, Wang Gui, Peng Ping, Han Qing, and Du Yun are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[县中振兴的真问题是什么？ | 议教]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On April 22, 2011, Book Exchange Station of Zouping County Experimental Middle School, Shandong. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6ad2e9f377.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6ad2e9f377.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;April 22, 2011, Book Exchange Station of Zouping Experimental Middle School, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;County subsidence is one of the core issues in the field of basic education in recent times. For example, Professor Lin Xiaoying of Peking University&#39;s &quot;Children in the County—— The book &quot;China&#39;s County Education Ecology&quot; paints this picture: College entrance examination scores have seriously declined, high-quality students have disappeared, and the teaching team is aging... Counties that were once an important link in the upward mobility channel for children from poor families have been unable to perform as expected. As a result, the desolation of education in the county has become a spreading reality, and the county is like a hometown that has bid farewell, becoming a relic of the new urban middle class who have completed individual urbanization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I am ashamed to say that during the years when I devoted myself to serving basic education schools, I visited some counties, but I was not aware of the sharp social issue of &quot;county collapse&quot;. problem, but not much in-depth understanding. For example, a certain county in Shandong Province that I once served relied on its rising admission rate and even continued to export students from Qingbei, challenging the &quot;big boss&quot; in the region and province year after year. Not only is it not a &quot;collapse&quot;, but on the contrary, it has soared in the local basic education rankings - often real estate self-media or parents&#39; actual word-of-mouth. It is eventually called a &quot;counterattack&quot; by the education industry media and is considered to have achieved A perfect transformation from a county high school located in the suburbs to a &quot;modern school well-known in Qilu and going nationwide.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;You can even read comments like this on social media, talking about an interesting phenomenon in Shandong: enterprising children from urban families often try their best to The solution is to go back and study in the county. Campus life is very rich. &quot;It is not a college entrance examination factory. There are many sports teams, cultural festivals, and art societies, and it has also cultivated many competition experts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, as mentioned in the comments, those who try their best to return to the county may not necessarily be &quot;enterprising children&quot;, but more likely to be &quot;enterprising children&quot;. Enterprising parents.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The factors of the general environment are well known: social urbanization drives educational urbanization, and due to the innate Confucian emphasis on education genes in the East Asian cultural circle, once educational urbanization begins, Its speed must be much ahead of social urbanization. So we see this phenomenon: children from rural areas enter the county, and children from the county town enter the city. The county town between the countryside and the city, among the counties that have created a large number of miracles after the reform and opening up, has lost its aura in the new historical changes. Furthermore, the pivotal value of urban-rural conversion and class crossing has gradually been lost. The process of this underlying logic manifesting itself in reality is reflected in the collapse of the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Children in the County&quot;, written by Lin Xiaoying, Shanghai People&#39;s Publishing House, July 2023.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/732705cbef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 13/732705cbef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Children in the County&quot;, written by Lin Xiaoying, Shanghai People&#39;s Publishing House , July 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, in this process of urbanization transformation, there will also be a phenomenon of &quot;counter-urbanization&quot; that rises against the trend: some former counties Expanded into a super school. The former county school mentioned earlier has also emerged as an educational group that can challenge the provincial government and has several branch schools, covering both public and private systems. In fact, the counties that I have visited and served often have the following two characteristics: balanced distance and extreme county mode. The so-called equilibrium distance means that these rising counties are often not far or close to the central city of the central city, or they themselves were once suburban counties of the central city and later became the suburbs of the city. The Ultimate County High School model refers to taking the model from the glory days of the early County High School to the extreme: after competing for high-quality students, using extreme exam-oriented methods, suppressing one&#39;s nature and gaining the psychological motivation to live toward death in order to succeed in the college entrance examination. But this psychological dynamic is often accompanied by strong feelings of resentment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is why some students from super middle schools think of themselves as typical examples of children from poor families. Even though urbanization transformation has been achieved, the ideology of these schools still remains at the county level. Through the confrontation between urban and rural areas, the bottom class and the elite, they have obtained the rationality and motivational support resources to inherit and complete the county education model. . I still remember the famous saying of a student from Hengshui Middle School: &quot;I am just a native pig from the countryside, but I am determined to conquer the cabbage in the big city.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;But this classmate, who regarded himself as a local pig, was picked up by his father in an Audi private car during the vacation. In those &quot;rising counties&quot;, there is also a question mark as to how many children are from the counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rising counties started with extremely exam-oriented education. After completing primitive accumulation, they began to enter a more diversified development. Even in the face of the new college entrance examination reform, the resources and capital they have are enough to cope with this change. They can even use this as an opportunity to achieve secondary development and complete the complete transformation from rural civilization to urban civilization - the transformation is completed. The sign may be that in the future, on social platforms such as Zhihu, graduates from these schools will no longer lament that after reaching university, there is still a gap between them and students who graduated from the real cities such as Xingshi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, behind the rise of super-secondary counties is often the decline of one century-old county after another. This is the real dilemma of county education. Wang Xinfeng, from the China Education Policy Research Institute at Beijing Normal University, pointed out in the keynote report &quot;County Dilemmas from the Perspective of Access to Higher Education Opportunities&quot; that at present, high-quality students, teachers and other educational resources are gradually gathering in central cities, and the gap in high school education resources continues to widen. , in some areas, the decline in the quality of higher education in counties has become an inevitable trend. This will not only have an impact on the county&#39;s education ecology and social governance pattern, but also explicitly and implicitly exclude access to higher education opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many of the expectations given to the county today are related to our social development stage: after entering the 1980s, the start of China&#39;s urbanization process provided the county with brilliant opportunities possible, but this brilliance diminished with the arrival of the next stage of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We might as well extend the timeline longer. Andrew Byron Kipnis, professor of the Department of Anthropology at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, in his book &quot;Desire for Governance Education&quot; describes Zouping, Shandong: Like other places in China, Zouping experienced shocking political ruptures in the 20th century. The end of the Qing Dynasty, the beginning of the Republic of China, the Japanese invasion, and the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party. Amidst all the ruptures, education showed the continued development of On the one hand, basic education has developed steadily - eliminating illiteracy, first by universalizing six years of primary education, and later by nine years of compulsory education. Although education developed most rapidly in the 1950s and 1970s, education also improved as early as the early 1930s during the rural construction movement promoted by Liang Shuming and others in Zouping. The institutional foundation for the popularization of education was laid even as early as the Republic of China. Finally, after more than half a century of continuous efforts, in January 1995, Zouping achieved two basic goals: nine-year compulsory education, and the elimination of illiteracy among the population under the age of 45. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, in the current discussion of the collapse of many counties, what does it mean to revitalize the county? Is it going back to the peak of the county in the 1980s and 1990s, or even earlier, to become a high point where the cultural context of the place condenses? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, the real problem in the revitalization of the county is not the county itself, but more importantly, the importance of the county&#39;s social ecology and educational ecology in the process of historical change. Shape and coordinate. At the same time, as an important part of social governance, how to achieve good governance in education under a deterministic new value scale is probably the real issue in the revitalization of the county. Specifically, this kind of &quot;good governance&quot;, as summarized by Wang Xinfeng, firstly requires adhering to the system concept, clarifying the characteristics of the social development stage, and re-examining county development issues under the strategic goals of common prosperity and new urbanization; secondly, it must improve education Allocate resources, strengthen comprehensive management of education, and ensure a fair starting point for county middle school students to obtain higher education opportunities on the basis of high-quality development; third, continue to deepen the reform of the examination and enrollment system, expand the implementation scope of special plans, and ensure that county middle school students have higher education in the college admissions process. Equity in educational opportunities and outcomes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The author used to be a college teacher and is now a basic education service practitioner&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[被砍掉又被续命，只因它是《万神殿》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260482]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Last year, AMC’s animated science fiction drama &quot;Yiban.io&quot; &quot;Temple&quot; detonated the entire Internet, and it still has a super high score of 8.8 on Douban, and even 100% unanimous praise on the Rotten Tomatoes website. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just when the majority of drama fans were eagerly awaiting the second season, the show was not well-received and had poor ratings. AMC, which was already financially weak, decided to cancel the sequel. Fortunately, Amazon took over and injected funds to continue the production of the second season, allowing &quot;Pantheon&quot; to be fully concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that the second season is online, it is immediately popular, with an opening score of 9.3, making it the strongest animated show this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d51400ace003e248fe55a2a3fc03381a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;469&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d51400ace003e248fe55a2a3fc03381a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Before analyzing the second season, let us first review the science fiction setting and story background of the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core concept of &quot;Pantheon&quot; is &quot;upload intelligence&quot;, referred to as &quot;UI&quot;. The technology company in the play uploads signal data to the network through precise scanning of neurons in the human brain to generate upload intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from AI tools such as &quot;ChatGPT&quot; that we are familiar with, to a certain extent, uploaded intelligence can be regarded as a brand new life form, but it gets rid of the physical body and travels in the online world with pure consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/638c91e580c26315f242bd7f1075d532.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/638c91e580c26315f242bd7f1075d532.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Season 1 In it, David, the father of the heroine Mandy, uploaded his neuron signals to the Internet before his death, becoming the earliest uploaded intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Indian engineer Chanda and genius girl Laurie have become uploading intelligence. However, their positions are completely opposite. Chanda wants to expand the world of uploaded intelligence in an extreme way; Laurie is a defender of the real world and wants to join forces with David to resist Chanda&#39;s conspiracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5b528a262c1e05d1d08171f2c5e1296c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5b528a262c1e05d1d08171f2c5e1296c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Season 1 In the end, David sacrificed himself to preserve human society, but what followed was a global disconnection, and governments around the world were afraid of the unlimited capabilities of uploaded intelligence. Not only that, due to the &quot;integrity defect&quot;, the uploaded intelligence itself is also very unstable, and may completely die as its energy continues to decay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to solving the problem falls on the hero Caspian. This is a cloned boy who grew up in design just like Truman in &quot;The Truman Show&quot;. Caspian&#39;s identity is Steve, the founder of the technology giant company &quot;Algorithm Beat&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/633fef39cf5c0fa88f9507f9f04beeca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/633fef39cf5c0fa88f9507f9f04beeca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258028&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, no. At the beginning of the second season, two major conflicts emerged. One is that public protests continue, and they believe that the crisis caused by Upload Smart is just a cover, demanding that the government immediately restore the network; the other is that the government still intends to use Upload Smart for its own use, but must address its own shortcomings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the “safe browsing” software launched by the government has become a prerequisite for people to access the Internet. To put it bluntly, this is an anti-virus software that specifically hunts upload intelligence; as for Caspian, with the help of Mandy, he solved the core problem of &quot;integrity defect&quot; and made the upload intelligence truly immortal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/079b5ca53d39aefa7f1a68cdff536a74.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/079b5ca53d39aefa7f1a68cdff536a74.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258029&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, The focus of the first season of &quot;Pantheon&quot; was on uploading intelligence&#39;s confusion about self-identity and the complex situation of ethical relationships. In the second season, the depth of thinking and critical consciousness displayed in the series are much broader and deeper. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the issue of &quot;integrity defects&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as more than ten years ago, the extremely smart Steve had actually understood everything about uploading intelligence, and even ordered his subordinates to freeze and seal his brain, starting a cloning project, with the purpose of cultivating intelligence. Caspian, let him solve the problem that he can&#39;t do anything about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/df2b3aafe8aa8eb9f8e8c5459044fa69.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/df2b3aafe8aa8eb9f8e8c5459044fa69.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to history Tiff has the same brain circuit, so Caspian cannot easily break through the mental prison. The most interesting thing about the episode is that it uses Mandy&#39;s words to inspire Caspian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Mandy&#39;s view, &quot;others&quot; are the reason why we are where we are today as a human species, and the reason why we live and die. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it more simply, we do not live for ourselves, but become uneven and colorful because of external driving forces. The richness of human nature does not depend on one&#39;s own cultivation and growth, but on the instantaneous changes around us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c86caf40a7d0894d876aa8cf5ad522f1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c86caf40a7d0894d876aa8cf5ad522f1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, when When Caspian analyzed David&#39;s raw data, he realized that concern for his daughter constituted a necessary factor for David to be a complete soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is actually similar to the setting of the first season. The reason why David, Chanda and Laurie, unlike other experimenters, have self-awareness is because they came into contact with their family and loved ones. . Emotion bridges the shortcomings of reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5cf3f9aa69ed948b2eb5caaa0d6265a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5cf3f9aa69ed948b2eb5caaa0d6265a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another character in the play A setting worth chewing is Mandy’s “sister” Misty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fog is neither AI (artificial intelligence) nor UI (upload intelligence), but CI (cloud intelligence). It sounds a bit convoluted, but it&#39;s actually not difficult to understand. AI is an intelligent agent created by humans; UI is the life form of human consciousness; and CI is a new existence that UI reproduces in the online world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Misty claims to be Mandy&#39;s sister is because she was automatically generated from David and Laurie&#39;s data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/b21304b07717bd09eb69cddc6a6551a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;603&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/b21304b07717bd09eb69cddc6a6551a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mandy knows After this situation, it is difficult to accept. After all, does mist count as a living thing? It is difficult to define. Even if it is regarded as a living body, if a stranger suddenly comes to Mandy and recognizes her, how should the latter treat it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of imaginative ethical setting has almost never appeared in previous film and television works. It not only explores the essence of life, but also asks: Does family ties originate from blood relatives, or does it rely on memory and emotion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pantheon&quot; does not deal with this topic perfunctorily, but tells us the mixed feelings in family relationships through the fierce conflict between Mandy and Misty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f4ad6918b09f6a1493ac0c728419a1c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f4ad6918b09f6a1493ac0c728419a1c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Mandy When she placed all her hopes on Misty, hoping that she could defeat Steve, the latter used a set of logical and rigorous arguments to convince Misty. Mandy was very angry about this, and even yelled out that Misty was not her sister at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that Miwu left angrily and even ignored Mandy in anger for a long time proved her &quot;humanity&quot; from the side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that human beings will feel sad because of the past, but because Misty has no past, she will only feel lonely and lonely about the future. This kind of psychological detail with great speculative significance may be the reason why the drama &quot;Pantheon&quot; often makes our souls tremble and make us realize something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/57ba95a043a940eb29344ced252608ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/57ba95a043a940eb29344ced252608ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, The content and themes of the first six episodes are still at the level of binary opposition, that is, the game between the &quot;human faction&quot; represented by Mandy and Caspian, and the &quot;upload intelligence faction&quot; represented by Steve, then The last two episodes completely exceeded the psychological expectations of fans of the drama, crossing over to bold assumptions about the future world in sociology, politics, psychology and other levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Steve was defeated, the technology of uploading intelligence has not stopped. Just twenty years after Caspian and Steve &quot;died together&quot;, a total of four billion people around the world were uploaded from real society to cyberspace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the reasons why people choose this path are not forced by impending death, but the inevitable result of the rapid increase in productivity and the subsequent changes in production relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/31c9e6070343239a4e00136afdd8dee9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;603&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/31c9e6070343239a4e00136afdd8dee9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Upload smart user The least time cost, the most work tasks can be completed, so in the real society, &quot;the living people are gradually being robbed of their jobs by the dead.&quot; When death becomes immortality, and freedom and wealth become available without any effort, human beings will no longer pity the physical body but yearn for the virtual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this relationship is fluid. When we follow Caspian&#39;s perspective and quickly understand the changes in the past two decades, we will find that no matter what time it is, hostility, war, and ideological division will always exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second season of &quot;Pantheon&quot;, like a science fiction accelerator with continuous brainstorming, takes us to imagine the &quot;earth past&quot; that is very likely to happen in the future, and allows love and family relationships to develop over decades and on. In the long span of hundreds to hundreds of thousands of years, incredible flavors are fermented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/12f8e61ae80a884e517ccee74c55ab85.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/12f8e61ae80a884e517ccee74c55ab85.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality , a piece of profound data shows that as of January 2021, more than 500 people around the world have been cryogenically sealed, and more than 3,000 wealthy people have registered for cryogenic projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will this group of people, like the uploaded intelligence in &quot;Pantheon&quot;, become the first batch of &quot;network immigrants&quot; in the metaverse in the future? Perhaps the distance between reality and the world of science fiction has long exceeded our imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国肥胖地图出炉：南方人靠会吃比北方人瘦？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257304]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;China Obesity Map&quot; was released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the largest study to date on the prevalence of overweight and obesity and related complications in China. According to the BMI classification standard for obesity in my country, the proportion of obese people is 13.7%. The top five provinces with obesity in the country are: Hebei (21.9%), Inner Mongolia (19.8%), Shandong (19.7%), Tianjin (19.6%), Liaoning ( 18.2%). Compared with northern provinces and cities, the obesity rate in southern provinces is lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Where does the obesity difference between North and South come from? The &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents (2022)&quot; defines the eating habits of Fujian, Guangdong and other regions as &quot;Oriental healthy dietary patterns&quot;. This model has the characteristics of high food diversity, relatively light diet, sufficient intake of fresh vegetables and fruits, relatively high intake of fish and shrimp, low intake of pork, etc., and enhanced intake of milk and legumes. , resulting in a higher overall meal quality compliance rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with the lighter eating habits in the south, northern cuisine is more flavorful and pays attention to both color, flavor and flavor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, the increase in obesity rate is not only caused by &quot;eating&quot;. From the perspective of scientific research: obesity is determined by system dynamics factors and environmental determinants. This push is amplified or moderated by individual-level genetic susceptibility, psychosocial factors, obesogens and adverse early life exposures and other coexisting underlying risk factors, through unhealthy diet and lack of physical activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While paying attention to obesity, the topic #weightloss# often also attracts much attention. For example, on Douyin, Xiaohongshu, Weibo and other platforms, there are Videos and notes on the topic #weightloss# have been read more than 10 million times. Not only that, but various weight loss tools are also emerging in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obesity is also a &quot;fulcrum&quot; that drives various diseases. The World Health Organization report believes that overweight and obesity are important causes of high blood pressure. Among endocrine and metabolic diseases, the diabetes rate among overweight people is as high as 20.4%, which is 4 to 5 times higher than that among people with normal weight. Modern research has also proven that obese people are often accompanied by hyperinsulinemia, which may be the root cause of cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Healthy and scientific weight loss and exercise are very important. For your own health, &quot;Know&quot; tells you how to say &quot;goodbye&quot; to excess fat correctly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/a588b511f1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/a588b511f1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4926193e5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4926193e5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/c2a2877735.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/c2a2877735.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/1963d6ccc4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/1963d6ccc4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4b9bb6c400.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/21/4b9bb6c400.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/21/c2675d0556.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 21/c2675d0556.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 21/300577827d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/300577827d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[借转融通“绕道减持”的不只高瓴，沪深交易所紧急打补丁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 8 and November 10, 2023, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued multiple Guidelines for self-regulation. Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/426cfe432f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/426cfe432f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 8 and November 10, 2023, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued a number of self-regulatory guidelines. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The well-known investment institution Hillhouse Capital staged &quot;disappearing shares&quot; in A-shares, citing the China Securities Regulatory Commission to initiate an investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, 2023, LONGi Green Energy (601012.SH) announced that it was suspected of violating restrictive regulations by transferring LONGi Green Energy shares. In accordance with the Penalty Law and other laws and regulations, the China Securities Regulatory Commission decided to file a case against HHLR Management Co., Ltd., a shareholder of Longi Green Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HHLR Management Co., Ltd.-China Value Fund (hereinafter referred to as HHLR) is an investment management company under Hillhouse Capital focusing on the secondary market. It was formerly known as Hillhouse Capital Management Co., Ltd.-China Value Fund Trading (hereinafter referred to as Hillhouse Asset Management). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March, HHLR, the major shareholder holding 5.85% of Longi Green Energy, lent 1% of its shares through two refinancings. However, after the maturity and return, HHLR’s shareholding dropped by 0.87% compared with before the loan. gap. The market suspects that HHLR reduced its holdings during the refinancing period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not only HHLR, but also many shareholders of listed companies have quietly reduced their shareholdings to less than 5% after refinancing. It’s just that Hillhouse Capital, as a star investment institution, has attracted a lot of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulatory response was rapid. On November 8 and 10, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued a number of self-regulatory guidelines aimed at patching the above vulnerabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Disappeared Shares&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;HHLR&#39;s shares were originally transferred from LONGi Green Energy&#39;s major shareholders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 19, 2020, Li Chunan, the major shareholder of Longi Green Energy, transferred 6% of his shares to Hillhouse Asset Management at a price of 70 yuan per share. The total transaction consideration was approximately 15.84 billion yuan. . Li Chunan is the concerted person acting in concert with the actual controllers of LONGi Co., Ltd. Li Zhenguo and Li Xiyan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the alumni news of Lanzhou University, LONGi Green Energy was co-founded by three classmates from the physics department of Lanzhou University in 1986 - Li Zhenguo, Zhong Baoshen, and Li Chunan. It was named after the old president Jiang Longji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the first trading day after the transfer announcement, LONGi Green Energy opened sharply and closed at the daily limit. Subsequently, LONGi redeemed its convertible bonds, the total share capital increased, and Hillhouse Asset Management&#39;s shareholding was diluted to 5.85%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 21, 2023, Longi Green Energy issued the &quot;Informative Announcement Regarding Shareholders&#39; Participation in the Refinancing Securities Lending Business and Equity Changes&quot;, stating that the renamed Hillhouse Asset Management, or HHLR, participated in the refinancing. Rongtong Securities Lending Business lends 0.85% of its shares with a term of 182 days. It plans to continue lending no more than 0.15% of its shares in the next 90 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Margin financing is when investors ask brokers to borrow money to buy stocks or borrow stocks to sell. However, brokers’ own funds and securities sources are limited, so refinancing has emerged, including refinancing and refinancing. Vouchers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The refinancing business in mainland China began in 2013. China Securities Finance Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as CSI Financial), as the counterparty to securities lending transactions, is the only domestic financial institution engaged in refinancing business. Its shareholders include the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, refinancing business means that CSI Financial lends its own funds or funds raised through the issuance of bonds to securities companies, and then the securities companies lend it to customers for them to buy and list. Company stock. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Securities refinancing business means that CSI Financial borrows securities from &quot;lenders&quot; such as shareholders of listed companies, and then refinances them to securities companies, which provide them to customers for sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the securities refinancing business that Hillhouse Asset Management participates in, CSI Financial first borrows circulating securities from the shareholders of Longi Green Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Longi Green Energy did not disclose the specific time for lending 0.15% of HHLR shares. However, its first quarter report for 2023 shows that HHLR’s shareholding has dropped to 4.85%, which means that HHLR participated in two refinancings within 10 days at the end of March. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also not disclosed when the shares loaned by HHLR will expire. Based on the time of its participation in refinancing and the 182-day lending period, it can be inferred that the 1% of shares lent by HHLR should be returned no later than September 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, LONGi Green Energy’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that HHLR’s shareholding is only 4.98%, which is 0.87% lower than the 5.89% shareholding before participating in refinancing. HHLR also did not disclose the reasons why its holdings decreased during the period when the shares were loaned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Disclosure of Listed Companies&quot; and other relevant regulations, when shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares change, they should proactively inform the board of directors of the listed company and cooperate with the listed company in fulfilling its information disclosure obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, LONGi Green Energy stated in the relevant announcement of HHLR refinancing in March that the shares were not registered under the name of the information disclosure obligor (HHLR) during the loan period, and “after the completion of this equity change, information disclosure The obligor shall no longer be a shareholder holding more than 5% of the shares of the listed company.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market generally believes that HHLR has circumvented the letter disclosure requirements for shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares through refinancing, thus achieving a &quot;detour reduction&quot;. Based on LONGi Green Energy’s current stock price of 23 yuan per share, HHLR has a floating loss of approximately 5.6 billion yuan compared with the time of purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter sent an interview letter to Hillhouse’s official email, asking whether he had reduced his shareholding during the refinancing period, and under which regulations he was determined to no longer hold more than 5% of the shares of Longi Green Energy. Shareholders have not received a reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not an isolated case&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For a long time, the securities lending business developed slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report of the Shanghai Securities Fund Evaluation and Research Center shows that as of April 30, 2020, the balance of margin financing and securities lending was 1.0431 billion yuan, accounting for 2.16% of the circulating market value of A-shares, of which the financing balance was 1.0216 billion yuan. Accounting for 97.9% of the total, insufficient securities sources are one of the main obstacles limiting the development of the securities lending market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to expand the source of securities, in 2019 and 2020, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges successively included qualified institutional investors such as public funds, social security funds, and insurance funds, as well as strategic investors participating in the issuer’s initial public offering. Include lenders and participate in securities lending on the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued relevant systems for the full implementation of the registration system, and extended the optimization measures for refinancing securities on the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM to the main board, further liberalizing the refinancing business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no express provision, during the period of participation in refinancing, the relevant shares are generally not registered in the name of the lender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of CSI Financial, the refinancing securities lending business does not constitute a substantive securities transfer. If equity distribution occurs during the securities lending period, CSI Financial will compensate the lender in accordance with the business rules. However, CSI Financial Finance does not provide lenders with compensation for voting rights. During the period of securities lending, the number of shares held in the shareholder register will temporarily change and will be restored after the securities lending expires and is withdrawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hillhouse is not an isolated case, this phenomenon frequently occurs in A-shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 5, 2022, Huayi Brothers (300027.SZ) issued an announcement stating that Shenzhen Tencent Computer Systems Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tencent Computer), a shareholder holding 7.942441% of the shares, reduced its holdings through block transactions. 1.942447%, and participated in refinancing lending of 0.999998%. After that, Tencent Computer&#39;s shareholding dropped to 4.999997%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of Huayi Brothers&#39; shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huayi Brothers’ 2022 annual report shows that Tencent Computer’s shareholding has dropped to 1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 11, 2022, Changliang Technology (300348.SZ) announced that the shareholder Shenzhen Tencent Information Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tencent Information) reduced its holdings by 0.78670% through block transactions and transferred Rongtong lent the same share, and its shareholding dropped from 6.57339% to 4.99999%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of Changliang Technology.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changliang Technology’s first quarter report for 2023 shows that Tencent Information’s shareholding dropped to 1.14%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 17, 2023, Guomai Culture (301052.SZ) announced that Zhejiang Bona Film and Television Production Co., Ltd., which holds 6.8756% of the company’s shares, participated in the refinancing and lent 0.8755% of the shares, and passed Large trades reduced holdings by 1.0001%. After the equity change, Bona Film and Television holds 4.9999% of the shares and &quot;is no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of the company&#39;s shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guomai Culture’s 2023 interim report showed that Bona Film and Television’s shareholding was reduced to 4.15%, and by the third quarter report, it was reduced to 3.15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 31, 2023, Yuncong Technology (688327.SH) announced that its shareholder Jiadu Technology (600728.SH), which holds 6.63157% of the shares, reduced its holdings by 0.81579% through block transactions. During the refinancing process, the same share was lent, which reduced its shareholding to 4.99999%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of the company&#39;s shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuncong Technology’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that Jiadu Technology’s shareholding ratio has been reduced to 3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shareholders of the above four companies all &quot;coincidentally&quot; reduced their shareholdings below the 5% letter disclosure red line through refinancing, and then reduced their shareholdings without letter disclosure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Just because there is a precedent does not mean it is right.” According to Wang Jiyue, a senior investment banker, supervision clearly requires shareholders to reduce their holdings of more than 5%, and Hillhouse’s approach took advantage of loopholes in the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Emergency patching&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Special treatment can be given to the disclosure rules of equity changes and shareholding reductions involved in securities lending.” Peng Bing, professor of Peking University Law School and securities law expert, told the South A reporter over the weekend explained that lending shares cannot be regarded as a true reduction of holdings because the lent shares will still be returned, so changes in equity should not be regarded as a reduction in equity and can be specifically disclosed as a temporary suspension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the words were spoken, supervision had already patched the loopholes in the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8th and 10th, the Shanghai Stock Exchange, Shenzhen Stock Exchange, Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM all updated self-regulatory guidelines, mainly revising the information disclosure content of relevant entities participating in refinancing business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the Shanghai Stock Exchange as an example. It issued the &quot;Shanghai Stock Exchange Self-Regulatory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 2 - Business Processing (Revised in November 2023)&quot;, which requires shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares to Clear requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the guidelines, when investors and their concerted parties participate in margin trading, securities lending and refinancing business, the number of shares of the same listed company held by their ordinary securities accounts and customer credit securities accounts shall be the same as the number of shares that have not been lent through refinancing. If the total number of shares of the company returned exceeds 5% of the company&#39;s total share capital, the reduction of the company&#39;s shares shall be subject to the Exchange&#39;s &quot;Detailed Implementation Rules for Share Reductions by Shareholders and Directors, Supervisors and Senior Management Personnel of Listed Companies&quot; and other rules regarding major shareholders. Regulations on reduction of holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the number of shares lent by investors through refinancing should also be included in the number of shares when investors reduce their holdings, fundamentally eliminating &quot;detour reduction&quot;. At the same time, the revised rules also prohibit relevant shareholders from participating in short-term trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above guidelines show that shareholders who hold more than 5% of the shares of a listed company, do not directly or indirectly increase or decrease the number of shares they hold, and only participate in the refinancing business to lend and withdraw securities within 6 months, shall not Relevant regulations on short-term trading apply. If the company&#39;s shareholding is less than 5% of the total share capital due to participation in refinancing and lending shares, the relevant regulations on short-term trading shall apply to the purchase and sale of stocks and other equity securities during the lending period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 44 of the Securities Law stipulates that if specific entities such as major shareholders, directors, supervisors and senior management of listed companies and companies listed on the New OTC Market engage in short-term trading activities, the proceeds shall belong to the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above guidelines, the specific situation of shareholders holding 5% of the shares participating in the financing and refinancing business during the reporting period must also be disclosed in the regular report on share changes and shareholder status.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;The specific information includes the name of the shareholder, the number and proportion of shares held at the beginning of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares lent through refinancing at the beginning of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares held at the end of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares lent through refinancing at the end of the reporting period, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[肺炎支原体感染潜伏期可达4周 专家：不建议自行给孩子吃阿奇霉素]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260514]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission held a press conference today (November 13) and invited relevant experts to introduce my country’s winter respiratory tract Information on disease prevention and control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0fda3637dda984ac42d2e05636fa7ab6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3642&quot; height=&quot;2049&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0fda3637dda984ac42d2e05636fa7ab6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258094&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Respiratory diseases in our country have entered the season of high incidence, and multiple diseases are intertwined&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, said that as winter begins in various places, respiratory diseases have entered the season of high incidence, and many diseases are intertwined. Respiratory diseases are intertwined and superimposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All localities must adhere to the common prevention and treatment of multiple diseases, follow up on key groups such as the elderly, patients with basic diseases, and children, and optimize vaccination services; they must coordinate medical resources, optimize diagnosis and treatment processes, and strengthen outpatient and emergency care, Pediatrics, respiratory departments and other forces are responsible for various medical treatment work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The incubation period of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can be up to 4 weeks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Quan, chief physician of Beijing Children’s Hospital, said that children are a high-risk population for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. Why are children infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae at a higher rate: &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;① Children’s immune systems are underdeveloped, and their specific and non-specific immune functions are not very mature; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;② Mycoplasma pneumoniae itself is highly transmissible and can be transmitted through respiratory droplets or close contact The incubation period of mycoplasma pneumonia infection is relatively long, usually 1 to 4 weeks, with an average of about 3 weeks. The carriage of pathogens Patients and sick people have certain transmissibility, and there are many opportunities for cross-infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is not advisable to give children azithromycin and other drugs by themselves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Quan, chief physician of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said that overall, viruses are still the most common pathogens of children&#39;s respiratory tract infections, and Azithromycin is ineffective and unreasonable against viral infections. In addition, children are young and have underdeveloped organ functions, and drug abuse may cause adverse reactions in children. We would like to remind all parents that children are not smaller versions of adults and should not use medicine at will. They must pay attention to its safety and effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What is the difference between mycoplasma pneumonia and influenza? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui, director of the Beijing Institute of Respiratory Diseases, said that the main clinical manifestations of mycoplasma pneumonia are fever and cough. At the onset of the disease, it manifests as severe paroxysmal irritating dry cough, which may be accompanied by Headache, runny nose, sore throat, earache. Compared with previous years, mycoplasma pneumonia has shown a trend of younger patients this year, but the condition has not been significantly aggravated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Influenza is more common in winter and spring. It starts with fever and upper respiratory tract infection, followed by worsening cough, dyspnea and some signs of the lungs, and even more severe systemic symptoms, including high fever, rapid disease progression, and fatigue. , headache, muscle soreness and other symptoms are more obvious. There are some similarities between the two in imaging. Respiratory specimen testing such as detection of type A or type B epidemiological antigens and nucleic acids can be distinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have respiratory infectious diseases increased this year? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui, director of the Beijing Institute of Respiratory Diseases, said that in fact, every winter is the season of high incidence of respiratory infections. Common mycoplasma pneumoniae, respiratory viruses, especially influenza viruses are more active than in summer and spring, leading to an obvious increase in the number of infected people. Increase. Current monitoring data shows that my country has entered the influenza season this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the COVID-19 epidemic, due to strict respiratory prevention and control measures, the incidence of acute respiratory diseases such as mycoplasma and influenza has indeed declined. With the normalization of prevention and control, these diseases have returned to their pre-epidemic behavior this year. is normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, combined with the fact that Mycoplasma pneumoniae itself has its own epidemic pattern (cyclical epidemics occur every 3-7 years), mycoplasma pneumonia in children is trending this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;ul>;&lt;/ul>; &lt;h4>;The epidemic situation of new coronavirus infection in my country has shown a fluctuating downward trend recently&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The epidemic situation of new coronavirus infection in my country has recently shown a fluctuating downward trend. Since late August this year, the number of reported cases of new coronavirus infection across the country has been declining for 10 consecutive weeks, and the positive rate of new coronavirus nucleic acid tests in fever clinics and sentinel hospitals across the country has continued to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to scientifically prevent respiratory diseases in daily life? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Dayan, director of the National Influenza Center of the Institute of Viral Diseases of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, said that the most effective and economical way to prevent infectious diseases is vaccination. In addition, we should pay attention to the following points:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Develop a healthy lifestyle, maintain adequate sleep and adequate nutrition , moderate physical exercise. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Develop good personal hygiene habits. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pay attention to keeping the home and workplace environment clean. Open windows regularly indoors for ventilation, and keep warm during the ventilation period. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;High-risk groups such as the elderly, children, and patients with underlying diseases should try to avoid going to crowded public places. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once respiratory infection symptoms such as fever and cough occur, the patient should rest at home to avoid transmitting the pathogen to other people. &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网络暴力，难以消散的漩涡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260510]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;As of June 2023, the number of Internet users in China has reached 1.079 billion. A survey in early 2022 showed that 38.6% of people in China have suffered varying degrees of online violence on social media. In recent years, many victims of online violence have committed suicide. How to control online violence is a difficult problem that needs to be solved urgently.</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为了快乐挖土，一个考古学家决定去当美食博主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260512]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;What happens when an archaeologist becomes a &quot;foodie&quot;? Zhang Liangren, professor of history at Nanjing University, gave an example. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A meal of soup dumplings in a roadside fly shop can reveal 7,000 years of history: from the pottery age and the Bronze Age kitchen utensils &quot;retort&quot;, From the ancient &quot;steamer&quot; on the kitchen murals of the Eastern Han Dynasty tombs in Henan, to the plum blossom buns in the caves of the Song Dynasty...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A bowl of small wontons can help him interpret the weather of the universe. : &quot;&quot;The Chronicles of Yanjing&quot; says: The shape of husband&#39;s wonton is like a chicken egg, which is quite similar to the chaos of heaven and earth, so it occurs during the winter solstice solar eclipse.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; ​​height=&quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dumplings from the Tang Dynasty&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eating hot pot today? Then it&#39;s time to show real technology - &quot;tell the history of whatever you see&quot;. The professor is not afraid. There was originally a legend of &quot;fried Qin Hui&quot; behind fried dough sticks, and tofu was called &quot;Plough Qi&quot; in Lu You&#39;s poem; &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; not only made Liu Genghong famous, but also recorded the method of making yuba; instant noodles are not a patent of the Japanese , but was &quot;invented&quot; by Yi Bingzhuo, a calligrapher from the Qing Dynasty in my country, who accidentally poured noodles into the oil pan at his mother&#39;s birthday party...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The temptation of delicious food hangs on the taste buds, and these historical knowledge and anecdotes remain in the audience&#39;s memory through Zhang Liangren&#39;s eloquent narration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258067 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Netizens commented that Zhang Liangren looks like the Chinese version of a lonely gourmet&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >; With this &quot;unique skill&quot;, Zhang Liangren gained 38,000 fans and 300,000 likes in just over two months after joining Douyin. He was called &quot;The Lonely Gourmet&quot; that is more suitable for Chinese babies&#39; physiques. This expressed the wish he expressed in the first video: &quot;Break the dimensional wall, take off the cold and mysterious mask of archeology, and let everyone see the lovely and warm inner nature of this subject.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;What people don’t know is that this archaeologist decided to become a food blogger because he could “dig in the soil” happily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. An archaeologist who only loves food&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Graduated from Peking University undergraduate and social studies A postgraduate student of the Academy of Science and Technology went to the University of California, Los Angeles to get a doctorate. He worked as a researcher for many years and later became a professor at Nanjing University. Zhang Liangren devoted his life to archeology: &quot;he can go to the field and write articles.&quot; He not only does Chinese archeology, Also doing world archeology. In his own words: &quot;The total number of countries he has visited and explored could circle the earth.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also Zhang Liangren&#39;s habit to eat wherever he goes. Iranian mutton stew and saffron rice, Russian kebabs, and Siberian grilled fish... all impressed him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258068 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren visited Tajikistan in 2011&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, Zhang Liangren admitted frankly that he is far from being a qualified &quot;foodie&quot;: he enjoys delicious food, but he has not yet reached the point of searching for delicious food. What really guided him to become a food blogger was his love for archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Last year, Zhang Liangren accidentally opened a monograph &quot;Diet in Chinese Culture&quot; from the 1970s. The editor-in-chief of the book, Zhang Guangzhi, is a famous Chinese archaeologist, anthropologist, and Zhang Liangren’s mentor. The whole book provides a panoramic display and interpretation of China&#39;s food culture. From the pre-Qin Dynasty to the Han, Tang, Yuan, Ming and Qing dynasties, how did the characteristics of agricultural society affect the evolution of food on this land? How did Confucian moral concepts and social organization methods determine the Chinese people? cooking and dining habits...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren read more than 400 pages in one breath, as if he saw a new door: he has been doing archaeology for a lifetime, and he has been eating for a lifetime. , but never realized that there was such a close connection between the two. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From then on, eating was no longer just about eating. He could not help but think about it while eating: Why must there be food and rice on the Chinese dining table? &quot;Dual diet&quot;, but Westerners are accustomed to &quot;one plate&quot;? What makes the Chinese form a shared meal system, while Westerners form a divided meal system? When were wheat and tomatoes introduced to China, and how did the stir-fry cooking method come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, food archeology is not a brand-new research topic. It is only because food is perishable and cannot be preserved in the long history, and it is too difficult to excavate that it leads to There are very few people doing relevant research in the global archaeological community, and even fewer in China. But Zhang Liangren decided that he would face the difficulties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Just do it. This year, Zhang Liangren recruited two students to specialize in dietary archeology, hoping to unearth more dietary cultural relics and fill the gaps in archaeological research. Zhang Liangren has always had an academic ideal: to let the world hear the voice of the Chinese archaeological community. &quot;The first is to publish Chinese archeology abroad, and the second is to participate more in international archeology and contribute to world archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For this reason, he has Single-handedly initiated archaeological projects of Sino-Russian and Sino-Iranian cooperation. The Iranian team adopted the European excavation method, digging straight down like a deep well. Zhang Liangren felt that this area was too small and too inefficient, so he persuaded the other party to use the Chinese trench excavation method. The results were remarkable and were not only published in international journals. The paper attracted the attention of academic circles and was visited by members of the Iranian Congress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;How to make cold knowledge more pyrotechnic? Letting more people realize the value of archaeological history is something Zhang Liangren and his friends around him often discuss. In July this year, with the help of several friends, Zhang Liangren opened his own Douyin account and started to explore food stores. Zhang Liangren is responsible for the appearance, and friends are responsible for filming and production. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He made no secret that the reason why he came up with the idea of ​​making short videos was to spread knowledge to the public, and the other original intention was to &quot;expand awareness&quot; and let more people People know the value of archeology and support archaeological research in more ways. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Pour some cold water on young people who want to study archeology&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren The video is full of the fireworks of life and has a sense of history. He picked up a mouthful of duck blood vermicelli soup and said that this vermicelli soup has only a few decades of history, but from a can of duck eggs unearthed from a mound tomb in Jurong, Jiangsu, it can be seen that the tradition of eating waterfowl in Jiangsu dates back to 2,500 years ago. It started years ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also interesting to examine the origin of imitation meat vegetarian food. Emperor Liang Wu of the Han Dynasty issued an &quot;administrative order&quot; requiring monks to stop drinking and eating. The need to be both vegetarian and satisfy one&#39;s cravings led later generations to use their brains and develop meat-like vegetarian food that can mimic meat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the image in the video is humorous and friendly, Zhang Liangren waved his hands and laughed at himself, saying that he is an &quot;old scholar&quot; who spends all day burying his head in old papers and not listening to what is going on outside the window. He is good at academic research, digging soil, and giving lectures; reviewing video scripts and embedding historical knowledge can also be regarded as an extension of his professional skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Only appearing on camera is a big problem: &quot;I am a person who is not good at words, and I cannot speak Mandarin well.&quot; In the first few videos, his eyes were habitually Avoid the camera and look away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But what can stump a true &quot;old scholar&quot;? He began to use his scholarly spirit to make short videos, and specially hired an announcer to train himself to correct his pronunciation, improve his intonation and language rhythm, and practice facing the camera. Now, although he is still a little green and awkward, he can already look directly into the camera, clearly tell the history behind the food, and even make some funny expressions and movements to interact with the imaginary audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The contrast between &quot;old scholar&quot; and various current buzzwords, the fresh combination of historical knowledge and gourmet temptations, and the high-frequency output of updates every two days make the book more interesting. Zhang Liangren became a &quot;top leader&quot; in the archaeological community in just over two months. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But compared with the increased traffic figures, what makes him even more happy is that many ordinary people will leave messages or private messages asking questions related to archeology and history. &quot;More people are interested in We are interested in archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many young students also left messages: Can they take the postgraduate entrance examination for professors? Zhang Liangren will be more cautious towards this type of fans. On the one hand, he is pleased that more young people want to join the archaeological industry; on the other hand, he has to remind them that doing research and popular science are not the same thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258066 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The history of fried dough sticks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren has long noticed , in recent years, with the broadcast of film and television programs such as &quot;I Repair Cultural Relics in the Forbidden City&quot; and &quot;National Treasure&quot;, archeology has gradually entered the public eye. Many of his own students were influenced by these programs and decided to apply for the archeology major. The first lesson he taught these young students was to pour cold water on them: &quot;Break their romantic imagination of archeology - TV programs present the most interesting and accomplished aspects of this subject, but behind the fun and achievements, It is extremely long and hard work. If you can’t stand the loneliness, don’t enter this industry.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, it took Zhang Liangren himself many years to fall in love with archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;870&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258069 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Let more people understand archeology&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When I took the exam When he was in college, he had no idea what his interests were, so he muddleheadedly applied for the Department of Archeology. During his undergraduate and postgraduate years, Zhang Liangren spent his time attending classes, reading materials, and writing papers. It was difficult and boring, just like the public&#39;s stereotype of archeology. It wasn’t until I started to come into contact with a large number of historical materials from all over the world during my PhD studies and participated in field surveys and excavations around the world that I felt the joy of this subject. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The part that he enjoys the most is the most feared &quot;digging&quot; part of archeology: sleeping in the open air, exposed to the sun and rain, under the pressure of scholars Title, doing heavy physical work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I like this kind of life to explore in inaccessible places, bask in the sun, look at the scenery, and breathe fresh air.” Moreover, compared to sitting in the library and studying Archeology can always surprise him with the achievements of predecessors and the first-hand information that is freshly excavated and stained with real historical dust, inspiring him to discover new problems. &quot;I am very excited and not boring at all.&quot;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, after using a basin of cold water to extinguish the romantic imagination of young people, he will use the true connotation of this subject to &quot;warm&quot; them back - after all, he has given This introductory course for freshmen is called &quot;The Archeology of Charm.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Curiosity is the answer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;History The Xianlin campus where the department is located is 20 to 30 kilometers away from downtown Nanjing. After working here for nearly ten years, Zhang Liangren’s life trajectory has never exceeded five kilometers around the campus. He mainly eats in the school cafeteria, and goes out to hang out when friends come. A meal as a supplement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But since he became a food blogger, he &quot;goes to the city to eat delicious food&quot; every day, and has even become a food trendsetter in Nanjing&#39;s archaeological circles. His colleagues always ask questions when they see him. One sentence: Which restaurant have you been to recently? He thought, how could he ignore so many delicious foods in Jinling, the capital of gourmet food? This kind of shop-hopping life seems to be pretty good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This career, which was originally just a means of &quot;saving the country through curves,&quot; now takes up a little more time every week than teaching. He has already begun to make long-term plans: after exploring Nanjing cuisine, he will also explore national cuisine, and then world cuisine; not only cooking food, but also introducing other archaeological related knowledge, such as the two issues of &quot;Three Whitening Tips of the Ancients&quot; and &quot;A 400-degree myopic guide to traveling through ancient times.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258070 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren participated in excavations in Russia in 2019&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One The video shooting session, which initially made him feel uncomfortable, gradually became more comfortable. Only then did he realize that those food programs on TV were all &quot;acted&quot;. &quot;A plate of meat was filmed at different angles for 20 minutes. When you eat it, it&#39;s cold in your mouth, and you have to act like it&#39;s delicious. What about &quot;Journey to the West&quot; &quot;The flat peach eaten by Sun Wukong in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real flat peach, and the bowl of wine Wu Song drank before fighting the tiger in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real bar? In order to stay awake, the actor must have drank water.&quot; He analyzed seriously. , as if he had discovered some incredible truth, which made the young man opposite him laugh. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Originally, he wanted to &quot;facilitate&quot; archeology to the public. Unexpectedly, in the process, the daily life of the public unknowingly entered his pile of old papers, which made this old scholar Got caught up in the fireworks and became a &quot;slash professor&quot; at the age of 58. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Now he can answer the question: What is the connection between archeology and daily life? Zhang Liangren’s answer is: curiosity. Whether it’s archaeology, gourmet food or being a short video blogger, it’s curiosity that pushes him to move forward. This experience can also be extended to other humans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“People are curious and want to know where they come from and where they are going, so everyone likes to go to museums and see ruins and cultural relics. And archeology It provides a kind of tangible history that can be seen directly with the eyes, which is more intuitive than the history presented in words. It is not only a key to the historical truth, but also an entrance to explore the development laws of human society.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nowadays, Zhang Liangren will tell his students that academic issues must be related to things that the people care about. Because there is a lot of fun in the world, and you can get it as long as you are willing to &quot;dig&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“能用的条文总是这么少”，专家呼吁立法解决网暴治理“九龙治水”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The governance of online violence needs to be solved urgently The problem is that the legislation is too fragmented. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the governance of online violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of overly fragmented legislation. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As of June 2023, the number of Internet users in China has reached 1.079 billion. A survey in early 2022 showed that 38.6% of people in China have suffered varying degrees of online violence on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;All cases of cyber violence have one thing in common, that is, they are violent and the consequences are tragic.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, in the &quot;Cyber ​​Violence Rule of Law&quot; Liu Yanhong, dean of the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, said at the seminar. On the forum, some scholars also expressed that they had suffered cyber violence and information intrusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From &quot;Dr. Deyang An committed suicide&quot; and &quot;Rumors were spread about a Hangzhou woman picking up express delivery&quot; to Liu Xuezhou and Zheng Linghua died in unbearable cyber violence, vicious cyber violence incidents have occurred frequently in recent years. Various reports. “When cyber violence occurs, it stings the nerves of us legal professionals, because our first reaction is to quickly search for any provision in the criminal law that can convict people, but we are very surprised to find that the available provision is always So few.&quot; Liu Yanhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Many participating scholars believed that for the governance of cyber violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of over-dispersed legislation, and anti-cyber violence legislation needs to be gradually promoted in a hierarchical manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But on the other hand, some scholars have reminded that the essence of the governance of cyber violence is the governance of speech expression, and the difference between cyber violence and criticism needs to be carefully clarified. boundary. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Not even the criminal law can catch up”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2013 On September 5, 2019, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Illegal Crimes of Cyber ​​Violence in accordance with the Law&quot;, which classified cyber violence for the first time and explained the alleged crimes of different cyber violence behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For example, if the perpetrator of cyber violence creates and spreads rumors on the Internet, derogating others&#39; personality and damaging their reputation, and the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of defamation; Those who publicly insult others by means of wanton abuse, malicious slander, disclosure of privacy, etc., and if the circumstances are serious, shall be convicted of the crime of insult; organize &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and if the circumstances are serious, they shall be convicted of the crime of infringement. Conviction of citizens’ personal information crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong believes that the current judicial interpretation has a narrow definition of cyber violence and pays less attention to cyber intimidation, stalking and bullying. On the other hand, as to whether human flesh search constitutes the crime of infringing on citizens’ personal information, “it needs to reach a certain number and change from quantitative to qualitative changes to constitute a crime. Therefore, it is difficult to determine that a general manual search conducted by multiple people infringes on personal information of citizens. Information crime”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Even the criminal law is unable to catch up.&quot; Liu Yanhong said that in the field of civil adjudication and administrative law enforcement in the field of online violence, this kind of &quot;law does not punish the public&quot; &quot;The tendency remains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of procedures, there is a lack of unified norms and standards for evidence collection in cyber violence cases. Yin Bo, a professor at the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, mentioned that in private prosecution cases of cyber violence Among them, the party’s ability to produce evidence is relatively weak. In order to break down technical barriers, evidence is usually extracted by internal or external professionals under the auspices of the public security or other judicial organs. However, the existing electronic evidence production still lacks technology and methods. &quot; Even the grassroots public security organs do not know how to collect evidence, dare not collect evidence, and cannot collect evidence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On August 3, 2023, the Beijing Internet Court released a number of typical cases involving online violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu is a &quot;big V&quot; blogger with nearly 500,000 Weibo fans. Another Weibo user, Sun, was involved in a dispute over a current affairs issue. Liu had a different view and sent insulting words to Liu through Weibo private messages. Liu posted Sun&#39;s private messages, Weibo account, photos and other information on Weibo, along with insulting remarks, triggering online violence against Sun from netizens. In the end, the court ruled that Liu had infringed the law and deleted the Weibo and comments involved in the case that infringed on Sun&#39;s portrait and reputation. Both parties apologized to each other in writing, and the amount of mental damage compensation was offset by each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong previously wrote that netizens who posted negative comments to insult Sun could have been held liable for civil infringement and administrative liability for disrupting online order, but in the judicial process In law enforcement practice, such acts committed by non-initiators and non-organizers are generally ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the other hand, for the current governance of cyber violence, there are relevant provisions in the Civil Code, Criminal Law, Administrative Penalty Law and other laws and regulations that can be used, but different laws Each has its own value orientation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, the current legislation on the governance of cyber violence is like a flood in Kowloon.&quot; She advocates comprehensive and progressive legislation, such as being first formulated by the State Council. Regulations on the Prevention and Control of Cyber ​​Violence, followed by legislation on the prevention and control of cyber violence, and finally the establishment of an organic law for cyber violence governance agencies, and finally the unified rise to the Anti-Cyber ​​Violence Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Wang Sixin, deputy director of the Research Institute of a Community with a Shared Future for Mankind at Communication University of China, also said that step-by-step legislation is more likely to achieve practical results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;To prevent platform abuse of power&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the seminar, Some scholars also warned that we should be cautious about anti-cyber violence legislation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;The governance of online violence is essentially the governance of speech.&quot; Zhi Zhenfeng, a researcher at the Institute of Law, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that for normal criticism and Supervision and discussion of different opinions should be protected. &quot;Online violence must be controlled, but everyone&#39;s rights to speech and expression must also be protected.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As to how to distinguish normal online criticism from illegal online violence, Shi Jiayou, a professor at Renmin University of China, said that subjectively speaking, online criticism is generally well-intentioned and its purpose is Often it is about safeguarding public interests or one&#39;s own legitimate rights and interests. From an objective point of view, Internet criticism is generally based on basic facts. The facts criticized are generally well-founded or have reasonable information channels, and are not groundless or randomly fabricated; even if the facts confirmed in the end are different from the initial There are discrepancies or partial inaccuracies in the critical remarks, but as long as the critical remarks do have an objective basis as a whole and the critic has reasonable grounds to believe in the authenticity of the facts cited, then the critical remarks should be considered to be a reasonable exercise of freedom of speech. scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, Zhi Zhenfeng emphasized that the focus of combating cyber violence should be organized manipulation of public opinion. “For example, behind cyber thugs and cyber trolls, there are often Organized ones, where one organization can control dozens or millions of accounts at the same time, as well as overseas account matrices involving national security, are all targets that should be targeted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, he believes that as a platform that builds a public opinion space, it has an obligation to maintain the order of the public opinion space. &quot;The platform has technical strength and can intervene through front-end and make samples.&quot; Use database modeling and other technologies to control cyber violence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Professor Wang Limei from the Data Law Institute of China University of Political Science and Law added this. She believes that platforms should first improve the real-name system, which can be based on the different natures of the platform and spokespersons. , implement front-end or back-end real-name. Secondly, platforms should set up preventive technical measures so that those who are cyberviolated can trigger the protection mechanism with “one click”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, Zhi Zhenfeng said that it seems that the platform has been imposed obligations, but in fact it has been given power. &quot;Then will the platform abuse this?&quot; Power, to make the already uneven power between the platform and users even more imbalanced? I have found that some platforms use the banner of supervision to delete posts that they do not like.&quot; He reminded that attention should be paid to preventing platforms from abusing their power and controlling speech. Abnormal market manipulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>