<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[科幻作家糖匪：被AI替代的人如何生活？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/o4Pd43WOaAdR06Ey8U48hjSWoGqg6aRVdO7dPqZ8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/o4Pd43WOaAdR06Ey8U48hjSWoG qg6aRVdO7dPqZ8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An electronic zoo in an urban apartment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;How do you think about killing a person in a place with complete surveillance?&quot; Intermittent voices came from the phone. . In the early autumn of 2023, in a cafe on the streets of Shanghai, science fiction writer Tang Bandit talked about the original idea of ​​the new novel collection &quot;Later Humanity&quot; in a telephone interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, when it was difficult to travel freely due to the fluctuations of the new crown epidemic, Sugar Bandit began to re-examine the house where he lived. At that time, she lived in an old house in downtown Beijing. The house was small and the study was filled with books. Sugar bandits prefer this kind of tranquility amidst the hustle and bustle of urban life. Although many friends have equipped their homes with a complete set of voice-controlled smart appliances, there are not many smart appliances in her home. Sugar Bandit lives alone, and the only camera installed in his home is to take care of his dog, which has been with him for 18 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you look at your home again, you will feel a sense of alienation: a house is like a building block that makes up a city. People live in it and use their mobile phones to pull a series of smart appliances in the house—— They are electronic creatures in the technological age, listening to their master&#39;s call. When smart appliances are domesticated enough to be intelligent, will they protect their owners and families like pets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Science fiction writing is the prism through which Sugar Bandit observes the world. Winner of the Hugo Award and Nebula Award, Chinese-American science fiction writer Yukun Liu translated Sugar Bandit&#39;s first science fiction novel &quot;Dirty Stories&quot;. When he saw Sugar Bandit, he felt that she was just like the stories she wrote, not bound by conventions. , do not write fast food dessert literature for sales. In the science fiction collections &quot;The Odyssey&quot; and &quot;The Man Who Saw Cetus&quot;, the sugar bandit is obsessed with traveling through cities, illusions and the universe. &quot;Whether it&#39;s aliens or time travel, whether it&#39;s urban horror or virtual reality technology, Sugar Bandit&#39;s novels are good at using these common metaphors in science fiction to express and question our insights as human beings.&quot; In Liu Yukun&#39;s view, this is exactly what Characteristics of the science fiction world, &quot;Reality is more science fiction than fiction, and science fiction thinking has become a way to tell the truth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The future has arrived, but it&#39;s just not popular yet.&quot; Although Kevin Kelly has already stated in &quot; &quot;Inevitable&quot; reminds people of their attitude towards technology, but when AlphaGo and ChatGPT arouse social attention, it is still difficult for people to regard artificial intelligence as the current reality. Instead, they either imagine the broad future opened by technology, or continue to maintain this alert. Sugar Bandit is a technology enthusiast who is keen on researching new technologies. However, in her collection of science fiction novels &quot;Later Humanity&quot;, she has set her sights on the &quot;posthumanity&quot; left behind by the technological era. She writes about those Ordinary people who have disappeared from society unknowingly use science fiction to re-describe the lives of those abandoned by the times, revealing the profound changes that technology has had on people&#39;s lifestyles and interpersonal communication patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sugar Bandit’s novel, the future has arrived and mankind has entered the era of comprehensive artificial intelligence. However, people still have memories of their past lives. Half of them have entered the clean future in the cloud, and the other half of themselves have entered the era of comprehensive artificial intelligence. The memory of the body stuck in the ground. In the cyber world where humans and machines are coupled, people have virtual clones uploaded to the cloud, brain-computer assembly surgeries to enhance brain power, artificial intelligence &quot;family masters&quot; that control everything in their apartments, and machines that satisfy the sexual desires of family members. &quot;Happy&quot;, people can also rent out their bodies in the spherical vibrator field... The sugar bandit describes the later human beings with delicate brushstrokes: He Lai who disappeared with his memory, Xin Min, the housewife who was monitored by the &quot;family mastermind&quot;, &quot; Chen Keqing, a beauty blogger who has a stable mentality and is like a plastic person...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These stories tell the most common daily things of human beings, but they write about Zhang Ailing-like feelings in the technological age and touch the softest of human beings.&quot; and the hardest parts, I have never seen science fiction express them in such a detailed, lingering and heart-wrenching way.&quot; Science fiction writer Han Song said that he feels that such science fiction novels are real literature that belongs to the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Happy Days,&quot; Sugar Bandit imagines a new kind of apartment in the future. In the future, people will no longer worry about mortgages and rents. The housing problem that once strained the entire society has long since dissipated. The right to residence is people’s birthright. “The younger generation has forgotten that era of housing tension. Due to the climate Conditions shortened the durability of a large number of buildings, living resources were highly concentrated, and housing supply was once very tight. Even if the last generation of baby boomers has passed and the urban population has dropped sharply, the habitable land area still cannot satisfy the existing population. The emergence of new apartments has ended that period Chaotic and crowded days.&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Happy Days&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, intensive and intelligent Smart apartments are given temperature by technology, and the temperature is passed on to those who choose it in the future. In new apartments, the artificial intelligence &quot;home master&quot; controls everything in the apartment, from the use of various furniture and appliances to the collection of data from earphones, air composition analyzers, and infrared camera needles throughout the home, and can even be refined to the Data analysis of pressure, heat and micro-radiation in each plane of the home. Technology provides a happy, efficient, and convenient life for the people who live here, and it also controls and monitors everything in these homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in these families, who is qualified to control the machines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WtMDY37206Cqnz5LHmqwUUSwMS9JIHXl40wpwm6V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WtMDY37206Cqnz5LHmqwUUSwMS9JIHXl40wpwm6V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the event site of the 4th Another Planet Science Fiction Conference, from left, Liu Cixin, Sugar Bandit, Han Song&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewed (Photo courtesy of author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Man and machine, are they enemies or friends? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Novelist Liao Jing felt a little horrified when she read &quot;Happy Days&quot; by Sugar Bandit. She sent Tang Bandit a WeChat message saying that she thought of &quot;1984&quot;. In the novel, the &quot;family master&quot; of the apartment is omniscient. &quot;It appears as a server, knows everything, and takes care of the couple in every possible and subtle way, but in fact it is a monitor.&quot; , and even became a ruler.&quot; Liao Jing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, in the past few years, everyone has often felt this way. It&#39;s like I spent money to buy a mobile phone, and after downloading some software, I put a chain on myself.&quot; Liao Jing shared his feelings at the Sugar Bandit&#39;s new book salon, &quot;We feel that we are the owners of the mobile phone, and that the mobile phone is about me, but if I forget to bring my mobile phone when I go out, I may not be able to go anywhere. When you think technology When you are cared for and taken care of all the time, you are actually trapped in some kind of shackles.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the penetration of technology in the digital age, people&#39;s sense of being monitored seems to be everywhere. When writing &quot;Happy Days&quot;, Sugar Bandit was curious that if people lose their initiative in the apartment where they live every day, then whether this apartment where people are taken care of in every possible way is more like the &quot;French philosopher Michel Foucault&quot; proposed &quot;Panopticon&quot;, can technology really empower the disadvantaged, or will it intensify exploitation and accelerate differentiation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel, even in the technological future where people can upload all their memories and ways of thinking to the cloud, families living in future apartments will still have a family model of &quot;the man is the head of the house and the woman is the head of the house&quot;. This comes from sugar. The bandit&#39;s special setting. The wife does housework at home. By arranging the &quot;domestic mastermind&quot;, the wife controls all matters in the home and appears to be the master of the home. However, the control authority of the &quot;family mastermind&quot; lies in the hands of the husband. Even if he just adjusts the electrical parameters in the home, he needs to wait for his permission after he comes home from get off work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although it is a story that takes place in the future, the actual reading experience is very contemporary. As a housewife’s situation that we often talk about, it has also appeared in many movies and TV series. She is in her Her status in family life is even lower than that of the &#39;brain&#39; of the apartment. She has always been in an environment of being controlled and monitored. Although she seems to be the master and has constant needs, in fact she does not even have the authority to modify the parameters. She would not get this permission.&quot; Liao Jing said, &quot;She was thinking, what do I need AI for? To enable me to be more proactive and better at completing housework. The question raised actually involves a core issue, which is who is it? Who is taking advantage of whom is enslaving whom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the technological leaps one after another, what is seen is technological progress, what is not seen is the hidden labor. In the novel, Sugar Bandit specifically depicts the relationship between this woman and the family AI: at home, the person who understands her best and gives her the most time to spend with her is the &quot;family mastermind&quot; AI that she has trained with her own hands. Her job is also to use human experience and emotions to &quot;feed&quot; AI, type it into text and input it into the AI ​​backend, so that AI can better serve humans. Faced with the ubiquitous family boss in the smart apartment, her cheating husband who turned a blind eye to her, and the sudden death of her best friend, the protagonist Xin Min fell into a fear of losing her subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of sugar bandits, the most cruel punishment is &quot;the disappearance of a person.&quot; &quot;Lock a person in a small space and pretend she doesn&#39;t exist. You seem to be free in this society, but you are made transparent. No one cares about what you think or what you like, and the occasional conversation with you is It all revolves around his needs. Your labor is small because it is covered by technology, and personal value cannot be realized through intellectual labor. Domestic labor does not count as labor, and your emotional labor is also exploited. In this case, this The heroine is the person who &#39;disappeared&#39; and does not exist.&quot; Sugar Bandit said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Science fiction is a way of thinking that saves us from our daily stereotypes and inherent thinking through extreme situations, the construction of different worlds, and other unfamiliar creative methods. Come out. So as to change the scale and angle of how we look at problems, and re-examine our current lives.&quot; In the master class of the 7th China-Europe International Literature Festival, Sugar Bandit pointed out when she was invited to share her knowledge and understanding of science fiction novels The significance of science fiction is not just to create spectacles that are different from reality. The key is to break away from ordinary perspectives and thinking. This imagination is rooted in the heavy reality and gains the power to grow upward from the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting of the machine in the novel is different from previous novels. When the &quot;family mastermind&quot; faces this seemingly inseparable couple, its only need is to maintain the stability of the family. It quietly helps the couple cover up traces of each other&#39;s derailments and protect the existing family&#39;s orbit. Like a parent, he wants this to happen. The home runs well. The desire of women in the novel is also to restore order, but they are not satisfied with the beautiful order restored by machines, but hope to obtain their own subjectivity. In the extreme setting of the novel, she kills her husband and disposes of the criminal tools through the smart apartment, and in the end the &quot;family mastermind&quot; also helps cover up the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is not so much about revenge, but about her finding a way to exist as a living person after her own human value has been erased. This is not an opposition between men and women, but a social structure problem.&quot; Sugar Bandit said that the novel transfers people&#39;s helplessness and indignation towards the world into personal plight. Breaking free from it and breaking through it are actually a matter of personal confrontation with the plight of the entire world. With the help of the machine, the woman gains freedom and her true identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How will the relationship between humans and machines change in the future? In the view of the sugar bandit, people today no longer treat technology like the confrontation or blind worship they had in the early 21st century. In the future, people may stand together with machines to fight against the so-called &quot;inhumanity&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQwtjJ1QnbZJt7xvxWizVueWRn7FuM6aITaSoEru.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQwtjJ1QnbZJt7xvxWizVueWRn7FuM6aITaSoEru.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; Later people&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The sugar bandit is in poor health and had a major operation in 2022. &quot;My condition this year is worse than last year. I have been sleeping only two to three hours a day for a long time. And in When I was in Beijing, I couldn’t go out. My whole person was in a shaky state.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the disease came, Sugar Bandit felt that he had finally entered an excellent writing state. Several novellas have been written. Different from previous novel collections, she has developed a very complete and systematic world in the new novel collection. She feels that she has found a very clear writing direction and has a very clear understanding of science fiction. Concept, can&#39;t wait to enter a new stage of creation, &quot;At that time, if you gave me an apple, I could write science fiction novels. That state was very stable and very wild, and I felt like I could do anything.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;The result was all of a sudden. I went to the hospital for a check-up and found out all of a sudden... Then I started to be rubbed by death for two years.&quot; Sugar Bandit recalled the medical treatment at that time in the noisy cafe, about her going to the hospital during the epidemic. Surgery in the hospital is difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology is always improving, and people tend to move forward with time and are good at forgetting. The English title of the new collection of novels &quot;After Humanity&quot; has two translations. The first one is &quot;posthumanity&quot;, which is a very important concept in science fiction novels. The second is to use Shanghai dialect to say that &quot;latecomers&quot; are those who are left behind. &quot;Those who arrive first will become more successful and resourceful people. Those who come later will obviously be more passive and will slowly and unknowingly slide into a marginal position. The future in the novel is very pessimistic.&quot; Sugar Bandit Said, &quot;The novel is the best mirror for the author, and the understanding of the world is presented in the text in a very honest and undisguised way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sugar Bandit&#39;s view, science fiction is not just about carrying science and technology A fanciful literary type, she loves science fiction because it is so lively and full of possibilities. In ancient China, novels developed from myths and legends to fantasy novels. The authors presented these fictional objects to readers with a naive and enthusiastic belief. Although technology has long dispelled the darkness of human pre-modern civilization, reality and fantasy have been confused again in another form. Especially in the years of the COVID-19 epidemic, shock has become the norm. Many incredible things happen, and people use science fiction to describe reality, whether it is a dream life given by highly developed technology or a nightmare reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people are already living in science fiction, how should science fiction literature express and respond to reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the writing of &quot;Later Humanity&quot;, Sugar Bandit felt that this process was a &quot;flying close to the ground&quot;, and several novels imagined future cities along the lines of real life. &quot;Such science fiction gives Will the huge sense of surprise make men feel excited? Not necessarily, but I want to be a little provocative and stinging, making people understand that even if technology is so advanced, family work still requires a huge amount of labor, patience and time. . Not only family labor, but also in modern life due to the emergence of technology, many labors have been covered up due to the advancement of technology.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People often say that AI will replace humans, but when AI replaces humans, At this time, what do humans do? Humans serve and train AI.&quot; Sugar Bandit said that &quot;technology is green&quot; is a huge illusion. Whether it is ChatGPT or many well-known artificial intelligence software, it requires a lot of manpower to train it, and these simple, repetitive and boring tasks often correspond to people in less developed areas of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel, she writes about the future of many people who have been left behind by the technological era, but these science fiction novels are almost becoming reality. In &quot;Half Articles and Half Tune&quot; written two years ago, residents living on an island are affected by ocean microplastics and gradually become plastic people. Recently, reports about microplastics harming human health have been appearing in the news. The body for rent in &quot;Running Ball&quot; involves the exploitation of the lower class by the upper class. When productivity develops to a certain extent, what people are exploited is not their labor power and intelligence, but their subjectivity and the joy of being a human being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why should we arouse concern for these people? Because today of these people may be our tomorrow. Now everyone seems to have no worries about food and clothing, live and work in peace and contentment, but it is possible that tomorrow due to something, the trajectory of life will continue. If we take care of those on the margins and speak for them, we will do something for our future,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[珍∙古道尔：与黑猩猩共度的传奇一生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259336]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/wPjs2fqHqWCrluRezzRKVpWPhAYCdCV7seBpgTu2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;647&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/wPjs2fqHqWCrluRezzRKVpWPhAYCdCV7seBpg Tu2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jane Goodall&#39;s research findings break the long-held belief that only humans can make tools ” perspective has introduced brand-new data into the study of anthropology and animal behavior. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already five o&#39;clock in the afternoon, but Jane Goodall did not meet even a chimpanzee. While there was still a glimmer of light, she planned to go to the observation point of her choice, where she expected to see chimpanzees building their nests. Suddenly, she heard the cry of chimpanzees, and four chimpanzees appeared in the telescope, eating a yellow fruit similar to plums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She decided to get closer to them. When she cautiously approached the big tree, she found that the branches were empty—the chimpanzees had slipped away again. This situation had happened countless times for more than half a year, and she felt an almost numb despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when her eyes moved down, she found that two adult chimpanzees were sitting on the ground less than twenty meters away from her, watching her. After a few seconds, they began to stroke each other&#39;s fur as if no one else was watching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This was truly one of the most exciting moments I have ever had the pleasure to experience in my life.” Jane Goodall wrote in the book “The Chimp Is Calling” that she finally got to see her up close. Watch the chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, 2023, the documentary &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot;, starring the 89-year-old British biologist Jane Goodall, was released in China. The film won the 71st Nominated for Best Documentary at the British Academy Film Awards, it has a Douban score of 9.2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since childhood, Jane Goodall has had a strong interest in animals. When she was one year old, her family bought her a toy chimpanzee, which became her cutest friend; when she was 4 years old, she stayed in the chicken coop for five hours just to observe how the hens lay eggs; when she just turned 8, she Make up your mind to go to Africa when you grow up and be with wild animals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an adult, when a friend invited her to visit a farm in Kenya, she did not hesitate to quit her job and returned to her hometown to work as a waitress for a period of time to save money for her trip to Africa. &quot;I never expected to get married or start a family. That was not within my scope of consideration. Going to Africa to live with animals was the only thing I wanted to do.&quot; Jane Goodall said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/HpRcTJ1jNuZIbTwW9gO4uEWrTfojng2am9fYIoA6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/HpRcTJ1jNuZIbTwW9gO4uEWrTfojng2am9fYIoA6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jane fell in love and got married to wildlife photographer Hugo. Later, the two chose to separate for their respective careers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The strange feeling of isolation&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;When she first arrived in Africa, someone told Jane Goodall that if she liked animals, she must visit Louis Leakey, the then director of the National Museum of Kenya. Jane Goodall followed the advice and later became Louis Leakey&#39;s secretarial assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, Louis Leakey applied for a six-month grant to study wild chimpanzees. In his view, studying the behavior of great apes is helpful in understanding the behavioral characteristics of human beings&#39; ancient ancestors. He wanted to find a researcher who could conduct fieldwork, uninfluenced by scientific theory, and unbiased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secretary Jane Goodall fits this requirement. Before going to Gombe to study chimpanzees in 1960, she had no academic training, no science degree, and even no knowledge of wild chimpanzees. However, she loved animals, was patient, and had a great passion for knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;Chimpanzees Are Calling&quot;, Jane Goodall recalled that when she first saw the endless forest in Gombe, her mother who accompanied her was afraid, and she herself All I could think about was “the strange feeling of being isolated from the world.” However, for a young woman, approaching chimpanzees and trying to be accepted into the group was unimaginable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She could only hope that the chimpanzees would get used to her and ignore her presence. The rhythm of her life in Gombe is very fixed. No matter what the weather is like, she always goes to the mountains early in the morning to observe chimpanzees - walking through layers of trees, wading through streams, climbing steep slopes, arriving at a suitable observation point, and raising the telescope in her hand. Sometimes she could see a group of chimpanzees swinging from a fig tree, and sometimes not at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And every time she tried to get a little closer, the chimpanzee would run away. &quot;That was probably when I was most depressed.&quot; Jane Goodall said. Even more frightening is that sometimes, chimpanzees can become aggressive when facing strangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the New York Times, Jane Goodall recalled that the chimpanzees would sometimes climb up the tree screaming, their hair standing on end, shaking the branches vigorously, and hitting her on the head with branches. At this time, she could only pretend to be calm, not look at them, dig some small holes in the ground and eat some leaves. After the chimp left, her legs began to tremble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, after several months of observation, the chimpanzees gradually got used to her presence and accepted her. The closer she got to chimpanzees, the more Jane Goodall discovered that they are so similar to humans. They also have emotions such as fear and jealousy, and they can even make tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One morning, Jane Goodall ran through three valleys, but she didn&#39;t even see a shadow of a chimpanzee. Just as she was struggling through the steep slope to the top of the peak, there was movement in the grass sixty meters away. Jane Goodall raised the telescope in her hand and saw a chimpanzee squatting next to a termite nest in red clay. A long and thin straw stick is inserted into the termite hole and then lifted up to lick it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days later, she observed a group of chimpanzees going to a termite nest, picking up a branch with leaves on it, then plucking the leaves from it, and shaping it into a handy tool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, people have believed that only humans can make tools. This discovery by Jane Goodall is almost subversive. When she telegraphed this to Louis Leakey, he was so excited that he responded: Humanity must be redefined, or chimpanzees must be recognized as human beings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/ccl0MFXqinTiK7UTwh1Uvrs9nSjYGFtwQNQCyMRy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/ccl0MFXqinTiK7UTwh1Uvrs9nSjYGFtwQNQCyMRy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In recent years, Jane Goodall has remained committed to animal and environmental protection, giving lectures around the world, calling on people to be aware of the endangered living situation of chimpanzees and protect ape habitats. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I can&#39;t leave, this is my life&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>; Jane Goodall once wanted to be a man when she was a child, &quot;Maybe it was because men could do what I wanted to do at that time, but women could not.&quot; At that time, even though she made important discoveries about chimpanzees, with the praise came doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think that because she is an untrained young woman, her research results are not worth mentioning. Some people think that she is famous because of her appearance - she is tall and has beautiful blond hair. Many newspapers at that time emphasized her female identity when publishing, and some even used her beauty as a gimmick. For example, one newspaper&#39;s title was &quot;Beauty and Her Beasts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People think I&#39;m famous because of my legs, which is stupid, and I don&#39;t take it to heart, but fame is useful because then I have to raise money myself.&quot; Jane Goodall said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She may be able to try her best to ignore outside comments about her gender and appearance, but for her, it is more difficult to achieve a balance between family and career. After Jane Goodall made her important discovery about chimpanzees, Louise Leakey received a grant from the National Geographic Society, allowing her to continue studying chimpanzees. At the same time, the National Geographic Society also sent a photographer, Hugo Van Rawick, to record the chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to guess the direction of the story. Jane Goodall and photographer Hugo fell in love, got married, and studied chimpanzees in Gombe together. Later, however, the National Geographic Society stopped funding Hugo, and his mission as a photographer ended. It was a period of difficult decisions for them. Jane Goodall wanted to continue studying chimpanzees in Gombe, but Hugo could not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was Jane Goodall who made the sacrifice initially. She spent most of her time with Hugo in the Serengeti, Africa, while Hugo photographed wildlife while she wrote books and took care of her son Guerra. At that time, she served more as Hugo&#39;s assistant and Guerra&#39;s mother. For her work in Gombe, she no longer tracks chimpanzees and is primarily responsible for managing the research station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, something unexpected happened again, and the polio epidemic suddenly broke out among the chimpanzees in Gombe. Jane Goodall returned to Gombe and decided to spend more time with Gombe&#39;s chimpanzees. At that time, her son was also with her. In the morning, she would analyze data and manage administration, spend an hour or two at the chimpanzee camp observing them, and spend the afternoon with her son Guerra. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But humans are group animals after all, and Jane Goodall understood the importance of sociality. When Guerra reached school age, Jane Goodall had to send him back to England to study. When she was separated from Guerra, she was sad and felt like she had betrayed him. As for her relationship with her husband Hugo, due to the long-term separation between the two places, the relationship seemed to be coming to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hugo told Jane Goodall that they had to decide how to live in the future. He needed someone to stay with him in the savannah of the Serengeti, and asked her if she would leave Gombe for him. Jane Goodall wrote to her mother for help. &quot;There is no one who cannot be lost... There is no such thing as heartbreak for men. Their work always comes first, and their dreams. Women are just used to set off.&quot; The mother&#39;s reply read. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jane Goodall made a choice, &quot;I can&#39;t leave, this is my life, and he also has his ideals.&quot; They eventually divorced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Documentary director Brett Morgan interpreted their relationship in an interview with POV magazine, &quot;I think it&#39;s a love story, but it&#39;s not about Jane and Hugo. I think it&#39;s about women. and her career, and the man and his career. Because the real love in the film, the otherworldly love, is their career.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Morgan interviewed Jane∙ in Gombe for the documentary Goodall, he realized, for the couple, &quot;this is a happy ending.&quot; Hugo remained in the Serengeti for the rest of his life photographing wildlife and became recognized as one of the best wildlife photographers of all time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jane Goodall continues to study chimpanzees and write books. Starting in 1986, her focus changed, and she realized that if the plight of African chimpanzees was to be known to the world, the next generation must become better conservationists. Since then, she has been traveling to various countries and cities giving lectures almost 300 days a year. Until now, she has been committed to environmental protection and animal conservation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How long will you study chimpanzees?&quot; Jane Goodall was asked in an interview, and her answer was:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think until I die&quot; that day, but I can’t tell you how many years are left.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这古典探案剧，野心真大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Looking at the famous scenes of domestic suspense dramas, &quot; Li Toyota lit a cigarette in reverse.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/11de423cd6866c95c00a4475d3f942df.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/11de423cd6866c95c00a4475d3f942df.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255223&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Ning The physics teacher had a new memory point - extinguishing candles with bare hands and pulling out teeth. The Song Dianshi he played took off his leather gloves and used his severed fingers to wipe away the burning candlelight; if the prisoner was dishonest during interrogation, he would first use pliers to extract a tooth before interrogating him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5ba5c6aeb5058311a4b8eaad0e95578c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;320&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5ba5c6aeb5058311a4b8eaad0e95578c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4b5142b006d8f9b1f196f0d263062d3f.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4b5142b006d8f9b1f196f0d263062d3f.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255219&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two clips are from the popular new drama &quot;Fanchengzhi&quot; Down&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1e175ec5605213aae8ab359171a472cc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1919&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1e175ec5605213aae8ab359171a472cc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255220&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the Ming Dynasty , Jiangnan County, serial murders occurred frequently, the deaths were horrific, and strange poems were left at the scene. The first victim&#39;s apprentice, Qu Sangeng (played by Bai Yufan), and Yamen&#39;s official Song Chen (played by Ning Li) join the game and solve the case with other companions...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When following this drama, there is always a kind of thing to watch. The feeling of &quot;Along the River During Qingming Festival&quot;. &quot;Along the River During the Qingming Festival&quot; is a genre painting by the Northern Song Dynasty painter Zhang Zeduan. It is very long and full of details. What comes to mind is the antique style and worldly sentiments. Looking more closely, there are many characters with different shapes, and there are twists and turns behind each person. A long story; magnify it 10 times and it will give you a different scenery. It is rumored that there are unknown secrets hidden in the pictures, and there are lice crawling in the Chinese clothes. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This coincides with &quot;Under the City&quot;. The plot unfolds by peeling off the cocoon, using Jingwei County to observe the style of the late Ming Dynasty, lamenting the fate of the characters, and watching the moths walking through the sturdy towers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;World conditions, society and the style of the late Ming Dynasty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When viewing paintings, it is important to first look at the overall situation, and the same is true for watching dramas. When you open &quot;Under the City&quot;, you will be drawn into the story by its highly restored late Ming aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stylization is its key word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smoky alleys covered with green moss due to perennial humidity, the smoky willow alleys with the setting sun reflected in the fragrance of rotten flowers, the yamen torture chambers with no sunlight and only the smell of blood...these seemingly inadvertent... The lens is full of long-lasting charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6ffe9ed43a58c151859bba963bc768bd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;2700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6ffe9ed43a58c151859bba963bc768bd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Preliminary art work When planning the design, the crew scanned many ancient architectural models for reference, and made more than 60 sets of three-dimensional models and more than 150 atmosphere pictures. The scenery and furnishings pursue realism and freehand brushwork, and perfectly restore the style of the late Ming Dynasty in a balance between reality and reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2e329b69043fad7c8d8e0ef480f8ce95.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;961&quot; height= &quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2e329b69043fad7c8d8e0ef480f8ce95.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255221&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each role They are all designed with matching looks. The book boy Lu Zhi alone has 16 outfits. The police uniform that Qu Sangen often wears is designed based on the historical data of the Ming Dynasty and incorporates the texture of ink. The easily overlooked waist accessories reveal the differences in status between people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4727c1fdf575eecbc3eec34640648f40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4727c1fdf575eecbc3eec34640648f40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;服道化是最直观的量尺，可以精准标刻出年代的风貌。只有建构了真实可信的环境，才能让观众进入剧情，更好地沉浸在繁城谜案之间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，本剧采取的是2.042:1宽银幕画幅，区别于传统的4:3或16:9画幅。宽度的延展意味着：镜头的景深更丰富，视效也更接近目触所及，得以提升观众的沉浸感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/adc88ec691b90e917c122de13ba898f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1623&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/adc88ec691b90e917c122de13ba898f0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;叙事视角与古典探案&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看《清明上河图》，时常会觉得眼花缭乱，左眼观郊野春意，右眼看河畔店肆。 《繁城之下》与它一样，从任何一个视角切入都可以丝滑进入不同叙事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1-3集主打小捕快曲三更的视角，师傅冷捕头之死以他的主观镜头呈现。师傅惨死，夫子丧命，旧仆现尸，凶手猖獗，三更浑浑噩噩地周旋在不同势力间查案，意外发现了20年前的陆家失火案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/91b6957ac720f205122ffde0fbee597e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/91b6957ac720f205122ffde0fbee597e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255225&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和同侪高士聪、挚友凤可追交游；慰问师娘和师妹；走访旧案证人……曲三更的社会关系铺陈开来，引入了各怀心事的小人物们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/e7e4b9a7330a5fc284c36cb576d22c04.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/e7e4b9a7330a5fc284c36cb576d22c04.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了第4集，剧情陡然一转至20年前，陆府尚且兴旺，话头交给了他们家的书童陆直。他为人聪明伶俐，深得陆府上下欢心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fed6dff701201c04cabac9dfa68e3b75.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fed6dff701201c04cabac9dfa68e3b75.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255230&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;借由他的视角，陆老爷、仆人陈旺、哑巴忠爷逐一登场，热热闹闹的陆府藏着许多秘密。陆直在不经意间发现冷捕头与陆老爷情人的恋爱关系，也知道了王夫子和学生的奇怪关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/cd5a1449ca797fb69e77f9662ec00431.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/cd5a1449ca797fb69e77f9662ec00431.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255231&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到这里再回想前3集的命案，会惊讶地发现：似乎一切都对上了，冷捕头、王夫子、陈旺都与当年的陆家有千丝万缕的联系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第5集又变为全知视角，一股脑倒给了看客新线索：衙门里来了急于立威的新捕头、曲三更和高士聪继续缉凶，以及街坊邻居嘴里的作祟猴妖。看似离题的闲笔猴妖案，又牵起了前尘旧案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每集的时长还不一样，没有刻意划分为45分钟一集，以段落的起与收为时间标记节点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;叙事视角不同，观众就能接收到不同信息，既能共情一心追凶的三更，又能屏气凝神地跟着陆直一探旧日渊源，还能在街市碎语中闲闲地搭只耳朵。前尘、今夕，旧事、新案，被灵活地串联在了一起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代悬疑剧往往走的是社会派的路子，以本剧为代表的古代悬疑则扎根于精巧扎实的古典主义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《繁城之下》强调逻辑至上，以解谜和诡计为核心：骇人的连环命案是开胃前菜，重头戏则是案中案、谜中谜、情中情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20年前，粉饰太平的陆府暗流涌动，被收养的“干少爷”陆直好奇心重得很，翻搅着成人世界的诸多奥秘，也窥探出了看似不相干之人的隐情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7e9a57a888937c8a370640eab69e6c2f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7e9a57a888937c8a370640eab69e6c2f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255232&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他是陆府失火案中的幸存者，也是连接过去和现在时空的一把钥匙，就像那只神秘莫测的灵猴一样行踪不明。 20年后的死者皆是昔日的局中人，那么，谁又是做局者呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;棘手的问题被抛给了捕快曲三更，他和同伴走街串巷、四处探访，从案牍库到烟柳巷都遍布了他们的足迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0ab156112d7688742ce91053be888f74.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0ab156112d7688742ce91053be888f74.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255234&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;探案不借助怪力乱神，也没有高新科技助力，单靠脑力和腿力，可以说是相当符合古代传统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b64e9a8d6036eadcb18af6669bace0aa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b64e9a8d6036eadcb18af6669bace0aa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255236&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，由于剧集独特的叙事方式，不对观众藏掖信息，不用镜头语言误导，故观众得知的信息量总是大于捕快。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们比曲三更早一步知道冷捕头的死亡方式，也先于他知晓20年前陆直的遭遇，期待的是捕快如何将碎片拼成一张图的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人物命运与社会生态链&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看《清明上河图》的时候第一感觉是：繁荣、人多。但若半卷画轴，放大研读，会看到细节里隐藏的盛世暗影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初看《繁城之下》，也觉市井繁荣、人声鼎沸。官吏乡绅、贩夫走卒、烟花女子，各路人马走马灯似的登场，粗粗勾勒出了蠹县人物群像。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当显微镜拉近，你会发现上至州府县官，下至平民百姓，都被纳入严密相扣的社会生态链中，处处都是机巧暗隐的博弈局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典史宋辰、冷捕头等人具备特定职权，但归根结底还是困在日益僵化的系统里、另用一套隐规则行事的基层小吏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典史是县令的佐杂官，无具体品阶但受命于皇帝签批，掌管缉捕、监狱等事务，所以宋辰对捕头有一定威慑力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;捕头统领的快班负责缉凶查案，皂班负责升堂打板，像剧中高士聪这样花钱进来当个临时工的人不少。所以一旦有事，高士聪们就是第一批辞退的对象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5434e1d86ea7305ac52af7967a2ad966.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;1428&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5434e1d86ea7305ac52af7967a2ad966.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空降的夏捕头是衙门最害怕的一类人，因为短时间内很难摸清他的背景。于是平常耀武扬威的小吏只有被打板子的命，忍痛看他立威。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1eafb08470d481b123abd98e742c34fc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1eafb08470d481b123abd98e742c34fc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255235&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“皇权不下县”这句俗语精准描绘了封建时代郡县以下的权力真空地带，底层官吏拥有了灵活自治的权力，因而基层治理也依赖黑白管理体制，对百姓是一个样子，对流氓恶霸又是另外的办法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冷捕头生前拿捏住了访行打行的命脉，并与其达成了稳固的合作关系，只要不涉及拐卖妇孺等伤天害理之事便睁一只眼闭一只眼，访行打行每月“孝敬”他固定数额的银两，用得着的时候也代行一些脏活累活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明朝官吏俸禄很低，心思活络之人便在别处想办法。冷捕头吃下的回扣，还会补贴一部分给快班的下属们。但也有如宋辰般清廉之吏，他一月的工资只够去见一次相好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/231e1c0322880ddcc2b8e159ef935769.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/231e1c0322880ddcc2b8e159ef935769.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255238&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冷捕头死后，换作皂班易捕头和打行做交易，但他手黑心贪，拿着账本以权谋钱，破坏了微妙的平衡，引发群氓众怒不说，还促使曲三更以计谋端掉访行打行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eebae343f522ea7228e4ce7967f31088.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;1825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eebae343f522ea7228e4ce7967f31088.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255237&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用计一段很是高明，犹如一出古代官场现形记。他利用了易捕头贪得无厌的弱点，假意投诚却暗中使绊，在捕头与打行的矛盾里坐收渔翁之利。他还借着出主意让易捕头触犯宋辰两袖清风的雷区，最后落得里外不是人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6a96d12fe399c1c84c5827957b4564e3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6a96d12fe399c1c84c5827957b4564e3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说起来，曲三更是剧中成长弧光最饱满的角色。一开始是个直肠子的爽快人，他不用深谙底层官吏的生存法则，自有如师如父的冷捕头庇护周全；师傅死后他被迫成长，开始做一些之前不愿沾染之事，如在三教九流间利用斡旋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他本质上和宋辰是同一类人，在淤泥里待久了难免戴上黑手套，但心里有一团公义之火，照亮他们仰望前路。不难推测，宋辰会是他新的指路人，将代行其师傅的职责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fbe94e7cb0ef6cfa0d2ece822efa9598.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fbe94e7cb0ef6cfa0d2ece822efa9598.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说完了小吏，再来说说平民，他们的生态链同样是“大鱼吃小鱼、小鱼吃虾米”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曲三更在街面上阻拦了一起欺压百姓之事，打行人扮黑脸，他们找来的假秀才扮白脸，局中局，套中套，为的就是吞并老汉的房产。不识字的老汉若不得三更相助，将会是成百上千受害百姓中的一员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/473301c62431b66e80654a0145bc0c60.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;904&quot; height=&quot;1465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/473301c62431b66e80654a0145bc0c60.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陆家的书童陆直天性聪颖，陆老爷高兴的时候一拍大腿，直呼给他脱贱籍，让他考个功名。明代不允许贱民参与科考，除非疏通关系脱离贱籍，另外曲三更这些胥吏也无科考权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f705ffc52289396448673bf882f0bb19.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;669&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f705ffc52289396448673bf882f0bb19.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为何陆老爷花点银子就能办好户籍之事？因为他是当地乡绅，还认识举人。明代举人数目众多，想当官得等着空缺，但不管如何，社会地位远高于普通大众，例如剧中的薛举人住着大宅，养着仆人，遣人走动着与小吏的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从蠹县的社会生态链来看，《繁城之下》不仅是一部古代悬疑剧，还是全幅度、多细节的明末实录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何谓蠹县？ “蠹”即蛀虫。这个阴晴不定的繁城有瓜果的芬香，也有爬行的腐虫。曲三更、宋辰、陆直他们，有人拿明牌，有人站暗桩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b4fe9e9f6a1e03eb55fa6e299b4297fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b4fe9e9f6a1e03eb55fa6e299b4297fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三人的名字也起得意味深远：“曲”和“直”是一对反义词，但“公道是一条绕了二十年的远路”，谁挠曲，谁枉直？ “辰”即辰光，阴暗角落里断指沾血之人会带来辰光吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a0939bb0c113b9855b6ad5d65f3fc942.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;904&quot; height=&quot;1027&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a0939bb0c113b9855b6ad5d65f3fc942.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在最新的剧情中，宋辰的隐秘过往被揭开，曲三更主动入狱寻求破局之道，而城中的猴妖抓捕大戏也愈演愈烈，陆直是否改名换姓有了新身份呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看似站在对立面的曲宋与陆直，其实都是微不足道的小人物，而一个无所依靠的人想在系统里获得他认定的公义绝非易事，必然要付出常人想不到的艰辛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写案、写人只是《繁城之下》的表层，归根结底，它直指的是身不由心的时运及命运悲剧、湮没在时代车轮下的恸哭哀鸣，以及山雨欲来的封建社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它让人想到了同属腾讯视频X剧场的另一部剧——《漫长的季节》，它们都以案件开局，都又不止步于悬案，而是有更大的野心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;个人挽歌在时代洪流中，被记录，被镌刻。公义或许会来迟，但不会缺席，就像阴雨连绵的蠹县，总有光风霁月的一天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[居民医保一年减少2500万人？是真的但别误读，这个保险真值得买丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，有媒体称“居民医保一年减少2500万人”，并设问为什么有人主动退保，其认为：“除了正常自然减少的情况，一个重要原因是居民主动退保。这主要是因为保费持续上涨。2003年-2023年，20年时间，个人保费增长了37倍。第二个原因是，不少未参保的居民身体健康。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个解释是错误的。国家医保局《2022年医疗保障事业发展统计快报》说得很明白：截至2022年底，基本医疗保险参保人数134570万人。随着全国统一的医保信息平台上线，各省加大数据治理比对，参保人数主要由于清理重复参保同比减少1727万人……其中，参加职工基本医疗保险人数36242万人，同比增加811万人；参加城乡居民基本医疗保险人数98328万人，同比减少2538万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城乡居民基本医疗保险（简称“居民医保”），是由以前的城镇居民基本医疗保险与新农合合并而来的，以体现对城乡居民的一体平等医疗保障。其与城镇职工基本医疗保险（简称“职工医保”）的运作模式有显著差异，最大差异在于前者是自愿参保，后者是强制参保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，因为居民医保是自愿参保，当然可以主动退保或不参保，但这样做是不明智的。因为居民医保个人每年出几百元保费是小头，政府补贴才是大头，无论男女老少，个人的优势策略是年年买、不断保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上海为例，上海居民医保个人缴费标准相比其他省份是较高的。 2022年，少儿学生个人缴费220元，财政补贴1660元，后者是前者的7.5倍；15-59周岁个人缴费860元，财政补贴2750元，后者是前者的3.2倍；60-69周岁个人缴费690元，财政补贴5940元，后者是前者的8.6倍；70周岁以上个人缴费520元，财政补贴6110元，后者是前者的11.8倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为个人，如果不需要强制参加职工医保，你会自愿参加居民医保吗？参加后会选择退保吗？答案是不言而喻的。说到底，居民医保是个人出小头+政府财政补贴出大头的筹款模式。当然，再往下推一步，政府财政收入或税收来自工作者与企业缴纳的税金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比较而言，职工医保是强制参保，以个人税前工资为基数，费率一般是个人缴纳2%，企业缴纳8%，有些城市养老负担重的，企业费率还会高一些。当然，无论是以个人还是企业的名义缴费，本质上都是个人全部工资或企业全部用工成本的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职工医保个人最低与最高缴费基数是当地社会平均工资的60%与300%，也就是说，两个人，一个顶格缴最高保费，另一个顶格缴最低保费，前者的缴费是后者的5倍，但这两人除了个人账户余额不一样之外，门诊及住院享受的报销比例是一样的，与个人缴费多少完全无关。这反映了职工医保的代内转移支付属性：高收入者对低收入者的转移支付。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就导致一些效应：某些处于自由竞争行业、成本敏感的“边际企业”，对于员工参加职工医保，策略是只让“正式员工”参加，或者做低员工税前工资，因为，在企业眼里，职工医保强制缴费有显著的税性，自然是能避就避了；某些人是灵活就业或自由职业，TA明智的做法是不参加职工医保，因为“太贵了”，而选择参加居民医保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再对比一下居民医保与职工医保参保者享受的医疗待遇。囿于文章篇幅，这里略过门诊不谈，只比较住院报销比例。不难发现，在两者个人支付成本相差悬殊的前提下，居民医保参保者的住院报销比例比职工医保低得并不多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样以上海为例。目前居民医保住院或急诊观察室报销比例，在50-300元的费用自负段之上，婴幼儿与学生为80%(一级)-70%(二级)-60%(三级)，19至59周岁为80%(一级)-75%(二级)-60%(三级)，60至69周岁为90%(一级)-80%(二级)-70%(三级)，70周岁以上为70%(一级)-60%(二级)-50%(三级)，括号内为医院等级。医院等级越低，报销比例越高，这是鼓励参保者尽量去基层医院。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比较而言，目前职工医保住院或急诊观察室，在职职工报销比例，起付标准以上、最高支付限额以下为85%，最高限额以上为80%；退休职工报销比例，起付标准以上、最高限额以下为92%，最高支付限额以上为80%。比居民医保报销比例是要高一些。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此不难看出职工医保的代际转移支付属性：工作者、年轻人与下一代对退休者、老年人与上一代的转移支付，或者可以直观理解为“所有的子女养所有的父母”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，无论居民医保还是职工医保，虽然名为保险，但和一般商业保险的运作逻辑是不一样的。商业保险，会根据参保人的年龄与健康状况，精算确定与收取保费，患有某些疾病会被拒保，个人参保前不能隐瞒某些疾病否则可能被拒赔。如果每年收取一个固定的保费，其实意味着会在年轻时多收一些，因为年轻时生病的概率低，收取的保费扣除当年的消费额就是所谓的“现金价值”。而政府医保，并不会因参保人的年龄太大或身体太差而拒保，也不会根据个人的年龄与健康状况精算保费。所以，这是一种保障(Security)。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，如果你父母在城里无业或在乡下，督促或替他们购买居民医保是明智的选择。在此基础上，再给他们购买大病医疗互助补充保险也是不错的选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[莫砺锋：“花瓣飘落的方向，是风决定的”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259413]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;博士档案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;莫砺锋，新中国第一位文学博士。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1949年4月，出生于江苏省无锡市。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963-1966年，江苏省苏州高级中学读高中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1968-1977年，在江苏省太仓县和安徽省泗县插队务农。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年-1979年，安徽大学外文系英语专业本科生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979-1981年，南京大学中文系中国古代文学专业硕士研究生，师从程千帆先生，获文学硕士学位。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1982年，成为南京大学中文系古代文学专业博士研究生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984年10月，毕业于南京大学中国古代文学专业。钱仲联、程千帆、唐圭璋、徐中玉等大师级学者和300多位南大师生共同见证了莫砺锋博士学位论文答辩。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984年起在南京大学任教。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2006-2007年，成为央视百家讲坛主讲人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2014年，被评为南京大学人文社会科学资深教授。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020年9月，任南京大学梅庵书院首任院长。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2022年5月，退休。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;曾任南京大学文学院教授、博士生导师，南京大学中文系主任，南京大学中国诗学研究中心主任，第八届、九届江苏省政协委员，第十届江苏省政协常委。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;学术兼职有全国古籍整理与出版规划小组成员，教育部社会科学委员会委员，中国唐代文学学会顾问，中国宋代文学学会名誉会长，江苏省中国古代文学学会名誉会长，复旦大学中国古代文学研究中心学术委员会委员。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/EeaIWbul4Ebi5tmXLkYQgKN31ihMAUMhBpO6pPm4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/EeaIWbul4Ebi5tmXLkYQgKN31ihMAUMhBpO6pPm4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255706&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月12日，莫砺锋在自家书房。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者魏翠翠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月23日，在南京大学文学院的一堂“唐宋文学研究”课上，一百多号学生挤满了教室。讲桌上放着一个黑色保温杯和一个素色背包，一位身着淡蓝色长袖衬衫，戴着无框眼镜的老先生端坐在讲台上说道，“感谢南大的同学至今没有把我轰下讲坛，让我完整地走完了教书生涯。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老先生叫莫砺锋，是南京大学文学院教授、南京大学中国诗学研究中心主任、梅庵书院首任院长，74岁的他当天完成了教学生涯的最后一课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1979年9月，莫砺锋考进南大，开始从事古代文学的学习，之后留校任教，至此已经是第44个年头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鲜为人知的是，莫砺锋还是新中国的首位文学博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1981年，国务院学位委员会公布了新中国第一批博士生导师名单，这批代表着当时学术界最高水准的业界精英培养出了新中国首批博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1984年10月，莫砺锋博士论文答辩登上了中央电视台的新闻联播，他也拿到了新中国成立后的第一张文学博士学位证书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为中国古代文学研究领域的资深教授，莫砺锋的前半生却与古代文学毫无关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1949年4月，莫砺锋出生于江苏无锡。1966年，高三毕业时，他报考志愿全填的是清华的工科专业。当年7月，高考招生暂停，成为工程师的梦想在瞬间破碎。此后十年，他下乡插队，在田间地头度过苦涩的青春时光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1977年恢复高考，他的人生迎来转机——进入安徽大学英语专业学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尔后，随着改革开放启幕，研究生教育恢复，莫砺锋再次抓住机会。1979年，也就是研究生考试恢复的第二年，在安徽大学英文系学习三个学期后，他考取南京大学中文系研究生，走上古代文学的研究道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;退休后的他依然致力于唐宋诗词普及工作，办讲座、参加书展……他曾说最大的心愿是做一个站在唐诗宋词“仙山秘境”入口处，向游客指点入山之路，解说沿途风景的导游，告诉大家，哪里别有风味，哪里又曲径通幽。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，江南阴雨连绵，路人行色匆匆，梧桐的树叶随着雨滴一起落下。在南京玄武区的一处居民小区里，莫砺锋聊起他的人生经历，他引用南朝哲学家范缜关于“随风飘落的花瓣”的比喻来形容自己的命运——“树上的花瓣被风吹落下来，飘落的方向不是花瓣决定的，而是风决定的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;除了读书别无他途&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在之前的采访中常常提及你的父亲，还讲过“兄弟姐妹与爸爸比赛背唐诗”的场景，你对文学的这种热爱是从家庭环境中萌芽的吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的父亲来自河南农村，初中读了一年多，遇日寇侵华，他辍学当兵，解放后一直在地方供销社工作，母亲也只读过初中一年级。小时候家里穷，读唐诗是因为家中正好有一本《唐诗三百首》，父亲喜欢，我们也跟着读。直到高中毕业，下乡插队后才较多地接触到古典作品。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母对我的影响和我现在从事的专业没有任何关系，他们对我最大的影响在于做人很诚恳，很勤劳，以及与人为善的生活态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在求学之路上，你表现一直都很优异，高考志愿填了清华的电机工程系、数学力学系，却在高考之前得知高考暂停，当时如何面对这种巨大的落差？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我当时在苏州中学上高中，这所学校非常好。我读中小学时在语文上表现得一般，但数理化还不错。我1966年高中毕业，但那一年正好废除高考，1966届到1968届前后三届的初高中生全部下乡，大学停止招生。大家都很失望，但我们没有选择，只好面对。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在1968年深秋开始下乡，在下乡的十年里，劳作之余，都在孜孜不倦地读书，甚至精读了一本《新名词辞典》，你还曾提及点煤油灯读书的经历。那时的阅读环境是怎样的，留给你的阅读时间多吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实阅读时间不多。集体劳动占据大量时间，那时江南农村真是精耕细作，每天下地的时间很长。只有在下大雨以及春节前后，地里才没活儿，那些日子可以看书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村里没通电，只能点煤油灯照明，一个月定额供应一斤煤油，一周就点完，也买不到更多。所以，基本上天黑就必须睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我读的书也杂乱无章，因为到手的书都是偶然得来，完全不知道下一本能读到什么书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;其他大部分人在做什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我有很多知青伙伴基本不读书，而是打扑克。那时流行彻底的“读书无用论”，我们参加农业劳动用镰刀和锄头，生产队养了6头牛犁地，这些农业劳动都不需要书本知识，大家都认为读书是很傻的事。1972年，大学开始招收工农兵学员，但名额很少，采取推荐制，大部分人没有进入大学的希望，我更没有。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这种彻底的“读书无用论”的情况下，你为什么爱读书？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这有多方面的原因。一是我喜欢读书，要是完全不读书，我会觉得人生毫无意义。二是我当时被彻底剥夺了上大学的机会，心里愤愤不平，决心像高尔基那样读完“我的大学”。自修式的学习，除了读书别无他途。下乡五六年以后，我彻底断绝了这辈子再进大学的希望，事实上已经没有任何可能。那时上面号召我们一辈子“扎根农村”，我已在心里准备一辈子当个喜欢读书的农民，耕读本是我们的老祖宗提倡的一种生活方式。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我隐隐约约地感觉到，“读书无用论”的现状是不正常的，它迟早会结束，只是不知道到底要拖到何年何月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/kfYND0AoqQx1wySkbrnVoXKWkoIQEKvbM5MTtRq9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/kfYND0AoqQx1wySkbrnVoXKWkoIQEKvbM5MTtRq9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255704&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1979年，莫砺锋考取南京大学中文系研究生，走上古代文学的研究道路。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;报考时，不知道程千帆是谁&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在1977年参加高考时报考安徽大学英文系的契机是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我那时人在安徽，当年省里招生规定，考生年龄不得超过25周岁，只有“学有专长”的老三届高中生才允许超龄报考。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我那时28岁，高中毕业已经11年了，但我没有任何专长。公社里的文教干事同情我。他注意到，我那段时间在读一本很厚的英文原版小说，是我从同学的舅舅那里借来的，干事认定我专长英文，就允许我以“专长英语”的资格报名参加高考。入学后，我发现有的同学其实是随意填报“学有专长”的，也根本没人来考核，但我比较老实，于是报了英文专业，就考进安徽大学的英文系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年改革开放的当年，研究生教育也恢复了，而你当时在安徽大学英文系学习3个学期，就毅然决定报考南京大学中文系的研究生，这么做的初衷是什么？&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;初衷很简单，每个月的助学金能从18元涨到35元。我在安大每月能领到18元助学金，手头十分拮据。我从安大宿舍出发到省教育厅去查阅各著名大学的招生目录的那个早晨，都还没有想过要报考中文系。我本想考南大的外文系，但外文系要考第二外语——法语、德语或西班牙语。而我没学过，只能临时改成中文系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你报考研究生时才大二，这在当时应该不常见？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大二考研究生本是不被允许的，但当时比较特殊。我们77级本科生普遍的情况是学生年龄偏大，我班最大的与最小的相差13岁。那时安大外语系的英语专业分7个班，我在7班。6班是快班，很多同学来自北京、上海，英语基础不错，他们认为自身已具备本科毕业的水平。于是，他们向学校提出提前考研的要求，学校一开始不同意，但他们不停地去磨，最终校方松口说，考虑到你们年纪比较大，再读四年本科，毕业时已三十好几，才决定开这个口子。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们班同学撺掇我跟着6班的同学一起去考研。结果我碰巧考上，于是到南大来读中国古代文学。最有意思的是，我报考时，对南大的古代文学学科一无所知，看到招生简章上的导师是程千帆先生，我压根不知道他是谁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从理工科到英语，再到古代文学，在做这些重要选择时，是否有些一以贯之的原则或者理念，你如何看待其中的偶然性和必然性？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这些都不是我决定的，而是命运决定的，我是顺遂命运者。我最近几年常说，我们就像树上的花瓣，被风一吹就飘下来，事先根本不知道飘到哪里，飘的方向不是花瓣决定的，而是风决定的。我就这样飘到南大。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偶然性中肯定包含着必然性，但从大环境来说还是偶然性。1966年如果不爆发“文革”，我要么考不上清华，要考上的话就会去学工科。我当时最大的理想是当工程师，我父亲对我的期望也是如此。可惜在他去世多年以后，我才进入大学。父亲没有看到我成为大学生、研究生以及大学教授，是我一生中最大的遗憾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老三届那一代人的命运差不多都是这样，很多事没有办法选择。当年有的同学侥幸被招工，但到城里后进哪个工厂，做什么工种，都只能听从安排。能招上工已经很幸运，我们都羡慕的不得了，毕竟能拿工资，而农民只能挣工分，一天工分的价值只有两三毛钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，这其中也有主观能动性。我一直没放弃读书，很多同学都放弃了。我在苏州中学有一些同班同学成绩很好，但恢复高考后他们早已结婚成家，有两三个娃，也就不想考了，他们后来很快就下岗，一辈子和大学无缘。这样的人很多，碰到那场“狂风”，一下被吹到泥淖里，再也没有翻身的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/lmKOzcxvroJZpvIKZIXnQFhta4ogGIFCqRVVjxH7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/lmKOzcxvroJZpvIKZIXnQFhta4ogGIFCqRVVjxH7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255705&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1980年，莫砺锋和导师程千帆在书房探讨学术问题。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;苦行僧式的培养&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你和程千帆先生的师生情谊也被大家称赞，你还记得和程先生第一次见面时的情景吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一次见到程先生时，他66岁，头发已经花白。他对我们说的第一句话是：“有很多考生考前来找我，到家里来见我，有的还带着礼物，只有你们3个人（莫砺锋和师兄徐有富以及师弟张三夕）连封信也没写过，这样很好！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979年你入学时学位条例还没有正式颁布，直到1981年国务院批准《学位条例暂行实施办法》，学位制度才正式建立。那时读博算不算冒险？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在1979年9月的开学典礼上，匡亚明校长说学位条例正在制定。他是国务院学位委员会的委员，参与这项工作。我们入学时不分硕士、博士，统称研究生。匡亚明校长说，你们以后会是第一批硕士和博士。两年后我们毕业，学位条例颁布了，我拿到硕士学位，后来又跟着程先生继续读博。我觉得读博是件好事，也完全没有“冒险”的感觉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在真正开始读博前，你对于博士生活的预期是怎样的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;也没有具体的预期，谁知道博士生涯是怎样的。我只是觉得读硕都那么辛苦、紧张，读博肯定只会更加紧张，所以心里做好了坐几年冷板凳的准备。反正我年轻时吃过不少苦，“曾经沧海难为水”，读博肯定不会比种地更辛苦。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那时我们还没有自主培养的博士，作为第一批文学博士的你们是怎么读博的，如何上课和撰写博士论文？据说你刚开始读博时，程先生也不知道博士论文要写到什么程度。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;确是如此，因为博士在中国属于新生事物。当时没有完整的课程体系，培养模式也是暗中摸索的。程先生也不知道博士论文要写到什么程度，他从学校图书馆里借来一堆国外已出版的博士论文，还有不少港台高校的博士论文，读了好几本，才心中有数。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;程先生的培养方式来自哪里，是如何形成的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得是他自己揣摩的，当然也可能是从国外或港台的博士论文的学术水准上推导出来的。由于当时全系只有我一个博士生，所以程先生没有为我在课堂开课，除了外语，我的课程学习完全采取专书阅读的方式，也就是自己读书，遇到难点去先生家请教。程先生规定我攻读8部典籍：《诗经》《楚辞》《论语、孟子》《老子、庄子》《左传》《史记》《文选》《文心雕龙》。每部书都要交读书报告，其中有4篇报告后来作为学术论文公开发表。那种培养模式有点像旧时的手艺人带学徒，师傅手把手地教，学徒边干活边学习。对于中国古代文学这样的学科，那种方式是相当有效的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年恢复研究生教育时，当年录取了1万人。如今，在读博士约为56万人。许多博士生不免担忧就业前景，对未来迷茫，文科博士更甚。你博士毕业时也会迷茫吗，以及如何看待他们当下的担忧和迷茫？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我1984年博士毕业时，分配工作，可以挑很多单位，最后我选择留在南大。那时国家培养的硕博人数少，客观上没有就业压力，这点跟现在很多文科博士的处境不一样。我很理解现在的同学们，现在博士生人数多，而岗位少。经过多年大规模研究生扩招，大部分单位都不缺人，所以就业越来越难。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这完全是时代的问题，不是个人的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的学生找工作也难。要是找不到工作，压力也会延伸到我这里。当然，今年毕业的3个博士生都已找到工作，分别去了四川大学、中南民族大学和浙江师范大学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/1oMhfOmrHc3MQsFfLDaH9gy2B27iG9KPackfRB5z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/1oMhfOmrHc3MQsFfLDaH9gy2B27iG9KPackfRB5z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255703&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2008年，莫砺锋在北京签售百家讲坛图书。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;致力于研究“大家”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾提及古代文学研究主要是做翻案工作，因为所有的观点都被人说过了，新观点就是做翻案文章。而你的研究对象多为杜甫、苏东坡、黄庭坚这些大家，选择研究这些“大家”的初衷是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实所有学术研究都是做翻案工作，理工科也一样。我在南大读博时，第一届全校就招了10位博士生，每个同学都来自不同系科。我们宿舍住3个人，一个化学系，一个计算机系，我跟他们交流，发现他们做研究，找题目写论文，跟我们一模一样，都是在前人成果的夹缝里面求生活，在很细小的方向上追求一些创新，补充或推翻前人的研究结果。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但对于古代文学学科来说，真正能代表一个时代学术成就的，应该是“大家”研究。一个时代的研究在整体上是否有突破，就看“大家”研究得如何。“小家”研究只是填补空白，不可能成为一个时代学术水准的象征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你最喜欢的两位诗人是杜甫和苏轼，甚至曾说愿意穿越到宋朝去黄州帮苏轼种地，你认为在研究杜甫和苏轼的过程中，他们带给你最大的体悟是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这可能跟程先生主张的“文学研究，感字当头”有关。我在进大学前开始阅读杜甫和苏轼，当时的唯一动机就是我喜欢他们，我读他们时感到亲切，得到安慰。我多次说过，当我在那座被狂风刮破屋顶的茅屋里过夜，眼看着满天繁星而冻得瑟瑟发抖的时候，杜甫的《茅屋为秋风所破歌》给我带来心灵的震撼。我种过十年地，我觉得自己当个农民并不算屈才。但我真心不愿意让苏东坡也在黄州开荒种地，他那样德才兼备的杰出人物有更重要的事情要做！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜、苏二人给我带来的最大体悟就是“安得广厦千万间”的人间情怀，和“一蓑烟雨任平生”的人生态度，我愿意尽我可能来宣扬他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在“大家”研究中是如何做到创新的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;真正的创新很难，我哪能做到。因为创新要求你比别人看得更深或更远，我没有那么高的水平。此外创新也需要偶然的机会，正好出现很好的新题目，或者很珍贵的新材料，这都是可遇不可求的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我只能尽量不人云亦云，不炒冷饭。我现在普及工作做得较多，讲一些常识性的内容，但如何将常识性内容讲得准确，要求也很高，这和学术的严谨性应该是统一的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;注意到从走进《百家讲坛》之后，你就一直致力于古典诗词的普及工作，开始做普及工作有什么契机？你曾说最大的心愿是做在唐诗宋词“仙山秘境”入口处的导游，这个愿望现在实现了吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我上《百家讲坛》也是偶然。南大百年校庆时，邀请央视的编导来录节目，录完后在《百家讲坛》播出，效果还不错，后来他们就来找我讲唐诗。节目播出后，很多观众来信，反响热烈，我感觉普及工作蛮有意义。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我现在最想达到的目的，是让普通读者和我一样喜欢唐诗宋词，喜欢杜甫和苏东坡。所谓普及，就是走出学校的小教室，走向社会的大教堂。让我欣慰的是，我开讲座时的听众里各个年龄层次各种身份的人都有，我真的走到社会大众中间，也算实现了自己的愿望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你认为古代文学的学术研究和普及工作在当下是否面临一些困境？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在的研究有概念化、碎片化的趋势，普及工作则有庸俗化的趋势。前者比如一定要强行发掘某些古典诗词中的现代性，实际上可能没有。如果生搬硬套一些新名词来贴标签，结论就不符合历史真相。还有一些学者选题过于细碎，意义不大。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;普及工作则有庸俗化的趋势。为了吸引观众，切合年轻人的口味，有不少戏说、曲解，而且把古人完整的意境弄得碎片化，缺乏整体感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有什么解决方法吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题难以避免，走向大众，必然会带来不同的口味和要求。我只能要求自己尽量做好。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对当下的年轻人，特别是大学生和研究生群体有什么人生建议吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我今年6月应邀到安徽大学参加毕业典礼并致辞。我40年前离开安大时没有获得毕业证书，如今以“杰出校友”的身份参加典礼，心中感慨万分。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在典礼上引用东坡的《定风波》来勉励学弟学妹们学习东坡的人生精神，来迎接自己的风雨人生。因为我们普通人的人生必然是充满风雨的，我们不能幻想走上一帆风顺的人生道路，所以一定要做好充分的思想准备。请让我引用在安大的致辞中的几句话来送给其他高校的大学生和研究生群体：“我衷心祝愿同学们像东坡那样始终以&#39;自强不息&#39;的积极态度来对待人生，有所作为。我也衷心希望同学们遇到人生坎坷时以&#39;一蓑烟雨任平生&#39;的格言自我勉励，从容应对！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[演唱会刷屏朋友圈，李健是中产抚慰者？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259370]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;When I miss you, you are in the sky; when I miss you, you are right in front of me.&quot; Recently, Li Jian held the &quot;Like the Sea&quot; online concert, which received more than 30 million views in 2 hours and quickly became a hit in the circle of friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s crowded entertainment industry, there are indeed few singers as lovable as Li Jian. We rarely hear music critics criticizing him, and we don’t see various marketing accounts on Weibo spreading any negative information about him. He is just famous, so popular that it is so natural and so popular that everyone expects it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/huSjlbT3I3FOoTHypGp5yeS64ovaHlSp8XRIbh88.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height= &quot;440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/huSjlbT3I3FOoTHypGp5yeS64ovaHlSp8XRIbh88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255635&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Birth: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Intellectual temperament&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Jian has such confidence. He graduated from Tsinghua University with a major in electronic engineering. Compared with many singers whose academic qualifications or cultural qualities are “meager”, Li Jian is outstanding. “Tsinghua top student” is an extremely enviable status, but it is also different from our expectations of science and engineering. The impression that a man is slovenly, unkempt, and ordinary-looking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s more important is Li Jian’s intellectual temperament. Li Jian’s home is neatly filled with records and books. The records he listens to include Leonard Cohen, The Beatles, Freshly Ground, Michael Buble, and Fabio Zanon, and the books he reads include Borges, Zweig, and Lawrence Bubble. Locke, George Orwell, and the last thing he took out was Leonard Cohen&#39;s biography &quot;I&#39;m Your Man.&quot; He has the sobriety and self-control of an intellectual. He consciously keeps a certain distance from the materialistic world and pursues advancement in the spiritual world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From his song selection, we can also see his independent temperament. Some people say that he is a &quot;musical poet&quot;, but in fact, he highlights more of his &quot;musical pride.&quot; For example, the online concert included 10 private covers and 14 original works, explaining his inner feelings about the sea and poetry. Li Jian is always singing in a low voice. He does not show off his skills or hit the high notes. His melody is soft and beautiful, and his singing voice is ethereal and graceful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the side of Li Jian&#39;s birth - he does not pursue external fame and wealth, but rather his pursuit, pride and persistence as an independent individual. In the lavish entertainment industry, he has not lost himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eAAaCHmRWWJ7NoJc5uuf8J6QNxhWB6R48hPNeYUt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height= &quot;440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eAAaCHmRWWJ7NoJc5uuf8J6QNxhWB6R48hPNeYUt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255636&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Entering the WTO: I wish the newly graduated &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;all the best&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If this was all Li Jian looked like, maybe it would be difficult for him to be so lovable. After all, there are many aloof singer-songwriters in the music industry - for example, Liang Bo, whose song &quot;Soul Singer&quot; shocked everyone, but his popularity and audience base are far less than those of Li Jian, not to mention other niche singers. What is unique about Li Jian is that he also has a worldly side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Li Jian is not obsessed with material things, he is able to live a good life. He works out, travels, knows coffee, has a special tea room at home, and collects records... Every time he appears in front of the camera, his clothes always make people feel comfortable and comfortable. Li Jian&#39;s life has a cold style. He is not a popular brand that can be seen everywhere on the street. He is Fendi, LV and Hermes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some interviews, you can see that Li Jian is concerned about some issues that arise in social development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the topic &quot;I hope everyone will experience less setbacks and hardships&quot; became a hot topic on Weibo. Not long ago, he told young people at a concert: &quot;I hope all people can live a simple and easy life.&quot; &quot;You can live a good life without putting in a lot of effort, especially those who have just graduated. It would be better if you experience less setbacks and tribulations. I wish you all the best.&quot; He is not cynical about the predicament. , not hoarse, but blessing and moving forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like his song selection, he is always singing about love, hometown, childhood, moonlight, stars, years and other beautiful things. He does not directly criticize vulgarity, but he sings about beautiful things in a tortuous way. this purpose. You might say Li Jian is &quot;conservative&quot;, but he is very safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s more, Li Jian is also a down-to-earth &quot;upright boy + cute jokester + cute foodie&quot;. He can dispel many serious and stereotyped ways of saying things with ease and make people smile. , and noticed his cuteness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, in Li Jianyan, birth and entry into the world are so perfectly combined. Many people can only do one thing, or they can&#39;t do even one thing well, or they are torn between the two. Li Jian perfectly possesses both. He is the personality ideal of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No wonder many comments say that Li Jian is the soul comforter of the middle class. Although Li Jian&#39;s fans include various groups, as media person Zhu Wei said, those who like Li Jian are mainly &quot;literary youth&quot;, &quot;petty bourgeoisie&quot; and &quot;well-educated and delicate emotional groups&quot;. These people belong to the middle class or pre-middle class. If there are any distinctive characteristics of China&#39;s middle class, one of them is the &quot;tearing&quot; between worldliness and worldliness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The middle class have a worldly side. They pursue material things, pursue style, keep to themselves, be conservative and moderate, and long for a quiet and peaceful life in this world. Unfortunately, for the sake of this quiet and peaceful life, they also Having to run around in the reinforced concrete forest of the metropolis, struggling to cope with the fast pace and complex interpersonal relationships in the workplace, and enduring huge life and mental stress, a stable and comfortable life seems out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So they have a worldly side. They want to escape from it all and ignore the house, car, children, and workplace. They want to carve out a spiritual home of their own and block out all the disturbances from the outside world. ; But if they really want to let go of all this, they will feel attached to and unwilling to accept it. The middle class is torn apart because they are unavailable no matter whether they are born in the world or join the world. So they often hesitate between the two, with Ma Yun on their left and Nebula on their right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jian was born perfectly and entered the world perfectly. He lived the way many middle-class people wanted to live, and in this way he became the comforter of the middle-class. Saying this is not to belittle Li Jian. Li Jian has no intention of playing such a role. He just happened to step on the node of the times-the middle class in this era is really tired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李克强同志逝世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259418]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 08:11:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 17th, 18th and 19th CPC Central Committee, State Council Comrade Li Keqiang, the former Prime Minister, was resting in Shanghai recently. He suffered a heart attack on October 26, 2023. After all-out rescue efforts, he failed. He died in Shanghai at 0:10 on October 27 at the age of 68. An obituary will be posted later. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“基因检测”挖出来的问题：清代战争制度与抱养继嗣风气]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259179]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, genetic testing has become popular, with dazzling commercial testing packages emerging one after another, and major genetic companies fiercely engaging in price wars , many people are eager to give it a try - the most attractive thing about genetic testing is the &quot;ancestry analysis&quot;: it claims to be able to find out where your ancestors came from and what ethnic origins you have. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The so-called &quot;ancestry analysis&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Human inheritance is mainly divided into three parts: paternal, maternal, and autosomal. Among them, paternal lineage tracing is more intuitive, which is to check the Y chromosome, because it can only be passed from father to son; while the principle of maternal lineage tracing is similar, which is to check mitochondrial genes. Mitochondria, regardless of gender, are obtained only from the mother. But both the Y chromosome and mitochondria only account for a very small part of the human genome. Each parent gives half of the autosomal chromosomes, accounting for more than 98%. It can be said that the autosomal chromosomes truly determine who you are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;ancestry analysis&quot; of various commercial tests basically use autosomal chromosomes as their biggest selling point. If you don&#39;t understand the principle, you may be misled - the so-called ancestry analysis is actually to sample and record the main groups of people from all over the world. Then use your test results to compare with the existing data in the file to see which groups of people are closest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So if you measure &quot;40% southern Han, 50% northern Han, 10% Mongolian&quot;, this does not mean that among your 100 ancestors, there are 40 southerners. 50 northerners, 10 Mongolians - this test result simply means that you are closest to the company&#39;s northern Han samples, followed by the southern Han samples, and finally the Mongolian samples. The autosomal data obtained by mixing these three samples in the above proportions is close to your test results, nothing more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we all know that there is no caste endogamy in East Asia, and the genes of the northern and southern populations must be gradually changing. In addition, different institutions take different samples, and the result is that the same person in different companies will often get different results: for example, some institutions use Shanxi Han people as the &quot;Northern Han sample&quot;, so if the Shanxi Han people take the test, they will get &quot;100% Northern Han sample&quot;. &quot;; And some companies use Han people from North China as samples from the north. If Han people from Shanxi are tested, they may find &quot;Mongolian ancestry&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in essence, this is not &quot;ancestry&quot; source analysis” rather than “relative analysis”. But if you are close to a certain group of people, you must have a common ancestor, so although it is a commercial gimmick, it is not fabricated out of thin air, and it still has its scientific basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The genes of the Manchu people are the same as those of the Han people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Where do I come from?&quot; is a philosophical question that interests people all over the world. It is natural that genetic testing is so popular. In order to attract customers, major genetic companies have also improved their sample databases, hoping to screen out uncontroversial comparison samples for all ethnic groups. However, this grand plan has failed when it comes to Manchu genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a nation with a population of tens of millions, major institutions have repeatedly sampled and calculated the Manchus, but found that they have never been able to obtain a benchmark sample of the Manchus. No matter how we expand the sample size and improve the analysis methods, even if the number of Manchus sampled has reached thousands, the conclusion is still that the Manchus are no different from the Han people in terms of paternal lineage, maternal lineage, and autosomes. If existing benchmark samples are used for analysis, the ethnic origin of the modern Manchu group is mainly composed of northern Han (80%), southern Han (6.57%), Japanese and Korean (5%), and Mongolian-Tungus (3%). . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such results have surprised many scholars and anthropology enthusiasts: the genetic differences between other Tungus-speaking populations, such as the Oroqen people, and the Han people are very obvious. The Manchu people are genetically almost the same as the Han people. You must know that the Qing Dynasty strictly prohibited intermarriage between Manchus and Han people (banner people). So how did the Manchu people, as a member of the Tungusic language family, become of Han descent? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Tradition of slave grabbing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A possible explanation is that this is related to the tradition of slave grabbing in Manchu (Jurchen) society. Before and after Manchuria entered the customs, they were still in a slave society. Every time they went out to conquer the country, they would plunder a large number of civilians as slaves. They were called &quot;Aha&quot; in Manchu. If they were slaves born at home, they were called &quot;wrapped Aha&quot;. For example, in the third year of Chenghua in the Ming Dynasty, the Ming army launched an in-depth attack on the Jurchens in Jianzhou and rescued 1,165 Han people who had become Jurchen slaves in one battle. As the Jianzhou Jurchens continued to rise, the scale of slave plundering became larger and larger, often numbering tens of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is currently no domestic research on the number of slaves plundered by the Ming Dynasty during the Later Jin/Qing Dynasty. However, at the same time, the Qing Dynasty also used troops many times against the Ming Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Li&#39;s Korea&quot;. According to historical records, during the Bingzi War in 1636, the Qing army plundered 600,000 Korean officials and civilians, men and women, as slaves and escorted them back to the Shenyang market for sale (this number is not yet Including the number of Korean people who were plundered by Mongolian soldiers in the Qing army and sent to Mongolia). Most modern scholars believe that 600,000 is an exaggeration, and the actual number is probably 400,000-500,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the entire Ming and Qing Dynasty wars, the number of Han people captured by the Qing army was probably even more difficult to count. For example, the French missionary Badomin, who came to China in 1698, mentioned in a letter to the French Academy of Sciences: &quot;The old Tatars are gradually dying in the pass, and their children are more likely to learn the language of the conquered place than their parents.&quot; language, because their mothers and servants were almost all Han Chinese” - it can be seen that the Manchu families in the early Qing Dynasty, their female relatives and servants were all derived from captured Han slaves. After a few generations, their maternal and autosomal inheritance will definitely become the same as that of Han people, and their mother tongue will naturally be replaced by Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The war system and adoption of heirs in the Qing Dynasty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, the patrilineal inheritance of the modern Manchus is almost the same as that of the Han people. This cannot be explained only by the Qing army&#39;s plundering of Han women. There is a view that this may be related to the unique war system of the Qing Dynasty that led to the trend of banner families adopting heirs:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many history buffs have noticed that the Ming Dynasty often deployed tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands of troops, such as In the Battle of Bozhou during the Wanli period, the three provinces each sent 80,000 troops, totaling 240,000 Ming troops. However, the Qing Dynasty could only mobilize thousands of soldiers at a time, no more than 10,000 or 20,000 at most. For example, in a border war during the Qianlong period, only 3,000 Eight Banners soldiers and 100 bodyguards, Batulu, were dispatched at the beginning of the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the Qing army must first guard against uprisings in Han areas, the Green Camp was extremely fragmented and scattered throughout the country. Then Mancheng was established in various key cities and transferred to the Eight Banners for garrison. Monitor the Green Camp through the relatively concentrated Eight Banners. If there is a civil uprising somewhere, troops can be sent to suppress it as soon as possible. Nip the uprising in the bud, and at the same time prevent the green camp composed of Han people from gaining momentum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with this fragmented military system, once a foreign enemy invades or it is necessary to organize an army to attack foreign countries, it will be difficult to assemble a large-scale army. Not to mention that it takes a long time to mobilize troops. In order to ensure the intensity of internal suppression, only a small number of troops can be mobilized. Even if they put together a somewhat sizable army with great efforts, this army is still a collection of various fragmented small forces, lacking organization and difficult to use in large-scale battles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ding Book compiled and reviewed in the fifth year of Shunzhi records that there are 347,000 strong men in the Eight Banners, including 55,000 Manchurians, 29,000 Mongolians, and 46,000 Han troops. There were 217,000 Han slaves under Manchuria and Mongolia, accounting for 62.5%. The Eight Banners of the Manchu, Mongolian and Han Dynasties, with a total of 130,000 strong men, were the main force of the fighting soldiers. Half of these Qing troops were in Beijing, and the other half were scattered throughout the city to garrison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, every time the Eight Banners sent out troops in the early Qing Dynasty, 10,000 people were mobilized to form a large corps. As a result, Manchu soldiers were quickly exhausted in various wars, while Han domestic slaves did not join the army and fought, and even if they joined the army, they mainly performed auxiliary and logistical work. This part of the population should have suffered minimal population losses in a series of wars in the early Qing Dynasty. Moreover, domestic slaves are considered the private property of the Eight Banners. If they are damaged, the bannermen will find ways to &quot;replenish&quot; them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Yongzheng period, the Qing Dynasty lost only 7,000 Eight Banners soldiers in the Battle of Hetongbo, and beat the bannermen in the capital to the point where every family was covered in sackcloth and filial piety. Next, Qianlong also claimed to have &quot;perfect martial arts&quot;, and wars became more frequent. The loss of the population of the Eight Banners had no time to make up for it through natural reproduction. Many Banner families lost their relatives after their men died in the war, so they had to secretly adopt children from Han slaves as adopted sons to help prevent the family from being cut off and leaving no female relatives to support them. There has always been a folk legend that Qianlong adopted the Chen family from Haining, and the prototype of the story may have come from this. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot; >;(This article is only the author’s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被烈犬咬伤募捐200万争议：医院称未开证明，轻松筹称家属自估金额]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259389]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爱囤“破烂”的老年人：怀旧、孤独、渴望被关注……]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259181]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My mother lives in her hometown in the countryside. She has the habit of hoarding garbage when she comes across cans, mineral water bottles, and cartons. Cardboard boxes, scrap wires, and even scraps from the village mosquito net factory were all picked up and taken home. She didn’t see much of them sold, so they were all piled up in the yard. My sister and I spend a long time cleaning up every time. Before long, she picks up so many things that they pile up like a mountain, and the small yard is like a garbage dump. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, there are a lot of old things stored in the two rooms of my mother, including clothes, shoes and hats from many years ago, rusty iron pots, shovels, farm tools, and even old things that my father brought to her from Xinjiang when he was still alive. The cotton felts, blankets, and sheepskin jackets were in tatters and a mess. We have to clean her out, and mother protects her like a baby, for fear that we will throw her away as garbage when she is not paying attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some villages and towns, old people with my mother’s habits are quite common. Some store less and put them in categories; some store more and put them in disorder; some garbage is mixed with daily necessities and they simply eat and sleep in the garbage pile. It is understood that this is mostly done by lonely elderly people. Very little of the garbage they pick up can be sold. Since they are unable to move it out, they have to coexist with the garbage over time. There are also elderly people who have children and also like to hoard rags. Their behavior and habits are often disgusted by their children, and they are even ridiculed as &quot;nostalgia mania&quot; and &quot;crazy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do these elderly people like to hoard &quot;rags&quot;? Investigating the reasons, I found through investigation that they are nothing more than the following:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it is based on frugality and cannot bear to throw away old things. The elderly are used to living a hard life, and they can make do with the old things at home, and seldom buy new clothes or new supplies. Even if their children buy them, they are often not used to them. They still think the old ones are better and are reluctant to throw them away. Some old people do not want to sell the rags they pick up for money, but feel it would be a pity to throw them away. Old man Wang in his hometown village likes to collect old furniture discarded by young people. It is often seen that he uses a tricycle to transport it home. Someone asked him: &quot;You have saved so much, can you use it yourself?&quot; Old Man Wang said: &quot;They are all high-quality wood. Where can I find this before! I can dismantle it and it can be used.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The second reason is based on nostalgia. There is warmth and emotion in the rags. Many elderly people are nostalgic for old things. Many of their clothing items have been with them for decades. Old things have memories, stories and feelings. In my family, my mother had a deep affection for the rags that filled two rooms, especially my father’s relics. She kept some of them when he was buried. Every time I wanted to dispose of them, my mother always said, “You throw them away as garbage.” &quot;Where can I miss your dad? I took out these things, rubbed them, and talked about them, as if talking to him...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is based on loneliness, to relieve loneliness. This situation is more common among the elderly who like to hoard rags. According to my mother, Aunt Zhang&#39;s three children all work in developed areas and earn a lot of money. They send her money on time every month. It should be said that Aunt Zhang has no worries about food and clothing. But she got up early and stayed up late at night, rain or shine, picking up trash everywhere. Aunt Zhang explained the reason: &quot;My children all know how to be filial, and I don&#39;t lack anything. But they rarely come back throughout the year, and I feel empty. I don&#39;t pick up rags all for the sake of selling them, but I just have something to do and feel at ease.&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is based on being noticed and longing for short-term happiness. When my friend was chatting with me, he mentioned that his relative, Granny Li, who lives in the city, had a unique reason for picking up garbage. Her old courtyard is rarely visited by people, and only during holidays and New Years are the children and grandchildren reunited. The small courtyard is filled with laughter and joy. Those are the happiest and happiest days of the year for Granny Li. Later, Granny Li discovered that whenever the house was messy, her children would come to clean it, so she had an idea and deliberately picked up garbage and made the yard messy and dirty, so that the children would come back to clean it up, which made the house more popular and lively. , it’s lively. The two daughters-in-law couldn&#39;t stand her behavior and said that Granny Li was a little mentally disturbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elderly are keen to hoard rags and rags, which is not only unsightly and affects the sanitation of the family environment, but more importantly, the elderly have more or less problems with their mental health. As a child, you should not only clean up regularly, persuade and comfort them, and return them to a normal life track, but you should also look for the reasons at a deeper level. As the saying goes: To untie a bell, you must tie the bell. Children should not only pay attention to material support, but also pay attention to spiritual support. Just like the old song &quot;Go Home Often and See&quot; sings, &quot;Find some free time, find some time, take your children, and come home often; Bring a smile, bring blessings, accompany your loved ones, and go home often...&quot; Give the elderly more spiritual comfort and let them feel the deep family affection and the warmth of home. To a certain extent, this is richer than simply giving them Material support is more important! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a staff member of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Tancheng County, Shandong Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions . Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访吴慷仁：“演员到底可以演多久戏，在我心里是个问号”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/3yTGMRWbT24vi0h8pG6nJ75fKKe7NbWv4bULWYte.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3yTGMRWbT24vi0h8pG6nJ75fKKe7Nb Wv4bULWYte. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Kangren has no agent or company. He entered the industry late and had 50 jobs before becoming an actor. work. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren&#39;s voice came from the other end of the receiver. Like an old-fashioned man, he carefully confirmed the name of the newspaper and the reporter&#39;s name, and his tone sounded gentle and gentle. He is on vacation. When he is not working, he spends his time in the same way as ordinary people. He passes the time by watching anime such as &quot;Spells Come Back&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, Wu Kangren may have been the actor with the broadest role map in the Chinese-language drama market. His images in movies and TV shows are so varied that it&#39;s jaw-dropping. In 2021, he dressed up in women&#39;s clothing, put on lipstick, and played the role of Mama Sang &quot;Baby&quot; in the highly acclaimed drama &quot;The Lights Are Coming&quot;. The character photo was published in Taiwanese newspapers, but no one reacted, &quot;It took two days to be discovered by others. Isn&#39;t this Wu Kangren!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2022 drama &quot;Her and Her Her&quot;, he plays A pervert who is sexually harassed in the workplace has a female fan who is so angry that she wants to &quot;quit her fans&quot;. Wu Kangren is very calm about this. He told Southern Weekend reporters that he is not worried about the loss of fans of the drama and movies. &quot;The next role will be different.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These roles are a huge departure from the &quot;flower boy&quot; image he played early in his career. At the age of 27, he played Hana Takuya in the classic idol drama &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; - affectionate, broken, and in line with all the settings of a tragic male lead. But in the following years, he continued to break away from that image full of romantic arcs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, on the 54th Taiwan Golden Bell Awards stage, Wu Kangren took the stage as the award guest. Everyone looked at the thin actor with sunken cheeks and a bald head with some suspicion. &quot;Isn&#39;t this a bald man?&quot; A barrage floated across the video. At that time, for the new drama, he lost weight to only 64 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has become routine for him to adjust his body shape, skin color and accent according to the requirements of the role. Someone made an Excel polyline table of Wu Kangren&#39;s weight data from &quot;Termites&quot; to &quot;Love&quot; and found that his weight suddenly went up and down, showing a steep W shape. A reporter from Southern Weekend asked him if he was not afraid of physical damage caused by drastic changes? He smiled and replied: &quot;I&#39;m still alive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fight&quot; is the key word that many people first think of when they mention Wu Kangren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Wu Kangren changed his appearance again in the Taiwanese drama &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; broadcast exclusively on Station B. He put on a Hawaiian shirt, revealing his dark skin, and became the 41-year-old frustrated middle-aged Gao Jiayue. As the eldest son in his family, he has been drifting away for a long time, running a restaurant named &quot;One Million&quot; with a rating of only 2.8 in Xiaoliuqiu. After several years of bleak business, his girlfriend couldn&#39;t bear the island life and cheated on him and left. His career went bankrupt, his love failed, and he tried to hang himself in a restaurant, but the rope broke. Dive to the bottom of the sea, take off your oxygen equipment, and prepare to drown yourself. He suddenly remembered that the oxygen equipment might be eaten by sea turtles and was not environmentally friendly, so he had no choice but to surface and returned home dejectedly to meet his family and have a &quot;long farewell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My parents ran a breakfast shop in Taipei to support their three sons. The mother struggled to endure her father&#39;s mental infidelity and continued to live under the same roof with resentment. The second son is an adopted son. He lives a regular life as an office worker and takes the initiative to take over the responsibility of taking care of his parents. The younger son is older and unmarried, and helps in the breakfast shop. The whole family is stuck in the inertia of the old life and is stuck in moving forward. Everyone is in a &quot;stuck moment&quot; in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren said that he doesn’t have much in common with the character, but as a peer of Gao Jiayue, he has also experienced Kaka moments in real life. &quot;What&#39;s the hardest time for an actor? The role you want to take is taken away, or people don&#39;t like your good performance when it comes out.&quot; Wu Kangren told a reporter from Southern Weekend. His response was simple and clear: keep eating, sleeping, and trying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 will be a harvest year for Wu Kangren. Two of his films, &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; and &quot;May You Live Forever&quot; were screened at the film festival. Both films focused on the bottom class. &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; was filmed in Malaysia, with Wu Kangren playing a deaf-mute illegal immigrant. After getting off the plane, he intuitively felt the gap between him and the character. At first glance, he was a &quot;white and clean civilized person&quot;, while the character he played lived in a dirty place all day long. He began to starve and continued to bask in the sun until his skin was tanned by ultraviolet rays and the locals in the market stopped looking at him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 First Youth Film Festival, he won the best actor for this role. The organizing committee commented on his performance: &quot;Faced with unconventional character settings, Wu Kangren used all available physical resources such as expressions, body parts, movements, and eyes to perform, interpreting the emotions and emotions of the film extremely vividly. Hearing thunder in silence reflects the actor&#39;s great empathy for the character&#39;s situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren has a rare sense of relaxation. He has no agent or company and works for himself. Lasted nine years. There are no personal restrictions or team control. It&#39;s all up to you to decide what kind of scenes to take on, what roles to play, how much to talk to the media, and what the standards are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He asked a Southern Weekend reporter which episode of &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; he had watched. After getting the answer, he conveyed his preferences as if he were a friend: &quot;Look further down, the back is really better. I really like it.&quot; I like it.&quot; Faced with the reporter&#39;s &quot;problematic&quot; question, he also bluntly said: &quot;This question is too broad.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the outside world, the different types of roles over the years have brought Wu Kangren Emboldened. But he said that when he was young, his sense of self-identity was very low and he felt that he was just a &quot;nobody&quot;. He entered the industry late and had 50 jobs before the age of 20. He worked as a rough laborer on construction sites, ran a street stall, and also worked in cafes and bars. Now that I am in my forties this year, the feeling of insecurity has subsided, and new questions have arisen in my heart. He said that in recent years, he feels that his life as an actor will not be too long, so he cherishes it more and increases the frequency of taking roles. This year, he has at least seven film and television works released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the interview, he almost subconsciously revealed his expectations for his subsequent career. He said: &quot;I want to continue acting until I am old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iNugJUjNXgJjxodcmTCYsmf9VQCWG6XI7zrO9Neb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iNugJUjNXgJjxodcmTCYsmf9VQCWG6XI7zrO9Neb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot; In &quot;In This Lifetime&quot;, Wu Kangren plays Gao Jiayue, a frustrated middle-aged man. After his career went bankrupt and his love failed, he tried to commit suicide but failed and returned home in despair. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, Wu Kangren accepted an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. The following is a self-narration compiled based on the interview content:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;It would be good to grow this big in my lifetime&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After receiving the invitation from &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; At that time, I had just finished filming the movie &quot;May You Live Longer&quot; in Hong Kong. When I finished filming, I only weighed 53 kilograms, which was too light. So before joining the set of &quot;In This Life Time&quot;, I ate as much as possible and weighed 66 kilograms when I returned. Last year I went to Malaysia and Hong Kong to shoot a movie respectively. I was made thin and dark. I came back to play the role of Gao Jiayue, a kid who came back from the island. In fact, he looked quite similar. In addition, director Xu Zhaoren is here, and I also like the script. I knew beforehand that Brother Xixiang (Xi Xiang, who plays the father) and Sister Guimei (Yang Guimei, who plays the mother) would take the role, so I also wanted to act together in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director took the sad story very lightly, and made the sad things somewhat funny, even humorous. Gao Jiayue is a person who really wants to die. But if you take what Gao Jiayue said to his nephew, &quot;I jumped into the sea, I wanted to die, but I saw turtles again, and I was afraid that the turtles would eat my equipment and it was not environmentally friendly.&quot; People say that he must think you are lying or joking. But when the audience actually saw the picture, all this became no longer such a joke: it was true, he wanted to die. I think this is where life is ridiculous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In My Lifetime&quot; is not about university knowledge. My own interpretation is, &quot;It would be good to grow this big in your lifetime.&quot; This sentence reflects a lot of feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When things don’t go as planned, it’s always a “stuck moment.” In our lives, sometimes things go against our expectations, and sometimes hard work may not necessarily pay off. This is a very cruel thing. You can’t get what you want, and you can get what you don’t want. How you can stabilize your mood, continue to live, continue to love the people around you, or make the people you love live happily is all a matter of subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people choose to escape, such as the parents in the play who have marital problems. Gao Jiayue came back to tell them not to continue evading. Some people tried to persuade them to make peace but not to leave. Gao Jiayue tried to persuade them to leave but not to make peace. Some people are always in his comfort zone, such as his two younger brothers, who complain about life but are unwilling to step out. How can a character like Gao Jiayue push them, but in such an annoying way? He has the courage to be hated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Real-life family dramas are not as easy as genre dramas. It is very difficult to act in a very real-life way. We actors have been acting for so long and are very familiar with rhythm, technique, and movement. We are also very familiar with how to perform well on camera. But when we try too hard to show the good side, the sense of drama will be stronger and the audience can see it. Xu Zhaoren hopes to adapt it to life, so we revised the lines in the direction of life. Chatting with the director and imagining the characters every day before going on stage is actually very brain-burning and tiring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The script of &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; is very well structured, and the relationship between everyone is clearly written. But we didn’t act according to the relationship between everyone in the script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We feel that we have put a lot of effort into it. In fact, at that time, I was so thin that I deliberately imitated Brother Xixiang. Since I wanted to play his son, did I have any similarities with him? We looked at his posture and sometimes imitated him in jumping and sitting. At that time, I had a lot of discussions with the director. Since you want to play a son and a brother, do you have the same attitude towards each family member, or is it a little different? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, when you are getting along with your younger brother, you just love to bully him. How to bully him? The screenwriter will not teach you to hit them with your hands in the play. This kind of action must be designed by yourself. And it has to be connected to when you were a kid. The second brother in the play is not your biological brother. Your attitude towards your biological brother (reporter&#39;s note: third brother) may be different from that of the second brother. In fact, it is very subtle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the relationship with his father was not good in the script, but in fact when we acted it out, Brother Xixiang felt that he loved his eldest son the most because he was his first son. Child. It is a very straightforward way for parents to express their love for you verbally. Brother Xixiang’s method is the kind of love in which he scolds you the harshest and hits you the hardest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original way of quarreling with my father was to talk to each other, but now as the show continues, it has become that I can actually have a good chat with my father. You are a rebellious son, but you are always unwilling to take what adults say seriously, which means we are acting the other way around. So in the first episode at the beginning, the father guarded the drunk Gao Jiayue from getting up, saying that he was afraid that you would spit it out and choke to death. Therefore, the relationship between Gao Jiayue and his father was not a quarrel at the beginning, but a show of weakness, that is, I was homesick and came back to see it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the script, there is no drinking in the scene of returning home. We discussed with the director and couldn&#39;t imagine what kind of state Gao Jiayue was in before he dared to step into this home again. A failed person, a person who is unwilling to start over, a person who dares not face himself again, but is so arrogant and thinks that I will succeed when I go out to start a business, and then returns to this home penniless, at this time, what should I do? How to do it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what I thought of was, otherwise we would have a drink, and he would have to get himself drunk before he dared to return to this house shamelessly. In the end we decided to use this method. How on earth would he face the truth? You can only get yourself drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that scene, I really drank sorghum wine. I&#39;m not that good at drinking, but I drank in a situation that I could control. After filming, I fell asleep, and the actors called it a day, leaving me alone on set. When I woke up, the only thing left was the lighting crew taking out the lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3ijT0Y9zockqo3BFBZxZtn4NO0EUMTVl8Cf8Zc2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3ijT0Y9zockqo3BFBZxZtn4NO0EUMTVl8Cf8Zc2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In recent years, Wu Kangren&#39;s film and television image has been very varied, and he has played many impressive supporting roles. In 2023, he will have at least seven film and television works released. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;At that time, I only wanted to take supporting roles&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;In recent years, Taiwanese dramas have become more varied in genre. Since they are so varied, of course actors have the opportunity to be varied. They just complement each other, from early idol dramas to later craftsman dramas, police and gangster movies, ghost movies, and now back to life. It&#39;s a big test for actors. You can&#39;t use your past skills to perform every play. When you encounter different plays, you have to make different adjustments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no particular pursuit to play various types of characters, I just want to accumulate different acting experiences. It should be said that I think the life of an actor will not be too long. I dare not say that for everyone. I think it is a question mark in my mind how long an actor can act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was in my early 30s, I began to realize this, which may have something to do with my upbringing. In the past, my self-identity was not so high. The so-called self-identity refers to self-confidence and even the value of existence. You may feel that you are just a nobody, a child who grew up on a construction site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I really felt that I could only work hard, otherwise what would I do? That’s why I got so many roles later. The reason I take on so many roles is not because I want to make a lot of money. In Taiwan, I can’t make much money from film remuneration. I hope that within a limited time, I can see my own possibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after I turned 35, I started to play different roles quite quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She and Her Her&quot;, &quot;The Lights Come on&quot; and &quot;Mom, stop making trouble!&quot; ” were probably all filmed at the same time, and during that time I only wanted to take on supporting roles. Because I think the burden of the protagonist is too heavy. The protagonist sometimes shoots for three or four months at a time. He is always immersed in a role or a long period of work. He is very tired and easily tired. I might as well play a supporting role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the epidemic was also going on at that time, I felt that filming supporting roles could be more fun and not be so stressful. You may say it&#39;s good to have more fun, but I have also reviewed it myself and found that those characters were really overplayed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Her and Her Her&quot; was a guest appearance to help, and I didn&#39;t think too much about it, because the role had to be played in a perverted way. I remember that the producer and director couldn&#39;t find anyone at that time, so they called me later. I had some friendship with the producer, so I went to help. I didn&#39;t want to attract everyone&#39;s attention, I just went to serve, serve. That role. I&#39;m not worried about losing the audience. The next role will be different. I&#39;ve never worried about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The First Light&quot; is another story. It was really because of good luck. I had a good role as the &quot;baby&quot; and he had a lot of space. He found me only after the filming started. I was free at that time and even Director Yi Qi asked you to act, and I said yes. I said you have to give me time to prepare, because I need to find a teacher to practice high heels and dance. In fact, we prepared everything in private, chatting with those drag queens, eating and drinking with them, and imitating their looks and voices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So sometimes taking a role is not so calculated, sometimes it’s just a feeling, because the director is right, I go because the script is right, I go because there are certain actors, or I feel that If it helps this drama, I will do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;When you are not acting, you are just a nobody&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;In This Lifetime&quot; has helped me a lot in my life. I&#39;m really lucky to be able to film &quot;In This Life Time&quot; at this age. Xu Zhaoren is a very good director, and it is very difficult to perform his scenes well. It was the third time I worked with him that this time I seriously felt that I might actually have done a good job. In the past, I didn&#39;t feel like I was able to add points to his dramas, but this drama did a little bit, and I felt like I was finally worthy of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, I take myself very seriously. Sometimes the success of a drama is the result of the team, sometimes it is the credit of the marketing, and sometimes it is the accumulation of credits between the characters. It is absolutely impossible to do it because of one person. Man, this drama is hit or miss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always been confident in my life as an actor. The so-called confidence means that I am willing to do it, not that I am very good. This is a concept. In the past, it was a very simple and clear thing to work hard and be rewarded. This thing has a profound impact on me. If you work, work hard, and sweat for the construction site, you will get the salary you deserve. This is a must-have condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And be responsible. You really have to do your job well, otherwise the boss will scold you, fire you, or ask you to pack up and leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acting is the same for me. Sometimes why you are so fat and why you are so thin is because no one has done it, and no one knows what can be gained from it. I want to know what I can gain from the state of mind of being hungry or obese. I think this is irreplaceable and is self-cultivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s hard for you to tell others that I was hungry for 4 months from May to August last year. From &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; to &quot;May I Live Longer&quot;, I lost 53 kilograms. I was so hungry. , how I lived. People just say, wow. But it’s not because my character has to be so thin that you can see how great I am, no. It’s about putting the characters there and seeing the finished product in the end. Even if the movie doesn&#39;t go well, people will think you&#39;re just thin, so what&#39;s the big deal? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because you will really experience it after you do it. We are not like the protagonist of the anime. Why is he almost defeated in the end and still able to wake up? Because he thinks about his family and friends. Like Luffy in &quot;One Piece&quot; and Goku in &quot;Dragon Ball&quot;, he suddenly doesn&#39;t know where he came from. strength. We are human beings, and we still have our own limits. Limits can only be reached through self-examination again and again. If people don&#39;t make mistakes, they won&#39;t know that they will make mistakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was acting, I often made mistakes, and I still make them now. It&#39;s just that sometimes someone will correct your mistakes, sometimes not, but I always hope to meet a director who can deny you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of each actor is different. Some talented actors need to retain their energy. I consider myself to be mediocre and I need to accumulate that energy. The growth process of each actor cannot be compared. Since it cannot be compared, there is no repetition. The lack of repetition means that only I understand what I am going through, and you will not understand. Only after each finished product comes out will you see the difference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an actor is not acting, you are just a nobody. At most, you will be exposed to fashion or commercial performances, and you will see the glamorous star appearance. In fact, if you take away those appearances, who you really are is very vague. Celebrities have a popular persona, and that persona is the persona that the audience likes, because now everyone likes to see good things, kind people, and even people with high moral standards. The actor&#39;s appearance is very blurry, and there&#39;s nothing wrong with being blurry, it&#39;s just a different experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always felt that actors are people living in the past, and the works you see are all me from the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Acting has never been free&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Actually, I have always felt that my work experience, having worked 50 jobs before I was 20, was not of much help to me. big. The accumulation of work experience is very life-like, but sometimes drama does not require you to perform life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;Copycat&quot;. It is a genre drama, and genre dramas are not life-like. If you want to stick to a life-like performance and conform to the rhythm of the camera and the director, when should you react? This is the pull between you and yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing Guo Xiaoqi in &quot;Copycat&quot; was very difficult for me, very difficult, extremely difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The skeleton of the genre drama is better written, but the portrayal of the characters may not be outstanding. Because it serves a crime and captures the real culprit, it takes the audience to see the reaction of each character. After watching it, the protagonist is actually empty. The so-called empty means that you can only accumulate some plots to serve the audience. How to put your own human flavor into it requires a lot of thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, you want to play him very smart, but you don’t want to play him too handsome, a little quirky, but you don’t want to make him too mythical. If you just look at the ferocity of the supporting characters, the main character will easily disappear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If &quot;Copycat&quot; is about using all the things accumulated in the past into one film, &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; is about forgetting all the things that I know. This is a transition between very skillful and unskillful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acting has never been free. How can acting be free? Acting is very scientific, including lenses, camera positions, performances, types, and even opponents. Acting is very unfree but very organic. Any situation may affect the whole body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called lack of freedom is that you cannot perform exactly the way you want, sometimes because of the orientation of the camera, sometimes because of the rhythm, sometimes because of the opponent actor, and sometimes because of what the character wants to present. situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do you think you have to take on so many roles? Because I think acting is a very passive profession, I just hope to put some of my own initiative into acting work in a passive situation as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The passivity of an actor is to be chosen. You will be there only after the script is written. If the script is not written, you will not exist. You may just act in another play. What space is there to be able to choose and take the initiative? That means to become thinner or fatter, to make the character more internal or more external, it doesn&#39;t matter. No matter what method you use, show your initiative. Those initiatives will affect the director&#39;s thoughts on the character, or the character can have a chemical reaction with other actors. This is the initiative that I think is valuable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s what acting is, you bring out your own life experience. If you don&#39;t have this life experience, you need to rely on a lot of field research and investment. Except for a few who can&#39;t do it, others can rely on self-study and hard work to accumulate the short one or two seconds on the screen to deceive everyone and say that I look like me. But when you go deeper, whether the performance is good or bad depends on each actor&#39;s own interpretation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, I like many senior actors, such as Mr. Li Xuejian from Mainland China, who can act at that age, or Mr. Jin Shijie, etc. Actors who grew up in Hong Kong in the 1980s and 1990s, such as Tony Leung Ka Fai, Tony Leung Chiu Wai, Nick Cheung Ka Fai, and Andy Lau, each actor has accumulated hundreds of dramas, leaving his own place. But for me, that kind of accumulation is very difficult. If I follow the current pace of actors, I will never be able to achieve it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nine years without an agent&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had an agent for about nine years. In the early years, I was still looking for one, but because of one job after another Come, I will keep acting. If there is a job, I will take it, if I get it, I will act, and if I act, I will go on stage. If someone says hello, I will applaud. I will say thank you, and I will keep acting like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After four or five years, it seems that people (agents) no longer come to me. They seem to think that I can do this. But in fact, I am very busy and have many things to deal with, including contracts and work. Time, schedule. I haven&#39;t taken on so many commercial projects, and shooting commercials isn&#39;t too complicated. Relatively speaking, my acting life is pretty simple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back now, I feel that every decision I made before was good. I did not sign for a big company, but signed for a small company, and I will live a happier life. Later, he left the protection of his original agent, and finally became an agent by himself for no apparent reason. I also have to be an assistant and carry my own bag, which contains travel supplies and stomach medicine. Be your own driver and drive to the scene, finish work by yourself, and borrow clothes by yourself. There are things to do and things not to do. There are some jobs that you can choose, and there are some jobs where you don’t have to make this money. If you don’t make this money, you won’t have so many burdens and baggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am an actor, and what we talk about is what actors do. In fact, I rarely talk about conditions, because if you talk about conditions, it will be complicated and waste a lot of thought. Being able to act well is the first condition. I&#39;m not a person who likes to compare. I don&#39;t compare myself to actors of the same age and tell them what they are like. If you don&#39;t think about it, nothing will happen. If you think about it, something will happen. You feel you are at a disadvantage because you have a value standard and judgment: my salary must be so high, or my conditions must be so high. If you don&#39;t have this value standard, there is no such thing as suffering a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, last year&#39;s &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; and &quot;May You Live Forever&quot; were both very low-cost movies, so why were they filmed? Because I like the script of &quot;Fudu Youth&quot;, I want to try to go out and experience life. Different environments will have different sparks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I did go, it was very worthwhile, and I made a great movie. &quot;May I Live Longer&quot; is from Hong Kong, so it&#39;s the same. I just read the script and said I would go. I didn’t talk about where I would live, and I didn’t even talk about my salary. The producer was surprised and said, &quot;Don&#39;t you ask about the price?&quot; I said I don’t need to ask about the price, just call the contract. He called over the contract and it was this price. I laughed. I know they don&#39;t have money. If I think I can accept it, I will go, and I will be very happy in my heart, and you will be very relaxed, because you have nothing to ask for, so you will go, just asking for a good performance in the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2015 to now, I don’t want everyone to think that because my life has become easier, I am not willing to make progress. I also hope to accumulate something. At least the stuff coming out this year is above the level, and I don’t want to deal with the performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s hard to say fate. It’s unlikely that you will have a breakthrough in every drama, really. This is a market. To survive in this market, we can only rely on each drama and how to play the role well after joining. In fact, there is not much that actors can do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>