<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[花西子眉笔引发的行业审视：直播电商，成也主播，毁也主播？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258032]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor was live broadcasting products on the booth. Pictures and texts Unrelated. Interface News Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/344031c58e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252933&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the 2023 Asian Pet Expo, an anchor broadcast live on the booth. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Interface News Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After briefly entering the live broadcast room, a domestic beauty brand established for more than two years decided not to enter the show again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is both a fame and fortune fair and a place at the forefront of the limelight. The most recent farce was on September 10, 2023, when super anchor Li Jiaqi criticized netizens while selling Huaxizi eyebrow pencil. The turmoil has been postponed to this day, and the Huaxizi brand has become the target of public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people in the industry are re-examining the sales ecology of anchors bringing goods. A brand manager Chu Shi (pseudonym) is also a melon-eater. For her, the high commissions and pit fees required by big anchors are difficult for small brands to resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;last straw&quot; that caused Chu Shi to give up the live broadcast was exactly a live broadcast. The brand invited a top anchor with tens of millions of fans, and the position fee was about 70,000 yuan, with an agreed sales guarantee of 210,000 yuan. They have high expectations and regard it as the &quot;most important event&quot; since its inception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end, the leading anchor only sold a few thousand yuan, and did not refund the corresponding amount according to the contract. Chu Shi called this incident a &quot;trigger&quot;. Although she felt that the business was unhealthy before, she was willing to abide by the rules of the industry. This time she was in the whirlpool and felt chilled: &quot;Given such a high commission, there are still pitfalls. For a bit fee, a brand like ours cannot play like that.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The brand went to the police station to report the crime, and then won the lawsuit through litigation. However, the refunded fees have not yet been received, and the anchor is still active in the live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“So much profit goes to the host”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For this new brand, the first “obstacle” to live broadcast admission sounds humble: identifying the reasons for rejection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu Shi and the others contacted thousands of anchors and bloggers. Chu Shi recalled: “In the first year, we really hoped to increase the brand’s exposure through some experts. I put a lot of effort into promoting it and its popularity. But the result is really not very good.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sending products to popular live broadcast rooms is the preferred way for small brands to gain popularity. Data from the live broadcast e-commerce industry blue book released by the China Institute of Metrology and other units show that in the first half of 2023, the sales of live broadcasts on key monitored e-commerce platforms reached 1.27 trillion yuan, with more than 110 million live broadcasts and more than 70 million live products. , the number of active anchors exceeds 2.7 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following the anchor&#39;s product selection process, they will communicate with the other party&#39;s business personnel and wait for feedback. If there is no feedback, it means it is inappropriate by default. It’s like rushing through the sand, “maybe less than 10% of anchors or business people will reply to us in this link.” &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first Chu Shi would feel confused, not knowing where he was stuck. Later, the picture gradually became clearer, &quot;In fact, it is not the product at all, but the dissatisfaction with the price or commission.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that anchors would focus on promoting the same product in various categories, making it particularly difficult for new products to emerge. The products that were strongly promoted by the anchors were actually the ones for which the brand offered high commissions. “For example, there are several products we know that offer commissions of 60 to 70 points, and they have already sold to the top in that category. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;70% commission means that if a product sells for 100 yuan, 70 yuan will be given to the anchor. The remaining costs should cover product development, raw materials, packaging materials and other costs, as well as warehousing logistics, site and labor costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We think this business is very unhealthy.” Chu Shi believes that high commissions force costs to be reduced. “So much profit is given to the anchors. They charge such high commissions, but they do not Without creating corresponding social value and providing more jobs, the profits of upstream brands and the supply chain have been reduced. Brands can only continue to reduce costs, and their products will become worse and worse, and the treatment of employees will also be worse. It’s getting worse.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four or five years ago, she worked with anchors for beauty brands at the time, with commissions ranging from 20% to 30%. However, the live broadcast ecosystem gradually evolved. “From the year before last to last year, the commissions continued to increase. It’s rising. I don’t think it’s because the anchors are raising the price, it’s because the industry is too complicated, whether it’s beauty or live streaming, it’s all too complicated.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beauty is recognized as one of the most popular fields. Nanshan, co-founder of the beauty MCN organization May Beauty, also feels the same way. Although there is a lot of beauty traffic on the platform, there are also a lot of people entering the platform. &quot;I think it started to roll out in 2019 and 2020, and every year it is better than before. He kept curling more and more without stopping.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of the volume, the mechanism of the volume, the content of the volume, the capital of the volume... the prices of things of the same quality are constantly falling in the competition, but the commissions for the anchors are gradually increasing. &quot;I think this volume is good in all aspects.&quot; , product homogeneity is also very serious, and every price range is full of competitors.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang, director of Hangzhou Xijiang New Retail Research Institute and former deputy director of Alibaba Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that taking eyebrow pencils as an example, from the perspective of raw material processing fees, including factory delivery The cost plus tax may be less than 10 yuan. The biggest cost of cosmetics is sales expenses. Previously, this part included marketing and channel expenses, that is, advertising, celebrity endorsements, channel deduction fees, and profits from offline wholesalers and agents. Now, if you sell through live e-commerce, it is a direct retail. The most important ones are traffic fees, advertising fees, anchor commissions for bringing goods, and pit fees. &quot;These fees account for a very high proportion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out that the biggest problem with the current live broadcast sales system is the trend of low prices. “After the emergence of live broadcast e-commerce, China’s retail market has been turned upside down. Everyone is fighting for low prices. &quot;If a company has no profits, it will have no money to do product research and development and innovation, and bad money may drive out good money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Only care about three points: price, commission, and pit fee&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Price and gifts are the key points when attracting consumers to place orders in the live broadcast room. At this point, super The head anchor does have a higher say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Lei (pseudonym), the person in charge of a domestic brand who once sent products to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, told Southern Weekend reporters that Li Jiaqi’s pit fee one or two years ago was “not expensive,” “about 8. &quot;More than 10,000 yuan&quot;, the commission is 30 to 40%, which is almost the same as other anchors. But Li Jiaqi&#39;s prices are very low, even at prices the merchant himself has &quot;never sold before.&quot; &quot;He doesn&#39;t care how much you originally sold them for, he will only tell you &#39;how much I want to sell them for.&#39;&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;He will demand &#39;I am the lowest&#39;, but he will not tell you openly. He will only tell you a price to see if you can give it.&quot; Qiao Lei said that both parties It is also necessary to sign a price guarantee agreement to ensure that there will be no lower prices, including the brand&#39;s own live broadcast room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This condition is almost harsh, but a large number of businesses are still willing to accept it. Even now, there are still small brands that are eager to get into the super live broadcast room and are waiting hard. Lillian (pseudonym) is the person in charge of branding and e-commerce at a start-up company that makes functional skin care products. For her, the road to Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room has not yet been opened. “I have been following them for half a year, and I still have During the data review stage.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Super anchors such as Li Jiaqi (first from left) will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/02/3872bf435f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252934&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Like Li Jiaqi (first from left) Super anchors will undoubtedly play a key role in the sales of small brands. Visual China Pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Chu Shi has come into contact with &quot;very few anchors who are truly professional.&quot; Brands provide product selling points, and anchors follow the script. &quot;They rarely ask us professional questions about products.&quot; , because today’s anchors have too many choices, and merchants of all sizes are waiting for them to deliver products. They don’t know the raw materials, ingredients and functions of the products. What they care about most are three points: How much is the price, how much is the commission, and is there any pit fee?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo (pseudonym), an anchor who has been doing live broadcasts for five years, told Southern Weekend reporters that she would learn about the product information before the live broadcast. Go to the live broadcast room every hour and communicate with the operation about the overall situation. During the live broadcast, consumers are mainly told three pieces of information: how favorable the price of this product is, how easy it is to use, and when and in what scenario it will be needed. If consumers are tempted but are still hesitant, they will emphasize the accompanying gifts and the decreasing inventory, &quot;to force another order.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chu Shi’s observation, this is because the time to explain each product in the live broadcast room is very limited. Within a few minutes, the strength of the discount is reflected in order to impress users and make them purchase. &quot;Use &#39;Quantity&#39; is the fastest way for them to reflect the value of the product.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Mo has been a brand external anchor for a long time, and has worked with 30 or 40 brands. She is charged by the hour. &quot;Selling more or less all depends on my own professional ethics and KPIs.&quot; There is not a lot of pressure on sales.” Recently, she decided to go it alone and collect commissions for selling goods. The more she sold, the more she earned, which gave her a greater sense of urgency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the platform will analyze the live broadcast data in real time, display the product placement expenses, sales volume and total sales of the day, and also conduct vertical comparisons. Increasingly intuitive data also tests the ability of anchors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The game mechanism between brands and anchors&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to create a super anchor. May Beauty, where Nanshan is located, once failed to become a super anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This MCN organization has incubated more than 60 beauty experts. Nanshan recalled that the company originally “wanted to go towards the top.” At the end of 2021, they tried to support a beauty blogger with more than 10 million fans. At his peak, the blogger could bring in 5 to 6 million yuan in goods per sale. But they soon discovered that the top anchors were &quot;not that easy to do&quot; and it was difficult to obtain &quot;a particularly good mechanism&quot;. The frequency of live broadcasts could not be increased, and the commission rate was relatively low. It was very likely that &quot;the work was in vain and no money was made.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the keys to being stuck in the top spot is the mechanism, that is, the brand merchants give the anchors product prices, gift configurations, commission sharing or other incentive resources. The differences in the mechanisms obtained by different anchors are obvious. Nanshan compared its own anchors with the leading anchors in the industry. The same shampoo was sold in both live broadcast rooms for 119 yuan for two bottles of 1,000 ml. At the head anchor, those who place orders can get an extra 400 to 500 ml of shampoo, but they may only get 100 to 200 ml. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sales that exceed brand expectations, make products a hit, have good daily video and live broadcast data, and excellent business negotiation skills can all help anchors get better mechanisms, &quot;If Without a good mechanism, it will be difficult for users to continue paying for it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Nanshan also observed that compared with the previous two years, brands have made less and less &quot;sacrifice&quot; in terms of mechanism. &quot;In 2021, brands are more willing to sacrifice some mechanisms for anchors. For example, if he sells it for 119 yuan in his flagship store, he may give 99 yuan to our live broadcast room.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Wuyang pointed out, The relationship between the brand and the anchor is essentially a game. The brand previously offered low prices in the hope of attracting fans to its official website account and paying direct attention to the brand itself through the use of anchors to promote products. Anchors need to keep the products in the live broadcast room low-priced, maintain their original fans, and increase their value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of the product in the live broadcast room, the commission ratio that the anchor can get, and the gifts for consumers are all the focus of the game. In August 2023, Nanshan negotiated a cooperation with an anchor with one million fans at a price of 180,000 yuan, including two or three short videos, two live broadcast warm-ups and one special live broadcast, and brought five products. The main demands of brands are to reduce commissions and reduce gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both parties held the mechanism table in their hands, went through two or three rounds of meetings and discussions, and finally chose to take a step back. The average commission has dropped from about 31% to 28%, and the product has gone from 119 yuan for two 600ml bottles and a 150ml gift to 128 yuan for two bottles and a 300ml gift, which is equivalent to &quot;getting three bottles at once for 128 yuan.&quot; Both parties are satisfied with the results. After two or three live broadcasts, the brand&#39;s initial investment &quot;will come back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanshan mentioned that some brands have also formed new cooperative relationships with anchors. That is, before the product is launched, the brand will let the anchor participate in product development, and the brand will communicate with the anchor: &quot;I &quot;How much do you think is appropriate for the product?&quot; &quot;I want to change the parts that are not suitable yet.&quot; The two parties will lengthen the line of cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Because anchors have a characteristic, they understand consumers better, which will make the entire industry chain closer to consumers.” Li Yongjian, director of the Research Office of the Institute of Financial Strategy of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, pointed out that the relationship between brands and anchors In-depth cooperation between enterprises is relatively beneficial, can improve the efficiency of the supply chain, and is conducive to the rapid formation of domestic brands. However, we need to be wary that some anchors may take advantage of consumers&#39; trust to further squeeze consumers. &quot;(Remember) you represent the interests of consumers and help them find high-quality and low-priced products.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Live streaming is still the direction of this MCN organization’s efforts in 2023. Nanshan’s basis is that consumers’ minds have been formed and they have the habit of buying things in live broadcast rooms on a daily basis. At the same time, live broadcast consumption behavior has become more rational. In addition to price, the suitability of the product will also be considered. “At this time, we use live broadcasts to In this way, we can &#39;grow&#39; users and let them place orders.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In May 2023, a beauty e-commerce company in Hangzhou was live broadcasting. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /02/dfc6cec3be.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 2023, a beauty e-commerce company in Hangzhou conducted a live broadcast . Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Where is the “ceiling” of live streaming e-commerce? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Different brands enter the live broadcast room for different purposes. Qiao Lei said that for some big brands, live broadcast is just a channel, and they value the &quot;grass planting&quot; effect more than the amount of goods brought by the anchor. New brands and small brands are different. They need to &quot;plant grass&quot; and &quot;mow grass&quot;. They hope to have enough sales volume, return the cooperation costs, and increase the turnover rate of goods. As for himself, the more important purpose is promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effect is obvious. Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast brought hundreds of thousands of visitors to their store. “The original daily sales were 50,000 to 60,000 yuan. Maybe after he helped us bring goods through the live broadcast, , the daily sales reached 80,000 to 90,000, and the influence is expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Yongjian pointed out that &quot;reliance on chefs&quot; is the biggest shortcoming of the live broadcast e-commerce ecosystem. For a new brand, telling a good brand story, making good products, and forming brand power are the most basic. It is very difficult to rely on top anchors to build a brand. &quot;There are individual (successful) cases, but whether this case can be sustained, if If there is no brand power and product power, I think it is questionable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the &quot;ceiling&quot; of live broadcast e-commerce has appeared. He said that the basic logic of e-commerce is to stretch the supply chain and shorten the marketing chain. &quot;Now suddenly there is an additional anchor, and 25% and 30% will be cut off. This business logic itself has problems.&quot; An imperfect profit distribution mechanism, a chaotic price system, and uneven development among anchors are all chaos in the live broadcast ecosystem, which has led to new problems, such as data traffic fraud and false orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Qiao Lei, the development of the live broadcast field has become mature. Regardless of whether the number of fans is large or small, the age of the audience is old or young, and whether the field is hot or cold, there are corresponding competitors. &quot;In fact, there are people occupying every card slot, and any vertical track It’s basically all covered.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiao Lei found that in the past, each platform and each anchor had its own audience and had little influence on each other. However, during major promotion periods such as &quot;618&quot; and &quot;Double Eleven&quot;, several The overlapping rate of consumers on the platform will be significantly higher, and all anchors carrying goods will be drawn into the same arena, making the strength of their competitiveness particularly obvious. &quot;When it comes to large-scale promotions, the living space of tail anchors is actually very small, and head anchors are still the main ones.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, small brands that are not very competitive will also choose to participate in major promotions. &quot;Lie down&quot; to protect yourself and withdraw from the fierce battlefield. Lillian said that traffic costs will increase during major promotions. She does not have the ability to seize traffic and divide the market, and will actively avoid the war. &quot;Normally (big promotion festivals) we are not anxious, we just put it away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Haoxing, a professor at the School of Economics at Zhejiang Gongshang University and a member of the Zhejiang Provincial Consumption Promotion Expert Committee, told Southern Weekend reporters that the current ecology of the live broadcast field is not sound. On the other hand, they have raised the sales price and made huge profits. All the dividends have been concentrated on the Internet celebrities. The profit distribution in the ecosystem is seriously unreasonable. This phenomenon must be broken in the future.&quot; He suggested that the market regulatory authorities strengthen supervision and hoped that the supply chain would become more mature and complete, with reasonable distribution of upstream and downstream profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the live broadcast industry has now reached a period of transformation. Various types of vertical industry chain live broadcasts, factory live broadcasts, and expert live broadcasts are all playing a greater role, and &quot;small but beautiful, small and specialized&quot; have emerged. Features, this is also the development direction of &quot;future version 2.0 live broadcast&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访许鞍华：因为不服气，所以继续拍电影丨影视大咖谈④]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257481]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FAMbdwT9pAbp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/cAlRut9HrIDnxNhEt8M1oRjAjk88FA MbdwT9pAbp. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 29, 2021, Xu Anhua attended the screening of &quot;The First Incense&quot; in Shanghai Post-communication activities. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Beginning of Winter in 2021, Xu Anhua was in a good mood. She flew from Beijing to Xiamen , planning to make this the last stop of her trip to the mainland. On May 22, 2019, the new film &quot;The First Incense&quot; directed by Xu Anhua started filming in Gulangyu Island, Xiamen. Two and a half years later, she returned here with the film. At the screening event, some audience members whispered to each other: &quot;I heard that this movie was not shot well?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is a good thing to have discussions.&quot; Talking about the reputation controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot; , Xu Anhua&#39;s attitude is very calm. Although her career has encountered many failures and doubts, the rating of &quot;The First Incense&quot; on Douban is only 5.6, becoming Xu Anhua&#39;s lowest score in 43 years of acting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Liu Ren told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Due to various reasons, &quot;The First Incense&quot; did not have a premiere. The director came to Xiamen this time to thank those who helped us during the previous filming. It is completely We paid for it at our own expense. The reason for the word-of-mouth controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot; is very complicated, which has nothing to do with the current publicity and distribution rules of the film industry. Ann (Ann Hui&#39;s English name) is not indifferent to this, but she often I cheered her up and said it didn&#39;t matter. Although she was angry, she would not be sad. She would fight back, learn from experience and continue filming - you see she is a confrontational person with a revolutionary heart.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot; The filming of &quot;The First Incense&quot; will most likely fail&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have been working on this project for seven years, and it is really a long story.&quot; Liu Ren, the producer of &quot;The First Incense&quot; said, &quot; &quot;The First Incense&quot; is the first project I produced. The company &quot;Blue Bird&quot; was handed over to me by my teacher Xia Meng (note: Hong Kong movie star, well-known patriot) before her death. She told me to make good movies. , so I asked director Xu Anhua to shoot &quot;The First Incense&quot;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film adaptation of Zhang Ailing&#39;s &quot;The First Incense&quot; has been going on for decades. During her lifetime, Zhang Ailing had liked the movie star Lin Dai to play the heroine Ge Weilong. Later, Lin Dai committed suicide and the matter was ignored. In the 1980s, Jade Bird Film Company, founded by Xia Meng, started a trend of co-productions between Hong Kong and the Mainland, investing in three films: &quot;The Wrath of the Sea&quot;, &quot;Heroes from Ancient Times&quot; and &quot;Back to Time&quot;. Xia Meng also considered purchasing the copyright of &quot;The First Incense&quot;, but due to some changes in the production environment of Hong Kong films, Xia Meng left the film industry, and the matter was delayed again. In the 1990s, Xu Feng, the producer of &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; purchased the copyright of the novel and contacted Yang Dechang, but due to various reasons, he did not make the film. It wasn&#39;t until 2014 that Liu Ren, who was working in the Shanghai publishing industry at the time, was chatting with friends and came up with the idea of ​​adapting Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel into a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Zhang Ailing&#39;s many novels, Liu Ren chose &quot;The First Incense&quot;. After some twists and turns, in 2015, he bought the five-year adaptation rights of the novel from Song Yilang, the copyright holder of Zhang Ailing, and set out to find his favorite director. In 2016, he received Xu Anhua&#39;s approval to serve as the film&#39;s producer. &quot;Ann told me at the time how difficult it would be to adapt this movie, and that adapting &quot;The First Incense&quot; would most likely fail. She suggested that I find a young director to make it. Because even if this movie doesn&#39;t work well and is controversial, young people People have a young person’s perspective, and it’s a good thing to have controversy.” Liu Ren told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2016 to 2019, Liu Ren has been doing various tasks for the filming of the movie, encountering various accidents and misfortunes. Seeing that the adaptation copyright is about to expire, the management proposed to ask Xu Anhua to be the director. . At that time, Ann Hui had just completed the movie &quot;When Will There Be a Bright Moon&quot;. She compared several job offers at hand and finally decided to take on the directorship of this film. She hired someone who had collaborated with her in the stage play &quot;The Story of the Golden Lock&quot; Writer Wang Anyi served as the screenwriter, and the prototype of the movie &quot;The First Incense&quot; gradually took shape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Anhua was born in 1947. When &quot;The First Incense&quot; is released in October 2021, she will be 74 years old. In 2020, when the COVID-19 epidemic broke out, Xu Anhua completed the post-production of the film and learned that the Venice Film Festival was going to award the Lifetime Achievement Award to him. She is the first female director in the world to receive this honor, which is seen as a victory for female filmmakers around the world. Xu Anhua delivered a speech in English when receiving the award, saying that he would go back to help more young people so that they would also have the opportunity to receive the Lifetime Achievement Award in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2020, a documentary &quot;Making Movies Well&quot; chronicling Xu Anhua&#39;s 40 years in film premiered at the Hong Kong International Film Festival. The director of this work, Wen Nianzhong, has served as the director of several of Xu Anhua&#39;s films. The art director showed the audience some fragments of Xu Anhua&#39;s life in his later years from the perspective of friends and collaborators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anhua Xu has never been married and has almost no emotional experience. She once said, &quot;Movies are my husband or wife, and literature is my mistress.&quot; She only has eyes for movies. She often falls down when she is too involved in her work. The most anxious thing is that there are no movies to shoot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Ren told the Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;When we were filming in Gulangyu Island, Ann fell in the bathroom one day and landed on the back of her head, which was very scary. She sent me a message as soon as she regained consciousness and said , &#39;Xiao Liu, I fell, I dare not move, can you come and see me?&#39; I rushed to take a look, and there were purple bruises from the back of her head to her neck, and I quickly took her for an MRI. Tell me, the first thing that comes to mind is that if something really happens, call A Kwan (director Kwan Jin Peng) to come (replace her). Ann is really a person who works hard for the movie, so many times I Forget that she is an old man in her seventies, we will continue to cooperate in the future, and I hope she can make two more movies before she is 80 years old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6, 2021, Despite negative reviews, the movie &quot;First Incense&quot; still grossed more than 60 million yuan at the box office, and is expected to become Xu Anhua&#39;s second-highest box office film in the mainland. The next morning, Southern Weekend reporters conducted an exclusive interview with Xu Anhua in Xiamen. At the end of the conversation, she suddenly said: &quot;Let me ask you a question too. To be honest, what do you think of &quot;The First Incense&quot;?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/21/11/11/M5ryo5J5rAZYjZTMSJN5fSpZ5Z2h8RNNaHn1BqlU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Anhua based on Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel of the same name The film adaptation of &quot;Half Life&quot; (1997), starring Anita Mui (right) and Wang Zhiwen (left). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;Zhang Ailing has become an inviolable writer&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The First Incense&quot; has received so much criticism on the Internet this time. To be honest, I am a little surprised , judging from the ratings on Douban.com, this is the movie with the worst reputation in your career. I would like to know, what do you think of the word-of-mouth controversy of &quot;The First Incense&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t expect there to be such a loud voice, but I think if this drama doesn’t get good reviews, it’s good to be controversial. of. It’s great if everyone can openly talk about their ideas about the movie and discuss the show together. It would also be good to talk more about other social issues. Maybe because of the epidemic, everyone is a little confused, and we can take this opportunity to clarify some basic concepts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have seen some interviews and you said you are filming After watching &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; and &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot;, I no longer want to make another movie adapted from Zhang Ailing&#39;s work, but why did I continue to make &quot;The First Incense&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s not that I don’t want to shoot Zhang Ailing. In fact, I really want to shoot it, but I really haven’t thought about how to shoot Zhang Ailing’s works so that the audience can accept them. In other words, how to shoot to make people feel that the artistic quality of the movie is even higher. After the filming experience accumulated in the first two films, I realized that adapting Zhang Ailing&#39;s works is very difficult to please. It is neither easy to please the Western (audience) nor the Chinese (audience). To be honest, &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot; was rejected by the Venice Film Festival. They originally enthusiastically asked me to bring the film to Venice, but after watching it, they felt that it was a very ordinary love movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, &quot;Half a Life&quot; was screened in the United States, and a well-known film critic said that we could treat this movie as William Wyler (director of &quot;Roman Holiday&quot;) This is a touching and decent romance film shot by a technically savvy director. They saw &quot;Half a Lifetime&quot; in this way, so I wasn&#39;t unaware of the consequences when I made &quot;The First Incense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, they couldn&#39;t tell the difference between the real scenes and the fake ones that we overcame huge difficulties to shoot. They also didn&#39;t understand the background of the characters and thought it was an ordinary &quot;soap opera&quot;. Because they have never seen Zhang Ailing, we have made a difficult adaptation based on the original text, and we have done enough work. They don&#39;t think it is different from Hollywood movies in the 1940s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both &quot;The First Incense&quot; and &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; have very long lines. These lines are particularly unpleasant in the movie, but if the sentences in the original work are not used, readers will not let them go. I. Zhang Ailing&#39;s readers will demand that your work be the same as or better than the original work, but I know that many of Zhang Ailing&#39;s stories are not creative, because her creativity lies in her writing method, not the story itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have never thought about how to make a good film. I can&#39;t make it into a niche art film because I won&#39;t get money. During this period, I heard various feedbacks and became more and more aware that the market had changed. What&#39;s more, over the years, Zhang Ailing has become an inviolable writer. There are many fanatical fans who are more familiar with Zhang Ailing than me. A slight mistake will be very troublesome. I am deeply aware of these problems, but I haven&#39;t figured out how to overcome them. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I made a story like this for the current &quot;post-90s&quot; and &quot;post-00s&quot; generations. They may not understand the relationship between the characters. They don&#39;t know who the uncle is, what the second wife is, and the life experience of the aunt. What&#39;s going on? It&#39;s not that they are ignorant, it&#39;s that they don&#39;t have these things in their experience. For example, if a girl loses her virginity in the countryside in the 1940s, she will be dipped in a pig cage. That&#39;s not the case now. It&#39;s understandable for girls to covet a comfortable life. That era was actually very hypocritical. No one talked about money, and a woman would not admit it even if she wanted money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under such circumstances, I have to make the story understandable and reasonable for young audiences, while at the same time staying true to the original work. It is difficult to balance these. I&#39;m not trying to defend myself because I can&#39;t take good pictures, I just want to share some of the problems I&#39;ve experienced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You seem to have said &quot;The First Incense&quot; and &quot;The Fall of the City&quot; Do you think it is better than the latter? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, definitely. It was completely wrong before, but now it may be a little deviated from the original work, but I did it on purpose. I shot &quot;Love in a Fallen City&quot; hoping to make it a very touching story, but in fact it should be the least touching story. It just has a seemingly good ending. This is Zhang Ailing&#39;s creativity. But because I grew up reading a lot of romantic novels, I wanted the hero and heroine to feel like they were &quot;war-torn mandarin ducks.&quot; This was actually wrong and completely violated the spirit of the original work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The First Incense&quot; from preparation to filming What do you think is the most difficult part of the process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anna Hsu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just finding funds is already very difficult, but it wasn’t me who found it, it was the producer who looked for it for three years. . After I bought the copyright, people talked about how &quot;The First Incense&quot; was (good) and how Zhang Ailing was (good), but when it came time to actually pay for it, no one was there. I don&#39;t blame them, because it&#39;s easy to calculate the box office by just calculating it. This is a literary film, which may require huge funds. It may be difficult to recoup the scenery and costumes of that era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, I think it is not a big problem to choose the actors and the filming team. Because of Zhang Ailing’s appeal, everyone is willing to give it a try. The second difficulty was choosing the location for filming, which was quite difficult. Later I chose Gulangyu Island. When it came time to actually shoot, because we already had such a mature team, there was no problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that it is difficult to find money for this film, but it is relatively easy to find actors. Yes, but the most controversial aspect of this film is the selection of actors. Did you receive any interference from capital during the process of finding actors? For example, will they tell you who you should and should not choose from a box office perspective?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There will be, but they are all normal discussions. , they didn’t give me much difficulty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/mLJe82RpYr86k7n90M5MkFh4s4W4yIq6SDQ3B9G9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Anna Hui (left), costume director Emi Wada (middle), and producer Liu Ren (right) on the set of the movie &quot;The First Incense&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“I am no longer anxious about the box office”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the documentary about you &quot;Making Movies Well&quot;, you expressed directly that every time you shoot After finishing a movie, you will worry about the box office, which is a very anxious thing for you. Throughout your career, you have almost never stopped working, which is not easy in the Hong Kong film environment. Can you talk about your cooperation and competition with different film companies at different times? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Anhua: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t need to talk about the previous difficulties in detail, and starting from &quot;The First Incense&quot;, what you just said焦虑已经不存在了，因为对我来说，判断一部电影成功与否已经不完全是（通过）票房了。上世纪七八十年代，当时的香港（电影）不卖钱可不行，那就找不到下一部的钱。我感觉现在只要能得个奖，有少部分观众觉得特别好，导演名声在外的话还是可以找到投资的。当然，也不是说就一定可以拍到理想中的东西，因为投资方还是要评估这部电影是不是有收益。但我意识到我也不用焦虑了，我焦虑的是怕没戏拍，不是焦虑别人骂或者是不成功，所以这个问题已经不存在了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回想起来，每一部戏都有不同的困难，如果我说得很细，好像是诉苦，也没有必要。这就是我工作的一部分，不接受就不要做了，老是抱怨没有什么好处的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一般提到你，大家都会想到你拍的那些文艺片，会说你很有社会关怀。其实你也尝试过不少类型电影，比如武侠片、恐怖片，你拍这些是否受到市场的左右？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;《幽灵人间》这样的“鬼片”其实从来都没流行过的，很少人拍的；武打片是曾经流行过，我想拍是因为我是“武侠迷”。我只有很少数的几部电影完全是为了工作，比如拍摄《上海假期》，是因为当时在等下一部电影开拍，有人和我说《上海假期》的导演退出了，问我要不要拍，我看了剧本觉得还不错。我认可一个剧本才会拍，不会不认可就拍的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;大家总有一个感觉就是香港电影整体的环境都特别商业，类似你拍的《投奔怒海》《千言万语》这样的电影是不够主流的，几乎没有人拍的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那倒不是，香港其实也有不少导演拍这些的，可是产量不多，我感觉至少也有十几位吧，比如关锦鹏、张婉婷、罗启锐，跟我们同时期的谭家明……其实上世纪七八十年代还是蛮多人拍这种电影的，不是我一个人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;显然你和他们也有一些差异，比如1982年的《投奔怒海》，你就关注到了越南难民这个题材，当时很少有香港导演去拍香港之外的人和事，这和你的个人经历有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有关系，1978年的时候，我在无线电视台工作，要拍一部写实的剧集《狮子山下》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我选了拍摄这个题材，就做了好多功课，还跑去难民营。我开始对他们以前在越南的生活产生兴趣，发现很多难民根本就是华人，他们的唐人街和我小时候生活的澳门蛮像的，我对这种地方特别有情感，就想把这些画面拍进电影里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以你一直都特别关注社会现实？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我很少概念为先的，都是先看到人和事，觉得不错，再慢慢琢磨，最后才会理出一个逻辑，用来回答各种问题。比如要告诉编剧为什么要选择这样的故事，很多都是事后才会考虑的，最初往往就是凭借一时冲动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我知道你之所以接拍《第一炉香》，其实和《投奔怒海》也有一些渊源，是因为青鸟这家公司。为什么在当时香港的大环境里，夏梦会投资《投奔怒海》呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这类电影一直是不好找钱的，但夏梦有自己的理想和她强硬的后台，他们拍这部片子完全不想赚钱的，主要是为了拍摄一部有文化感的电影。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的电影处女作《疯劫》就获得了成功，拿了金马奖；《投奔怒海》获得了金像奖，当时你都不到35岁，可后来的十年间，你的几部电影又都不是很理想，直到《女人四十》事业才有了起色，这中间你是怎么熬过来的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我想知道为什么会这样，到底是拍的电影出了问题，还是我自己出了问题，不了解社会跟观众了吗？我其实蛮好奇的，也很想知道到底为什么有些片子不好，所以我就继续拍，能拍就拍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天回过头来看，你有找到这个原因吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有的，其实每一部都不一样。总体来说，1985年到1995年是香港动作片的全盛时代。整个行业里的工作人员习惯那种工作方式了，完全不配合我们这种类似学生作业、半工业化的方式，他们都是同时做好几组的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我的心情一直不太好，觉得自己和他们格格不入，工作也没有做好。因为工作人员拍商业片，同时做好几组，他们很累的，我也会觉得整个大环境不支持我拍的这类电影。 1994年以后，这波高潮就结束了，香港的电影工业开始慢下来了，大家差不多就回归到一次一部戏的状态里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这个过程当中，你没想过转型的问题吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我1986年就拍了《书剑恩仇录》，但不成功。 1991年左右拍了《极道追踪》，是一个黑帮片，也不成功。主要是我真的不喜欢拍动作，我跟动作指导合作，交给他就不管了，等到他来给我看，我也不习惯要反复地沟通。其实动作指导在现场指挥，我应该在后面待着，不停地跟他研究怎么拍，但我不是很喜欢这种形式的合作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;所以到了《女人四十》之后，你才找到什么样的电影是更适合自己的——也许投资不是特别大，但可以保持自己风格的电影？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，是这样的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/11/UFgR9VVlKnRjoF0jlRGlfTwx3JL09oYncmLdDsFh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;许鞍华根据张爱玲同名小说改编的电影《倾城之恋》(1984)，周润发(右二)和缪骞人(右一)饰演男女主角。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“我其实比较像内地导演”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是最早来内地拍戏的香港导演之一，1985年拍《书剑恩仇录》的时候，曾经在内地生活了整整一年。后来你的《半生缘》被看做当时合拍片的一部典范。等到了《玉观音》《黄金时代》等电影，可以说几乎就是内地资本占主要部分了。可你也不像陈可辛等导演那样把重心完全放在内地。或者像徐克，他和你一样都算是“香港新浪潮”的导演，但拍摄《长津湖》这种主旋律电影也得心应手。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对。我觉得1980年代我拍《投奔怒海》和《书剑恩仇录》的时候，内地的电影工业是很落后的。现在相对于香港来说，内地的电影工业变得很发达。比如你走进一家后期公司，它什么都安排好了，非常成熟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港商业片的导演和内地导演的思路也不太一样，他们有自己的创意，但完全以市场为焦点的，追求的是好看就行。但内地，就算是商业片导演都还是有一套伦理，想要文以载道，一定要有核心的主题才拍。我其实比较像内地的导演，要有一个主题贯穿在电影里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在香港大学读的是文学专业，我觉得你是很看重电影里的文学性的，而且你很喜欢在电影里使用一些文学元素，比如《男人四十》里的诗词。我觉得这些元素是你电影里的人物的来处，你的电影和王家卫等导演不同，人物总是有一个来处的，可能是物理意义的来处，也可能是精神意义的，这个来处往往是中国内地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，这些可能和我的经历有关，但也不是刻意的，有时候不是我加进去的，比如说《男人四十》里面念古诗的场面都是编剧岸西原创的。 《客途秋恨》里面那是真实的东西，我爷爷教我念诗，也不是我刻意地加的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你来内地拍的几部电影努力做着各种探索和尝试，《姨妈的后现代生活》《玉观音》《黄金时代》等等，几乎每一部都有争议。尤其是前两部，因为是现代戏，大家会觉得你不是很懂内地的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有争议是挺好的，的确也存在一些隔膜，比如观众有时候不喜欢配音，有时候不喜欢语言上带着口音，都不一样的。他们很在意台词讲得好不好，但我们广东话其实不太在意这个，讲的自然随便就好，没有所谓抑扬顿挫台词的训练，这是很大的分别。我想未来我可能还会拍内地生活，但要看题材是怎么样的，能拍的当然拍了，只是恐怕比较难，因为完全不知道好多生活细节。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你从《黄金时代》开始就一直在拍年代戏，是不是这样会更容易规避掉这些文化隔膜的东西？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，因为有些时候我不懂网络。尤其是现在这个网络时代，我连衣食住行都不懂，完全不一样了，比如说如何跟人家交往啊，怎么通电话啊，我都不知道了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“导演是一个年轻人的职业”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020年，你获得了威尼斯电影节的终身成就奖，当时你说未来想把精力放在培养年青一代的电影人身上，未来你在这方面可能会做哪些工作？你们这代导演被叫做“香港新浪潮”，你觉得未来华语地区的年轻导演是否还能形成一股新的浪潮？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有机会就做吧，我不会刻意去开一个公司，我不善于做这些事。如果有问题大家一起商量就很好啊，但不是真的大展宏图地做。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我讲“新浪潮”讲得太多了，开始有些受不了，其实正好那时候有一些从外国念电影的人回香港，一开始都在电视台工作，刚好差不多时间拍了电影，那时候传统的电影大厂制度有点不知道何去何从了，我们这群人在电视上拍了一些写实的东西，后来也就继续拍下来了。其实不是法国新浪潮这种革新电影历史和语言的想法了，当时也蛮繁荣的，大家都有戏可以拍，都很开心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实这些年一直都有不错的年轻人出来，只是可能不叫“新浪潮”，因为没有那么集中。香港还是很小的，从各种影展来看内地导演，一些年轻人拍得很好，坚持几年多拍几部，就会变成中坚分子了，这个跟“香港新浪潮”一样，只不过没有大锣大鼓地这么命名而已，其实你们媒体真的可以多给他们一些曝光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;给年轻人机会是好的，但没必要把帮助青年人挂在嘴里，变成一个没有预设的口号，我感觉年轻人需要的是精神上支持，而不是跑去做一个监制，要是出了问题，是换了对方，还是支持他做一些自己不认同的事情呢？我不想把这件事作为一个全职的事情，因为我不喜欢管人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;是不是可以理解为，你在工作里既不想管别人，也不想被人管？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不是的，拍电影是一个高度合作的工作，怎么能不跟人合作呢？可是我自己有一些标准，有什么是人家不能管的，要不然你白拍了；有些什么是人家能管的，自己知道就行了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也要看具体的情况，比如说真是很想拍某部电影，底线可能会变低，或者反而会高要求。我是保持这个灵活性的，不能一早说了自己一定如何，到时候可能会自打嘴巴的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你已经74岁了，我真的很好奇你是如何保持一直拍电影的状态，你的同辈人甚至一些晚辈，很多都退休了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我自己都在问这个问题，我在工作的时候没有想过克服什么困难，因为困难是一定的，导演这个行业和自己的灵感以及多想拍有关系。有些人拍得差不多了，就觉得要去赚钱了，或者要改职业了，这恐怕不是因为遭遇了什么挫折。一个人其实很难一生都在拍电影，导演是一个年轻人的职业。超过五十岁，体力就跟不上了，也跟不上时代了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍《女人四十》以前，我才四十多岁，就有朋友叫我退休了，但我就是不服气，我也没有什么事情是可以超越拍电影这件事的。当然，我的例子只是个别情况，拿来给人家做一个鼓励，但也许没有什么用，做导演又不能发财，喜欢才可以一直拍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前几年内地电影市场特别繁荣，一些人会产生做了导演就可以获得某些名利的错觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没关系，你什么时候停，为了什么去拍，只要自己搞清楚就可以了。我觉得做每件事都需要想清楚为何去做，不是人家如何也跟着去做。做导演最好是能够不断地挑战自己，如果每次都一样，来来去去都是同样的东西，我可能就不会继续拍了。另外，在这个激烈变迁的世界和社会，导演的位置变得很快。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我一直在考虑拍什么人家才会想看，也可能去拍剧集。老实讲，最重要的就是要保持身体健康，没有这个什么都做不了，至于想拍什么，会不会有成就，这些都是不能保证的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;说到年龄限制，欧洲和美国年纪很大还在拍的导演并不少，比如克林特·伊斯特伍德(Clint Eastwood)，九十多岁了还在拍电影，但亚洲几乎没有这样的导演，你觉得和文化有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;许鞍华：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当然了。他们团队比较适合年纪大的导演吧，因为分工分得比较细，拍摄制度也比较完善，可能每天就拍6个小时，他们都是有度的，比较容易，不像我们这边这么拼命，但你说的这种现象其实都是非常少数的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[代长胖、代健身、代赶高铁……这些赚钱的路子你能看懂吗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“互换住房”有没有风险？理解年轻人对人性的乐观、对陌生人的善意丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The long holiday is long and it’s time to travel. According to the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, domestic tourism trips nationwide are expected to reach 896 million during this year&#39;s long holiday, a year-on-year increase of 86%. During the seven-day long holiday in 2019, the country received a total of 782 million domestic tourists. There is one more day this year, which means that the average number of domestic travelers during this year’s long holiday has returned to the level of 2019. It seems that the recovery of the tourism industry is real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data shows that during the long holiday, the cultural tourism market in popular tourist cities such as Shanghai and Suzhou in the Yangtze River Delta and Pearl River Delta regions is extremely hot. Orders for hotels, air tickets, etc. have increased at least five times compared with the same period last year. Prices have also generally risen significantly. On the eve of the long holiday, many netizens posted &quot;travel housing exchange&quot; posts on social platforms, looking for netizens with travel destinations opposite to their own to exchange housing and save money. This is in line with the original intention of tourism: traveling is nothing more than going from a place you are tired of playing to a place others are tired of playing, escaping from daily life and looking for a sense of alienation and freshness that is different from daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When exchanging houses, each party will go to the other party&#39;s city and live in the other party&#39;s house at the same time. The risk should be controllable, because each party at least knows the other party&#39;s real information such as address and contact information. &quot;Reciprocity&quot; is originally an effective means to establish a &quot;balance of power&quot; and control risks such as breach of trust. However, if the housing exchange agreement reached by both parties is that one party will first go to the other party&#39;s city during this holiday and live in the other party&#39;s house, and the other party will claim his own consideration after a period of time, there will inevitably be some risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is security risk. Even if there is an agreement, the person who comes to check in is a stranger to you, and you cannot verify his or her identity. He may use a fake name and ID card. Even if you do not reveal your true identity, your address, contact information and other information will always be with you. Really, this creates asymmetry and asymmetry. If the other party has a serious disease, it will harm the health of the family; if the other party has bad hygiene habits, the living environment will be very poor, which will inevitably cause headaches. If the other party intentionally or unintentionally damages the facilities in the house, it will also be troublesome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is the risk of breach of trust. As long as it is not a transaction or agreement where the money is paid and the goods are delivered, there is such a risk. After you have fulfilled the agreement and entertained them with good intentions, but when you go to the city where they are located, they directly break the contract and breach of trust. There is nothing you can do. To protect your own rights and interests, or if the living conditions provided by the other party are far from what they claim, and they take advantage of you, you will most likely have to hold your nose and endure it. Physical exchanges are not delivered at the same time, and it is common for the goods to be incorrect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are complaints about &quot;specialty exchange&quot; everywhere on the platform: being taken advantage of and deceived by the other party. In the final analysis, there is still an underestimation of human nature. The ancients had a saying of &quot;Be cautious of independence&quot;, which is very reasonable as a criterion for judging whether a person is truly moral. Many people&#39;s morals are flexible: they speak morally in front of acquaintances, because failure to speak up will have consequences and will affect their reputation; they don&#39;t speak morally in front of strangers, and even do evil on the spur of the moment, because they feel that no one knows them. It is difficult to be held accountable even if someone is willful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, in order to avoid the above two risks, you insist on verifying the other party&#39;s identity, such as finding a trusted third party to guarantee, or collecting the other party&#39;s accommodation fee in advance? In this case, what&#39;s the difference between doing a B&amp;B? If you want to stay in a B&amp;B, wouldn&#39;t it be easier to list the available rooms for sale on the OTA platform? After being screened by the platform, the security risks are controllable and there is no risk of breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you insist on doing it yourself, you are actually following the old path of Airbnb’s evolution: At first, everyone just wanted to save money than staying in a hotel and build a platform to build a bridge. But after a period of brutal growth and After the chaos, it was discovered that the grass-roots team was not good enough, and it still needed specialization and standardization, so that professional people could do professional things. It was difficult to use amorphous &quot;non-standard&quot; services for a long time. In the end, Airbnb had not returned to the hotel model. The so-called B&amp;Bs that are aggregated are just numerous small-scale hotels run by private individuals. In large-scale talent shows, the final winners are often those who major in music or dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having said that, exchanging housing is actually &quot;sofa living&quot; with a different name, and it also has its own ecological niche. People with families can&#39;t help but frown when they think of the above risks. When going out, they would rather spend money to stay in a hotel than get into trouble just to save money. This is indeed good. But for young people who have just started working, they rent a house that they can just live in. There are no valuables or facilities in it, they have no long-term possessions, and in short, they have no money. Because they are relatively young and fresh when they first enter the society, they have no understanding of human nature. With optimism and kindness towards strangers, the above-mentioned risks are not a problem. Isn’t it appropriate to let netizens from other places come and stay for a few nights, and do the same when I go to other places? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are young people, both are poor, both understand the need to save money, and have a common topic. A stranger may be able to bring him a world that he has never been exposed to or even imagined before, fully exposing himself to Through randomness, you can interact with more people and discover a larger and broader world. If you go out on your own, you can &quot;travel thousands of miles&quot;, and when others walk in, you can &quot;travel thousands of miles to you.&quot; Movement is relative, and changing the frame of reference is the same thing. Your own experience and the experience of others can increase your knowledge. See. Although you may meet some bad people and weirdos, you will also get to know some good friends who can become lifelong friends. The risks are controllable, so why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of openness and sharing spirit among young people is commendable. To a certain extent, if all you think about when encountering problems are risks, and then you are hesitant and hesitant to do anything, it is actually a sign that your heart is getting older. Therefore, we can warn young people of risks in good faith, but there is no need to intimidate young people with various risks. We should be happy to see young people make full use of this youthful time. This beautiful and wanton time is short. Our body will age, but our mentality should try to stay young, energetic and courageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[布克奖得主弗兰纳根：活下去，比时代活得更久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3sGId82ZeAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3 sGId82ZeAd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Joel Saget/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The world is becoming more and more uncertain and disorderly. Since no one knows what will happen tomorrow, this story may remind them that in an uncertain world In this world, we still have each other&#39;s love, which is probably the only thing we can be sure of in this life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, the Australian writer Richard Flanagan (Richard Flanagan) wrote the novel The novel &quot;The Way North&quot; won the Booker Prize. The novel is based on his father&#39;s experience of being captured by the Japanese during World War II and building the &quot;Death Railway&quot; in Thailand and Burma. It tells the life of Australian military doctor Dorigo Evans in two lines: he tried his best to save lives in a prisoner of war camp and was on the verge of death. companion, when he is lonely and hopeless, he will continue to recall the only unforgettable love in his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Flanagan&#39;s writing, &quot;Dorigo Evans will live a long time and witness all the changes&quot; - he feels that something is withering, but he will live on and be better than himself Live longer...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a masterpiece about love and war,&quot; the Booker Prize citation stated. &quot;Flanagan&#39;s elegant narrative tells a story of the coexistence of sin and heroism.&quot; The story connects the East and the West, the past and the present.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flanagan was born in Tasmania, southeastern Australia, in 1961. For generations, people have lived in this &quot;end of the world&quot; &quot;The logging life on a desert island. Both his grandparents were illiterate, and his father was the only one in the family who received a basic education. &quot;My father had a strong feeling for the beauty and magic of words. He lamented until his death that people can use these 26 letters to glimpse the universe. Reading can enjoy freedom and transcendent power. The magic carpet of literature has lifted me from this world. Take a small island far away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, Flanagan published his debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;. He tells the story of the river guide Aliyah in a language that is freehand, dreamy, and full of original tension. Even through his experience of capsizing a boat and drowning in Tasmania&#39;s Franklin River, through the torrent-like confessions of the dead, Flanagan closely tied his personal experience to the mythical history of Tasmania&#39;s ancestors. &quot;I could write about the mud, the smell, the heat and the blood, but it was the readers who brought the emotion, the sympathy, the sorrow and the pity. The book didn&#39;t get many reviews at the time, but it gained readers, which is enough to give a book life .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late summer and early autumn of 2023, the new translation of Flanagan&#39;s &quot;The Road to the North&quot; and the Chinese translation of his new work &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot; were published in China. Hobart, the capital of Nigeria, accepted an online interview with Southern People Weekly. “Literature opened my eyes to the depth and breadth of each person, and the possibilities that are within each of us, both evil and good. When you realize that people can be everything, they can be murderers and When you are a saint, you can learn to look at the world with humility and understand that anything that happens has nothing to do with you, but is a way of our existence as human beings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The lower world is more real, The universe of literature points directly to human nature&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I heard that before becoming a professional writer, you worked as a construction worker and gardener, and you also considered going to northern Australia for mining. How have your past work experiences inspired you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed, I have done a lot of work, and these experiences have made me realize that most people&#39;s lives are so difficult. In order to have food to eat and a house to live in, people struggle to survive. They don&#39;t like their bosses, and their jobs are very menial and extremely hard. This is actually the daily life situation of most people in the world. I always tell myself that if I’m lucky enough to be a full-time writer, I’ll never forget those hard times and I’ll never complain about the difficulties of writing, because you’ve been given the extraordinary privilege of having the opportunity to do what you love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various experiences in the past have also made me discover that when you are close to those powerful and famous people, their world is not real, but when you are at the bottom, people are often very honest, and they are Tell the truth to each other, so you&#39;ll find plenty of truth. My grandparents were both illiterate, and I was lucky enough to become a writer. When I was with them and their friends, I could see a real world, but when I was with people who had achieved great things, I found that understanding The truth is much more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, the protagonist Aliash fell in love with a girl of Chinese descent, Kota He. You also wrote about the history of the He family. What original material was there? You also visited China in 2018, can you share your impressions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, I have some Chinese cousins. In the 19th century, many Chinese came to Australia and they intermarried with the locals, so many Australians Everyone has Chinese relatives. I wrote about China in my novel because I grew up in such an environment and I am no stranger to the Chinese. There was a period in Australia&#39;s history when racism was high and many Chinese were forced to leave, but thankfully that has changed again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I visited China last time, I talked with the Chinese writer Yu Hua. His experience was very different from mine, but we shared our thoughts on reading and writing. His literature The hero is also William Faulkner like me, and I find that our creative philosophies are also very similar. When you become a writer, you may enter forbidden areas, but you also belong to a literary universe, and that universe speaks directly to human nature. I was deeply moved by the fact that you meet a friend from far away, who writes a book from another far away country, but you share similar sources of inspiration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned your hero Faulkner. Faulkner believed that experience, observation and imagination are three necessary conditions for a writer. Which one is the most important in your writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Faulkner is not completely telling the truth here, because his experience is not rich, and mine is not. not much. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Laugh)&lt;/span>; I visited Faulkner&#39;s former home in Oxford, Mississippi, and he created that world out of his imagination, a kind of To a certain extent, this is also his observation of that world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing is a craft that requires long-term polishing, just like making furniture. Many times it is just the continuous improvement of ordinary labor, which is what Maupassant said: writing black words on white paper. But there is also a mysterious part to writing. The great jazz musician Duke Ellington once talked about his composition. People said that the piano music was so great. He said, no, it was a dream. I completely agree that all great creations are like a dream. When you dream, you will find that, for example, you are in Shanghai and I am in Tasmania, but we are connected, talking about the absent Yu Hua and the late Faulkner. You find that you are not just one person and one person. You are connected to everyone, even beyond time, space and life and death. All of this is you and not you. It is important to find this in imagination. This points to the highest realm of creation. When we reach there, we know that we are not you. No longer alone. Writing reminds me to share with others, and just as people can relate to a work of art, I think creators must bravely break into that place. Observation and description alone are not enough. We need to rely on imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;We are constantly corrupting as we move forward, and we are lost in the theater of emotions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Why is there always light at the beginning of all things?&quot; &quot;The Path to the North&quot; opens with this philosophical question. How did this beginning come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Parts of this novel touch on the dark side of the world. I think that if your creation involves darkness, it must be balanced with light. If all readers see is the dark side, they will not believe it, and they have reason to choose not to believe it, because it is not in line with our knowledge and understanding of ourselves as human beings. . If there is only darkness in the end, then it does not truly tell the whole story of human nature. The core of the human spirit lies in having hope. Without hope, we are just zombies. So, I chose to balance the whole story with light and hope. Therefore, this work is about war, but it also depicts love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, my first memory of light is actually in that church, my grandmother and mother hugged me, and I saw a beam of light coming over me, and it was the woman who loved me. running in their arms. As we age, we lose our sight, our hair... but I think the saddest thing is that we lose that sense of wonder. As a child, you retained this extraordinary and wonderful feeling that as long as you could see the light, you were content. I wanted to commemorate this flash of memory by placing it at the beginning of the novel, because it tells a truth that we have long forgotten. As we grow up, we lose this sense of wonder, awe and joy, but this was once It’s a great truth that we learn as children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;697&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The novel opens with a description of a little boy’s fear after his finger was injured and being bullied by his peers while playing ball. Have these details about a boy’s growth also happened in your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, these are more based on stories my father told me. Tasmania is not like other places. It is the poorest region in Australia. People here not only live in poor areas, but also live in older eras. I tried to write that feeling in the story. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the football story, once again, he ran into the light and felt the light. This moment embodies the profound feelings we had when we were young, and we can never go back to them. There&#39;s this misconception in the West that we&#39;re constantly moving forward and shedding innocence, and I don&#39;t buy that. We are constantly corrupting as we move forward. In fact, innocence is a treasure we once had, but we are too forgetful and have discarded many of the most basic things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Later, crying became a simple confirmation of emotion... Emotions have become fashionable, emotions have become theater, and as actors, people have no way of knowing who they are after getting off the stage.&quot; Can you give some interpretation to this passage in the book? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The world is undergoing tremendous changes. People now express their emotions more, but sometimes, the emotions they express are not Not sincere. It&#39;s not good to suppress emotions, but I think sometimes expressions in public spaces have gone too far. Whether people agree with it or not, this is one of the biggest changes in the past 100 years. I think a novel could reflect these kinds of changes that we talk less about. I wanted a character who understood these strange changes and documented them. For the protagonist Dorigo, this change is shocking because he has been playing a certain role his whole life. He is not a hero but has to pretend to be one because this is what the other prisoners of war demand of him. After the war, he had to continue playing this role, he had to wear this mask, and he knew it was a lie, but it had become a necessity in life for other people, so he agreed, partly because he avoided it. own emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What interests me is that when a person becomes a leader or a celebrity, we often think that they created this identity themselves, but in fact we &quot;created&quot; them, we decided to let them Becoming a celebrity or a hero, sometimes these roles are a kind of imprisonment for people. Celebrity and fame are some manifestations of misunderstanding and trouble. Behind this is loneliness. The fact is that the more famous you are, the lonelier you are. This is not a paradox. But the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life is alive, walking on the roof of hell, gazing at flowers&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The title and the first part of the quotation of &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot; are all quoted from haiku by Matsuo Basho. The last four parts of the novel are opened with haiku by Kobayashi Icha. Please tell me your considerations in choosing these haiku. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This book was difficult for me to write. At first I didn’t think I could do it. I didn’t want to offend my father by writing something that he felt was incompatible with his experience and seemed like a betrayal. It took me 12 years to write this work, and it also took me that long to find the most suitable way of expression. Finally, I finished this writing with love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t want to judge anyone, I just want to show what humans do to each other. I wanted to organize the book in a form that I learned from Japanese literature. I could use the most beautiful things in Japanese culture to present the worst atrocities in the same society. Writing it like this might be a way for me to liberate myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The structure of this book is a bit like &quot;Rashomon&quot;, looking at crimes from multiple perspectives, presenting different perspectives on the same crime, interspersed with Japanese poetry. I long to strip away all the trappings, and in fact, the more you strip away, the more you allow readers to discover the true meaning. When I write, I try to keep taking things away, cutting and cutting, so that what is left is something that the reader can find meaning and purpose in, rather than me telling him what it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Two of the haiku of Kobayashi Icha you quoted involve &quot; &quot;The World of Dew&quot;, how do you understand &quot;The World of Dew&quot;? What do you think of Eastern Zen thought? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Japanese militarism was deeply influenced by Zen thought&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(Note: The theory of Zen is one of the ideological weapons used in Japanese militarism&#39;s war mobilization. For relevant discussions, see &quot;Japanese Zen and Militarism&quot;, &quot;Misunderstandings of Modern Japanese Zen and Its Beyond&quot; and other papers)&lt;/span>;, There is a strange ecstasy in the latter, but the same ideas can also manifest themselves as evil when they advocate Japanese militarism. At the end of the book, I quoted a haiku: &quot;While I&#39;m alive/Walking on the rooftops of hell/Looking at the flowers,&quot; for me, that&#39;s the haiku that sums up the book. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2014, Australian writer Richard Flanagan (right) won the Booker Prize for his novel &quot;The Passage to the North&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;In the novel, you inserted the &quot;circle&quot; made with one stroke of the brush into the text. Could you tell us about your understanding and conception of this pattern? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a famous death poem by the 18th-century haiku poet Zomizu. Death poems are one of the traditions of Japanese literature. Before, Zhishui grabbed a brush and &quot;drawed&quot; the poem. People found that he just used the brush to draw a circle on the paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To me, the void, mystery, and reincarnation contained in this circle fit the theme of the story, and also fit the novel’s repetitive structure, echoing from beginning to end, “the magnificent wheel, the eternal return.” &quot;: The Opposite of a Circle and a Thin Line.&quot; At the end of the book, we don&#39;t know whether Dorigo is dead or alive. In fact, he never left the prisoner of war camp. Some ghosts trapped him in a special place forever: there is love and hell. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tasmania, we have a different concept of time: it often feels like time goes back and forth and never moves forward. I think this is a broader concept of time. We often move from this year to next year, and then to the year after that. What happened 10 years ago is in the past, but the aboriginal people here believe that what happened a thousand years ago It is happening today and it will happen again tomorrow. I think this more truly reflects our self-perception. The idea that what happened in the past is the past is actually an illusion. Nothing has ever passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people suffer from dementia, we say they have lost consciousness, but they have only lost their memory. Once you lose your memory, you cannot control your current life because people rely on their memory to understand everything. So this Australian Aboriginal concept of time plays a role in my work, and my novels are often presented in a cyclical structure, rather than being linear in a one-dimensional space like most English novels. Narrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The past can be forgiven, but cannot be forgotten&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;From &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; to &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot;, your writings have all explored the secrets of memory. You once mentioned, &quot;I have witnessed how people who have lost their memory fall into panic. .&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I&#39;m fascinated by the way people remember the past. We usually think of memory as a kind of witness. I tell you what happened 50 years ago, just like I have a camera. But in fact, memory is more likely to be an act of creation, capable of spinning lies as well as truth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father gradually lost the memory of the violence and pain he suffered, but in the end, he left behind the idea of ​​love. Although what he experienced was not love, what he finally had Memory was something he himself discovered to be valuable. I thought a lot about this, trying to capture the way people think through memory. Memory is thought to represent some kind of statement of justice, which it may or may not be. There is a paradox here: when people experience major trauma and you and your compatriots suffer great pain, the first thing people want to do is forget. I think the reason why humans survive is the ability to forget; but with At the same time, in order to free yourself, you must retreat into your memory and face the shadows in order to understand what happened and free your soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to war, we are fed a lot of lies about villains and heroes. When something terrible happens, it doesn&#39;t just affect the individual, a terrible war or social unrest, the trauma affects my family as well. and friends, will eventually slowly poison the surrounding community, and even the entire society. Because war is a black hole of horror, and those huge traumas are difficult to describe and spread. Those who have experienced it sometimes erase part of their memories. The responsibility falls on novelists, who try to piece together the past to better understand what happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your father once said: &quot;You can forgive the past. , but you can’t forget.” You just mentioned releasing your soul. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just said that people survive by forgetting, but they have to remember something, and people will hate it. You want to live because hate is a strong emotion, but ultimately, you can&#39;t move forward in your hate and you have to put it aside and find another way out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father experienced a very touching thing during his lifetime. About twenty years ago, three middle-aged Japanese women showed up at my house. They were incredibly brave and dedicated their lives to documenting Japan’s war crimes. One of them wrote a book about Unit 731, a horrific crime committed by the Japanese in your country. She suffered a lot in Japan for writing this book. She herself is actually a survivor of the Tokyo bombing, a horrific crime committed by the Allies against Japan that killed more than 100,000 innocent civilians. But she came to my house with two other ladies. They wanted to apologize to my father. They did not represent the government or the Japanese people. I was very surprised. I never thought that someone from another country would come to my house and apologize to us. It meant a lot to our family to apologize and it was such a release for all of us. The feats of these three women taught me that there is a way out, and that it is not about dividing people into opposing sides, but that we can rise above it all and live a better outcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salute to the open and free world&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You often mention your father, can you tell us about your mother and siblings? I know you are the fifth of six children, have they all read your work? Any feedback? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You did your homework! We were all very close as brothers and sisters, and everyone was surprised that I became a writer. No one expected a writer from Tasmania. They read my books and liked my novels. Being a writer and winning the Booker Prize are honors, but in any family, you are ultimately a son or a daughter, a brother or a sister, and what your family means to each other is the most important thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother was a lovely woman, full of stories. Tasmania was once the golden bag of the British Empire and a huge prison. Over the centuries, the British exiled felons here. Political prisoners, slave owners and slaves... all kinds of people came here. here. My ancestors are Irish, and there are many Catholics in Ireland. They gathered, intermarried, and settled here, forming a unique culture. Ireland is rich in stories and has produced many writers. I talk about my father because of &quot;The Road to the North&quot;, but I am very close to my mother. I have listened to her telling stories passed down from generation to generation since I was a child. Many of my writings come from my mother. Like women of her time, life was restricted and unlike Women today have all kinds of opportunities, but she was an amazing woman and I loved her so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How has Irish literature influenced you? Are there any Irish writers that you particularly admire? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I admire many Irish writers, but the ones who really influence me are Borges, Neruda, and Marquez , Cortázar and other South American writers, because their world is more like the world of Tasmania. We have people here who do comedy, trying to find their own experience, their own reality and escape the colonial influence of the British, while they were trying to escape the colonial influence of Spain in South America. The beauty of Faulkner is that he was both an American writer and not, he was from the South but was never really accepted into the United States, but he had an important influence on French and South American literature, and in my opinion he really was the 20th century The central figure who achieved breakthroughs in novel writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; Aliash was not born in Tasmania, but in Trieste. Why did he choose this small European city as his birthplace? Joyce lived in Trieste, does this have anything to do with where he wrote &quot;Ulysses&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s right! As you can imagine, Death of the River Guide was my debut novel, and I wanted my first &quot;child&quot; to be born in Trieste. Trieste is different from many places in the world. It is a mixture. It is freer and more open. It is not really Italy, it is not really Slovenia, and it is not really Germany, but it is all, all kinds of ideas. and culture meet there. What interests me is that Joyce wrote his great novel not in Paris, not in Dublin, but in this dilapidated, disintegrating old port. His writing was influenced by all these peoples, and he was deeply inspired by &quot;The Consciousness of Zeno&quot;, but the author Italo Svevo only used a pseudonym. He was an Italian Jew, and his real name was Ettore Schmitz. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another reason why Aliash was born in Trieste. My wife is from Slovenia. When I wrote &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, Yugoslavia had just disintegrated and Slovenia had just Birth. I am very interested in multi-ethnic countries where different ethnic groups live together and often have frictions and conflicts, but sometimes they are full of creativity. You just asked me which writers I am influenced by. I mentioned South American writers, but I am also influenced by Central European writers. Before World War II, especially before the 1940s, those great &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Central European)&lt;/span>; writers did not represent their own countries; Greater ideas at the time, but after ethnic cleansing many places became small enclaves. Australia, which was a very racist country for most of the 20th century, now opens its doors and welcomes everyone in and is a richer place because of its cultural and spiritual tolerance. Central Europe at the beginning of the 20th century allowed me to see a world full of hope. I made the protagonist in my novel live in Trieste to pay tribute to that open and free world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Hometown pain&quot;: I have never left home, but I feel vaguely separated from my hometown and feel deeply lost&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About your new work &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot; published in 2020, you once mentioned that this work is related to &quot;Hometown Pain&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（solastalgia）&lt;/span>;The artistic conception of this new word is related. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a new word proposed by an Australian philosopher: When a person&#39;s environment is destroyed and his heart is lost, I vaguely feel that I am separated from my homeland. I have never left home, but I feel the painful feeling of being a stranger in a foreign land. The term began to be used heavily after Australia experienced its horrific bushfires. That&#39;s the feeling one gets after a hometown has gone through some hard times and realizes that the good old days are gone forever. I think the trauma of so many precious things being taken away from us in the name of development and progress, which benefits only a few and deprives everyone else, affects us in very real ways. causing a devastating blow to the body and mind. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 17, 2018, one-way space in Beijing, Chinese writer Yu Hua (right) talks with Australian writer Richard Flanagan&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot;, facing a disaster, the heroine Anna keeps checking the news updates on her mobile phone, but her fear and anxiety only increase. Starting from the loss of a ring finger, various parts of her body gradually disappeared, but she felt no pain or consciousness. How did this idea come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We live in a strange time, with a lot of things happening to us, but we choose not to look at them. At the beginning of the novel, I quoted the English Romantic poet John Clare&#39;s &quot;Memorial&quot;: &quot;The ax of destroyers and selfish desires has cut down its prey; / I will never see the water lily path and the narrow round oak street here again / There are also large hollow trees like church pulpits: / The enclosure movement was like Napoleon, eradicating everything...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The enclosure movement in the 19th century was a very tragic and terrible event in European history. thing, but I think there&#39;s a new enclosure movement in the world now that&#39;s taking away from us those things that anchor us spiritually. People started losing limbs, eyes, knees...no one noticed, and at the same time we were checking our phones more and more every day instead of paying attention to what was going on in the real world. With the rise of social software, many people’s souls have been occupied. Everyone has a public life and a private life and a secret life, and great literature creates characters in conflict who do one thing and think the opposite, and there is a third side that they don&#39;t understand either. Why are we so contradictory? This is what we humans are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, these technologies allow us to display our private lives publicly, interpret our lives, and turn them into benefits to please others. This is a threat to us no matter where we are, and for most people, I think, ultimately, their presence is not to help us, but to exploit us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think you are a pessimist or an optimist? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Neither. In &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot;, Anna&#39;s mother said before her death that the world is so beautiful, but few people see it. I think the world is beautiful when I find those lovely people, but we often choose to turn a blind eye. The more we allow ourselves to see, the greater our hope becomes. So I am not pessimistic. I try to discover the simple beauty in people every day. I believe that this little bit of joy will nourish you and keep you alive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“助农”靠假货，走红靠演技？野生MCN怎么成了“凉山制造”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258014]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访《人世间》导演李路：“任何时代都是以小人物为分母构成的”丨影视大咖谈③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257479]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE6 3. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the TV series &quot;Human World&quot;, the head of the Zhou family, Zhou Zhigang, returned from the junior college after his retirement. &quot;Photographic films&quot; to my hometown and the urban-rural fringe area. Even so, it is difficult for the family to reunite and make dumplings during the New Year. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the crew)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV series &quot;The World&quot; shows the &quot;silent generation&quot; and also brings to life the &quot;silent generation&quot; generation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, it was China in 1969. In Jichun City, a provincial capital city in Northeast China, a young man named Zhou Bingkun experienced two major events: one was witnessing death row prisoners being paraded and shot, and the other was working together in a factory workshop My son&#39;s good friend was deeply shocked; secondly, his father Zhou Zhigang wanted to work as a bricklayer in the &quot;third front&quot; to support the construction of the third front. His brother Zhou Bingyi and sister Zhou Rong also responded to the call to &quot;go to the mountains and countryside&quot; and became educated youths. Zhou Bingkun and his mother depended on each other. The family&#39;s life trajectory has changed dramatically since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story unfolds from here, spanning fifty years. The five members of the Zhou family, who are from the working class and are the permanent residents of &quot;Light Word Film&quot;, are the center of the story, from which branches and branches radiate. In addition to the Zhou family, there are as many as hundreds of characters appearing in &quot;The World&quot;, outlining the &quot;big rivers&quot; of a generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play is adapted from the novel &quot;Human World&quot; by writer Liang Xiaosheng and Mao Dun Literary Award-winning novel of the same name. When director Li Lu got the novel, &quot;Human World&quot; had not yet won the award. Li Lu was so moved after reading it that he decided to adapt it into a TV series. His two previous masterpieces were the anti-corruption drama &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and the legal drama &quot;Itinerant Prosecution Team&quot;. Earlier, he was the deputy director of production at Nanjing Film Studio and the director of the TV Drama Production Center of Jiangsu TV Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Lu is ambitious in making TV series. If he wants to make a film, he must make a great work. The little characters in &quot;Human World&quot; meet his inner definition of &quot;greatness&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the project was finalized, Li Lu asked Liang Xiaosheng to meet. The first thing he asked Liang Xiaosheng during the meeting was: Why do you want to write this novel? Liang Xiaosheng told him that it was just some personal feelings at first. Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s father was a construction worker in the &quot;Grand Third Front&quot;. He left home in the mid-1950s and only returned every few years. After finally returning home to visit relatives, the &quot;educated youth&quot; Liang Xiaosheng went to the countryside again. He always missed his father and saw him very rarely. One of the reasons why Liang Xiaosheng wrote &quot;Human World&quot; was to make up for the lack of emotion. Especially after the death of his father, he felt that he should use words to pay tribute to that generation of workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation of Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s family is very similar to that of the Zhou family in &quot;The Human World&quot;. During the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, his father went to the third line, and Liang Xiaosheng and his eldest brother went to the countryside. The mother, brother, sister and one child were left in the family. Little brother. The elder brother suffers from mental illness, and the younger brother bears the burden of taking care of the whole family. Zhou Bingkun in the play has the shadow of his little brother. &quot;These young people who stay in ordinary working families in the city are almost missing in our literature, drama, film and television dramas. They are rarely shown and they are a silent generation. So I will write a book for them.&quot; Liang Xiaosheng said in the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Xiaosheng also had questions about Li Lu. He asked Li Lu: Why should such a novel be made into a TV series? Li Lu replied: &quot;I have feelings for the theme of workers.&quot; Seven years ago, Li Lu spent his own money to acquire an industrial-themed novel, but could not find a screenwriter. Like Liang Xiaosheng, Li Lu is also from the Northeast. When he was growing up, he witnessed the prosperity and decline of Northeast heavy industry, and also witnessed the pain and perseverance of workers in the face of being laid off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since &quot;Human World&quot; was launched on January 28, 2022, it has become a hot topic on the Internet. The angle of discussion covers all aspects and overflows the play itself - there are discussions about success and filial piety: Part 1 Who is more successful or more filial, the elder brother and sister from Peking University, who returned from school to become the deputy governor, and the younger brother who never went to college and devoted himself to taking care of the family? Someone discussed love: The old couple of the Zhou family have not seen each other for several years. Is there any love between them? My sister Zhou Rong risked everything for love and went to a mountain ravine to accompany the poet to live a hard life and become an educated youth. Years later, she had to face her lover&#39;s cheating and betrayal. Was her efforts worth it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the broadcast of &quot;Human World&quot;, Li Lu often received WeChat messages from friends. A doctor friend sent a WeChat message and repeatedly confirmed to him, &quot;Bingkun and Bingyi, are they okay in the future?&quot; ? No problem, right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe this type of drama has become less popular over the years, so it really touches everyone&#39;s hearts.&quot; Li Lu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Lu remembers that when &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; was broadcast in 2017, &quot;There was feedback from all walks of life, including many provincial leaders who watched &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; during lunch and sat there with their lunch boxes. , as well as the people in the army and the grassroots of society, it is really a broken circle. This time we are also paying close attention to whether the circle is really broken in the true sense. Is it you who are shouting, or more people like it after dinner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;It must be warmth as the background color&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Original work by Liang Xiaosheng &quot;The Human World&quot; is called &quot;the epic of the common people.&quot; When you decided to shoot &quot;The Human World&quot;, how did you understand and sort out this work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was June 2018 when I got &quot;Human World&quot;. At that time, it had not won the Mao Dun Literature Award, and it had not yet won the Mao Dun Literature Award. It’s not called a “popular epic,” just a set of novels that have just been published. After &quot;In the Name of the People&quot;, I took on some projects, but I felt that none of them surpassed &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and &quot;Inspection Team&quot;, which made the cooperation team very difficult. They asked what kind of theme you should choose, and I said, great, just three words. Later, a literary editor told me that Liang Xiaosheng had just published a novel that you should read, but it was longer, with 1.15 million words. I read this novel and was very interested. But there is still a huge difference between text and visuals, and the reading level and viewership are completely different. Therefore, there needs to be an improvement from the novel text to the script, and there is another way to go from the script to the visualization. The 58-episode TV series now presented to the audience is an extremely compact version that we have made, because we rough cut it to 88 episodes, fine cut it to 72 episodes, submit it for review to 66 episodes, and finally compress it to 58 episodes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You hope to make a great work, &quot; &quot;Human World&quot; tells the story of a group of small people. Is there a connection between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To clearly see the huge power behind the words of the novel &quot;The World&quot;, this may not be seen by many people. How can writing the youth history of such a small family, an alley, and an area reflect the tremendous changes in China over the past fifty years? How can it have huge appeal and influence? Speaking of conscience requires discernment. Some people even questioned the Internet sense, and some questioned the age level of the audience, whether anyone would watch such a story about suffering, etc. I am the overall person in charge and the actual operator of this drama. From the selection of materials to the gestation and layout of this drama, I have always been like &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; (I signed the contract with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate Film and Television Center with my personal ID card). I know how to make this kind of play, who should be cast, and on what platform it will be broadcast. It is very clear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the filming of &quot;The Human World&quot; was finalized, I met with teacher Liang Xiaosheng. After meeting me, I wanted to hear Teacher Liang’s original intention of creating it. Just like when I approached Zhou Meisen, Zhou Meisen impressed me with just one sentence. He told me what kind of &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; he wanted to make and how to make it. This time too, after Teacher Liang came, I think everyone has the same point of view. They have a sense of mission. They want to serve the people, want to serve the common people, and want to serve the people and things of this era, which have undergone drastic changes in Chinese history over the past 50 years. Given visual and written proof, everyone still has feelings for family and country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years ago, I personally paid for a novel about factory industry, but I couldn’t find a screenwriter and no one would write it. I think this is also inevitable, because seven years ago we were still walking around in absolute entertainment, and no one would sit down and watch it when it was filmed. Therefore, the most important thing is that many things happen at the right time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The opening of &quot;Human World&quot; is about the years of educated youth during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; , what are your thoughts on the presentation of this special historical period? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Xiaosheng’s “scar literature” is “good human literature”, which has left a deep mark on the literary world. But this time in the TV series, we did not add more words to the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and the issue of educated youth, and used only a few words to represent a community. For example, the female educated youth who plays the piano is a southern educated youth from Shanghai. When she came to Northeast China, it was so cold. In her words, my hands were reserved for playing the piano and could not do menial work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there were many stories about educated youth like this, but we didn’t exaggerate or expand it, we just filmed the plot truthfully. She sacrificed a lot to return to the city, but even for such a small character, we didn&#39;t write her off without writing a single word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Scar literature&quot; was very popular during a historical period. Gradually faded out of public view. What do you think of scar literature, especially adapting it into film and television works that can be accepted today? What is the biggest challenge you face? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Scar literature&quot; is a term used in a specific historical period after the reform and opening up. Nowadays, it is no longer necessary to mention &quot;scar literature&quot;. It fits. &quot;Human World&quot; is not about scars, but about the fireworks of the world. It does not mock anything with a critical eye, but every little bit of life reflects the changes of the times. If you like this work, you must agree with the values. You can only do it if you have passion. If you don’t have passion, you can’t do it, so just shoot something else. I agree with the theme and values ​​of the novel &quot;Human World&quot;. What I did was make some convergences from the visualization aspect. When I was doing the overall planning, I determined that warmth was the background, and the adaptation would be centered around this. When filming &quot;In the Name of the People&quot;, the evaluation of the TV Drama Department of the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television at that time was that light holds darkness, justice holds evil, and this ratio must be used correctly. The proportions of our play use warmth as the base color. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Lu believes that &quot;Human World&quot; is not about scars, but about fireworks in the world, in which every little bit of life reflects the changes of the times. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the crew)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;There is a blue sky in any era, and the sun rises every day&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What changes did you make from the novel to the TV series? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We change words and scenes. There are many examples like this. Sometimes we change the line of action. The screenwriter condensed the original novel in the second creation, because you can&#39;t tell it too eloquently like the novel, after all, the episodes are here and the characters are here. Shooting is another conceptual matter. The on-site actors have some improvisations, the director has some improvisations, and there are even some desk adjustments that need to be made. Our cast of actors this time is of a relatively high standard, and they basically all have the same background in acting. In this case, the director&#39;s responsibility is to identify and identify, this is okay, that is not okay, and there is no need to ask them to act exactly as I want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Teacher Ding Yongdai plays Zhou Bingkun’s father. When he joined the crew, he had just finished filming &quot;Across the Yalu River&quot; and played Peng Dehuai. After he came, he kept his hands in his hands every day, like a general, so I became anxious, &quot;Old Ding, Brother Ding, take your hands off. You are an old worker now. Hunch your waist a little bit, be a little bit silly.&quot; Come on, we don&#39;t have thousands of troops here!&quot; He was really a good actor. He came back after a few days and lowered his body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These require the skills of actors, but also require the crew to create a creative atmosphere. Many people who came to visit the class were shocked. We had an RV lounge. Basically, no one ran outside when we were changing lights and lenses. We all sat there chatting and watching each other&#39;s performances. It was very quiet. No one was posing or running around. They were all quietly preparing for the next scene and the next shot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The protagonist in &quot;Human World&quot; is a &quot;light type film&quot; The Zhou family, as well as the various characters associated with them, total more than a hundred people. How did you arrange these characters? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I found the screenwriter Wang Hailu and invited her to come. Not long after, the new crown epidemic broke out and I returned to Beijing from other places. After reading more than a dozen episodes of the script, I watched it from night to daybreak. Tears filled my eyes. I was very excited and sent a long WeChat message to Wang Haiyu, saying that this direction was the right one and it was done. Teacher Hailu&#39;s refining and description of the topic is similar to the novel, but there are also differences. For example, the character Luo Shibin was my proposition. I said there should be such a person. He is a businessman, a generation of businessmen who came up after the reform and opening up. There is no one in the original novel, and Luo Shibin provided a color comparison board. Like Zhou Bingkun, he is a small person. He has no success in the worldly sense, but you can see the ferment on the Internet now that &quot;a stupid son will benefit his parents&quot; and &quot;the old trouble in the family is actually the warm baby of his parents.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We did not expect that the social discussion would extend to so many places, but the benevolence, justice, propriety, wisdom, trust, filial piety, and the warmth between people reflected in the light-type film are what we value more. , or in other words, there is still a corner of people’s hearts that has been missing over the years. You see the scene that often appears in Korean dramas, that of a family having a delicious meal. It is true that over the years, the population of our family has become more and more sparse, the flavor of the year has become less and less, the human touch has become less and less, the neighbors do not interact with each other, and the only child has no family community. However, although it is rare, you cannot say that everyone does not have it in their heart. They all have it, but they are not awakened. This play has an awakening function, which is to weave here the warm connection between human relationships, family, country, small and big things that the Chinese people have had for thousands of years. Following this direction, we removed some peripheral things and made warmth one of the main themes of the play, so that everyone can feel more about the great changes in China in the past fifty years, composed of officials, workers, and people from all walks of life. The product of hard work, dedication, and forbearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The appearance of Zheng Juan (Zhou Bingkun&#39;s wife) played by Yin Tao is surprising deep impression. It was obviously a shabby thatched house, a down-and-out woman without cotton pants, but the scene of her sitting on the kang skewering candied haws and making a living was eye-catching. What considerations did you take when shooting a scene like this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We spent a long time filming the scene where Yin Tao appears. If we go by the pace of a TV series, it would be very expensive. We spent a lot of time filming it. A lot of time is spent on lighting and scenery. If we follow the pace of some dramas, one episode in three days or one episode in four days, it would be impossible to shoot this scene. From our perspective, there is a blue sky in any era, the sun rises every day, and there are beautiful people in even the darkest corners, it just depends on which perspective you look at. Although Zheng Juan&#39;s home was bare with only a few broken cabinets and rotten cotton quilts, her beauty could not be blocked, otherwise Zhou Bingkun wouldn&#39;t have been so moved as soon as he saw Zheng Juan. So any age has its own unstoppable beauty, especially for our show. Disney bought the copyright a month after the filming started, and it wants to be broadcast around the world. So we have this awareness all the time, not only for ourselves. Every family, this play will travel across the ocean. You can be broken, but you can&#39;t be dirty. Your window grilles may be very poor, but they still need to be clean. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The protagonists in the play, the Zhou family and his son, especially Do you think the relationship between Bingkun and his father is a typical Chinese father-son relationship? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, Zhou Bingkun and his father are the kind of father-son relationship we are calling for or have had. Zhou&#39;s father worked as a bricklayer in the &quot;Grand Third Line&quot;. He was an eighth-level bricklayer. His income was not low at that time, equivalent to the income of a senior cadre. The lines are also mentioned. Since he got married, he has not met Li Suhua, his wife, many times. He took three years of family leave, and sometimes he saved it when he couldn&#39;t come back. One year, the Spring Festival was even eight years away. Come back, think about it, how many eight years does a person have in his life? Zhou Bingkun is undoubtedly the biggest male protagonist in this drama. The character who tells the most about the destiny of the whole drama is Bingkun. The novel uses a low-down perspective, a person who has not succeeded in the worldly sense, and the ups and downs of his life&#39;s destiny as the narrative point. I think this is the main reason why Liang Xiaosheng&#39;s novel won the Mao Dun Literature Award - little people, big heroes. Any era is composed of these people as the denominator. It is impossible for everyone to succeed and become a big shot. Life is the accumulation of countless Zhou Bingkun. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;In the Name of the People&quot; is your other It was a masterpiece that was not favored by everyone at the time. Unexpectedly, a theme film later became a hit. The same is true for &quot;In the World&quot; this time. What is your secret? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Lu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If there was a formula for making a hit, then everyone could make a hit. &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; and &quot;In the World&quot; are two completely different genres and plots. &quot;In the Name of the People&quot; has a strong plot and a sense of time against the background of the anti-corruption craze at that time. But &quot;Human World&quot; does not have these two items. It has neither a strong plot nor a strong timeliness of anti-corruption. Instead, it is narrated. (They) are completely hits with two techniques and two styles. Hot hits are the result. Without the passion and thinking in this area, it would be impossible to make this kind of thing. It must be inspired by feelings, passion, and responsibility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[玉树光影澜湄源丨指尖华夏③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257583]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Yushu Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Qinghai Province, the birthplace of the Lancang-Mekong River has a pleasant scenery, with landscapes in the morning light and sea of ​​clouds The light and shadow change against the background, and the scenery is picturesque. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;499&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon in Yushu Zaduo County, Qinghai Province, a sea of ​​clouds appears over the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;511&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taken at Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai golden peaks surrounded by the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chadan Wetland, the source of the Lancang River, photographed in Yushu, Qinghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Chunjin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai, Lancang River A sea of ​​clouds appears in the sky. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[红河梯田上，那些逆流的追乡者丨月是故乡明③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257354]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Hani Village, the spring of the cattle herding class&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Yuanyang Hani Rice Terraces Airport Connection Line Construction has made the road conditions in the already extremely isolated mountain villages of Honghe County even worse. Most of the short 8-kilometer mountain road has turned into mud. It took more than half an hour to reach the destination of Qielongzhong Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Farmers resting among the terraces of Qielong Zhongzhai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;39 The 20-year-old Che Zhixiong picked me up at the door of my house and helped me carry my luggage up to the Datongbu room on the third floor of my old house. This is for investigators from all over the world doing ethnoanthropological research. Different from the village youths, he went to Gejiu, a major town in southern Yunnan, to work for two years before he was 20 years old. He then returned to the village and worked as a team leader and veterinarian. Six years ago, he began to organize nearby left-behind children and teach them to sing and dance traditional Hani. Song and dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun, the administrative village to which Qielong Zhongzhai belongs, is the birthplace of Hani multi-part folk songs, a national intangible cultural heritage, and Che Zhixiong’s father, Che Kesan, is the provincial inheritor. . In 2018, after attending the one-week village imaging training class of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; in the county seat, Che Zhixiong excitedly set up a Canon DV distributed by a charity organization, shot and recorded the life and festivals of Qielongzhong Village, and then recorded his The edited materials are saved to the hard drive for researchers from Kunming to take away when they come over. &quot;In the past three years, two 4T hard drives have been filled up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another house opposite the residence is Che Zhixiong&#39;s new home. . Last summer, with the help of 40,000 yuan in project start-up funds donated by a caring fan of Wang Yibo, Brother Che emptied the first floor and repainted it, turning it into a &quot;local imaging and cultural transmission hall.&quot; On the wall between the load-bearing columns, two LCD TVs are hung. The station at the door was broadcasting a CCTV set of the rice-planting gate opening ceremony filmed and produced in the village. When the rice-planting girl marries the young man from the field in early spring, the villagers who plant the rice-planting are all the bridesmaids and best men. Planting the rice-planting in a good field means marrying into a good family. Che Kesan frequently appears in the camera. As the ditch leader, he has to strictly measure the proportion of each ditch dug to ensure that the water from the forest reservoir flows fairly and accurately into the field ridges of each household. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV inside is Che Zhixiong&#39;s own &quot;Personal Film Exhibition&quot;. The sudden heavy hailstorm, the city children who came here for study tours, and the slaughter of cattle to worship the gods during the &quot;June Year&quot;, each section is an anthropological documentary with a complete narrative and clear rhythm. &quot;Most of my peers don&#39;t understand so many Hani rituals, let alone children. I only have a third-grade elementary school education, and all I can do is film and edit all the festivals here,&quot; Village Eyes &#39;People then use it to add subtitles. As for Kuaishou Douyin, it may occasionally attract attention, but it is not complete and even the surface is not captured.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New documentary director Che Zhixiong, Talk about your creative passion. He then pointed to the &quot;One Year&#39;s Festival Ritual&quot; display board on the wall between the two LCD TVs. For example, in the first month of the lunar calendar, the Hani people hold Lazuozuo and Angmatu successively, both of which are sacrificial ceremonies for the dead. &quot;Our ancestors will turn into little gods after they die, and they may come back to harass us. After death, the little gods will turn into great gods, and only then will they bless us. We kill cows for sacrifice to ensure that they can turn into great gods. . When the great god dies, it turns into dew, which drips down at night to irrigate the terraced fields and breed new life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It happened that an old man in the village was about to leave, so the driver took me to where the villagers kept watch. room. All the middle-aged and elderly people who stayed behind gathered here. The woman was in the back room, and the man was on the terrace, drinking pot-stewing wine just scooped out of a sealed earthen vat, chewing green chili peppers dipped in chili oil, and chatting in Hani dialect. The old man who smoked hookah encouraged me to be more generous, &quot;Go inside with your phone and take pictures.&quot; The daughter of the deceased man came back and told me, &quot;She is 80 years old, there is no need to stay in the hospital and suffer, let everyone have fun It&#39;s our tradition to stay with you.&quot; Later, most people would go home and sleep, but there would always be someone staying with them to wait for the final moments. Che Zhixiong carried the old man on his back, and while watching him the documentary he shot on TV, he told me, &quot;The bema (shaman) in the village will calculate the exact day to leave, and the funeral will begin three days before.&quot; . The posthumous affairs are more grand, and one or twenty cows may have to be killed and raised in the underworld for the deceased. This is not an exaggeration. Each of the children will have one, and if the spouse and family members have others, the beef will be taken back to their respective villages to be divided. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Longzhong Village keeps vigil at night. Che Zhixiong carries the departing old man on his back and watches the documentary he shot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun Village, where the village primary school is located, is only a 20-minute walk from the village. Less than ten children would go to the village every night to learn Hani dance from Che Zhixiong. The popular song &quot;Honey Baby&quot; with a hip-hop style has become a &quot;county dance&quot; vigorously promoted by Honghe primary and secondary schools, and children never tire of dancing it. The &quot;Music and Dance&quot; that has been passed down from our ancestors in production and life is more popular among energetic children because of its rich routines of squatting, jumping, lining up and circling. Accompanied by the cheerful beats and high-fives, I also followed the Hani cattle herding class and entered a selfless state of joy with nature and heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Zhixiong teaches children music and dance in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The young people of Yisa Town dedicated their entire youth to musical instruments&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Honghe County Government The town of Yisa is located at the top of a hill where two winding asphalt roads meet. At the highest edge of the ancient city, starting from the east gate with three floors and three rooms, a large and majestic ancient castle that combines Chinese and Western styles spreads out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a masonry town brought on horseback by local business gangs 90 years ago, and the primitive tribes who practiced slash-and-burn farming, carved wood and knotted ropes were upgraded into &quot;Little Shanghai outside the Yangtze River&quot;. Jiang refers to the Red River that flows to Vietnam and divides Red River Prefecture into two. Places such as Jianshui and Mengzi, which have many Han immigrants and are economically developed, are in the north and are called inside the river; while counties such as Yuanyang, Honghe and Luchun, which have developed world heritage terraced landscapes, are outside the river, which is backward. Yisa means &quot;drought and water shortage&quot; in the dialect of the Yi people who first came here to open up wasteland. During the Qianlong period, copper mines were discovered in the mountains, and immigrants followed the mining industry. These ancestors also experienced a history of prosperity and decline with the Qing Dynasty. At the end of the Qing Dynasty, the copper mines dried up and the new mountain people had no land to cultivate. They had to drag horses and go deep into the mountains and forests of Southeast Asia to do trade. They gradually developed from traditional caravans to tobacco gangs. In the early years of the Republic of China, the government&#39;s vigorous crackdown on opium led to a sharp increase in black market profits. Cigarette gangs organized and strengthened private militia to safeguard their vested interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; The French designers I knew drew drawings and hired Jiangnan craftsmen to build various stone mansions with European-style exteriors and Chinese-style interiors, row upon row on the hills. Since then, more men have dispersed overseas and reorganized their families, making Honghe County the second largest hometown of overseas Chinese in Yunnan, with more than 10,000 overseas Chinese distributed in 18 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wave of overseas immigrants on horseback has long been replaced by the wave of designated labor exports. But there are always people who insist on staying behind, such as Awen, the traditional musical instrument maker and inheritor I met at the east gate. &quot;Do you understand Honghe dialect? I can&#39;t speak Mandarin.&quot; Awen confessed in advance on WeChat. The craftsman who doesn’t speak Mandarin must be an old man with a white beard smoking a hookah, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the bluestone road, the roaring Aprilia 150 motorcycle turned off its engine. The &quot;white vest&quot; on the car took off the helmet with the three colors of the Italian flag. The cool guy with a ponytail stepped forward and said, &quot;I That’s Ah Wen.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I went from the village to the county cultural center to work when I was sixteen or seventeen years old. Now I am 35 years old, and I have dedicated all my youth to musical instruments.” In the restaurant next to Daguangtang in the center of the ancient town, Ah Wen Wen continued to introduce himself. &quot;I quit my job last year. I know nothing but making musical instruments. I&#39;m so hurt by music!&quot; Although he was a little sad, when he was flipping through the various beautiful instruments on his phone, Awen became excited again, &quot;I ride a motorcycle. When I visited various villages in Hani, I couldn&#39;t put it down when I saw these treasures. Every sanxian and every straw have different materials, appearance and sound quality. They can&#39;t be made in factories. They will be gone when the older generation leaves. I can only Take photos and videos, listen to the sounds, and restore them all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dinner, we walked through the lush Xishan Park and walked to the musical instrument workshop next to the County Cultural Center. Master Wu Zhiming was lying on a bamboo chair. When he heard me say that he had just come from Qielong Zhongzhai, memories of his life came back to him, &quot;It can be said that it was them who started my career, and I played a role as a link between past and future.&quot; 1986 In May, when Wu Zhiming, who was employed by the County Culture and Sports Bureau, went to Puchun to collect folk music, he heard the eight-part chorus of rice-planting girls coming from a distance, and followed the sound to find it... Later, he changed from a county actor to a song and dance creator. and music theory researchers, and brought Hani singing and dancing to the world. Ah Wen and Che Zhixiong have traveled as far as Shandong and Beijing respectively, but their master and father have already traveled to Taiwan, Singapore, Japan and the Netherlands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Awen from Yisa Town Musical Instrument Making Workshop&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like those young and middle-aged people in the city who are separated from their work units and pursue personal values, Awen also worries about how to monetize his hobbies. &quot;Many scholars and teachers can only provide spiritual support, but &#39;Village Eyes&#39; has raised 10,000 to 20,000 yuan for me.&quot; . But there are many others, but even a small business loan of 50,000 yuan cannot be approved.&quot; With the capital, Awen can build his own studio and improve the efficiency of working all night and three days to make two sanxian. One piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still have to be realistic and start with a wind instrument that saves time and materials. Although it is not as good as the cucurbit flutes in the pedestrian streets of ancient cities, you should try to reduce the production cost first, and then put it into Go to the Samaba Visitor Center to try out the sales.&quot; Xu Tianming, an old colleague who still works at the County Cultural Center, reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming is from the Yi ethnic group. In June 2021, under the guidance of the state song and dance troupe, he and other colleagues rehearsed the first courtyard drama &quot;Caravan Women&quot; in Honghe Prefecture. The Wanxing Courtyard was staged by relying on money. As the name of the play suggests, it tells the stories of chaste women displayed in this mansion. The dancers, from the image of disgraced grooms at the beginning, jumped to become a men&#39;s team in suits returning home joyfully, and the girls who looked through the love finally became the old mothers holding a revolving door, looking forward to the return of their husbands. Although the over-an-hour play is in a very complete musical format, it is not an original performance and is reduced to a series of popular Han-style compositions. Moreover, because the fee is not enough, embarrassing copyright information often comes out of the soundtrack. . Everything is difficult at the beginning. The ticket agent told me that starting with their play, all the counties and cities in Honghe Prefecture will create their own courtyard dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Hollowed Village, a Holiday Paradise for City People&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming suggested that Awen go to Samaba, which sells bamboo flutes. It is located at the end of the gently undulating hillside and is the most famous place in Honghe County. The scenic area has more than 14,000 acres of the world&#39;s largest concentrated contiguous terraces with more than 4,300 levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samaba Terraces&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A on the other side of the landscape terraces Although Yinxiang is the birthplace of the 600-year-old Hani Street Festival, the most beautiful historical and cultural village &quot;Zuofu&quot; failed to retain a few mushroom houses with ethnic characteristics and was replaced by reinforced concrete. house. Of course, there is nothing wrong with pursuing a once-and-for-all residence, but &quot;it is good to leave many old things in the village and tidy them up. For example, at the east gate of the county, the two mansions of Yao and Qian were used as public prosecutors and detention centers respectively before they became museums. It has always been used as a reservation.&quot; Liu Zhigang, who manages Kangteng·Honghehe Valley Tent Camp deep in Jiayin Township, as an outside operator, has a relatively objective and neutral voice on rural protection and development issues, &quot;and it is not far from Jiayin Township. There is a Tusi Mansion, and it is very grandiose. It could not have been so grand before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conten Company, which creates high-end vacation products, chose the project outside the scenic area because it had to find convenience for renovation. of hollowed out villages. &quot;Shitou Village has been empty for more than ten years. There are only one or two families who have owned houses in the new village. They use the old houses to store farm tools. It is not difficult for us to use them as campsites.&quot; Liu Zhigang is now busy developing another hollow village. , Suhong Village in the core area of ​​Samaba Rice Terraces. To this end, a tourism investment company has been established with the county government, and famous architect Zhang Yonghe has been hired as the chief planner to create timeshare real estate based on the &quot;low-involvement&quot; concept to allow urbanites to live in rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the heavy rain, the county road from the camp to Suhong Village was completely cut off by mudslides, and we had to climb down the narrow village road with hundreds of turns. The landscape along the road gradually changes from the rain-watered mulberry trees and red chrysanthemums at high altitudes to the steaming dense banana forest with broad leaves covering the sky. In the past, the smoke-traveling gang probably often did this, shuttling back and forth between alpine mountains and tropical dense forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A corner of Suhong Village&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Hani people’s hoes are But the enemy&#39;s iron gun. Seven thousand women have become widows, seven thousand children can&#39;t see their parents, the high swings have been knocked down, and the three-story mushroom houses have been burned down.&quot; An ancient Hani song once lamented the ancestors The fate of being defeated all the way and moving southward. After finally settling in the &quot;two mountains and three rivers&quot; area consisting of Ailao Mountain, Wuliang Mountain, Lancang River, Yuanjiang River and Honghe River, with the help of my good friend Old Buffalo, we dug out magnificent terraces with hoe after hoe. Nowadays, except for a few local people who work in the camp due to the demand for original ecological services, for more Honghe youths like Awen who stay in their hometown, city people come to experience the terraced life of transplanting rice seedlings, harvesting in autumn, and setting up tents. It&#39;s so familiar that it won&#39;t be rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;People chasing hometown&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The NAS system of the computer in the Kunming office of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; stores a large number of documentaries shot by Che Zhixiong. This is a public welfare organization that helps farmers and herdsmen in western rural areas record the ecological and cultural changes in their hometown through their own ethnic perspective and using cameras as tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who introduced Che Zhixiong to me was Li Xudong, a young man from his hometown who had just graduated more than a year ago. &quot;I studied hotel management at a private university. After graduation, I worked as a housekeeper in a high-end B&amp;B in Dali for two months. In August last year, I saw someone posting the official account &#39;Village Eyes&#39; in one of my most active groups. I was attracted to this charity organization after reading an article about Hani’s cattle herding class.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the male classmates in the village who went out to work and the female classmates who married early, Adong, who was born in 1996, They are very few young people who have a conscious sense of national identity early on. “Since my sophomore year, from January to April every year, I have taken leave, hitchhiked home from Kunming, participated in organizing the grand Silhouette Festival, written event planning, served as host, worked as a financial accountant, and dressed in national costumes , followed the horn team, taking the children who no longer have contact with the seedlings, to play in the terraced fields. This festival is a rest and entertainment time for the Hani people after planting the spring seedlings, and they also look forward to the rich autumn harvest in a few months.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A Dong also cooperates with four friends to operate a public account - People Chasing Hometown. Share the Hani branch, costumes, rituals, music, poetry and other content mainly in Honghe County at any time, publish essays by fellow villagers, and launch an essay collection activity for primary and secondary school students in your hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meet Hani villagers on the road&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Honghe Hani Rice Terraces were successfully applied for World Heritage status It has been 8 years, and it has given local people cultural confidence. &quot;The current situation should be said to be &#39;what goes in and what goes out&#39;. The return flow has increased. Young people go out to work, but when they are over 40 years old, more people come back. At the same time, the part-time status of half-farmers, half-workers also makes the villagers&#39; The enthusiasm for farming is back.&quot; Zhang Hongzhen, director of the Hani Terraces Protection and Development Research Center at Honghe University, recounted his observations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我所理解的五千年中华文明之精华]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257944]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China is a giant country in terms of population, land area, and history and culture. The late well-known archaeologist Su Bingqi, who proposed the &quot;starry sky&quot; theory about the origin of Chinese civilization, once said that what we want to build is a modernization with Chinese characteristics commensurate with the ancient country of five thousand years of civilization. This naturally puts forward the idea of ​​five thousand years of civilization. What is the essence, what is the national soul, and what is the spiritual pillar? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of &quot;Chinese nation&quot; was proposed by Liang Qichao a hundred years ago, but even starting from the Liangzhu Culture characterized by jade culture, the civilization creation of our ancestors on the land of China has exceeded 5000 years. The Liangzhu ancestors’ divine and animal facial patterns, head-up and head-down dragons, and tomb forms with obvious ritual connotations, all clearly show that they are an important source of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese civilization naturally has more than one origin. In addition to the Liangzhu Culture in the Taihu Lake area, there are also the Hongshan Culture in western Liaoning, the Yangshao Culture in the Central Plains, the Pengtoushan-Chengbeixi Culture in the Yangtze River Basin, the Longshan Culture that is a fusion of various cultures in China, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The basic spirit of Chinese civilization has gradually formed in the historical development, including the invention of square characters, the &quot;work&quot; of the &quot;system&quot; of the previous kings in the actual social development form, and the &quot;narration&quot; of the previous teachers, as well as The &quot;interpretation&quot; of scholars and intellectuals of all dynasties. Whether it is the &quot;new underground materials&quot; that are advancing rapidly in the modern era or the rich ancient documents dating back to Oracle Bone Inscriptions and Bronze Inscriptions, they can all help us today understand more deeply what the &quot;Chinese national spirit&quot; is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this understanding cannot only be directed towards the past. Although Zhou is an old state, its destiny is renewed. It is facing the future and participating in the present. Here, I try to summarize what I understand about Chinese civilization from five aspects: society, politics, faith, economy, and culture and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Society: Family Orientation and Individuality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a social perspective, we attach great importance to the value of a small community such as &quot;family&quot;, which leads to the spirit of benevolence and individual personality. growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benevolent people are the most important to people who are close to each other. To be close means to be filial to one&#39;s parents, to be kind to one&#39;s children, and to be friendly to one&#39;s brothers and sisters based on human blood and nature. And &quot;Old people are like the old people, young people are like the young people&quot;, and this kind of love is extended to everyone. Different from Mohism’s proposition of universal love, as the mainstream of Han culture, Confucianism admits that “there are differences in love”, but it still has a feeling of universal love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern people tend to value individualism first. Does this kind of &quot;familism&quot; conflict with respect for individual personality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a motivational point of view, parents raising their children comes from their own nature and is the best natural mechanism to help individuals grow. Family love provides relatively pure love and good emotions between parents and children. In terms of children&#39;s growth, the family structure can provide more support. From the perspective of ethnic continuity, this culture is obviously beneficial to increasing fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dear love does not advocate unconditional submission. If parents are at fault, the &quot;Book of Filial Piety&quot; advocates that &quot;there are faults in the family&quot;, but it only advises parents to pay attention to their attitude and methods. Mencius encouraged everyone to &quot;nurture my awe-inspiring spirit&quot; and &quot;even if there are thousands of people, I will go there&quot;. It is a kind of personalism with abundant independent consciousness and free spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in reality there are overbearing and irresponsible parents and rebellious children, this is precisely because they have betrayed the love of their relatives and cannot be blamed on this kind of balancing of family structure and individual personality. The social structure and value form of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family, a small community, constitutes a social unit, and the independent individuals with community and public care bred in it have become the foundation of the country. The laws promulgated by the governor should encourage this kind of love, but not destroy it. If conditions are created to make it easier for parents to raise their children and for children to get closer to their parents, it is care that nourishes this spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Political ideal: The world is for the common good&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the mainstream of our culture, individuals not only live within the family structure, but also naturally extend to the country and the world. To cultivate oneself, manage one&#39;s family, govern the country, and bring peace to the world, in &quot;The Great Learning&quot;, individuals need to constantly study things to gain knowledge, be sincere and righteous, and expand their areas of concern and efforts to the vast areas of the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When someone asked Confucius why he did not engage in politics, Confucius quoted &quot;Shangshu&quot; and replied: &quot;Filial piety is only filial piety, and friendship is with brothers.&quot; Politics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a social structure and cultural spirit, &quot;keeping the family together&quot; is already a part of public affairs. Expanding this spirit to a wider social space is also &quot;for government&quot; rather than for government. You must &quot;serve as an official in the government&quot; to enter politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern families are families of three or four, but in Chinese history, unless official laws deliberately required &quot;family separation&quot; to weaken the organizational strength of small communities, our culture often praised &quot;multi-generational families&quot;. &quot;Together under the same roof&quot; encourages large families to live together and help each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of large family living together combines the principles of &quot;kinship&quot;, &quot;respect for respect&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; to form the social autonomy of a small community. From this, the tradition of gentry autonomy was derived. This made it possible to create a &quot;small government, big society&quot; where the imperial power did not extend to the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhou system of feudalism and founding of the country directly used family as a link to establish the basic political order of the entire Chinese world: on the one hand, the eldest son inheritance system was implemented to ensure the institutionalization and stability of the inheritance of power; On the one hand, talented people are selected to govern. Of course, the Zhou system still embodies moral governance in the family and the world, and the degree of openness of power is still limited. In the political field, the value that best embodies the spirit of the Chinese nation is the spirit of &quot;the world is for the common good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original text of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; is: In the journey of the great road, the world is for the common good, selecting talents and talents, adhering to trust and cultivating harmony, old friends do not only kiss their relatives, do not only give birth to their children, so that the old will die well. The strong have their uses, the young have their talents, and those who are modest, widowed, lonely, and lonely are all supported... Another example is &quot;The king and his ministers are united by righteousness.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s not all about the same surname&quot;... These political thoughts, which exude eternal brilliance, have broken through the &quot;kinship&quot; principle of the family and become a concrete manifestation of the commonwealth of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since selfish desires are difficult to eliminate, it is extremely difficult to achieve the goal of serving the world for the common good. Needless to say, the Qin system, from the Han and Tang dynasties to the Song, Ming and Qing dynasties, the separation of imperial power and prime ministerial power, the system of admonishing officials and historians, the feudal system throughout the Han, Tang, and Song dynasties, the education of princes, and the system of co-governance of scholar-bureaucrats, etc., are only partial and It plays a certain role in the short term. Royal power is never truly under the law. The Chinese nation’s political spirit of “the world is for the common good” is so premature and yet so immature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the famous &quot;Debate between Righteousness, Benefit and Overlord&quot; with Chen Liang, Zhu Xi lamented decisively: For fifteen hundred years, he was just sitting on this, so it was just a matter of time to make up for it. Although there may have been some moderate prosperity during this period, the Tao taught by the three kings Yao and Shun, Zhou Gong and Confucius, has not yet been practiced in heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the political standard of the world for the common good continues to exist. Whether to put the interests and happiness of the people first in governance, and whether to keep the economic, social and spiritual life vigorous and prosperous? These political requirements for governors are also an important dimension of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Economy: People have permanent property&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the economy, how does &quot;the world is for the common good&quot; be reflected? For the government, it is &quot;the king, why should he call it profit&quot;. From the emperor, princes to officials, managers at all levels should not compete with the people for profit; for the common people, it is &quot;those who have permanent property have perseverance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to do this specifically? What the government wants to do is to &quot;benefit the people according to their interests&quot; and naturally carry out production, trade and consumption activities based on the needs of the people in the world. Therefore, in the choice between cannon and butter, butter obviously takes precedence. This only requires the establishment of a service-oriented government that provides &quot;benefits at no cost&quot; and cannot compete with the people for profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Benevolent government must start from the borders.” The basis for the interests of the people is to ensure that citizens have their own three-acre land, and they can use their own land according to their personal and family interests. Judgment, to produce and trade. Although Mencius&#39;s proposition mainly focused on delimiting the boundaries of mine fields, its essence pointed to the determination of property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, Mencius also advocated encouraging commerce and protecting travelers by providing warehouses for merchants and requisitioning them in accordance with the law to avoid stagnant goods, only registering and inspecting but not collecting taxes, only doing labor service but not collecting land rent, etc. Let it be beneficial to farmers, so that all merchants in the world will be happy and willing to hide in their markets, all travelers in the world will be happy and willing to go out on their own roads, and all farmers in the world will be happy and willing to plow their fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the current economic reform is concerned, the confirmation and long-term stability of agricultural land rights, as well as deepening the reform of state-owned enterprises, protecting the investment and property rights of the private economy in various fields, tax laws, etc., all fall into this category. economic issues. This also determines whether entrepreneurs have long-term confidence in the Chinese economy and whether they dare to make large investments. In short, the essence of the economic spirit of an ideal Chinese community is to achieve economic prosperity, prosperity and prosperity for the people, and ensure the material life of the people through the property rights, production and trade system of &quot;big public ownership and private ownership&quot; and the fiscal and taxation system that is light on corvee and light on taxes. of plenty. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Belief: The unity of nature and man&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For families, why should fathers be kind and sons should be filial? For rulers, why should the world be for the common good? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do ordinary people have perseverance only if they have perseverance? For a person like Yan Hui, why can he achieve &quot;a basket of food and a ladle of drink, and he cannot bear the worries, but his joy will not change even after he returns&quot;? How can he have perseverance without permanent income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This involves the fourth dimension of Chinese civilization, faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businessmen believed in the personified &quot;Emperor&quot; and were biased toward the dominating heaven; Zhou people believed in &quot;the destiny of heaven is constant, only virtue is the supplementary one&quot;, and in the dominating heaven there was a profound meaning of the heaven of righteousness; although Confucius &quot;revered &quot;Keep the ghosts and gods at a distance&quot;, but still &quot;offer sacrifices to the gods as if they were present&quot;, reminding the disciples to realize the sincere spirit of life from the great popularity of &quot;Heaven can say nothing&quot;, and firmly believe that they carry &quot;Heaven will not lose the grace&quot;, which deepened the Zhou people&#39;s The concept of destiny; in the Han Dynasty, Dong Zhongshu believed that humans are copies of heaven, that heaven and humans can sense each other, and can warn the king of his misconduct and mismanagement with &quot;disasters&quot;; by the Song and Ming dynasties, heaven mainly became the heaven of justice, tending to one an inner transcendence and infinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For heaven, most of the most outstanding kings and sages of the Chinese nation had a strong and heartfelt awe, and regarded the unity of heaven and man as their ultimate pursuit, thus giving integrity to daily life and political life. sense of meaning, certainty and direction. Mencius has a very vivid description of this realm of belief that is both ordinary and holy: what is desirable is called good, what is called self-belief is called faith, what is full is called beauty, what is full and glorious is called great, what is great is called transformation. Holy, what is holy but unknowable is called God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Father&#39;s kindness and son&#39;s filial piety originate from the &quot;nature of destiny&quot; and from &quot;the child is free from the arms of his parents for three years&quot;. If this kind of human nature is brought into full play like Shun in &quot;Yao Canon&quot;, we can A saint who acquires a set of abilities including avoiding disasters, harmonizing the family, and governing the country is a saint who unites nature and man;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Emperor&quot; regards himself as the eldest son of Heaven to gain legitimacy and even sanctity, and must serve Heaven To carry on, we must nourish all people, and the world is for the common good;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ordinary people don’t understand this enough, and they don’t have the time to cultivate themselves. They need a constant income to have perseverance. This is normal, but it has a family “kissing” mechanism. With nourishment, there is still benevolence and righteousness in the heart. As long as you don&#39;t cut it off, you can also see the virtuous and considerate people; The obsession with external objects returns to the state of life where meaning flows. March is not contrary to benevolence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is extremely difficult to truly practice faith. For ordinary people, if they have permanent property and perseverance, maintain a comfortable life and common sense rooted in the meaning of family, they can become qualified members of the Chinese community; for people in high positions, if they cannot &quot;devour their heart and soul to understand heaven, &quot;If you cultivate your mind and cultivate your nature to serve Heaven&quot;, you will begin to pollute a large area from the source of law, politics, culture and education, and spread evil to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Mencius affirmed that all people have the four ideals, he also clearly realized that &quot;human beings are somewhat different from beasts.&quot; He quoted from &quot;Shang Shu·Tai Oath&quot; that &quot;Heaven sees me and the people see me, and God listens to me and the people listen&quot;, and gave a principled explanation of the relationship between heaven and the people. God’s will is unpredictable and manifests itself through public opinion. A holy king who unites nature and man is rare to find in five hundred or even a thousand years, but secular kings who are holy because of their kings are everywhere. The reverence for heaven and the people is not empty talk, so it is necessary to establish a technical system to restrict the royal power, so that public opinion can be fully reflected, and governance can fully reflect public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public opinion may be divided and antagonistic, what should we do? Will it bring about the disadvantages of &quot;welfarism&quot;? Will the &quot;public opinion&quot; of this generation harm the &quot;public opinion&quot; of future generations? These challenges have entered the field of building a modern republic and legal system. In addition to drawing on the more mature modern governance system, we also need to give full play to the spirit of &quot;Spring of the First Year, King Zhengyue&quot; in &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot;. In the era of great changes, we should constantly return to the origin of politics and beliefs, consider profits and losses, and &quot;make&quot; new systems. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Literature and education: Respecting teachers, respecting morality, and vigorous spirit&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Liangzhu, Hongshan, Yangshao to Longshan, from Xia, Shang and Zhou to Qin, Han, Tang, Song, Ming and Qing, the Chinese community gradually formed and split frequently And it can be continuously unified, and the culture whose roots were formed over five thousand years will never be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have a unified square character that has basically not changed since ancient times. Even though &quot;the winds are different in hundreds of miles, and the customs are different in thousands of miles&quot;, a county may have several dialects, but we can still recognize and identify with each other. There is also the ideological system from Zhou Confucius, Mencius, Xun, Lao and Zhuang. They have governed themselves and made history, and they have also learned from history and classics, providing rich resources for spiritual inspiration and institutional reconstruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no insurmountable rivers or mountains in the land of China. Whether it is divided into feudal states or prefectures and counties, the gradually formed Zhou Wen and Han systems, Tang style and Song style are diverse but capable of unification, and have strong agglomeration effect. For thousands of years, no matter what force entered China, it would be transformed by Chinese culture to a large extent. They inherited Chinese culture and therefore gained basic recognition from the scholars in this tradition. This is the attraction and centripetal force of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this cultural spirit faces not only the debate between China and the West, but also the changes in ancient and modern times. How to inherit and update our cultural spirit has been a major issue that several generations of intellectuals in modern times have struggled with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Han Dynasty to the Tang and Song Dynasties, we spent thousands of years absorbing Buddhist culture, which not only gave birth to Chinese Zen Buddhism, but also gave birth to Taoism in the Song and Ming Dynasties. Since the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China, in the face of the strong Western learning and Western politics, scholars from both sides of the Taiwan Strait and three places have translated a large number of translations, digested them quickly, practiced them politically, and compared and absorbed them academically, which has initially opened up a new situation for Chinese culture. The process is far from over. To return to the roots and create new things requires a free and powerful cultural and educational system that represents the fifth dimension of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher is someone who teaches, teaches and resolves doubts. China has a tradition of scholarship. The Jixia Academy, which flourished 2,400 years ago, was once an international academic center in China, even though it was officially run by the Qi State. Scholars from Taoism, Confucianism, Legalism, Ming Dynasty, Ming Dynasty, Agriculture, Yin and Yang, Mencius, Xunzi, Shen Buhai, Lu Zhonglian, Shen Dao and other scholars whose names were important for a time and even influenced thousands of years are here to &quot;discuss without ruling&quot;, &quot; &quot;Discussing state affairs without holding office&quot;, the ideological power derived from this has surged forward with the source of living water, and its influence continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Confucius broke away from &quot;learning in the government&quot; and gave private lectures, to the &quot;Jingshe&quot; in the Han Dynasty, from the &quot;academy&quot; where individuals studied and lectured in the Tang Dynasty, to the Yuelu Academy in the Southern Song Dynasty, where Zhang Shi lectured , the Bailudong Academy restored by Zhu Xi... The folk academy system is well-established, with independent subject-based teaching systems, autonomous methods for students to participate in management, and relatively independent funding sources, finally forming a mature private school system. By the Ming Dynasty, academies such as Longgang, Guiyang, and Kuaiji, which were founded or presided over by Wang Yangming and promoted the purpose of Xinxue, changed to Donglin Academy, which criticized the shortcomings of Xinxue and advocated practical learning. This has never ceased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These academies have the character of pursuing the Tao rather than seeking official positions, the style of study of free debate, the aura of making friends to help others, and the worldly sentiments of &quot;the sound of wind and rain, the sound of reading, family affairs, state affairs, and world affairs.&quot; In &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;, Huang Zongxi even put forward the view that &quot;what the emperor is right may not necessarily be right, and what the emperor is wrong may not be wrong, so the emperor will not dare to be wrong for himself and publicize his right and wrong to the school.&quot; Right and wrong and truth were elevated to a higher status than the emperor, restoring the traditional essence of discussing politics based on Tao, and inspiring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern intellectuals need to inherit the spirit of scholars, not only to interpret and continue the great ancient Chinese civilization, but also to &quot;work&quot; according to the times and explore new philosophical, institutional and scientific principles. In short, the foundation of this cultural and educational system is the guarantee of the institutionalization and legalization of &quot;teachers&quot; and &quot;scholars&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The final conclusion: This article believes that heaven (the belief system in which heaven and man are unified), earth (the economic system in which people have permanent property), and the country (the political system in which the world is for the common good) System), relatives (kinship is the most important, a personality development system nurtured in the family structure), and teachers (a cultural and educational system full of dynamic research, preaching and civilized dialogue), the above five constitute the main content of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国跳水队包揽亚运会跳水项目首个比赛日的两枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:38:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese group Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yu Xi in the competition. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;252916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 30, 2023, the diving competition of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou officially began. The first competition day was the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final and the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final. In the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving competition, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan/Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with a huge advantage. The Chinese team achieved six consecutive titles in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving at the Asian Games. In the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final, although the Chinese team Yan Siyu/He Chao made varying degrees of errors in the fourth and sixth jumps, it did not affect their overall success in winning the gold medal with a 29.55-point lead over the runner-up South Korea. The Chinese diving team won two gold medals on the first competition day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese group will be all red Chan (right)/Chen Yuxi during the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao competed. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 30, the Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform is the first completed event in the Hangzhou Asian Games diving competition. As Olympic champions, this is the first time for the gold medal team of Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan to participate in the Asian Games. The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition does not have preliminaries and will go directly to the finals. In this project, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan are the only ones in the world in terms of strength, while the strong players in the second tier are mainly from Europe and the United States. During the competition, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan led the way from the first jump, with a total score of 375.30 points in 5 jumps, leading the runner-up Japanese team by 85.26 points, and won the first gold medal in diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, Chinese group Yan Siyu (Part 2)/ He Chao is in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard also has no preliminary schedule and goes directly to the finals. The Chinese combination Yan Siyu/He Chao ranked fifth in the order of appearance. During the competition, He Chao and Yan Siyu demonstrated their extremely high technical level and tacit cooperation ability. Taking off, turning, and entering the water, the entire set of movements of the two people is very smooth. Although he successfully won the men&#39;s synchronized three-meter springboard championship, He Chao was not very satisfied with himself because of his mistake in the last jump. &quot;The result was good, but all the movements were not perfect in the process. This is the first time for Yan Siyu to participate in an international competition. I am also participating in an international competition again after six years, which is a test for both of us. But winning this gold medal is our best gift for National Day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On September 30, 2019, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79 .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed the gold medal in their hands to the audience . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao shows the audience the gold medal in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games diving event will be held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium from September 30 to October 4, 2023. A total of 10 gold medals will be produced. gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), and the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Jili (first from the left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Linong Anak Pamg (first from the right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;785&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Matsuri (first left), the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Rinon Anak Pamg (first from right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Yan Siyu (third from left)/He Chao (third from right), the runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae-kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan ( Second from left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/01/53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;793&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/ 53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, champion Chinese group Yan Siyu (third from left)/ He Chao (third from right), runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae Kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan (second from left) and third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik Bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>