<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[汽车4S店被要求“限时搬迁”：优化民营经济发展环境应落到实处丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province were &quot;required to relocate within a limited time&quot;, which attracted industry attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Automobile Dealers Association recently posted on its official social media that a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City have received notices from government departments requiring them to relocate to designated automobile parks within a time limit. The article said that according to incomplete statistics, almost all car 4S stores within the Third Ring Road of Shijiazhuang City are involved, and there are more than 100 dealers of various brands. The large-scale relocation and reconstruction are expected to cause direct economic losses of more than 1 billion to the dealers. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, &quot;Automotive Business Review&quot; magazine reported that according to statistics from the Shijiazhuang Commerce Bureau, the relocation involved 177 sizable 4S stores, affecting almost all 4S stores in Shijiazhuang. The notice, stamped with the bright red seals of the local Natural Resources and Planning Bureau, the Public Security Bureau, the Urban Management Bureau, the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, the Fire Rescue and the Subdistrict Office, requires that all 4S stores be relocated and vacated before September 30, and the stores must be closed. , those who do not move into the automobile industrial park must close their stores before September 10th; temporary and illegal 4S stores must be demolished by themselves before September 10th, otherwise they will be demolished by force; &quot;Refuse to cooperate, maliciously obstruct and hinder the execution of official duties&quot; &quot; will be &quot;seriously dealt with in accordance with the law, and those suspected of committing crimes will be held criminally responsible in accordance with the law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, demolition work has begun, and many car brand showrooms have been razed to the ground in the Hebei International Automobile Trade Park, the largest local automobile park. According to reports, the relocation of automobile 4S stores was carried out in the name of &quot;comprehensive improvement of temporary (illegal construction) low-end market&quot;: the government requires existing 4S stores to be closed and demolished, and relocated to four new parks planned by the government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon in various places to require companies to relocate to new parks planned by the government under various pretexts. A few years ago, a county in eastern Shandong Province required all stone companies in a town famous for stone production to relocate to a newly built &quot;stone industrial park&quot; in the name of &quot;industrial agglomeration.&quot; A few years later, on the grounds of &quot;air pollution control&quot;, all barbecue restaurants in the county were required to move to the newly built &quot;BBQ Street&quot;. If you don&#39;t want to relocate, then close without negotiation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is true for the car 4S store in Shijiazhuang that &quot;requires time-limited relocation&quot;. Once a document is issued by the city government, the district and sub-district offices will enforce it. If they are unwilling to relocate, they will close the store and demolish it. However, the expenses and costs associated with relocation, as well as the possible impact on industrial development, need to be calculated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What impact may relocation have on companies and industries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, of course, the renovated business premises must be abandoned and moved to a new location. Not to mention the rent, renovating is a huge expense. According to an estimate from an article by the China Automobile Dealers Association, each new store after the centralized relocation is expected to require an additional construction investment of 10 million to 20 million yuan. In recent years, car sales have dropped from their peak, especially due to the impact of the epidemic. Many dealers were already struggling to survive until the epidemic was relaxed, and they are planning to take advantage of the opportunity to develop their business. Some stores even just opened a few months ago, and were required to dismantle and relocate the store before selling a few cars. The tens of millions of yuan invested just now were in vain. It was difficult for the store owners to invest more funds in the construction of new stores, so they had to Forced into bankruptcy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some shop owners questioned the procedural issues. According to a report by Shijiazhuang Daily in June, the policy formulated at the special meeting of the Municipal Party Committee at that time was to &quot;build first and then destroy&quot;. First, ensure that the new automobile industrial park is completed and put into use by the end of September, and then complete &quot;overdue temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; in October. &quot;4S store relocation and renovation. However, in actual implementation, &quot;establish first and then destroy&quot; has become &quot;first break and then establish&quot;. According to reports, the four new parks currently planned are still under construction. Even if work is rushed 24/7, it will be difficult to complete before the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Part of the reason why Shijiazhuang City proposed the relocation and rectification of 4S stores is that some current 4S stores have problems such as &quot;extended temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; and are a &quot;low-end market&quot; that need &quot;rectification and improvement.&quot; In fact, the current automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City are relatively concentrated in four parks. Some of these parks are automobile industrial parks previously planned by the government, and some are actively gathered and formed spontaneously during the market development process. The location selection of these stores was a decision made by dealers after investigating factors such as the business district environment and customer needs, and was also in line with the municipal planning at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Requiring time-limited relocation&quot; affects not only 4S stores, but also the millions of existing car owners in Shijiazhuang, as well as new car owners who are preparing to buy cars. Officials require almost all 4S stores to close before the end of September. It is not yet known when the new park will be completed. Even if the new park is built, and even if the 4S store has the money to relocate, the decoration of the new store will usually take at least two to three months. There will be a window of several months in between. During this period, let alone citizens being unable to buy new cars, it is even difficult to ensure vehicle maintenance and repairs for old car owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the central government issued the &quot;31 Articles on the Private Economy&quot;, which requires optimizing the development environment of the private economy, protecting the property rights of private enterprises and the rights and interests of entrepreneurs in accordance with the law, and promoting the development and growth of the private economy. The Hebei Province Private Economy Leading Group also announced the &quot;Hebei Province Private Economy Development Work Points in 2023&quot; in April 2023, proposing to continue to optimize the business environment. As for optimizing the business environment, the most fundamental thing is probably not to provide enterprises with various industrial guidance and policy preferences, but to reduce interference in the market, respect the property rights of enterprises and the autonomy of entrepreneurs, and allow entrepreneurs to make market decisions independently. Only with more services and less guidance, more support and less trouble can the private economy develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[证监会再出“新招”规范上市公司分红强化制度约束和激励]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256974]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:30:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the common wish of investors to obtain higher dividends within a reasonable range. On September 18, a reporter from 21st Century Business Herald learned that the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to launch a series of measures to improve the normalized dividend mechanism for listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has introduced and implemented a &quot;linking&quot; policy between dividends and shareholding reductions. Listed companies have not distributed cash dividends in the past three years, or the cumulative cash dividend amount is less than 30% of the average annual net profit in the past three years. , controlling shareholders and actual controllers are not allowed to reduce their holdings of the company’s shares through the secondary market. According to the person in charge of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, it is planned to further strengthen institutional constraints on companies that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends to urge dividends, promote the optimization of dividend methods and rhythm, so that companies that pay dividends can get more incentives, and at the same time, strengthen the supervision of companies that exceed their ability to pay dividends. constraints, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the amount of dividends paid and the proportion of A-share companies ranked among the top in the world. Data show that in the past five years, the amount of dividends paid by A-share listed companies has increased year by year, with a cumulative dividend of 8.2 trillion yuan, and the amount of dividends has exceeded the amount of financing that year. In 2022, a total of 3,291 Shanghai and Shenzhen listed companies in my country&#39;s domestic market paid cash dividends, accounting for 67.1% of the total number of listed companies at the end of 2022. The total cash dividends for the year reached 2.06 trillion yuan, of which the amount of dividends attributed to A-share shareholders was 1.62 Trillion yuan. From an international comparison, the number of dividend-paying listed companies in the domestic market ranks first among the world&#39;s major securities markets, the total amount of cash dividends ranks second in the world, and the proportion of dividend-paying companies ranks second in the world. In addition, 163 listed companies announced cash dividend plans for their 2023 semi-annual reports, with dividends expected to be 203.01 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Mature companies with continuous improvement in dividends, and companies listed on the main board have a higher proportion of dividends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the sustainability and growth of dividends of listed companies in my country have continued to improve. Data shows that as of 2022, the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for five consecutive years has increased from 20% ten years ago to 48%, and the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for 10 consecutive years has increased from 8% to 31%; 412 listed companies have paid dividends continuously. The proportion of companies that have grown in three years has increased from 3% ten years ago to 12%, and the proportion of companies that have grown in five consecutive years has increased from 1% to 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dividend yield and dividend payout ratio also show a fluctuating upward trend. The dividend yield distribution range has gradually increased from 0.5%-1.5% before 2010 to the current 1.5%-2%. In 2022, the average dividend payout rate in my country&#39;s domestic market is 32.5%, and the average dividend rate is 1.97%, which is in the middle and upper reaches of major global markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which sectors and industries pay higher dividends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders believe that dividend features are generally in line with the company’s development stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of sectors, the dividend payout rate of main board companies is the highest, reaching about 33%, which is 8 percentage points higher than the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of industries, industries with stable performance and low investment demand tend to have higher dividend ratios. Judging from the average dividend payout ratio, energy, major consumption, and public utilities rank among the top three, with dividend ratios as high as 50%, 48%, and 45% respectively. Listed companies in these industries have low new investment needs and relatively stable cash flow. Hence the average dividend payout level is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, the real estate, industry, and information technology industries have greater investment demand, and the average dividend payout ratio is also lower, at 28%, 26%, and 25% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the dividend level of A-share companies in the start-up and growth stages is lower than that of companies in the mature stage. Due to their relatively weak financing capabilities and strong willingness to save and defend, private enterprises have slightly lower dividend levels than state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Whether a high proportion of dividends is reasonable or not needs to be viewed comprehensively and accurately&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dividends of listed companies need to comprehensively consider multiple factors such as profitability, cash flow, debt, growth stage, development goals, etc. Different types of The attitudes and demands of shareholders towards cash dividends are not completely consistent, and it is necessary to balance the interests of the company and shareholders, major shareholders and small shareholders.&quot; The interviewed experts believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this expert, whether a company can pay dividends and how much it pays are mainly affected by three factors: first, the undistributed profits accumulated by the company from its operations in the current year and in the past; second, the cash it currently has; It is whether the retained earnings can meet the company&#39;s future development needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dividend ratio needs to be determined comprehensively based on the company&#39;s profitability, development stage, and future development needs. According to industry insiders, whether a company pays dividends and how much it pays are not necessarily linked to the profit of the year. Although the dividend ratio of some companies in individual years is relatively high, it is still reasonable. This must be comprehensively analyzed and viewed accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, some companies have stable profits and cash flow and have little investment demand, so they maintain a high dividend payout ratio. On the other hand, some companies will keep the amount of dividends unchanged despite declining profits or losses, and stabilize investor expectations through continued dividend payments, which will lead to higher dividend payout ratios in certain years. At the same time, in order to reduce redundant funds, some companies will implement special dividends based on accumulated undistributed profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts interviewed believe that, of course, it is not ruled out that major shareholders may distribute dividends arbitrarily and hollow out the company regardless of the company&#39;s future development needs. This should be strengthened, but this should be a very small number. To judge whether dividends are reasonable, we need to start from three dimensions: first, we need to see whether the profits are real and whether there is fraud; secondly, we need to see where the cash comes from and whether it is borrowed money to distribute dividends; finally, we must make a comprehensive judgment based on the motivation of major shareholders to pay dividends. A high proportion of dividends cannot be equated with dividends beyond capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, we need to view high-proportion dividends comprehensively and accurately. On the one hand, we must identify dividends based on false profits at the expense of the interests of listed companies; on the other hand, we welcome dividends based on the company’s true profit level and development needs. A high proportion of dividends that can effectively return investors.&quot; said an industry insider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four aspects will be followed to further standardize dividends of listed companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to review the &quot;Supervisory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 3 - Cash Dividends of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Dividend Guidelines&quot;) ) &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association&quot;) and other rules have been revised. On the basis of the &quot;linking policy&quot; for dividends and shareholding reductions that have been introduced in the early stage, we will continue to improve and optimize the cash dividend supervision system and strengthen information disclosure supervision. , conveniently optimize the mid-term dividend payment process, better play the role of investment side, and continue to enhance investors&#39; sense of gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the head of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, this policy adjustment will proceed from four aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen institutional constraints and urge companies to pay dividends that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends. The first is to strengthen information disclosure supervision. For companies listed on the main board that do not pay a certain proportion of dividends, they are required to disclose and explain the reasons. The second is to strengthen disclosure requirements for companies with large financial investments, and urge companies to improve the efficiency of asset use and better focus on the main business and return investors. The third is to strengthen inquiries and supervisory interviews. Strengthen regulatory inquiries to help investors make better judgments on dividend information, and urge more dividends through interviews and other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, promote further optimization of dividend methods and rhythm. Specific measures in this regard can be summarized in two points: First, simplify the mid-term dividend payment procedures to facilitate the company to further increase the frequency of dividends and allow investors to better plan capital arrangements. Second, guide the company to formulate a dividend policy for stable growth. Promote companies to amend their articles of association to improve the operability of dividend policies; guide companies to explore dividend distribution policies with stable growth and reward investors with more stable dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, let companies with good dividends receive more rewards and &quot;taste the sweetness.&quot; On the one hand, it gives more &quot;honor&quot; to companies that pay good dividends. The exchange will study how to further favor high dividend-paying companies in the evaluation of information disclosure; the Listed Companies Association will study and optimize the preparation method of listed companies&#39; dividend lists and increase publicity efforts to guide companies to establish a correct value orientation. On the other hand, promote the development of more influential dividend index products; encourage fund companies to issue dividend fund products, and guide market funds to increase their preference for cash dividends from listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, strengthen restrictions on companies that pay dividends beyond their capabilities. Although paying dividends beyond capacity is not a prominent problem in A-shares, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will still pay close attention to it and take multiple measures to strengthen prevention. The first is to work hard to ensure that the company&#39;s performance is true and the basis for dividends is solid, and to effectively prevent listed companies from falsifying their finances and financing dividends. Second, for listed companies that have high asset-liability ratios and insufficient operating cash flow, but continue to pay dividends at a high proportion, detailed disclosure of the rationality of the dividend plan and its impact on the company&#39;s production and operations is required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“杀猪盘”受害者决定复仇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D57PCasl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D5 7PCasl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The story of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is inspired by a large number of real cases of &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, decided to take revenge after being defrauded of 550,000 yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met for the first time, Zhou Dongyu asked Ma Yingxin in a joking tone, what do you think about me? Like a person who has been cheated? It was September 2021, not long after Ma Yingxin returned to China. In the first week after arriving in Beijing, she had a meal with Zhou Dongyu and talked about Zhou Ran, the heroine of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, a victim of emotional fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingxin felt that the real intention in the witty words was that she thought the audience would not be convinced if she played a deceived person. Ma Yingxin’s answer: When you think you will not be cheated, you are basically increasing your chances of being cheated. After hearing this, Zhou Dongyu did not refute or admit, &quot;But she did go back and think about it for two days and said, let me play this role.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I believe that after the movie is released, the first reaction of the audience will be, will Dong Yu be deceived?&quot; Ma Yingxin told the Southern Weekend reporter, but this was precisely one of the reasons why she chose Zhou Dongyu. &quot;I don&#39;t want to choose someone who everyone will think will be deceived when they see her. Then she acted in this story. I don&#39;t think she conveyed anything. It&#39;s precisely Dong Yu who is like this. Maybe in the audience&#39;s perception, they don&#39;t believe her. If you will be deceived, then it will be more interesting for us to read this story.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was early autumn in Beijing in September. In an office building near the China World Trade Center, Ma Yingxin wore a black knitted sweater and pushed Wearing a wheelchair, he entered the conference room neatly. After a car accident when she was young, she has been using a wheelchair. Stopping in front of the long white table, she did not say any greetings and only said softly, &quot;Let&#39;s get started.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creation of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is based on a large number of real cases. The background of the story is the emotional scam in telecommunications network fraud, commonly known as &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. After 2019, Ma Yingxin began to receive relevant news frequently. What puzzled her was that mainstream comments were belittling and blaming the victimized women. They were &quot;love-brained,&quot; &quot;stupid,&quot; and even the word &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; itself was a stigma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people, without thinking deeply about this problem, think how could I be deceived. But in fact, so many people have been deceived.&quot; When writing the script, in addition to online information, Ma Yingxin also Ask a friend to find the real victim and chat. She discovered that there were many more victims than she thought, and many of them were very smart and outstanding people. Emotional deception is different from ordinary financial fraud. The victim will feel humiliated and dare not tell others. Some people do not even call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emotional fraud usually refers to online fraud that induces victims to make &quot;investments&quot; based on opposite-sex online dating. The long-term process of establishing an emotional relationship is called &quot;pig farming.&quot; In recent years, as more information has been disclosed, people have discovered that the means of emotional fraud are highly specialized and even involve psychological knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman working in the financial industry in a big city in China also had doubts when communicating with scammers. The other party claimed to be a colleague. She asked some questions about the industry intentionally or unintentionally, and the other party could answer them appropriately. After being deceived, the woman did not tell her family, and only a few friends vaguely knew about it. She worries that if her colleagues find out, what she says in the company will have no weight in the future. When talking to Ma Yingxin, she always used a relatively relaxed tone, &quot;I thought everyone had passed the financial test, so there should be no problem.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, Ma Yingxin finished writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;. The heroine Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, is a female drifter from Beijing who was defrauded of 550,000 yuan. She followed clues to a small coastal town and met the con man Lin Zhiguang, played by Zhang Yu, and his friend Xu Zhao, played by Zhang Youhao. Emotional deception is based on imitation, performance, manipulation, and insight into and gaming of the subtleties of the human heart. Zhou Ran decided to retaliate in his own way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The filming location of the movie was Dongshan Island in Zhangzhou, Fujian. Maying hoped to find an island filled with fog. When writing the script, the first thing that came to her mind was the scene of three people meeting in the fog. She thought that this scene was like the state of a deceived woman - &quot;She was in the fog and couldn&#39;t see anything, but a male voice kept coming. She had been in a heavy fog for nine months.&quot; Until the source of the voice came out of the fog and a specific image of a man appeared, the fog began to disperse. &quot;From this moment on, Zhou Ran saw some things clearly. She wanted to take action. Finally, she was not in a place shrouded in fog and without anything. A situation that cannot be caught. I see you clearly, but you don’t know my situation or my mentality. She took the initiative.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China. She has loved watching movies since she was a child. After online paid movies became available, her father paid two to three thousand yuan in internet fees in one month. As an adult, Ma Yingxin went to Spain to study and study law, where she lived for more than ten years. She likes Almodóvar, has been writing scripts for the past ten years, and has made short films &quot;Dead Words&quot; and &quot;Man in the Chair&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is Ma Yingxin&#39;s first feature film. As a new director living overseas, this project was set up by chance. A few years ago, she met the writer Shuang Xuetao at a literature lecture in Spain. She introduced that she was engaged in film work in Spain and also wrote scripts. Shuang Xuetao said, if you want to hear other people&#39;s opinions, you are welcome to send them to me. At the end of 2020, after writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, she sent it to Shuang Xuetao on WeChat, &quot;I said that we exchanged WeChat messages when you came to Spain two years ago. Who am I? At that time, you said that you could give the script to Look, I now have a story that happened in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, they had a long phone call. Shuang Xuetao was on the sidelines preparing to play football at the time, but did not play until the end of the game. &quot;We didn&#39;t talk too much about the script on that phone call. He was actually trying to find out if I could be a director.&quot; Later, Shuang Xuetao became the producer of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, and Don He, who had collaborated with &quot;Fire on the Plain&quot;, served as the producer. Producer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the one-and-a-half-hour interview, Ma Yingxin occasionally needed to put her hands on the armrests of her wheelchair and lift her body to relax. Before becoming a director, she may face some labels, &quot;maybe a woman, followed by my personal physical condition&quot;, which she can accept, but in the final analysis, she wants to introduce herself as: an honest creator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; partly comes from parroting. The liar uses parroting techniques to help teach and complete the deception, which is essentially an act of imitation. She wanted to express, &quot;Women&#39;s appreciation of emotions is not a disadvantage of women, or something that should be eliminated.&quot; This is part of being a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China in 1986 and has lived overseas for many years. &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is her first feature film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;These women are ordinary people&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Very smart, even outstanding&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;You once said that you would not make a movie based on a certain social issue, but rather that a certain issue fits the issue you want to discuss and use this issue to develop a story. You think &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is very much like a fable. What does it contain to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was watching the news about &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;, the comments below kept discussing that the victim was stupid and must be It’s some very stupid, love-minded women who get scammed. After seeing these words, I have doubts based on my understanding of people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think it is impossible for a person not to have emotional connections with people in this life. It is not only limited to emotional love relationships, but also has emotional and trusting connections with your friends and people around you. . If this is the case, a group of people come here, and they are deliberately trying to deceive you. What can you do? It has nothing to do with whether you are a smart person, unless you don&#39;t relate to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I tried to find out what kind of people the victims were. I read online information and asked friends to contact me. I came to the conclusion that these people were ordinary women, just like me and the people around me. Nothing is different, have normal expectations for life and love. They are very smart, even brilliant women. So I&#39;m not going to create a typical or any kind of spectacle victim image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding why people are deceived, I had a communication with the producer Shuang Xuetao. He said that liars are an ancient industry, and cheating with feelings has been happening since ancient times. , but in a different form today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of being deceived involves many essential human issues, such as people’s eternal desire for true love, and the use of emotions to manipulate, deceive, and game between people. This is a very tense relationship. , which is theatrically intense. So this story has two levels. One is that the &quot;pig killing plate&quot; itself is an unfair or biased impression of the female victims, and the other is that this issue also contains other more essential issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You start from the emotional state and inner struggle of the victim after being deceived. , was this perspective formed from the beginning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I spent half a year to a year thinking about the script. I feel that the creation is not a complete representation of reality, and I don’t want to film it. I have so many news materials in my hands and then put them together in the form of a movie. Movies need to have a structure that puts in the things you most want to discuss. Later, I started writing the script after having two relatively clear ideas. One was that I wanted the victim and the liar to meet in reality, and the second was that I wanted to reenact the process of cheating and being cheated. I wrote it on and off for about half a year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xue Tao is very interested in many liar movies. He feels that this movie is a subversion of liar movies, because they usually focus on liars and describe how powerful liars are. How clever. He said that you did it from the perspective of a victim, which kept the genre of the con man movie and was subversive at the same time. In addition, he also said that liars have existed since ancient times, including big liars, small liars, and industry liars, so this is also a movie about trust. From both perspectives, this issue is worth pursuing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, he said that I provided a female perspective, because if a man were to make this movie, it might turn out differently. Don He has worked with female directors before and feels that this is a female expression, which is very precious and should be expressed like this. As a male, he could not understand every expression in it very accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The two male protagonists in the story are engaged in &quot;pig killing&quot; in a fraud park, and their true identities are confusing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Don&#39;t think this movie is going to teach women a lesson&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you choose Zhou Dongyu to play Zhou Ran? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After we promoted this project, the first thing we considered was who would play Zhou Ran, because it depends on an actress. Get up drama. At that time Don He recommended Dong Yu because they had collaborated on &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot;. Frankly speaking, I was hesitant at the time. Of course Dong Yu is very good, but in my heart I am a girl, and I think this character is exactly the opposite of her screen image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot; was shown to friends and family, and I went to see it. In the first half of the movie, Dongyu was still a girl, but in the second half, she showed another state. . Another more important reason is that I found that Dong Yu can handle very complex emotions, which is a very rare ability, because Zhou Ran has to constantly deal with complex emotions, not a simple &quot;I want revenge&quot; character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand the complexity of the character Zhou Ran? There are a lot of undercurrents and real and fake games in this story. Do you think she ever hesitated? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think her determination for revenge started from the moment she met the liar, even before she met the liar. Yes, but it was after she met the liar that she decided how to take revenge. Because this liar walked up to her and said, I am sincere, how many difficulties I have, what a special person you are, and he is still using words at this moment. She may have wanted to put him in jail before, and wanted to catch him, but after that scene, something deeper was aroused. She felt that just letting him go to jail was not enough, so she adopted a series of subsequent methods. Including the voices she heard from other female victims in the car, it also gave her a lot of strength and she must do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But you said whether she swayed and struggled during the process, I think she did. Because she is an ordinary person, not a well-trained liar, her doing this is beyond the scope of what ordinary people can bear. If she didn&#39;t struggle, it was a revenge, I came to act a scene, without any emotional fluctuations, and finally sent you in, it was not so powerful for me. On the contrary, she struggled a little bit and finally completed it, which I think is a very powerful act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Through the perspective of female victims, the expression you ultimately want to point to What is it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think we can understand the common experiences of women and the common intellectual and emotional struggles through the experience of this victim. Especially in recent years, with the emergence of the so-called &quot;love brain&quot;, I feel that it has been dwarfing women&#39;s natural appreciation of emotions, and has obscured the real problem in such an incident, which is the use of Those who seek benefits based on emotions are at fault, or this is what society really needs to be vigilant about. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not actually the core of this movie, but my own idea is that I hope that we can at least make a movie with a female protagonist. When the audience walks out of the cinema, they don’t just feel This movie wants to teach women a lesson about how women should not do anything. In the very few screenings we had before, female viewers could understand her way of revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Yingxin believes that the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is a fable that contains more essential issues such as trust and emotion. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is sincerity? He doesn’t know either&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your account at station B There was a special episode about Zhang Yu in &quot;Weekend Movie Party&quot;. How did it feel to work with Zhang Yu this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course, the role of Lin Chiguang is very different from his previous screen image, such as in &quot;The Calm&quot; and &quot;Siberian Tiger&quot; In it, he is a reserved, restrained and even repressed character, or another very reckless, direct, and fierce character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Zhiguang is completely different. He is a person who thinks very, very much. He is constantly performing true and false performances. He is very good at using language to manipulate others and use language to game or win. deceive others. The same thing is that Zhang Yu himself is also a very good thinker. At that time, he read the script and found it very interesting, but at the same time he had some opinions, so he wrote a page and sent it to Don He. A screenshot of the Don River was sent to me. When I saw it, I was very unconvinced and asked why you had so many opinions. So I wrote him a letter to answer these questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Zhang Yu is such an actor. He has a lot of questions to ask you, but after getting the answers, he can communicate and he will be very happy. Moreover, Lin Zhiguang has a relatively gentle trait in dealing with people. This is also something Zhang Yu himself has. He is also a very gentle person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was written on that piece of paper? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For example, why should I kill an octopus? Is this directed at me? What is the purpose of this image? I say that movies should not explain things. The more you explain, the less things you will learn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did he himself create anything for this character? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The language he created most is Lin Zhiguang’s language. We have fought many times about this matter. He wants Lin Zhiguang to have A very soft, Southern and not-so-Southern accent. This character deceived people and said that he was in Southeast Asia. He should have a unique accent, not Zhang Yu&#39;s accent, and not a Mandarin speaker. This was something he felt was very important to this character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对这两个男性诈骗者的形象是怎么理解的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;林致光是一个不相信任何东西的人，他在网上扮演阿昌，生活中又扮演林致光，所以他基本是活在扮演当中的人。他非常善于操纵别人，非常擅长操纵情感，是一个空空荡荡，很无助，很彷徨的人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许照是一个被毁掉的人，比较年轻就到了那个地方，他对这一切没有任何认知，为了生存开始做这些事。他还没有真正体验过什么是爱，什么是真心，就已经在运用它去骗人了，这导致他是一个很混沌的状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以在现实中他面对周冉，面对一个真实的女性，他其实也很混沌，分不清自己到底有没有爱她，有没有珍惜她。林致光有一句台词说，我以为你真的喜欢她。他说我是真的喜欢她，你说的嘛，要真心。但是这个真心到底是什么呢？我觉得他也不知道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;麻赢心在拍摄现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;女性复仇的方式是独特&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;、&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;有力的&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;周冉和林致光在车里接吻的镜头，不是一个很直接的亲吻镜头，甚至有点像“借位”。为什么这样设计？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是有意这样的，因为他们不是肉体关系，是精神上的博弈，所以肢体部分我会尽量往下压。那场戏最重要的是语言上的博弈，情感的博弈，周冉用一轮又一轮语言把林致光瓦解掉，获得他的信任。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最后林致光回到了车厢，他是真的被俘获了吗，还是不得不回来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题之前也有人问过我，我不觉得林致光爱上了周冉，在这么短的时间里，尤其是对林致光这样一个人来说，几乎是不可能的。我认为他那一刻是对于这个女性能够原谅他，甚至有可能跟他建立未来的生活，对这件事情产生了妄想。即使他是一个骗子，他也有一刻产生了妄想，所以回到了这个车厢。还有一种可能性是，他需要回到车厢才能拿到那笔钱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那场戏冬雨处理得也非常复杂，我几乎不太愿意用语言解读那场戏，但我核心的认识是最后的对峙，冬雨的表演非常有力量，她甚至做了一个鬼脸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那是她自己加的反应？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，她在那一刻突然有那一个动作，我认为是一个非常强大的反应，而且是只有她会给的一个反应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对于你来说，周冉最终的复仇是一种女性主义表达吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得我在这部电影里非常诚实，我本身是一个女性，所以一定是女性的表达，但是它是不是女性主义的表达，坦白说女性主义我还在学习。但这部电影至少提出了一种女性看待事情的方式，和她行动的方法。提到复仇，你总会觉得它是一种暴力行为，因为由复仇带来的联想，之前是由男性电影或以男性为主导的电影来给人建立印象的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个新的印象，女性复仇的方式是独特的。如果你认同情感或者谎言能给人伤害，那她复仇的方式就是有力的。确实有一些观众会觉得是不是不够爽，期待一些更暴力或更剧烈的复仇方式。但对我而言，反而这种方式才是真正有力的，而不是更暴烈、更外化的东西，我觉得她真的用了一个人是如何被摧毁的方式去报仇或回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你觉得林致光体会到了这种伤害，或者接收到了这个信息吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得林致光至少是诧异的，是他意想不到的。至少从表演上来说，最后那一场戏章宇的角色非常用力地看周冉，他就是想要看到一些答案，但是他看不到。我认为至少这个问题会困扰他。而且除了被绳之以法，对过去做的事情，他可能有机会真正地反思。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[211高校女硕士遭杀猪盘被骗138万：财务决策与婚恋决策分开是防骗关键]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，“211女硕士遭杀猪盘两周被骗138万”冲上热搜第一。当事人雪儿从江苏某211院校硕士毕业后，入职上海某银行。今年五六月份，她在某社交平台发布了择偶的帖子。一男性主动与她联系，称他住在上海杨浦区五角广场，毕业于上海财经大学，在互联网大厂工作，此时在北京出差。在网上交流一段时间后，对方给雪儿发了一个链接，让她点击下载一个名为“luno”的app，教她在上面买币，然后用币买涨买跌，赚点外快。刚开始雪儿赚了一些钱，随后，对方以各种理由让雪儿先后投入130多万，最终雪儿发现陷入骗局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;层出不穷的“杀猪盘”，对各类人群通杀，针对男性的裸聊陷阱，针对女性的婚恋陷阱，显示了骗子对两性心理差异的精准把握。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然拥有高学历、高收入、高颜值，但不少女性也深陷其中。究其原因，某些高知女性在婚恋中，往往没有做好财务决策和婚恋决策，尤其是混为一谈，使骗子有机可乘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓财务决策，涉及资金方面的支出、投资等行为，需对投资项目的合理可行性、投资规模、投资止损标准、投资失败带来的后果等，进行综合考量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“杀猪盘”的变现套路，往往是以高息诱导受害人。然而，你图的是高息，骗子瞄准的是你本金。人们应建立一个投资常识，投资产品的预期收益与投资风险是正相关的。就如日常购买各类理财产品，理财产品会标注不同等级，预期年化收益率不高但标注低风险的理财产品，主要投资于高信用等级债券（如国债）、货币市场等低风险金融产品，而预期年化收益率高但标注中高风险的理财产品，则投资产品组合中股票、商品、外汇等高波动性金融产品的占比高。理财机构在客户购买产品时，还要进行个人投资风险评估，根据其填报的以往投资品类、收入状况等信息，为其推荐更符合其风险偏好的投资品种，避免其盲目投资。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，当女方听到对方介绍“包赚不赔、利息远超市场平均水准”的投资产品时，就应引起警惕。郭树清曾经提醒过广大金融消费者和投资者：高收益意味着高风险，收益率超过6%就要打问号，超过8%就很危险，10%以上就要准备损失全部本金。另外，就是不要轻信不明信息，不要随意透露个人信息，不要打开不明网络链接，不要轻易汇款转账。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但凡遇到大额资金投资，事先多了解一些投资理财专业知识，或者请具有相关经验的人士或机构提供建议，然后根据自身风险承受能力、资金面等，进行投资与否、投资金额、出现问题如何及时止损等方面的决策，应成为所有人具备的“财商”。尤其是作为高知女性，更应有起码的学习能力。上述案例的雪儿在银行工作，虽然从事IT工作，但找几个懂理财的同事请教并非难事，可她被男方尤其是“投资”最初的获利所惑，一步步深入陷阱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，男女还要做好婚恋决策。一般而言，在婚恋市场，男女双方的诉求排序不同。男性往往更看重女性颜值、年龄等，女性则将男性的财富、家庭背景等标准作为重点。对于高知女性而言，婚恋市场上某方面优秀的男性不少，但富人则很少，兼具外形和财富的高富帅，属于典型的稀缺人群，他们的选择空间极大，所以对“高富帅”的竞争其实是很激烈的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;骗子之所以打造高富帅人设，在于他们深知这一人群身处卖方市场，女性往往求之难得。一旦遇到，某些女性急于将白马王子牢牢抓住，有严重的依赖心理，易对骗子言听计从。部分女性过于追求爱情的完美和投资的高收益，忽视了现实中的风险和不确定性。在面对“杀猪盘”骗局时，受到情感和利益的双重诱惑，从而掉入骗子的陷阱，最终人财两失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论男性还是女性，进行婚恋决策，至少要做好三点事先评估：其一，客观评估自身条件，自己在婚恋市场的大致排序是什么？不要净想着买两块钱彩票中五百万。知人者智，自知者明，古人诚不我欺。其二，如果对方的言行与人身让你很舒服，如浴春风，那就不要太上头，应该吹一下冷风，用理智判断一下，对方就是这样的人品还是处处在迎合你？贪图情绪价值可以理解，但对方暗中的标价可能昂贵到你难以承受。其三，哪怕认定对方是真命天子，也别将婚恋决策和财务决策捆绑。越来越多走到婚姻这一步的男女，都开始强调婚后财产、生活开支“AA制”，你何以婚前就能将血汗钱交给对方帮忙投资？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 10:25:34 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳门街坊的横琴生活：粤澳合作区两周年记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎明破晓，伴随着旅客通关时发出的清脆提示音，伫立在横琴口岸的新旅检大楼，再度迎来了繁忙时刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天，约1.2万人次港澳居民经横琴口岸往返琴澳两地，澳门居民黄惠霞正是其中一员。差不多两年前，她迁居横琴粤澳深度合作区，成了一名“新横琴人”；如今，她长居横琴，每周会返回澳门三四次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“交通更便利了、房子更宽敞了、生活环境更舒适了、社区服务更完善了、来合作区的澳门人越来越多了……”谈到在横琴两年的生活感受，黄惠霞如数家珍。而未来，随着澳门轻轨延伸横琴线项目投入使用，横琴到澳门的交通将会更加便利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年9月5日，《横琴粤澳深度合作区建设总体方案》（以下简称《横琴方案》）印发，赋予横琴“促进澳门经济适度多元发展的新平台”“便利澳门居民生活就业的新空间”“丰富&#39;一国两制&#39;实践的新示范”“推动粤港澳大湾区建设的新高地”四大战略使命。12天后，横琴粤澳深度合作区管理机构正式揭牌，合作区建设驶入“快车道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自2009年《横琴总体发展规划》印发以来，国家相继出台了一系列创新政策，为横琴发展擘画美好蓝图。”中山大学区域开放与合作研究院院长毛艳华告诉南方周末记者，“横琴粤澳深度合作区具有区位条件优越、合作基础扎实、扶持力度大等多重优势，目前的发展势头正盛，而未来一定更加可期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;横琴的澳门街坊&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我原来在澳门的房子很小，只有六十多平方米，搬到横琴后，居住面积一下子增加到150平方米。”迁居横琴两年，黄惠霞对横琴的居住环境、交通条件、社区服务、医疗以及通关等方面的变化，有着最真切的感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初秋的天沐河水光潋滟，两岸绿树成荫，草木繁盛。沿着河边全长约7.2公里的生态长廊漫步，生态群落区、公园式社区等极具韵律感的城市滨水景观带渐次铺开，而一水之隔就是澳门塔、新葡京大厦、美高梅酒店等澳门地标性建筑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞两年前从澳门搬到横琴上村，那里有60%的住户都是澳门居民。上村距离天沐河步行只需要十分钟左右，每日闲暇的时候，她都会到河边散步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞还清楚记得刚搬到横琴时的情形，那时候由于人流量不足，公交线路很少，回澳门一趟要在路上折腾很久。“现在我每周都要往返澳门三四次，出了小区就有好几趟公交车可以抵达横琴口岸。”黄惠霞告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;横琴口岸位于横琴岛十字门水道西岸，与澳门一桥相连，处于“一国两制”的交汇点和“内外辐射”的接合部。目前，横琴口岸已经实现“合作查验、一次放行”，出入境人员只需“在一个大厅、排一次队、接受一次检查”就可完成内地、澳门双方出入境手续，人均通关时间只需30秒左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通关时间大大缩短，流程更加优化，让两地往返的澳门居民过上了更加舒适的双城生活。黄惠霞明显感觉到，每日通关到合作区的澳门居民越来越多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据统计，目前在横琴定居就业的澳门居民达7000余人，经横琴口岸出入境的港澳居民日均客流从2022年的5900余人次，增长至2023年的近1.2万人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了居住环境、日常起居和交通条件上的重大改善，横琴合作区的养老、医疗和社区服务也在不断向澳门标准靠拢。2019年，澳门街坊会联合总会在横琴设立服务中心，组成专业服务团队，为合作区内年满60周岁的老人提供澳门标准的居家养老上门服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“截至2023年8月底，我们已为琴澳两地居民提供服务逾96万人次。”澳门街坊总会一名负责人告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而得益于跨境执业政策持续推进，目前在横琴执业的港澳短期行医医师累计有67名。包括黄惠霞在内的“新横琴人”足不出区，就可以找熟悉的澳门医生看诊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们在横琴可以就地参保，享受和珠海市民同等的医保待遇，就医买药都很便利，而且个人花费也不高。”黄惠霞说，“后续&#39;澳门新街坊&#39;项目竣工后，将有澳门医疗团队进驻，还配备有大型医疗服务中心，以后的生活将更加便利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞所提到的“澳门新街坊”，是合作区首个为澳门居民打造的综合性民生工程，会配套各项澳门标准的公共服务和社会福利，将为超万名澳门居民打造优质宜居社区。目前，该工程已进入验收阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“未来在合作区的生活肯定会越来越好。”黄惠霞告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“四新产业”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;借着横琴合作区快速发展的东风，王瑞明来到横琴寻求发展。刚刚过去的几个月，他收购了一家澳资企业，计划成立新公司，主要从事金融和互联网产业，预计将于9月底正式开业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为从事合作区重点支持的金融行业，他的公司可以享受15%税收优惠政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王瑞明是一名“侨三代”。近几年，受粤港澳大湾区营商政策、环境吸引，他一直在湾区积极布局，先后在香港和深圳注册了金融公司，主营基金、信托和保险等业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“横琴的金融产业高度开放、跨境资本自由流动，是跨境人民币结算最活跃的地区，有很多世界五百强企业落户这里，未来很有希望成为中国金融业对外开放的新高地。”王瑞明告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年上半年，合作区内金融业增加值达88亿元，占&lt;span>;GDP&lt;/span>;近四成，同比增长2.9%，呈现出加速集聚的态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“合作区围绕&#39;四新产业&#39;扎实推进，不仅对产业定位更加明确，而且共商共建共管共享体制机制也已经初步搭建。”毛艳华指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澳门地少人多，不足33平方公里的土地上生活着逾68万人口，平均每平方公里超过2万人，是世界上人口密度最高的城市之一。土地资源不足、产业结构单一等难题，一直困扰着澳门发展。而与澳门一水之隔的横琴，面积达106平方公里，空间优势显著，为支撑澳门经济多元发展提供了充足空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2009年8月，国务院就批准实施《横琴总体发展规划》，明确指出要以横琴为载体，共同打造跨界合作创新区，为逐步改变澳门经济结构比较单一的问题提供新的空间。而伴随着粤港澳大湾区高质量发展逐步推进以及《横琴方案》出台，琴澳融合上升到新高度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自开发之初，横琴就被赋予了服务澳门经济多元发展的使命。十几年的开发建设中，这一使命不仅没有变，而且更加突出。”毛艳华指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自揭牌运作以来，横琴合作区聚焦“四新”战略定位，大力发展科技研发和高端制造、中医药等澳门品牌工业、文旅会展商贸以及现代金融产业“四大产业”，针对集成电路业、金融业、文旅会展业等推出一系列新政。两年的时间，一批批重点项目加快推进，琴澳一体化发展格局已初步建立，促进澳门经济适度多元发展的支撑作用正在逐步显现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅在2023年上半年，合作区实际运营的集成电路企业就超40家，初步形成涵盖知识产权（IP）、第三代半导体等领域的集成电路设计产业生态；粤澳合作中医药科技产业园一季度企业税收贡献近8000万元，同比增长59%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产业集聚以及政策红利之下，横琴粤澳深度合作区已成为澳人澳企投资创业的新平台和新高地。目前，合作区有澳资企业超过5600户，较合作区挂牌前增长22.3%，注册资本超1480亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《横琴方案》开启了粤澳深度合作区建设的新篇章。”毛艳华表示，“未来合作区建设要继续围绕服务澳门产业多元发展这一初心，从建设一流产业功能园区出发，大力发展实体经济，利用好创新体制，进一步吸引园区内外要素充分流动集聚，从而打造珠江西岸高质量发展的新增长极。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中黄惠霞、王瑞明系化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rS zHzGpQrZ3O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2019, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram in operation was nicknamed &quot; Dangdang car”. In June 2023, Zhangjiang trams will be suspended. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retro, good-looking, fresh... City trams once had such Internet celebrities label, but in the past few months, news of tram outages have appeared frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, an announcement circulated on the Internet stating that due to difficulties in operating funds, modern trams in Honghe Prefecture, Yunnan will cease operations on August 10, 2023. On August 11, the chairman of Honghe Prefecture Modern Tram Co., Ltd. responded that the announcement was false news. At present, the local tram has not been suspended and is operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Tianjin Development Zone Guide Tram Line 1, which had been in operation for 16 years, announced that it would cease operation and started procurement of demolition projects. In June, Shanghai Zhangjiang Tram No. 1, which had been in operation for 13 years, was suspended and the tracks were quickly dismantled. Two years ago, in 2021, the trams in Zhuhai, Guangdong, were suspended and planned to be dismantled after more than three years of operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram was out of service, and workers were dismantling the track. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Shijun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, 3 of the 39 rail lines across the country have been suspended. According to the &quot;Urban Rail Transit 2022 Annual Statistics and Analysis Report&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Report&quot;) released by the China Urban Rail Transit Association, as of the end of 2022, a total of 39 tram lines in 23 cities across the country have been put into operation, with an operating mileage of 578.3 kilometers. , equivalent to half the distance from Beijing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The primary reason for the suspension of operations is low passenger flow. This is not the first time such news has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2015, after the opening of the Chengdu Tram Chengdu Tram Line 2&#39;s first section, the line was not connected to the urban rail transit network and the passenger flow was low, which led to great pressure from public opinion and suffered &quot;some problems&quot;. &quot;Trams are useless&quot; controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are trams frequently suspended? How to avoid the &quot;chair transport&quot; situation? Compared with subways with large passenger flows, trams are &quot;urban rail transit low-capacity systems,&quot; Li Hongchun, an expert and deputy director of the academic committee of the China Urban Rail Transit Association and vice president of the Modern Tram Branch, told Southern Weekend that doing a good job Line network planning achieves a high degree of integration of multiple transportation modes, and low-capacity systems can develop systematically and healthily. There are also many successful cases in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Low passenger flow is the key to the suspension of trams&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Insufficient passenger flow and serious losses are the key reasons for the suspension of trams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jiemian News, before the suspension, the daily passenger volume of Shanghai Zhangjiang trams had dropped sharply to about 1,000 passengers. Wang Qingfeng (pseudonym), a bus enthusiast who works in Zhangjiang, recalled that sometimes “when we get on the bus from the starting station, there are almost no passengers on the bus along the way.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 25, 2022, at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on a working day, there were almost no passengers in the Shanghai Zhangjiang tram car, and there was only one conductor. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The operating pressure of the Honghe Prefecture tram, which denies rumors of suspension, is not optimistic either. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the tram passenger intensity in Honghe Prefecture was 0.01 (10,000 passengers/km·day), ranking at the bottom in the country. The passenger volume that month was only 26,000, with an average of less than 900 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 29, 2018, a tram was undergoing joint debugging and testing in Honghe, Yunnan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low operating frequency is an important reason that affects passenger flow. The longer the departure interval, the lower the attractiveness of passenger flow. Low passenger flow further affects the departure interval, forming a vicious circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval between Zhangjiang tram trains before they stop running is 15 to 20 minutes. For commuters, the waiting time is too long. &quot;Instead of waiting for the tram, it&#39;s better to buy a shared bicycle.&quot; Wang Qingfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only shared bicycles, but also the opening and operation of many subway lines such as the eastern extension of Shanghai Metro Line 2, Line 11, and Line 13, have dispersed the passenger flow of trams. Before the suspension, in February 2023, Zhangjiang trams reduced their operating hours from 17 hours a day to only 4 trips during the morning and evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Pudong Modern Rail Transit Co., Ltd. stated in the announcement that in recent years, the public transportation system in Zhangjiang area has been continuously enriched and improved. Multiple urban rail lines have been put into operation, and ground bus lines have been optimized and adjusted many times. The passenger flow of Zhangjiang Tram 1 has been declining year by year, and ground buses will replace the connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Insufficient technical applicability and high maintenance costs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to low passenger flow and long departure intervals, the trams in Tianjin Development Zone and Shanghai Zhangjiang are subject to The vehicles are imported products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both use the Translohr system produced by the French company Raul, which has rubber wheels, single track and a small footprint. However, not many cities around the world use this system. With the gradual decline of Raul after its acquisition, the production of related parts has been greatly reduced, resulting in high vehicle maintenance costs and long maintenance cycles, and some parts are facing the risk of &quot;supply interruption&quot;. Difficulties in purchasing parts have also led to difficulties and high costs in maintaining trams in Shanghai Zhangjiang and Tianjin Development Zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qingfeng recalled that when he was riding a tram in Zhangjiang, he discovered that there was a thick wooden pole in the driver&#39;s cab. The tracks are sometimes blocked by debris, and drivers need to get out of the car and use wooden poles to clear the debris, which greatly affects traffic efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Zhuhai tram, Li Hongchun mentioned in an interview that the TramWave ground power supply system it used lacked engineering practice, and the builders had insufficient understanding of the applicability of the technology, resulting in system problems after the line was opened. The failure rate is high and the operation service is unstable. At the same time, factors such as low passenger flow and high maintenance costs have directly affected the remaining section of Line 1 that was originally planned to be rebuilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being low in frequency, the out-of-service trams were also considered too slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Report&quot; shows that the average travel speed of subways in 2022 will be 36.47 kilometers/hour, the average travel speed of trams nationwide is only 22.3 kilometers/hour, and the travel speed of Zhangjiang trams is only 19 kilometers/hour Hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the maximum design speed of Zhangjiang trams is 70 kilometers per hour. The reason for the slow running speed is that trams do not have dedicated right of way - they share the road space with all vehicles and are still subject to traffic lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Zhangjiang tram does not have a dedicated right of way. It shares the road space with all vehicles and is still subject to traffic lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long trams waiting for traffic lights exacerbate congestion. For example, the Zhangjiang tram passes by Pudong Foreign Languages ​​School Affiliated to Shanghai International Studies University. Parents will park their private cars on the roadside when picking up their children. When the tram comes in, it will occupy the entire road. One citizen said: &quot;You can either use the non-motorized lane next to it to overtake, or you can only follow the Dangdang tram.&quot; Dangdang tram is the nickname given to Zhangjiang trams by Shanghai residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Planning issues, not standard issues&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking around the world, trams are not a niche issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;China Tram Development Report (2020)&quot; released by the Modern Tramway Branch of the China Urban Rail Transit Association shows that subways and trams are the mainstream systems of urban rail transit in the world, of which subways account for 47 %, trams account for 42%, and light rail accounts for 11%. In Europe, trams are the mainstream public transportation mode in many cities. For example, in Berlin, Germany, trams account for as high as 55.6% of the rail transit mileage. In China, this proportion is only 5.71%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some voices pointed out that the tram was &quot;unacclimated&quot; after it came to China. But Li Hongchun reminded that many tram projects are operating well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In very large and megacities, trams can be used as extension lines and encrypted lines of large and medium-sized transportation systems such as subways. For example, Beijing&#39;s Xijiao Line, as an extension of Metro Line 10, starts from Bagou Station and connects tourist attractions such as Xiangshan Park, National Botanical Garden, Yuquan Country Park and the Summer Palace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Western Suburb Line is positioned to be “mainly for commuting, supplemented by tourism,” Li Hongchun added. The Xijiao Line is the first tramway in the country to be operated with multiple connections - two train sets are connected together to increase passenger flow. During the &quot;Xiangshan Red Leaf Festival&quot; in 2019, the maximum daily passenger flow reached 94,700, making it the first single tram in the country. The daily passenger flow is the highest recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the May Day holiday in 2022, in order to reduce the full load of the carriages, the Beijing Xijiao Line will adopt a multi-connection operation mode. A single train will change from 5 carriages to 10 carriages, with 8 groups per day. Heavy-duty trains are put into operation with a minimum departure interval of 5 minutes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China News Service reporter Jia Tianyong Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Huai&#39;an, Jiangsu, trams even serve as the city&#39;s backbone public transportation, ensuring Passenger flow demand. Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is the first tram line in China that enters the core area of ​​the city, and its passenger flow has always been at the forefront of tram lines in the country. According to the rail transit operation data of 52 cities across the country in July released by the Ministry of Transport, the passenger flow in Huai&#39;an was 580,000, reaching nearly 20,000 passengers per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 16, 2020, in Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province, modern trams that were suspended due to the epidemic resumed operation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In tourist areas, trams can also play the role of special tourist buses, such as the Nanping Wuyi New District Line in Fujian , connecting Nanping City High-speed Railway Station to Wuyishan Station, seamlessly connecting with Wuyishan Scenic Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the experience of successfully operating trams, unlike large-capacity systems such as subways, trams, as low-capacity systems, are redeveloped on existing road resources, which is difficult and needs to be adapted to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that the suspension of some trams does not reflect problems with the tram system itself, but problems in planning and design. For example, the area near the first phase of the Zhuhai tram project is mostly high-end communities. Residents mainly travel by car. Moreover, the north side of the line is dominated by mountains. The development intensity along the line is low, there is little residential land, a lack of commercial facilities, and the line radiates from one side. , resulting in low passenger flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to plan rationally? Li Hongchun believes that trams are positioned as an environmentally friendly transportation system that fills the gap between large-capacity subways and conventional buses. First, we must ensure a clear level of public transportation planning and strengthen integration with comprehensive transportation. For the connection of hubs, the division of labor between trams and conventional bus systems must be properly handled, and the line network layout must consider the integration of large-capacity systems and medium- and low-capacity systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 26, 2020, the first tram in Wuyishan City, Nanping City, Fujian Province slowly drove out of the Xiandian depot and entered the trial operation stage. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the Sanya tram is located closest to the entrance and exit of Sanya Railway Station, and the Jiaxing tram The station is directly connected to the newly developed campuses on both sides by pedestrian tunnels, making these designs more convenient for residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Site selection needs to be supported by a certain population density. Li Hongchun mentioned that it is necessary to accurately predict the passenger flow in the line corridor to avoid the situation where the actual passenger flow does not reach the estimated amount. In terms of construction timing, &quot;we must first consider what needs to be built most, not where it is easier to build.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first section of Chengdu Rong Line 2 was opened, the low passenger flow was questioned because it had not yet been connected to the urban rail network. After the opening of the second section, it was connected to the subway, and the passenger flow reached nearly four. Ten thousand people, an increase of dozens of times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of operations, regarding the issue of tram rights of way, Li Hongchun believes that priority signals should be provided for trams to ensure the safety, speed and efficiency of tram operations. For example, Huai&#39;an Tram Line 1 is equipped with three major systems: tram signal priority control system, intersection red light electronic police and road section checkpoint system, and intersection video surveillance system, and arranges traffic coordinators to realize tram priority at intersections. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hongchun believes that under the dual influence of my country&#39;s rapid urbanization and the substantial increase in private car ownership leading to congestion, the development of public transportation is an inevitable trend in history. The construction cost of the subway is at least ten times higher than that of the tram. Compared with the bus, the tram has the advantages of large transportation capacity, high comfort and punctuality. Under the trend of carbon neutrality, tram It is an important option for public transportation construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 9:30 am on October 26, 1909, Congkuanchengzi (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changchun&lt;/span>;) Ito Hirobumi, who arrived in Harbin by special train, stepped off the train. A short man wearing a peaked cap and western clothes calmly touched his chest, ribs, and abdomen. He fired three shots and then fired four shots at the accompanying Japanese officials, shouting &quot;Ula Golia!&quot; in Russian.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened suddenly, and everyone was still dreaming. Ito Hirobumi was put on a special train and died 30 minutes later. The man with a resolute face, An Zhonggen, was captured in an almost tragic manner; the seven gunshots fired over the Harbin Railway Station, which was built in 1899 and named in 1903, rapidly and profoundly changed the 20th century. The situation in Northeast Asia at the beginning - Although the train station was demolished and rebuilt in 1959, there are still vivid traces of this incident in the station, including the Ahn Jung-geun Memorial Hall and the platform where the incident occurred: the &quot;Δ&quot; and &quot;□&quot; on the ground , respectively, where Ahn Jung-geun and Ito Hirobumi are standing, about 5 meters apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old scene of Harbin Railway Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Ruo Ge As Li said, &quot;When poems and legends are silent, only buildings speak.&quot; - Around the train station, everything is completely different from what it was more than a hundred years ago. Only the Church of Saint-Iver still quietly &quot;leans&quot; on it. Stand aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Street: &quot;The Cross-Communication of Multiculturalism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Old Harbin&quot; without city walls is actually neither ancient nor modern - it is The &quot;modern city&quot; grew up amid the roar of trains. China&#39;s defeat in the Sino-Japanese War and many factors such as Tsarist Russia&#39;s use of alliance with Japan as bait to seize more interests in Northeast China gave birth to the construction of the Middle East Railway. In 1896, Russia obtained the right to build the Middle East Railway. In June of that year, Russia&#39;s Middle East Railway The General Administration of Construction moved from Vladivostok (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Vladivostok&lt;/span>;) to Harbin. At the same time, the railway was divided into The six ends of the east-west and south-west lines are being constructed in opposite directions at the same time. As the center of the 2,500-kilometer &quot;T&quot;-shaped railway that runs from Manzhouli in the west, Suifenhe in the east, and Lushun, Dalian in the south, it has quickly become an international city with &quot;sky-high buildings, merchants, soaring land prices, and every inch of land is precious.&quot; - &quot;The desolate wilderness turned into a prosperous port in an instant.&quot; Capitalism has become the &quot;power&quot; for Harbin&#39;s rapid growth and rise, but at the same time, foreign capital has inhibited and hindered the development of national capitalism, making it an &quot;alien&quot; between traditional Chinese cities and modern capitalist cities; a railway has even more influence on Harbin. The local architectural culture has had a huge impact, with a wave of compulsory and replacement architectural design trends - integration, addition, mutation... In the silent dusk more than a hundred years ago, in this city with wonderful characteristics, it began Continuously “cultivating”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Harbin Railway Station and St. Iver&#39;s Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Red Army Street, which shoots out straight from Harbin Railway Station, was originally named Horvat Street. It is the starting point and germination of Harbin&#39;s city construction. It spreads outwards with it as the axis, showing the annual rings of the city&#39;s growth. The original site of the Longmen VIP Building was built in 1907. At the other end, there were the Russian Consulate General in Harbin and the Officers Club of the Russian Trans-Amur Military District, as well as the &quot;famous&quot; Yamato Hotel in the Northeast; the Sino-Russian Daosheng Bank, built in 1920, is now It is the Heilongjiang Provincial Research Museum of Literature and History, still maintaining the original French Renaissance style; the Cheschakov Tea House’s mixed classicism, baroque and Renaissance style exterior bay windows, overhanging awnings, and open-air balconies are set among the Among the green trees, looking at the signboard of &quot;HSBC Camera Company&quot;, it is difficult to imagine that it was designed by Zhdanov, a Russian Jewish architect who has lived in Harbin for 37 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Red Army Street and the east-west Dazhi Street once intersected at the ancient Gothic wooden structure St. Nicholas Church. Nowadays, there is no trace of the Church of San Nicola. The International Hotel built in 1937 looks like a huge accordion. Opposite it is the former Italian Consulate, the Gibelosso building built in 1919, which is full of exquisite reliefs. The octagonal exterior walls are stacked upward layer by layer to form a lovely eclectic building dominated by Baroque style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another group of &quot;solemn vs. cute&quot; buildings is on Dazhi Street. The famous &quot;big stone house&quot; Harbin Railway Bureau Office Building was completed in February 1904 as the Middle East Railway Administration. Magnificent, majestic and dignified, it is like a &quot;huge castle&quot;; the Harbin Railway Museum, just across the street, has a simple interior decoration, while the exterior maintains the yellow and white colors from its days as the Middle East Railway Club, full of joy. breath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lama Terrace&quot; where St. Nicholas Church is located is the highest point in Harbin. It can be protected from floods when the Songhua River rises. Therefore, starting in 1899, Russia began to regulate the location of this place. The Qinjiagang area (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Nangang District&lt;/span>;) is undergoing large-scale urban construction. Within five years, the China Eastern Railway Administration Building and the Moscow Shopping Mall Building were built. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s Heilongjiang Provincial Museum&lt;/span>;) and other European-style buildings were completed, and the east-west axis of Qinjiagang - Horvat Street, Dazhi Street and Main streets such as the New Business Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today&#39;s Guogol Street&lt;/span>;) were built. In the 1930s, the Qinjiagang area had &quot;grand buildings, neat streets&quot;, &quot;fresh air and fragrant flowers&quot;. Most foreign consulates were concentrated here, becoming Harbin&#39;s administrative center and a gathering place for foreigners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiulin Company located in Nangang District today&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;East and West The various subsystems of Fang civilization collide, rub, infiltrate, and blend with each other here. The unprecedented integration of the architectural culture of various ethnic groups in the world presents a &quot;cross-communication of multiculturalism.&quot; The Middle East Railway brought a large number of overseas Chinese - according to statistics, in 1923, the total population of Harbin reached 400,000, with nearly 200,000 overseas Chinese and more than 180,000 Chinese. Twenty or thirty years after the Russo-Japanese War, Harbin has become an international city. It brought Russian culture, Jewish culture, Japanese culture, Tatar culture... and nearly 70 churches including St. Nicholas Church, St. Sophia Church, and the Church of the Annunciation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhdanov is to Harbin what Hudec is to Shanghai. Among the three churches &quot;clustered&quot; on Dongdazhi Street, the Church of Our Lady of Saints and Saints designed by Zhdanov (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Church of Our Lady of Protection&lt;/span >;) is the most eye-catching. This Byzantine-style church is said to have preserved the 2,600-kilogram bell that was cast in Moscow in 1899, but it is not available to see now. What can be seen is the notice board erected next to the church: &quot;Please pay attention to your behavior, God is working.&quot; Watching you”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Church: Bells Echoing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike the Virgin Mary Church, which is located on the busy main road of the city, the Tatar Church, also designed by Zhdanov The Tai Mosque is hidden among the residential buildings on Tongjiang Street. The red and white walls are full of Byzantine style of quiet and dignified temperament. It is like a &quot;mysterious little castle&quot;. Especially at dusk, it has a sense of simplicity. From 1899, when the first Russian Jew, S. I. Berzeri, came to Harbin to the 1940s, countless Jews came to this &quot;second home&quot; and built buildings here, including a hexagonal church with a dome holding up the Shield of David. Many Jewish buildings including the Star Synagogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tatar Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least a hundred years ago, the majestic The bells once echoed over Harbin. In the sound of the bells, expatriates from all over the world, adventurers and exiles of all kinds stopped to listen and found a moment of solace in their hometown in this foreign land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symbol of Harbin - St. Sophia Church, the melodious bells played on important religious festivals can be said to be the deep memory of the city for the older generation of Harbin people. It is said that in the church on a snowy day in winter, the Byzantine-style appearance can allow more snow to stay on the surface of the building. The wind blows the snowflakes, which are like the ultimate romance in a crystal ball; on a snowy night, the church will turn into gold bricks. The castle with bright tiles and the towering cross are like stars in the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hagia Sophia on a snowy night, the scenery is as dreamy as a crystal ball. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to observe the details of the church quietly, the best time is at dusk. The full dark green dome full of momentum is lifted very high by the main body of the clear red brick building. The golden cross shines brightly, showing a dynamic beauty of rising successively. Viewed from the side, the tops of the four tents are staggered, and the slanting light shines on it. The architectural details cast mysterious shadows, honest and simple. Step into the church and enjoy the daily rotating concerts, as well as the mottled walls and Roman-style arched windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting sun reflects on the top of the church, which reminds people of its sister with the same name on the other side of the Eurasian continent, and also allows people to relive the rich history of the city&#39;s past. In fact, this church had &quot;humble origins&quot; and was only the military chapel of the 4th Infantry Division of Tsarist Russia in Eastern Siberia. In March 1907, it was renovated with funds from the Russian businessman Cheschakov, whose home was on Red Army Street. In 1912 A layer of bricks was laid on the original foundation. In 1923, the Russian architect Kasikov re-selected a site in the southeast corner of the old church and built it. It was completed in November 1932, giving it what it looks like today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Concert in Saint Sophia Church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saint Sophia The architectural style and decorative style of the church draw on the Russian brick carving art of the 17th century. The St. Alexeev Church at the corner of Gogol Street and Shikes Street organically combines a huge building volume with facade brick decoration. Giving it a strong Russian accent and unique mood. Although this century-old building, which was originally an Orthodox church and was converted into a Catholic church in 1980, also has a majestic and scattered beauty. Even under the clear blue sky in the northeast, it can be regarded as the appearance of the city&#39;s architecture, but it is not as lively as Sofia Square. There are very few people around after sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lights&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: Chinese Baroque&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Qiulin Kvass rustles after opening the bottle cap. This famous drink looks like Beer, slightly red in color but with only 1% alcohol content, is very suitable for &quot;bottle blowing&quot; when traveling and hiking - such as walking from Alexeev Church, along Gogol Street to the L-shaped building built in 1908 A grand building with a light green tone - Qiulin Yangxing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many old buildings on Gogol Street, but while maintaining their former glory, they have inevitably declined and become dilapidated - just like Daowai District. To the north from the train station, east of the railway across the river, is the Daowai District, formerly known as &quot;Fujiadian&quot;, where immigrants from Shandong and Hebei settled in Guandong. Although it is one of the earliest urban centers in Harbin, due to the lack of complete and precise planning, in the 1930s the streets here were &quot;narrow and uneven&quot; and &quot;everywhere you go is so disgusting that you have to cover your nose and avoid it.&quot; &amp;nbsp;——The folk proverb at that time said: &quot;Nangang is heaven, inside the road is the world, and outside the road is hell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unique &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; architecture also grew here. Along the street, the Western Baroque facade is used, while incorporating the auspicious decorative patterns of traditional Chinese architecture. Iron railings or &quot;Guanyin bottle&quot;-style concrete railings are set up on the edge of the protruding platform. Stepping inside, it is purely a northern courtyard. The architectural shape combines earth and western elements, giving it its own charm. The Chinese Baroque neighborhood, which is mainly located on South Second and Third Streets and has been renovated into a tourist attraction, is lackluster. Many of the green brick streets and wide courtyards have been transformed into catering shops. They are more organized but lack the liveliness and prosperity of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot; on Dong Jingyu Street in the neighborhood is the most authentic. Originally built in 1890, this long street was originally called Zhengyang Street. It is also the birthplace of Harbin&#39;s national commerce: Zhengyang Tower, Laodingfeng, Shiyitang, Daluoxin Department Store, Hengdeli, Tongji Shopping Mall... every inch of land Jin&#39;s Old Street used to be lined with businesses. At the intersection of Jingyu Street and Nantou Street, the four-story brick and wood structure Purification Hospital was built in 1920. It was formerly known as Tongyi Qinghuo Store. It is one of the masterpieces of &quot;Chinese Baroque&quot;: the swaying reliefs of vine flowers from Ioni The exterior walls of the sub-column and Corinthian columns are winding all the way down, and the gorgeous and luxurious style is unforgettable, fully reflecting the hope of fame of the national industrial and commercial people at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Purification Hospital located outside Laodao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All famous, Prosperity and bustle have their end. Today&#39;s Laodaowai has lost its popularity due to large-scale construction, and its decline is fully visible: dilapidated buildings can be seen along the street, and the roofs are covered with decaying grass, as if the old buildings are sighing; the cats and dogs wandering on the street look full of vicissitudes of life. Feeling; beside the ruins, you can occasionally see small electric cars with the sign of &quot;darning&quot;, which is a common livelihood for middle-aged and elderly women in the Northeast - sewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In old Harbin, if the window of &quot;middle&quot; is &quot;Zhengyang Street&quot;, the epitome of &quot;west&quot; is Central Street - in Xiao Hong&#39;s pen, the city street is like a &quot;complex and unclear color&quot; &quot;Map&quot;, Harbin today has similar characteristics - it is also a commercial street, Jingyu Street outside the road has become a large construction site, and Central Street inside the road, at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning, there are tourists wandering around carrying kvass bottles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Laodaowai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Night, spring night, Central Street is a night full of music. Music from homeless people, music from Japanese dance halls, music from foreign restaurants... After 7 o&#39;clock, in the middle of Central Street, at a crossroads, the loud loudspeaker screamed, this The singing almost resounded throughout the street.&quot; Xiao Hong once wrote about Central Street in &quot;Spring Hangs on the Treetops&quot;, with a lot of irony and banter; however, the &quot;gradually countless&quot; things she recorded were &quot;like long ropes pulled in the sun&quot; The bright lights, like a string of yellow copper bells, seem to be still hanging on the 1,450-meter-long Central Street, which starts from the Songhua River Flood Control Victory Memorial Tower in the north and ends at Jingwei Street in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On some side streets, it is quieter. The light of the street lamps imprints the shadows of the leaves on the road. The aging Russians are talking about the good days that no longer exist. ... In You may think it is ugly during the day, but on a beautiful night, you put beautiful clothes on everything, and everything seems to be beautiful.&quot; The shorter streets in Jin&#39;s works form a fish-like formation with the Central Street. The bone-shaped street layout supported the &quot;enchanting&quot; appearance of this street after the completion of the China-Eastern Railway in 1903, where foreign merchants gathered and shops were dotted; especially in 1924, the Russian engineer Komut Rashok was responsible for the design and supervision of the construction. After the rectangular bread-shaped granite pavement was replaced, the bread stone road replaced the muddy dirt road. The appearance of the street was greatly changed, and it became rich and luxurious. In the 1930s, Central Street had become an architectural art gallery and an international architectural expo. Both sides of the street Most of them are Baroque, Gothic, Renaissance and other styles of buildings, creating a beautiful skyline; there are many foreign stores, dance halls and cinemas, restaurants and bars... At that time, Central Street became a place of pilgrimage for commodity fetishism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Street (today’s Central Street) is beginning to take shape&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the streets paved with square stones, the sound of Victorian carriages has long since passed into the twilight of history. Only the pieces of breadstone that have been worn away by the passing years are still shining brightly on today&#39;s pedestrian streets. Visitors tell stories about the smoky past of the long street - on summer evenings, the brilliant sunset shines slantingly on more than 70 European-style and imitation European-style buildings, and they seem to have their own unique character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Music: Soul of the North&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is also the Madiel popsicle that is essential when visiting Central Street - Matsuura 1918 West, which was renovated in the Matsuura Yoko Building. Diagonally across from the restaurant is Madiel&#39;s cold drink hall. Nowadays, &quot;Madiel&quot; can be eaten all over the country at different prices, but it is said that they are all &quot;a bit uninteresting&quot;. You still have to buy 5 yuan a piece here, which is made in the front store and in the back factory, without wrapping paper, which is the most authentic: In winter, the daily sales here start at 10,000 sticks, and sales usually explode on New Year&#39;s Day, with 30,000 to 40,000 sticks sold a day. During the peak tourist season in Harbin, &quot;Naked Madiel in the North Wind&quot; is one of the features of Central Street. Everyone wants to &quot;cool themselves down to the bottom.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After nibbling on the popsicles, you can turn around and taste the hot red cabbage soup, mandarin fish in milk and delicious canned shrimps at the Madier Western Restaurant - since the Russians started cooking pots in Tianjia in 1898 With the opening of railway canteens, Russian-style Western food began to take root in China. In the Central Street area alone, there are Tadaos and Huamei (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;former Mars There are more than 30 Western restaurants such as Western Food Tea Shop&lt;/span>;) and Madiel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The food and delicacies are endlessly memorable, especially when accompanied by music - whether in Matsuura, Huamei, or Madiel’s own Western restaurant on the first floor, Madiel can often be heard in the summer The music show on the balcony on the second floor of the hotel includes violin music, saxophone performance or bel canto solo. Artists who appeared to be from Central and Eastern Europe took turns performing hard, attracting tourists to stop and adding a lot of excitement to Central Street. It was also reminiscent of their &quot;predecessors&quot;, the foreign musicians who gathered here in the first half of the 20th century. : In 1936, singers Alexander Wilkinsky and Fedor Chaliapin came to Kazakhstan to hold a concert; in 1938, 10-year-old Helmut Stern came to China with his parents, and at the age of 14 He held a concert in Harbin and later joined the Harbin Symphony Orchestra, which was founded in 1908 and was once known as the &quot;First Symphony Orchestra in the Far East.&quot; After going to Israel in 1948, he became the chief violinist of the Berlin Philharmonic... Starting in the 1920s, Foreigners in Harbin have founded nearly 30 music schools. The strong music atmosphere that has lasted for a century has become an important cornerstone for Harbin to be awarded the title of &quot;City of Music&quot; by the United Nations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old view of Madier Hotel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Madiel Hotel Er&#39;s balcony music show is just a small note in the &quot;Music City&quot;. &quot;In the Madier Hotel, that hotel with a big stage and a luxurious hall, a play was organized between the movie screenings and a dance program was started... I happily put aside the boring rehearsals of the troupe and went to them specifically There.&quot; Dancer and poet Larisa Angell lived in China for 34 years and often performed at the Madier Hotel founded by Russian Jew Joseph Kasper in 1906. Her beautiful figure and summer Photos of Ryabin and Wilkinski, as well as tableware, lamps, electrical appliances, accessories, and promotional posters of Madier Cinema, together form the &quot;historical and cultural corridor&quot; in the hotel; during her years of activeness in Harbin , this very ancient building on Central Street is regarded as &quot;having the most luxurious ballroom and restaurant, the most modern and comfortable guest rooms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the scenery of the Madier Hotel was unparalleled, until the &quot;Casper Kidnapping Case&quot; that shocked Harbin in 1933 came to an abrupt end. On the evening of August 24 of that year, after dining at the Madier Western Restaurant, Simon, the son of Joseph Kasper Sr., was kidnapped by the Inspector General of the Kazakhstan Police Department, Martinov, and 15 gangsters; on December 3, Simon’s body was found It was discovered in Xiaoling near Harbin, causing an outcry. The following year, the sad old Joseph took his wife and children and left for France. Soon he died of illness in Paris. Madier also declined from glory to glory. Only the leather bag left by Casper in the &quot;Historical and Cultural Corridor&quot; of the hotel can be traced. Talk about being a witness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 25, 1948, representatives of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and democrats such as Shen Junru and Zhang Bojun in Kazakhstan reached an &quot;Agreement on Various Issues Concerning the Convening of a New Political Consultative Conference&quot; in the No. 1 conference room of the Madier Hotel. . At that time, the 73-year-old &quot;Heng Lao&quot; Shen Junru lived in a hotel and often went for walks along the Songhua River. He saw the rare scene of the river freezing and then thawing again, so he wrote a poem: &quot;After the river freezes, I see rushing water and snow. Even the tide is not full. The atmosphere of the earth also changes with people and events. From now on, geese from the north no longer have to go south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Dormition Church in the Cultural Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Meng Huizhong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south bank of the Songhua River at the end of Central Street is Stalin Park, a narrow and long &quot;riverside&quot;. From here you can You can enjoy the scenery of the river that is sometimes rapid and sometimes gentle, touch the soul of the northern city, and feel the carnival atmosphere of the &quot;Harbin Summer&quot; concert that has been held for more than 60 years in the summer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rivers and songs flow into the distance, deposited over hundreds of years. Harbin is like a sponge, absorbing all sounds, while those mottled old buildings become witnesses of the city&#39;s historical changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province publicly announced the verdict of the original party group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress In the case of member and deputy director Gong Jianhua accepting bribes, the defendant Gong Jianhua was sentenced to 15 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 5.5 million; the bribery income of Gong Jianhua and his The interest shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2004 to 2020, the defendant Gong Jianhua used his position as deputy secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, executive deputy mayor, leader of the Nanchang Municipal Planning Land Operation Leading Group, deputy secretary of the Yichun Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, and municipal Chairman, Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, Secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers or status, provide relevant individuals with land listing, project contracting, and project development. Provided assistance with matters such as job promotion and job promotion, and illegally received property equivalent to more than RMB 83.61 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the defendant Gong Jianhua’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes, and the amount of bribes he accepted was particularly huge. In view of the fact that Gong Jianhua truthfully confessed his crime after voluntarily surrendering to the case, and voluntarily confessed some bribery facts that were not yet known to the case-handling agency, he had the circumstances to surrender, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribery proceeds and their accruals have been sealed, detained, and frozen in the case, which is legal. , determine the circumstances of lenient punishment, and he may be punished leniently in accordance with the law. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3 nh27B3yxPJUsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, during an academic conference, Li Wei (pseudonym), a professor at the School of Physical Education of Shihezi University, casually agreed to a friend’s request for a paper name. It was a paper related to swimming. In 2021, a third-party agency discovered that the paper was suspected of being synthesized by reverse translation software and reported it to the Ministry of Education for confirmation, and the Ministry of Education fed back the situation to Shihezi University. The school launched an investigation and sent a letter to the other school, and found that Li Wei, the corresponding author, had not previously known about the existence of this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei was punished and could not participate in various project applications and evaluations for three years. During the ongoing self-examination of academic misconduct in college theses and the cleanup of false claims, Li Wei was reported again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in late May 2023, many universities have successively announced the launch of self-examination and cleanup of academic misconduct in papers, requiring self-examination and cleanup of academic papers since January 2018. Previously, on April 27, 2023, the General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a self-examination notice, requiring universities and scientific research institutes to self-examine and clean up common academic misconduct including plagiarism, plagiarism, forged peer review, ghostwriting and investment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main purpose of self-examination is to reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers and strive to curb the increase. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a self-examination operation that was not intended to be made public. Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the notice only became known to the outside world because two universities posted the notice as an attachment online. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The self-examination document is “not public &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the notices issued by each school, the main targets of this self-examination are These are all academic papers published by teachers and students of the school as the first signed unit. The focus areas of self-examination are basically the same, and they are all relatively common academic misconduct. It mainly includes six categories: plagiarism, plagiarism, and duplication of publications; forging corresponding authors, forging or manipulating peer reviews; forging, fabricating, and tampering with experimental data and pictures, using one picture for multiple purposes, and selective use; buying, selling, and ghostwriting papers; and purchasing experiments. Research data; nominal phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the notice of the Ministry of Science and Technology, universities and scientific research institutes in all provinces should carry out self-examination and clean-up work. However, according to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, only nearly 30 universities, including Shihezi University, Qinghai University, and Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, have issued this notice on their official websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice was originally a non-public document, but it became known to the outside world after two universities posted it online as an attachment to the notice. In fact, the notice documents issued by the Jiangsu and Anhui Provincial Science and Technology Departments did state &quot;This matter will not be made public&quot; at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a top-down campaign to investigate academic misconduct. Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact nearly 30 universities that publicly released the notice. Among them, Shihezi University, Qinghai University, Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University were interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, different universities have slightly different self-examination methods. However, they all adopt the method of teachers filling in forms and reporting by themselves. The content of the form mainly contains the personal information of the self-examination teacher, such as position, school, research direction, etc., as well as paper information, including paper title, DOI/PMID, publication time, publication journal, author category, academic violations, etc. The college’s statistical researchers are required to screen academic papers published within the verification period, identify academic papers with the above six conditions, put forward rectification suggestions, and form a self-examination work summary report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specific inspection methods can be roughly divided into focused spot inspections and comprehensive inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University and Yanshan University adopted a comprehensive inventory approach. A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University told Southern Weekend reporters that they had comprehensively checked 8,671 papers signed by teachers at the school within the time limit. The school organized an investigation team. The teachers first filled in the self-examination form, and then the college compiled and submitted it. Finally, the school&#39;s scientific research office reported it to the XPCC Education Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Social Sciences Office of Yanshan University said that after the announcement, the secondary college organized teachers to conduct self-examinations and submit self-examination forms and commitment letters. The college issues a self-examination report based on the self-examination situation, which is finally summarized and reported by the Social Science Office. Southern Weekend reporters contacted some colleges of the school to inquire about the implementation status. Among them, a staff member from the office of the School of Construction Engineering and Mechanics confirmed the statement of the aforementioned person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinghai University and Southwest University of Science and Technology adopt focused spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that the school&#39;s Science and Technology Office takes the lead and adopts a two-level system. First, the college&#39;s professor committee organizes self-examination, and then the school inspection office conducts random inspections. Specific to different disciplines, the degree of rigor varies. For example, due to the subject characteristics of medicine, academic misconduct is prone to occur. The school conducted a census of more than 150 papers published by teachers from the clinical medical school between January 2022 and May 2023, while other disciplines were Spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the requirements in the notice are from January 2018 to May 2023, the aforementioned teacher in charge said that Qinghai University has two inspections every year, at mid-term and at the end of the year, so this time it will be from 2022 to the present. Check the thesis again as a key point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why he adopted the method of focused spot checks was that Qinghai University’s strong disciplines are mainly agriculture and forestry. “Due to the plateau specificity, many papers do not have experiments and data, and cannot be copied from other places. Therefore, The probability of academic misconduct will be relatively small.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spot checks are conducted on a proportional basis. He gave an example, based on the total number of papers published by the college within the period, for example, 50 papers were published, and 10 papers were randomly checked, including the original data of the scientific research and whether the person named on the paper was a member of the research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology said that they mainly screen key papers, and others mainly rely on feedback and reports from school teachers and other staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Almost no problems were found&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of large-scale self-examination has little impact on This is the first time for many universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant officials from Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University stated that similar large-scale system self-examination work had not been carried out before. The person in charge of Southwest University of Science and Technology emphasized that issues such as academic misconduct and pseudonymity were previously mainly investigated and handled through reports from others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in most notices, the self-examination time left for teachers is about one month. At present, the self-examination work has basically been completed at the school level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some self-examination window periods are shorter. The Science and Technology Office of Shijiazhuang Railway University issued a notice on July 26, 2023, requiring each college to complete the self-examination and cleanup work before July 30. If problems are found, a summary form should be filled out in a timely manner and submitted to the Science and Technology Office, and remedial measures such as corrections and retractions should be taken, and &quot;no feedback after the deadline will be deemed as a paper without academic misconduct.&quot; They gave each college only four days for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the four schools interviewed, the result of the self-examination was “almost no problems.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers at Yanshan University said that the self-examination work was completed at the end of July and &quot;no problems were found&quot;, and emphasized that the relevant results have been reported to the Provincial Department of Education. Teachers from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology also said that the school has completed a preliminary screening and found no relevant violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether a self-examination report needs to be issued, a staff member from the office of the School of Architectural Engineering and Mechanics of Yanshan University said, “The school only requires us to fill in a self-examination form and issue a report if there are any problems, but our school should no problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, the teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that since inspections were organized twice a year before, no serious academic misconduct was found this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only exception is Shihezi University. They self-identified three illegal articles. The violations were improper naming, purchasing data, and repeated publication. They belonged to the School of Physical Education, School of Medicine, and School of Animal Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the improper listing and purchase data are illegal articles that have been investigated before this inspection. Although notices from the science and technology departments of many provinces stated that papers that have been investigated and dealt with may not be included in the scope of this self-examination. However, the teacher in charge of the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University believes that it &quot;still serves as a warning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to punish after investigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology stated that if problems are found during self-examination and cleanup, scientific researchers must promptly report to the unit and take remedial measures such as corrections and retractions. Those who comply with the lenient treatment circumstances specified in Article 34 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; may be given lenient treatment in accordance with the regulations; those who conceal or make false reports shall be punished in accordance with Article 3 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; Article 15 and other relevant regulations will be dealt with seriously and publicly announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University explained that the school has criticized and educated the teachers involved and required them not to apply for projects within three years. They are not allowed to be prioritized and receive talent titles, nor can they apply for science and technology projects. award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University will take lenient treatment for those who took the initiative to report in this self-examination. Zhang Xiaoqian and Li Jie of the School of Animal Science and Technology published the article &quot;The Effect of Culture Temperature on the Test Results of Streptococcus Thermophilus Inhibition Method&quot; in 2019. The teacher involved submitted papers to two journals, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; and &quot;Chinese Dairy Cow&quot;, of which &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; was the core journal. In May 2019, &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; took the lead in publishing the paper, and four months later, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; published this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discovering the duplicate publication, the author of the paper repeatedly negotiated with the person in charge of the journal &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; and asked the other party to withdraw the paper, but was rejected. It was not until July 2023 that the author of the paper negotiated with the relevant notice from the Ministry of Science and Technology, and the other party finally agreed to withdraw the paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University said that because the author of the paper took the initiative to report it and contacted the magazine several times to withdraw the paper, the handling was lenient and only criticized and educated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why self-examination? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why is there this large-scale top-down self-examination? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explanation in the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice is to consolidate the main responsibilities of each unit, reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers, strive to curb the increase, and guide scientific researchers to strengthen their awareness of scientific research integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the core of self-examination is to eliminate the stock and curb the increase. The aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology explained that for example, a scientific researcher bought an article ten years ago and either published it to apply for a professional title to make a profit, or it has never been used. If it doesn&#39;t work, I can only hold it in with all kinds of severe crackdowns now. Once it is published, it may explode one day. Either way, they will be uneasy. Self-examination and clean-up is a good opportunity, &quot;It is to give these scientific researchers who have made mistakes a chance, whether they were ignorant or lucky at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it also gives scientific researchers an opportunity to self-examine and sort out. &quot;It is always a good thing to sort it out, to enhance the awareness of integrity, to find out the family background, and to avoid the situation of being named but not knowing it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for curbing the increase, &quot;If you know that everyone is watching this matter , they will never do it again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology mentioned that since it is a self-examination, there are mitigating circumstances. &quot;If there is no profit from it, you may not even be held accountable, but criticism is definitely required.&quot; He believes that self-examination serves more of an educational and deterrent role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first time an inventory has been carried out. Southern Weekend reporters learned that this work was also carried out at the ministry level in 2022, with the purpose of letting relevant departments and local levels understand the importance that ministries attach to scientific research integrity work, but it was &quot;not made public&quot; at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the possible concealment of reports, the aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that if there are no problems during the self-examination, but problems are found in the future, and they are within the time period from 2018 to the present, then the punishment will definitely be aggravated. , &quot;This is equivalent to confronting integrity checks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you look at it over a longer period of time, behind the self-examination are the increasing number of retractions of papers and the tightening of scientific research integrity management measures in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 20, 2017, academic publishing giant Springer issued a statement stating that 107 papers published in &quot;Tumor Biology&quot; had been withdrawn due to suspected peer review fraud. The papers involved are all from China and were published between 2012 and 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Association for Science and Technology expressed its opinion at the time, hoping that Springer Publishing Group could improve the internal control mechanism as soon as possible, strengthen the management of journals, and deal with problematic papers before publication instead of withdrawing them after publication. At the same time, we are highly vigilant about &quot;predatory journals&quot; that seek financial gain and collude with &quot;third-party&quot; institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 15, 2023, Healsan Consulting LLC of the United States released the &quot;2022 SCI Paper Retraction Briefing&quot;. The briefing shows that as of December 31, 2022, a total of 41,642 SCI manuscripts have been withdrawn worldwide, including 19,421 from China. Specifically, from January 1, 2022 to December 31, 2022, there were 5,488 SCI manuscripts retracted around the world, of which 2,879 were retracted in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also an increasing emphasis on scientific research integrity. In May 2018, the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued &quot;Several Opinions on Further Strengthening the Construction of Scientific Research Integrity.&quot; The opinions emphasize the need to severely crack down on behavior that seriously violates the requirements of scientific research integrity, establish a lifelong accountability system, and investigate and deal with it at any time once discovered. This is the first time that the central government has issued a document raising the importance of scientific research integrity to a very high level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, in 2020, the Science and Technology Progress Law was revised to further clarify the relevant punitive measures for breach of trust in scientific research. In 2022, 22 departments including the Ministry of Science and Technology revised the &quot;Rules for Investigation and Handling of Scientific Research Integrity Cases (Trial)&quot;, which resulted in more specific handling rules for the investigation and handling of scientific research dishonesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, starting from 2018, the Ministry of Science and Technology has successively announced the results of investigations and treatment of untrustworthy conduct in scientific research every year. There are one batch of results from 2017 to 2019, two batches in 2020, and two batches in 2021 and 2022. Four batches were announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There will be follow-up after this round of self-examination. The aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that, in particular, problems that have not been found at all are precisely within the scope of focus. &quot;This time I came with the red seal of my unit, and there was not a single problematic article. However, if the articles are frequently withdrawn later, or problems arise during the investigation, then the unit&#39;s main responsibility will definitely not be fully implemented, and it will be seriously investigated and dealt with.&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生频频被举报，“飞刀”为何难合规？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257002]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsP srAMQWtq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Currently, consultation and multi-point practice are two ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot; The main path, but the remuneration standards of both should be consistent with the remuneration system in the main practice institutions. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the disease is not cured, should the surgery fee be refunded? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, Mr. Ma, a family member of a patient in Qixian County, Henan Province, said that his father &quot;had a bump on his face&quot; in July, so he came to Qixian Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital for treatment. The hospital informed me that a specialist from Kaifeng would perform the surgery and that a cash payment of 3,000 yuan would be required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surgery was performed by experts from outside hospitals, the surgical fee was higher than the market price, and the cash payment was all reminders that Mr. Ma&#39;s father had undergone a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery. &quot;Flying Knife&quot;, as the name suggests, &quot;hits the flying knife to open the knife&quot;. Doctors leave their hospitals to visit other places in their spare time, mostly performing surgical operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s interesting is that the patient’s condition was not good, and Mr. Ma wanted to repay the 3,000 yuan surgical fee charged by the surgeon. This was based on the “Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians’ Out-of-Home Consultation” issued by the former Ministry of Health in 2005. Regulations regarding consultation fees should be paid uniformly to the consulting medical institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident was reported by Henan Metropolis Channel, it immediately attracted attention in the industry: Should &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery exist? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some doctors believe that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery currently lacks institutional protection, brings risks to both patients and doctors, and should be banned. Some doctors also hold objections, believing that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery helps experts earn income, patients receive convenient treatment, grassroots hospitals gain technical experience, and local medical insurance funds can stay local, so it should be supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, &quot;throwing knife&quot; surgery remains in a legal gray area. Policies that can make &quot;flying knives&quot; comply have encountered many obstacles in the hospital&#39;s internal management and institutional processes. Under the huge market demand at the grassroots level, private &quot;flying knives&quot; have always existed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Income issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For doctors, the core reason for the long-lasting success of &quot;Flying Knife&quot; is &quot;increased income.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, consultation and multi-site practice are the two main ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot;, but the remuneration standards for both must be consistent with the salary system within the major practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Provisions on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; mentioned that the consultation fees involved in the consultation shall be subject to the regulations of the location of the inviting medical institution, and additional fees may be charged as appropriate on the basis of local regulations. The increase will be determined by the provincial price department in conjunction with the health administrative department at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The range of &quot;discretionary&quot; is destined not to be too high. Cheng Sheng, the department director of a secondary hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of inter-hospital consultations in Beijing is about 300 to 300 yuan. 500 yuan, &quot;Which expert is willing to waste time and energy by making such a trip?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the salary of multi-site practice, the former National Health and Family Planning Commission issued the &quot;Regulations on Promoting and Standardizing the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; in 2014. &quot;Notice of Several Opinions&quot; stipulates that the salary of multi-site practicing physicians is determined by consultation between the medical institution and the physician at the place of practice based on factors such as actual working hours, workload, and work performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the income that doctors who perform daily surgeries in our hospital can earn, a respiratory doctor in Shanghai once revealed to a Southern Weekend reporter that his remuneration for each operation is about 300 yuan. A hard-working doctor Two or three operations are performed every day, and the monthly performance bonus income is about 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Corresponding to this is the income from &quot;flying knives&quot;. Wang Gui, who works as a &quot;flying knife&quot; agency, revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery for a patient ranges from 3,000 yuan to 9,000 yuan, with the agency taking a 10% commission and the rest going to the doctor. The main factors that determine the cost are the doctor&#39;s level, the difficulty of the operation, and the distance of practice. An operation priced at 10,000 yuan may require the support of multiple doctors across provinces, and the operation lasts 7 to 8 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Agents tend to stratify experts. Top experts are generally subject leaders, master&#39;s and doctoral tutors, and department directors of top hospitals in their cities. These doctors are the first choice for foreign aid in large hospitals in provincial capital cities. The seniority and popularity of ordinary experts are low, and the general location of &quot;flying knife&quot; is county-level hospitals. “There are quite a lot of surgeons in general surgery, ophthalmology, gastroenterology, hepatobiliary surgery, thoracic surgery, and orthopedics,” Wang Gui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without an intermediary like Wang Gui, &quot;throwing knives&quot; mostly occur between doctors who have personal relationships. Most of the inviting doctors come from district and county hospitals, or have studied in the expert&#39;s department, or have studied under the same discipline. &quot;Both parties must know the basics.&quot; said Cheng Lei, director of thoracic surgery at a tertiary hospital in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, regardless of the form, compared with the above-mentioned &quot;Regulations&quot; and &quot;Notice&quot;, &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Formalization efforts have never stopped&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of some doctors, in addition to economic benefits, &quot;Flying Knife&quot; can also showcase their skills and improve &quot; Jianghu status&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Lei told Southern Weekend reporters that he once went to overseas hospitals to demonstrate technology under the organization of a surgical instrument manufacturer, helping a tumor ablation surgery to be implemented nationwide. “It’s more like a flying knife than a flying knife. It’s about teaching.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even as the chief physician of thoracic surgery, Cheng Lei has to ask for help from colleagues who can handle difficult surgeries. Cheng Lei&#39;s father was diagnosed with aortic dissection in a hospital in Jiangsu and suspected aortic aneurysm. The local hospital did not have the conditions for surgery, and it was hundreds of kilometers away from Shanghai for treatment. Once the tumor ruptured on the way, it would be life-threatening. Finally, Doctor &quot;Flying Knife&quot; solved the urgent problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, given the reality of uneven distribution of medical resources, governments at all levels have never stopped trying to bring &quot;flying knives&quot; onto the formal track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; proposed an inter-hospital consultation system, and the 2009 &quot;Notice of the Ministry of Health on Issues Concerning the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; responded to the concerns from all walks of life about allowing multiple sites. The call to practice. Since 2020, the construction of medical consortia has accelerated, and the consultation, training, and referral systems of hospitals within the same medical consortium have become increasingly mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be understood that if an expert wants to perform surgery in the same hospital for a long time, he will usually apply for a multi-site practice registration. If it is a one-time operation, a consultation method will be used.” Senior Jingheng Law Firm Partner Zhang Li, who has been a doctor for six years, explained this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the multi-site practice system, there was a restrictive rule that &quot;a doctor is not allowed to practice in more than three medical institutions.&quot; However, the &quot;Physician Practice Registration Management Measures&quot; promulgated in 2017 allowed doctors to Practice in multiple locations across provinces. It also stipulates that doctors who practice in multiple locations within the same provincial administrative region of their main practice institution only need to register with these practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change from a registration system to a filing system means that doctors can practice at multiple locations without permission from the main practice institution and the local health department. With the support of such policies, a set of data released by the National Health Commission in October 2020 showed that the number of multi-site practicing doctors in the country has reached 260,000, four times that of 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Hospitals don’t want to see their doctors flying around”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are still many obstacles to the promotion of multi-site practice, which also provides “ Throwing knives&quot; creates the soil of reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees mentioned soft discipline in hospitals. The Southern Weekend reporter obtained the &quot;Multi-site Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; implemented by a well-known hospital in Southwest China, which requires doctors to complete the multi-site practice registration, but also to register with the local health bureau and submit it to the hospital. Photo, physician qualification certificate, practicing physician license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cumbersome in-hospital approval process is not an isolated case. According to public reports from the self-media &quot;Seeing Medical Circle&quot;, in 2020, the &quot;Measures for the Management of Multi-site Practice of Physicians (Trial)&quot; issued by Changsha First Hospital stipulates that doctors who practice multi-site must have intermediate professional titles or above, and their departments must be above. The department&#39;s year-end KPI assessment results for the first year rank above the average level, etc. The document also states that non-commandatory activities in medical institutions outside the hospital must be approved by the department director, reported to the medical department and the leader of the hospital in charge, and can only be registered after approval by the hospital office meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Multiple Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; of the above-mentioned Southwest Regional Hospital requires that multi-site practicing physicians should sign a labor agreement with the multi-site practice institution on the practice category, scope of practice, employment period, work tasks, Medical responsibilities, time arrangements, assessment methods, salary, insurance benefits, etc. are clarified, and the agreement is filed with the Medical Department of our hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pang Liang, a surgeon at a private hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that some hospitals have banned doctors from practicing outside their homes. One of the reasons is that they are worried that patients will be diverted to other hospitals, which will affect their income. Xie Rushi, honorary president of the Shenzhen Non-Public Medical Institutions Association, analyzed from a purely managerial psychological perspective, &quot;Hospitals don&#39;t want to see their doctors flying around. This is normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Flying knives&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Controversies continue, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The people will not hold the officials accountable&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Flying knife&quot; surgeries performed without permission may be classified as illegal medical practice and subject to severe punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the technical appraisal of medical malpractice determines that it constitutes a medical malpractice and bears the main responsibility, at the administrative level, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be suspended from practicing or even have his physician&#39;s practicing certificate revoked; if he violates criminal law, the doctor may also Prosecuted on suspicion of medical malpractice. If the medical malpractice is of equal liability and below, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be held administratively liable. As for the civil compensation part, the law stipulates that the subject of compensation is medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a large extent, disputes related to &quot;throwing knives&quot; still belong to the category of &quot;people do not complain and officials do not investigate&quot;, and the patient&#39;s will has a great influence on the development of the case. In one case that Zhang Li represented, when a &quot;flying knife&quot; expert performed a chest nodule operation, the patient suffered from massive bleeding and &quot;could not get off the operating table.&quot;事后医生上门道歉，家属也认为国家培养一个医生不容易，选择放弃行政投诉及刑事举报，所以“飞刀”医生没有涉及行政与刑事处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在另一起案件中，医生进行一场胸部整形手术，患者术中同样出现大出血，康复之后告到了专家所在医院的卫生主管部门。最后专家被行政撤职、调离工作岗位、被罚暂停执业三个月。这是章李所接触过的处罚结果最严重的一起“飞刀”案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使不发生医疗事故，医生也可能被病人“闹”。一个广为人知的例子是，2019年，一山西患者请到了北京天坛医院医生对其进行神经外科支架植入手术。据中国青年报报道，事后患者家属在支付1万元现金“飞刀”费用时，偷偷录像并举报，导致涉事医生和该医院帮忙收钱转交的医生均被停职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个隐忧是，“飞刀”医生开完刀后拂袖离去，将术后护理留给基层医院，但后者可能缺乏相关知识，对病人福祉构成隐患。庞梁提到了2019年的一起医疗事故：一位男性患者在某医院进行了胃减容手术，由一位参加学术交流的外地医生执刀。术后5天，患者猝然离世。尸检报告显示，患者在术后继发胃漏、急性化脓性腹膜炎、腹腔脓血性积液，导致感染中毒性休克、多脏器功能衰竭而死亡。这可能是当地医院缺乏合适的术后护理的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“病人觉得效果没到预期，要退钱，不退钱我就告你，一告一个准。”程磊表示，“飞刀”手术的灰色属性是医生们的天然软肋，高额的费用是上不得台面的。遇到纠纷，发出“飞刀”邀约的基层医院大多不会去找专家的麻烦，而是默默出钱“把事平了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;合法合规难题待解&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看似很美好的“飞刀”，仍未走出不合规的本质，这意味着身处其中的患者、医生的抗风险能力都极其脆弱。比如，一些医院会给医生投保医疗事故责任险，帮助减少发生事故后的经济损失，但未经备案的“飞刀”手术显然不在理赔范畴内。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生们也逐渐摸索出一种“半合规”的院外会诊操作路径。出诊前先让基层医院出具邀请函，在自己院内完成备案。会诊完成后，再在正常收入的基础上加收一笔钱。后者不计入财务流程，也不会由病人直接付给专家，而是经由邀请方医院转手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前日常中都是这么干的，需要有一定的补充收益这样才有人愿意去会诊。”谢汝石告诉南方周末记者，如此一来，“飞刀”行为本身是合规报备过的，属于合法的医疗行为，但收入的部分属于红包，仍然见不得光，可能面临院内纪检部门的查处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于自我保护，医生们也会筛选“飞刀”病例，避免参与风险太高的“飞刀”手术。王贵表示，患者提出请院外专家执刀的要求后，管床医生会评估该患者家属是否“比较敏感”，容易挑刺，经济条件是否宽裕等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在庞梁的设想中，为了让“飞刀”收入走到阳光下，大医院应该建立一个公开的专家库，按照科室、级别对每位专家明码标价，供患者和基层医院选择。这一价格可以与日常执业的薪酬拉开差距。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是让“飞刀”真正获得名分。王贵所在的机构具备齐全的诊疗营业资质，控股民营医院。专家均在这家医院注册多点执业，再由该医院派遣出去提供咨询服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在章李看来，如此一来医生便能绕开公立属性的主执业地医疗机构，合法地进行外出会诊。在一篇教医生如何合法“飞刀”的文章中，他将这个做法称为“远程导弹”，而“洲际导弹”则是创建或加入医生集团、诊所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生集团主要是对接会诊供需双方，派遣集团医生前往基层医院提供服务。但医生集团不属于医疗机构，医生仍隶属于一个主执业医疗机构——或为医生的老东家，或为医生集团内的民营医院。本质上，医生集团只是中介平台，医生走的仍是多点执业或会诊道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾参与创办多个医生集团的谢汝石表示，医生集团可以与患者或派遣地医院签订告知协议，确定“飞刀”手术的价格，并且以医生集团名义收费。如此操作，使得处于灰色地带的“飞刀”费用合规。不过，医生集团面临的问题是，通过招投标形式与派遣地医院达成合作关系十分困难，而和患者一个个单独洽谈合作又不能形成商业模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使资质齐全，王贵所在的机构依然十分谨慎。他们对外宣称的商业模式是提供医生的咨询服务，包含术前评估、术后康复方案制定等，但不包含手术执刀。 “实际上是会执刀的，但不能这么说，因为没有文件允许我们这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中程磊、王贵、庞梁是化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新冠疫苗：每年秋天来一针？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些国家，新冠疫苗可能要像流感一样每年推荐接种了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日，美国疾病预防控制中心（CDC）发布建议，六个月以上的所有人都应该在今年秋冬季注射一针新版新冠疫苗。几天前，美国食品药品监督管理局（FDA）批准了莫德纳（Moderna）和辉瑞（Pfizer）的两种新版疫苗，新版疫苗针对的是名为XBB.1.5的奥密克戎病毒变体，这一毒株在全世界大部分国家广泛传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接种疫苗依然是预防新冠病毒住院和死亡的最佳措施。疫苗还可以减少长期的新冠影响。根据CDC发布的建议，近两个月没有接种过新冠疫苗的人，都可以接种这一新版疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们拥有了更多的工具来预防新冠病毒带来的严重后果。”美国CDC主任、医学博士、公共卫生硕士曼迪•科恩（Mandy Cohen）表示。发布这一建议的原因在于，新冠病毒仍在不断变异，新的亚型接连出现，而疫苗的保护作用随着时间急剧下降，接种新版疫苗能更好地保护大众健康。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CDC的独立咨询委员会以13∶1高票同意建议普遍接种这一疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赞成者之一、美国埃默里大学医学院副教授桑德拉·弗莱霍夫(Sandra Fryhoffer) 博士认为，新冠重症可能发生在所有年龄段包括没有基础疾病的人身上，加上很多人此前没有接种加强针，意味着对新冠病毒的整体免疫力都在下降，因此应该推荐全部人接种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;普通人打还是不打&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;鼓励接种新冠疫苗已逾三年，但疫苗策略正在悄然发生改变，大部分国家没有像美国一样，推荐所有人接种加强针。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，英国政府宣布，新版加强针免费提供的对象是65岁以上的老年人及一线医务人员和脆弱群体。法国不建议非脆弱群体接种加强针。德国压根没有秋季加强针计划，尽管它之前建议高危人群应该每年接种一剂新冠疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员普遍认为，由于新冠疫苗的主要作用是预防重症而非感染，因此高危人群接种受益最大。而低风险人群和未成年人要不要再接种，科学界仍存在争议。 “对于老年人、有基础疾病和免疫缺陷的人群接种加强针非常有意义。”约翰斯·霍普金斯大学健康安全中心传染病专家艾米什·阿戴尔贾（Amesh Adalja）表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;新冠病毒蔓延三年多来，不少人对病毒的感染逐渐麻木，选择接种疫苗的人数也逐渐下降。但事实上，无论在美国或是中国，反复感染新冠的人不在少数。美国CDC科学家报告称，自7 月中旬以来，因新冠住院的人数一直在增加，虽然其中大多数为幼儿和老年人，但住院的五岁以下儿童中有一半没有潜在的健康问题，这提醒人们即使其他方面健康的人也可能有罹患新冠重症的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在即将到来的秋冬病毒流行季，流感病毒、呼吸道合胞病毒和新冠病毒很可能交叉感染，这会对脆弱人群造成比较严重的后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;在冬季来临前做准备&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在我国，整体疫情处于局部零星散发状态，但新冠病毒并未消失，病毒在人群中的传播现象仍持续存在，身边不乏有人几个月前才经历“二阳”，现在又遭遇“三阳”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基于新冠的传染性极强，得过新冠后抗体自然衰减及没有绝对的保护性新冠疫苗，基本上多数人每年会感染1-3次。”深圳市第三人民医院院长卢洪洲教授解释，“对于免疫功能正常的人群，不会造成特别大的影响。”但对于高龄、糖尿病、肿瘤基础病等免疫功能低下人群，卢洪洲建议每年定期接种新冠疫苗。接种疫苗的策略，可以包括鼻喷疫苗和皮下注射疫苗联合免疫、多价新冠组合疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月25日，国务院联防联控机制综合组印发的《近期重点人群新冠病毒疫苗接种工作方案》提出，对老年人等重点人群实施针对性新冠病毒疫苗接种。明确在新冠病毒XBB变异株流行期间，重点是今年秋冬季，优先推荐接种含XBB变异株抗原成分的疫苗。专家呼吁已感染且未完成基础免疫的人群，应该在感染3个月后接种1剂次疫苗，这将有利于在后续可能发生的疫情中为重症、死亡高风险人群提供更好的保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有专家预计，9月开学后新冠病毒感染人数会增加。按照免疫力周期推测，下一波新冠流行可能出现在今秋11月左右。而此时也正逢流感季，新冠叠加流感，可能导致呼吸道感染相关重症增加，因此建议同时接种流感疫苗和新冠疫苗，这也是世卫组织的推荐——两种疫苗叠加可以最大限度地预防重症和减轻病毒交叉感染带来的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“住院和死亡人数增加表明，冠状病毒病将会长期存在，世界仍然需要预防、检测和治疗新冠的工具。”世卫组织总干事谭德塞博士在2023年9月6日的媒体通报会上强调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>