<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[不清楚孩子上了什么学，回家陪读三年仅是一次情感弥补？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259687]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Downstairs where I work, there is a circle of shops, including restaurants, small supermarkets, fruit and vegetable shops, and morning stalls. The shop... is surrounded by an industrial park, and there is only one commercial place around. It is very lively here during meals and commuting, and these shops are running well. I have been working here since the building was built, and most of these shops have been operating here since the beginning, so I know many of the merchants and often chat with them while shopping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years ago, the proprietress of the Shaxian snack bar downstairs returned to Fujian to accompany her children in high school. Recently, I saw her when I was eating at a snack bar in Shaxian County, and asked, &quot;Are you back from studying with me?&quot; She said, &quot;Back!&quot; I asked again, &quot;Which university did your child go to after the college entrance examination?&quot; She scratched her head and answered. : &quot;I don&#39;t know!&quot; I asked: &quot;You have been studying with your child for three years, and you have achieved results after three years. You don&#39;t know what your results are?&quot; She still shook her head and said, &quot;I really don&#39;t know...anyway ...It seems to be from our side...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, I went to the small supermarket nearby to buy something. The small supermarket was run by a couple, they were from Anhui, and the male owner I am explaining to the hostess, don’t forget to transfer living expenses to the child. I asked, &quot;Is your child going to college?&quot; They nodded and said they just went to college this year. I continued to ask: &quot;Which university does the child go to?&quot; The male host lowered his head and thought for a moment, and said, &quot;I can&#39;t remember either.&quot; I looked at the hostess, and she said, &quot;Don&#39;t ask me, I can&#39;t either.&quot; I know...&quot; the male host interjected, &quot;He said he was in Chengdu... studying design... or something else...&quot; I couldn&#39;t help but be dumbfounded and joked: &quot;You two don&#39;t know what&#39;s important! You two only know how to transfer it to your children. Living expenses!&quot; They both looked at each other, not understanding what I was laughing at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, most couples or one spouse works outside the home and the children study in their hometown. If one spouse works outside the home, the life of the spouse at home will focus on the child&#39;s studies and spend time accompanying them to school. Both husband and wife work outside the home, and many people choose to go back to study with their children at some important stages and moments, such as the third year of junior high school, the third year of high school, etc. This is all in the hope that by accompanying them to study, they can help their children learn so that they can get into the ideal school. However, when I heard that the proprietress of a snack bar in Shaxian County accompanied her child to high school for three years and did not know what university the child finally went to, I thought that the effectiveness of accompanying him to study is questionable. It should be about the same whether he studies with him or not. , the three years of accompanying her were probably just an emotional make-up. When I heard that the couple in the small supermarket did not know the school and major their children were studying in, I was thinking that this seemed to be someone else’s business. The essence of university education is to pay for living expenses with your head covered. It is an education that is at a loss. invest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before yesterday, I called a water station downstairs and asked the store to send me a bucket of bottled water. The store responded that it could not be delivered, and there was no one in the store. The child was about to enter high school, and the wife went home to study with the child. If she wanted water, she would bring it herself. Originally, I could call another water station to have water delivered, but after the previous two experiences and my thinking, I immediately decided to go downstairs to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the water station and asked the shopkeeper: &quot;Why does your wife want to go home to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Then everyone is accompanying you, so it&#39;s impossible for us not to accompany you!&quot; the shopkeeper replied . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do when I go back to study with me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What else can I do, cook, wash clothes, supervise my children not to play with mobile phones...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Like this Is it interesting to study with you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shop owner chuckled: &quot;We don&#39;t know about that... They say it&#39;s difficult to take the high school entrance examination now... I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t be able to pass...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not an educator myself , but I think there are some basic intellectual things that should be similar. I said to the shopkeeper, take the notes and I will tell you what time it is. I told him with my fingers: 1. Clarify your child&#39;s learning goals, which can be specific to which school he wants to attend, and understand the school&#39;s enrollment plan, enrollment requirements, and performance requirements. requirements and performance requirements as the program; 2. Maintain close contact with school teachers, understand the school’s learning progress and children’s learning situation, and solve possible learning problems in a timely manner. The basic problems should be grasped and the difficult problems should be overcome. ; 3. Your spouse should establish a good work and rest system, and supervise the child to balance work and rest during the learning process. When it is time to study and when it is time to rest, if you want the child not to play with mobile phones, first of all, she must not play with the mobile phone while the child is studying; 4. Don&#39;t use your emotional compensation as a moral standard to ask your children. Encourage your children to learn, but you must also respect your children&#39;s willingness to learn. 5. Caring for your children is long-term. It does not end when you enter high school in the future. Children are independent. However, your child&#39;s study and life are not independent. They are an expression of your family&#39;s common wishes and are closely related to your daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I finished speaking, and the shopkeeper also finished memorizing it, but he blinked, not knowing whether he understood or not. I told him that we would continue the discussion the next time I came to carry water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading to your children is not just about doing laundry and cooking, nor is it as easy a job as sitting aside and playing with your mobile phone while asking your children to do homework and answer mock tests. What is the goal, what are the plans to achieve the goal, how to correct errors in the process of implementing the plan, how to achieve long-term emotional interaction after the plan is realized, how to make up for the failure of the plan, etc. These issues should be considered by the accompanying parents. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a fruit and vegetable shop downstairs. The proprietress of the fruit and vegetable shop also came back from school soon. I asked her: &quot;How did my child do in the exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She replied: &quot;I passed the exam. But the school is not very good, and the child has to repeat the year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked: &quot;Will you no longer accompany me during the repeat year?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said: &quot;I won&#39;t accompany you anymore. , I’ve had enough company, it’s up to him how he does in the next year’s exam, let him go!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s dinner time, people in the industrial park and people upstairs all come upstairs It&#39;s time to eat and consume, and the merchants are busy again. Looking at them being busy, I think about the children behind them who are still studying. I don’t know which universities, high schools or other places of study those children are in. I just hope that they will be healthy in body and mind and make progress every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a practitioner in Shanghai fruit industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦直播间卖假和田玉？谈谈玉的文化、国标及科学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After online anchor Li Jiaqi was accused by JD.com’s purchasing staff of forcing him to “choose one from two” and questioned the alleged monopoly, he went on a professional crackdown on counterfeiting Wang Hai also questioned whether the Hetian jade sold in Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast room was fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jade is a unique culture in China. The Chinese ancestors selected the &quot;beautiful stones&quot; from various stones. Jade is warm, shiny, meticulous and tough, so it is also considered by the Chinese to be benevolent and benevolent. Justice, wisdom, courage, and purity are the five moral qualities. Wearing jade has the effect of preventing evil spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese ancestors’ understanding of jade can be traced back to the Neolithic Age. Humans ground stone tools as tools for chopping and scraping, hunting, and cutting meat. Some ground stone tools showed a smooth and beautiful appearance, and humans began to have a preliminary understanding of jade. This also marks the beginning of the transition of human beings from material needs to spiritual needs. Archaeological research has found that in the late Neolithic Age, many jade products and jade ornaments appeared. At this time, the ancients had realized that jade and stone had completely different functions and aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 3000 BC, jade craftsmanship was separated from stone tool processing technology and became an independent craft category. Based on the production traces left on the jades unearthed from the Hongshan Cultural Site and the Liangzhu Cultural Site, experts have inferred that a rotating jade processing tool - a weight machine - had appeared at that time. This is no different in principle from the jade processing machines we see now. The Shang and Zhou dynasties were the growth stage of Chinese jade art. The scope of use of jade expanded, and the number and types increased significantly. However, the shapes were still very simple, with only sporadic decorations. Hotan jade also appeared in this era for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period, the art of jade carving developed. At that time, scholar-bureaucrats wore a series of jade ornaments all over their bodies. What reflected the spirit of the times at that time were a large number of jade pendants in the shapes of dragons, phoenixes and tigers, with complex and beautiful shapes and strong Chinese style and national characteristics. The jade pieces of the Tang Dynasty are all treasures. The craftsmanship was further developed and refined. The texture is warm and the luster is soft. Gold and jade complement each other, making them rich and elegant. In the Song Dynasty, jade gradually entered people&#39;s lives. Influenced by calligraphy and painting at that time, the style became more realistic and full of life. During the Ming and Qing Dynasties, jade art reached its peak, and various types of exquisite jade articles emerged in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The definition of real jade and non-real jade has long been reflected in the system of jade use in Chinese history. Hotan jade is the highest level of jade, it is real jade, and is used by emperors. After countless years, Hotan jade has just entered the folk world. The one that caused the controversy this time was Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing Wang Hai’s doubts, Yuanyang Jinlou, the owner of the cargo in Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, posted the appraisal certificates, including the National Jewelry and Jade Quality Supervision and Inspection Center (NGTC), Guangdong Gold and Silver Jewelry Testing Center Co., Ltd., National Gold and Silver Products Quality Inspection and Testing Center (Nanjing) Organization, Shenzhen Zhongdi Jewelry Testing Co., Ltd. These institutions are not without authority. So, what is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the question of whether it is fake. According to Wang Hai, GB/T38821-2020 stipulates that the appraisal certificate must have total mass and physical photos, and consumers received 18 appraisal certificates attached to the necklace. Not only are each 40g, but they are also photos of a shared necklace. , then it is suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the problem of counterfeiting is easy to solve, but what is difficult to solve is the second level problem, which is the standard issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standards used by these institutions are the national Hetian jade testing standards GB/T16552-2017 and GB/T16553-2017. This 2017 standard does not clearly stipulate the specific content of tremolite. As long as the main component is tremolite, it can be named &quot;Hetian Jade&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hai adopts another standard, namely GB/T 38831-2020. The GB/T38821-2020 &quot;Hetian Jade Identification and Classification&quot; launched in 2020 was developed by the State Administration for Market Regulation and China Released by the National Standardization Administration Committee, it is the latest national standard for the Hetian jade industry. The mineral composition of Hetian jade is described as: &quot;Mainly composed of tremolite, the secondary mineral can be actinolite, and can contain a small amount of calcite, diopside, pyrite, pyrite, chromite, and magnetite. , quartz, serpentine, chlorite, epidote, wollastonite, apatite and garnet, etc.&quot; According to this standard, the naming rule is: when the percentage of other minerals in the same piece of jade is less than 5%, Hetian jade can be named directly. When the percentage of other minerals is more than 5% (except black jade), if the other minerals contained are evenly distributed and the boundaries of the mineral particles are clear, use &quot;tremolite jade&quot; with a note indicating that it contains other minerals. For example: tremolite jade (including tremolite jade) carbonates). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, things are clear. Both standards are used in the industry. The 2017 standard is more relaxed, while the 2020 standard is more stringent. However, this standard is not mandatory and is only a recommended standard. Jade sellers adopted the loose standards introduced in 2017, saying that their items were Hetian jade; while Wang Hai, who fights against counterfeiters, adopted a stricter standard in 2020, saying that the jade sold by Li Jiaqi was fake and did not meet the standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, jade has been difficult to identify clearly since ancient times. What exactly is jade? In fact, many people don&#39;t understand. When we talk about what a thing is, it is actually a chemical question. Chemistry is the study of the composition of matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a chemical perspective, jade is actually a mixture. When we talk about gold, we refer to the material composed of gold atoms; when we talk about quartz, we refer to silicon dioxide; when we talk about ice, we refer to dihydrogen monoxide. Of course, minerals are mixed with other impurities, but in an abstract sense, these things are composed of single atoms or single compound molecules. But jade, in an abstract sense, is a mixture. For example, just like when we talk about Chinese medicinal soup and borscht soup, even in an abstract sense, it must be a mixture of multiple ingredients. Therefore, jade is a mixture, which is a mixture of two or more compounds and elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this concept, it is easier to understand jade. Jade has different chemical compositions, different colors, and different types. The chemical composition of jadeite is sodium aluminum silicate, the most representative of which is jadeite. The chemical composition of nephrite is hydrous calcium magnesium silicate, the most representative of which is Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Hetian jade has four main mineral components: silicon, aluminum, iron and magnesium. Silicon accounts for a large proportion of Hetian jade, and its main forms are calcium silicate (CaSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), magnesium silicate (MgSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), and sodium disilicate (Na&lt; sub>;2&lt;/sub>;Si&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;5&lt;/sub>;), etc.; the aluminum element is mainly albite (NaAlSi&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>; 8&lt;/sub>;), and also contains a small amount of aluminum silicate; iron mainly exists in the form of potassium ferroaluminate and iron silicate. It can be seen that Hetian jade has many ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charm of jade, its appeal to people in terms of look and feel, stems from this characteristic of jade&#39;s chemical composition. This has also caused various confusions in the naming, identification, and even price of jade. Some people say that the wholesale price of jade sold by Li Jiaqi is only a few dozen yuan. But then again, the wholesale price of tens of thousands of jade in those tourist attractions and jewelry stores may only be a few hundred yuan or less. This is the characteristic of the jade industry. As the old saying goes, &quot;Gold has a price, jade is priceless.&quot; This does not mean that gold is not as valuable as jade, and jade is a priceless treasure. It means that the price of jade has been confusing and confusing since ancient times, and the profits are often abnormally high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room is said to have the lowest price on the entire Internet. Consumers believe it, but there is a gap between their expectations and reality. In fact, if you really want to buy cost-effective jade, the live broadcast room is not a good place. Only knowledgeable people with instruments can identify, and only with the ability to identify can we negotiate a good price. Obviously, most consumers cannot do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[过度加工食物可能成瘾并严重影响健康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCyJ69RpVgzEp0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCy J69RpVgzEp0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over-processing of food refers to industrial production and the addition of at least 5 or more ingredients, additives (usually sugar, stabilizers, preservatives, preservatives, pigments), etc., in this way Processed foods are called ultra-processed foods. Their purpose is to make them delicious and convenient, and more importantly, manufacturers can earn higher profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessively processed foods include soft drinks such as cola, bread, cakes, potato chips, pizza, biscuits, candies, burgers, instant noodles, ice cream, spicy sticks, etc. More and more research results show that the intake of overly processed foods may be harmful to human health and increase the risk of various diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recent study by Brazilian researchers suggests that overly processed foods may harm brain function. The reason is that overly processed foods contain many added and unhealthy ingredients such as sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors and preservatives. Past research has shown that overly processed foods are directly linked to an increased risk of heart disease, metabolic syndrome, and obesity, and now research is linking overly processed foods to a risk of decreased brain function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers collected data on nearly 11,000 men and women in Brazil with an average age of 52 who participated in the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health. The researchers followed them for a long time, with a median follow-up time of 8 years. The results found that participants who consumed more than 20% of their daily calories from ultra-processed foods experienced a 28% faster decline in overall cognitive function and a 25% faster decline in executive function compared to adults over 59 years old. In other words, the decline in cognitive function and executive function is more obvious among adults aged 35-59. Overall, overall cognitive functions include learning ability and memory, while executive functions include language fluency and behavioral agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the researchers admit that they cannot yet explain the mechanism by which excessively processed foods lead to reduced brain function, and there is no neuroimaging to confirm their results. Therefore, future research is to explore which overly processed foods lead to cognitive decline in the body and the molecular mechanisms behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation, however, is that when people regularly consume overly processed foods, they are less likely to get the fiber, microbes, minerals, and plants they need to stay healthy, fight off disease, and reduce inflammation. Nutrients. Ultimately, this may affect a person&#39;s brain function and functioning, as the brain requires a steady supply of these nutrients to function properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed foods have also been linked to cancer. Researchers from Imperial College London have found that high intakes of ultra-processed foods may increase an individual&#39;s risk of developing cancer and dying from cancer. Previously, a large number of studies have revealed that consuming large amounts of overly processed food will increase the incidence of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Now, British researchers have used the British Biobank to collect dietary information from 200,000 young people to study the relationship between body health and diet. This is the first such study to be conducted in the UK. The researchers monitored the people&#39;s health for 10 years, analyzing their risk of developing any cancer and 34 types of cancer, as well as the participants&#39; risk of dying from cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers conducted the most comprehensive assessment to date of the link between overly processed foods and people’s risk of developing cancer, including soda, industrially produced bread, and more. Ready-to-eat meals and most breakfast cereals. These foods often contain high levels of salt, sugar, fat, and artificial additives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that people who eat a lot of overly processed foods are at a greater risk of developing cancer. Overly processed foods are particularly related to ovarian cancer and brain cancer. They also increase an individual&#39;s risk of death from cancer, most obviously. of ovarian and breast cancer. For every 10% increase in a person&#39;s intake of overly processed foods in a person&#39;s diet, the overall risk of cancer increases by 2%, and the risk of ovarian cancer in particular increases by 19%. It is associated with a 6% increase in overall cancer mortality, a 16% increase in the risk of death from breast cancer, and a 30% increase in the risk of death from ovarian cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The association between excessively processed food intake and cancer remained after adjusting for social, economic, behavioral and dietary factors such as smoking, physical activity and body mass index (BMI). Furthermore, previous research has shown that British adults and children consume the highest amounts of ultra-processed food in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the study by British researchers cannot explain the causal relationship and mechanism between over-processed foods and cancer, they believe that existing research evidence shows that reducing the intake of over-processed foods in the daily diet may avoid Higher cancer rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed food has become widespread around the world and is addictive. A research report published in the British Medical Journal on October 9, 2023 by researchers from the United States, Brazil, and Spain pointed out that an analysis of 281 studies in 36 different countries found that 14% of adults and adults worldwide 12% of children are addicted to over-processed foods, and 1/7 adults and 1/8 children may be addicted to over-processed foods. These foods include ice cream, carbonated drinks and convenience foods, which can lead to cancer, obesity and Increased risk of heart disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the consumption of ultra-processed foods is soaring around the world, and now more than half of the daily energy intake in the UK comes from ultra-processed foods. In the United States, ultra-processed foods account for 58% of Americans’ energy intake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that so many people eat over-processed foods suggests that they are addictive. Researchers explain the addiction to over-processed foods as higher levels of dopamine secretion may lead to over-processed foods. of addiction. Extracellular dopamine levels in the brain&#39;s striatum caused by refined carbohydrates or fats are similar to those of addictive substances such as nicotine and alcohol, thus creating a craving similar to alcoholism. Therefore, foods that contain high amounts of refined carbohydrates or added fats are likely to be addictive substances. The speed at which these overly processed foods deliver carbohydrates and fats to the intestines may also play a role in their addictive nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Symptoms of addiction to over-processed foods include: strong desire to eat, withdrawal symptoms, difficulty controlling food intake, and obesity, overeating, poor physical and mental health, and reduced quality of life. Despite this, he continued to eat without restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of this suggests that the relationship between overly processed foods and health, as well as the addictive nature of such foods, should be further studied, and appropriate measures should be taken to protect people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京香山论坛：大国小国，平等对话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 10:06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Ten&#39; means maturity, perfection, harvest, and also indicates a new starting point and renewal. Let’s go.” On the morning of October 30, 2023, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, told officials from the defense departments of many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held from October 29th to 31st, reaching the highest level and largest scale in history - more than 90 official delegations from countries and international organizations participated, including 19 defense ministers , 14 military commander-level representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the podium at the opening ceremony, the &quot;ten&quot; in &quot;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum&quot; was painted in red. In the audience, foreign defense ministers, representatives of international institutions and experts are looking forward to an &quot;international security event&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/01/7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01 /7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256571&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Great powers play a more important role”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nine o’clock in the morning on October 30, the main venue on the second floor of the Beijing International Convention Center was packed with seats. Dozens of defense ministers and senior representatives from various countries in military uniforms sat in the front row of the auditorium; the back row was divided into two floors and filled with nearly a thousand experts, observers or media members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot; is marked with white letters on a blue background inside and outside the venue - this is the theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum and the core idea of ​​the Global Security Initiative in February 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Youxia pointed out that without mutual respect, it will be difficult to coexist peacefully, and common security will be out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 19 defense ministers participating in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu was the first speaker. Before the opening ceremony, Shaoyigu and Zhang Youxia walked into the main venue side by side and sat in the center of the first row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Russia-China relations are exemplary and are increasingly attractive to other countries.” Shoigu mentioned, “The circle of friends between Russia and China who do not want to be involved in the Western confrontation agenda is constantly expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a country involved in the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Shoigu’s attendance attracted much attention. He mentioned that after Russia countered NATO&#39;s eastward expansion, the United States was using Ukraine to attack Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Russia will only use nuclear weapons when it is attacked by a nuclear attack or when its national survival is threatened.&quot; Shoigu said in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the second time that Shaoyigu has attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The last time was in 2019. After the meeting, Zhang Youxia held talks with Shaoyigu at the Bayi Building in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/c2f75269a6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/c2f75269a6.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256572&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speeches of the guests at the first plenary session all closely followed the theme of &quot;Responsibility of Major Powers and Global Security Cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is important to strive for peace. In promoting global peace and security, major powers play a more important role.&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong said in the second half of the first half that major powers promote peace and make war a Obsolete things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“From Asia-Pacific to the Global”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening ceremony, defense ministers and representatives from various countries arrived in Beijing one after another. As the organizer, Zhao Xiaozhuo, deputy director of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum Secretariat, is extremely busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 21:00 on the evening of October 29, when Southern Weekend reporters met Zhao Xiaozhuo, he had just finished the welcome dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the first forum, Zhao Xiaozhuo still has fresh memories. &quot;At that time, most of the participants were scholars, and the total number of participants was only a few dozen, so it was very small.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Xiangshan Forum was founded in 2006 and is hosted by two think tanks from the Chinese military, the China Society of Military Science and the China Society for International Strategic Studies. In 2014, the forum was upgraded from track two (private) to track one and a half (semi-official, semi-private). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since then, military and political leaders and national leaders will appear every year, and the conference has been adjusted from once every two years to once a year.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to online meetings during the epidemic, the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum attracted official delegations from more than 90 countries and international organizations including Russia, the United States, Saudi Arabia, and Iran, with more than 1,800 participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 9 forums, there have been as many as 6 forums with the theme of &quot;Asia-Pacific&quot;. With the major changes in the nature of the forum, the scope of topics has also expanded from Asia-Pacific affairs to global issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xinbo, Dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University, is a frequent visitor to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. Since the first forum in 2006, he has attended the forum almost every year. He said, &quot;The theme of the forum is increasingly consistent with China&#39;s core concepts and basic principles of international security, and the topics of the sub-forums are also increasingly consistent with the current actual international security situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256573&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30 On the same day, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 30, ten small closed-door seminars were held simultaneously, covering topics such as global security governance, artificial intelligence security, and Sino-US crisis management and control. &quot;It has never happened before that ten meetings can be held at the same time.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;It is up to the participating representatives to choose which forum they want to go to, who they want to talk to, and how much they want to talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Chande, a researcher at the Institute for Defense Analyses and former deputy assistant secretary of defense, is an &quot;old friend&quot; of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and a well-known &quot;China expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I pay attention to China every day, and my understanding here may be deeper than that of the United States.” He told Southern Weekend reporters with a smile before the “Northeast Asian Order” sub-forum. The United States first sent official representatives to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum in 2015. Four years later, in 2019, then-U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense Shi Chande led a team to attend the meeting. It was the first time that a current senior U.S. military official appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the early days, the U.S. delegation’s participation in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum was relatively low, and basically only the military attache from the embassy in China was sent to participate.” Wu Xinbo recalled that as the importance and influence of the forum increased, the United States began to start from domestic Send some mid-level delegations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Similar to the Shangri-La Summit and the Munich Security Conference, an official’s rank determines his stage. This is a common international practice.” Zhao Xiaozhuo said, “After lower-level officials arrive, they are often only responsible for collecting information. Various opinions and information.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the U.S. military delegation was led by Owen Lewis, dean of the Joint Forces Staff College of the U.S. National Defense University; previously, the president of the U.S. National Defense University also led a delegation to Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Carles, senior director for China affairs in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense of the United States, took over the &quot;baton&quot; from the head of the delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The levels of Carles and Shi Chande are similar, but in terms of specific ranking, Shi Chande is higher.&quot; During the welcome dinner, Zhao Xiaozhuo specially analyzed the level setting of U.S. officials to the U.S. Navy Feng Dewei, vice president of the center, asked for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calles, the official leader of the US delegation at this forum, kept a low profile and rarely appeared in public. On the evening of October 30, she appeared at a small seminar on &quot;China-U.S. Crisis Management&quot;, but did not speak. She only briefly communicated with the participants after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;the level of the participants in the forum is not the most important matter. The communication between the two parties focuses on the substantive content.&quot; Wu Qian, spokesperson of the Ministry of National Defense, pointed out at a press conference held before the opening of the forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;International Issues &quot;Desktop Collision&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:00 on October 29, half an hour before the official start of the meeting, the conference room with less than 100 people was packed with people from all over the world. Representatives, experts and media, etc. This is a dialogue titled &quot;China&#39;s Role in Maintaining Asia-Pacific Security.&quot; Under the chairmanship of Wu Xinbo, experts from China, the United States, Russia and South Korea took their seats in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why can the Asia-Pacific maintain stability for thirty years?&quot; The host first asked the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, a former Chinese diplomat, shared &quot;the reasons for the Asia-Pacific economic miracle&quot;: peace and stability, focus on regional cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She gave data from the Bank of Asia, &quot;In the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown seven times. Nearly half of it was created by China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the United States&#39; GDP has grown seven times. Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Project at the Western Institute of National Affairs, believes that &quot;the change of power between China and the United States will bring huge uncertainty to Asia. In the next 10 to 15 years, the process of peace and stability in Asia may be disrupted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen&#39;s view was refuted by Fu Ying: &quot;Today, China is the driving force of the development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited greatly from it, but now this has become a problem?&quot; Fu Ying said, The United States has launched a &quot;China-US trade war&quot; and the gains outweigh the losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen during the celebrity dialogue on October 29. (Photo by Yao Yijiang/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256574&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the celebrity dialogue on October 29, Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen. (Photo by Yao Yijiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Russian expert Karaganov mentioned that &quot;Russia wants to create a peaceful and stable Eurasia and Asia-Pacific.&quot; Karaganov is the dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This scene better reflects the current international security situation.” After listening to the whole process, Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Northeast Asia Security Trends and Shaping&quot; parallel forum on the afternoon of the 30th, explosive scenes took place one after another. American scholar Shi Wen and Director of the Asian and African Studies Department of the Japanese Defense Research Institute Masuda Masayuki were criticized by Chinese scholars one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Northeast Asian issue depends on the interaction of multinational relations between China, Japan, the United States, and South Korea.” Shi Wen said. He was the third speaker at this forum, and there were also scholars from China, Russia, South Korea and the UK. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen flicked the tablet on the armrest of his seat, trying to regard the North Korean nuclear issue and the Taiwan issue as the same type of regional conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快，该场分论坛主持人、中国国际战略学会副会长、退役少将杜农一便阐明观点，“台湾问题的核心是中国的主权和领土完整。它与朝核问题等不可一同类比。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在下半场里，日本学者增田雅之成为众矢之的，因为他将地区安全问题归咎于中国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接过话筒的中国国际战略学会高级顾问杨旭光改变了原本的讲话思路，他说，增田雅之试图给中国人“上课”，“确实我有点无言以对”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨旭光直指，中日两国之间的症结根源上在于日本心理上的不平衡，试图将中美博弈视为采取行动的“难得机会”，并不断对台湾问题指手画脚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被反驳期间，增田雅之坐在台上，尴尬地笑了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;让发展中国家发声&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在欧美国家主导的国际舆论场上，发展中国家的声音鲜少被人听到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“虽然是全球村，但每个国家都有自己的目标。”10月29日的“中外青年军官学者研讨会”上，巴基斯坦俾路支斯坦研究和发展智库首席执行官贾瓦莉亚·塔琳坦言。她身旁的美国青年学者表情严肃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七十多年来，印巴边境问题悬而未决，克什米尔始终如同扎在两国关系上的一根刺。贾瓦莉亚提到，每次巴方想对话，印度都没有积极回应，双方关系只是停在智库层面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“发展中国家面临两大问题，一是发展，二是安全。”中国军事科学院何雷中将告诉南方周末记者，从某种意义上讲，发展中国家是当今世界的“弱势群体”，安全诉求应该得到更多重视和合理关切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了北京香山论坛，国际知名安全论坛还有香格里拉对话、哈利法克斯国际安全论坛、慕尼黑安全会议以及首尔防务对话等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这些论坛具有明显的&#39;圈子&#39;属性，发展中国家没有太大的发声空间。”赵小卓提到，只有北京香山论坛明确为发展中国家提供舞台，让他们充分表达自己的安全关切和诉求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;主会场的各国代表（吕慧乾/摄）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256575&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;主会场的各国代表。 （吕慧乾/摄）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者观察到，平行分组会议和研讨活动中，有5场会议以发展中国家和“全球南方”为主题，超过一半的发言嘉宾来自于发展中国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“全球南方”不是一个新概念。早在1969年，美国政治活动家卡尔·奥格尔斯比就曾首次使用这一术语。 “欧美国家正在用全球南方将中国排除在发展中国家之外，最大限度孤立中国。”赵小卓认为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国在全球南方中处于非常关键甚至核心的位置，中国的成功已经成为全球南方在国际层面最重要的推动力……中国一直通过&#39;一带一路&#39;推动和平发展，可美国在搞什么呢？”香港中文大学（深圳）校长讲座教授郑永年在10月29日上午反问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;带着对巴以冲突的担忧，土耳其亚太研究中心创始主任赛尔楚克·乔拉克奥卢第一次来到北京香山论坛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“巴以冲突已造成双方近万人死亡，而且还暗藏着溢出的隐患。”赛尔楚克向南方周末记者表示，他希望在“中东安全新架构”上讨论如何为巴以提供新的解决方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿莱西奥·帕塔拉诺曾多次参与新加坡的香格里拉对话和北京香山论坛。他认为，北京香山论坛更为“务实”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位英国伦敦国王学院战争研究部教授很健谈。论坛刚开始，阿莱西奥就被前来请教的媒体拉着采访了1小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他告诉南方周末记者，为发展中国家提供发声平台，是北京香山论坛的最大优势之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各国防长、代表带着寻求和平的愿景来到北京香山论坛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“共同安全、持久和平是所有国家共同发展的基础。”阿富汗发展与和平研究中心主任伊提扎尔·哈迪姆告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿富汗，伊提扎尔是前政府官员，现在是一名现代政治史教授。他向南方周末记者打趣，“我是戴着两顶&#39;帽子&#39;来参会的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿富汗现在有3600万人正遭受极端贫困和饥饿。 “只有为人民创造就业岗位，他们才不会转向战争。”伊提扎尔期待中国能够参与阿富汗重建工作，“中国可以帮助发展中国家促进经济和社会发展，而不是分发火药。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生刘雅琪、林曦、蒋来、徐子仪、冯嘉怡、张馨怡对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;晚年的段义孚（右三）与友人在一起。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（出版方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚以一件中年时的偶遇结束了自传《我是谁？ 》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夜间，他在不宽的高速公路上驾车，前面只有一辆车。他对自己的驾驶技术信心不足，所以将前车的尾灯视为引导，由此获得安全和舒服的感觉。突然那辆车闪起右转灯，拐进乡间小道。肉眼可见，路上只有他在驾驶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“于是，就只剩下我自己的车前灯来引路了。这灯光只能照亮很短的一段路，而这路，在更远之处，则被吞没在了重重的黑暗里。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚是著名地理学家，人文主义地理学的创始人之一。他富有智性地理解人和地方的关系，认为自己是世界主义者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《我是谁？ 》写于1999年，段义孚当时69岁，人类即将进入新千年。他将“我是谁”视为新千年来临之际的时髦问题。这个问题实际上早在1960年代就越来越受到关注，“为了产生一个稳固的自我意识，一个人需要曾经的岁月，而不光是现在和未来”。值得一提的是，《寂静的春天》就是在1960年代令诗意与科学结合起来，共同审视人与环境的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚在接下来的二十几年仍旧思考着，还写出了重要的作品。 《我是谁？ 》是很好的阶段性总结，展现出真诚的自我审视。他似乎越来越接近一个位置，却又无法确定什么时候才能抵达，甚至变得更远些。理想当中的位置，总随着时间、空间和思考变动着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1940年代初，段义孚一家准备由重庆迁往澳大利亚。合影时，段义孚（左三）试图挤开弟弟，紧挨着母亲，从而获得更多关注。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（出版方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;他&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;眼中的世界是向内缩小的&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;一开始，段义孚就征引了苏格拉底的言语：未经审视的人生不值得度过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中年之前，段义孚没在什么城市住满过五年。他离开中国后继续辗转，直到38岁搬到明尼阿波利斯，停下来从事学术工作。迁徙与父亲的工作和历史事件都分不开。他相信自己是无根的，“天生就该自我审视”。他终身未婚，无法完全融入美国社会，身份认同问题始终在那儿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为自己是乐观主义者，“常把黄金时代放在未来”。他知道自己很早就获得自信，在国外生活时没怎么受到种族主义伤害，到晚年则开始质疑自信的来源。他处世的种种方法，与经历的事件与居留的环境紧密相连。这本书展现了他自己的“地方感”——对特定地方的情感和判断。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1956年的印第安纳大学第一次面试中，一位亚洲史教授曾经惊讶于他的家族身世。段义孚回想起童年往事，才确定对方并没有开玩笑。按照他听到的说法，段家在近代分成两支，都在安徽，段义孚家属于贫寒一支，父亲段茂澜靠合肥那支的族叔段祺瑞全程资助读完南开中学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚生在天津，7岁到10岁因战争住在重庆郊区的村庄，家庭经济窘迫。学校是属于发电站的单间房。那片地方弥漫着酸腐味，恶臭的泥浆拖住他的鞋子，他既厌恶又恐惧。他偶尔遇见出殡的队伍，中间拱卫的遗体给裹在竹席子里面。上面绑着一只公鸡，倘若诈尸，它就会啼叫起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1954年，段义孚在美国亚利桑那州做实地调查。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（出版方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小小的学校是不同的地方，学生们在那里知道全世界的历史、文化与科技。王尔德的作品《快乐王子》给他留下无法磨灭的印记，他知道：“再也不能把&#39;好&#39;仅仅局限于履行社会义务了”。这些觉悟激励段义孚去思考，他始终探索着如何确定一个人在世界中的位置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚在叙述中提到一些重要的历史人物。段茂澜与校友周恩来掰手腕，测试对方受伤的手臂是否痊愈。还有南开中学的校长张伯苓拥有罕见的冰箱，把一盘盘冰块分给大家，父亲为了留给他而采用了撒盐延迟融化的偏方。大人还在思虑该如何对待远亲汪精卫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于父亲，段义孚带着矛盾的情绪。他渴望关爱，但因父亲对兄弟的偏爱而失落；他牢记困窘时日的温情，也因父亲的严峻或盛怒而备受创伤。对父亲最深刻的记忆，甚至只是童年的一场噩梦，梦中的情景留存了许多年：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我张开双臂想拥抱他……怎么回事？一个幽灵却站在了我面前，可以看出，那是我的父亲，但他身上却披着一件丧服。这具幽灵在不断变化的气流中移动着，没有重量。那是一个恶鬼，一具尸体，空洞的眼睛里泛着黄色的光。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;母亲给他留下的印象是温暖并坚韧的，可惜她过早去世了。同时，身体状况令段义孚越发敏感，他一度病恹恹的。他坦陈自己的怯懦，也不愿意参与改变社会的活动。即便面对种族主义，粗鲁的男孩子们视他为“小妹儿”，他都没有动力主动反击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚眼中的世界是向内缩小的。他小时候接触种种不得了的大事，长大后战争结束了，要面对的是众多个人问题。他把这样的成长经历归纳为从宇宙走向灶台，用优美的写作将人生与学术融在一起。他引用了诗人TS 艾略特的言语：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我们所有人，在一生所听到、看到、感觉到的一切（一只鸟鸣，一条鱼跃，一位老妪行走在山路上）为什么会富含感情地重现出来，而其他东西没有？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;青年时期的段义孚。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（出版方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;是否愿意成为孤独的船长&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“诗意可以突破语言逻辑的屏障或者界线。”刘苏对南方周末说。他以此形容段义孚笔下的优美文字。他翻译了《恋地情结》和《我是谁？ 》两本段义孚的著作，正在翻译《分割的世界和自我》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2010年前后读研究生时，刘苏常苦于无书可读。他很多次为书中提及的思想吸引，却找不到相关的中译本甚至英译本。他想尽办法寻找原著，去豆瓣找读过书的豆友询问，也去图书馆，但说不定只能复印半本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“干脆我自己来翻译吧！”那些经历激发了刘苏的热情。他由此走上学术翻译的道路，未来的大学生将不再面对阅读的困境。同时，很多学者也参与了地理学经典的翻译和引介，段义孚和大卫·哈维等学者的中译本足以汇聚成文集。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年夏天，在挤得水泄不通的重庆地铁里，刘苏收到另一位译者志丞的微信消息，问他是否愿意一同翻译《我是谁？ 》。即便空调充足，他还是出了一身热汗：“这本书终于要翻译成中文了！”他认真琢磨过，在异国带着“异乡人”身份的孤独生活，自己是不愿意过的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《我是谁？ 》令刘苏心生共鸣。他经历了漫长的单身生活，结婚时，同学们的孩子都快上初中了。他或许因此体会到段义孚的孤独，以及那句自陈：“我把大量的时光都消耗在了伤春悲秋的诗文里，花费在了图书馆和咖啡厅这样的场合里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘苏上完课，和学生告别，走出教学楼后会去图书馆待一会儿。哪怕不写什么，也愿意呆坐在角落，体会段义孚说的“几乎一辈子都生活在校园里，被年轻人包围着，身心愉悦”。他有时去附近的咖啡厅靠窗坐下，望着行人、车辆和街灯，孤独才远一些。精妙语言汇聚的感性聚拢过来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚在1998年，也就是《我是谁？ 》前一年的作品《逃避主义》中问：最伟大的逃避是什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以爱邻舍般的心去低头管理好身边的环境时，还能抬头仰望浩瀚的星空。”刘苏谈及对这句话的理解，补充了更现实的一面，“作为一名学者，我也会像他那样常常仰望那片形而上学的思想、理论的星空。但是，每当我低头环顾自己的单身生活时，却频频产生出了一地鸡毛之感。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;段义孚（1930-2022），蜚声国际的华裔地理学家，生于天津，毕业于牛津大学，晚年曾回到中国。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（出版方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘苏在书里寻找关乎单身生活的记述。段义孚把公寓整理得朴素而温馨，穿着低调而得体，健康、长寿，人际关系不错，还收获了珍贵的友谊。不过，“他却曾梦见自己一个人死在了家里，腐烂的尸体没人发现”。段义孚总在书写自己的孤独，一种错综复杂的感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“或许原因在于孤独才是人最本真的存在方式吧，不孤独的状态，其实都是逃避的产物。”刘苏援引了《逃避主义》的说法。有三个问题围绕在段义孚的生命当中：自幼年就萦绕的“我是必死的”；关乎个体意识的“我是谁”；还有“什么是美好的人生”。段义孚写出“地理学拯救了我”，地理学就像一条道路，让他通向对自身和人类生命问题的理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;翻译《我是谁？ 》也让刘苏收获了“值得珍藏的友情”。新书发布会后，他与志丞、编辑们与读者朋友一起冒着大雨钻进面馆畅聊。五个人各自在五本书上签名，珍藏起来。他还想把感受写成比较长的邮件，分享给段义孚。邮件还没写完，段义孚就于2022年8月去世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚在那一年出版了新书，最后写道：“我要再一次劝你，年轻的旅行者啊！一定要充满勇气像一名船长一样操纵自己的船只，尽管只有生活中那些令人困惑的线索和星星作为你的指南。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘苏为错失而失落，但会继续翻译人文主义地理学的经典著作。他也问自己，是否愿意成为孤独的船长，走上一条窄路。不论答案是怎样的，段义孚的书“始终会投射到每一个读者的内心”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;哪里才是真正的家园&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;段义孚在《回家记》的前言中追忆，常有人问他觉得哪里才是真正的家乡。他则轻描淡写地回答：“总的来说，是地球。”“到底是地球上的哪里呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，追问的意思大概是：肯定有一个地方让他最舒服、最向往，能形成最深刻的归属感。 “有些特定的景观的确对我有巨大的吸引力，比如说一种超脱了美学的景观——沙漠。我觉得自己在心理上与沙漠很亲近，甚至可以把它看做家园。”段义孚一次又一次写到对沙漠的喜爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1954年冬天开始，段义孚在亚利桑那州东南部为博士论文做实地研究，研究对象是叫做山麓侵蚀面的荒漠地形。乐观的英国学生大卫·哈里斯加入后，荒野带来的物质与精神上的困难变得稀薄，逐渐为友谊取代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这层关系带给了我满足感，但同样也引起了不安——几乎所有到达一定深度的人际关系都会同时体现出这二者。为什么？是我有什么问题吗？”段义孚在书中问道。 1962年，他们再度合作。他仍旧单身，成为了教师；大卫则结了婚，有了两个女儿。 “如今的大卫，比我之前认识的，在人格上更广阔，更难以捉摸。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下面的描写是敏感和令人刺痛的，这样的感触在书中反复出现。他们各自开车去查科峡谷考察，段义孚在前面带路，大卫一家在后面跟随。黄昏时分，也许大卫认得路线，也许孩子们需要照顾，大卫的车一声鸣笛，卷起尘土开到前面去了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我们之间的距离越拉越大，不久，在我眼前剩下的，就只是扬起的尘土了，到最后，连尘土都看不见了。我便陷入了一片孤独的阴影里……当我努力追赶哈里斯一家的时候，第一次感到了孤独和痛苦。更糟的是，我甚至觉得自己很荒诞。我到底在新墨西哥州的土路上做什么？开车追一个坐在轿车里的年轻家庭？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在段义孚眼中，友谊必须满足两个基本条件——志同道合和惺惺相惜——两者在理想的友谊中应当保持平衡。 “如果过度倾向于共同的兴趣和利益，这两个人就更像是同事而非朋友；反之，他们可能更像是恋人，会盯着对方的眼睛而不是世界。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“害羞的人，不爱交际的人，或者像我这样被古怪的追求抑制了社交需要的人，或许更应该投身于大自然……可能只有待在无机物的环境中，例如沙漠、冰山里，人才能心旷神怡、宠辱偕忘。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段义孚还写到德国人亚历山大·冯·洪堡。洪堡是现代自然地理学的奠基人，“对大地测量的发展做出过卓越贡献，并首先运用绘画和诗歌的方式开拓了人的地理经验——感受、情感和观念，而这些正是人文主义地理学的起点之所在”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洪堡活了90岁，终生精力充沛，六旬还可以穿越西伯利亚和中亚地区。他乐于社交，但未曾结婚，三次受困于和男性的感情纠葛。他在给已婚军人赖因哈德·冯·哈夫滕的信中写道：“即使你要拒绝我，冷冷地看待我，就像看一个污点似的，我依然想和你在一起……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果离开了宇宙，或准确地说，离开了和谐自然和人类极致成就所带来的喜悦，我的人生将变得悲惨，活不下去。”段义孚列举了种种人类的悲苦，“但是，我却不愿久待在那些阴影里……”他相信那道光、宇宙之美，事件的美与善。接下来的章节就是“地理学拯救了我”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，借参加建筑学会议的契机，段义孚离开六十年之后回到中国，特意多待了一段时间。他在写了一本《回家记》，由志丞译为中文。在重庆之旅那部分，他再度提到困扰一生的噩梦。 1980年父亲在台北去世，他并没有回去见最后一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自传的末尾是车灯微光与茫茫黑暗的对比，那不是绝望，段义孚仍旧审视着自己。他请译者附上了自己在2012年的讲稿，作为对“我是谁”的更新的理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“世界上并没有所谓的普通人。每天和你说话的人其实都是灵魂不死的人……和我们一起开玩笑、一起工作、结婚，也被我们冷落了、剥削了的人其实都是灵魂不死的人。而在这些人里面，有的人是不灭的惊悚，有的人是不朽的辉煌。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;可能时间太久，他真的忘了&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《我是谁？ 》的编辑俞诗逸，多少显得沉默——就像在微信中用一条条文字交流时那样——但很快就打开局面，健谈并幽默起来。他的日常安排很规律，那天甚至追加了一小段时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来他补充，不应该谈太多自己的故事，自传作者更应该获得篇幅。那么，这部分就是本文的番外篇。人们总面对着“我是谁”之类的问题，问题与答案随着情景不停地变动，各自披上了诱人的色彩。比如大导演伯格曼就声称，相比十年前，他对自己的了解更少了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俞诗逸对离散事件怀有独特情感。 1949年初，太平轮海难发生在他出生的岱山岛西边的海域。小时候他对这场悲剧毫不了解，离开家乡读大学后才经由纪录片知晓。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，大约12.5万名壮丁、军人和2.5万名文职人员、民众从舟山迁往台湾，后来形成了两三万人规模的第一代舟山人群体。 1987年台湾老兵还乡运动的发起者就是舟山人，“三通”之前他们与故土接触非常困难。当地史料陈列馆利用了一整面墙，展示那时由红十字会转来的信件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岛屿形塑着认知。俞诗逸十年前离开舟山到宁波，读书又到了上海。成长时期，舟山还没有跨海大桥，台风一来，岛就是孤岛，物理与心理一并与世隔绝。相对于县城、省城、都会，小岛来客似乎是“小”的、边缘的。一开始他渴望由边缘融入主流，现在则想拥有主体性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“作为一个移民，到了一个新的环境，你的地域认同是最早被提起的。”俞诗逸有朋友生在湖北长在深圳，后来到上海。他问：“他者”的乡音是哪里的？ 1973年，43岁的段义孚正式成为美国公民。他已经在美国定居近二十年，不断调试，成为“世界主义者和书写离散主题的思想家”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有小爷爷——也就是祖父的弟弟——过年时聊起往事。他自称曾经驾驶烧柴油的简陋船只，从衢山岛出发，一晚开到上海董家渡。独自一个人，没有GPS，有的只是经验和指南针。俞诗逸无从想象渔民的处境。没有陆地、晃晃荡荡，他们会害怕吧？他把无边无际的想象写进笔记：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;瘦长的他驾驶着小小的舢板，从岛上出发，往西北方向开去，穿过黑夜与白天，到了董家渡。那时的照明系统并不完善，也无定位系统，有些航道在夜里甚至近乎漆黑，他竟安然地到了目的地，未提一句遇见的风浪。我想也许是时间过得太久了，他也早就忘却了一路的风雨。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;记得花鸟岛有座有名的灯塔，不知他是否路过，在特定的条件下，还会有荧光海的奇景。总觉得从家乡前往上海的航道，充满了各种神秘的力量。我坐过一次从岛上开往沪上的渡轮，黄昏上岸，黎明落地，那是我第一次见像泉水般汩汩的海浪，和翱翔在天际的海鸥。从三等舱的小小圆玻璃往外看去，有若隐若现的灯光，也许我见过花鸟岛的灯塔了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我问族人，你上岸了吗？他说卸了货，没上去。我好遗憾，想从他嘴里套出八十年代上海的秘密，他却说，没有什么，董家渡过去便是外滩，那些西洋的玩意儿看不懂，那时凡货凭票，族人是水上人，自然也获取不得。他驾驶舢板，沿着黄浦江又一路往上，最后竟到了江阴。这无疑是一场冒险，至于去那做什么，又是如何回岛，他没说几句，就歇下不谈了。可能时间太久，他真的忘了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记忆和讲述形成一个又一个碎片，嵌入生命。小爷爷离开上海三十多年之后，俞诗逸也到了上海。 2022年的“十一”假期，他又和父亲坐船上岛。父亲本来犹豫，毕竟房子不再是他们的。很多地方不一样了，旧房新房此起彼伏，好在路在原地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俞诗逸回到自己出生的弄堂，二十多年前买的商品房还在，只是旧了些。后门开着，他进去，看到很多年前的搓衣板。那么多年过去，它居然还在，好像神迹。旁边有人居住，他不好意思打扰，只想转去前门看看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;住户看到陌生人，警觉起来，问：“你是谁？”俞诗逸愣住，沉默几秒钟，本能地回答：“这是我家。”他走到前门，拍过照便离开了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你变成&#39;他者&#39;了。”他追忆起来，“物理实体的东西在，它曾经就是我的家。”房子究竟转了几道手，他不知道，只感觉释然，终于可以告别了。快二十年，他总想起这个家，不放心，怕给拆掉。如今玩伴、邻居全离开，留下的只有照片和搓衣板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对故乡的认同、记忆，转过来成为别人识别你的手段。被问“你是谁”没多久，2022年12月俞诗逸接手《我是谁？ 》，2023年8月书在上海书展推出。以上，总有点意外的缘分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天安门下半旗悼念李克强同志]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259779]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:28:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;新华社记者鞠焕宗摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月2日，为悼念李克强同志，首都天安门下半旗志哀。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”：是一种可鄙的价值观吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;互联网上流传着诸多有鼻子有眼、煞有介事的谣言，有些是旧的然后不断翻新版本，有些是新的。比较新近出现的一个是：中国留学生论文“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”，结果被新西兰教授判了零分，并发出灵魂之问，“为什么要成为人上人，那其他人下人怎么办，为什么要将你的同胞分为三六九等，人与人之间难道不应该是平等的吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做一些互联网考古工作的话，不难发现这是一个某自媒体炮制出台的三无新闻，没有具体的时间、大学与人物。编造者的动机是借心目中权威的洋人之口，显示某些中国人的言行与价值观之Low，及自己心仪的价值观之高。不过，“外来的和尚好念经”，对此类谣言信的人还不少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”原始版本当为“不受苦中苦，难为人上人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《西游记》第32回。唐僧说：“徒弟们仔细，前遇山高，恐有虎狼阻挡。”孙悟空说：“师父，出家人莫说在家话。你记得那乌巢和尚的《心经》云&#39;心无挂碍，无挂碍，方无恐怖，远离颠倒梦想&#39;之言？但只是扫除心上垢，洗净耳边尘。不受苦中苦，难为人上人。你莫生忧虑，但有老孙，就是塌下天来，可保无事。怕什么虎狼！”这是把师父教育了一番。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又《警世通言》之《玉堂春落难逢夫》。只见大门上挂着一联对子：“十年受尽窗前苦，一举成名天下闻。”“这是我公公作下的对联。他中举会试，官至侍郎：后来咱爹爹在此读书，官到尚书。我今在此读书，亦要攀龙附凤，以继前人之志。”又见二门上有一联对子：“不受苦中苦，难为人上人。”公子急回书房……心中回转，发志勤学。这是自我激励了一番。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个版本的差异在于：“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”，前句是后句的必要条件；“不受苦中苦，难为人上人”则是概率表述。后者显得更严谨一些，容许了例外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此类俗语怎么看？如果你把“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”看成全称判断，那自然不难找到反例，在逻辑学意义上这个命题就被驳倒了。不过，此后所有人觉得这话错了就弃而不用？显然不会，大家只会觉得你在抬杠，因为这不是俗语的正确打开方式。俗语的使用本来就是情景性的：只有把特定前提条件加上去，或置于特定语境，这俗语才成立，才可以使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各种语言中，都存有大量意义完全相反的俗语。这里举中文为例：“威武不能屈”Vs“大丈夫能屈能伸”；“人不犯我，我不犯人”Vs“先下手为强，后下手遭殃”；“宁为玉碎，不为瓦全”Vs“留得青山在，不怕没柴烧”；“退一步海阔天空”Vs“狭路相逢勇者胜”；“忍一时风平浪静”Vs“是可忍，孰不可忍”；“万般皆下品，唯有读书高”Vs“三百六十行，行行出状元”；“青出于蓝而胜于蓝”Vs“嘴上没毛，办事不牢”；“三个臭皮匠，胜过诸葛亮”Vs“三个和尚没水喝”……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你告诉我，前后哪句是对的，哪句是错的，抑或都是错了？其实，只要放入适当的语境，这些意义相反的俗语都可以对，这才是俗语正确的使用方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体到“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”或“不受苦中苦，难为人上人”，也有与其意义相反或强调重点不一样的俗语，如“一命二运三风水”“选择比努力更重要”“不要以战术上的勤奋掩盖战略上的懒惰”等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我看来，就成功而言，是诸多先天与后天因素共同决定的。一、命：即你什么时候出生在什么国度什么家庭，这构成了你的初始条件与边界条件；二、智：智力禀赋，大脑的算力与算法，这也是先天的；三、神：你的知识体系与价值观，及你的生命力、动机、勇气与耐性，先天与后天的成分都有，但后天成分较大，因为你总可以选择你的价值观，选择做一个有勇气的人；四，运：你无从知道也无法控制的因素，因为你身处一个复杂随机系统之中。在特定的进程中，“神、智、命、运”，哪些因素更重要，不可一概而论。一个人的成功总是历史走向与个人命运的共振。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，在诸多决定成功的因素中，吃苦或勤奋或耐性当然是重要的，对没有背景的人来说尤其如此。其他的述如“宝剑锋自磨砺出，梅花开自苦寒来”“书山有路勤为径，学海无涯苦作舟”，听起来是不是顺耳多了？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人不喜欢的是“人上人”。这个得两看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面，从权利或规则的角度看，当然应该人人平等，没有人凌驾任何人之上，也没有人屈从于任何人之下，反对任何人享有特权或施行奴役，这是文明社会的基本准则。在这个意义上，不应该有“人上人”及“人下人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，社会上总会有某些职业更受推崇，社会评价或美誉度更高，如外科医生等专业人士，享有较高的社会地位，算不算“人上人”呢？还有，一些人因为能力、学识或德性过人，受到大家的尊重与仰慕，甚至不乏追随者，如新乡贤这样的社会凝结核，左邻右舍闹纠纷找他评理，他算不算“人上人”呢？在企业或组织中，无论等级比较森严的，还是管理比较“扁平化”的，都有指挥链，有上下级关系，下级得服从上级的指挥做事，高管与上级算不算“人上人”呢？一言以蔽之，从权力或影响力的角度看，精英或社会地位较高者，常被称为“人中龙凤”，算“人上人”没毛病。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故而，想当“人上人”，追求的是压倒别人的特权或将别人踩在脚下，自然是一种可鄙的价值观；但想当“人中龙凤”，在专业领域深耕，或提升自己的才德，成为一时人望，获得较高的社会地位，又有什么问题呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[书城伏案的侧影：写在刘世南先生百年诞辰之际]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259765]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3AasqhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;916&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3Aasq hT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Shinan took a photo in front of the Chongshao Library of Jiangxi Normal University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Taosheng)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;People who long for friends who fear friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Shinan Mr. (1923-2021) was a fighter. This is the first impression of him by people who are familiar with him and those who are not familiar with him. He dared to criticize various scholars, including those older than him, those of his generation, and those younger than him. His articles were scattered in various books and periodicals from the late 1970s to the new century, making readers People who feel the enthusiasm and persistence of his criticism are of course embarrassed by the critics, but they do learn from him, and many criticized scholars express their gratitude to him and respect him even more. His criticisms were actually aimed at problems, especially the style of study. His crisp and refreshing writing style contained a profound call for a sincere, simple, serious and down-to-earth style of study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not many people know that he is very eager to be criticized. He criticized Mr. Liu Mengfu (&quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; page 301), and Mr. Mengfu also criticized him. He invited Mr. Mengfu to write a preface to his &quot;Daluo Ju Shi Cun&quot;. Mr. Mengfu wrote a long preface in which he included his own critical opinions. He criticized it with real swords and guns. Mr. Shinan did not think that Sorry, let it remain in the preface as it is. This is the style of sincerity and magnanimity. He said in a letter to me on July 26, 2005: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Mengfu is in middle age and a poet. Learn the art of poetry and achieve the best of both worlds. He looks down upon him as a servant, looks down upon his followers, and is sincerely afraid of his friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He respects and looks forward to his &quot;fearful friends&quot;. When he heard Mr. Tao Wenpeng mention that some parts of his &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; were a bit &quot;old&quot;, he wrote a letter asking Mr. Tao to point out his shortcomings in detail. Mr. Tao replied, and Mr. Shinan made a copy of the letter. Send me a copy and write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send me a copy of Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s letter, to be compared with Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s book review Although Mr. Yun and Mr. Tao made many mistakes in their compliments, Mr. Tao was able to correct their flaws. I hope Mr. Yun can do the same. In the past, Chen Si once said: &quot;The writings of the world cannot be without disease. I always have good people to ridicule my writings, and if there are bad ones, I should revise them in due course.&quot; He also quoted Ding Jingli and said: &quot;Who in future generations will know that my writings are evil?&quot; I hope that Mr. Zou Zhen, as the editor-in-chief of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, will be able to rectify the shortcomings of my book and inform future generations of those who govern Qing poetry about what to avoid. This is the meaning of an academic public instrument. (January 12, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he is still not satisfied with Mr. Tao&#39;s criticism and hopes to get more and more real criticism. He regards criticism as an &quot;academic official tool&quot;. &quot;To look at it. This allows us to understand more clearly that the reason why he carried out academic criticism with all his might was because he really had no selfish motives and was only dedicated to the healthy and mature development of the academic world. His attitude towards criticism is not only aimed at others, but also aimed at himself, which is conducive to his own improvement and is conducive to clear understanding in the academic community. He sets an example and has a bright mind, which is admirable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan and his &quot;Detailed Notes on Three Hundred Qing Poems&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was very moved by others&#39; corrections to him and expressed his gratitude repeatedly. Our publisher was planning to launch chronological anthologies one after another. Considering that Mr. Shinan was familiar with Qing literature, editor and editor Zhou Xuanlong, then director of the Classics Department, sincerely invited him to annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Considering that time was tight, he asked his Student Professor Liu Songlai assisted. After the manuscript arrived, Ms. Wen Lichen, a graduate student at Beijing Normal University, intern, reviewed it for the first time under my guidance. Then I reviewed it again. After writing two revisions, I sent it to Mr. Shinan for review. He said in a letter written in the Provincial Library on October 1, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 22 and Review comments and copies of book reviews have been received. Please read them. After reading it, I feel ashamed and excited! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the articles of Kuangzheng and Supplement, we can also see that Mr. Wen Lichen and Wen Lichen have made profound achievements in the study of female history, and their admiration for them cannot be overstated! I secretly say that the &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; will be of some benefit to this world in the future. It shows that the cooperation between the four of us is not caused by Song Lai and me. I plan to add a few words to the preface of this book to clarify the meaning and to show that we do not dare to take advantage of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He later insisted on adding words of praise to me and Xiaowen in the preface of the book, which shows that he was happy after hearing about it and had an open-minded and sage mind, which was like a spring breeze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Liu Shinan’s two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Mr. Shinan&#39;s fighting spirit is mainly reflected in his diligent reading and writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He does not have many books, mainly because the collections of two generations of his were destroyed during the special period, which made him extremely sad, and he generally stopped buying books (&quot;Odd Records of Masters and Friends&quot;, page 117). He mainly visits the library. He is a frequent visitor to the provincial library and school library. In 1994, after fourteen years of arduous reading, research, and writing, he finally completed &quot;History of the Qing Poetry School&quot;. When proofreading the manuscript the following summer, he reviewed the process with joy:&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reminiscent of the past, when every year passes, the bookstore is still busy with calligraphy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wan Jiaqing Tuanluan, sitting alone and smiling. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The box is full of cards, and there are more than delicious meals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fourteen years of hard work, the book is finished with a pen and inkstone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Appendix to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; &quot;Proofreading in the Midsummer of Jiaxu&quot; &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; Manuscript...&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Note: &quot;Every Spring Festival and New Year&#39;s Eve, I sit in the library, facing the administrator from a distance.&quot; Our publisher is preparing to publish the simplified version, and I am honored to be responsible. The editor, during the editing process, greeted him and mentioned this impressive scene. He wrote me a reply in the sample library on the evening of December 30, 2003 and the next day:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Thank you for your attention. You still remember that I was still sitting in the library on New Year&#39;s Eve. If school maps were still open, I would indeed do that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;A silverfish in the book of life and death&quot;, this is how I have been here all my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, he still couldn&#39;t let go every day. One New Year&#39;s Eve, the curator and he &quot;faced each other from a distance&quot;, which was quite a scene. He wrote to his student Professor Guo Dan: &quot;It is now nearly 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon on New Year&#39;s Eve. Director Zhang and I are the only two people left in the library reading hall; Director Zhang is on duty in person and will accompany me until 4 o&#39;clock with a smile. The bell closes the door.&quot; (Guo Dan&#39;s &quot;The Realm of Scholarship and the Style of Personality - A Note on Mr. Liu Shinan&quot;, &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 237) Such a curator is really a good curator, and such a reader is really a good reader. This is called It is a good story in the contemporary reading world. The postcard he sent me on December 31, 2006 said: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bookstore is sitting at the desk, cocooned and forgotten. Time passes in a hurry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If Hua Yan was not drunk this night, who would have known that the day after tomorrow would be the New Year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Still reading on New Year’s Eve, it is indeed the style of reading seeds. Of course, he didn&#39;t just focus on New Year&#39;s Eve. In fact, every day was precious to him. Letter from June 4, 2004:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; is very busy, I have never been so nervous , because the school will be closed during the summer vacation, so I have to finish this before the vacation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the scene when I was rushing to select and annotate &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; with Professor Song Lai. Later, when there was no urgent work, I still went to the library unremittingly. In the past, revolutionaries had a heroic saying: &quot;Sit through the prison.&quot; Mr. Shinan, in his old age, still insisted on going there regardless of his illness. He really had the spirit to penetrate the library. The letter dated January 10, 2013 said:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​year has passed and I was recently hospitalized for removal of nasal warts. Medical advice It was basal cell carcinoma and had been completely removed. I am already ninety years old and have lived and died for a long time, so after I was discharged from the hospital, I still sat in the library. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Professor Guo Dan called Mr. Shinan to wish him a happy New Year on the morning of the first day of the Spring Festival in Year Yiwei in 2015, the answer he heard was &quot;I am already reading in the provincial library&quot;! (Postscript to the reprint of &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;) Mr. Li Taosheng has been accompanying Mr. Shinan for many years. He said in the article &quot;Unforgettable words from the bottom of my heart&quot;: &quot;Books are all his spiritual sustenance.&quot; &quot;No matter the wind, frost, rain or snow, he always He would always show up at the library on time like a staff member. He said he hoped he could die at his desk in the future.&quot; (&quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;, page 249) This shows how obsessed he is with books. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;From thousands of books&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan has read extensively and is particularly familiar with classics and history, so he can read many treatises We are sensitive to misunderstandings, misjudgments, and corrections and can provide corrections. In addition to helping others publish absurdities, he mainly devoted his energy to the research and writing of &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;. In addition, a lot of study was done on the annotations of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. After taking on this task, he devoted himself wholeheartedly to the selection of articles. Although Professor Song Lai was invited to participate in the annotation work, he still did everything personally:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From text selection to punctuation to the comments, I will read them all and revise them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At these times, I was busy selecting articles, mainly from &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot; and &quot;Continued&quot; Choose from &quot;Xiu Siku Quanshu&quot; and &quot;Cunmu Series&quot;, and a few have to be found separately from the thread-bound library. For example, Jiang Shiquan has no text in &quot;Continued Cultivation&quot;, but &quot;Pictures of Night Classes with Sound Machines&quot; must be selected. Others can be deduced by analogy. The selection of the text is time-consuming. After selecting it, it must be photocopied and then hand-copied into simplified Chinese characters. (December 16, 2003) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to concentrate on the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, he served as the chief academic consultant for the compilation of &quot;Yu Zhang Series&quot; in Jiangxi Province universities for several years. (that is, final check) also resigned. This shows his determination to devote himself wholeheartedly to the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. Because he was familiar with the collected works of the Qing Dynasty, and he read them day and night, by December 30, 2003, he had &quot;read page by page the Qing Dynasty Collection of Continuing the Complete Collection of Siku Quanshu&quot;, and had reached 154 of the 188 volumes. , there are still 30 volumes left, I can finish them before the winter vacation,&quot; and said, &quot;Then I will read &quot;Sikuquanshu&quot;, there are not many collections. I haven&#39;t read &quot;Cunmu&quot;, so I don&#39;t know how many.&quot; In selecting articles, &quot;Be sure not to show off your hands and eyes, and don&#39;t be attracted by people&#39;s enthusiasm&quot; (letter dated December 30, 2003). In this letter, he still could not hide his critical eye and expressed his opinions on several books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I was reading the collected works of Zeng Guofan today, and I found four books that were annotated by modern people. Take &quot;Yuancai&quot; as an example , Tu Xiaoma&#39;s version, Lai Xinxia&#39;s version, and Guo Yuheng&#39;s version all concluded: &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; &quot;Is it possible to say that it is not false?&quot; On the contrary, Zheng Zhenduo&#39;s &quot;Late Qing Dynasty&quot; &quot;Selected Works&quot; concluded: &quot;Is it true to say that the accusation is not false?&quot; That&#39;s right. Tu, Lai and Guo... I don&#39;t know that the &quot;ye&quot; in &quot;Ke Hu Ye&quot; is actually &quot;ye&quot;. Books such as &quot;Jing Zhuan Shi Ci&quot; make it very clear, and the ancient prose written by Han Yu and Ouyang Xiu is swaying and often colorful. There is this aria. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;king&quot; in &quot;Everyone is king and is ordered to do so&quot; has been misunderstood. &quot;Mistakenly changed to &quot;must&quot;, it is also analyzed. He did not deny your contribution, he just wanted to explain that he would learn from their achievements, but would never simply plagiarize:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Even if we refer to this kind of annotated version, we must analyze every detail, never make vague and influential remarks, but strive to be clear and accurate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are actually very few similar works that we can rely on. Even if we refer to them, they must be adopted with discernment. This is in line with what Mr. Shinan has always advocated: &quot;Speak from the heart, never tamper with a single word.&quot; academic spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By June 26, 2004, it was the final stage of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;. He wrote to me to introduce the writing situation of the preface of the book:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The preface can prove that the two of us have a slightly new understanding of Qingwen and do not follow what others say, precisely because we have put a lot of effort into the annotation of the works. For example, &quot;the genre is single but the styles are diverse&quot;, we not only pointed out &quot;how it is&quot; but also explained &quot;why it is so&quot;. This is the characteristic of our learning. It is also aimed at traditional Chinese literary criticism. The traditional method is improvisational and perceptive, and only points out &quot;how it is&quot; without analyzing &quot;why it is so&quot;. We have accepted the influence of Western academics and always like to pursue a &quot;why&quot;. Therefore, with regard to the emergence of the Tongcheng School (including the later Yanghu School and the Xiangxiang School) and the praise of &quot;all the articles in the world can only be found in Tongcheng&quot;, we try to find out its logical inevitability through this phenomenon. There are always laws to follow in phenomena, among which the law of cause and effect is most worth pondering, and the results of pondering are also the most thought-provoking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Tao Wenpeng heard about this preface and immediately asked Mr. Shinan to publish it in &quot;Literary Heritage&quot; in advance. Mr. Shinan said in his letter on January 12, 2005:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tao Jun asked to rewrite the preface of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; For the thesis, I have cooperated with Song Laijun. However, Huamei may not be fashionable and Zhu Yi may not nod. But I can be confident that the words and sentences of these two people come from their hearts and come from thousands of books. There is no suppression or similarity. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confidence reflected here comes from his steady reading and long-term cultivation. This spirit is reflected in his works and critical articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The method of popularizing culture through book selection is traditional, but it is an effective method of cultural communication for thousands of years. However, few people are willing to take on such work now because it requires Investing a lot of energy requires a high level of appreciation, extensive knowledge reserves and profound cultural heritage. The art of annotation is extremely difficult to learn, and it can easily lead to mistakes. However, Mr. Shinan resolutely agreed to do the work of &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot;, which shows his confidence and responsibility. After the publication of this book, readers responded very well. Mr. Shinan was very happy and wrote a letter saying:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What will your company do next year? If there is a new topic that is suitable for me to work with, I hope it will be successful. Although Gai Pu is already old, his spirit has not faded, but he is itching again and again, unhappy and unprepared to do anything. (Written in Provincial Map on October 1, 2005)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that he has the ambition of &quot;being an old man, but aiming for a thousand miles&quot;. Considering that he is old and cannot be overworked, we did not invite him to do another one. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Young Thinker&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shinan seems to be a bookworm while sitting in the library, but he is actually a &quot;young thinker&quot; ( Chen Ji&#39;s &quot;Mr. Forever Young&quot;, &quot;Occasionally Diary of Teachers and Friends&quot;). In addition to &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; and &quot;Daluoju Poetry and Essays&quot;, Mr. Shinan also has &quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; revised and reprinted, and &quot;Occasional Notes of Teachers and Friends&quot;. These two books are not &quot;pure&quot; books. , the collection is relatively mixed, the form is very random, but the theme is clear, they are all academic texts, and they are all &quot;dry information&quot;. It preserves a large number of academic correspondence, collects some book reviews, talks about academic methods, and more importantly, the academic spirit. It is interesting. We also collected some opinions that differed from those of Mr. Shinan. He said in the preface of &quot;Occasions of Teachers and Friends&quot;: &quot;&#39;The dispute is between gentlemen&#39;, and it is by no means a dispute of will. For me, it is &#39;I love my teacher, and I especially love the truth.&#39;&quot; He once again praised Mr. Mengfu, Praise him as a &quot;critical friend&quot; and &quot;admire his courage to stick to the truth.&quot; Regarding this book with the theme of &quot;I and the Intellectuals I Understand&quot;, Mr. Shinan said: &quot;The nature of this book is similar to &quot;The Inheritance of Sinology Teachers in the Kingdom of China&quot;. It is academic and can be used as a modern and contemporary book. Materials on academic history and intellectual history.&quot; Indeed, its content is more than an independent paper. It contains rich materials for contemporary scholars&#39; ideological exchanges and even confrontations. It has great academic value and is undoubtedly a breakthrough in form. and pioneering. The letter dated July 18, 2004 stated:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You will feel that this is a picture of the times, which reflects the The vigorous fighting of the soul. It can leave a valuable legacy to future generations and let them know how intellectuals in our era are searching. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;External Edition&quot; of this book includes an article &quot;How do contemporary intellectuals inherit and carry forward the fine traditions of ancient Chinese scholars?&quot; &quot;&quot; embodies his exploration on the ideological and spiritual level, letting people know that he is not a nerd, and his active mind and body surpass many young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In academic research, he has direct and in-depth discussions. In terms of poetry creation, it also has profound meaning and is worth appreciating. On January 12, 2005, he wrote a letter to talk about his &quot;Da Luo Ju Shi Cun&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. , you will know that the humble poems are not works criticizing the wind and the moon, but are all words of crying and sighing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said in the preface to &quot;Shi Cun&quot;: &quot;Any poem must be written for a purpose. It will never lament the old age and humbleness, but only the worries of the people, the country and the world.&quot; Many of his poems directly record reality, which makes people sigh and impress him with his broad mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I felt that it took Mr. Yu fourteen years to write &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;. After the book was edited and published, I wrote a book review and published it in &quot;Hainan Daily&quot;, which was later revised and published. In Guangming Daily. I sent it to Mr. Wang for review. He said in the letter dated June 4, 2004:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;is busy working on &quot;Selected Works of the Qing Dynasty&quot; , I usually put the letter aside and reply later. I didn’t expect to receive your letter today, let alone read your book review. After reading the book review carefully, I burst into tears. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You may be wondering: Why am I so easily excited? There are about seven or eight book reviews about &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, but I have never been so excited. As for you, as the editor-in-chief, you obviously read &quot;History of Qing Poetry School&quot; carefully, so you also carefully read &quot;Outside the Academic Palace&quot;. In addition, you have superb appreciation, rich life experience, and correct ideological understanding. , can I write such a book review that makes me excited. The masterpiece is not long, but it all hits the point, especially the point of humanistic care, which only you dare to point out. Frankly speaking, when I wrote &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot;, I really had the mentality of Confucius writing &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot; and Ma Qian writing &quot;Historical Records&quot;. This point was only pointed out in a book review by Professor Wang Qizhen of our school, but the article seems not to have been published yet. But you coincide with Mr. Wang, which is the most gratifying thing for me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Yunbo, please let me say a word of sincere gratitude: &quot;Uncle Bao, you know how to take care of me. I am proud that Yu Qing will not be a guest.&quot; This is a couplet made up at random, all using &quot;Historical Records&quot;, and I feel it is very relevant. Some people may question: How can people deal with things? Then I have to say it without any shame: Just consider yourself dead. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My husband affirmed the book review I wrote. I have this confidence, but I never expected that it would make him &quot;cry with emotion&quot; and write &quot;Uncle Bao knows how to manage&quot; and so on. words of thanks; he directly confided his ambitions and pursuits, which shows that he didn&#39;t take anything for granted. In 2011, he recorded a super-star academic video, talking about &quot;Me and the History of the Qing Poetry School&quot; (later included in &quot;Occasional Notes of Teachers and Friends&quot;), and mentioned that &quot;Mr. Ge Yunbo is really my close friend.&quot; All of this moved me very much, and made me feel the power of the seniors to inspire the younger generations. It also made me feel the glory of being a down-to-earth editor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above experiences have undoubtedly increased our closeness. When our family went to Nanchang for the first time to visit Mr. Shinan on October 6, 2018, the host and guest were delighted. He held my hand forcefully and held on for a long time. It was not like the hand of a 96-year-old man at all. He can support himself. He also often goes to the library. We all believe that he can easily survive his old age. We look forward to visiting him again. But unexpectedly, I received a text message from Professor Song Lai on August 2, 2021, and learned that Mr. Shinan passed away the night before. I originally wanted to write a sentimental article after learning from the pain, but I was burdened with publishing projects and was unable to do so. This year marks the 100th anniversary of Mr. Shinan&#39;s birth. I made up my mind to write a brief statement of my admiration and gratitude for him, so I came up with the above immature commemorative text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[娄底7岁女孩遭性霸凌疑云：到底是夸大其词还是轻描淡写？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen in Loudi, Hunan claimed that his 7-year-old daughter was raped by more than a dozen female classmates in her class during lunch break at school. Bullying and even injuries to the private parts have attracted great attention on the Internet. The local report stated that an investigation confirmed that a female student was involved in a brief brawl, but no intentional harm was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 28, a parent from Loudi, Hunan Province posted on social media, saying that his 7-year-old daughter was studying in the second grade of a primary school in a township in Loudi, Hunan Province. During lunch break on October 20, she was raped by 16 or 17 girls in her class. The classmates bullied her on the playground. These female classmates not only beat her daughter, but also sexually bullied her, causing injuries to her lower body and causing unbearable pain. Both the school and the parents of the bullying students have a negative attitude towards solving the problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Little girls in the second grade collectively bullied their female classmates, especially sexual bullying, which was appalling. People can&#39;t help but think of the sexual bullying incident of a 9-year-old primary school student in a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi that came to light a few months ago. Therefore, the incident quickly became a hot spot on the Internet and attracted great attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, Lengshuijiang City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Loudi City), where the incident occurred, issued a situation statement in the name of a joint investigation team, saying that after discovering the relevant videos, the Municipal Education Bureau immediately established a , the Public Security Bureau and other departments. After preliminary investigation by the public security department, it was found that the girl involved Zhang and six other female classmates were classmates in the second grade of a primary school in the city; at noon on October 20, because of an incident while skipping rope on the playground There was a dispute and &quot;mutual fighting&quot; occurred for about 1 minute, during which Zhang was &quot;briefly surrounded and slapped&quot; by several other classmates; after monitoring and monitoring was obtained, the girl involved was questioned &quot;protectively&quot;, and the witnessing teachers and students were investigated, but no evidence was found. Intentional injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The characterization of the incident in this official report is completely different from the accusation made by the victim’s mother. The description of the incident process is also vague and unclear, and there is no clarification on the key issues of the accusation. If the official has sufficient evidence that the girl&#39;s parents are exaggerating, they should publicly refute the evidence. Otherwise, not only will it fail to eliminate public doubts, but it will arouse greater doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first question is whether the girl Zhang’s lower body was injured. According to information released by Zhang&#39;s mother, Zhang had multiple soft tissue injuries on his body and his lower body was also injured. He was in unbearable pain when urinating and was forced to hold in his urine. However, although the official report confirmed that &quot;mutual fighting&quot; occurred, it did not mention whether Zhang was injured. This is also the aspect that attracts the most attention from netizens and makes people the most angry. Officials should not shy away from this, they should investigate this and make the results public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Zhang’s lower body is indeed injured, then this is a very serious violation of minors. The cause of the injury must be found out. If it involves criminal behavior, he must be severely punished. If Zhang was not injured, then enough credible evidence must be produced to refute the accusations made by the girl’s parents. For example, Zhang can be taken to a tertiary hospital outside Loudi City for examination accompanied by his parents, and the examination results can be announced. If Zhang’s mother exaggerates or lies, she should not avoid it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, it is necessary to release the relevant video of the incident that occurred on the playground to set the record straight. Zhang’s mother said that Zhang was beaten by 16 or 17 girls in his class on the playground. The official statement stated that except for Zhang, only six students were involved in the incident, and that several girls were &quot;fighting with each other&quot; for only about a minute, while Zhang was only &quot;briefly surrounded&quot; and &quot;swatted&quot; by several classmates. According to the two sides, not only the number of participants is hugely different, but there is also a huge difference in nature between &quot;beating&quot; and &quot;fighting with each other.&quot; Since the official statement mentioned that the police obtained the school&#39;s surveillance video, it means that the incident was recorded, and it was not the &quot;aging surveillance&quot; mentioned by the school in Zhang&#39;s mother&#39;s post. Since there is a video, it should be made public in its entirety so that the public can judge for themselves whether it was a &quot;beating&quot; or a &quot;fighting&quot;, how long it lasted, and whether there was any &quot;intentional harm.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, for the sake of protecting minors, minors who can be identified in the video can be treated with protective techniques, such as mosaic, blurred faces, etc., but it should be ensured that several minors can be seen. The individual&#39;s involvement in the incident, and the extent of the &quot;ruffling&quot; involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems a bit incredible that a 7-year-old girl would bully her classmates and also be sexually involved. But it&#39;s not impossible. In a bullying incident at a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi, the bully was only 9 years old. This was not the first time that bullying had occurred, it had also started in the second grade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a stereotype that bullies in school are boys. In fact, this is not the case. Among school violence incidents, the proportion of women committing violence is not low. In March 2023, a bullying incident broke out in Hainan in which a 13-year-old girl was beaten and humiliated by a group of same-sex peers. When the Datong incident attracted great attention, criminal law teacher Cai also received news that a female classmate was bullied by other female classmates in the dormitory, and also engaged in sexual behavior, and the perpetrator even took a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, CCTV reported on a study and found that more than 80% of the perpetrators of school bullying videos posted on the Internet were women. Of course, this may be related to the fact that female bullies are more likely to take videos and upload them online to humiliate their victims, but it also shows that female perpetrators of school violence are by no means uncommon. Moreover, among the campus bullying committed by women, many of them are a group of people bullying one person, and the targets of their bullying are mostly women. Also, among the bullying committed by women, a high proportion involves sexual humiliation, such as being forced to strip naked and take photos. This may be because it creates a stronger sense of shame for the victim. These characteristics of female bullying are consistent with the accusations made by the mother of the victim in the Loudi incident that more than a dozen girls beat and sexually bullied her daughter. This is one of the reasons why netizens are more willing to believe victims’ accusations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter has attracted great attention on the Internet, and the official understatement of the situation is obviously difficult to convince the public. This reminds people of the sexual bullying incident at a bilingual school in Datong, Shanxi. The school and the authorities tried to turn the incident into a minor matter, but in the end, the bullying incident was confirmed. The same is true for this suspected bullying incident in Loudi. If the authorities have sufficient evidence to support their account of the situation, they should make it public promptly to refute the accusations made by the girl&#39;s parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTp OzxQVWlMy0o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009), a contemporary master of rituals and a famous Confucian scholar, dedicated his life to Studying the study of the three rites, he has made outstanding achievements in many fields such as etiquette, history of Confucian classics, philology, inscriptions on oracle bones, bibliography, and compilation of ancient books. In particular, the study of the &quot;three rites&quot; has solved many problems in the history of etiquette and Confucian classics. Many unresolved problems were highly praised by Gu Jiegang. The picture was taken in May 1986. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo (1917-2009) was an &quot;invisible man&quot; at Hangzhou University. In October 1978, I entered the Chinese Department as an undergraduate student. He once gave us a few lectures on &quot;Common Knowledge of Ancient Culture&quot; in the &quot;Ancient Chinese&quot; class, but no one had much impression of him. When I was in graduate school, he was a member of the mentor group, and I started to get to know him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The headquarters of Hangzhou University (today’s Xixi Campus of Zhejiang University) in the early 1980s was small in area. Tall plane trees stretched out towards the boulevard, forming domes, showing the history of this campus. years. In the southeast corner are several rows of four-story buildings made of blue-grey bricks. The teachers&#39; dormitory and the graduate student dormitory face each other. Between the two floors is the boiler room, where the fire roars in the morning and we go there every day to turn on the water. In autumn and winter, the sycamore leaves have faded to gray, and the walkways of the boiler room are covered with finely crushed coal ash. Against the blue-grey brick walls, the vision is gray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Mr. Shen lived in a room on the first floor of the first unit of Building No. 1, about fifteen or six square meters, opposite the public toilet. It was humid in spring, sultry in summer, and cold in winter. . There was no kitchen, so he could only light a fire in the corridor, so for more than 20 years, he had been eating in the canteen, occasionally cooking hoof bones and the like to improve his life. It wasn&#39;t until 1986 that he was assigned a two-bedroom house and moved out of here (in July of that year, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor by the State Council&#39;s Discipline Review Group). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have never entered his residence, but every time I pass by, I will stop for a moment. Later, I visited his door many times in my dreams. Through the glass above the door, I seemed to see the banners on the wall, but I couldn&#39;t always see clearly what was inside. It was like his personality and education were very mysterious and hard to see clearly. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I often meet him on the way to the cafeteria. He was over sixty years old at that time, with a broad forehead, sparse hair, and a gray beard, but his face was very rosy. He is not tall, but very strong. In winter, he put on an old gray smock over his old cotton-padded jacket, and carried a shallow bamboo basket in his left hand, which also looked like a dustpan. His big hands had thick knuckles. He always had a smile on his face and seemed to be moving as he walked on the road, making a slight &quot;huffing&quot; sound in his mouth. If he encounters the gaze of others, he responds with a smile in his eyes, his mouth seems to be moving, but he does not speak. He looked gentle and calm, yet as deep as the ocean. He beams with energy when he smiles, inspiring passers-by. So I think he was in a good mood at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we &quot;new&quot; graduate students often talked about at that time was our own supervisors and each other&#39;s supervisors: which field we mainly worked in, what books we published, where we published papers, and what we heard about them. What are the requirements for students, what are the mantras, what new things were said in class...proudly introduce the findings of the instructor, share with each other, and listen carefully to other people&#39;s additions and discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Roommate Chen Shenyong is the first graduate student led by Mr. Shen Wenzhuo. My understanding of Mr. Shen gradually enriched through classmate Sheng Yong’s admiring explanations and everyone’s discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Fang Jianxin, Mr. Shen, Li Jiemin, Wang Yunlu (photographed in 1997). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Shen Wenzhuo, whose courtesy name is Fengsheng and nickname is Yinan, is from Wujiang, Jiangsu. He entered a private school when he was young, and studied by himself when he was older, without obtaining any diploma. In his early years, he studied ancient Chinese poetry from Shen Chang, and studied literature and history from Jin Tianhe and Yao Tingjie. In the early 1940s, he specialized in the study of &quot;Three Rites&quot; from Cao Yuanbi and became his close disciple, teaching and mentoring him for nine years.曹元弼（1867-1954），人称清代最后一位杰出的经学家，时已年逾古稀，故寄厚望于沈文倬：“善守可望有成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年，他发表了《说高禖》《“蜡”与“腊”》等文章，引起顾颉刚的注意，破格聘其为国立编译馆副编审，主要负责校点经籍、编撰提要、草拟经学词典。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，被派往北京华北人民革命大学政治学院学习。次年6月，分配至上海图书馆，任编目部副主任。我们经常查阅的《中国丛书综录》，极厚的三册，叠起来有一尺多高，就是由他主持编成的。 1960年，《综录》编辑组被评为上海市先进集体，身为组长的他，作为代表出席了上海市群英会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1963年2月，应姜亮夫教授的邀请，调入中国科学院浙江分院的语言文学研究室（设在杭州大学，夏承焘为主任），为专职研究人员，只身赴杭州。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3月，甫抵杭，即往谒马一浮先生；4月下旬，再往。 “以后学求谒前辈学者之礼相见，主亲客敬，融洽无间”。有所悟，也有所思，撰有《蒋庄问学记》以记之。秋后到长春东北文史研究所讲《仪礼》，入冬回杭。欲再谒，未成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年，“谈论古学的风气戛然而止，而情趣也大减”。不久，即下乡参加“社教运动”，到了我的家乡诸暨县的某公社，驻留有时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前，他有多篇论文在《考古》上发表（1961，1963），传言时任中国科学院院长的郭沫若先生见后，评价颇高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“文革”发生后，研究室解散，他转入杭大中文系，在系资料室做资料员。因博闻强记，同事惊为“活字典”。他则独自默处，但从未停止礼学研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1974年，被安排赴安吉参加杭大最后一期“五七”干校“农林班”，白天做“鸭司令”，晚间仍探礼学之奥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1975年3月，将《武威出土&amp;lt;礼&amp;gt;汉简考辨》等四种，寄请顾颉刚先生审阅。顾复信称“台端实为今世治礼经者之第一人也”，同时又叹息，这些成果不知何时才能面世。以上这些话语，当时只是在一个很小的圈子内流传，并不为外界知闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;顾颉刚复沈文倬函。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到“文革”结束, 情况又有了变化。 1979年，他转到教师岗位。次年，评为副研究员，时已64岁。我们82级研究生，是他第一次招生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时杭大对中华书局的《文史》和上海古籍的《中华文史论丛》最为推崇，视为古代文史领域的顶刊，沈先生则是其中的常客。其中如《略论礼典的实行和〈仪礼〉书本的撰作》(《文史》15、16辑，1983)，提出“礼典的实践早于文字记录而存在”，由以阐明礼典与礼书的关系，后来杨向奎先生称此文是“鸿文巨制，成绩空前”。又如《黄龙十二博士的定员和太学郡国学校的设置》（1983）一文,对汉代建立经学博士的复杂史实条分缕析，正皮锡瑞《经学历史》之误，纠王国维《汉魏博士考》之偏，从而详判武、昭、宣三代各经博士官的兴废增缺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有后学称，沈先生的文章视野非常开阔，既有宏观的关照，贯通古今，又有微观的考证，心细如发。同时运用各种方法容纳材料，信息量极大。他对传统礼学中的任何问题，几乎都有独到的见解，文中的每一句话，几乎都凝聚着思考的结果。他的叙述语言非常典雅，几乎与引用文献可以无缝对接，是一种很难达到的境界。对此，我也深表赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，我那时并没有认真拜读过沈先生的著作与论文，也怕读，因为太深奥了。我只是读过他在《中华文史论丛》上的专栏，名为“菿闇述礼”，有时一期刊发数则，所占篇幅，不过一两页，所释则为一字或一物，都属疑难问题之解说，于文史研究关系颇大，而文字典雅凝练，令我叹服不已。这类短文，他从1946年就开始写作了,采山之铜，累积甚丰。很多年后，他汇集成书，仍取栏目之名，不过薄薄一册，十余万字，但甚得好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬先生在书斋中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我开始学写论文时，就知道短论文是最难写的，因为数百字、千余字，要提出一个真问题，罗列材料并且讲清楚，是多么的困难呵！据说沈先生的另一本著作《〈礼〉汉简异文释》，写成时有四十余万字，他并不急于发表，反复压缩，最后出版时，只有十六万字。在我们读研究生时（1982.9-1985.6），他除了一些论文，尚无著作出版。他的第一部专著《宗周礼乐文明考论》,其实是他的论文集，在1999年才问世，写作跨度逾40年，总数也才14篇。那时他已经是耄耋之年了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生一生淡于名利。他说：“治经治礼不易，只有心除&#39;魔障&#39;，胸臆如水，方能专注向学，趋于会通。”他一生的著述其实不多，学者却推许他为“礼学大师”，因为他的文章不靠量的堆积，而是以质取胜。他的每一篇文章都解决了历史上悬而未决的问题，累积起来，便令人叹为观止，且是仰之弥高了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非常幸运的是，沈先生专门为我们开了课。当时我们五名研究生，由五位导师指导，他们每人讲授三堂课，构成了一个学期的研究生课程。他的三堂课，连郭在贻老师也来听了，就坐在后排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生从小患有严重的口吃，连讲一句完整的话，对他而言，都是很吃力的事情。这也是他很少上课的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时老师们所讲的内容是自选的，也都是多年深思所得。印象中，沈文倬先生讲到了先秦诸子流派和古文今文有关问题。在我当时有限的知识里，《论》《孟》《老》《庄》作为独立的著述，稍有涉猎，《墨子》未曾读过，《礼》《书》则不敢碰，至于各家之间的关系，则全无了解。沈先生的课，却讲出了各派思想之间错综复杂的关系，特别是稷下学派、名家，这些几无著述传世的学派，原来也曾在与各家的角逐中占得大势，令其他各家不得不作回应与调整；某些消失的流派，其学说则为他家所融合而流传于后世。这让我忽然明白，原来每一家说法都不是在对某种理论来作完整系统的阐释，而是针对对手发表自己的观点，如果不知道这个论辩的背景，便会觉得其论极偏，像是对着空气作战，不知其所以然。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很像我在篮球场上打中锋，每一次强打，都必须用力把背后顶着我的那个人靠开，才能翻身把球打进。你必须知道那“顶”的力量有多大，才能明白我这一“靠”要花多少的气力。若是将我身后的人物虚化，人们在镜头中只见我对着空气用力地先靠后转，必然会嘲笑我过度使用了蛮力，即所谓“失之偏颇”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的课室里，沈先生“哧哧”地把一个个字从口中用力地迸出来，有些词花了两三次方才说得完整，就用手绢擦一擦汗水，口中依然不停。讲到开心处，他也会带着吃吃的笑声。他先用他自己的考证与解说，重新厘定了旧有概念，然后再作延伸，对一连串的问题提出新的界说，于是相关的人物事件、流派学说，被拂去久积的尘垢，露出了完全不同的容貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们所有人都肃然聆听，唯恐错过了一个音节。因为那一个个迸出来的字，如同一个个阵符在空中翻飞，构成了一个奇妙的阵法，从中显现出历史的真相。那阵势如此波诡云谲，力与力你来我往，波与波争相角逐，声与理相互呼应，这端的是百家争鸣的时代啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四十多年过去了，沈先生的具体解说，我只留下了若干印象，例如“礼书”晚于“礼典”；“古文”最初是指六国文字，“今文”则指汉隶，他从文本书写所用文字的角度，解释各经诸文本在汉代的传承情况；某人的解说，被立于学官，即是“师法”，未立之时，则是“家法”……其他具体的知识，如今大都已经忘记，只有他“哧哧”的声音，偶然还在我的耳边响起，于是他的讲解所引发的那种感触，再次如潮水般漫过我的脑回路，让我感受到一种莫名的震荡。更为重要的是，通过这些讲解，我懂得必须透过文献的表象，去感受时代背后那一道道的“力”及其相互作用，才能依稀看见上帝那只“无形之手”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生在谒见马一浮先生后，撰有一诗：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;儒经释典一炉熔，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;证得心同理亦同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;善美深微容别解，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;舒徐礼乐自圆融。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并记云：“（马）先生知予治姬旦之礼，颇申礼善乐美之旨，为之赞叹不已。予亦进&#39;舒徐&#39;一义，先生颔之者再，不以别解见摒焉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我回忆沈先生的三堂课，记录当时所见所闻的点点滴滴，敬取他的末句为题，以表怀念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解聘247名自聘科级干部：萍乡经开区“瘦身”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年， 2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者翟星理/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是我人生中的一次重大选择。”2023年4月，张世春选择放弃体制内身份，留在江西省萍乡经济技术开发区某大型国企工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，他已经在这家国企工作了4年，但保留着事业单位编制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月，萍乡经开区根据萍乡市委市政府通过的人事制度改革方案，宣布撤销19个自设机构，并解聘247名自聘科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被解聘人员中有相当一部分原本就是在编人员，经开区自聘的职务被解除后，他们可以选择保留编制、由经开区统筹安排新的工作岗位，也可以放弃编制到企业工作。原本就是编外人员的被解聘者，则可以参加全员竞聘上岗，也可以选择辞职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春就是一位由萍乡经开区自聘的科级干部，面对改革，他有两个选择，“想保留编内身份就要回机关，想留在企业就必须放弃编制”。召开一场家庭会议后，他决定留在企业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春成为自聘干部的成因并不复杂。作为中国最早设立的经开区之一，萍乡经开区经过31年发展，人口从最初的1万人增加到现在的约25万人，职能也由单一的经济开发拓展到兼顾社会管理和公共服务等，发展过程中自设管理机构、自设岗位、自聘人员，这其中既有客观原因，也有以前机构编制管理不规范、用人随意性较大等主观原因。而这也是国内开发区普遍存在的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，中共中央、国务院印发《党和国家机构改革方案》，明确中央和地方都要进行编制精简。在此基础上，多地开始清理编外人员，黑龙江省哈尔滨市、湖北省十堰市、云南省楚雄州、广东省惠州市、湖南省株洲市等地纷纷出台清理编外人员的方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区全面规范人事管理，在解聘的247名干部中，包含清退违规借用人员63人，辞退17人，另有8人放弃事业编制到企业工作。改革后全员推行“主办制管理”（一种人员管理方式，将在编人员和编外人员统一聘为各级主办），而非简单将编外人员“扫地出门”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;被解聘的副部长&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生于1970年的张世春，参加工作后先当了10年教师，本来的身份就是事业编制。离开学校后，张世春进入教育局工作，1997年又调到萍乡经开区，后来当上了经开区党工委党群工作部副部长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，因工作需要，张世春被调整到经开区一家大型国资企业担任党委副书记、纪委书记，编制还保留在经开区党群工作部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时像世春这样的情况还是比较多的。”党群工作部副部长喻志峰解释，即从经开区机关到企业任职，仍然保留着机关编制的这类人员，一共有七八位。国有企业都没有事业编制，但他们仍然保留着事业编制身份，属于经开区自聘的科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自聘，就是自行聘任，未经上级组织部门备案，上级组织部门并不认可。如果一个公务员或事业编人员经正常组织流程被任命为副科级干部，需要上级组织部门为其备案，但经开区根据工作需要，未经上级组织部门备案就聘为正科级，那么实际上他的级别仍然是副科级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年和2022年，江西省委巡视组两次巡视萍乡都指出这个问题。以2022年为例，当年4月省委第四巡视组巡视萍乡，7月28日，第四巡视组向萍乡经开区党工委反馈巡视情况，4条主要意见中第三条就是针对经开区的组织工作，“完善上下贯通、执行有力的组织体系差距较大”。巡视组提出整改意见建议，“聚焦解决好机构人事领域重点突出问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喻志峰介绍，经开区人事领域比较突出的问题就是自设机构过多、自聘干部过多：经过多年发展，经开区自聘的科级干部达到247人，主要有三类：经开区在编人员、上级机关或兄弟区县调入的干部、经开区自聘的编外人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人事改革工作启动后，经开区组织相关领导干部对这247名自聘干部进行一对一谈话，由经开区党工委主要领导牵头。喻志峰说，一对一谈话持续了几个月，主要是阐释政策和改革的紧迫性，“耐心细致地做解聘对象的思想工作”。对于原本就在编内的自聘干部，给他们选择权，可以放弃编制选择在企业工作或保留编制在机关任职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春更倾向于放弃编制留在企业任职，但他也对家人讲明了在企业任职的风险：一旦企业发展遇到困难，他的收入也会随之下降，甚至可能失业，“我们商量之后最终决定我留在企业，也是相信经开区改革后企业会发展得更好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，执行解聘工作的喻志峰本人也是自聘干部。被解聘前，他的职务是党群工作部党支部书记、副部长。解聘后，他还是事业编，但只保留了党群部副部长的职务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“小马拉大车”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;解聘247名自聘干部的同时，萍乡经开区还撤并了19个自设机构，包括区政法委、区国资委、区信访局等。喻志峰解释，“在多年经开区发展的历程中，随着不断增加的社会事务和服务人口，经开区在未取得上级同意的情况下违规自设了机构、聘任了大量干部。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年，1995年升格为省级开发区，2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区，2021年12月底调区扩容后辖区总面积119平方公里，常住人口约25万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2021年6月，国家级经济技术开发区有230个。萍乡经开区GDP已连续5年稳居全国百强经开区行列，2022年全国排名第62位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和全国其他经开区一样，萍乡经开区也是市政府的派出机关，为功能区而非行政区。 “设置之初，经开区的职能单一，主要是经济发展任务，因此上级部门给经开区核定的编制数不多。”萍乡经开区党工委党群部部长朱敏告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经开区提供给南方周末记者的材料显示，经开区设置之初并未划定具体区域范围，1995年升为省级开发区后，萍乡市政府决定将6个行政村划作直接开发范围，开发面积10平方公里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“按照这样的面积和人口，当时经开区也确实不需要太多编制。”朱敏说，但在发展过程中，萍乡经开区的面积逐渐扩大，而且伴随产业聚集、萍乡市老城区人口纾解等因素，导致经开区人口剧增。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按萍乡市官方发布的数据，经开区常住人口从2011年的11万人增长至2021年的25万人。同年，萍乡市下辖的芦溪县常住人口为26万人，莲花县常住人口为21万人。这意味着，经开区管理的人口与萍乡市的普通县城相当。在经济规模上，萍乡经开区2022年新年贺词显示，2021年前三季度经开区完成地区生产总值223.159亿元，总量列萍乡市第1位。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;管理25万人口的萍乡经开区有多少编制？朱敏介绍，2022年，上级编制部门对经开区管委会编制进行了重新核定，现有参公编102名，事业编138名，合计编制240名。而南方周末记者从权威渠道了解到，周边地市某区公务员编制有700多名，事业编有1000多名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为应对随着人口和区域面积不断增加而增加的社会管理职能，萍乡经开区开始自设机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，经开区自设机构基本分为两种情况：人口增长产生社会管理需求，必须自设机构提供公共服务；市级职能部门出于垂直管理需要，要求经开区设立相应机构以进行工作对接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，经开区自设5个社会工作管理局，每个局管理几个行政村，实际上履行的是乡镇政府或城市街道办职能；经开区的城管局、园林管理局的设立，则是因为萍乡市城管局、园林管理局要求经开区也设立管理机构，便于城管、园林工作在萍乡全市统一规划和开展工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一些自设机构是经开区为统筹条线工作而设置的。经开区公安机关是萍乡市公安局设立的开发区分局，检察职能由萍乡市检察院设立的驻开发区检察室履行，审判机构由安源区法院托管，设立了开发区法庭。为了统筹公检法和信访、巡访、综治工作，经开区又自设了政法委。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过31年开发建设，经开区已成为一个高度产城融合的功能区，经开区管委会的职能从单一转向综合，事实上在履行类似区县政府的职能。南方周末记者采访期间，经开区一位主要领导分析，以现有编制和人员数，经开区要履行好所有管理职能有点像“小马拉大车”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“锁死入口，畅通出口”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自设机构、自聘干部过多虽然有实际工作的需要，但也是机构人事管理不够规范造成的，机构、干部过多也产生了很多不良后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在干部队伍建设上，上级组织部门不认可经开区自聘干部，对干部成长造成了不利影响，这客观上是不利于干部的培养的。”喻志峰解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏调任经开区任党群工作部部长之前在萍乡市委组织部任职。 2019年，朱敏到萍乡市委组织部干部一科工作，负责联系经开区，“当时我就提过经开区组织工作不规范的问题，自设机构太多”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，萍乡市委、市政府大力推进萍乡经开区人事制度改革，市委组织部、市委编办、市发改委等部门牵头组织外出学习其他地区经开区人事改革的经验。到2022年，人事改革推进的力度明显加大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年第11期《中国机构改革与管理》杂志刊发了萍乡市委编办的署名文章《萍乡推动编外人员规范化管理》。文章总结萍乡市对于编外聘用人员进行清理的工作经验，总体原则是把编外聘用人员和在编人员统一纳入总量管理，机构编制部门根据部门的职能和编制情况核定编外聘用人员员额，对超出核定员额的编外聘用人员坚决清理，对员额内的编外聘用人员规范化管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文章还总结了使用编外人员的方向，对行政审批、行政执法、档案管理、政工人事、信访以及涉密等岗位禁止使用编外聘用人员；坚持“管事不聘人”的原则，用人单位的物业管理、安保、绿化养护、食堂服务、信息网络服务、公共建筑设施和设备维护等工作，除中小学、幼儿园食堂外，一律不得使用编外聘用人员，全部采取市场服务外包、政府购买服务的方式予以解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，经开区此次清理编外聘用人员也在上述原则框定的范围内进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月人事制度改革后，经开区根据萍乡市委、市政府批复的人事制度改革方案实行了员额总控。在这个基础上，经开区进一步规定，按照员额总控的要求，未来不再新增编外人员，只在编制限额内招录人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“锁死编外人员进入经开区的入口，同时强化对现有人员的考核管理，推行末位淘汰制，畅通出口。”朱敏说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;绝不是“扫地出门”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在解聘自聘干部时，经开区主要担心的是引起解聘对象的过度反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏就改革方案向萍乡市委主要领导进行过汇报，“领导强调了大方向：改革的目的不是把你们经开区改没了，经开区仍然是萍乡经济发展的引擎。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;撤并19个自设机构后，重新调整工作归口，将撤并掉的机构职能分别并入经开区党政办公室、经济发展局、社会发展局等8个内设机构和园区企业服务中心、社会治理中心等8个事业单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，经开区打破身份界限，对在编人员和编外人员统一实行“主办制管理”，不区分是否在编，只看岗位，主办共分为12级，每个级别对应不同的薪酬。主办有晋级机制也有降级机制，并且设置了每年5%的考核不合格率，明确连续两年考核不合格的直接予以淘汰，实现主办级别能上能下，薪酬绩效能升能降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在朱敏看来，经开区逐步消化编外人员绝不是简单的“扫地出门”，而是通过主办制让留下来的编内编外人员在同一个赛道竞争，“不管是体制内的还是体制外的，都要给这些年轻人留机会”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者采访期间，经开区正在进行一项调研，主题是探索干部队伍激励的新机制，通过竞岗、转岗、待岗、降岗、解聘等方式，构建具有竞争性的选拔机制。南方周末记者向经开区几位主办求证，他们表示在机构改革之后，工作节奏更快、工作强度更高、工作压力更大。 2023年国庆假期后，不少主办连续工作至今，周末基本也只能休息半天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而另一个原因是，机构撤并、清退人员后，原有机构的社会管理职能并未完全剥离，各项职能被划分至新成立的事业单位中，因此工作总量并未减少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，随着下一轮改革的到来，全国的经济技术开发区或许将迎来一次职能上的“瘦身”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年3月发布的《安徽省“十四五”开发区高质量发展规划》，有专门章节论述开发区体制机制改革，重点提到&amp;nbsp;合理划分开发区管理机构、属地政府、开发运营公司实权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，《河南省开发区高质量发展促进条例（草案）》提请河南省人大常委会第一次审议，草案明确管委会主要承担政策制定、发展规划、行政审批、招商引资、企业服务等行政管理职能，未提及社会管理职能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两地的表述都释放出一个信号：省级层面对开发区的职能定位也许仍然是经济发展。那么，在各地开发区发展过程中逐渐增加的社会管理职能如何处理？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，国家层面针对全国开发区下一轮体制机制改革的总体规划中，理顺开发区与行政区的关系，逐渐剥离社会事务管理职能是趋势之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>