<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“4个月挣250元”，去横店当“童漂”值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260937]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 12:25:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/26999ccfcca7220487e539964eb758de.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/26999ccfcca7220487e539964eb758de. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, many parents are now taking their children to work as &quot;child slaves&quot; in Hengdian, looking for opportunities to star in film and television dramas. The life of &quot;child drifters&quot; is also very bitter. &quot;100 people fight for one seat&quot;, &quot;earn 250 yuan in 4 months&quot;, and &quot;pay a large amount of money to join the group&quot; are the norm for many &quot;child drifters&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media statistics, among the films, online dramas, TV series and other film and television cultural works filmed in Hengdian in 2022, 230 will have underage entertainers participating, with more than 6,000 people participating. This number is not small, and it is also the reason why &quot;child drifting&quot; exists - Hengdian does provide opportunities to act and become famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, with the influx of children and their families from all walks of life who have dreams, &quot;child drifting&quot; quickly becomes involuntarily involved. The &quot;child drifting&quot; industry can no longer be said to be a pure dream-chasing story, but has evolved into a bizarre capital game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;With 20,000 yuan in 1 year, you are guaranteed to be in at least 3 plays within 1 year, and you can appear as special actors, etc.. With 50,000 in 3 years, you are guaranteed to be in at least 8 plays in 3 years, and you can be in special actors and roles, etc.&quot; , this is the charging model of several children&#39;s agency companies in Hengdian reported in the media. According to the payment amount, they are divided into various levels of &quot;members&quot; and then equipped with corresponding resources. Obviously, for families who lack economic foundation, &quot;child drifting&quot; is already very cruel, and the return rate is extremely low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another problem with &quot;child drifting&quot; is that the main subjects of pursuing dreams are children. If they are in an unstable situation, what about education? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Compulsory Education Law stipulates that parents or other legal guardians of school-age children and teenagers shall ensure that they enter school on time, accept and complete compulsory education in accordance with the law. If parents let their children leave school early for the dream of being a child star, it is already suspected of breaking the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if a child successfully completes compulsory education, the basic education is too weak, and the impact may be lifelong. The cost of &quot;child drift&quot; is too huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, parents should have a more rational and comprehensive assessment of the risks of child abuse. After all, there is huge uncertainty in &quot;what you do is what you want&quot;. Is it wise for a family to risk everything for an opportunity with a very low probability? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, children do not yet have full capacity for civil conduct, and they do not actually have a complete and clear understanding of the nature of their own behavior. Many children do like acting, but they lack awareness of &quot;sunk costs&quot; - once their acting career is blocked, how can children return to their regular growth path? Children are ignorant of this, and parents who lack prudence are undoubtedly irresponsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is no need for public opinion to make excessive criticism of &quot;child drifters&quot; and their families. Some common criticisms on the Internet, such as &quot;using children as money-making tools&quot; and &quot;parents have dreams of getting rich&quot;, are not necessarily accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the interviews that many parents just want to try their best to help their children realize their dreams because their children want to act. They are not necessarily profit-driven parents. This is essentially the same as asking their children to &quot;attend a prestigious school&quot;. They have both chosen a very involutive path with uncertain prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While parents are advised to be cautious, society should also intervene. For example, whether those entertainment agencies are formal or not should actually attract the attention of relevant departments. Some parents reported that &quot;bringing money to join the group&quot; was suspected of being defrauded. After paying the money, not only did they have nothing to do, but they were also &quot;blacklisted&quot; by the person involved. For these, the market supervision department should follow relevant clues to investigate whether there are any violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A red line that cannot be blurred is: no matter what growth path a family chooses for their children, education must be compulsorily implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In any case, the bitterness of Hengdian&#39;s &quot;child drifting&quot; is, after all, an unspeakable involution. The journey of chasing dreams is of course full of hardships, but this path does not seem to fit in with a simple narrative of children’s growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of this, parents still need to carefully consider whether &quot;child drifting&quot; is suitable for their family situations; and society should obviously work hard to eliminate the risks and hazards involved, protect the rights of minors, and at least allow them to There are fewer pitfalls on the road to &quot;Tongpiao&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[假如我变成了“熊孩子”丨世界儿童日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉罪的“豆芽”：网售体彩242亿元被控非法经营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260927]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On August 3, 2022, Hohhot, passengers on the China Sports Lottery &quot;Lucky Train&quot; Photos taken on the theme train. (People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258819&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 3, 2022, Hohhot, passengers took photos on the China Sports Lottery &quot;Lucky Train&quot; themed train. (People’s Vision/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The online platform is no longer available?&quot; On November 15, 2023, Wu Yong, the owner of a sports lottery shop in Changxing County, Zhejiang Province, Another inquiry from a regular customer popped up on WeChat. He receives similar messages almost every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong operates 5 sports betting shops in the county. He was once the owner of the national outstanding sports betting outlets selected by the Sports Lottery Management Center of the State Sports General Administration. But now, he is planning to transfer three of the stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On February 16, 2023, Wu Yong was detained by the Public Security Bureau of Jishui County, Jiangxi Province on suspicion of illegal business operations. He was released on bail after &quot;returning the stolen goods&quot; of 1.2 million yuan. Awaiting trial. The Jishui County Procuratorate determined that from 2019 to 2023, Wu Yong sold 127 million yuan in sports betting through the &quot;Douya&quot; App, making illegal profits of more than 8.1 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The operating model of the &quot;Douya&quot; App is that lottery players place orders online, and the store owners will issue tickets at offline lottery stores after receiving notifications. App operators make money by collecting a 1% handling fee from store owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the indictment, there are nearly 14,000 lottery agency stores registered in Douya, with more than 2.71 million lottery players. From 2019 to 2023, the total number of lottery tickets sold through &quot;Douzhao&quot; was approximately 24.2 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From a time perspective, the actions Wu Yong and others were accused of mainly occurred after the state cleaned up and rectified online lottery sales in 2015. In the past eight years, the Ministry of Finance has not Open authorization for online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the criminal law, one condition that constitutes the crime of illegal business is violation of &quot;national regulations.&quot; However, the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; formulated by the State Council in 2009 do not provide for the sale of lottery tickets through the Internet. Relevant regulations are formulated by the Ministry of Finance and other relevant ministries and commissions. During the trial of this case, the focus of dispute between the prosecution and the defense was whether Wu Yong and others violated &quot;national regulations&quot; by selling lottery tickets through the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Ban&quot; brings dividends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong&#39;s lottery The store business started ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2013, the year before the World Cup in Brazil, Wu Yong, a fan, rented a storefront in the business district of Changxing County and ran his first sports betting shop. Open. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, many leading Internet companies launched online lottery sales businesses on their respective platforms, and the business of offline lottery stores was not booming. According to Wu Yong, online lottery sales services have attracted a large number of young people. Before the start of the World Cup, the business of his lottery shop &quot;basically only returned the money&quot;, and most of the customers were acquaintances who watched the football with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After reviewing relevant public information, the Ministry of Finance has not publicly disclosed the size of the Internet lottery market. One data for reference is the &quot;2014 Internet Lottery Market Analysis Report&quot; released by Pantone Consulting, an organization that has long tracked the lottery market. It shows that in that year, China&#39;s Internet lottery sales reached 85 billion, doubling the sales volume in 2013. The market share exceeded 20% for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the hot Internet lottery market was quickly cooled by policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On January 15, 2015, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued the &quot;Self-examination and self-correction work on unauthorized use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets&quot; Notice on Problems&quot;. At the end of February, several Internet platforms including Alibaba, Tencent, NetEase, Sina, and People&#39;s Daily announced they would stop selling lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly and unexpectedly, Wu Yong enjoyed multiple dividends brought by the &quot;ban&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lottery players who were originally attracted by the Internet platform began to patronize his lottery shop. From time to time, people ask him that buying lottery tickets offline is too troublesome. Is there any way to buy lottery tickets online? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While communicating with colleagues, Wu Yong learned about the application &quot;87 Caidian&quot; (the predecessor of &quot;Douzha&quot;). He found the company&#39;s phone number online and called to inquire. Afterwards, the company&#39;s sales staff contacted him and asked him to provide store photos, sales certificates, bank cards, ID cards and other qualifications for verification. After passing the approval, Wu Yong&#39;s online lottery business started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After lottery players download the App through the lottery store promotion code shared by Wu Yong, the purchased lottery tickets can only be issued from Wu Yong’s store. Since 2015, online sales have accounted for nearly half of Wu Yong’s total store sales. The subsequent COVID-19 outbreak has further accelerated the development of Wu Yong’s online business. “Almost 70% to 80% of lottery tickets sold through the App will be sold,” he estimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021 is Wu Yong’s best year, with online lottery sales reaching more than 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Football matches are mostly concentrated in the evening, and lottery players buy tickets half an hour before the game starts. An offline sports lottery store generally only has one terminal ticket issuing machine. When business is booming, the ticket issuing speed cannot keep up. Starting in 2018, Wu Yong successively applied for four sports lottery agency stores as a clerk or relative to absorb more orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While using &quot;Bean Sprout&quot;, Wu Yong noticed that some store owners were notified by the local sports lottery management center because of their use of this app, and their store sales permissions were suspended. In his store, there are also posters issued by the county sports lottery center prohibiting online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But he &quot;didn&#39;t take it seriously.&quot; After all, it would be difficult to even recoup the capital by relying on scattered customers in physical stores. “To survive, it is impossible not to use online channels.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the case that at least 62 lottery shop owners who have used &quot;bean sprouts&quot; are currently under investigation by the Jishui County Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to two shop owners who have been sued to court by the procuratorate, Southern Weekend reporters confirmed with the other six shop owners involved in the case that they were involved in the case between February and June 2023. He was successively released on bail by the Jishui County Public Security Bureau on suspicion of illegal business crimes, and is still under investigation by the public security organs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These six people expressed similar thoughts to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Everyone is doing this. If you don&#39;t do it, won&#39;t you lose money?&quot; said a shop owner. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Fluctuating policies&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He and Wu Yong were prosecuted by the Procuratorate There is also another lottery shop owner, as well as Wang Lingfeng, the actual controller of Beijing Chun Xinya Technology Co., Ltd., the operating company of &quot;Bean Sprout&quot;, and 6 employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Lingfeng entered the Internet lottery industry at the end of 2014. According to what he told Southern Weekend reporters, he entered the industry at the suggestion of the leader of a sports lottery management center in a certain province in East China. Since then, he has been invited by sports lottery centers in many places to provide training to shop owners, &quot;How to use &#39;Internet +&#39; thinking.&quot; Selling lottery tickets&#39;&quot;. However, Southern Weekend reporters were unable to verify this with the sports betting agency he mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2016, Wang Lingfeng mentioned in an interview with &quot;Sina Pantone&quot; that before the policy banning the sale of Internet lottery tickets was introduced in early 2015, the company had begun to cooperate with many places. The sports lottery center discussed cooperation. The center recognized their model and was willing to promote it to shop owners. After the ban was issued, all negotiations stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To his surprise, many lottery shop owners took the initiative to find the company. &quot;At that time, I really felt that they were almost finished, but they actually survived.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In that interview, Wang Lingfeng said that the biggest difficulty faced in starting a business is &quot;policy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Internet lottery system has experienced a process from tightening to relaxing and then tightening. In China, the only legal lotteries are sports lotteries and welfare lotteries licensed by the State Council. The Ministry of Civil Affairs and the State Sports General Administration are responsible for the management of national welfare lottery and sports lottery respectively, while the Ministry of Finance is responsible for the supervision and management of lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In December 2007, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Issues Concerning the Use of the Internet to Sell Lottery Lottery by Lottery Agencies&quot;, mentioning We must stop using the Internet to sell lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in 2010, the Ministry of Finance issued the &quot;Interim Measures for the Administration of Lottery Sales on the Internet&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Interim Measures&quot;), pointing out that it is necessary to promptly select companies with Interim Measures Units with specified conditions and good management foundation shall submit to the Ministry of Finance for approval before launching pilot projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The interim measures also emphasize that without approval, no unit may use the Internet to sell lottery tickets. However, this document is still interpreted by the industry as a positive signal, which means that the online lottery sales model, which was previously in a gray area, is expected to be legalized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With no organization approved by the Ministry of Finance, the Internet lottery industry has developed rapidly. Portals such as Sina and NetEase and e-commerce platforms such as Taobao, JD.com and Dangdang have all launched lottery services. According to Pantone Consulting statistics, in 2011, China’s Internet lottery sales exceeded the 10 billion yuan mark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2012, the pilot online lottery sale was launched. The Ministry of Finance agreed with the Sports Lottery Management Center of the State Sports General Administration to entrust China Sports Lottery Network and 500 Lottery Network to carry out online sports betting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2015, the policy gradually tightened, and relevant departments issued the aforementioned ban on online lottery sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On April 28, 2016, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Public Security, the former State Administration for Industry and Commerce, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly issued a document pointing out that since 2015, The clean-up and rectification of online lottery sales has achieved initial results, but in some areas there are still problems with orders and prohibitions. The document once again emphasizes that lottery issuance and sales agencies and their agents are strictly prohibited from selling lottery tickets online without authorization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, a survey released by CCTV in April 2018 showed that there are still more than 300 lottery websites in operation, with the annual lottery sales amount not less than 1,000 billion. During the start of the World Cup in Russia that year, multiple lottery apps appeared at the top of the download rankings of mobile application malls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Four months later, on August 21, 2018, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration jointly organized 12 ministries and commissions including the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, and the Ministry of Public Security. An announcement was issued to resolutely prohibit unauthorized online lottery sales, and pointed out that the Ministry of Finance has not approved any lottery agency to open this business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;13 days later, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration issued another decision on amending the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Unauthorized use of the benefits of Internet sales Lottery and sports lottery&quot; are included in the list of &quot;illegal lotteries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 3, 2023, the sports lottery exhibition in the sports service exhibition area of ​​the Beijing Service Trade Fair. (People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 3, 2023, Beijing Service Trade Sports Lottery Exhibition in the Sports Services Exhibition Area. (People’s Vision/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;National Regulations&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;After the policy was tightened in 2015, the Ministry of Finance no longer authorized the sale of lottery tickets on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration can only supervise provincial and municipal lottery distribution centers and agents. Su Guojing, founder of the China Lottery Industry Salon, believes that if online sales of lottery tickets are allowed, once &quot;ticket stealing&quot; and various disputes arise on the online platforms of non-lottery institutions, how and who will supervise them will become a big problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;ticket eating&quot; means that lottery players buy lottery tickets online, but the platform or agent does not actually issue the tickets, but directly pockets the ticket money. If a lottery player wins a small prize, they can cash it in directly. If a lottery player wins a large prize, the platform or the agent cannot pay the fee, and the site may be closed or run away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Procuratorial Daily&quot; reported a case of &quot;ticket eating&quot;. Sun, the owner of a lottery shop in Shanghai, used the Internet to sell lottery tickets 508 from February to April 2019. Ten thousand yuan, the actual ticket issued was 4.43 million yuan, and the ticket consumption was more than 600,000 yuan. In 2020, the Shanghai Qingpu District Court sentenced Sun to 6 years and 6 months in prison for illegal business operations and fined him 600,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On Douya, every few months, Wu Yong will be asked by customer service to randomly check the actual ticket issuance status. Customer service randomly selects 10 orders. Wu Yong needs to find the corresponding physical tickets, take photos and send them to customer service for review. Wu Yong said that for lottery players’ online orders, he actually issues all tickets offline. The indictment also did not mention his behavior of &quot;eating votes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, there will still be &quot;fish that slip through the net&quot; on the platform. A Hunan sports lottery shop owner who was prosecuted by the Jishui County Procuratorate along with Wu Yong was accused of &quot;eating tickets.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the indictment, from January 2019 to the end of 2021, he used the &quot;Yuncaidian&quot; App (also the predecessor of &quot;Douzha&quot;) to sell 148 million lottery tickets. Yuan, the amount of &quot;ticket eating&quot; was more than 64 million yuan, and the illegal profit was more than 3.27 million yuan. In an interview with Southern Weekend, the shop owner said that he had indeed engaged in the behavior of &quot;eating tickets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unlike those who &quot;eat tickets&quot;, lottery shop owners such as Wu Yong sell lottery tickets through apps, but issue tickets offline. Are they also suspected of illegal operations? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2022, the Xiushui County Court in Jiangxi Province issued a judgment on a similar case (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Xiushui Case&quot;). Southern Weekend reporters learned from the defense lawyer of one of the defendants in the case that in this case, neither the lottery app nor the owner of the lottery shop withheld money from the tickets but did not issue them or &quot;eat the tickets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Xiushui County Court finally determined that the person in charge of the lottery selling app and several lottery shop owners who cooperated with the app were guilty of illegal business operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The basis of the court&#39;s decision is that the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot; stipulate that lottery tickets sold on the Internet without authorization belong to the category of illegal lottery tickets. In addition, the App also set up copying and syndicated buying programs with a gambling nature, etc., which changed the rules for lottery sales and prize redemption. &quot;The sales amount was extremely huge and the circumstances were extremely serious, disrupting the order of the lottery market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 225 of the Criminal Law defines the crime of illegal business as violating national regulations, operating specialty items stipulated in laws and regulations without permission, or otherwise disrupting market order. illegal business practices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the defendant appealed, the court of second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The lawyer in the Xiushui case told Southern Weekend reporters that during the court session, one of the key points in the confrontation between the prosecution and the defense was, what are &quot;national regulations&quot;? As well as the relevant documents prohibiting online lottery sales without approval, are they considered &quot;national regulations&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 9 and 10, 2023, the first instance of the illegal business case involving Wang Lingfeng, Wu Yong and other nine people was held in the Jishui County Court of Jiangxi Province. The above issues were also heard in court. in focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 96 of the Criminal Law explains &quot;violating state regulations&quot; as violating the laws and decisions formulated by the National People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee, and the administrative regulations formulated by the State Council. Regulations, prescribed administrative measures, issued decisions and orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Yong’s defense lawyer and associate professor at the University of International Business and Economics Zheng Haiping pointed out in court that the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; were formulated by the State Council and fell into the category of &quot;national regulations.&quot; However, the &quot;Regulations&quot; only prohibit the &quot;unauthorized issuance and sale of lottery tickets&quot; and do not explicitly prohibit the use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prohibitive regulations on the use of the Internet to sell lottery tickets mainly appear in the &quot;Implementation Rules of the Lottery Management Regulations&quot; and the &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Internet Lottery&quot;. However, the former is formulated by the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the State Sports General Administration, while the latter is issued by the Ministry of Finance. From a legal perspective, they are only departmental regulations and shall not be deemed as &quot;violating national regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At present, the Jishui County Court has not made a first-instance judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The distribution pattern may be broken&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Bean Sprout Case&quot; The other six shop owners who have not yet been charged are also waiting for the verdict. They opened offline lottery shops in Fujian, Shandong, Jiangsu and other places. They all claimed that they did not &quot;eat tickets&quot;. After paying &quot;illegal gains&quot; ranging from hundreds of thousands to millions, they were released on bail pending trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After representing the illegal business case heard by the Xiushui County Court, the aforementioned lawyer who represented the Xiushui case successively received inquiries from parties in nearly ten similar cases. &quot;More than 80% of cases are filed and investigated by the public security organs of Jiangxi Province.&quot; This means that lottery shop owners who use online sales are facing the risk of criminal offenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite the risks, it is not uncommon for stores to sell lottery tickets through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters randomly called 10 sports lottery stores in Beijing and asked as lottery players whether they could buy lottery tickets online. Eight lottery stores stated that they can add WeChat and purchase online, and two of them sent App download links for online sports lottery purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As far as the attitude of the regulatory authorities is concerned, the characterization of purchasing lottery tickets through the App is different from that of letting store owners purchase lottery tickets through WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the sports lottery management centers in Beijing, Zhejiang, Hunan and other places that purchasing lottery tickets through Apps is explicitly prohibited, but purchasing lottery tickets by adding the store owner’s WeChat account Whether it is a violation or not has not yet been clearly defined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Huzhou Sports Lottery Center in Zhejiang Province, where Wu Yong is located, believes that buying lottery tickets on WeChat is an online lottery behavior and &quot;is not as serious as illegal, but we do not advocate it.&quot; The Changsha Sports Lottery Center stated that if any lottery shop owners are found to be selling lottery tickets through WeChat channels, they “may be punished by withdrawing their tickets.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Why is it so difficult for online lottery sales to be loosened? Su Guojing told Southern Weekend reporters that in China, the public welfare nature of lottery is emphasized while its gambling attribute is weakened. Internet platforms provide more convenient sales channels and payment methods than offline purchases, but they may cause lottery players to become addicted and make it more difficult to control minors’ lottery purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Haiping, associate professor at the School of Psychology at Beijing Normal University and former deputy director of the China Lottery Research Center, said that another problem caused by Internet lottery sales is that the original The distribution pattern of public welfare funds has been broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lottery funds are divided into three parts: bonuses, issuance fees and public welfare funds. According to regulations of the Ministry of Finance, half of the lottery public welfare funds in each province are turned over to the central finance, and the other half is retained in the provincial finance. The Internet sales of lottery tickets break geographical restrictions. In provinces with developed Internet economies, sales will increase and more public welfare funds will be retained in local finances. Provinces dominated by offline sales will inevitably lead to a decrease in public welfare funds. This can easily lead to unhealthy competition in lottery sales among provinces, which will not only break the original pattern of raising and distributing public welfare funds and create new inequality between rich and poor, but also lead to various market chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Su Guojing&#39;s view, if the lottery industry does not introduce higher-level laws and &quot;if the responsibilities and rights in Internet sales are not clarified, the problem cannot be completely solved.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[去扬州看东坡：到心仪之地，施仁爱之方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There are many thoughts and memories in Pingshan Hall&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Yangzhou once had a dense population of outstanding figures from all dynasties, and its winding flower paths are layer upon layer filled with cultural gold dust. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Overlooking the Slender West Lake from the Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Exiting the North Gate of Slender West Lake, across the road is the Daming Temple. Entering the slope of the scenic spot, the &quot;Qiling Ruins&quot; archway appears in front of you, with four pillars and three couplets, and double eaves and tile ridges. There is a stone plaque embedded in the wall on the east side of the courtyard. The big red characters &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot; are very eye-catching. They come from Qin Guan&#39;s &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; written by Ci Yunzi: &quot;If a tourist talks about the beauty of climbing, he must write &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot;. Take a look.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After passing the Tianwang Hall of Daming Temple, there is an octagonal doorway on the west side, passing through it is Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In front of Pingshan Hall is a wooden flower gallery. The old wisteria planted on both sides are circling and twining. The dense branches and leaves and blooming wisteria flowers sprinkle the ground with coolness. I suddenly remembered the &quot;weeping willow in front of the hall&quot; and exited the flower gallery first. There are wintersweet, viburnum, boxwood, crape myrtle, etc. planted around. The leaves of magnolia are lush and moist. The tree is seven or eight meters high. It should be very gorgeous when in full bloom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a milky white stone on the grass on the south side of the vestibule, with the word &quot;European Willow&quot; written in big green characters on it. It is indeed there. Below is Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;Chaozhongcuo&quot;: &quot;The sill of the flat mountain leans against the clear sky, and the mountain scenery is blurred. Weeping willows are planted in front of the hall, and there are few spring breezes...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first year of Renzong Jiayou&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1056)&lt;/span>;, my friend Liu Chang was going to be appointed as the magistrate of Yangzhou. Ouyang Xiuwei gave this poem as a farewell farewell. It has been several years since he was transferred from Yangzhou, and he still misses the Pingshan Hall where he once visited. There is a hint of melancholy about the passage of time in the words, but the tone is broad-minded and clear, without any sense of decadence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I looked around, but there was no sign of the willow tree. It was a bit strange, so I continued searching. It turned out that it was right next to the stone, low, young, and leaning as if it was about to lie down. It was a tamarisk tree. The leaves are short and stubborn, not graceful at all. If you imagine the weeping willows planted by hand in Central Europe, they should be the delicate and slender ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingshan Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall is very crowded. Tour groups are coming and going. The couplet below the plaque of &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; incorporates the vastness of time and space, the boundless wind and moon, and there are knowledgeable and knowledgeable scholars in the scenery: &quot;When you lean on the railing at dawn, you can see the green mountains of six generations; when you come to drink wine at night, the bright moon is right above your head. On the east and west sides of the plaque, there are plaques &quot;Sitting on Flowers and Carrying the Moon&quot; and &quot;Feng Liu Wan Zai&quot; hanging high. The latter was inscribed by Liu Kunyi, the governor of Liangjiang in the late Qing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the windows of the east and west wings of Pingshan Hall, Sikuquanshu&#39;s &quot;Six One Poetry&quot;, &quot;Ouyang Wencui&quot;, &quot;Wen Zhongji&quot;, etc. are placed; four wooden poetry plaques occupy half of the wall, recording He wrote poems by Su Zhe and others about Pingshan Hall. Mei Yaochen&#39;s &quot;Thousands of Mountains Flying Shadows Across the River&quot; and Su Che&#39;s &quot;Looking down at the river and the mountains from the hall&quot; both have a silhouette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eighth year of Renzong Qingli&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1048)&lt;/span>;, when Ouyang Xiu moved from Chuzhou to Yangzhou, he was still in the &quot; The political low period after the failure of the Qingli New Deal. He cared about people&#39;s livelihood, and maintained a lenient and simple administration without slacking off. People in Chuzhou and Yangzhou felt his virtue and government, and built shrines to Ou Gong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After official duties, Ou Gong spent time in poetry and wine. He built a Pingshan Hall in the southwest of Daming Temple, where he could not only meet friends and relatives, climb high and look far away, but also enjoy the tranquility alone. He was very happy in the letter he wrote to Han Qi, his former magistrate: &quot;Dupingshan Hall dominates Shugang, and the mountains south of the Yangtze River can be seen thousands of miles away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at Ouyang Xiu&#39;s description, I thought Pingshan Hall was located. The Shugang is majestic and tall. Today, I was standing outside the hall. Under the stone railing directly south of the tamarisk tree, there was a piece of happy and beautiful red leaves. I tried to look into the distance again, but my sight was blocked by trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we took the elevator to the 70-meter-high Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple, which was really good for the distant view. Pingchuan and vast fields stretch as far as the eye can see, with no peaks in sight. The gray buildings in the distance are as small as building blocks. The Slender West Lake at your feet is like a long scroll of scenery. The water bank is curved and lingering, as if randomly embedded in thick or light green trees, with a few pavilions scattered among it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daming Temple Qiling Pagoda (right) and Hongfo Pavilion&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Among the many stone carvings displayed in Pingshan Hall and Ouyang Temple, Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Moon on the Xijiang River&quot; and Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;The Drunkard&#39;s Pavilion&quot; attract people&#39;s attention. The latter was written by Dongpo in Yingzhou. Shen Xiong&#39;s flexible regular script has always been favored by calligraphers. The lyrics of &quot;Xijiang Moon&quot; were written in Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Shi’s feelings for Mr. Ou are unusual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ouyang Xiu has always promoted virtuous people, and his grand reward for Su Shi was well known to the world. The prevailing Taixue style of writing at that time was tortuous, profound, difficult and eccentric, and Ouyang Xiu and others were determined to correct it. In the spring of the second year of Renzong Jiayou&#39;s reign (1057), Ou Gong, as the examiner of the provincial examination of the Ministry of Rites, wrote &quot;the words are very simple and have no meaning&quot;. Su Shi, who was decorated by &quot;Zhaozao&quot;, was promoted to the second place in the &quot;Lun&quot; examination. There are many famous people among this year&#39;s Jinshi, and the Jiayou Gongju Examination is regarded as &quot;the first in the millennium imperial examination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After some well-known candidates who were determined to win the exam failed, they were angry and dissatisfied. Someone wrote a memorial letter as a prank and sent it to Ou Gong&#39;s house. There were also frivolous scholars who surrounded Ouyang Xiu and made noises in front of his horse. &quot;Thousands of people gathered to laugh and curse.&quot; It was difficult for the patrolling soldiers to stop him. But since then, the sick writing style has gradually been reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ouyang Xiu spoke highly of the three Sus, and Su Shi&#39;s rich and fluent writing impressed him even more. In his letter to Mei Yaochen, he happily said: &quot;Reading Shi&#39;s book makes me sweat, so good, so good! I should avoid the road and let him go out of his way. What a joy, a joy!&quot; This is the discovery of outstanding young people by senior writers. I can&#39;t help but feel happy, and it&#39;s the sympathy of genius for genius. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Gong’s support and expectations made Dongpo grateful for his whole life. He said that he was &quot;the most deeply influenced by it&quot;. In the seventh year of Yuanfeng (1084), Dongpo traveled from Huangzhou to Ruzhou. When he passed through Yangzhou in October, he set foot on Pingshan again. Hall. He &quot;remembers the drunkard every time he goes to Pingshan&quot;, and this time is no exception. The ink on the wall is still there, but my mentor has passed away. It has been more than ten years since we last met. Dongpo deeply missed Ou Gong with a piece of &quot;Moon over the Xijiang River&quot;, and also lamented that time flies and things are illusory:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;em>; After passing the Pingshan Hall three times, I heard the sound of a snap of my fingers&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I haven’t seen the old immortal in ten years, and dragons and snakes are flying on the wall. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt; em>;If you want to express your gratitude to the governor, you still sing the spring breeze of the willows. Don&#39;t say that everything will be empty when you turn around. When you don&#39;t turn around, it&#39;s all a dream. &lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou and Su, two literary loyal dukes, leaders of the two generations of literary circles, both set an example for the world with their moral articles. Both of their terms were short, but they made Yangzhou people miss them and made Pingshan Hall full of magnetism. Descendants came to worship in an endless stream, leaving many poems and essays, continuing a romantic tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shizhen&#39;s &quot;Flowers and Grasses&quot; said: Pingshan Hall is not high in terrain and has an ordinary environment. &quot;However, the European and Su poems make the place heavy.&quot; Once the pavilions and pavilions are stained with the luster of a wise man, or Blessed by Li Cihongpian, it will be more charming. Even if the eaves and corners of the corridor columns have been worn away by time, they are still immortal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall was abandoned and rebuilt several times. The existing buildings were rebuilt during the Tongzhi period and were subsequently overhauled many times. It made Yixingya feel beautiful and condensed a touching teacher-student friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What can be done in half a year&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;By the time Dongpo came to Yangzhou as a prefect, it was more than 40 years after Pingshan Hall was built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhezong Yuanyou&#39;s seventh year&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1092)&lt;/span>; In February, Dongpo received his appointment in Yingzhou , he was very happy to move to Yangzhou. He took office in March and stayed in Yangzhou for less than half a year. It is difficult to achieve anything in such a short time, but he impressed the people with his good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo loves flowers. He plants flowers, appreciates them, gives them hairpins, sighs at them, and interacts with them in various ways. The plum blossoms, orchids, chrysanthemums, peonies, crabapples, camellias, and rhododendrons in his paintings are either beautiful or quiet, some stand alone, or the trees are full of beauty. He was also able to appreciate the charm of peony. He wrote a poem &quot;Zhao Chang Peony&quot; and said: &quot;Yangzhou has been red with thousands of leaves recently, which is the beauty of the fashionable times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Dongpo took office, he did A decision that ruined the scenery: the Wanhua Festival was cancelled. He wrote to his friend Wang Gong: The Wanhua Hui has become a big harm to Yangzhou, and the suspension of the Wanhua Hui &quot;will ruin the scenery, but it will not cause karma.&quot; His article &quot;Harming the People with Joy&quot; said: Yangzhou peony is the best in the world, and Wanhua Hui uses flowers. More than 100,000 branches not only destroyed the gardens of various houses, but also disturbed the people and harmed the people. Yangzhou people were very dissatisfied. , causing harm to the poor people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Mozhuang Manlu&quot; written by Zhang Bangji, a scholar of the Northern Song Dynasty, records: The Wanhua Hui began when Cai Jing learned about Yangzhou, and continued every year thereafter. The flower party was held, &quot;everyone was excited and happy.&quot; Zhang Bangji commented: Su Gong’s administration was basically like this, benefiting the people, so he was praised by them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On his way from Yingzhou to Yangzhou, Dongpo witnessed the tragic situation of the people struggling to survive and being displaced: there were many refugees in the cities along the way, unable to pay their accumulated debts&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style, italic style _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(owing taxes to the government)&lt;/span>; and dare not return home. When traveling to the countryside, Dongpo often screened officials and visited villages. The elders all cried with sorrow: Although the summer wheat is ripe this year, the demand for payment of accumulated debts in the good years will be more stringent. &quot;If the apprentice is at the door and the yoke is on the body, no one will be able to die.&quot; Dongpo couldn&#39;t help crying. He wrote two memorials: I once knew Hangzhou and Yingzhou, and now I went to Yangzhou. &quot;I personally saw that the people in Zhejiang, Jingxi, and Huainan were all burdened by accumulated debts.&quot; They were increasingly in distress, and more than half of them were exiled or died. Huai and Zhejiang had the most accumulated debts and suffered from disasters year after year. The officials, under the supervision of their superiors, pressed for collection and threatened and flogged the civilians every day. How do people live in peace and contentment? How is the benevolent government of the imperial court reflected? Dongpo &quot;said nothing&quot; and asked the court to suspend collection for one year, &quot;so that the people who have been trapped for a long time can know the joy of having a full meal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Su Shi&#39;s request, the imperial court issued an edict on June 1 that the debts accumulated on Huainan East and West Road and Liangzhe Road were suspended for one year. He couldn&#39;t help being happy: &quot;The edict is generous and the debts are owed, and the father is of good looks. Congratulate me again, I won&#39;t be greedy for this treasure. I smiled slumped at Ruan Ji, and drank a few books to thank me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Dongpo found out about Taxation, warehouse law, water transportation, etc. also put forward suggestions for improvement to promote the advantages and eliminate the disadvantages. Disciple Li Zhuo&#39;s &quot;Teachers and Friends&quot; records: In the past, the government allowed Gangyun&#39;s boatmen to carry goods privately to supplement their income. They often regard official ships as their home, repair them at any time, and sail them quickly. In recent years, private transport has been strictly prohibited. As a result, the bad people on the boats have become poor, and the amount of water and rice has been lost several times more than before. Both public and private companies have suffered losses. Some boatmen have stolen goods due to hunger and cold, and have broken down and sold the cars and boats. In Yangzhou, Chuzhou, Sizhou and other prefectures, many boatmen were whipped and sent away, and some became beggars and thieves. The memorial on Dongpo suggested restoring the old practice, which was approved by the court. The disadvantages are eliminated, both public and private parties benefit, and no one is punished for it. Li Lao quoted the words of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; and lamented: &quot;The words of a benevolent person are extremely beneficial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gulin Hall to the north of Pingshan Hall was built by Dongpo, and the existing buildings were rebuilt in the late Qing Dynasty. It is connected to Pingshan Hall by a corridor with red beams. Separated by a wall to the east of Gulin Hall is the Main Hall of Daming Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three characters &quot;Gulintang&quot; on the forehead of the hall are derived from Dongpo&#39;s Dharma stickers. The couplet &quot;Under the deep valley is graceful; in the high forest there are tall trees and trees&quot; comes from his poem &quot;Gu Lin Tang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall feeling of Gulin Hall seems to be less solemn than that of Pingshan Hall. From the perspective of etiquette, it is in line with the order of seniority and youth. Of course, the decoration is also very rich. On the walls of the lobby and the east and west wings, there are portraits of Ouyang Xiu, Mei Yaochen, and the Su brothers, &quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; and &quot;Red Cliff Night Tour Picture&quot;, etc., and calligraphy of East and West. Poe Linyan Zhenqing&#39;s &quot;Tie for a Seat&quot; and his &quot;Tie for Seeing&quot;, &quot;Tie for One Night&quot;, etc. Displayed in the window are the yellow-covered &quot;Song Dynasty Dongpo Collection&quot; and the Siku Quanshu&#39;s &quot;Dongpo Shu Biography&quot;. The walls are neatly arranged with poem plaques written by the &quot;Four Scholars of Su Sect&quot;. Among them, Chao Buzhi&#39;s seven-line poem &quot;Zhao Jinyun Guards Guan Yanyuan, Professor Zeng Yan and Ji Pingshan Hall&quot; was written when he invited Zeng Yanhe and others to gather at Pingshan Hall: &quot; &quot;Shu Gang is connected to Shu Mountain, and dragons and tigers reach up to the purple sky... There are no traces of Shaoshi Yangliu.&quot; From the latter sentence, it seems that Ougong Liu no longer existed when Chao wrote the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; on the wall of Gulin Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the fifth year of Yuanyou of Chao Buzhi &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1090)&lt;/span>; served as the general magistrate of Yangzhou. Dongpo knew about Yangzhou, and he served as his deputy, and the teacher and student got along well with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the seventh year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1092)&lt;/span>; In August, Dongpo received the imperial edict and served as Minister of War and concurrently In the southern suburbs, the envoy Lu Bo was enshrined. After repeated urging from the imperial court, Dongpo arrived in Beijing in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi was the son-in-law of Du Chun, the minister of the Ministry of War. When Dongpo took over, he happened to be Du Chun&#39;s immediate boss. Considering that his father-in-law and his teacher had never been close together before, and he was worried that they would not get along so well, Chao Buzhi introduced to Dongpo Du Chunli&#39;s style of life and the advantages of being an official and benefiting all things. Later, his father-in-law wrote a letter saying that he had a good time working with Dongpo, but he felt that he was &quot;arrogant and argumentative.&quot; Chao Buzhi replied with a long letter, detailing Su Gong&#39;s high integrity in governing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have nothing to praise for the fact that Su Gong is a corporal. However, he is upright, pure and has few desires. He has become extremely frugal, but he takes on official responsibilities. He is jealous of evil and loves things. He does everything he knows, especially if he does not neglect the details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi bluntly refuted his father-in-law - he did not think that Mr. Su had this problem: &quot;The letter came from him because he was so arrogant and argumentative. This is beyond Bu&#39;s knowledge.&quot; He also reminded his father-in-law: People Not sages, everyone has his shortcomings and strengths. He gave the example of Ji An and Zheng, the famous officials of the Western Han Dynasty: they had different temperaments and had different brilliance and flaws, but Sima Qian praised them as virtuous. Therefore, &quot;Gentlemen use the same to differentiate, if that is possible.&quot; Chao Buzhi believed that if all the sages were harmonious in the court, then the local good deeds would be consistent with the court, and then nothing would be impossible. This son-in-law is really serious about arguing with his father-in-law and defending his master. Chao Buzhi was the earliest known among the four scholars of Su family, and his admiration for Su Gong can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Walking to the small garden on the north side of Gulin Hall, this corner is relatively quiet. A group of rockeries, several old osmanthus trees, the slanting branches of the osmanthus cover the ridge of the green tile roof, and the tall maple poplars and bamboos sway in the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Small garden on the north side of Gulintang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo After arriving in Yangzhou, he was in poor health and rarely received guests. After receiving the tea as a gift from Mao Zhengzhong, he organized a dinner party on the Dragon Boat Festival and entertained guests with sumptuous dishes and rice dumplings in accordance with the solar terms. He especially used the clear water from Shujing to cook tea. Dongpo confessed: &quot;Repaying the favor to the king is not in vain. You know that I am not sipping lightly.&quot; Mr. Mao&#39;s good tea was not given to the wrong person. Now you know how solemnly I drank it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Gulin Hall was built, Dongpo also drank tea in the woods beside the hall, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Writing poetry almost got into trouble again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Very different from the hustle and bustle of Slender West Lake, Zhuxi Park is sparsely populated and quiet. It is located on the bank of the ancient canal and was built in 1989 near the ruins of Zhuxi Temple. The scenery inside is good, it seems like the back garden of a Yangzhou person&#39;s home. There are not many outsiders to disturb it, and it is quietly beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rain, the air is cool and moist, and the patches of ginkgo, osmanthus, pine, bamboo, red maple, etc. become cleaner and fresher. The camellias are in full bloom, and the dense, finely chopped off-white flowers of pittosporum exude a light fragrance. There are shallow mountains, thatched pavilions, stone bridges, bonsai, and several old ruins of former sites, all of which are impressive. On the left side of Zhuxi Jingshe stands a portrait of Wu Daozi, a praise inscribed by Li Bai, and a copy of the Three Jue Stele written by Yan Zhenqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Three Jue Monuments&quot; in Zhuxi Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The water area in Zhuxi Park is not small, with streams and lakes, and the water is introduced from canals. The semicircular bridge hole of Yueming Bridge connects with the reflection in the water, just like a full moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the pond deep in the park, there are two vertical corridors of inscriptions, displaying poems by Du Mu, Wang Anshi, Qin Guan, Jiang Kui and others in praise of Yangzhou. Dongpo&#39;s poem stele &quot;Ci rhymes with Su Bogu&#39;s visit to Shugang and sending Li Xiaobo as envoy to Lingbiao&quot;, which was once a treasure of Zhuxi Temple. Later, the poem stele disappeared. Wang Shizhen went to the temple to search carefully and found the ruins of the stele. He brushed away the cobwebs and dust, and &quot;sighed three times, as if he were talking to the public and singing in reciprocity that day.&quot; Then Ci Yun wrote &quot;The Stone Engraving Poems of Visiting Mr. Dongpo in Shangfang Temple&quot;, &quot;I remember the Emei people, their literary talent is truly immortal.&quot; The stele. On display in the gallery are copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park Stele Corridor&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Return&quot; In front of the stele of poems &quot;Yixing, &quot;Three Poems inscribed on Zhuxi Temple&quot;, there is a large rosy red rhododendron, full of flowers and brilliant colors, which perfectly matches his cheerful and joyful poems. The third one wrote:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I feel that nothing has happened in this life, and I am still having a great year this year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am happy to hear the good words after returning from the mountain temple, and the wild flowers and birds are singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of the eighth year of Yuanfeng (1085), Dongpo received Shenzong’s edict. Allowed to live in Changzhou. He happily returned south from Nandu &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Shangqiu, Henan)&lt;/span>; and arrived in Yangzhou in late April. The pastoral dream has come true, and I feel good. On the first day of May, I visited Zhuxi Temple with my friends. I was entertained and enjoyed everything I saw and heard. I couldn&#39;t help but write poems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Su Dongpo&#39;s Poetry Monument in Zhuxi Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quilt in the park In a corner hidden by bamboo branches and holly, there is an old well. The wall of the small gray stone well is more than a foot above the ground, and there are several deep marks on the inside that have been made by the well ropes over the years. The word &quot;Shujing&quot; is engraved on the stone tablet about one meter high next to it, which was inscribed by Professor Qin Ziqing, a descendant of Qin Guan. Shujing, also known as the &quot;First Spring&quot;, is one of the eight scenic spots in Zhuxi Temple. Ancient people said that the water from the well tastes sweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple is located at the end of Sichuan Hill, where the hills tend to become gentle. It is said that the ground veins of Shugang are connected with Shu, and the spring veins are also connected with Shujiang River. Therefore, Dongpo called the water from Zhuxi Temple the flavor of his hometown, and he wanted to carry the well water with the flavor of his hometown to his new home in the south of the Yangtze River. It&#39;s so pleasant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, he almost got into trouble again with poetry. In the sixth year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1091)&lt;/span>; when Dongpo was appointed as a Hanlin scholar and knew how to make imperial edicts, his political enemies went so far as to check the records for Luo Zhi. It was said that Emperor Shenzong died in March of the eighth year of Yuanfeng. Su Shi regarded this as a &quot;good word&quot; when he wrote a poem, and he was overjoyed. Dongpo quickly wrote a letter to defend himself, saying that he returned to Changzhou after mourning the late emperor in Nandu in early March. When I went to Zhuxi Temple in early May, &quot;I saw a dozen people, elders of the common people, talking and laughing to each other. One of them put his hands on his forehead and said, &#39;See, what a young official!&#39;&quot; I was pleased to hear that the common people were praising the young emperor. Sincerely; in addition, his request to return to Changzhou to farm was approved; when passing through Huaihe and Zhejiang, he saw a good harvest in sight, so he wrote a poem and inscribed it on the wall of the temple. If I have any bad intentions, how dare I openly show them to others? Moreover, it had already been two months since the death of the late emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally no danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park is very quiet&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangxiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Park Located on Zhuxi Road, there are also streets named after Zenzhi, Shangfang, etc. in the surrounding area. Go east out of the south gate of the park, go to the intersection, and turn north onto Jiangdu North Road. The small high-rise residential building on the right side of the road is called Zhonghai Shixi. I feel that the quality of the community is good. It must be a pleasant sight for residents to overlook the garden path of the park from their balconies. Three to four hundred meters ahead is Zenzhi Road, a slightly narrower branch road. On one side of the road is a construction site, surrounded by beige walls with slogans such as &quot;Yangzhou is my home, take good care of it.&quot; Continue north along Jiangdu North Road, and the next intersection is Shangfangsi Road. There is less traffic, the road is smooth, and occasionally three or two pedestrians walk leisurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple, also known as Zenzhi Temple and Shangfang Temple, was originally the palace of Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty. Later it became a famous temple and hosted many emperors, famous ministers and literary figures. It was destroyed by war in 1853. From palaces and gardens where emperors enjoyed themselves, to famous temples where eminent monks resided, to historical sites where poets lingered, they transformed into parks, communities, and streets where citizens walked... This corner of the soil has lost so much prosperity and joy that it has melted away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty, countless poems were written about Zhuxi Temple, and many brilliant figures in the history of literature left their traces here. It&#39;s romantic and arouses people&#39;s imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If their figures were reproduced on film, it would look like this: Du Mu came with the sound of cicadas after the autumn rain, the surrounding moss covered the steps, and the sweet-scented osmanthus fluttered; Zhang Hu walked through the bustling ten-mile street , went to Zhuxi Temple, stood on the Yueming Bridge, watched the beauties parading around, and sighed that if he wanted to die, he would die in Yangzhou; Dongpo was particularly active. After entering the temple, he drank Jisu water first, then Yingsu soup, and borrowed vines. The bed was made of tile pillows, so I lay down and enjoyed the cool bamboo breeze. Before I left, I didn&#39;t forget to draw a jar of well water and dip it in ink to write a poem on the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His &quot;image&quot; materials are the most abundant and vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[抢课大战后，年轻人在夜校找到了生活的盼头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260905]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the countdown reached zero, the system crashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prepare for this battle to grab classes, Jim, a girl born in the 1990s, specially made a form and arranged the volunteers in order of priority, including African drum lessons, hand disc lessons, silver jewelry making classes and tie-dye craft classes. . The plan could not keep up with the changes, and on August 11, the system crashed as soon as it was started. She was lucky enough to get a spot in an African drum class. &quot;It&#39;s like grabbing tickets for a concert,&quot; she said. &quot;I have to have a sense of belief. I have to get it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;500 yuan, 12 lessons, Each class is one and a half hours long. In the fall of 2023, night school, a mass life with a sense of the times, suddenly became popular on social platforms. According to data from Meituan and Dianping, searches for “night school” on the platform increased by 980% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi, a &quot;senior student&quot; at the Shanghai Citizen Night School, experienced firsthand the enthusiasm that he had never experienced before. Around 2018, she accidentally learned about the existence of citizen night schools. Her mother originally wanted to learn mobile phone photography, but when she signed up for the night school, she found out that the age limit was between 18 and 55 years old. There is a special &quot;senior college&quot; for seniors over 55 years old. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi has since &quot;entered the pit&quot;. In the past five years, she has tried leather goods classes, crochet classes, and buttoning classes one by one. She said that at that time, citizen night schools were not as popular as they are today, and “you could basically get them by sticking to the spots (open places).” Most of the night school courses at that time were common subjects such as calligraphy and painting, yoga, and vocal music. Five years later, the registration page is confusing. There are many courses on the list that can arouse interest just by looking at the names, such as &quot;Pet-Friendly Social Courses&quot;, &quot;Shanghai-style Drinking Tea&quot;, &quot;December Flower Goddess Series Courses&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of young people joining night classes is very simple. A girl explained her intention to Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;Socialize, meet more like-minded people, or you just want to learn a new skill, or just go and see Look, if you can learn, just learn, if you don’t, forget it. It doesn’t matter.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the fierce situation, Ren Yi encountered the waterloo of rushing to class, but in the end he got good luck. In a dynamic system where people drop out of classes at any time, she missed one class. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Flock into night schools to “learn art”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi prefers handicraft courses and has previously taken leather goods and crochet classes at night schools. In the leather goods class, they use a complete piece of vegetable-tanned leather as a starting point. After cutting, punching, and stitching, they learn to sew card holders, key bags, or gold bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the buckle class in the fall of 2023, the new object she fiddled with was the buckle, a button used to fix the placket of traditional clothing. The course starts at 7pm on a weekday and lasts for one and a half hours. She coiled long soft buckle strips into various kinds of buttons, such as gourd-shaped and swallow-shaped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time flies by. &quot;Every time, we may not be able to finish the work at the end, but the cleaning lady is so anxious that she has to get off work, so she rushes us.&quot; Ren Yi considers herself to be a relatively clumsy student in the class, &quot;but I just never tire of it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the buttoning class, students learned to make the buttons that fasten the placket of traditional clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu is a freelance illustrator. His daily routine is &quot;sleep early in the morning and get up at noon.&quot; &quot;The night class at seven o&#39;clock every night happened to be a relatively sober moment of her day. She signed up for tea art classes, flower art classes and Yue opera classes, which were held from 7 to 8:30 pm every Wednesday, Thursday and Friday respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu said that the tea art class and the flower art class are &quot;leisure and leisurely&quot;. If you spend thousands of dollars to learn it outside, it is not worth it. It is better to use the money to learn a language, which will look better. Practical knowledge. The low price of night school lowered the threshold for her to get involved in such hobbies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Eryu’s tea class notes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, if I wanted to learn this kind of course, I could only search it online. Being able to identify the level of a teacher “may lead to being deceived”. Before signing up, Lu Eryu paid attention to the background of the tea art teacher. He was a &quot;first-class tea art technician&quot; and &quot;an inheritor of tea ordering in the Song Dynasty&quot;, with reliable qualifications. The teachers at Citizen Night School have been screened, and the course introductions are clearly listed, which saves you a lot of trouble. “You may have something you want to learn, but when you think of complicated things to understand, keep asking these questions. That home, maybe the enthusiasm has worn off after the consultation.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She likes the atmosphere of the tea art class very much. There are more than ten people in groups of four or five. A group of people listened to the teacher talk about the origin of tea and the brewing method of black tea. The teacher taught the formula for memorizing the six types of tea, &quot;&#39;traffic light (black tea, green tea, yellow tea)&#39;, plus &#39;black, white, and green&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tea art classes at night schools are cheaper than training courses on the market, and the teacher qualifications have been specially screened, making it convenient and reliable for young people. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the tea art class, the teacher brought different brands of mineral water or purified water and poured it on In a transparent cup, everyone can blindly taste the taste of tea made with different water. Tools that measure pH value can measure &quot;some water is 7.37, some is 8.08, and some is 6.26.&quot; Lu Eryu observed that the pH value of water usually has little impact on the taste, while the hardness and mineral content of water will bring about polarizing evaluations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the handicraft class that Ren Yi took, the last class was usually a results report, where everyone displayed the results of the semester. &quot;The long table in the entire classroom is filled with various works of everyone. If there is a night market today, our entire class can come out to practice stalls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Achievements of the handicraft class. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is not something that needs to be persisted&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;I signed up for night school simply because of several considerations. First, it is very economical. Courses of the same quality and content may cost two or three times the price on the market. Second, it is very secure and the risk is relatively low. It is a project run by the Shanghai Mass Art Museum. It is not like many hobby training institutions outside, which have been affected by the economic downturn. I ran away before finishing the course, and my money was wasted. .&quot; Jim told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has only been officially employed for a few years. She works in a government agency, and her profession requires her to maintain a &quot;serious and rigorous image.&quot; She has certain standards for both her professional image and her own behavior. But during African drum lessons, she doesn&#39;t have to be so tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, Jim commutes by bicycle, carrying a backpack with an African drum behind him. From a distance, he looks like a backpacker. A solid wood African drum weighs five or six pounds. When her colleagues asked her if she was going out to play, she never explained, &quot;I said I was just going out to play.&quot; After get off work, she took off her professional clothes, changed into casual clothes, rode 20 minutes to the night school, and then rode home for half an hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher who teaches African drum lessons knows a variety of instruments, such as ukulele, ruan, guitar, and keyboard. There are 12 lessons. The first half starts with basic quarter notes and eighth notes, and is interspersed with rhythmic teaching in the middle. Now that the course is halfway through, she is struggling with the latest assignment - the teacher requires everyone to compose a song of their own. She observed that African drum teachers pay great attention to cultivating their arrangement skills, so that after they learn it, they can convey their life insights through the instrument instead of just typing out a melody written by others according to the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Djembe drumming) is not something that I need to insist on. I don&#39;t find it burdensome. It is something that I can relax after work.&quot; Jim said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After weighing the distance of the class location, the time cost and the urgency of learning, Sun Yiran finally chose the bridge class. This is a very mental chess and card game. While listening to the teacher, she wrote down the card types and rules in her notebook. The bridge class is only one subway stop away from her home. &quot;It&#39;s like when I go to night school, I just get off the subway one stop earlier to go to class. After class, I take the same subway and get home in one stop.&quot; Some of my classmates in the night school class live in Pudong and rush to night schools farther away from home after work just because they are interested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiran feels that taking night classes once a week will not put too much pressure on him. &quot;There are really other more important things, and I have other time to deal with them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is usually engaged in data analysis work. According to her, it is to organize, analyze and output information into facts that &quot;anyone can see is like this&quot;. &quot;Work is not a purely rational state. Bridge has complete rules and obvious logic, which can actually be calculated. You can completely make an AI robot that can calculate probabilities and what cards the other party may play.&quot; Sun Yiran said, &quot;I Although my work sounds like sorting and analysis, it is not purely rational. There are many human factors involved in decision-making. I will feel a little restricted at work, but bridge does not.&quot; She said that this is the fun that bridge can bring her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A multiplayer chess and card game, it can also be fun to observe the different styles of players on the bridge table. Sun Yiran observed that some people have bright minds and can deal with various types of cards easily on the card court, but they have a &quot;very strong desire to win&quot;; some people, like her, need to constantly look through their notes during the game, thus dragging the game out. It is very long; and the game is just treated as a game, tending to let the opponent directly tell the cards, and everyone thinks about what to do together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bridge lesson notes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yiran described the weeknights before going to night school as boring and time-killing. &quot;Eating dinner, working out, and watching variety shows are all over. There is no end to watching variety shows or movies. If you have time, you can keep watching and never finish them. But if I have other things to do, it won&#39;t be because I haven&#39;t watched less. It’s a two-hour variety show and I’m sad.” Sun Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Evening classes have attendance assessment. If you are absent for more than three times, you will lose your registration qualification for the next season of night classes. Many interviewees said that the evening classes are now halfway through, and most people have persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nowadays, young people are under greater work pressure than before, and they need more release and some fun. Everyone has different ways of having fun.&quot; Sun Yiran said, &quot;Because the Internet is developed, everyone is more accustomed to it. Instead of communicating online, there is less offline communication. The extra time will give you more time, so everyone may want to go out and play more, including going to night school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Every I am looking forward to it every week.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After incorporating night school into their weekly schedule, these young people also feel the changes that their seemingly useless spare time has brought to their daily lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the results of the MBTI personality test, Lu Eryu is an &quot;I person&quot;. In the &quot;Liberating Nature&quot; Yue Opera class, everyone has to stand up to sing, press their legs, and run in circles. The students in the class were paired up, one sang Hua Dan and the other sang Niu Sheng. The Yue Opera class is all girls, regardless of age, ranging from those born in the 1970s to the 1990s. In the first few classes, they were learning &quot;Sister Lin Falls from the Sky&quot;, and Lu Eryu chose to play the role of a heroine who &quot;can be more introverted&quot;. &quot;Jia Baoyu has some eye-catching scenes. He said that Miss Lin fell from the sky, and she had to show &#39;Wow, so beautiful&#39;, and she was surprised to see Hua Dan. Some students will show particularly exaggerated expressions, and the teacher will also be amused. , you will also be infected in this environment.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Lu Eryu, who considered herself a &quot;home girl&quot;, would not go out for more than 20 days except to go downstairs to throw away garbage. She said, &quot;Night classes are actually equivalent to forcing yourself a time to go out, so as not to be completely disconnected from society. Because you don&#39;t go to work, and you don&#39;t go to offline (social activities), you are getting further and further away from the crowd, so it is a bit forced on yourself. It feels like being away for three days.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing African drums with his classmates gave Jim an unforgettable experience. When playing drums, because you are not familiar with the music score and are worried about not being able to keep up with the rhythm, the rhythm will often become faster and faster. At this time, as long as one person realizes the problem and can slow down, more and more people will find that the rhythm is faster and work together to bring it back to normal. track, &quot;Maybe the overall rhythm will be pulled back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jim said that this is the opposite of the &quot;involution&quot; that everyone is keen to talk about now. There is a classic figurative metaphor of &quot;involution&quot;: in a movie theater, a person in the front row stood up, blocking the view of the back row, so more and more people stood up, and eventually everyone could only stand and watch the movie. The slowed-down pace in the African drum was just the opposite. &quot;At that time, I realized that it could still be like this. It felt amazing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back in the classroom again, Sun still felt that the atmosphere in night school was much better than that in college or middle school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Before high school, you were basically forced to learn these things, whether you like it or not. Although you choose your own major in college, there are basically a large proportion of people in every class. In fact, I don’t want to listen at all.” She observed that in bridge classes at night schools, there was rarely silence, and the teacher’s questions always received enthusiastic responses from the students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as the bridge knowledge deepened, Sun Yiran, who came to class with the mentality of learning new things, also felt the pressure of knowledge accumulation. &quot;Now I feel a critical point. The joy that doing this thing brings me is almost equal to the effort I have to put in to do it well.&quot; She worries that as the difficulty increases, bridge will become a little stressful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This spot is relatively difficult to grab. You signed up, paid money and time, and if you don&#39;t practice well, you might as well not go.&quot; Sun Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yiyi, who enrolled in a leather goods class, occasionally felt anxious. Once, due to a business trip, I had to miss a lesson in my leather goods class. &quot;I wonder if I will learn less than others if I miss a class?&quot; The teacher in turn comforted her and would help her make up for this class when she comes back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Yiyi generally feels that &quot;there is hope every week.&quot; &quot;It allows you to break away from work and find a new sustenance. You are already tired from work during the day. If there is a new content at night, you can adjust your life. It will make your life focus not always on work, but can be divided a little bit.&quot; Give your mind to other things,” she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Ren Yi and Lu Eryu, the other interviewees are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[近十年来最具话题度的日本动画完结，如何盖棺定论？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260933]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 4, 2023, &quot;Attack on Titan Final Season Finale Part 2&quot; will be broadcast. This episode with a tough-to-pronounce name announced the complete end of the ten-year &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that everything has settled, we can fully evaluate &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;), the most popular and topical Japanese animation work in the past decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic scene of the giant staring in &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To evaluate the work &quot;Giant&quot;, the first question that must be answered is: Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular and discussed globally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;342&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic gesture of the protagonist of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, television is still the main broadcast channel for animation. The vast majority of Japanese animations in the Chinese context are classified as late-night programs. They usually air after midnight. This broadcast schedule shows that these animations were not considered to be produced for the public from the beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is because Japanese cultural products have formed an industry with extremely mature market segmentation. Almost every work that appears in such a market is specialized for its main audience group, and the same is true for Japanese animation as a late-night TV show. Popular works during the same period when the first season of &quot;Giant&quot; was aired included &quot;There&#39;s Something Really Wrong with My Youth Love Story&quot;, &quot;How Can My Sister Be So Cute&quot;, &quot;Date A Live&quot;, &quot;The Perverted Prince and the Laughing Cat&quot;, &quot;Let&#39;s Work&quot; ! &quot;Demon Lord&quot;, &quot;A Certain Scientific Railgun S&quot;, etc. These animations, from background settings, characters, to story directions, are all customized for Japanese animation lovers in the traditional sense and can appeal to these core target groups. Good, but it also limits the dissemination of these works to a wider public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the conventional production concept of Japanese animation has always been low cost and small output. In the Japanese animation industry, which has long relied on DVD and Blu-ray discs as its main profit channels, an animation can be considered a best-seller if it can sell 10,000 discs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Giant&quot; is an &quot;alien&quot; in Japanese animation. The average sales volume of the nine-volume animated disc of &quot;Giant&quot; in the first season was 52,067 copies, and as of August 2016, the total sales volume was 468,603 copies. It was also the number one selling TV animation in Japan in 2013. In mainland China, iQiyi, which exclusively introduced the copyright, received a total of 320 million online views by the end of the first season. In North America, the work has sold 200,000 copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Japanese animation works, the production level of &quot;Giant&quot; is far higher than the industry average (regardless of the graphics, actions, and soundtrack). This is the production company of the previous seasons of &quot;Giant&quot; Wit Studio has earned the nickname &quot;Hegemonic Society&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production cycle of the &quot;Giant&quot; animation is also different - such a popular work did not continue to work while the iron was hot. The second animated season of &quot;Giant&quot; airs, four years after the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This long pause comes from the decision of &quot;Hegemony Society&quot;. The company believes that the success of &quot;Giant&quot; is mainly due to its own production level, and thinks that instead of producing &quot;Giant&quot; animation whose copyright does not belong to itself, To earn some hard-earned money, it is better to use production resources like &quot;Giant&quot; to produce your own original animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This animation is &quot;Kabaneri of the Iron Fortress&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;The Iron Fortress&quot;), and Wit Studio has devoted considerable resources to it. Judging only from the animation quality outside of the plot, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is better than the first season of &quot;Giant&quot;. However, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is far from meeting Wit Studio&#39;s expectations in terms of reputation and popularity. The shortcoming lies in the story of &quot;Iron Castle&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;detour&quot; of Wit Studio just provides a control group, allowing us to clearly see the root cause of the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; through the control variable method-its own story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from those stories with &quot;otaku&quot; attributes that are generally targeted at two-dimensional enthusiasts in the Japanese industry, &quot;Giant&quot; is an extremely rare work that is truly created according to the model of popular works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;, humans and titans fight. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popular pop culture works have some very basic characteristics, that is, they do a good job of showing the world view, On the basis of suspense creation, rhythm control, characterization, etc., use good production level to tell a story well. The original comic book &quot;Giant&quot; followed this rule until the final ending - good-looking stories are liked by people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to evaluate &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; mainly comes from the original comic, the evaluation of &quot;Giant&quot; should also be based on the original comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the &quot;Giant&quot; comic, readers at the time had this to say: When the final chapter of the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was released, the fans of &quot;Fullmetal Alchemist&quot; were the happiest because there would be more comics in the new century. The status of the ceiling is preserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems almost a joke, but it is actually fair. Before the end, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was expected to become the strongest shounen comic since 2000, but in the end it failed to reach the top due to problems with the ending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The qualifiers such as &quot;new century&quot;, &quot;monthly updates&quot; and &quot;shounen comics&quot; are not like the increasingly subdivided statistics in sports competitions. &quot;As long as you add enough qualifiers, everyone can win.&quot; It is possible to become the first in history in some aspects.&quot; It&#39;s because, in a place like Japan that emphasizes market segmentation, there are great differences between different types of Japanese comics. Not only youth comics, shounen comics, and girls&#39; comics have completely different creative models and concepts. Even if they are both shounen comics, monthly comics and weekly comics are almost two completely different ecologies due to the difference in publication frequency and length of each issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, trying to simply and crudely bring together works from different creation eras in &quot;Guan Gong vs. Qin Qiong&quot; will not lead to valuable conclusions. Japanese comics, which are highly commercialized, are largely driven by readers’ preferences. Therefore, the story direction and themes expressed in a comic largely reflect the acceptance of the mainstream audience at that period, and are not solely determined by the author. Moreover, the comics created later are more likely to be more perfect in terms of plot and plot than the previous works. Putting aside these talks about the degree of completion and the level of narration, it is unavoidable that the book &quot;focuses on the present and ignores the past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the most important indicators to measure the success of a commercial work - popularity and sales - cannot be used as a basis for comparing the quality of works across eras. The current Internet environment, coupled with the increasingly saturated marketing of producers, and the continuous development of markets outside Japan, have resulted in current works generally having higher popularity and sales than in the past. For example, when &quot;Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba the Movie: Mugen Train&quot; was released, it broke the Japanese movie box office record of &quot;Spirited Away&quot; which had been held for more than 20 years, and now ranks first in the box office history of Japanese movies. But I&#39;m afraid not many people would think that the quality of &quot;Demon Slayer&quot; really surpasses &quot;Spirited Away&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how do you evaluate what kind of work &quot;Giant&quot; is in the history of Japanese comics? You might as well change your thinking and think about this question: When will the next highly topical Japanese comic work like &quot;Giant&quot; appear, and can it avoid the unfinished ending of &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For current and future Japanese comics, works like &quot;Giant&quot; with a complete world structure and description of social organization are rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world constructed in comic works actually comes from the author&#39;s own worldview and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the history of Japanese comics, you will find that the eras in which cartoonists in previous periods provided them with rich life experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest cartoonists, such as Osamu Tezuka and Fujiko F. Fujio, personally experienced World War II and the reconstruction of postwar Japan. In their works, they can well grasp the grand propositions of war and human destiny. For example, Osamu Tezuka&#39;s &quot;Firebird&quot; is a grand work on the theme of the universe and life that cannot be surpassed in the history of Japanese comics. Fujiko Fujio&#39;s &quot;Doraemon&quot;, even though it is a funny comic for children, does not forget to make Doraemon and Nobi Nobita laugh and cheer in the work: &quot;Japan is defeated!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The subsequent generation of Japanese cartoonists personally experienced the Japanese left-wing movement in the 1960s and 1970s, which affected the depth and value of exploring social propositions in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, as Japan’s economy took off in the 1980s, cartoonists who grew up in this era had an international vision that surpassed their predecessors. Their works also began to really focus on the real world outside Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today’s young manga authors are living in Japan during the “lost thirty years” after the economic bubble burst. Corresponding to the economic stagnation is the slow development of Japanese society and the isolation of popular culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comic writers who grew up in this environment not only have difficulty understanding the real relationship between countries, but also have difficulty understanding the logic of social operations. This has led to a large number of Japanese comics now. When they were still within the scope of campus in the early stage, the plots and characters looked pretty good. Once the plot develops beyond the scope of the school in the later period, various flaws will appear in the character logic and world setting, eventually leading to a bad ending. The same is true for popular works in recent years, such as &quot;Kaguya-sama Wants Me to Confess ~ Geniuses&#39; Battle of Love Minds ~&quot;, &quot;The Promised Neverland&quot;, and &quot;BEASTARS&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, works like &quot;Giant&quot; are rare in the current Japanese comic industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty of world building is only one aspect. &quot;Giant&quot; has the current popularity mainly because of its control of the story rhythm before the end. Before Chapter 90, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic achieved the charm that &quot;information asymmetry&quot; should have. Various hidden clues are revealed bit by bit, gradually piecing together a complete world. In this process, the foreshadowing and echoes before and after the comics can be said to be like a gray line and a thousand miles of hidden connections. This joy of exploration is the most attractive part of &quot;Giant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what if we don’t demand the authenticity of the world view, but instead ask, &quot;Can there be another Japanese comic with a story as exciting as &quot;Giant&quot; that is not unfinished at the same time?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It doesn’t seem easy either. This is because, for a comic published in serial form, the fascinating previous plot and the bad ending are actually highly positively correlated. This form of serialization determines that Japanese comics are a matter of &quot;killing the king and taking the road&quot;. If you want to catch the attention of readers in the highly involved Japanese comics industry, you must make various abnormal plots in the early stages of comics that are &quot;not shocking but endless&quot;. The more these plots violate the logic of daily behavior, the easier it is to arouse readers&#39; interest. However, in order for the story to proceed normally, the author must give a reasonable explanation to these abnormal passages in the subsequent plot. This in itself is an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all Japanese comics have this problem. For example, one of the flaws of &quot;One Piece&quot;: the ceiling of the entire comic&#39;s combat power, why the red-haired one of the four emperors had his arm bitten off by a sea monster at the beginning of the comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes this situation worse is the high update frequency of Japanese comics. As a weekly Japanese comic, comics authors are generally required to update more than ten pages of content every week, while monthly magazines generally require thirty to forty pages of content per issue. During this period, the author has to complete story and line conception and storyboard design, as well as comic drawing from draft to final product. Although most cartoonists hire more than one assistant, the work intensity of cartoonists is still far beyond what most people imagine. Under such a continuous and high-intensity working state, it is difficult to expect comic writers to maintain the exquisite conception of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Giant&quot;&#39;s clever handling of various early foreshadowings and clues seems so unusual among Japanese comics. It is also the continuous increase of previous characters and story lines that increases the difficulty of ending the entire story and also raises readers&#39; expectations. All this has become an unsolvable problem before the author Isayama Hajime. In the end, he chose an ending that puzzled most readers. This kind of regret is unavoidable when you think about it carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十一届茅盾文学奖颁奖，专访茅奖新晋得主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260851]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of November 19, the 11th Mao Dun Literature Award Awards Ceremony was held in Tongxiang, Zhejiang Province, the hometown of Mr. Mao Dun. Five novels won awards: Yang Zhijun&#39;s &quot;Snow Mountain Land&quot;, Qiao Ye&#39;s &quot;Bao Shui&quot;, Liu Liangcheng&#39;s &quot;Bemba&quot;, Sun Ganlu&#39;s &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, and Dongxi&#39;s &quot;Echo&quot;. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎不只小孩得，大人也要当心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260909]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 22:05:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumonia is not limited to children, adults should also be careful. Recently, a 30-year-old Ms. Zhu from Guangzhou developed fever, chills, weakness in her limbs, and coughed up yellow sputum. She originally thought it was a common cold, but she didn&#39;t get better. After a bronchoscopy, it was discovered that it was &quot;mycoplasma pneumonia.&quot; After targeted anti-infection He was discharged after improvement after treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;She has an inexplicable high fever that persists and cannot be relieved by ordinary treatments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;30-year-old Ms. Zhu is usually in good health, but she suddenly developed a fever recently. The maximum body temperature was 39.8°C, accompanied by chills, chills, and weakness in the limbs. She went to the hospital for treatment. After the doctor gave her ibuprofen to reduce fever and cephalosporins to fight infections, her symptoms were not significantly relieved. She then coughed up yellow and white sticky sputum that was difficult to cough up, especially at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Ms. Zhu came to the outpatient department of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital to seek treatment. Dr. He Yaowei discovered through chest CT examination that she had an infectious lesion in the lower lobe of her right lung, so she was admitted to the hospital to further improve the examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The doctor found through bronchoscopy that there was a large amount of yellow-white sticky sputum in Ms. Zhu&#39;s right lower lung bronchus. Through rapid etiology testing, &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae&quot; was discovered. In other words, Ms. Zhu suffered from the recently popular &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of her situation, the doctor gave her levofloxacin for targeted anti-infection and symptomatic support treatment such as cough and phlegm reduction. Ms. Zhu quickly improved and was discharged. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;258779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chest CT before treatment: Multiple small flakes and patchy increased density can be seen in the lower lobe of the right lung , the density is uneven, the boundary is blurred, patchy consolidation shadows can be seen, and air bronchial shadows can be seen within them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258778&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Thorax CT after treatment: Multiple small flakes and patches of increased density in the lower lobe of the original right lung were significantly less dense than before. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is also an important causative agent of adult pneumonia&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, explained that mycoplasma pneumonia is Acute pulmonary infection mainly caused by interstitial lesions caused by Mycoplasma pneumoniae is significantly different from pneumonia caused by common bacteria such as Streptococcus pneumoniae in clinical manifestations. Therefore, it is clinically distinguished from Legionella pneumophila, Chlamydia pneumoniae and acute pneumonia. Pneumonia caused by other atypical pathogens such as grammaticis is collectively referred to as &quot;primary atypical pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current epidemiological survey results of multiple adult community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) in China show that Mycoplasma pneumoniae and Streptococcus pneumoniae are important pathogens of adult CAP in my country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, the incubation period of mycoplasma pneumonia is 1 to 3 weeks, and the onset is diverse. Most patients only have low fever and fatigue, and some patients may have sudden high fever accompanied by obvious headache and myalgia. and nausea and other systemic symptoms of poisoning. The most prominent respiratory symptoms are dry cough, which often lasts for more than 4 weeks, is often accompanied by obvious sore throat, occasionally chest pain, and blood in sputum. In a few severe cases, respiratory failure may occur, manifesting as respiratory distress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the non-respiratory symptoms, earache, measles-like or scarlet fever-like rash are more common, and a few patients may be accompanied by gastroenteritis, pericarditis, myocarditis, meningoencephalitis, myelitis, and hemolysis. anemia, disseminated intravascular coagulation, arthritis and hepatitis, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having few positive signs in the lungs and obvious imaging manifestations are important features of mycoplasma pneumonia. The lesions are mostly cloud-like patchy infiltrates with blurred edges and low density, radiating from the hilum to the peripheral lung fields. When the lung parenchyma is involved, large consolidation shadows may also appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quinols and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, commonly used drugs for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia include macrolides, fluoroquinolones and Tetracyclines and macrolide antibiotics (such as azithromycin and clarithromycin) are currently the drugs of choice for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia in children. Quinolones and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia. However, there are also mycoplasma pneumoniae and macrolide antibiotics. Lactone antibiotics are resistant, so the clinical selection should be based on the individual situation of the patient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will mycoplasma pneumonia cause &quot;white lung&quot;? A small number of mycoplasma pneumonias invade a wide range of lesions or have poor mucus drainage, involving the bronchi, alveoli, and interstitium of the lungs, causing &quot;atelectasis&quot; and even &quot;white lungs&quot; on imaging. Through effective anti-infection, expectoration, and shooting, Back and bronchoscopy treatment and other methods can cure the disease in a short time, and most patients have a good prognosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors remind that Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year, especially in late summer, autumn and winter, when the incidence is high. The main sources of infection are patients and carriers, which are mainly spread through air droplets, such as coughing and sneezing. Preschool and school-age children and adolescents over 5 years old are at high risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The preventive measures for mycoplasma pneumonia mainly include: ① Stay away from the source of infection, regularly open windows indoors for ventilation, and it is recommended to wear a mask when going to crowded and closed places. ② Perform good hand hygiene, wash hands frequently with soap (hand sanitizer) and running water, or use alcohol-based hand sanitizer to wipe your hands. ③Eat more fresh vegetables and fruits, drink enough water, get enough sleep, and exercise moderately to enhance immunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, reminded that during the period of high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, if you have upper respiratory tract infection symptoms such as cough and fever, it is recommended to seek medical treatment as soon as possible to find out the cause. Treat in a targeted manner and do not take medicine on your own to delay the condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[体验“人生的旷野”后，两位985大学生选择回归国企和考研]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg6VvrzP.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2449&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg 6VvrzP. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;234068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the school recruitment season, we can hear different employment stories of college students. In many narratives of 2023, the word &quot;wilderness of life&quot; appears frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although more and more college students are joining the difficult job search path of civil servants, central enterprises, state-owned enterprises, large Internet companies, etc., there are still some people who choose to find the wilderness of life on the so-called non-mainstream path. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two guests on this podcast, one of whom is a graduate with a double 985 master&#39;s degree, chose to take 3 months out of the busy school recruitment season to study cooking at New Oriental School and graduate. It has been on the hot searches on Weibo and Xiaohongshu twice. Another guest is also from 985 University. After graduating from undergraduate degree in 2021, he has experienced 100 different lives through various unique part-time experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after experiencing the wilderness of life, they eventually returned to the traditional path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has higher education brought us? Do we have to return to the mainstream path eventually? Does the wilderness of life really exist? Let’s find the answer in this podcast conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;Guests for this issue: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qianyu&amp;nbsp;2022 Master&#39;s Degree from Renmin University of China Graduate, currently working in a state-owned enterprise in Shanghai&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KAMA (pseudonym) 2021 undergraduate graduate of Nanjing University, currently preparing to take exams in the art field&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Listening tips:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 03:25 Before and after graduation, I was on two hot searches&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:52 at In college, you will feel that everyone has the same goals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 13:48 Life is a process of constantly collecting plastic bags&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 25:57 Leaving the step-by-step study life , I chose a stamp collecting part-time job&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 36:25 Young people always have to do a reverse weaning from their parents&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 38:43 When I was working part-time, I concealed my academic qualifications &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 50:11 Learning to cook at New Oriental made me feel that people can live no matter what&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 52:20 After leaving college, I realized my shameful sense of superiority&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;► 60:44 Does higher education constrain our choices? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editor: Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[双向出击拉拢英菲，日本意欲何为？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the United Kingdom will send 150 soldiers to Japan to participate in the &quot;Alert Island 23&quot; military exercise . This bilateral exercise is the first joint exercise since the &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot; between the two countries officially came into effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week ago, the fifth &quot;2+2&quot; meeting between Japan and the UK&#39;s foreign ministers and defense ministers was held face-to-face after a lapse of five years. In a joint statement issued after the talks, the two sides made it clear that they would increase the frequency of joint exercises. In addition, Japan will also provide cooperation with the United Kingdom in dispatching an aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific in 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Providing cooperation for the deployment of British aircraft carriers to the Indo-Pacific is just the latest step in deepening defense cooperation between Japan and countries outside the Asia-Pacific region. At present, Japan is promoting the joint development of next-generation fighter aircraft with the United Kingdom and Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan not only extended military cooperation invitations to European countries, but also played diplomatic cards in Southeast Asia. Previously, from November 3 to 5, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida visited the Philippines and Malaysia for the first time. Since the beginning of this year, the Kishida government has frequently visited Southeast Asia, covering almost 10 ASEAN member states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s efforts to win over countries in and outside the Asia-Pacific region such as the United Kingdom, France, Australia, and the Philippines are nothing more than wanting to revisit its old dream of the Russo-Japanese War and seek more interests for itself. While the United States continues to promote its Indo-Pacific strategy &#39;, and in the context of great power competition, relevant countries have also followed suit, trying to get a share of the regional game.&quot; Teng Jianqun, director of the Diplomatic Research Center of Hunan Normal University, told Southern Weekend reporters that in the context of multipolarization of international politics and global economicization, At the moment, Japan is trying to win over a large number of countries to stir up trouble in the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in the UK responded to the erroneous remarks about China in the UK-Japan “2+2” joint statement, saying, “China has indisputable territorial sovereignty and maritime rights in the East China Sea and South China Sea. rights and interests. China will unswervingly safeguard its sovereignty and rights and interests, and firmly oppose relevant countries to sow relations between regional countries and create confrontation and confrontation. If the UK and Japan really want to become responsible countries, they should stop fanning the flames and stirring up trouble everywhere. Do things that contribute to regional peace and stability.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258739&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 11, 2023, local time, London, England, British Prime Minister Sunak (right) and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in London Towers sign defense agreement. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Winning over&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Fumio Kishida met with the US Secretary of State at his official residence. Lincoln talks, exchanged views on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and confirmed that the two sides will cooperate on related issues. The day before, Blinken had just concluded his &quot;whirlwind diplomacy&quot; in the Middle East and arrived in Japan to attend the Group of Seven (G7) foreign ministers&#39; meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The G7 Foreign Ministers’ Meeting, held in Tokyo from November 7th to 8th, was the last offline meeting hosted by Japan during its tenure as the G7 Presidency. During the meeting, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoko Kamikawa held talks with the foreign ministers of Canada, Germany and other member states, and took the opportunity to hold 95-minute consultations with the British Foreign Minister and Defense Minister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In talks with defense ministers from various countries, the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific&quot; was frequently mentioned by Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s reaffirmation of the &#39;Indo-Pacific Concept&#39; through the G7 Foreign Ministers&#39; Meeting is just a rehash of old tunes with nothing new. What really deserves attention is Japan&#39;s gradual advancement in implementation.&quot; China Institute of International Studies Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the International Institute for Strategic Studies, analyzed this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the Japanese government adopted three security documents: the revised &quot;National Security Strategy&quot;, &quot;National Defense Strategy&quot; and &quot;Defense Force Preparation Plan&quot;, which not only clearly stated that it must have counterattack capabilities, but also emphasized that While taking the Japan-U.S. alliance as the foundation, we will deepen cooperation with so-called &quot;friendly countries that share values&quot; and strive to realize the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than a month after the &quot;Three Security Documents&quot; were released, Japan and the United Kingdom signed a &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot;, allowing both sides to conduct larger-scale and more complex military exercises on each other&#39;s territory. At this point, the United Kingdom has become the only European country that can conduct bilateral military exercises on Japanese territory, and is also the second country to sign this agreement with Japan after Australia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After the promulgation of the new security strategy, Japan&#39;s defense policy has shifted from defensive to offensive, and the weapons and equipment, combat posture, and troop deployment of the Japanese Self-Defense Force have also changed from defensive to offensive.&quot; Teng Jianqun pointed out, &quot;The signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement means that the relationship between Japan and relevant countries is entering a paramilitary alliance. The Japanese Self-Defense Forces can use this to go out and send troops to the United Kingdom and Australia to achieve the so-called &#39;national normalcy&#39; in a roundabout way.&quot; At the same time, Japan also wants to take the opportunity to release its military production capacity and accelerate the entry of weapons and equipment into the international market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to linking up with countries outside the Asia-Pacific region, the Philippines has also become a key target for Japan to try to win over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, Fumio Kishida arrived in the Philippines and held talks with Philippine President Marcos. In Manila, Fumio Kishida delivered his first speech to the Philippine Congress. In his speech, Kishida Fumio praised that bilateral relations between Japan and the Philippines have entered a &quot;golden age.&quot; At the same time, Japan and the Philippines also reached a consensus on launching negotiations on the Reciprocal Access Agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The targets chosen by Japan are all core members of the US military alliance. Australia is known as the US&#39;s &#39;Southern Anchor&#39; in the Asia-Pacific region, and the UK is its core ally in Europe.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Although the Philippines is weak, the new President Marcos has tilted his foreign policy toward the United States after taking office. The United States is trying to turn it into a sharp thorn wedged in the South China Sea.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Linkage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan is not only &quot;casting a wide net&quot; on the road to expanding its &quot;paramilitary alliance&quot;, but also continues to promote joint military exercises with relevant countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese media reported that the goal of the &quot;2+2&quot; talks between Britain and Japan is to enhance military coordination and interoperability by holding &quot;more frequent and more complex military exercises.&quot; After the signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement, the first joint military exercise between Japan and Britain is on the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, during the meeting of the G7 foreign ministers, the United States dispatched two aircraft carriers, the USS Ronald Reagan and USS Vinson, and the Japanese helicopter carrier USS Hyuga to conduct joint military exercises in the Philippine Sea. Rear Adm. Carlos Sadillo, commander of the U.S. Navy&#39;s First Aircraft Carrier Strike Group, pointed out that the exercise was designed to &quot;demonstrate how the United States and Japan can quickly respond to crises and interoperate and coordinate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Australia, the Japan Air Self-Defense Force is seeking to normalize military deployment. Japan plans to station F-35, F-15 and F-2 fighter jets at air bases in Australia as early as fiscal 2024, with each deployment lasting several months. Japanese media pointed out that there is no clear legal basis for dispatching permanent troops to Australia or providing security assistance when necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Reciprocal Access Agreement facilitates joint military operations between Japan and Britain and Australia, and the same equipment purchased from the United States provides a sufficient platform for mutual integration and interoperability.&quot; Military Expert Wang Qunhuai told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, the United States approved the sale of 105 F-35 fighter jets to Japan. Adding the 42 previously purchased, Japan will have a total of 147 F-35 fighter jets. Australia and the United Kingdom are also &quot;die-hard fans&quot; of F-35 fighters and have ordered a total of 210 F-35 fighters from the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in 2023, the United States successively agreed to sell hundreds of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missiles to Australia and Japan to enhance its naval long-range strike capabilities. It is worth mentioning that the United States has always been very cautious about the export of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; missiles. Prior to this, Britain was the only country besides the United States to possess this type of missile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In fact, the sale of weapons and equipment is an important tool for the United States to strengthen alliance relationships. The more American equipment is used, the deeper the relevant countries will be tied to the United States, and the more military sovereignty concessions will inevitably be made.&quot; Analysis by Wang Qunhuai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s military assistance to the Philippines came more directly. &quot;The Kishida government not only wants to provide money and equipment, but also tries to send troops to the Philippines.&quot; Tang Qifang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his visit to Manila, Fumio Kishida sent a &quot;maritime gift package&quot; to the Philippines. According to a senior Japanese government official on November 3, Japan will provide five sets of fixed coast surveillance radars to the Philippines. This is the first time Japan has provided defense equipment to a foreign country under this mechanism since it established the &quot;Government Security Capability Strengthening Support&quot; (OSA) framework in April. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, Japan focused on relying on &#39;government development assistance&#39; (ODA) and using economic diplomacy to expand its international influence, but now it has turned to improving the security capabilities of recipient countries.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Japan It is hollowing out the peaceful constitution step by step, trying to transform from an economic power to a military and political power.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team formation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewed experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Japan and the United Kingdom , the Philippines and other countries inside and outside the Asia-Pacific region &quot;form a circle&quot; and actively carry out defense cooperation, each getting what they need and utilizing each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, then Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe held talks with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and proposed the &quot;Free and Open Indo-Pacific Strategy&quot; for the first time in the joint communiqué. &quot;Since then, Japan has continued to promote this proposition in diplomatic settings, intending to cooperate with the United States in enhancing its intervention capabilities in the East China Sea, South China Sea and even the Asia-Pacific region, and to demonstrate its presence and enhance its international status and influence.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tang Qifang’s view, Japan’s continuous breach of red lines in defense policy is inseparable from the acquiescence and connivance of the United States. &quot;The United States expects Japan to act as a &#39;pawn&#39; in the Asia-Pacific and help it reduce its burden and pressure. Japan also hopes to vigorously develop its military power and pursue becoming a military and political power. Although the interests of the two sides are different, the strategic goals are basically the same.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The United Kingdom, Australia and other countries also have their own plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After Brexit, the UK has become an &#39;outcast&#39; in Europe. Based on geopolitical considerations, the UK hopes to use Japan as a &#39;bridgehead&#39; to strengthen its military deployment in the Asia-Pacific and highlight its status and From the perspective of business interests, the UK attaches great importance to the economic vitality of the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; Teng Jianqun analyzed that this is also the main reason why European and Asia-Pacific countries are willing to cooperate with Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as March 2021, the British government released &quot;Global Britain in the Era of Competition: A Comprehensive Assessment of Security, Defense, Development and Foreign Policy&quot;, which pointed out for the first time that the UK&#39;s global strategy must move towards the &quot;Indo-Pacific&quot; &quot;region&quot; tilt, and in May of that year dispatched the most advanced &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific region for the first time to conduct so-called &quot;freedom of navigation&quot; operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the British aircraft carrier&#39;s &quot;global journey&quot; did not go smoothly. Two destroyers accidentally separated from the formation. In September 2023, the British Navy&#39;s &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier conducted joint patrols with allies along the coast of Norway and the North Atlantic. Due to the significant reduction in the number of British Air Force fighter jets, the British aircraft carrier, which can normally carry about 30 F-35B fighter jets, only carries 8 fighter jets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The wish of &#39;Global Britain&#39; is very good, but Britain is no longer the &#39;Empire on which the sun never sets&#39; in the past. Whether its strength can match its ambitions is still a question. And the Philippines is not only weak in strength. On the other hand, the determination to follow the United States is not as strong as that of Japan, Britain and Australia.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;It remains to be seen how important the relevant countries can play in the so-called &#39;Indo-Pacific strategy&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts As a die-hard ally of the United States, Japan is not willing to become a &quot;tool&quot; of the United States and still hopes to regain its autonomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the United Kingdom, Japan and Italy announced that they would jointly develop a common airframe for next-generation fighter aircraft. The three countries are determined to integrate their respective capabilities in cutting-edge air combat technologies such as stealth and high-tech sensors. By 2035 The latest fighter jet was launched years ago. It is worth noting that this is the first time since World War II that Japan has participated in a joint research and development program for advanced fighter aircraft that does not include the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Japan has specially set aside funds in its defense budget for fiscal year 2024 and plans to develop an air-to-air missile for use by the next-generation fighter aircraft jointly developed by the three countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan does not want to put all its eggs in the American basket, nor does it want to hand over its military industry dividends to the United States. However, historically speaking, no matter what kind of cooperation Japan adopts, it will It is difficult to break through the restrictions imposed by the United States in military production. This time is no exception. The United States will try its best to block it and strangle its research and development plans, including Japan&#39;s new generation fighter aircraft, in the cradle.&quot; Teng Jianqun concluded, &quot;Japan&#39;s Strategic independence has always been difficult to escape from the constraints of the Japan-US alliance framework.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[9.9元价格战背后：前三季近万家咖啡企业倒闭，有独立咖啡馆营业额不够发工资]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260913]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Lin Li runs an independent coffee shop on Beijing Road in Guangzhou. This shop has been open for more than three years and is currently experiencing difficulties. During this period, the monthly turnover could not cover employee wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told reporters from Nandu·Wancaishe that this year there has been a wave of store openings in the coffee industry. Some people who do not know how to open stores blindly open stores and occupy market space. Professional community coffee shops have attracted customers who know how to taste fine coffee. , and the spatial experience originally provided by independent coffee shops has become no longer rare, because chain coffee shops are also setting up large stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The chain coffee brands with larger store areas have taken away the in-store customers, and the community coffee shops along the street have taken away the in-store and take-out coffee cups. In short, now coffee shops The density is too high.&quot; Lin Li lamented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d33e2d4d182d5e6ae80bb77a5591e6b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d33e2d4d182d5e6ae80bb77a5591e6b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, Coffee chains are making every effort to open stores. Recently, Cudi Coffee, which was founded just one year ago, announced that it has more than 6,000 stores, setting a new record for domestic coffee stores; Luckin announced that it has more than 13,000 stores and predicts that it will open 15,000 stores by the end of this year; Starbucks is also speeding up Expanding stores, it &quot;opens a new store every 9 hours in China&quot;; Manner, a specialty coffee brand founded in Shanghai, is also running wild. Yesterday (October 30), its number of stores officially exceeded 1,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, amidst the craze for coffee, a large number of coffee shops failed to survive this year. Statistics from the third-party platform Kamen show that in the first nine months of 2023, the number of newly registered coffee-related companies was approximately 45,000, an increase of 74.10% over the same period last year, and 9,825 coffee companies were deregistered, with the number of cancellations increasing by 58.95% year-on-year. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, reporters from Nandu Bay Financial News visited a number of independent cafes, trying to understand whether they can survive the &quot;9.9 yuan cup of coffee&quot; storm and the increasing density of coffee shops. , what do they rely on to survive? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cafes are everywhere, and the 9.9 yuan price war continues&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Nearly 10,000 coffee companies closed down in the first nine months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Lin Li works as a manager at an independent coffee shop on Beijing Road in Guangzhou Store manager, this store has three floors. The first floor of the store serves as the entrance. The second and third floors are bright and comfortable with simple decoration. There are large floor-to-ceiling windows on the side near the corner, allowing you to have a panoramic view of the outside scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coffee products sold in the store include classic American coffee, milk coffee, special coffee and hand-brewed specialty coffee, with prices ranging from 20 to 100 yuan. There are also some baked simple meals for single consumption. The amount is about 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/4b6280e9848604abf3a19a02f5a9a56c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/4b6280e9848604abf3a19a02f5a9a56c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told Nandu ·Wancaishe reporter, &quot;There used to be many customers on weekdays, and the daily turnover could reach tens of thousands of yuan.&quot; It is located in a tourist area, and it is &quot;extremely busy&quot; on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since the adjustment of epidemic prevention and control measures this year, the operation of the store has turned from profit to loss. In this regard, Lin Li said that he originally thought that there would be more customers this year, and he also vigorously promoted some creative and special products at the beginning of the year to attract traffic, but the effect was not good. &quot;Currently, the turnover is only two to three thousand yuan on weekdays and tens of thousands of yuan on weekends.&quot; However, after deducting the high cost of 65,000 yuan in shop rent, water, electricity and raw materials, there is still more than 10,000 yuan left, which is not even enough to pay employees&#39; wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is located in a popular tourist destination, tourists do not help its business much. During the National Day this year, boss Lin Li visited nearby coffee shops. Although the streets were crowded, there were many empty seats in the coffee shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told reporters an observation: Foreign tourists are basically adults with children, and they do not have the habit of drinking coffee. On the contrary, Guangzhou locals did not travel abroad last year and came to coffee shops to kill time. There are more people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to changes in consumer customer groups, the increasing number of coffee shops on the streets has also impacted store business. Lin Li bluntly said that there has been a wave of store openings in the coffee industry this year. Some people who do not know how to open stores blindly opened stores, squeezing the market space. “The chain coffee brands with larger store areas have taken away the customers who come to the store, and the community coffee shops along the street have taken away the customers. The number of coffee cups sold in stores and for takeaways has increased. In short, the density of coffee shops is too high now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The density of coffee shops in the Beijing Road business district is indeed increasing. Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned through Dianping that there are about 200 coffee shops within 2 kilometers of the Beijing Road business district. As of October 27, about 30 coffee shops have opened in the past three months, that is, every Within three days, a coffee shop opened in the Beijing Road business district. Among them, there are many well-known chain large space coffee shops such as Lavasa Coffee, store by.jpg, M Stand, and Starbucks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, chain coffee brands have indeed been making great efforts to open stores. For example, Kudi’s stores have exceeded 6,000, and Luckin’s stores have exceeded 13,000. Statistics from Kamen show that in the first nine months of 2023, the number of newly registered coffee companies was approximately 45,000, an increase of 74.10% compared with the same period last year. At the same time, many coffee shops have fallen in the coffee wave. Kamen data shows that in the first nine months of 2023, 9,825 coffee companies have been canceled, and the number of cancellations has increased by 58.95% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to intensive store openings, leading coffee chain brand Luckin Kudi Tims has also successively launched promotions of 9.9 yuan/cup or 8.8 yuan/cup, lowering the selling price of coffee in order to seize the market share. customer. Although there is a big difference between the customer base of low-price coffee and the customer base of independent coffee shops, the impression that a cup of coffee only costs 9.9 yuan is still engraved in the hearts of many consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/b5d8d224b36f1aa66eb98e4984ecbc14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/b5d8d224b36f1aa66eb98e4984ecbc14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li revealed, A customer once was surprised when he saw the price list after entering the store, &quot;Americano coffee actually costs more than 20 yuan.&quot; However, Lin Li believes that &quot;six or seven years ago, the Americano and latte we drank were more than 20 yuan a cup.&quot; Yes, this is the normal price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill, another independent cafe operator, also encountered customers who were confused about the price at his store. Bill thought, &quot;American and American cuisine cost more than 20 yuan. The nine-yuan American style uses different coffee beans, and the taste is different, so the price is naturally different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the competitive pressure brought by the store opening wave and price wars, Bill&#39;s store coffee Some price adjustments have been made. For example, the price of iced Americano coffee has been reduced to 20 yuan, and many stores have launched a beverage promotion of &quot;42% off in the morning and 32% off in the afternoon on weekdays&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reduce the store area and shift towards high-end customers&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Independent cafes are also planning to change&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the numerous stores that are still struggling with losses, Bill will The coffee shop moved from a shop along the street in Guangzhou to a community, and its store went from losing money to being able to continue operating. Although the operating area of ​​Bill&#39;s store has only been reduced by about 10 square meters, the rent burden has been cut in half, down to four digits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill is a coffee fan with more than 20 years of coffee experience. Out of interest, he opened his first coffee shop in 2019. However, the rent of this shop is high due to the location where it is located. , but the flow of people is not much, and it has been affected many times by the epidemic before, so it is not profitable. Last year, Bill accidentally saw a store in the community for rent, so he closed the old store and started over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new coffee shop covers an area of ​​about 20 square meters, and most of the coffee drinks sold in the store are hand-brewed coffee. Bill manages it by himself because costs have dropped. According to his estimate, he can run the business with only 300 yuan a day. On the day when a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News visited, he sold several hundred yuan of coffee beans and several hundred yuan of coffee drinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue, who lives in Guangzhou, also wanted to open a coffee shop. Before opening the shop, she did some research. Mingyue found that although there were many coffee shops in Guangzhou, most of them had different decoration styles and menus. The drinks on the menu are all very similar. “As soon as I look at the menu, I can imagine what this cup of coffee will look like and taste like.” Moreover, what confuses Mingyue even more is that even though there are so many coffee shops, when she wants to When drinking a cup of hand-brewed coffee, she didn&#39;t know where to consume it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/90b868772cf40aeccd71515e58371d9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/90b868772cf40aeccd71515e58371d9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, last year , Mingyue opened an independent cafe in the Yanyun West Community of Huifu East Road, Guangzhou. In order to distinguish it from most coffee shops in the market, she positioned the shop as a high-end cafe targeting high-end customers. The cafe is located in a quiet community. It has a two-story store with an area of ​​about 200 square meters, a monthly rent of 25,000 yuan, and three employees. The price of coffee products in the store ranges from 38 to 168 yuan, and competition-level premium hand-brewed coffee is also available. However, the supply of such products is small, and the pricing depends on the type of beans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year after opening the store, Mingyue confessed to a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News that the coffee shop business is not easy. Not many people know about the newly opened store. It is a process of slowly accumulating word-of-mouth and popularity. , until last month, the store was still losing money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the situation has been slowly improving. The differentiation of positioning and the ability to brew coffee have helped her a lot. Mingyue said, &quot;We suffered the most when we first opened, because at that time Severely affected by the epidemic... Only half of this month (October) has passed and we have recovered our capital. This month is a steady profit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Independent cafes survive on high-quality beans&lt;/h4 >; &lt;h4>;But it may be difficult for novices to identify the route&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After visiting these independent cafes, reporters from Nandu Bay Financial News learned that the reason why there are so many coffee shops in operation is difficult, in addition to the location where they are located. In addition to the problem and the influence of coffee competition, one of the problems is that the target group positioning is not clear enough. His customer group includes white-collar workers, freelancers, and office workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why stores like Mingyue and Ah Bill can survive is that in addition to working hard to accumulate regular customers in terms of cost and positioning, it is also very important that they have good quality and cost-effectiveness in the supply chain. A channel for coffee beans that are high quality and in line with market tastes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d27afb385794723e0854e23204cf3d24.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; height= &quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d27afb385794723e0854e23204cf3d24.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258784&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Coffee beans sold at Mingyue store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue attaches great importance to the selection of coffee beans. The positioning of her coffee shop is to make competition-level specialty coffee, and she can often get some micro-batch specialty beans. Mingyue told a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News that she drank more than a thousand beans from April this year to now before finally deciding to purchase a dozen beans. &quot;Finding beans can represent many things, and the struggle to make specialty coffee is actually to compete with your ability to select products.&quot; Her feeling is that being able to find good coffee beans will benefit the store&#39;s customer base - those who know the goods and are willing to spend money. For customers who have money to drink expensive beans, it is very competitive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to high-quality coffee beans, another key point in product selection is to allow customers to drink coffee with high cost performance. Mingyue is trying to improve the price-performance ratio of the coffee in the store as much as possible. For example, the Americano coffee sold in its store is priced at 68 yuan. It uses green label Geisha beans. &quot;Customers who know the product will think that I sell it very cheaply when they see it in the store.&quot; The price of this bean in the market is 88 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/9bb65a681121dcf9ca50165b21d30b73.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/9bb65a681121dcf9ca50165b21d30b73.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to passing high quality In addition to providing coffee drinks, selling coffee beans is also the main way for some independent cafes to make money. Some cafes will buy green coffee beans and roast them themselves, making them into cooked coffee beans before selling them, but the coffee beans are usually sold to regular customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu·Wancaishe reporter learned from many coffee practitioners that, excluding all processing costs, the selling price of cooked beans is about three times that of green beans, and a green coffee bean sells for 100 -120 yuan/kg, so converted, the selling price of this cooked coffee beans is about 300 yuan/kg, and the specific situation will be different in each coffee shop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Bill, he would rather sell coffee beans than sell coffee. Bill roughly estimated that 50% of his store&#39;s turnover comes from selling coffee beans, and 50% comes from consumption in the store. &quot;The people who buy beans are mainly regular customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill’s coffee menu has a full three-page hand-brewed coffee bean list. In addition, he also took out more than a dozen beans from the cabinet that were not on the bean list and introduced them to reporters in detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7567eda950cc92f0e34c20047344c3c3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7567eda950cc92f0e34c20047344c3c3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making Regarding coffee, Bill doesn’t have many coffee equipment in his shop. An Italian machine is his main tool for making American coffee and milk coffee. Bill said frankly, “When I opened the store, I planned not to sell coffee drinks, but I decided to do it after thinking about it.” This decision was the right one. Half of Bill’s current sales volume in the store still comes from these coffee drinks. “These are what we use.” To stabilize the basic market.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill sells hand-brewed coffee, with prices ranging from more than 30 yuan a cup to 100 yuan a cup. He said that the price of beans is directly linked to the quality of coffee. Expensive beans will have obviously rich and lovely flavors, such as bergamot, lemon, and tropical fruits. Cheap beans have a relatively bland flavor and are priced low. Just expect that the flavor of this cup of coffee will not be that rich. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue’s store also sells coffee beans. 70% of her turnover comes from in-store consumption and 30% from selling beans. However, Mingyue said that since the store has only been open for a short period of time, it has not accumulated many regular customers, and there will be greater room for growth in this part of the business in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d892ab5957be5431c882bca384a1a444.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d892ab5957be5431c882bca384a1a444.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258787&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The prize Mingyue won in the coffee competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the ability to obtain high-quality coffee beans has helped Bill and Mingyue a lot, because the quality of coffee beans varies and there are many supply channels, it is not easy for novices to understand the process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li calculated an account for the reporter and opened a cafe. In addition to investing about 300,000 yuan in decoration and equipment in the early stage of opening the store, the price range of coffee beans on the market is very wide - raw materials. Beans range from 30 yuan/kg to tens of thousands of yuan/kg, and cooked coffee beans range from 80 yuan/pound to tens of thousands of yuan/pound. “It is difficult for a layman to tell the true price of a bean. As for what price it should be sold in a store, I don’t know the beans... and there are many companies that specialize in coffee shop opening planning. If people who don’t know the business buy beans directly from them, they will basically make money.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion: &lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Consumers have more choices&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;The era of coffee segmentation may have begun&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As coffee competition becomes increasingly fierce, the practitioners of these independent cafes They are also thinking about where to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discussing with his boss, Lin Li plans to terminate the store&#39;s operations in November this year and wants to reopen it in a smaller store. As for the store&#39;s future competitive direction, he said he is still thinking about it, &quot;Maybe it depends on how to make the products more refined, instead of just making Italian, milk coffee, special blends, and hand-brewed everything.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f7624557efce35d6d08cf44daf90061e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f7624557efce35d6d08cf44daf90061e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Those who are in it know best how fast the coffee market is changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue is glad that she initially targeted the high-end specialty coffee track. Mingyue revealed that a year ago, a senior told her that opening a chain of popular coffee shops was the most profitable trend, but just recently, the senior told her that his chain of coffee shops could no longer continue, and was replaced by Luckin and others. The big chain coffee brands are losing competition, and he needs to find a new outlet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mingyue has seen that the coffee market is gradually segmented, and some customers’ tastes are already “very advanced”, such as its previously launched Combo product (ie “one bean, more”). It&#39;s exactly what the customers suggested. Mingyue said frankly, &quot;We need to be very precise in a very narrow field, rather than doing everything. Customers have already learned how to choose. If we do it seriously, there is still a lot of room for development.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mingyue&#39;s The plan is to wait until this hand-brew store can make a stable profit before opening a new store specializing in special blends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Li and Bill are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>