<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[汇金出手增持四大行 系时隔8年再出手]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258427]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Central Huijin&quot;) increased its A-share holdings. It has been eight years since Central Huijin last increased its holdings in the four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks was approximately 477 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to announcements from the four major banks, this increase in holdings is just the beginning. Central Huijin will continue to increase holdings in the secondary market in its own name in the next 6 months (counting from the date of this increase in holdings). The four major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin is a wholly state-owned company established in 2003. It has strong capital strength and holds shares in nearly 20 leading companies in four major categories, including banking, insurance, securities, and comprehensive institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This increase in holdings of the four major banks is of great significance to insiders in the securities industry. It sends a positive signal of stabilizing the capital market. It is also expected to drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve the rhythm of the sector. Large with small, the floor pushes the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Operation again after 8 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 11, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank collectively announced that the controlling shareholders Central Huijin increased its A-share holdings by 37.2722 million shares, 27.61 million shares, 24.8879 million shares and 18.38 million shares, and planned to increase its A-share holdings in the next 6 months (from the date of this increase). It continued to increase its holdings of the Bank’s shares in the secondary market in its own name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much is the amount of this increase? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the closing price on October 11, the four major banks increased their holdings by a total of 477 million yuan. Among them, the highest is 136 million yuan from Agricultural Bank of China, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China with 130 million yuan, China Construction Bank with approximately 117 million yuan, and Bank of China with 94 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Central Huijin increased capital for the four major banks was in 2015, at a total cost of nearly 20 billion yuan. In 2015, Central Huijin increased its holdings in Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank by 1.255 billion shares, 1.014 billion shares, 1.810 billion shares, and 497 million shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has also led some market participants to predict that Central Huijin’s increase in its holdings in the four major banks is only the beginning, and the proportion of subsequent holdings may be further increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has strong financial strength. According to the 2023 semi-annual report, its total assets and net assets are as high as 6.71 trillion yuan and 6.21 trillion yuan respectively. Its operating performance is also remarkable, with operating income of 323.615 billion yuan and operating profit of 316.607 billion yuan in the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Affect geometry? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Central Huijin has increased its holdings in the four major banks, and its market impact cannot be underestimated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yifeng, chief financial analyst at Everbright Securities, said that Huijin’s increase in holdings sends a positive signal to stabilize the capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the four major banks have stable profits and high dividend rates, but they are at very low valuation levels. Huijin&#39;s increase in holdings demonstrates the controlling shareholder&#39;s confidence in state-owned financial institutions with low valuations and high dividends; secondly, the four major banks have a larger weight in the Shanghai Composite Index, and continued increase in holdings is expected to have net-breaking valuations but stable operations and dividends Companies with high profitability will form support, which will help boost market confidence; finally, the four major banks play the role of &quot;lead goose&quot; in credit extension, and this increase in holdings will also help convey confidence in the stability of my country&#39;s financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Ma Kunpeng, chief analyst of CITIC Securities Bank, this will drive bank stocks back to the main line of China Special Assessment, and then achieve large and small stocks, and the floor will push the ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, he believes that the four major banks are the cornerstone of the banking sector and have key guiding significance for the overall prosperity of the sector. They are also the core of the banking industry’s valuation system with Chinese characteristics. They are important for today’s increase in holdings and The proactive announcement of the willingness to increase holdings in the future and the entry of real money into the market are not only an overall support for the banking sector, but also a high degree of affirmation of the special valuation of banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It suggested that we should attach great importance to the systematic revaluation of the banking sector starting from the special valuation of major banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng regards the special valuation of major state-owned banks as a systematic revaluation supported by real logic and believes that it has three major logical pillars: First, the risks of major state-owned banks in key areas such as real estate and urban investment Not high, significantly better than the industry average; secondly, historical bad debt has been completely cleared, and the full-caliber bad debt rate has fully reflected and digested the bad debt implied by the current valuation, and has peaked; furthermore, the ROE of major banks has been at the bottom, promoting The profit growth rate at the critical point of ROE recovery is very close to the current profit growth rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kunpeng believes that on the one hand, the current macro economy is at a critical turning point for stabilization and improvement, and the macro turning point is more beneficial to major banks that are more biased towards sector beta. On the other hand, the main line logic of the special evaluation of major banks this year is also conducive to major banks taking the lead in performing. Therefore, unlike the previous rhythm of first anchoring the sector&#39;s ceiling valuation and then driving low valuations, this year&#39;s rhythm should be the opposite, first raising the sector&#39;s floor valuation and then pushing the ceiling higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的一则班内社会学调查：为何现在的年轻人不喜欢回家了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258419]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A recent post is very popular. The original text says this, &quot;When you are helpless, you often have thoughts in your mind. I said &#39;I want to go home&#39;, but it seems that it is not the real &#39;home&#39; in reality, but a safe, comfortable place in my imagination, without pain and trouble.&quot; I estimate that the posters are most likely young people, and the people who post and comment on them are also mostly young. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Home, also known as home in English, is different from house, which is only a building with residential functions. Home is a word with obvious cultural and geographical color, often associated with family, family, affection, warmth, shelter, arms, harbor, etc. Going home, the so-called going home, is also full of positive energy, a sense of justice and legitimacy, such as &quot;go home often&quot;, &quot;rich or not, go home for the New Year&quot;, &quot;fallen leaves return to their roots&quot; and other popular This can be seen in the song titles or sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, I must go home during holidays, especially long holidays. The simple truth is that it was very difficult for my parents to raise and train me as an adult. Now that they are older, I have no reason not to take the time to go home to visit and accompany them. In other words, if I don’t go home during the holidays and only play by myself or play with my wife and children, I will feel guilty and feel that I am a selfish and heartless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Times have changed, and today’s young people, especially those born in the 1990s and 2000s, have completely different understandings and perceptions of home and returning home. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My sociological investigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;My nephew is a freshman. During this past holiday, he only stayed at home for three days and asked his friends out on the fourth day. Have fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I randomly asked the 18 people I teach, including sophomores and juniors, 7 of them &quot;did not go home during this holiday&quot; and 7 of them &quot;stayed home for 7 days or more&quot;. 1 person, 3 people &quot;stayed home for 5-6 days&quot;, 4 people &quot;stayed home for 3-4 days&quot;, and 3 people &quot;stayed home for 1-2 days&quot;. Among the 7 people who did not go home, 5 people directly expressed that they &quot;didn&#39;t like going home&quot; and 2 people said that &quot;I had other arrangements during the holiday, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot; Among the 11 students who went home, 92% held the view that they “like to go home, but don’t like to stay at home for too long.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One conclusion is that the young people I observed do not like to go home very much, or do not like to stay at home for too long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering returning home as a population movement phenomenon, even if it is a temporary population movement, we might as well borrow the push-pull theory of demography to explain: Going home proves that there is something attractive to me at home, which makes me Things that feel comfortable, this is the &quot;pull&quot;, pull me home; if I don&#39;t want to go home, don&#39;t go home, or want to leave home after a few days, there must be something I don&#39;t like at home that makes me feel The uncomfortable place, this is the &quot;thrust&quot;, pushing me away from home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For young people, what are the main components of the “pull” to go home? &quot;It&#39;s holiday, I want to go home and eat something delicious&quot;, &quot;Studying at school is too stressful, I want to go home and rest for a few days&quot;, &quot;I miss my parents and want to go home to spend a few days with them&quot;, &quot;They It’s not easy to support my studies, so I have to go home and spend time with them during the holidays.” The students generally gave their answers in terms of emotional expression and feedback, as well as self-repair and relaxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are obviously many &quot;push&quot; components of not going home, not wanting to go home, and wanting to leave home soon after returning home. Here are some of the answers I got, and I divided them into categories according to the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have other more important arrangements: &quot;I traveled with my boyfriend during the holidays. We went to Xi&#39;an to watch a concert, so I didn&#39;t go home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save money ’s: “If I don’t go home, I can save a lot of money. For example, if I stay at school for eight days, it costs 500 yuan, but the high-speed rail ticket alone costs more than 500 yuan for me to go home. Not going home is a big deal for me. A kind of financial savings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who feel that there are communication barriers with their parents, cannot talk together, or feel that they are not free and uncomfortable: &quot;Communicating with parents is obviously not as pleasant as communicating with roommates or peers. , my real sense of gain is also much different.&quot; &quot;I want to relax when I go home, such as watching a movie with my friends. I like to put on makeup before going out. My mother likes to keep asking, who are I with and what are I doing? , What time will you go home? I am very annoyed by it. I feel like I don’t have any freedom at home. I don’t like this feeling.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common ones are those who have thoughts about their parents’ thoughts, or want to get rid of their parents’ judgment on their own lives: “It was fine for the first two days when I went home. I ate the food cooked by my mother. I was very happy and relaxed, but Later, my parents, especially my dad, always asked me about my life plans and future plans, which made me feel even more stressed.&quot; &quot;As soon as I came back, my dad kept nagging me in my ears to take the postgraduate entrance examination and public entrance examination. , saying that a certain job has security and will be relatively stable in the future, and that that job is not good and has no future, etc., &quot;My mother gave me some instructions on how to find a boyfriend, telling me not to find a boyfriend in such and such a place, but to find a fellow villager. I&#39;m about to collapse.&quot; &quot;In the eyes of my parents, I am always a child. Once my ideas are inconsistent with theirs, they will think that I am disobedient, rebellious, and unfilial, and they will criticize me and scold me. &quot;I don&#39;t like this.&quot; &quot;My dad is a local teacher in our area. He wants me to return to my hometown to be a teacher after graduation, which will be stable and relaxing. The problem is that I don&#39;t want to go home, and I don&#39;t want to be a teacher.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that among the various elements of &quot;push&quot; in the eyes of the students, the differences in ideological concepts and lifestyles between the two generations, parental authority, and (excessive) control of children&#39;s rights to free development and self-determination Intervention is the most obvious manifestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the acquisition and growth of students from professional fields has also made the parent-child relationship relatively tense, and conflicts or contradictions have become apparent. Some students said, &quot;I am studying sociology. I have a certain theoretical understanding of power asymmetry and discipline. When I went home and heard what my parents said to me, I clearly felt that their words were full of PUA, and their words and deeds reflected obvious power discipline. The traces of what I learned in school are vividly reproduced in my home, and this feeling makes me extremely distressed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, some students also pay attention to strategies when communicating or confronting their parents. One student mentioned, “When my parents talk about topics I don’t want to talk about, such as finding a partner, my The strategy is usually to use other topics to divert the topic. I will say that I am very busy, I have to study, I have to study, I have no time to fall in love, etc. to prevaricate them. I generally do not have head-on or direct conflicts with them, and I will selectively avoid them. Something I don’t want to talk about”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;push&quot; is greater than or significantly greater than the &quot;pull&quot;, the realistic choice for young people is naturally that they don&#39;t really want to go home, or they want to leave home after they can&#39;t stay home for a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It’s OK to go home; it’s not OK to stay for a long time”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, most young people will not resist going home, but they are limited by the differences in thoughts and concepts between generations. , there are obvious differences in the understanding and cognition of some things and problems, which often leads to some problems when young people and their parents stay under the same roof for a long time. Young people have the mentality of doing more than doing less, so they choose not to Go home, or go home less often, or reduce the number of days you stay at home. In a nutshell, &quot;It&#39;s okay to go home; it&#39;s not okay to stay for a long time.&quot; This is the choice of most young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the students I surveyed, regarding the frequency or probability of going home during the holidays, I observed that: it seems that young people who were born and grew up in a good family or a wealthy family have a relatively low frequency, and those who think they are in a high position have a relatively low frequency. Parents who are powerful or well-connected will have more future expectations and life plans and designs for their children. They are more likely to overstep their authority and suppress and restrain their children more frequently. The latter will of course be more uncomfortable and less free. A classmate said, &quot;My dad always talks in a bossy and arrogant way. I hate it. &#39;You must take the postgraduate entrance examination&#39;, &#39;You must take the public examination&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t need to spend time putting on makeup&#39;, &#39;You don&#39;t &quot;I always go out to drink&quot;, &quot;I have eaten more salt than you have traveled&quot;, &quot;If you don&#39;t listen to the old man&#39;s words, you will suffer a lot&quot;, I feel annoyed when I hear these words.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, for those families with average economic conditions, after the children come home, the main thing for the parents is to cook for the children and have fun with them. The atmosphere is relatively harmonious, and the communication topics are not involved or rarely involved. Children&#39;s future, children&#39;s real feeling is that they are comfortable and comfortable, and they feel no or little pressure. The holidays are real companionship for them, and they fulfill the original meaning of the holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real life, there are still a small number of young people who don’t like to go home. They have fierce arguments with their parents as soon as they come home. They show contempt for their parents. Even when they go home, they are locked up. They go out to watch movies and play games without any verbal or other communication with their parents. For families with average or poor economic conditions, some young people turn a blind eye to the objective fact that their parents save money on food and clothing to support their education and college. They think this is what parents should do and it is a matter of course. &quot;I am Your children, it is only natural that I spend your money.&quot; In their view, parents are synonymous with old traditions, old ideas, decadence and backwardness. Their strategy is usually to &quot;not work together if they have different paths&quot;, that is, to &quot;cut off the relationship&quot; in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, such children are not grateful to their parents for their upbringing. Faced with such a child, the other parent naturally feels disheartened and laments that his fate is bad and his family is unfortunate enough to have raised such a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Problems with parenting styles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not to mention the remark about &quot;raising children to prepare for old age&quot;. Parents work hard to cultivate and support their children. As children, we must have a basic sense of gratitude. Bar? Why is it missing? What is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the root lies in parents and their training methods. Many parents think that the standard of a good parent is to provide their children with basic or relatively superior material living conditions. I will try my best to satisfy my children&#39;s needs. This is even what good parents are all about, but this is not the case. In the process of raising and educating their children, parents cannot stop at purely financial support, but also involve all aspects, such as the source of value and the arduous process of creating value. Parents are too doting on their children. They have always known to give and give away since they were young. Children, let them feel that the material conditions they have are taken for granted, and do not instill in them values ​​such as a sense of responsibility, equality of rights and obligations, and the other side of freedom is self-responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As children, they never know or understand how difficult it is for their parents to make money. Their parents do not give their children the opportunity to experience and appreciate the hardship of their parents making money. Another example is paying attention to the inner world of children and the psychological changes during their growth. Many parents think that it is enough to feed and clothe their children, but they seldom pay attention, care and concern to their children&#39;s spiritual world and spiritual life. They seldom pay attention to, respect and listen to children&#39;s way of thinking and ideas. This is a common problem in so-called &quot;East Asian families&quot;. The common point is that both parties only focus on or care about material supply and acceptance, and do not care about each other&#39;s psychology. State, especially no or very little attention to the other person&#39;s mental state and personality traits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the solution to similar problems, from an economic perspective, when young people grow up and become adults, they theoretically have their own economic and behavioral capabilities. Shouldn&#39;t they completely &quot;cut off the relationship&quot;? Okay, is it okay for you to support yourself now? Then repay me all the fees I paid you after you turned 18, and then talk about &quot;breaking up the relationship&quot;. This may sound harsh, but it is the truth. Parents are adults, and their children are also adults, so they should get along with each other according to the contract in the adult world. If you borrow something, of course you have to repay it. This is only natural. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the question of whether young people are willing to go home, how often they go home, and how many days they stay home essentially refers to the relationship between young people and their parents. Young people and their parents have different values, different cultural levels, different starting points, and different life experiences, which will inevitably lead to different views and opinions. This is a normal phenomenon. In the process of communication or getting along, both parties should adhere to the basic principle of empathy, consider issues from the other party&#39;s perspective, respect the other party more, care more about the other party, especially respect and care about the other party&#39;s inner feelings and experiences, and advocate effective communication between the two parties. and communication to gradually resolve or eliminate the inner barriers and gaps between each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those &quot;rebellious children&quot; or &quot;parasites&quot; who only know how to take without knowing anything in return or feedback, I think parents can consider reducing or even stopping the material support for their children. In the past, they only focused on the material aspects of their children. Conduct in-depth examination and reflection on the parenting methods that focus on life but neglect the spiritual world of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, I would like to return to a concept from the perspective of anthropology - making a home. The corresponding English word is home making, which means that home is not natural or naturally generated. Home is more than just a physical level. It refers more to the social level. Home is the result of social construction. Home requires the joint efforts of parents and children to build, build and operate. Only parents and children adopt common behaviors, actions, consultations and Only through collaboration can a true home be formed, and only then can the home in young people&#39;s imagination truly exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大熊猫野化放归，都要上啥“培训课”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258425]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/482c666bae28b65adc021eac7d29f4cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The Giant Panda National Park has beautiful scenery. The picture shows the Liziping area. Photo courtesy of the State Forestry and Grassland Administration&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driving from the urban area of ​​Dujiangyan, Sichuan, along the winding winding mountain road to the west, after driving for more than an hour, we arrived at the China Giant Panda Conservation Research Institute Center (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Panda Center&quot;) Wolong Hetaoping Base. The climate here is cool, rainy and humid, and it is located in the natural living environment of giant pandas. It is very suitable for wild training and captive breeding of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reintroduction of captive giant pandas into the wild is a key technology pioneered by the Panda Center, which is mainly divided into the stages of reintroduction training, release and monitoring. Over the years, generations of scientific researchers have devoted a lot of effort to establish a complete technical system for giant panda wild training and reintroduction monitoring, which has achieved good results in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why should giant pandas be reintroduced into the wild? What significance does this have for the protection of the giant panda population? From captivity to release, what &quot;training courses&quot; do giant pandas need to take? Recently, reporters conducted on-site visits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3acb8beb101d736d5a5f6e17e6c8354f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253798&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers conduct a health check-up on a giant panda cub. Photo by He Shengshan&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild giant panda population&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The mountains and forests are green and the streams are trickling. In the rewilding training area of ​​​​Hetaoping Base, except for a path that the staff walked up and down the mountain, there are almost no traces of human activities, and the original ecology is preserved. In order not to disturb the silence, the reporter turned his cell phone to silent and walked in quietly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the dense jungle, giant panda &quot;Bosi&quot; and his cub are sleeping soundly. Not far away, keepers in &quot;panda suits&quot; were using this time to clean the pens and replenish fresh bamboo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In order to mask the human smell, the &#39;panda suit&#39; is sprayed with extracts of panda feces and urine.&quot; He Shengshan, director of the Field Research Animal Management Department of the Hetaoping Base, told reporters that unlike captive giant pandas, the The breeders are close to and dependent on them, and the breeders trained in the wild must remain &quot;invisible&quot; at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reintroduction into the wild is an important means to rehabilitate and rebuild the wild population of giant pandas, and is of great significance to the protection of giant pandas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, my country has vigorously implemented natural forest protection, wildlife protection projects and the construction of giant panda national parks to protect giant pandas and their habitats, with remarkable results. The results of the fourth national giant panda survey show that the number of wild giant pandas has increased from 1,114 in the 1970s and 1980s to 1,864, distributed in Qinling, Minshan, Qionglai Mountain, Daxiangling, Xiaoxiangling, Liangshan, etc. Six major mountain systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, natural geographical barriers isolate these wild giant pandas in six major mountain systems, and human activities have divided these six major habitat populations into small local populations that cannot interact with each other. &quot;Habitat fragmentation has resulted in the inability of genetic exchange between isolated populations, reducing the genetic diversity of small local populations and accelerating the disappearance of endangered small populations,&quot; said Wu Daifu, director of the Hetaoping base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To save a species, the integrity and stability of the community in which it is located and the genetic diversity within the species must be protected. &quot;Currently, the main measures taken to protect giant pandas in our country are in-situ protection and ex-situ protection.&quot; Wu Daifu said that the connection point between the two methods is to release giant pandas bred in captivity after rewilding training. Return to small endangered populations in the wild, thereby improving their genetic diversity, reducing the risk of extinction, and reviving the wild giant panda population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As global breeding problems such as difficulty in mating and conceiving and raising young to survive have been overcome, artificial breeding of giant pandas has achieved fruitful results, and the captive giant panda population has achieved self-sustainment. In 2003, the Panda Center launched the training and reintroduction of captive-bred giant pandas into the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2006, the male sub-adult giant panda &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was released into the wild after independent rewilding training. However, less than a year later, workers found its body in the snow. After analysis and judgment, &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; fell from a height and was seriously injured and died during a fight with a wild giant panda for territory and food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Panda Center summarized the failed rewilding case of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; and believed that maybe it was the lack of suitable learning objects that led to the lack of survival ability of &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; in the wild; maybe it was because the population in the reintroduction area was saturated, and &quot;Xiang Xiang&quot; was not able to survive in the wild. &quot;Lack of enough living space; the competition for territory and mates among adult male giant pandas in the wild is extremely fierce. &quot;Xiangxiang&quot; may not have enough fighting experience and cannot resist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sum up experience and make persistent efforts. In 2010, with the stable growth of the captive giant panda population, the Panda Center launched the second phase of the captive giant panda rewilding training project, and proposed for the first time a new rewilding training method of &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c89176807e0a5e9d5b83652545c85998.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253797&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The giant panda &quot;Qin Xin&quot; was released into the wild. Photo by He Haiyang&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Helping giant panda cubs learn wild survival skills as soon as they are born&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“At 1:16 in the morning, the cub screamed, &quot;The mother lay on her side to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 4:53 am, the mother adjusted her sleeping position to protect her cub&quot; &quot;At 8 am, the mother ate 9 bamboos in the morning and drank water twice. The cub screamed loudly and defecated once, but there were no abnormalities.&quot; ...In the monitoring room of the Hetaoping base, the work log of the keepers records in detail the daily activities of the giant panda &quot;Hui Hui&quot; and her newborn cubs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are 4 giant panda cubs in the first stage of rewilding training at the Hetaoping Base: &quot;Zhichun Zai&quot; and &quot;Bosi Zai&quot; who are over 1 years old, and two newborn cubs . &quot;All organs of newly born giant panda cubs are not fully developed. We must always pay attention to them and conduct video surveillance around the clock, and take timely measures if any abnormality occurs,&quot; said breeder Zhang Dalei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the growth and behavioral development characteristics of giant pandas, rewilding training is divided into two stages. From birth to about 1 year old, in a small training circle of about 2,000 square meters, the cubs eat breast milk. ; From about 1 year old to before release, in a large training circle of 200,000-300,000 square meters, the cubs gradually learn to eat bamboo independently. The large-scale training enclosure is located in the wild habitat environment of giant pandas, where there are tall trees, dense bamboo forests and complex terrain, in a completely natural state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on long-term practice and research, the Panda Center creatively implements &quot;mother animals raising cubs&quot; training. &quot;From birth, the cubs live with their mothers and gradually learn survival skills such as foraging for food, finding water sources, and avoiding natural enemies in nature. In the past, breeders could not teach pandas to climb trees in a few days. Now panda mothers use their mouths to climb trees. Just push the baby up the tree, and the panda baby will learn to climb the tree twice.&quot; He Shengshan said that giant pandas can be released into the wild only after completing a series of training and undergoing expert evaluation. &quot;At this time, two or three-year-old pandas will learn to climb trees. Giant pandas are in the post-weaning and pre-adult stage, and as sub-adults, it is easier to integrate into the wild giant panda population.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The selection of female animals is very particular. &quot;It is best for the mother animal to be a multi-parous giant panda with experience in wild life, or an individual with strong ability to raise young.&quot; He Shengshan said that at the same time, the body of the mother animal must be kept in good health, and factors such as age and genetic background must also be considered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid &quot;imprinting behavior&quot; in giant panda cubs, the impact of human activities must be minimized. &quot;Every time the female panda is fed food, the keeper will put on a &#39;panda suit&#39; to prevent the cubs from becoming dependent on humans.&quot; Zhang Dalei said that pandas should be made to avoid humans as soon as they sense humans instead of actively approaching them. Only then can they return to the jungle smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to feeding food, cleaning the enclosures, etc., keepers are also responsible for observing and recording the growth, development and behavioral performance of giant pandas, such as the time of first walking, first climbing, first eating bamboo, etc. Since 2012, Zhang Dalei has raised 7 giant pandas for rewilding training. &quot;Although the work is hard and tiring, as long as they return to the wild and live a healthy life, I will feel a sense of accomplishment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Accompanying giant pandas all year round is an enviable job, but it also contains risks and challenges that few people know about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In summer, mudslides often occur in the mountains, and the wild training circle is often put to the test. &quot;The mudslide that occurred on August 20, 2019, was less than 100 meters away from the cabin where we were resting. The situation at that time was very thrilling.&quot; He Shengshan still has lingering fears. Encountering wild animals in the wild is also common. &quot;Wild boars, snakes, etc. are often encountered in the mountains. Only by accumulating rich experience and being fully prepared can we avoid danger again and again,&quot; He Shengshan said. Now, he and his colleagues always make preventive plans in advance, bring enough supplies before going up the mountain, and carry satellite phones with them to ensure smooth communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researcher Wei Hua almost lost his life while training giant pandas in the wild. In December 2016, the cub &quot;Baxi&quot; who was trained in Tiantai Mountain was close to the age of release, but no sign of &quot;Baxi&quot; was found for two consecutive days. Wei Hua and his colleagues were very worried and entered the training circle to search, but found no trace of him. Thinking of being attacked and seriously injured by the giant panda mother &quot;Ximei&quot; who was eager to protect her cubs. Even so, Wei Hua still believes: &quot;&#39;Ximei&#39; biting me shows that it is wild and maternal. This is exactly the goal we pursue when releasing giant pandas into the wild.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6b7edb5080465fd325ad27a55d763969.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Giant panda mother teaches her cub to climb a tree. Photo by Xue Yubin&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Carry out the reintroduction of giant pandas in an orderly manner to improve the genetic diversity of small populations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After giant panda rewilding training, how to determine Release back into the habitat? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao, senior engineer of the Investigation and Monitoring Department of the Panda Center, said that scientific researchers will comprehensively consider various factors such as suitable habitat quality, area, staple food bamboo biomass, and genetic background of released giant pandas to determine the release site. . In 2018, giant pandas &quot;Qin Xin&quot; and &quot;Little Walnut&quot; were released into the Longxi Hongkou National Nature Reserve in Dujiangyan City, located in the Minshan Mountains, after undergoing wild training and scientific evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to monitor the survival status of giant pandas after they are released? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hao said that when giant pandas are released, they will be put on an electronic collar that can be tracked and monitored, and their movement trajectory, health status and other information will be tracked through satellite signals. &quot;However, the collar It will fall off in about a year and a half, and long-term tracking and monitoring cannot be carried out. We must rely on infrared cameras, feces sampling and other methods to collect more data.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wherever the giant panda is, we will follow it.&quot; Xie Hao He said that the monitoring team members searched for giant panda feces in the deep mountains and old forests, recorded relevant detailed information, and analyzed the giant pandas&#39; gender, age, population, and genetic relationships by extracting DNA. &quot;In the mountains and valleys, we often walk for more than half a month, resting wherever we catch up at night. Sometimes we can&#39;t keep up with food supplies, and we have to go hungry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 2021, Dujiangyan During field monitoring, staff of the city&#39;s state-owned forest farm captured images of wild giant pandas through infrared cameras, which were suspected to be giant pandas released in 2018. A team of experts went to the site to inspect and collect fecal samples for further testing. Through the DNA extracted from it, it was determined that this female giant panda over 5 years old was the giant panda &quot;Little Walnut&quot; released in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;219&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/8900c1ccd18fd5129b1f27d7af40f4df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253801&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Researchers use radio equipment to track and monitor the movements of giant pandas. Photo courtesy of China Giant Panda Conservation and Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingchun, deputy director of the Wild Ecology Research Office of the Panda Center, was excited when he saw the image of &quot;Little Walnut&quot;, &quot;This giant panda has a round body and a good mental state.&quot; Normal and living in good condition in the wild. When the DNA identification results confirmed that it was indeed &#39;Little Walnut&#39;, the rewilding training team was very excited. This showed that the rewilding training of &#39;Little Walnut&#39; for more than two years was successful. I hope it can be It thrives in the wild, and we look forward to finding a suitable husband, breeding offspring, and bringing us more surprises!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the Panda Center has released 11 captive-bred giant pandas, and 9 are still alive. , 7 of which were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Xiaoxiangling Mountain System that are at risk of extinction, and 2 were successfully integrated into the wild population of the Minshan Mountain System. Among the released giant pandas, 1 male and 4 females, a total of 5, are over 6 years old and are in the prime stage of breeding. &quot;Only by releasing giant pandas into the wild population and breeding offspring can we achieve the goal of expanding the wild population. But finding clear evidence that the released giant pandas have offspring requires patience and time,&quot; Wu Daifu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, our country is building an integrated sky, air and ground monitoring system for national parks. &quot;We take this as an opportunity to add cameras, infrared cameras and other monitoring equipment in the areas where giant pandas are released into the wild to improve large-space monitoring capabilities.&quot; said Yang Jian, director of the Investigation and Monitoring Department of the Panda Center. At the same time, we will strengthen the research and development of collars. Efforts are made to improve battery life, improve positioning accuracy, and realize real-time transmission of recordings to understand the wild movements of giant pandas and other wild survival information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We will evaluate genetic contributions through dynamic monitoring of the population.&quot; Yang Jian said that through technologies such as &quot;cat face recognition&quot; and DNA individual identification, we will use technologies such as &quot;cat face recognition&quot; and DNA individual recognition to analyze giant pandas&#39; kinship, age structure and genetic level. We will carry out dynamic monitoring, establish a database of regional population size, structure and geographical distribution, and verify whether the released individuals are breeding offspring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Daifu said that within the scope of the Giant Panda National Park, we will analyze the factors limiting the recovery of small local endangered populations from aspects such as genetic diversity, population dynamics, community characteristics, and human interference, and scientifically formulate plans. , carry out the reintroduction of giant pandas in an orderly manner and improve the genetic diversity of small populations.同时，通过在生态廊道开展放归，增强种群间的基因连通性，为实现大熊猫种群的野外复壮提供关键支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，大熊猫野化培训梯队已经建立，未来每年将有培训合格的大熊猫个体放归野外，并努力复壮大熊猫小种群。 “我们将加快大熊猫野化培训、放归、监测等关键技术的创新和推广应用，力争每年放归大熊猫3至6只，并通过引种加大野生大熊猫濒危小种群资源保护，逐步建立野生大熊猫遗传种质资源库，实现圈养种群与野生种群基因双向交流。”吴代福说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列情报机构睡着了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258423]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W519uIJUPDbL0XMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1436&quot; height=&quot;958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xcPaSqDxQmYrHkrCAFG7JH82W51 9uIJUPDbL0XMu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253630&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Gaza City, Palestinian militants fired rockets at Israel &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 7, 2023, the Palestinian resistance organization Hamas launched an attack on Israel in the border area between Palestine and Israel. Multiple cities launched compound sneak attacks, not only launching a large number of rockets but also conducting violent ground attacks. According to current statistics, at least 700 Israelis have been killed in Hamas attacks. This is the deadliest war between Israeli military and civilians since the Yom Kippur War in 1973. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu promised the people &quot;terrible revenge&quot; on Hamas and declared a state of war. This was Israel&#39;s first time in 50 years since the end of the Yom Kippur War in 1973. declared a state of war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this attack happened suddenly, there should be many clues to follow before such a large-scale attack. Why did Israel, which has Mossad, known as the most efficient intelligence agency in the world, not Can we give early warning? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before discussing this issue, we first need to understand that the intelligence work in the Palestinian-Israeli-controlled areas is positioned as domestic security business in Israel, so the main responsible agency is not the famous Mossad (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Intelligence and Secret Service&lt;/span>;), but the Shin Bet (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;National Security Agency&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shin Bet&#39;s past work in the Gaza Strip has always been considered low-key and effective. For example, in &quot;Operation Green Prince&quot;, they successfully instigated the rebellion of the son of Hamas senior Hassan Yusuf. Mosab Hassan Yusuf, for more than ten years since 1996, has obtained a large amount of intelligence from the core decision-making levels of the Hamas organization through him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Israel assigns the main intelligence work in the Palestinian-Israeli region to the Shin Bet is actually because there are frequent personnel exchanges between the two places, so there are many operations and inspections that require the cooperation of the police department, and Mossad Mainly responsible for external intelligence and covert operations, its personnel have less cooperation with local police forces, which is not conducive to seamless connection. In addition to internal counter-intelligence and anti-terrorism work, the Shin Bet also has security and protection work for dignitaries and important departments. It is closely connected with the police department, which is obviously more conducive to its work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So if we really want to hold the responsibility for the poor response to this Hamas raid, the Shin Bet cannot escape the blame, but in the final analysis, this incident also exposed the structural failure of the Israeli military and police intelligence and security system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information provided to me by some insiders, there are several main reasons for Israel’s ineffective response this time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is Israel’s constitutional crisis starting in 2022, which has led to military The police intelligence and security system is in panic. The judicial reforms carried out by the right-wing government led by Netanyahu may have shaken the foundation of Israel&#39;s national unity, causing experienced intelligence personnel and military police to retire early and emigrate overseas. The morale of those in office has also inevitably been low, weakening the country. overall combat capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the internal security situation in Israel has been severe in the past year or so. The vendettas and gun battles between Arab gangs on the streets have seriously affected Israel’s social security. Organized crime investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also technical reasons. In recent years, the Shin Bet and the police have tended to rely more on signal intelligence and technical investigation. Due to their extensive electronic monitoring and aerial reconnaissance operations, as well as big data artificial intelligence intelligence analysis, they can obtain There is far more massive intelligence information than in the past, and automated processing is very fast. Classic manual intelligence acquisition methods like &quot;Operation Green Prince&quot; have become &quot;obsolete&quot; techniques and are no longer the focus of the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although signals intelligence has given Israel an advantage in recent years and is in line with the development direction of intelligence work, Hamas has now found a way to deal with it. Since the Gaza Strip is not large, a large amount of information can be transmitted through primitive person-to-person transmission to avoid signal detection. Since there is no electronic communication, no matter how powerful the monitoring technology is, it is useless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Israel, the current results can be said to be caused by a combination of low morale, personnel loss, resource tilt, and opponent evolution. In fact, the complexity of intelligence work far exceeds the imagination of the outside world. Some people use the term &quot;finding a needle in a haystack&quot; to describe it, which is actually not accurate. This type of counter-terrorism intelligence work is more like finding the poisonous needle in a sea full of needles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opponent&#39;s counterintelligence work is not limited to keeping secrets. At the same time, it will also release a large amount of true and false threat information to confuse the public, just like the shepherd boy who keeps shouting &quot;wolf is coming&quot;, leaving people at a loss as to what to do. Israel suffered heavy losses this time, and of course the intelligence and security agencies must be held accountable. However, from a professional perspective, the confrontation between intelligence and counterintelligence has never stopped. Signal intelligence obtained through network penetration, artificial intelligence, and big data analysis is not the only method for future military and counter-terrorism. Only through multi-method reconnaissance and multi-dimensional examination can the negative impact of the fog of war be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从费翔到蔡国庆，年轻一代为什么狂追“妈妈严选”男偶像？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/302c6f1c787a6b4c0b7f30a6519e0044.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/10/302c6f1c787a6b4c0b7f30a6519e0044.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, two stars born in the 1960s, Fei Xiang and Cai Guoqing, have become popular on the Internet and are deeply loved by young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were all their mothers’ idols when they were young, and were called “Mom’s Strictly Selected” by netizens. Many netizens lamented that this summer was the process of &quot;questioning my mother, understanding my mother, and becoming a mother&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How popular were the two &quot;Moms&#39; Selections&quot;? Why are today&#39;s young people attracted to them just like their mothers? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How popular were the idols of &quot;Mom&#39;s Choice&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before this summer, many young people In the eyes, both Fei Xiang and Cai Guoqing are &quot;passed&quot; stars - at least among young people. However, in the 1980s and 1990s, when many mothers were young, the popularity of Fei Xiang and Cai Guoqing could rival those of today&#39;s top celebrities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fei Xiang was born in Taiwan, China, in 1960. In 1978, Fei Xiang graduated from Taipei Shilin American School and was admitted to Stanford University in the United States to study medicine with honors. A year later, he transferred to the drama department of Stanford University. In 1981, Fei Xiang returned to Taiwan and entered the entertainment industry by starring in the Taiwan TV drama &quot;Eleven Women&quot; directed by Sylvia Chang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1982, Fei Xiang joined EMI Records (EMI Records) and launched his first solo album &quot;Lian Lian&quot; in Taiwan, which began to become popular. Fei Xiang was selected as one of the top ten Asian singers in Singapore. Together with Taiwanese singers Liu Wenzheng, Fei Yuqing, Feng Feifei and Jiang Ling, they were selected and ranked in the top five. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1986, Fei Xiang accompanied his mother back to Beijing to visit his grandmother. This opportunity aroused Fei Xiang’s deep feelings for his family and country. He moved to mainland China to develop and published books in the mainland. With his first solo album &quot;Songs Across the Four Seas&quot;, he became the first Taiwanese artist to cross the Taiwan Strait and enter the mainland music scene. The tape release exceeded one million mark in one fell swoop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1987, Fei Xiang became the first Taiwanese singer to return to the motherland and sang the songs &quot;Clouds in Hometown&quot; and &quot;A Day in Winter&quot; at CCTV&#39;s Spring Festival Gala. &quot;Fire&quot;, Fei Xiang&#39;s popularity in mainland China reached its peak overnight. Its foreign, open, free and unrestrained image, music style&lt;/span>;and performance style are refreshing and make thousands of girls crazy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fei Xiang has released multiple albums in mainland China, each of which has become a hit. In 1989, Fei Xiang held a total of 65 concerts in 12 cities in mainland China. CCTV and Central News Film Studio also specially made videos and films for broadcast nationwide. In 1990, Fei Xiang went to New York to develop on Broadway and successfully transformed into a Broadway actor with solid singing skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that Fei Xiang&#39;s status in the country in the 1980s was considered to be the top among the top. To the audience at that time, Fei Xiang &lt;span>; was not just a star, he also carried a lot of responsibility. It captures people&#39;s imagination of beauty, future and hope, like a fire in winter, lighting up many people&#39;s lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1968, Cai Guoqing was born, and he became famous at a young age. He joined the Central People&#39;s Broadcasting Station Children&#39;s Chorus at the age of 7 and published his first album at the age of 9. In 1986, Cai Guoqing participated in the first National Hundred Singers Concert and began his singing career. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1990, Beijing held the Fourth National Young Singer Grand Prix. Cai Guoqing won the silver medal in the popular singing group with his song &quot;Beijing&#39;s Bridge&quot;. At the Beijing Asian Games of the same year, which was the first comprehensive international sports competition held in my country, Cai Guoqing sang &quot;Tonight&lt;/span>;The Stars Are Bright&quot; at the closing ceremony, further becoming well-known to audiences across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991年，蔡国庆第一次登上中央电视台春节联欢晚会的舞台，演唱《去远方》。 From 1991 to 1995, Cai Guoqing participated as a main actor for five consecutive years. Cai Guoqing is a frequent guest at the Spring Festival Gala. He has appeared on the Spring Festival Gala stage 23 times so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the new century, Cai Guoqing is still active in the music scene, participating in various important theatrical performances, and participating in some variety shows as a judge from time to time. Cai Guoqing&#39;s elegant and solemn image is still a favorite of his mother, but it also makes some young people feel a bit distant, so he is not very popular among the younger generation. Many people know &lt;span>; him and don&#39;t particularly like him. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d8c7f22596c2ea307d89512e69702a61.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d8c7f22596c2ea307d89512e69702a61.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253564 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;&quot;Understand Mom, Become a Mom&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The two &quot;Moms&#39; Choice&quot; were once very popular, but in the era of the Internet and the fan economy, they The influence is more limited to the mother’s generation. This situation has changed this summer. Why are young people attracted to &quot;Mom Strictly Selected&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First of all, let’s look at it from the perspective of a star. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;During the domestic entertainment industry,&lt;/span>;many young top-notch celebrities, such as sky-high salaries, poor acting skills, lack of professionalism, and poor personal ethics, have been repeatedly exposed. The emergence of &quot;Selection&quot; has made young people discover that the older generation of artists are so self-disciplined, dedicated and professional. These are the role models for stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Yin Shou, played by Fei Xiang, had not stood up, there would not have been the success of &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot;. The audience also saw Fei Xiang&#39;s figure in the movie. It simply didn&#39;t look like the body of a middle-aged and elderly man in his sixties. The muscle lines were so clear that there was no trace of fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To maintain a healthy and good figure, &lt;span>; self-discipline is indispensable. As soon as Fei Xiang joined the set, he strictly controlled his diet and carried out devilish training such as equestrian, martial arts, and fitness. The filming lasted for a year and a half, and his training also lasted for a year and a half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fei Xiang has strong business ability and is very dedicated. As early as 2012, &quot;Painted Skin II&quot;, which he collaborated with Wu Ershan, was released. He participated in many promotions of &quot;Painted Skin II&quot; and was responsible for the promotion of the film in Taiwan alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time the road show of &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot; &lt;span>; took place in 29 cities, 33 days, and 170 shows. Fei Xiang participated in the road shows in 29 cities, and participated in a total of 164 road shows. It was so intense. Big, he still works personally and fights on the front line. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the Venice Film Festival, he initially went alone on behalf of the entire crew. Fei Xiang even participated in the English subtitles of &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot; that was released locally all night long. Translator, I have to attend an event the next day... How many big and small celebrities in domestic entertainment can be dedicated to such a degree? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This time Cai Guoqing participated&lt;/span>; in &quot;Beyond the Troubles 3&quot;. Many people thought that he would sleep on his laurels, but Cai Guoqing had no airs or baggage at all. . On the first stage, he challenged Jay Chou&#39;s &quot;Mojito&quot;, allowing the audience to hear the lyrics of the song so clearly for the first time. However, Cai Guoqing&#39;s singing is also different from Jay Chou&#39;s flavor, and his business ability is still online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, whether he was practicing singing or dancing, Cai Guoqing maintained a positive and energetic state of mind. He worked hard, was humble and sober: &quot;After a breakthrough, it is heaven for me to produce high-quality works.&quot; It&#39;s a great thing; it&#39;s a great encouragement to be recognized by today&#39;s audience.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Young people pursue &quot;Mom&#39;s Strict Choice&quot;, and another one is that the younger generation looks at the elders perspective. For example, the reason why young people affectionately call Fei Xiang &quot;Fei Xiang daddy&quot; is not only because he plays a father in &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot;, but also because he is the ideal father figure and ideal elder in the hearts of many young people. image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In real life, many elders are often keen on preaching to young people as elders and dictating their lifestyles. From Fei Xiang&#39;s series of interviews, we can see that he respects everyone&#39;s lifestyle and has profound insights into marriage, love and other key life issues. He is non-interfering, non-preaching, wise and graceful. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are also some elders who are keen to rely on their elders as elders. I have the final say in everything, young people must listen to me, and young people must respect me. , You have to praise me...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Beyond the Troubles 3&quot;, many young people saw a so real and personal Cai Guoqing for the first time: he has no airs at all and is very He is free-spirited and able to mingle with young people. He is willing to &quot;listen to&quot; others&#39; suggestions and is extremely easy-going and friendly... Who wouldn&#39;t love to have sex with such an &quot;elder&quot;? Young people will not have the pressure, embarrassment and suffering of those in lower positions. They still have respect for their elders in their hearts, and they can still be themselves freely and easily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In short, the reason behind young people&#39;s pursuit of &quot;Mom&#39;s Choice&quot; is their dissatisfaction with the current internal entertainment ecology, and the fact that young people have been suffering from the pressure of their elders for a long time but are unable to do so. The helplessness of breaking free or daring to be angry but not speaking out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;While we hope that there will be more “Mom’s Careful Choices”, young people might as well follow “Mother’s Carefully Selected” as an example and grow into a better person. people can eventually become better elders. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从张亮和杨国福说起：特色县的产业聚集为何常常以乡情亲缘为纽带？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258299]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It was rumored on the Internet that the two hotpot giants Zhang Liang and Yang Guofu were relatives: Zhang Liang was originally working in his uncle Yang Guofu’s shop He worked part-time there, and later went out to work alone and founded Zhang Liang Malatang. Later, Zhang Liang said: &quot;There is no blood relationship, it is kinship.&quot; Yang Guofu also made the same statement as Zhang Liang. Therefore, one thing is probably certain, that is, Zhang Liang was indeed inspired by Yang Guofu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Liang and Yang Guofu also inspired the locals. Their hometown of Bin County in Harbin has developed into a gathering place for the spicy hotpot industry. In addition to Zhang Liang and Yang Guofu, there are many other brands that are worth mentioning. Known as the &quot;Capital of Malatang&quot;. In the words of the person in charge of production of Yang Guofu Company: &quot;If a village works, everyone will follow, and the industry will rise.&quot; It is not difficult to imagine that countless ambitious young people in Bin County have followed their footsteps and entered Mala. Start a business in the ironing industry to change your destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, this is not a special case. Many people will remember that when they were in high school, the print shops around the school were owned by Hunanese; in universities thousands of miles away, the copy shops in and around the school were still owned by Hunanese; when studying for graduate school, change places and print. The store is still owned by Hunanese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These Hunanese are all from Xinhua County, Loudi City, a famous photocopying town. Xinhua County is located in the central part of Hunan Province, with mountains crisscrossing the territory and a harsh environment. The per capita cultivated land is less than 0.15 acres. The harsh natural environment forced Xinhua people to go out. As early as 1960, before the reform and opening up, Xinhua people Yi Daixing and Yi Daiyu brothers accidentally learned the mechanical typewriter repair technology in Fuling, Sichuan, and this became the Xinhua people&#39;s copier industry. The origin of. Xinhua people spread second-hand copying equipment from Japan and the United States to China through international trade, provide support for maintenance and consumables, and sell it to copy shops through professional markets, forming a complete industrial chain of &quot;international trade + professional markets + professional stores&quot; . With this industry chain, wherever there are new people, the price of copying will drop rapidly, driving people from other regions out of the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many such phenomena, such as Tonglu Express, Chengdu Snacks, Shaxian Snacks, Fujian Putian Medical, Caoxian Hanfu, Guanyun Underwear, etc. To a certain extent, this is a unique phenomenon formed by the grafting of industrial agglomeration and Chinese-style interpersonal relationships: industrial affinity and geographical agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The formation paths of these industrial clusters are similar. Initially, a local person becomes successful in a certain industry, expands his career, and attracts more relatives and friends to join; in the industry chain, he also follows the connections of acquaintances. Find a supplier or distributor. Later, relatives and friends may start their own business, or others may see it and imitate it, and more people may join. Finally, an industrial cluster was formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many reasons for this phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a theory of six degrees of separation in sociology, that is, any two people in the world can be connected through six people who know each other. Simply put, you know the President of the United States through six people. This may seem impossible, but in fact it is not difficult to put it bluntly. For example, one of the paths: anyone can easily get to know a college student, and connect to the principal through the college student&#39;s teacher. The university president is already a very high-level relationship, and through two or three more people, it can reach a higher level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the basis of six degrees of separation, some scholars have proposed the three-degree separation theory, that is to say, there are strong connections within three degrees of separation, and strong connections can trigger human behavior. A connection that is more than three degrees apart is a weak connection, and weak connections can only transmit information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to understand that strong connections can trigger action. Strong connections first broaden people&#39;s horizons and provide choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an up owner called &quot;African Fei Ge&quot; at Station B. He shoots videos about African customs and customs, and has caught up with the trend of short videos. His education level is not high, but because he has a father who has been working in Africa for more than ten years, he went to Africa to work. He is smart and hard-working. He first worked part-time, then went into business, and then discovered short videos. Obviously, without his father, it would be basically impossible for him to come into contact with the choice of &quot;going to Africa&quot; ​​in his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strong connections can also stimulate &quot;people around you&quot; to pursue success. Even if you only make a small fortune, people around you will be very sensitive and will feel envious. On the other hand, the people around you may be your childhood friends, classmates, relatives, or friends of friends. They understand each other better and will not be deified. They will make people feel that they are objects that can be imitated and successes that can be achieved, which in turn stimulates people. Pursue this success yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This strong connection transfers resources. Once, I went to Nantong to attend an event and visited the Home Textile City. I met a young boss who was born in 1997. He was 24 years old at the time. He drove a BMW 5 Series and ran a large home textile store. After the activity, everyone had dinner together. The boss said that he had been working since he was 16 years old. I asked him when he switched from working part-time to starting his own business. The reason why I ask this question is: I started out to work at the age of 16. I don’t have a high degree of education. It must be because my family’s financial conditions are not good, so I started working early, accumulated the first pot of gold, gained industry experience, and then started my own business. Be successful. But he said: I have never worked part-time, and I started an independent business as soon as I came out. My parents, my brother, and my sister are all in this business. They took me and opened their own shop. This is a typical example of strong connections providing choices and resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Business itself also pursues this kind of strong connection. Industrial agglomeration in economics refers to the highly dense gathering of several different types of enterprises that produce certain products within a reasonably large area, as well as the upstream and downstream enterprises and related service industries that support these enterprises. Companies in the same industry gather together to search for raw material products, the cost of obtaining supporting products and services, and the cost of transportation and communication all become smaller due to the closer geographical distance, resulting in greater competitiveness. industry agglomeration. In essence, cost reduction is the most basic driving force for industrial agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to establish trust between strangers. The biggest costs for enterprises in the business process are communication costs and trust costs. Then, similarly, from the perspective of cost reduction, companies in the industry chain will gather along interpersonal relationships. This is also the reason why family businesses have flourished in various countries for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, from another perspective, this is what people call a circle. Of course, it’s up to you to benefit from the circle. Some people can’t do it even if their parents give it to them. Some people just hear about it and take action immediately, follow, learn, imitate, and finally achieve success. So, in the final analysis, the biggest factor is the people themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百年广三铁路上的佛山火车站停运升级，市民游客前来打卡“最后的绿皮车”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258405]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[财政部：停止销售“六六顺”等41款即开型福利彩票游戏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The Ministry of Finance regarding the suspension of sales of &quot;Liu Liu Shun&quot; Waiting for approval opinions on 41 instant welfare lottery games&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Caizong [2023] No. 36&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;China Welfare Lottery Issuance and Management Center:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Your Center&#39;s &quot;Request for Instructions on Stopping the Sales of 41 Instant Welfare Lottery Games including &quot;Liu Liu Shun&quot;&quot; (Zhongcai Fa Zi [2023] 111 No.) received. According to the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; (State Council Order No. 554), &quot;Lottery Management Regulations Implementation Rules&quot; (Ministry of Finance and Civil Affairs Sports General Administration Order No. 96) and &quot;Lottery Issuance and Sales Management Measures&quot; (Caizong [2018] No. 67) and other relevant regulations, the relevant matters are hereby notified as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. In order to further optimize the structure of welfare lottery games and promote the healthy development of the lottery market, it is agreed that your center will stop selling 41 instant models including &quot;Liu Liu Shun&quot; Welfare lottery game (see attachment). Your center should issue an announcement to the public within 2 months from the date of approval. The announcement content includes the name and number of the approval document from the Ministry of Finance, the date of suspension of sales, the deadline for prize redemption, etc. After 60 calendar days from the date of announcement, the sales of the above 41 lottery games will be stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. After the above-mentioned 41 lottery games stop selling, prizes must be paid in accordance with regulations during the prize redemption period. After the prize redemption period, your center should complete the lottery fund settlement with the lottery sales agency. Overdue bonuses that have not been redeemed will be included in the lottery public welfare fund, and the bonus balance will be transferred to the general adjustment fund. Overdue bonuses will be disbursed according to regulations. After the prize redemption period, your center and the lottery sales agency shall submit written reports to the financial department at the same level within 60 calendar days. The report content includes lottery issuance and sales, lottery prize withdrawal, redemption, balance transfer, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Your center should strictly follow the current lottery management system regulations, urge lottery sales agencies to strengthen sales safety management and risk control, and effectively do announcements, prize redemption, settlement and other related work. It is necessary to rationally plan the structure of instant lottery games, coordinate and connect the game approval, budget preparation, printing and logistics, marketing, sales and other work links, effectively save costs, improve efficiency, and ensure the sustainable and healthy development of instant lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attachment: 41 instant welfare lottery games including &quot;Liu Liu Shun&quot; that have been agreed to stop selling&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/ZzHR8zF18Igbj6ifjjItr5bsHZQAg40CfCFTgG1u.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1032&quot; height=&quot;1986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/11/ZzHR8zF18Igbj6ifjjItr5bsHZQAg40CfCFTgG1u.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253796&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人生中的丧失丨洛城机密]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258383]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/QIOLdyerbnCbufWbj43eXoGlo8kzgQtfBRBxiDaO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/QIOLdyerbnCbufWbj43eXoGlo8kzgQtfBRBxiDaO . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253725&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still from the movie &quot;Interstellar&quot; (2014). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter three years ago, I went to Joshua Tree National Park for stargazing with my boyfriend at the time. Neither of us knew when we went there that Joshua Tree’s reputation came from a hallucination caused by an overdose of marijuana. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Joshua Tree is located deep in the desert in the outer suburbs of Los Angeles, so it can be said that this illusion is a type of mirage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My ex-boyfriend is from South Korea, a devout Christian, and a scientist by profession. His favorite movie is Nolan&#39;s &quot;Interstellar&quot;, and his fascination with the stars can be said to be a combination of science and faith. On the one hand, he has an endless thirst for knowledge about space and areas unknown to mankind. On the other hand, if we borrow Mr. Qian Mu’s metaphor and regard the known human beings as these little bits of starlight, and the vast and endless darkness as the unknown realm, then the ex-boyfriend’s response to this is: There must be a creator who created All of this, and we humans must spend our entire lives searching for the goodness of everything He created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I love reading theology books, I do not believe in any religion. At that time, the starry sky was more of a natural wonder to me. It&#39;s a pity that the two of us put on down jackets and raised our heads like nestlings begging for food in the cold desert night. The starry sky that caught our eyes was not as charming as the one I had seen on the Iowa farm. Sitting on the tractor in the Iowa farm, I was really shocked by the Milky Way above my head: the stars were like the stone bridges on the streams in the Yunnan-Guizhou region, intermittently extending from one bank of the river to the other bank. I tried to Trace each star point with your eyes, imagining that the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl are like this, carefully stepping on the stars to meet in the middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My ex-boyfriend went stargazing for the first time, and the blurry starry sky over Joshua Tree captured his heart. He also became more convinced that it was the hand of God that created all of this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Perhaps, the different attitudes towards Xingguang have already hinted that this relationship is destined to end in vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think of this past incident, it may be because I have been wandering around for these years. Some time ago, a teacher at Washington University in St. Louis asked me to write a letter of recommendation for her. Her resume was full of ups and downs in her academic career. She had held teaching positions in New York State, Pennsylvania, Texas, and Missouri. Now, After ten years of teaching in St. Louis, she finally had a chance to settle down. As a doctoral candidate, I also know that if I am looking for a teaching position, I am destined to face this kind of great migration experience every few years. To be honest, I&#39;m tired of this. The biggest difficulty with living a nomadic life is this: you never make lasting connections. It&#39;s not easy to make one or two close friends, or a lover who you thought would be a lifelong companion, but because of your own or the other person&#39;s migration, the relationship broke up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Separation, to me, is like letting go of two people and falling into the vast abyss of the universe at the same time without a trace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is no accident that many poems at home and abroad use starlight to compare separation. I have reached the age where my eyes well up with tears when I read Du Fu&#39;s &quot;If we don&#39;t meet each other in life, we will move like participating in business&quot;. When I was in middle school, the first time I read Xu Zhimo&#39;s &quot;Accidental&quot; I just thought it was romantic. I even thought it was a high-sounding excuse for a playboy because of various ancient moral prejudices. However, now, once again imagining &quot;you and me&quot; who &quot;disappeared in an instant&quot;, all we can remember in the end is &quot;the light that shined on each other when we met&quot;, and I feel more helpless. Because the lost relationship and friendship can no longer be traced in the dark night, the only thing that can be remembered is the memory as bright as the starlight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern psychology classifies &quot;death of relatives and friends&quot;, &quot;broken love&quot;, &quot;unemployment&quot; and &quot;loss of money&quot; as &quot;loss&quot;. Loss is difficult to digest, because no matter how much we mourn, how much we regret, how much we grieve, we cannot get rid of the reality that it is hard to recover. I have not been close to people since I was a child, so once I lose someone close to me, it is difficult to recover. Even today, seventeen years after my grandfather passed away, I still miss him and walk with him on familiar streets in my dreams. Even though I am clearly aware that I am in a dream, I still hope that this dream can last longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with losses, many people will eventually fall into the mentality of gamblers, constantly increasing their bets in order to win back everything they have lost before, so that they fall deeper and deeper into the trap. I have met friends who have always been in good schools. Because of a failure in an exam or failure in applying to a prestigious school, they kept applying year after year, so that all the meaning of life lies in whether they can get back this one. After falling out of love, many people will rush into the next relationship, eager to turn the previous failure experience into the next success. Unfortunately, this kind of eagerness for success will probably only suffer greater trauma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year, I also sat alone in the mire-like darkness, and almost fell into the never-ending gambler&#39;s mentality. Finally, the famous words of the ancient Roman Neo-Stoic philosopher Epictetus woke me up: &quot;Don&#39;t think of loss as loss, think of it as return.&quot; In other words, those dazzling moments when the stars meet are never It does not belong to me, but it is temporarily loaned to me by the universe. One day, I must return this gift. All I can do is try to cherish it while borrowing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is opening this generous &quot;library&quot; behind the world? I don&#39;t know, I don&#39;t have the answer. All I know is that those who believe in gods are blessed, and they can draw more strength from their faith to survive the dark night. Let&#39;s take the loss as an example. A devout believer will shed his attachment to himself. Without attachment, there is no need to go bankrupt just to save face. Without attachment, he will feel that when he walks in the world, all encounters and companionship are worthy of gratitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the British poet WH Auden&#39;s famous work &quot;More Love&quot; (translated by Huang Canran), Auden regards the burning of stars as &quot;the unrequited passion of mankind&quot;, because of this love Only with the admiration and gratitude of the stars can he say: &quot;If all the stars fall or disappear, / I will learn to look at an empty sky / and feel the solemnity of its complete darkness, / although it may take me a while .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[浙江国祥 IPO申购前夕暂停，谁欲分享资本盛宴？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258403]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/EzqH3Y4F6QmiFFWlwVxyIw3QnpuhD4Fv75Ob7Szf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/EzqH3Y4F6QmiFFWlwVxyIw3Q npuhD4Fv75Ob7Szf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253745&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Retailers play cards on the exchange. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang, which plans to start subscribing in the secondary market on October 9, 2023, due to Public opinion surged, and the Shanghai Stock Exchange actually stopped the IPO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, the first day of resumption of work after the holiday, the Shanghai Stock Exchange issued a response to reporters&#39; questions, saying that in the spirit of being responsible for the market and investors, it would respond to the situation reported by the self-media and treat Zhejiang Guoxiang Conduct a special inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the prospectus, Zhejiang Guoxiang was established in 2009 and is headquartered in Shaoxing City. It is mainly engaged in the research and development, production and sales of industrial and commercial central air-conditioning special equipment. It has served Luxshare Precision, BYD, and Ningde Well-known customers and projects in various industries such as Times, Hangzhou Metro Group, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital, and Beijing Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2015, Zhejiang Guoxiang was listed on the New Third Board, and submitted prospectus materials to the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Science and Technology Innovation Board twice at the end of 2016 and in 2020, but the IPO failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Zhejiang Guoxiang once again impacted the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange. It took 159 days to obtain approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission for its IPO registration, which was just one step away from success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, Zhejiang Guoxiang announced an issue price of 68.07 yuan per share, with an issue price-to-earnings ratio of 51.29 times. The plan was to open subscriptions on October 9. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, after a short holiday, the clamor that its issue price was too high has become louder and louder. In addition, there have been doubts about Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s secondary listing of the same asset in the past, and the controversy has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, the Shanghai Stock Exchange once again issued a response to the suspension of IPO issuance by Zhejiang Guoxiang, introducing the Shanghai Stock Exchange’s preliminary review and supervision of the company, and stated that in response to the market and the majority of investors, Concerned, the Shanghai Stock Exchange will seriously organize a special inspection of Zhejiang Guoxiang and will decide on follow-up work based on the results of the special inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did Zhejiang Guoxiang cause public outrage? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Second listing of the same asset? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the prospectus, Zhejiang Guoxiang’s assets come indirectly from Zhejiang Guoxiang Refrigeration Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Guoxiang Refrigeration), which is the first Taiwan-funded enterprise listed on the A-share market. , which is quite symbolic in the mainland capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taihai.com reported in 2008 that the parent company of Guoxiang Refrigeration was Guoxiang Refrigeration Machinery Company, which was established in Taoyuan, Taiwan in 1966. It was the largest manufacturer of industrial refrigeration and air-conditioning equipment in Taiwan at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above report stated that in 1995, Chen Hegui, chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration Machinery Company, went to Zhejiang to invest and established Guoxiang Refrigeration as a joint venture with Zhejiang Shaoxing Refrigeration Equipment Factory. After that, Chen Tianlin succeeded his father Chen Hegui and became the chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration. Guoxiang Refrigeration was listed on the A-share market in 2003 with the stock code 600340. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to subjective and objective factors such as poor operating conditions, Guoxiang Refrigeration suffered continuous losses in 2007 and 2008. In May 2009, it was issued a delisting risk warning and became *ST Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2009, Guoxiang Refrigeration announced that it planned to sell out all its existing assets and liabilities through major asset swaps and the issuance of shares to Xingfu Foundation, and at the same time inject the shares held by Xingfu Foundation into Real estate development and regional development business assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month ago, Chen Tianlin resigned as chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration, and Chen Genwei served as chairman and general manager of Guoxiang Refrigeration. Chen Genwei has been working for Guoxiang Refrigeration since 1997, and has successively served as section chief of the Quality Assurance Department, Secretary of the Board of Directors, and Director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2011, Guoxiang Refrigeration Asset Restructuring received approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission, and the real estate company China Fortune Land Development successfully used its shell to go public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since China Fortune Land Development’s main business is real estate investment and development and has no intention of operating central air-conditioning business, in 2012, Zhejiang Guoxiang Holdings Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Guoxiang Holdings) controlled by Chen Genwei and his wife used 80 million to acquire the transfer Zhejiang Guoxiang has 100% equity, and Chen Genwei has also been promoted to chairman of Zhejiang Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retailers therefore questioned Zhejiang Guoxiang’s IPO, which was considered a secondary listing of the same asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, during the IPO application process of Zhejiang Guoxiang in 2020 and this time, the Shanghai Stock Exchange made inquiries about the source of Zhejiang Guoxiang’s assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the Shanghai Stock Exchange asked Zhejiang Guoxiang to explain the proportion of its assets from the original listed company in its current assets and the role of its production and operations in its inquiry. It also asked the company to combine Past cases in the capital market indicate whether there are similar precedents in which the assets of a listed company were reorganized and then relisted with the same assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang listed a number of similar cases in its reply, such as Sichuan Instruments (603100.SH), Leon Micro (605358.SH), etc., saying that their main assets came from listed companies’ acquisitions. out assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the secondary listing, the Shanghai Stock Exchange stated in its response to reporters on October 9 that after review, the transactions of this part of the assets occurred in 2011 and 2012, and the total book assets related to the acquisition at the end of 2022 The relevant net fixed assets accounted for 15% and 0.06% of Zhejiang Guoxiang’s total existing assets respectively. Zhejiang Guoxiang has shifted from focusing on commercial central air conditioners to mainly industrial central air conditioners. Its business, products, and technology Substantial changes have taken place in research and development, personnel and sales models, actual controllers and management. At the same time, there is basically no overlap between Zhejiang Guoxiang’s sales customers and suppliers and *ST Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding listing standards, the Shanghai Stock Exchange quoted Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus, saying that its cumulative net profit in the past three years was 387 million yuan, its net profit in the most recent year was 186 million yuan, and its cash generated from operating activities in the past three years The cumulative net flow was 600 million yuan, and the cumulative operating income was 4.226 billion yuan. &quot;Zhejiang Guoxiang complies with the first set of motherboard listing standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/IMsplTUYVODSvJG1Hixdfl4GpDumv6wy93BY5qAF.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/IMsplTUYVODSvJG1Hixdfl4GpDumv6wy93BY5qAF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 253746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The closing stock index of the day is displayed on an LED screen outside a building in Lujiazui, Shanghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Super Raising&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;1.4&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Billion Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to the secondary listing, the trigger for IPO controversy is also the excessive issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s issue price is 68.07 yuan per share, and the issue price-to-earnings ratio is 51.29 times. Such a high issue price was also beyond Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that the company is expected to use 737 million yuan in raised funds for this fundraising project. Based on the issue price of 68.07 yuan per share and the number of new shares issued of 35.0234 million shares, if this issuance is successful, Zhejiang Guoxiang is expected to raise a total of 2.384 billion yuan, after deducting the issuance expenses (excluding value-added tax) of 227.8 million yuan, The net amount of funds raised is expected to be 2.156 billion yuan, with an excess of 1.419 billion yuan raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s issue price-to-earnings ratio of 51.29 times is not only higher than the industry average, but also higher than the comparable companies in the industry it lists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;special equipment manufacturing industry (C35)&quot; in which it is located, as of September 26, 2023, the static average price-to-earnings ratio of C35 in the CSI Index industry in the past month was 27.81 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang disclosed five comparable companies in the same industry. After excluding the extreme value Jialitu (180.3 times) and the loss-making Yimikang, the average price-to-earnings ratio of the remaining three companies in 2022 is 45.82 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market criticized Zhejiang Guoxiang’s operating performance as being unable to match the issue price. Within the industry, Zhejiang Guoxiang has not yet occupied a dominant position, and its sustained profitability has been repeatedly questioned by the Shanghai Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang stated in the prospectus that since its establishment, it has been focusing on the research and development, production and sales of industrial and commercial central air-conditioning. After years of efforts, it has grown into a relatively large player in the industrial and commercial central air-conditioning industry. An enterprise with high brand competitiveness. However, the company&#39;s market shares in 2020, 2021 and 2022 are only 1.20%, 1.28% and 1.77% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that Zhejiang Guoxiang’s revenue increased from 470 million yuan to 834 million yuan from 2015 to 2019. However, its net profit fluctuated greatly, which were 53.3466 million yuan, 47.1391 million yuan, and 28.3440 yuan respectively. Ten thousand yuan, 43.937 million yuan, 67.3813 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years of the epidemic from 2020 to 2022, Zhejiang Guoxiang not only increased its revenue steadily, but its net profit also increased significantly, reaching 99.7907 million yuan, 101.3427 million yuan and 185.9114 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this IPO issuance process, the first question in the implementation letter of the Shanghai Stock Exchange Review Center required Zhejiang Guoxiang to disclose the matching of its net profit growth in 2022 with the company&#39;s revenue growth, and analyze the rapid revenue growth in 2022 The main logic of growth and the sustainability of future growth, and reveal the risks of unsustainable rapid growth and provide reminders of major matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Shanghai Stock Exchange Listing Committee meeting held on June 19, the Shanghai Stock Exchange once again required Zhejiang Guoxiang to explain whether its ability to continue operating has been significantly improved and improved based on the fact that its assets came from the original listed company *ST Guoxiang. , whether the relevant risk disclosure is sufficient. At the same time, the sponsor representative is requested to express clear opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The motivation for institutions to create new products at high prices&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The high issuance price is reported by institutional investors during the inquiry period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that a total of 8,732 placement targets managed by 800 offline investors participated in Zhejiang Guoxiang’s preliminary inquiry. The quotation range is 7.80 yuan/share-103.50 yuan/share, corresponding to the total number of proposed subscriptions. The total number of shares sold was 51.074 billion, and the overall offline subscription multiple was 2,700 times the initial offline issuance scale before the callback. Quotation subscriptions were relatively active. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After excluding invalid quotes and the highest quotes, there are still 733 investors, corresponding to 8,547 allotment objects. The highest quotes excluded refer to allotment objects whose subscription price is higher than 81.49 yuan/share, and allotment objects whose subscription price is 81.49 yuan/share and whose planned subscription quantity is less than 3.8 million shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lower of the average and the median quotes from offline investors is 73.6 yuan/share. Among them, the median quotations from public funds, fund management companies, insurance companies, securities companies, futures companies, trust companies and private equity funds are all around 74 yuan, which is higher than the final issuance price of 69.07 yuan per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among public funds, this is especially true for those who quote high prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seventeen products of Golden Eagle Fund quoted a high price of 92.52 yuan per share, a 33.9% premium to the issue price, and were all eliminated. 29 products under Harvest Fund quoted 81.94 yuan per share. They were eliminated because the number of planned subscriptions was less than 3.8 million shares. Another 122 products with the same quotation met the subscription quantity requirements and were shortlisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the valid quotes, Wells Fargo Fund (quoted at 80.75 yuan/share), Chuangjin Hexin (quoted at 80 yuan/share), Shenwan Lingxin Fund (quoted at 79 yuan/share), ICBC Credit Suisse Fund and CCB Credit Fund (quoted at 79 yuan/share) The quotations of public funds such as 78 yuan/share) far exceeded the issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is a company whose performance is really not impressive so sought after by institutions? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A private equity fund person explained to Southern Weekend reporters that the issue price pricing rules are relatively complex, involving the average and median of institutional quotations, and the average and median of quotations from social security funds, pension insurance, etc. Compare. The inquiry for new stocks only eliminates 1% of the high prices. As long as the quotation is slightly higher than the average price, institutions can be shortlisted and finally get the new stocks at the issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If new stocks in the market have a good profit-making effect recently, or the subject of new stocks is popular, institutions will increase their quotations to ensure shortlisting. The person said frankly, &quot;Regardless of the finalists, we all point to other institutions to look at the fundamentals. In fact, no one looks at it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main board’s new stock inquiry and pricing mechanism originally had an invisible ceiling of 23 times the price-earnings ratio. After the comprehensive registration system reform was launched, the company&#39;s issuance price was liberalized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, market voices generally believed that companies to be listed with good development prospects would obtain higher valuation levels in the issuance of new shares, and companies with relatively limited development space would see their valuations return quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Former senior sponsor Wang Jiyue told Southern Weekend reporters that after the new IPO policy, the supply of new shares was low and the risk of new shares was expected to be low, so prices went up. Not only the institutional quotations of Zhejiang Guoxiang are high, but the overall quotations of new shares are also high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are some irresponsible quotations.” Wang Jiyue analyzed that the reason why institutions quoted high prices was because they expected that the stock price would not break within a few days after listing. Loss is a small probability event and does not affect the interests of fund managers. , the quotation is not binding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Institutional quotations have become based on transaction expectations, rather than based on the company’s true value.” In his view, the meaning of the existence of institutional investors is to guide correct quotations. &quot;The power to set the issue price is in the hands of institutions, and there are not many practical constraints on institutional quotations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Institutional investors who participated in the inquiry also attributed the motivation for high-priced new products to &quot;making money from new products in the near future.&quot; Private equity fund Shiva Mavericks has 6 products quoted at 73.65 yuan, which were shortlisted for Zhejiang Guoxiang’s effective quotes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Hong, the manager of Shiva Mavericks Fund who is known as the &quot;Ten Billion Private Equity Boss&quot;, responded to the quotation in Xueqiu and said, &quot;Monguli will have obvious profit-making effects in the future, and it will sell on the first day of trading.&quot; The average profit is 80%, so the main purpose is to seek finalists for quotations, and don’t care about the price. If you lose money after a few losses, then you have to be selective and quote a lower price.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liang Hong’s view, the problem lies in the high-priced IPOs, rather than in recruiting new ones. &quot;Some people say that this or that company is not worth the money, so why should they pay a high price? I want to know even more, why do they take over the market at a high price after there is so much money after listing? If not, why should I call you?&quot; At present, Liang Hong is Messages have been deleted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after the new shares are listed, who will take over? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xueqiu user &quot;Xiaye Guapeng&quot; cleverly discovered that for stocks listed at the end of each quarter, through the top ten circulating shareholders disclosed by them, we can know what the new shares will be after 5 trading days. Which funds are taking over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no limit on the price of new shares in the first five trading days, and they are subject to special regulatory attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this logic, he analyzed 9 stocks that were listed at the end of each quarter in 2022 and 2023, and found that securities companies, which are strongly related to the issuance of new shares, will use their own funds to make large-scale purchases a few days after listing. Buy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如在2023年6月21日上市的致欧科技(301376.SZ)和国科军工（688543.SH），在中报披露的十大流通股东均包含券商中金公司、中信证券、华泰证券、国泰君安证券和招商证券，且它们均为新进股东。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Jiyue’s view, high-priced innovation by institutions is not a single issue. &quot;New stock pricing rules, new stock supply and demand, stock circulation ratio, and behavioral finance under the tradition of new stock speculation all need to be taken into consideration.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hundreds of millions of underwriting fees are suspended&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Stock investors also have doubts about Orient Securities (600958.SH), the sponsor of Zhejiang Guoxiang, and believe that Orient Securities has not been diligent and responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Orient Securities’ sponsorship fee for undertaking Zhejiang Guoxiang’s IPO this time is 2 million yuan. In addition, Orient Securities is also the underwriter, and underwriting fees are charged based on a certain proportion of the total funds raised. This is the more important income of Orient Securities in this IPO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus shows that the underwriting fees charged by Orient Securities vary according to the total amount of funds raised, and the rate ratio fluctuates in three levels: 7.50%, 7.70%, and 8.70%, and different fixed fees are also attached. cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Zhejiang Guoxiang’s total fund-raising of 2.384 billion yuan, Orient Securities can receive over 184 million yuan in underwriting fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the total revenue of Orient Securities’ investment banking business was 741.5 million yuan. Zhejiang Guoxiang’s underwriting fee of nearly 200 million yuan is of great significance to its performance in the second half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, Orient Securities issued an announcement on the investment banking project, stating that the underwriting rate for the Zhejiang Guoxiang issuance was 7.74% as determined through negotiation between the sponsor and the issuer. However, the specific calculation method was not disclosed. Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s issuance has been suspended, and Orient Securities has not yet collected underwriting fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus, the company also has indirect equity relationships with Orient Securities and its affiliates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Orient Securities Hande holds 2.74% of the total pre-issuance share capital of Zhejiang Guoxiang, while Shanghai Orient Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Orient Securities, invested 11.11% in Orient Securities Hande. In other words, Orient Securities indirectly holds 0.03% of the shares of Zhejiang Guoxiang before its listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s controlling shareholder Guoxiang Holdings holds 16.34%, 14.71%, 4.44% and 12.51% of the capital contributions of Orient Securities Zhoude, Orient Securities Tangde, Orient Securities Xia De, and Orient Securities Hechuang respectively. share. Shanghai Orient Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Orient Securities, holds 15.03%, 19.12%, 18.89% and 19.99% of the investment shares of these four companies respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned five companies named &quot;Orient Securities&quot; are all investment institutions mainly funded by Shanghai Oriental Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd. and serving as executive partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oriental Securities has been investigated by the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 15, 2016, two penalty decisions issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission disclosed the entire process of creating the &quot;demon stock&quot; of Anshuo Information (300380.SZ), which Oriental Securities was mainly involved in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 30, 2014, a then computer industry researcher from Orient Securities sent an email to the chairman and general manager of Anshuo Information, saying that the stock price of Anshuo Information had fallen to near the issue price and that the value was absolutely underestimated. , expressed the hope to communicate with the company and then recommend it to the organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From June 22, 2014 to April 30, 2015, the then chief analyst of the computer industry at Orient Securities and the above-mentioned researcher used &quot;extremely business scalable, strongly optimistic, and the best quality banking IT&quot; We wrote emails with inductive and exaggerated words such as &quot;Target, Unparalleled, Absolutely Leading&quot;, and sent a total of more than 11,000 emails to 1,279 people in 128 funds, securities firms, private equity and other institutions, disseminating iShares information to carry out Internet financial services and the Internet. financial business situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some fund management companies bought a large amount of iShares Information from November 1, 2014 to May 27, 2015. At the peak, a total of 221 public funds held more than 70% of iShares Information. outstanding shares. Anshuo Information&#39;s stock price rose from 28.30 yuan/share on April 30, 2014 to 450 yuan/share on May 13, 2015, an increase of 15.9 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the China Securities Regulatory Commission opened the case for investigation, the above two employees of Orient Securities were ordered to make corrections and were given administrative penalties of 200,000 yuan and 150,000 yuan respectively, and a warning was given to Anshuo Information and the company’s chairman and secretary. , and were fined 600,000 yuan, 300,000 yuan and 200,000 yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[147万名“塔尖”客户金融资产21万亿，“最耀眼明珠”撑起银行逆周期重任]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258401]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the existing mortgage interest rates were reduced in batches&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;Almost all deposit and loan business interest rate spreads fell&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;historical lows&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;very cyclical businesses Do banks still have countercyclical sectors?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The latest &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mid-year reports disclosed by various commercial banks revealed an unusual information&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Researcher from Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Taked relevant data of 12 major banks as a sample, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; combined with research reports from professional consulting institutions&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;from &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;People&#39;s Bank of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Hereinafter referred to as &quot;private bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Number of clients and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;structure&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Assets per capita&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The development status and influencing factors of private banks were &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sorted out, compared and analyzed from dimensions such as /span>;&lt;span>;, private bank asset management scale and other dimensions. It was found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>; overwhelmingly The retail assets under management (AUM) of most commercial banks have performed well. The private banking business, considered &quot;the brightest jewel in the &lt;span>;crown of the financial industry&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, has bucked the trend and has grown well. Become a strong anti-cyclical sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Statistical analysis also found&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, 147&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ten thousand&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;names&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;Private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Customers have 21 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; assets, average assets per household&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The amount reached 1477.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; million&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The overall private travel customer base&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Tend to be younger&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But domestic private banking services are still in their infancy&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Financial asset allocation and non-financial services are far away from the international mature system&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The strong will always be strong&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Five banks&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;private bank AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;all Over&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The number of customers and the scale of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are undoubtedly the two most direct indicators for observing the business conditions of private banks. Data from 12 listed banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mid-year reports&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; show that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; commercial banks The number of private clients and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; growth rates are both positive&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, and the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;growth rates are the lowest&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; 3.76%,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And there are four banks with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; double-digit growth&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;There are three banks with double-digit growth in customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The head effect is becoming more obvious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As of the end of June, China Merchants Bank &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China and China Construction Bank &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; four &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The assets under management (AUM) of major state-owned private banks all exceeded 2 trillion yuan, an increase of 5.89 from the end of the previous year&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;-&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12.90%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank, which has the reputation of &quot;King of Retail&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This indicator&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;high&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; achieved 4.02 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, becoming the only one&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;among the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; banks mentioned above&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Private Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank with AUM exceeding 4 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank Private Bank’s average financial assets per account Up to &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2804.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;10,000&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;almost twice as much as &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The average household value is 14.7799 million yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of the number of private banking customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the above five&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has more than 100,000 customers, accounting for 69.18% of the total private banking customers of the 12 listed banks. Among them, the number of private customers of ICBC, China Construction Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Agricultural Bank of China &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; exceeds 200,000, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Its&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;number of customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; increased by 15.9%, 10.12% and 13.50% respectively&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Much higher than the growth rate of other businesses&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Except&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the above five&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;head banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;In addition, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ping An Bank, which has been aiming to create a new benchmark for &quot;light banking&quot; in recent years, has also demonstrated its ambition to focus on the private banking field. Data show that as of the end of June, Ping An Bank&#39;s private banking AUM reached 189 million yuan, an increase of 16.3% from the end of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The growth rate ranks first among the 12 banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The ratio of private bank AUM to the bank&#39;s retail AUM is as high as 49%. Ranked first among the 12 listed banks;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;its private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; average AUM per account was 21.7922 million yuan, second only to China Merchants Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Based on the two indicators&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;number of private clients and asset size&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, 12 listed banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;&#39;s&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1.47 million&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banking&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; customers, with 21 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; assets , the average household assets reached 1477.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6ecKSHFsvknF6pHq1kj6Gr2jodvJ5CWaPGNbbuyv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1713&quot; height=&quot;2008&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6ecKSHFsvknF6pHq1kj6Gr2jodvJ5CWaPGNbbuyv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253793&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/V13FS5vCfSfCefOeMt6iyydR3UHrpnmyjhFweujC.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1713&quot; height=&quot;1594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/V13FS5vCfSfCefOeMt6iyydR3UHrpnmyjhFweujC.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253792&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private banking clients are getting younger&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The wealth creation effect of the new economy is obvious&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why the number of private clients and asset size buck the trend Growth&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The huge customer base&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is an important condition for the rapid development of the private banking business of the above banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the year, the &quot;China Banking Industry Private Client Management White Paper 2023&quot; released by the Boston Consulting Group and other institutions mentioned &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt; span>;, in order to bring about the same increase in asset management scale, the bank&#39;s cost of acquiring new customers is five times higher than maintaining old customers, while the profit contribution of existing customers is 16 times that of new customers. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In other words&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, under the same target number, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; compared with &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; other small and medium-sized banks, state-owned banks have more retail customers. The customer acquisition costs required to develop private banking business are relatively small. This can also confirm the principle of the pyramid model commonly used in the field of customer management: that is, a large base of ordinary customers can lay a solid foundation for the cultivation of high-end customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center&#39;s review&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The mid-year report also confirmed this again&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As of the end of June, the corresponding value of the total retail AUM of the four major state-owned banks in industry, agriculture, China and construction &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; was 14 trillion&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;-&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;20 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;; although China Merchants Bank is a joint-stock bank, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;because&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;With many years of deep business strategy in retail business, the bank’s total retail AUM reached 12.84 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; during the same period, far exceeding other joint-stock banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/iM3Il9BtplHUzjyUOxEHr5lEdbP85EkCnXq8tC5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/iM3Il9BtplHUzjyUOxEHr5lEdbP85EkCnXq8tC5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253750&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Researchers at the Financial Research Center also &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; learned &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; among the above-mentioned 12 listed banks, only China Merchants Bank The threshold &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is determined as &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; “the monthly and daily average fully discounted RMB total assets are 10 million yuan and above” standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The threshold for other banks is mostly &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;600&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ten thousand yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;However, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the setting of high threshold &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; does not allow China Merchants Bank to operate privately &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Business development brings resistance. Data from the same period show that compared with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;end&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, China Merchants Bank’s AUM and customers The quantity achieved an increase of 5.89% and 6.21%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9JuMgJLu06PflealulQuK9pb6OLMFVecN1H4EeRT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9JuMgJLu06PflealulQuK9pb6OLMFVecN1H4EeRT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;More interesting Yes&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the midst of economic transformation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the composition of private banking customers has also changed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Change. China Merchants Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Bain &amp; Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; recently&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; released the &quot;2023 China Private Wealth Report&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;It shows that compared with 2021, in 2023, the proportion of the first generation of wealth creators, directors, supervisors and second generation of the family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the total number of private banking customers surveyed was respectively 25%, 16% and 12% dropped to 20%, 14% and 9%. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the proportion of professional people increased from 12% to 17%. Among them, among the two categories of wealth creation generation &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;directors, supervisors and senior management, private banking groups engaged in the new economy accounted for 7% of the total number of private banking customers surveyed&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This reflects the wealth creation effect associated with the rise of the new domestic economy. At the same time, the proportion of people under the age of 40 who engage in private practice has increased from 42% in 2021 to 49%, and the high-net-worth population has become further younger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center surveyed several large regional private banking branches and found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private customers value Preservation and inheritance of financial assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; rather than appreciation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Because they believe that corporate operations have higher risks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial assets in private names must be safe&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The above-mentioned report research &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has supported this &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Only&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; accounts for 12%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Among them&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;36% of the people said that “the income is higher than the savings income”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private banking&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Light capital&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Help&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Banks through the cycle&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Private&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;Business&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Why do business firms flock to it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Private banking business is basically an off-balance sheet business for banks, and it takes up little capital&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is a capital-light business&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. In recent years, when facing problems such as shrinking net interest margins and non-performing assets, the capital-heavy development model driven by the scale of the banking industry has come under pressure. Private banking business is expected to become a new engine for banks&#39; own profit growth and business model transformation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Finance&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Research&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Researcher at the Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Combining&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The 2023 &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mid-year reports of the above-mentioned 12 banks found that ICBC spent a small amount of space describing the profit data of private banks. Data show that as of June 30, the bank&#39;s &quot;Personal Financial Management and Private Banking&quot; category achieved fee and commission income of 14.019 billion yuan, accounting for 17.02% of the bank&#39;s total fee and commission income, ranking second only to &quot; Settlement, clearing and cash management&quot; ranked second. Since this income also involves personal finance items including ordinary customers, it is impossible to make precise statistics on the income of private banking business. The proportion of private banking AUM in retail business AUM in the table below may be evidence of its contribution to the retail business field. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NFNcXkXomvnztAF5ykpJUJPyF5S0fxsfxP20UDBd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NFNcXkXomvnztAF5ykpJUJPyF5S0fxsfxP20UDBd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Researchers at the Financial Research Center believe that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in terms of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; business categories, private banking business is related to asset management, retail &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Investment banking and many other businesses. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The establishment of a private banking system has strong extendibility for the operation and management of high-net-worth customers. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As a top retail brand, private banking has a prominent brand spillover effect, which is very important for bank retail business. The advancement will also be of great help. In addition, most of the private banking clients are entrepreneurs, who have diversified needs for investment banking and corporate business. By leading the private sector to the corporate sector, it can also have a strong linkage effect on the investment banking and corporate business lines. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yMbrIwXun5ui95CTO0MULgNQdfEVd7kptfYGJg9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1256&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yMbrIwXun5ui95CTO0MULgNQdfEVd7kptfYGJg9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From&lt;/ span>;&lt;span>;On the liability side, private bank customers can accumulate a larger proportion of demand deposits and reduce deposit cost rates. On the one hand, high-net-worth customers have greater daily liquidity needs and tend to reserve a certain proportion of demand deposits to meet daily capital needs. On the other hand, high-net-worth customers are important buyers of bank wealth management products and asset management products. Before the establishment of wealth management products, customers&#39; prepaid funds are included in current deposits. Banks can flexibly arrange the issuance period and duration of wealth management products to achieve the purpose of depositing a large number of current deposits and reducing bank liability costs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared financial report data and found that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; years&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ago In 6 months, the deposit interest rate cost of China Merchants Bank&#39;s retail customers was only 1.36%, which is not only far lower than the 2%-2.4% range standard of joint-stock banks of the same size, but even lower than The level of state-owned banks is around 1.7%. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This proves&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that when private banking business develops to a certain scale, it will have a positive effect on reducing bank deposit costs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/C8wIZtTf1G95F9pNss8iDxG1mQ6cxWOozLJemKrw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/C8wIZtTf1G95F9pNss8iDxG1mQ6cxWOozLJemKrw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Instruments such as family trusts&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;are mainstream&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Based on the special contributions and demands of private banking clients&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;What financial instruments have commercial banks reserved and innovated for private banking customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that as one of the tools in private bank asset allocation pools, family trusts with inheritance and bankruptcy isolation functions are being widely used. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Five major state-owned banks such as Industry, Agriculture, China, Construction, and Communications&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank, Ping An Bank, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Joint-stock banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are all in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Interim Report&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; for&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The business growth data of the family trust is described. As of the end of June, the cumulative paid-in scale of ICBC Family Trust was 29.18 billion yuan, an increase of 40% from the end of the previous year; the scale of paid-in funds of China Construction Bank was 95.074 billion yuan, an increase of 6.82% from the end of the previous year; the number of Bank of China Family Trust customers increased by 52.5% from the end of the previous year. The scale of Agricultural Bank of China’s family trust business is nearly 80 billion yuan, a net increase of 32 billion yuan from the end of the previous year; the scale of Ping An Bank’s family trust and insurance trust business is 44.086 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 39.3%; the number of family trust business orders of China Merchants Bank exceeds 10,000, and the business scale An increase of 22.79% compared with the end of the previous year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Insurance trusts have leverage and inheritance functions&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; have also become popular configurations in the past two years&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private firms&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;employees&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; members of the South A researcher at the New Financial Research Center on the Weekend said that due to limited business scope, banks currently establish trusts for private banking customers through cooperation with external trust companies. But for investors, entrusting their personal property through a bank is equivalent to psychologically receiving the bank&#39;s brand endorsement&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the past two years, the number of bank private banking customers and asset size have continued to grow, including the growth of wealth such as family trusts, which shows that in the face of an uncertain environment, high-net-worth individuals are still willing to invest in Wealth is held in the banking system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;2023 China Private Wealth Report&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mentioned that as the &quot;first rich&quot; group,&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Private banking clients&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s comprehensive needs have expanded from focusing on individuals, families, and businesses to the fields of social responsibility, public welfare, and charity. They look forward to better charity projects, charitable foundations, charitable trusts, etc. Architectural design services. The survey shows that 73% of high-net-worth individuals have started or are preparing for wealth inheritance. In terms of intergenerational inheritance, the current first-choice method for high-net-worth individuals is to pass on wealth to their children. The purchase of insurance and real estate is expected to be expanded in the future, including the creation of family trusts and corporate equity arrangements. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private practice&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Still &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;at the junior level Stage&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Benchmarking international private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;What is the level of private banks that are increasingly valued in China&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the financial &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; regulatory authorities first proposed the concept of private banking in 2005, China’s private banking industry has gone through more than ten years&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Process&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the past ten years or so&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; many domestic commercial banks have opened related businesses, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The scale of assets has grown rapidly. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the meantime&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Although many banks have set up their private banking business separately as a business unit system&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;National vertical management&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;but after the separation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; returned to the large retail system&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;have the potential to accelerate&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If we take the mature private banking systems of developed European countries as a reference, domestic private banks are still in their infancy in terms of wealth management coverage and customer service levels. This may be one of the reasons why many domestic banks still put private banking business into the large retail framework and do not conduct separate accounting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for the development of domestic private banking business, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that we can start from the following three aspects&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First, strengthen investment research and professional product design capabilities, and enrich the product system. Continue to track customer needs and market changes, and promptly adjust asset allocation strategies and product structures. Improve the level of asset allocation in major categories, achieve regional diversification and asset class diversification through overseas diversified asset allocation, and help investors ensure investment returns and asset value preservation and appreciation;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;The second is to use technology to help build a digital private bank. With the rapid development of technology, the integration of financial technology and wealth management continues to deepen, and its application chain will gradually penetrate from the client side to product development, investment portfolio, valuation management and other product-side links. With the help of financial technology, we provide investment advisors with investment advice, conduct operational warnings, track customer investment progress, and greatly improve the efficiency of private banking services and customer experience;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The third is to attach importance to non-financial businesses . &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Different from traditional wealth management business, the business scope of private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; includes financial services and non-financial businesses, among which non-financial businesses involve very Extensive, including investment consulting, tax planning, daily consumption, medical health, tourism, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the international &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mature private banking system, consulting management fees generated in the non-financial field are expected to account for 45% of the overall income&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Domestic private banks can use this as a starting point, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;link to various professional institutions&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;create more&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Profit&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>