<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[醉驾女子反诬交警“猥亵”：如此虚假指控，“灵感”从何而来？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260647]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, in Huangshi, Hubei, a drunk woman rear-ended the car in front of the traffic police, and the police prepared to drink her. During the test, the woman actually said she wanted to report it to the traffic police for &quot;obscenity.&quot; Finally, the police forcefully took the woman to the hospital to collect a blood sample. The test results showed that the alcohol content in her blood was 207.75mg/100ml, which met the standard for drunk driving. The case is currently under further processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the video of the scene, the woman involved rear-ended her car. The traffic police on duty saw that the woman&#39;s face was &quot;red&quot; and asked her to get out of the car and take an alcohol test. The woman involved responded, &quot;I don&#39;t blush when I drink.&quot; The traffic police required the woman to take a breath test as part of their normal law enforcement, but the response she received was &quot;I&#39;m going to sue you for obscenity.&quot; When the traffic police said, &quot;As a citizen (you need to cooperate with law enforcement),&quot; the woman involved simply said, &quot;I&#39;m not a citizen, so I won&#39;t brag.&quot; Then she had to rely on enforcement to complete the blood sample test. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The facts of this case are not complicated, and the basic facts are as clear as water. But there are still many points worthy of in-depth discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, judging from the facts of this case, in addition to being suspected of dangerous driving, the woman involved is also suspected of other illegal and criminal acts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The alcohol content in the blood of the woman involved has exceeded the standard of 80mg/100ml, which is considered drunk driving. Her behavior violated both the &quot;Road Traffic Safety Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. According to Article 91 of the Road Traffic Safety Law, anyone who drives a motor vehicle drunk will be restrained by the traffic management department of the public security organ until he sobers up, his motor vehicle driving license will be revoked, and he will be investigated for criminal responsibility in accordance with the law; he will not be able to obtain a new motor vehicle driving license within five years; and according to the Criminal Law Article 133: Anyone who drives a motor vehicle drunk on the road shall be sentenced to criminal detention and shall also be fined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the woman involved was only driving drunk and rear-ended the car, her punishment may be limited to the revocation of her driver&#39;s license, detention and fines, and she would also be compensated for the loss of the owner of the car in front of her. The problem is that other behaviors of the woman involved at the scene are also suspected of illegal crimes. Her sentence &quot;I will sue you for obscenity&quot; is a public accusation against an individual in a public place, so she must be held accountable for the truth of the accusation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video clearly shows that the traffic police on duty were enforcing the law normally. They reasonably suspected that the owner of the rear-ended car was suspected of drunk driving and required him to undergo an alcohol test. They were completely performing their official duties. According to the &quot;Operational Procedures for Investigating and Dealing with Drunk Driving&quot; attached to the &quot;Traffic Police Road Duty Law Enforcement Work Standards&quot;, the traffic police on duty have the right to &quot;require motor vehicle drivers suspected of drunk driving to get out of the vehicle and undergo an alcohol test.&quot; Therefore, the public accusations made by the woman involved are outright false accusations, and she should bear corresponding legal responsibility. At a small scale, this is slander and slander, at a larger scale, it is even false accusation and frame-up, because the woman involved also said, &quot;I want to sue you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 42 of the &quot;Public Security Administration Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;those who openly insult others or fabricate facts to slander others&quot; &quot;fabricate facts and frame others in an attempt to subject others to criminal prosecution or public security &quot;Management of punishment&quot; is an illegal act and shall be punished with detention and a fine. Article 243 of the Criminal Law also stipulates that fabricating facts to frame others with the intention of subjecting others to criminal prosecution constitutes the crime of false accusation and frame-up. If the circumstances are serious, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or surveillance; if serious consequences are caused, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years and not more than ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the social phenomenon behind this case is even more worrying, that is, some people use their specific identities and speech skills to bypass clear rules and seek privileges for themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman in question reflexively &quot;sue you for obscenity&quot;, which shows that similar thinking has been deeply rooted in her bones, that is, she uses false accusations to carry out threats and circumvents clear rules to seek the privilege of impunity for herself. The &quot;inspiration&quot; brought by &quot;false accusations of sexual assault&quot;, &quot;false accusations of rape&quot; and &quot;Internet essays&quot; in reality may have long been internalized into the thinking of the parties concerned. The stereotype behind this kind of thinking is enough to make people feel chilling: as long as the matter is settled first If you &quot;make a big fuss&quot; and accuse the other party, you can extort money if you go forward, and you can get away with it if you back off. And even if the words fail, there will be no punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more worrying is that if there is no video evidence in this case, can the woman involved insist that the traffic police molested her and then counter-sue the traffic police on duty? Can the woman in question use this to blackmail the traffic police on duty and gain the advantage of getting out of jail for herself? It seems that as long as I make such a fuss, others and even public power will &quot;give way to me&quot;. This is a trample on justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, what is even more serious is that the woman involved made false accusations against state public officials, which is a blatant challenge to the law enforcement authority of the police. According to Article 8 of the &quot;Regulations on Safeguarding the Authority of Civil Police Law Enforcement by Public Security Organs&quot;, in the process of performing their duties and exercising their powers in accordance with the law, or because of the performance of their duties and powers in accordance with the law, police officers encounter &quot;threats, intimidation, insults, slander, or threats to themselves and their close relatives, In cases of &quot;harassment&quot;, the public security organs should actively safeguard the law enforcement authority of the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if the woman involved is not dealt with seriously and her other illegal and criminal acts other than dangerous driving are investigated, it will inevitably bring negative incentives to similar behaviors and stimulate more lawless people to follow the same pattern, and even Continuing to carry out false accusations and creating obstacles for the normal law enforcement of the police is definitely not a blessing to the public interest. This case is still under investigation and the police on duty should be treated fairly to deter those who try to follow suit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[浙江慈溪首富惹麻烦：原高管未能兑现股权激励，举报上市公司危废风险]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260676]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;August 30, 2023, Shanghai International Power Components and Renewable Energy Management Exhibition Held at the New International Exhibition Center in Pudong, Hesheng Silicon has a booth. Visual China/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/46bff09a8d.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/46bff09a8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258419&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 30, 2023, the Shanghai International Power Components and Renewable Energy Management Exhibition was held at the Pudong New International Exhibition Center, Hesheng Silicon Industry Equipped with exhibition stand. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A report letter made the silicon giant with a market value of over 60 billion become a hot topic of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>; On November 12, 2023, the wife of Fang Hongcheng, the former general manager of Hesheng Silicon Industry (603260.SH), verified her identity through the Internet Report: Luo Liguo, chairman of Hoshine Silicon Industry, &lt;span>;coerced the Jiaxing City Government of Zhejiang Province to intervene in the judiciary&lt;/span>; and imprisoned Fang Hongchengguo on the grounds of relocating a listed company. &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Hongcheng joined Hesheng Silicon Industry in 2009 and served as the general manager of the company since April 2011. He resigned in December 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;His wife said that after Fang Hongcheng&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;resigned&lt;/span>;, Luo Liguo refused to fulfill the equity agreement &lt;span>; between the two parties and put pressure on the Jiaxing municipal government, which led to Fang Hongcheng&#39;s resignation. He and his brother Fang Hongxing were arrested and detained for 17 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early the next morning, Hoshine Silicon issued a clarification announcement, disclosing that Fang Hongcheng’s case of bribery and job embezzlement by non-state staff would be heard at the Pinghu People’s Court on the same day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company’s official website shows that Hesheng Silicon Industry was invested and established by Ningbo Hesheng Group in 2005 and listed on the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange in 2017. It is the most complete silicon-based full industry chain company in the world and the only one in the industry that also has industrial silicon. It is a high-tech enterprise with production capacity of , organic silicon, polycrystalline silicon, photovoltaic modules, etc. It has production bases in Zhejiang, Xinjiang, Yunnan, Sichuan, Heilongjiang and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hopson Silicon Industry’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that the Luo Liguo family is the actual controller of Hopeson Silicon Industry. Luo Liguo and his children collectively hold approximately 78.59% of the equity of the listed company. According to the 2023 Hurun Rich List, the Luo Liguo family ranks 66th with a wealth of 60 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who spoke out on behalf of Fang Hongcheng was his cousin Tong Jianpeng. He told Southern Weekend reporters that Fang Hongcheng’s case did not open as scheduled on November 13, but instead held a full-day pre-trial conference. November 14 is still a pre-trial conference, and the court date is still uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 14th and 15th, Fang Hongcheng’s family filed applications for off-site jurisdiction with the Jiaxing Intermediate People’s Court and the Zhejiang Provincial Higher People’s Court respectively, hoping to transfer the case to a people’s court outside Jiaxing for trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What happened behind this real-name reporting controversy? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The equity lawsuit interrupted by the criminal case&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The conflict between Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo stems from two equity disputes in recent years. Fang Hongcheng received partial support in the first instance of the case. Southern Weekend reporters obtained relevant referee documents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2015, Fang Hongcheng signed an &quot;Equity Incentive Agreement&quot; with Hesheng Silicon and its employee stockholding platform Ningbo Yingrong Enterprise Management Consulting Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Ningbo Yingrong), stipulating that Fang Hongcheng It acquired 5% of Ningbo Yingrong&#39;s equity at a price of 2.786 million yuan, thus indirectly holding 300,000 shares of Hesheng Silicon Industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, the &quot;Equity Incentive Agreement&quot; also stipulates that Fang Hongcheng needs to continue to serve Hesheng Silicon Industry for 5 years after receiving the equity incentive, and not engage in horizontal competition during this period&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;Do not damage the interests of the company, otherwise you will be held responsible for relevant legal liabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2017, after the company was listed at an issue price of 19.52 yuan/share, it rose all the way to 252.79 yuan/share, and the company’s market value exceeded 260 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Hoshine Silicon Industry’s annual equity distribution decision was to convert 0.4 shares into shares per share. Fang Hongcheng’s shareholding in Hoshine Silicone Industry therefore increased to 420,000 shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December of that year, Fang Hongcheng resigned from Hesheng Silicon Industry. Fang Hongcheng said in a self-report that he started his own business after leaving his job. In 2019, he established Zhejiang Xianglin New Materials Co., Ltd. and Zhejiang Yingke New Materials Co., Ltd., which are controlled by him and have no competitive relationship with Hesheng Silicon Industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 30, 2021, Fang Hongcheng sued Ningbo Yingrong, with Hesheng Silicon as the third party. Fang said that the lock-up period for its shareholding has expired, and requested that the proceeds from the realization of incentive equity be paid in accordance with the agreement, and the unpaid annual dividends from 2018 to 2020 should be made up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The People&#39;s Court of Pinghu City, Zhejiang Province found in the first instance that the above-mentioned three parties also signed a &quot;Supplementary Agreement&quot; in 2018, clarifying that Fang Hongcheng agreed to reduce its shareholding by 25% to pay taxes and other fees. . Including the dividend shares distributed in 2018, Fang Hongcheng holds a total of 315,000 shares of Halcyon Silicon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Pinghu Court held that the non-competition clause was not a condition for obtaining incentive equity, but an obligation after obtaining the equity. The plaintiff Fang Hongcheng should bear legal liability for failing to fulfill the corresponding obligations, rather than losing the incentive equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On March 28, 2022&lt;/span>;, the Pinghu Court supported part of Fang Hongcheng’s petition in the first instance and ruled that Ningbo Yingrong had sold the 315,000 Hesheng Silicon A shares it held. After deducting transaction costs, it was returned to Fang Hongcheng, and the latter was paid stock dividends of 147,600 yuan. Ningbo Yingrong subsequently appealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the second instance of the Jiaxing Intermediate People’s Court, Fang Hongcheng was subject to criminal compulsory measures on suspicion of official embezzlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiaxing Intermediate People’s Court believes that Fang Hongcheng’s prosecution should be dismissed and the relevant materials should be transferred to the public security organs. If the public security organs determine that the case is indeed a civil dispute after review, Fang Hongcheng can assert separate rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2022, the Jiaxing Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the first-instance judgment of the Pinghu Court and reject Fang Hongcheng’s prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Illegal agency holding&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another equity dispute occurred directly between Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 1, 2017, Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo signed an &quot;Equity Transfer Agreement&quot;, agreeing to transfer the 1.2611 million shares of Hesheng Silicon held indirectly by the latter (accounting for 0.21% of the total pre-listing share capital). Transferred to Fang Hongcheng at a price of 3.17 yuan/share. Moreover, Fang Hongcheng voluntarily promised to serve Luo Liguo&#39;s actual control company for at least 5 years after signing the agreement, and not to engage in horizontal competition during this period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the two also signed the &quot;Equity Holding Agreement&quot;, with Luo Liguo holding the above shares on behalf of Fang Hong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to materials provided by Fang Hongcheng’s family to Southern Weekend reporters, Hoshine Silicon began listing work in 2011, with Fang Hongcheng serving as the leader of the listing working group. After the Spring Festival of 2017, &lt;span>;either because of Fang Hongcheng’s recognition of his work&lt;/span>; or because he was worried about his job-hopping, Luo Liguo proposed that Fang Hong accept his year-end bonus and transfer a small amount of money in Luo’s name at the price of the company’s net assets. The equity is held by Luo on behalf of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the judgment document, on December 14, 2017, Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo signed a new &quot;&lt;span>;Equity Transfer and Agency Holding Agreement&lt;/span>;&quot;, which agreed that Fang Hongcheng would pay 50 yuan per share. The total price of the 261,100 shares transferred before the transfer was 13.055 million yuan. After this transfer, Fang Hongcheng still indirectly holds 1 million shares of Hesheng Silicon Industry, which is held by Luo Liguo on behalf of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Hong admitted that she indirectly held a total of 1.4 million shares of Hesheng Silicon. Because on the basis of the above-mentioned 1 million shares, it also holds 0.4 shares for each converted share distributed by Hesheng Silicon Industry in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On April 25, 2021&lt;/span>;, Fang Hongcheng applied to the Hangzhou Arbitration Commission for arbitration over this equity transfer dispute, requiring Luo Liguo to sell 1.4 million shares, &lt;span>; and transfer the proceeds and related shares &lt;/span>;The dividends for 2018 and 2019 will be paid to myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Supervision has always been strict on the issue of equity holdings of listed companies&lt;/span>;. The Hangzhou Arbitration Commission cited the Securities Law and the &quot;Administrative Measures for Information Disclosure of Listed Companies&quot; and determined that the agreement between Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo on holding shares on behalf of others was invalid, but other clauses were still valid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hangzhou Arbitration Commission believed that the two parties agreed that Fang Hongcheng would serve Luo Liguo Real Control Company full-time and diligently for at least 5 years starting from January 1, 2017. However, Fang Hongcheng resigned on December 7, 2018 and only performed 40 % of the service period commitment, so you can receive 340,676 shares of Halcyon Silicon and part of the dividends from 2018 to 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 23, 2022, the Hangzhou Arbitration Commission ruled that Luo Liguo reduced and liquidated 340,676 shares of Hesheng Silicon Industry, deducting transaction costs, and paid it to Fang Hongcheng together with a dividend of 376,700 yuan. Luo Liguo also appealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Liguo claimed in the appeal that Fang Hongcheng violated the non-competition agreement by joining Xinyaqiang (603155.SH), a company in the same industry, as deputy general manager and holding 2.81 million shares the same month he resigned from Halcyon Silicon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Hongcheng did try to do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin Yaqiang’s prospectus shows that the company signed a labor contract with Fang Hongcheng on December 20, 2018, agreeing to appoint Fang Hongcheng as the company’s deputy general manager if the conditions for employment are met. This agreement was reviewed and approved at the shareholders&#39; meeting 6 days later. Fang Hongcheng was granted 2.81 million incentive shares and invested with his own funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because Fang Hongcheng failed to provide relevant documents that met the conditions for the appointment of deputy general manager, he voluntarily applied and with the consent of Xinyaqiang, the labor contract between the two parties was terminated on December 30, 2018. Fang Hongcheng voluntarily transferred out of its shares in Xinyaqiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 23, 2022, the Hangzhou Intermediate People’s Court rejected Luo Liguo’s application to revoke the arbitration award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hopson Silicon stated in the clarification announcement that the award is currently in the implementation stage. Luo Liguo has filed an application with the court not to enforce the arbitration award, which is still pending in the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Hongcheng received partial support in the above two disputes. Based on Hesheng Silicon’s stock price at the time, Fang Hongcheng could make a maximum profit of more than 81 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bringing out hidden dangers in hazardous waste treatment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2022, Hesheng Silicon Industry announced that the company’s former director and general manager Fang Hongcheng had been investigated and terminated by the public security agency for suspected job embezzlement. Transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution, the criminal conduct involved occurred during his tenure at the company. The case was discovered by the company&#39;s internal self-examination and reported to the public security organs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident brings out the hidden dangers of hazardous waste disposal in Hesheng Silicon Industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant research papers, in the production of silicone, a mixture of by-products with a boiling point lower than 40°C is called low boilers, most of which are tetramethylsilane and dimethylsilane. Chlorosilane, trichlorosilane, methyl chloride, etc. The boiling points of low-boiling components are very close, so it is difficult to separate and utilize them. These compounds are flammable and explosive. Among them, tetramethylsilane is included in the national &quot;List of Hazardous Chemicals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hopson Silicon Industry’s prospectus and 2023 semi-annual report both disclosed that low-boiling by-products are the company’s main solid waste and are strictly implemented for external sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fang Hongcheng’s self-report and the materials provided by his family members, in 2011, Hesheng Silicon was in trouble both internally and externally, and was in urgent need of technological transformation and cost reduction. Since the technical transformation of hazardous chemicals production involves government approval, Luo Liguo decided to proceed quickly with all new construction and reconstruction projects, competing with policies to race against time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Hongcheng listed 8 illegal new construction and reconstruction projects at that time, all of which failed to go through relevant approval procedures such as safety assessment and environmental assessment as required. The direct economic benefits of most projects were 10 million yuan/year. above. One of the projects is to relatively safely dispose of low-boiling substances classified as hazardous waste in a closed system and turn them into relatively stable &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above materials stated that &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; is the name of Hesheng Silicon Industry. It is a less corrosive, complex, flammable and explosive oily dangerous chemical converted into a low-boiling substance and water through the reaction. Taste. Hesheng Silicon still needs to dispose of the &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; in a timely manner, otherwise it will cause the company to stop production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This job fell to Fang Hongcheng&#39;s younger brother Fang Hongxing. &quot;Fang Hongxing risked violations of laws and regulations, safety and environmental risks, and cooperated with others to dispose and utilize &#39;hydrolysis oil&#39; and obtain profits.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In April 2019, Fang Hongcheng established Zhejiang Xianglin New Materials Co., Ltd., an asset-light company that produces special silicone coatings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The above materials show that the following month, Hesheng Silicon accused Fang Hongcheng of &quot;breach of trust and damage&quot; on the grounds that Luo Liguo was unaware of the matter and Fang Hongcheng built it without authorization. &quot;interests of listed companies&quot; and reported the case to the Jiaxing Port District Public Security Bureau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Fang Hongcheng filed lawsuits and arbitrations regarding two equity disputes, in August 2021, Hesheng Silicon reported the case to the Hong Kong Public Security Bureau for the second time on suspicion of Fang Hongcheng being a non-state employee taking bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report letter from Fang Hongcheng’s family attached a decision to cancel the case made by the Hong Kong Public Security Bureau on December 31, 2021, stating that there were no criminal facts in Fang Hongcheng’s suspected bribery case by non-state staff and the case was cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Fang Hongcheng and Luo Liguo have argued several times over the disposal of &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; in the equity dispute litigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Liguo used a set of sales contracts and evaluation reports as evidence, accusing Fang Hongcheng of &quot;selling cheaply&quot; &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; with an estimated price of more than 10,000 yuan per ton during his tenure, at a price of less than 2,000 yuan/ton. Seeking huge benefits for its affiliated companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fang Hongcheng used email exchanges and statements as evidence that his production and sales of &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; were only in compliance with the decisions of Luo Liguo and other company executives, and were not an act of personal gain. Moreover, the production and sales activities of &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; are illegal and non-compliant, and will not bring any legitimate benefits to Hesheng Silicon Industry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the court focused on the equity dispute between the two and did not make a ruling on the &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The company will no longer relocate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, Fang Hongcheng was placed on file by the Hong Kong Public Security Bureau. In his self-report, he stated that the Fang Hongcheng brothers were summoned on June 13 and placed under &quot;residential surveillance&quot; in a designated residence the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fang Hongcheng and his family believe that the change of events was due to Luo Liguo blackmailing the Jiaxing Municipal Government on the pretext of moving the listed company from Jiaxing City to Cixi, a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Ningbo City. To. According to relevant articles from relevant departments of the Jiaxing Municipal Party Committee in 2018, Hesheng Silicon Industry is the first listed company cultivated by Jiaxing Port Zone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hopson Silicon stated in the clarification announcement that the company’s registered address is in Jiaxing, but the Jiaxing production base is mainly chemical production facilities and the office conditions are limited, so it will announce the office address in January 2022 Changed to Cixi, Ningbo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Ningbo Evening News&quot;, Luo Liguo was born in Changhe Town, Cixi, the &quot;hometown of straw hats&quot;. He started his business by opening a straw hat factory and is known as the richest man in Cixi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the clarification announcement, in order to unify the office address and registered address, the company held the 12th meeting of the third board of directors and planned to change the company&#39;s address to Cixi. Later, in order to maintain relevant qualification registration, the company terminated the change of company address and canceled the shareholders&#39; meeting to review the matter. These two events were announced on May 28 and June 8, 2022 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In May 2023&lt;/span>;, Fang Hongcheng’s family reported to Jiaxing Port Area Emergency Management Bureau, Jiaxing Municipal Emergency Management Bureau and Sichuan Provincial Emergency Management Department that Hesheng Silicon Industry illegally constructed a low-boiling hydrolysis device , issues surrounding the illegal sale of hazardous chemicals, received mixed responses&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the complaint letter, the Jiaxing Port Area Emergency Management Bureau responded three times stating that no hydrolysis device was found on site, that low-boiling substances could be sold as by-products, and that &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; was not hazardous. Product Catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Sichuan Provincial Department of Emergency Management stated that &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; is a hazardous chemical and is not within the scope of the safety production license of Hesheng Silicon Industry (Luzhou) Co., Ltd., and has ordered the company to suspend the use of &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; &quot;Hydrolysis oil&quot; production equipment, and investigate the company&#39;s suspected production safety violations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hopson Silicone clarified the situation of &quot;hydrolysis oil&quot; and stated that the &quot;Hazardous Chemicals Registration Varieties&quot; handled by its Jiaxing subsidiary Hoshine Silicone (Jiaxing) Co., Ltd. includes low-boiling oil (i.e. &quot; hydrolyzed oil&quot;). The &quot;Hazardous Chemicals Registration Varieties&quot; that its Luzhou subsidiary Hesheng Silicon Industry (Luzhou) Co., Ltd. has handled also includes hydrogenated silicone oil S. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Qichacha, Hesheng Silicon Industry (Jiaxing) Co., Ltd. was established on June 29, 2020. This means that Halcyon Silicon did not respond to how Fang Hongcheng handled low-boiling materials during his tenure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[文物保护的困境与探索]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260664]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Recently, a thousand-year-old cliff statue monument located in Nanjiang County, Sichuan Province was found to be painted with &quot;makeup&quot;, and netizens called it &quot;disfigured&quot; &quot;. There have been many incidents of man-made destruction of cultural relics this year. How can we ensure that cultural relics are preserved for a long time without being damaged? Cultural conservation workers are constantly exploring.</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:56:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话人类学家项飙：怎么去面对已知无解的问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Xiang Biao sat among a group of young people in Guangzhou, laughing with everyone, occasionally frowning and speaking, More often than not, listening to each person’s thoughts, experiences, and traumas. Most of these traumas come from family of origin and close relationships. Sometimes everyone forgets that Xiang Biao exists. During a party, he quietly got up to wash the dishes, and almost no one noticed him. These young people are participants in the &quot;Seeing the First 500 Meters&quot; social art workshop launched by artists He Zhisen and Xiang Biao, as well as Duan Zhipeng, a doctoral student at the Oslo School of Architecture and Design. The works of the workshop have participated in the 9th Shenzhen-Hong Kong Urban/Architecture Biennale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Xiang Biao returned to China was in 2019 before the epidemic. Xiang Biao is the director of the Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology in Germany and a professor of social anthropology at the University of Oxford in the UK. He became famous for his research on Zhejiang Village in Beijing. After many years abroad, he has become active in the Chinese-speaking world again in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Xiang Biao returned to China this time, he frequently chatted with various people. For example, every time he took a taxi, he didn’t want to miss the opportunity to talk to the driver. In his hometown of Wenzhou, he found that most taxi drivers were over 45 years old and usually had another job. A driver told Xiang Biao that he helped people open credit cards. Xiang Biao was curious about who else was using credit cards now that mobile payment is so convenient. The driver said that some people need small loans for short-term turnover. And looking for customers to open a card involves the gray chain of data buying and selling. In an online car-hailing car in Guangzhou, when the conversation came up about the career of the driver&#39;s son, he pointed to the platform recording equipment in the car and made a shushing gesture, and the conversation stopped. &quot;These are all new points for me. I don&#39;t know if they are useful, but they can help me discover the richness of society.&quot; Xiang Biao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiang Biao said that he is a person who is far away from art. He almost never watches movies and rarely goes to art galleries and exhibition halls. There was only one exception when he served as a judge for a German artist’s application project. . &quot;This is a German habit, to find people with different subject backgrounds to participate in the review.&quot; He said. The &quot;Seeing the First 500 Meters&quot; workshop is his most in-depth participation in a public art and social art activity. His original idea was to encourage everyone to go to the community and meet strangers, but on the one hand, due to the uncertainty caused by the epidemic in 2022; on the other hand, many people found that if the radius of 500 meters continued to be reduced, the things they were most concerned about would be , is family and companionship. As a result, many of the workshop&#39;s works were skewed. Everyone&#39;s anxiety is superimposed on social and personal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zhisen once held an exhibition in a vegetable market in Guangzhou. On the podium of South China University of Technology, he said that he had held more than 100 workshops, and most of them dispersed after seeing the first 500 people. m” members are the most closely connected. I heard that Xiang Biao made a special trip to Guangzhou to chat with everyone. Some of the participants in the workshop came from Nanjing and some from abroad. On this day, Xiang Biao sat quietly in the back row of the lecture hall, like an older student. He followed workshop member Manman through the noisy lanes and handshake buildings of Shipai Village to the art space in the urban village. This space, known as the &quot;mobile club&quot;, was originally a garbage recycling station. Xiang Biao talked with everyone about Wenzhou, the south, and the differences between the north and the south of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pV6FUnCDyc5oDAwewe9FJCGkWMNjCZKxZczL7bL2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pV6FUnCDyc5oDAwewe9FJCGkWMNjCZKxZczL7bL2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Xiang Biao (first from left in the back row) communicated with young people at the &quot;Mobile Club&quot;, an art space in Guangzhou. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiang Biao found that he was more popular among young people in China than he imagined, but he did not feel that he was a young person not as a mentor but as an interlocutor. Dialogue research is also his working method in facing the research direction of &quot;common anxiety&quot;. In October 2023, Southern Weekend reporters conducted an exclusive interview with Xiang Biao in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Understanding art through anthropology, &quot;recognition&quot; is different from &quot;understanding&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why has the contemporary art world paid more and more attention to anthropology in recent years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The so-called elite art collected in galleries and museums can do a lot in terms of methods, techniques and forms of expression. But if it is public art, if you only make breakthroughs in form and method, it will be meaningless to the common people. Others will not know what your breakthrough is, and it cannot evoke that kind of resonance. The common people will not understand what you are doing. If there is no connection with his life, then he cannot participate or be further stimulated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, public art needs to be ideological, to find a problem, and then this problem can be expressed in a very condensed artistic way, whether it is a drama, an installation, or a painting. Well, once you express it, everyone can recognize it, and at the same time, the way you express it makes everyone see that this is a door, and they can&#39;t help but open it. There is a space behind the door. This way everyone can participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such an artistic work must have a certain degree of thought, a large amount of observation of experience, a very detailed and sincere appreciation, and then sublimate an image, a motif, and a core symbol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then why is anthropology, rather than general social sciences or psychology, communicating with art? Because anthropology is to see some problems and truths from very specific experiences. It is not like philosophy, which starts from an existing problem, such as &quot;What is a good person?&quot;; it is also not like sociology, Think about it from a macro social phenomenon. Anthropology uses daily behavior to see some of the problems behind it, so anthropology has a strong sense of recognition. People can tell at a glance that this is related to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand &quot;sense of recognition&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Recognition means that when you see something, it evokes your understanding of your own life experience, and it will produce a mutual projection. So recognition is very important. Our understanding of the world must be based on our own life experience. You mobilize your memory and then make a new interpretation of this thing. This is called recognition. If you don’t understand, you just don’t recognize it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, whether it is Kafka or Benjamin, if we do not have a good understanding of European culture, we cannot recognize them. In fact, what he said is very direct in his context, and it is easy for people with similar life experiences to recognize it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like when we look at Lu Xun, it is difficult for young people today to understand Lu Xun, also because they do not recognize it. This does not mean that you can solve it through knowledge and logic. Of course, it does not rule out that there is a purely literal and logical way. You think you understand it, but you are completely unable to mobilize your own experience. (This situation) actually happens a lot. We all feel this way when we read some documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many people who engage in academic research and art. In fact, their understanding is not based on their own life experience, but on establishing relationships between texts, which can also form an understanding. Or logical interpretation, it feels like you understand it, but the effect of this understanding is very different from what we call &quot;recognition&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The participants of the workshop you met in Guangzhou this time, Most of them are very young. Did you encounter any new excitement while communicating with everyone? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course there is a lot of excitement. They are not willing to adopt the mainstream meritocracy (to live), and may not necessarily be successful in a secular sense. Some people have just resigned. Their backgrounds are quite diverse, including carpenters, civil servants, video makers, and marketers. There are also people who study art, not particularly many, but these people all have a certain sense of art. Artistic sense means that they are more sensitive to their own perceptions. They may not necessarily think about these sensitivities, but the &quot;sensitivity&quot; will stay on him or her, and it is a bit sticky and will not be easily brushed off. Artistic people are sensitive and adhesive people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workshop was a great education for me. It made me softer and paid more attention to people&#39;s subjective emotions. As I just said, these young people are not very mainstream. Many of them are weak and not very confident. There were several people who could barely speak at the beginning of last year, couldn&#39;t sleep the day before the meeting, and were so nervous. Many young people I have interacted with before, such as students at Oxford, are very talkative. Oxford is a famous place for cultivating politicians. But many of the expressions of the young people in this workshop were inconsistent. This kind of difficult expression sometimes turns into awkward silence, but once he or she speaks, you can feel that there are very rich feelings behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to my previous habits, the efficiency of this kind of communication is very low. I am a relatively rational person and have been pursuing clarity. I now realize that I was actually very closed-minded and had a very single perception of the world. I need more patience, this is an education for me. I think that to promote many things here, we cannot all do them in a rational way. Art is a good tool. I listen more. Before, I didn’t pay enough attention to the richness and sensitivity of emotions, and the many mixed and unclear things, but now I pay more attention to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I am not a mentor, but an interlocutor”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you interact with the audience during lectures or online live broadcasts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the speech, the questions asked by the public fell into two categories. The first type is to ask questions based on the concepts I proposed. To be honest, this kind of question is not particularly meaningful. In the end, it turned into me having to define and explain the concepts. What is really impactful are the second type of questions, which are very specific questions based on life experience. It&#39;s a difficult question to answer, but it gives me some punch. For example, some parents will ask me, saying that involution is not good. My child&#39;s grades are getting worse and worse. Should I send him to tutoring? No matter how I answer, this parent will most likely send their children to make up classes. Then my answer may be, how you define make-up lessons when you interact with your children is very critical. I can feel the parent&#39;s anxiety and entanglement. I can&#39;t change the objective environment, but the more useful and appropriate answer to him is how to define, state, and treat this matter. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We may need to distinguish between thinking and thoughts. Thinking is inferential and requires rigorous logic; thinking is divergent and multi-dimensional. This kind of dialogue allowed me to change from one-dimensional thinking to richer and more sensitive thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你参加的学术性的工作坊有什么不同？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那种工作坊都是要用非常清晰的语词去表达，把生活理论化、概念化地去讲，时间一般不会超过三天。这个“看见最初500米”完全不一样，它是开放的，没有一个固定的主题，而且是反对概念化的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;很多年轻人喜欢和你交流，而且很信赖你。你觉得自己是年轻人的导师吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这次回国我还蛮惊讶的，发现我比自己想象得要更受欢迎一点，年轻人的热切程度超出了我的想象。但是我并没有年轻人的导师的感觉。我很反感导师这样的角色，我自己作为青年人的时候，就不太去理人生导师，所以我不会变成自己讨厌的角色。我是一个对话者。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得最重要的不是我告诉你应该怎么样，而是我激励你去更多地思考。我会提出一些问题，凸显一些悖论，做一些分析，促使你去思考，让我们发现原来的思考可能有些简单，这是我的工作。即使我有一些所谓建议，也是关于怎么去思考，而不是在道德上和行为上应该怎么样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但确实很多年轻人向你提问的时候，会问关于焦虑、内卷这些问题，有一种期待你做人生导师的感觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不这么看。他们在朋友聚会也会互相问这些问题的，会说内卷“卷”成这样了，我该怎么办？这些问题不仅朋友间会问，亲戚间会问，晚上睡不着觉的时候也会问自己。我觉得可能那个问题占据了他的脑子，会自然地出来，所以他会向所有人问那个问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有趣的是，我怎么去接这样的问题。他知道我不会给他一个答案，不能为他引一条路。大多数人不会这么想。他其实问的是，一个已知无解的问题，应该怎么去面对。所以我把自己放在他那个情况下，理解他的处境，带着真诚去回应，这可能是比较有效的。这完全就是朋友式的交流，不是导师和被指导的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《把自己作为方法》这本书很畅销，这可能也是年轻人从你这里受到启发的原因。作为一个人类学家，为什么近几年来你会比较乐意接受访谈，或者在大众媒体上出场？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;19、20世纪，社会科学刚刚出现的时候，世界跟今天很不一样，当时学者与非学者的区别在当时非常大。比如欧洲的一个学者，要学习古希腊文、拉丁文、各种哲学，中国的学者梁启超、严复这些人首先引进社会科学，大部分民众是目不识丁的。但是21世纪，我们的青年受教育的程度，他的思考和掌握知识的能力、他的信息，跟学者没什么区别。而且我们往往觉得高手在民间，现在B站上的一些东西，其实比很多学院里的学者写得有趣。这就意味着学术研究不能在像19、20世纪那样，从自己的学术命题出发，写篇文章两三百人看一下，公众不知道怎么回事，那不行。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我在德国的工作，就是要倡导一种新的研究风格，不是从学术命题出发，而是从公众的焦虑本身出发，把“焦虑”作为题目，来共同研究。或者说，是对话式研究。每个人有自己的生命、自己的挣扎，它里面的味道，和我们在外面猜猜看看不一样。我们的输出应该是如何应对这个世界，给出思考的方法、概念和理论的视角，引起更多的讨论。对于对话式研究来说，在公众媒体上交流就非常重要，这是我的工作方法，不是辅助性，而是根本性的工作方法。不是我有什么结论要告诉大家，而是在不断的往复中，碰撞和深化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这种对话、往复中，你收到过什么形式的反馈？毕竟你也没在B站开账号，反馈不是用弹幕给出来的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我发现当代艺术特别敏感，2020年国内有四个展览以“附近”为题目。其实“附近”从学理上讲，是个很含糊的东西，我原来自己也没有觉得很有趣，只是一般性地提一下。 “附近”这个概念收到的是热情的反馈。我提出“乡绅”这个说法，收到的反馈就没那么热情，更多是疑问和批判性的。还有些话题我觉得有趣，但公众的反应一般。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人会在网上找到我的Email给我写信。并不是他提出的问题本身有什么意思，而是我会去思考，他为什么提出这样的问题，我就知道有些问题是具有普遍性的，我还要经过一段时间去观察。所以反馈不是直接给我的，需要一个过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;共同的焦虑与16型人格&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;回国这段时间，你几乎每天在高强度地跟各种人聊天，你一直这么健谈吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没有测过。我不是一个性格上很外向的人，有时候有一点社恐，很长时间对人的主观情感都不敏感。甚至我一直觉得自己有轻度的自闭症，我看牛津的一个分析哲学家的传记，他经常跟别人说话，但是大家发现，他对很多常识性的东西是无感的，对人际关系的理解非常简单，但对有些东西的分析又可以非常深刻，我觉得这好像跟我很像。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老实说我是比较内向的，比较怕和很多以一起吃饭。那种场合的聊天，很少有人能够完整地讲他的经历，谈话的内容很容易变成各种片段、八卦、极端的故事，很多是道听途说的。我惊讶的是很多知识精英也爱讲这些。在那种环境下，我就很难维持自己，变得非常安静，想快点结束。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在中国年轻人很流行聊16型人格，大家经常互相问“你是I人还是E人”，你怎么看这个现象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;人格分类是个很有趣的现象，它跟年轻人原来对心理学的好奇还不太一样，不仅仅是想了解自己的心理状态，认识自我，它现在主要是一种社交工具，互相知道对方的类型，然后互相画像，然后互相提问，但这个提问其实不一定是说要（根据对方的人格类型）对症下药，而是说没办法用一种自然的话语开始沟通，用人格分类就可以比较安心地去聊。这和社交媒体的作用很有关系，我们习惯与人设，也就是类型的人、画像中的人互动，但是不太知道怎么和人本身互动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在大多数学术研究是围绕着课题走，你用这样的方式来进行对话，研究共同的焦虑，你觉得自己是一个幸运的人吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我是非常幸运，我在牛津本来就很幸运的，到了德国马普所，对我的约束就更少，而且给了一个平台，鼓励你做一些奇怪的事情。在“共同的焦虑”这个方向，我们有博士后在非洲做“压力”，有人在拉美做“执著”，在什么样的具体生活情况下，人们会对什么问题，以什么方式做执著的投入，这可以让我们学到什么。这跟哲学讨论不一样，是很现实的观察。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么你会特别重视“焦虑”？为什么会从“共同的焦虑”，而不是比如说“共同的关切”出发，来进行对话式研究？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;公众关切的东西往往是受一种主流话语形塑的，容易用一些数据直接去表达。关切是一体化、概念化的。焦虑带着情绪性，更接近生命体验本身。对老百姓来说，生活的目的不是批判，而是生活得更好。当然有很多东西值得批判，但要从他生活的目的里面出来，批判才会落到实处，便于他们的行动，然后可以在看起来不可改变的结构之下改变生活，改变人们的思考。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究焦虑，要比研究公众的关切，或者某一个议题，难得多得多，因为焦虑这个东西很模糊，讲不清楚，没法定义，更不用说定量了。这就意味着我们必须找到新的语言、新的思想方法。跟着议题走很容易，但创新也很难。但是从焦虑出发，就更能抓住当下的新的矛盾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“焦虑”是近几年持续很久的一个热词，对大家焦虑的状况，你有什么观察？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;项飙：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;焦虑的状况比我想象得还要严重，很弥漫性的。本来从报道上就能看到现在心理疾病的高发，然后通过跟年轻人的对话，与各种各样的人聊天、接触，我就更加从经验层面看到大家怎么去描述焦虑，焦虑是如何蔓延的，包括亲密关系当中，焦虑被放大或被扭曲。同时，大家意识到自己在焦虑，这就意味着大家在期待一种改变，至少期待一种更好的回应自己处境的方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;焦虑的一个原因是我们对生活的感知的断裂。当生活出现了极大的摇摆，摇摆之后如果没有充分的讨论和沟通，那对老百姓来讲，就没法对事情的发展形成完整的理解。这里面肯定有各种各样的创伤，这个创伤留在自己身上，我们如果处理不好，它会一直留下来，变成我们今后的恐惧、无力、神经过敏、激烈的反应等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经常有人问我，你为什么不批判？其实批判还是很重要，但我把更多的注意力放在分析我们身上的创伤，我们怎么对待它，怎么去保存自己的力量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁“包租婆”邝肖卿成中国女首富 房地产仍是女企业家财富首要来源]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;现年94岁的新鸿基地产（0016.HK）创办人郭得胜的夫人邝肖卿以720亿元的身价，首次成为中国女首富；“十连冠”女首富杨惠妍排名降至第五；上榜的50位女企业家近六成为白手起家，房地产仍然是其财富第一大来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月14日，胡润研究院与商界女性成长与社交平台红颜会联合发布《2023红颜会·胡润女企业家榜》（下称“胡润女企业家榜单”）显示如上信息。这是胡润研究院连续第十八次发布此榜单，财富计算的截止日期为2023年9月1日。与胡润百富榜总榜不同，女企业家榜单独计算能够从家族财富中剥离出的女企业家个人财富。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;94岁“第一包租婆”邝肖卿成中国女首富&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“这18年来，前50名中国女企业家的上榜门槛从5亿上升至135亿，涨了近30倍。”胡润百富董事长兼首席调研官胡润如上表示。不过，从胡润百富总榜上来看，女企业家占比下降1.3个百分点，至25.4%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡润女企业家榜单显示，94岁的邝肖卿以720亿元财富首次成为中国女首富，也是胡润女企业家榜18年来第六位中国女首富，前五位是张茵（三次）、杨惠妍（十次）、吴亚军（两次）、周群飞（一次）、陈丽华（一次）。龙湖地产创始人吴亚军以665亿元，蝉联中国白手起家女首富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258386&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;（胡润女企业家榜单TOP10，来源：胡润百富）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，邝肖卿生于1929年，籍贯广东省花都区花山镇，香港企业家，新鸿基地产创办人郭得胜的夫人，总财富720亿元。她也是新鸿基地产的最大股东，在家族德高望重，是新鸿基地产的灵魂人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新鸿基地产是香港最大的地产商之一，据新鸿基地产2023财年（2022年7月1日至2023年6月30日）数据显示，公司营业收入为712亿港元，归母净利润为239.1亿港元，净利润率为34.52%，同比增加2.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邝肖卿有“中国第一包租婆”之称。从新鸿基地产近五年财报来看，物业租赁贡献的营收占比一直最大，约为三分之一。从最新财报来看，截至2023年6月30日，新鸿基地产在香港的土储约有5800万平方呎（约为538万平方米），其中超六成为多元化的物业，绝大部分用作出租及长线投资，为集团带来可观的经常性收入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据胡润百富称，邝肖卿首次成为中国女首富，主要受益于今年港币汇率的上涨及公司分红。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从港币汇率上涨来看，今年以来，人民币兑港币的汇率从0.8左右上升至0.9附近，最高约为0.93。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从公司分红来看，同花顺显示，新鸿基地产属于内资南下买入最多的蓝筹股之一，近五年累计派现717.2亿港元。2023财年（2022年7月1日至2023年6月30日）公司共计派现两次，派现金额为143.4亿港元，股利支付率为60%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，最新财年（派息日为11月16日）新鸿基地产分红每股3.7港元，是上一财年分红的三倍。邝肖卿个人持有新鸿基地产小于0.01%，为2.502万股，邝肖卿与直系亲属等共同持有新鸿基地产19.5%的股份，共计5.65亿股。以每股3.7港元的分红派息计算，邝肖卿个人持股部分，以及与他人共同持股部分将获利大约为20.91亿港元。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“十冠王”杨惠妍排名下降至第五位&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在本次榜单中，还有一大关注点是十次夺得女首富桂冠的杨惠妍财富大幅缩水，排名跌至第五。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以胡润女企业家榜单排名变化来看，碧桂园董事会主席及执行董事杨惠妍2023年的财富相比去年缩水最多（270亿元），以480亿元位列第5；其次是受添加剂事件影响而业绩下滑的海天味业执行总裁程雪，财富缩水了165亿元；再次是“玻尿酸女王”华熙国际投资集团董事长赵燕，财富缩水了145亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨惠妍生于1981年，是碧桂园创始人杨国强的二女儿。2005年，杨惠妍从美国俄亥俄州立大学市场营销及物流专业毕业回国，以杨国强私人助理身份加入碧桂园，并担任采购经理。她先后在碧桂园投资中心、采购部、人资中心、数字化管理中心等部门担任要职。2023年3月，杨惠妍正式成为家族企业接班人，担任碧桂园董事会主席。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年4月，碧桂园在香港上市，杨国强将名下股份悉数转给杨惠妍。26岁的杨惠妍以160.2亿美元位列2007年福布斯富豪榜榜首，同时成为中国新任女首富。从2007年到2022年这16年间，杨惠妍十次问鼎中国女首富。值得注意的是，2022年杨惠妍的财富同比缩水近六成，但依然位列榜首。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（杨惠妍十次问鼎中国女首富，来源：胡润百富）&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨惠妍财富缩水与碧桂园危机紧密相关。2023年，由于宏观经济和地产的不确定性增强，碧桂园债务频频亮出红灯。“面对消费端与融资端的双向收紧，集团流动性承受着前所未有的压力。”碧桂园在2023年中报表示。从碧桂园近五年的年报及中报可以发现，碧桂园的战略目标已经从审慎务实的补充优质土储变为“保交楼”和尽力安排偿债。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月30日，碧桂园服务（6098.HK）发布公告称，公司控股股东、非执行董事兼董事会主席杨惠妍向国强公益基金会（香港）有限公司捐赠价值64亿港元的股票用作慈善公益。但此举引来市场争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，胡润女企业家榜单显示，新上榜的女富豪数量为8位，是18年来最少的一次，比去年少3位。新人中排名最靠前的是从事大数据中心与算力基础设施产业的润泽科技的周超男，财富200亿元；其次是海底捞创始人之一舒萍，财富180亿元；再次是台湾的裕隆汽车掌门人严陈莉莲，财富160亿元。新人中还包括同花顺董事兼副总经理叶琼玖，财富135亿元。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;近六成女企业家为白手起家房地产仍然是其财富最大来源&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从财富来源来看，近六成女企业家为白手起家，近四成为继承。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体来看，胡润女企业家榜单显示，2023年有34位白手起家的女企业家，占比59%，与去年基本持平；24位非白手起家，比去年少2位，占比41%，去年这一指标为43%。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白手起家的女企业家主要是自己创业或与丈夫共同创业。比如龙湖的吴亚军、富华的陈丽华和立讯精密的王来春，恒力的范红卫、通威的管亚梅和蓝月亮的潘东等。非白手起家的女企业家一方面是继承财富，如娃哈哈的宗馥莉、碧桂园的杨惠妍等；另一方面是企业家的遗孀等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从年龄来看，白手起家的女企业家平均年龄约为59岁，继承者的平均年龄为54岁。&amp;nbsp;7位上榜的“80”后的财富全部都是继承所得，她们是：碧桂园42岁的杨惠妍，苏商40岁的严昕，娃哈哈41岁的宗馥莉，达利食品40岁的许阳阳，福莱特玻璃36岁的阮泽云，合盛39岁的罗燚和晶澳太阳能科技35岁的靳军淼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从女企业家从事的行业来看，房地产仍然是女企业家财富第一大来源，上榜人数占比17%，与去年持平；能源与消费品并列第二，占比13%；食品与饮料、有色金属、大健康等行业都有所上涨，下降的则是化工及投资行业。&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（男女企业家从事行业分布情况，来源：胡润百富）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“相对来说，中国女企业家做房地产和消费品行业较好，而男企业家做食品饮料、传媒娱乐和汽车行业较好。”胡润说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，胡润表示：“今年表现较好的女企业家主要来自苹果产业链，包括蓝思科技的周群飞、领益智造的曾芳勤；第二是得益于疫情后娱乐、餐饮业复苏的美高梅中国的何超琼、海底捞的李海燕和舒萍；第三是ChatGPT带动的百度的马东敏等。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育不是功名利禄的“油门”，而是做人做事的“把门”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;三叔来找我诉苦，说又帮堂弟还了一万元的债务，然后照例感慨一句“还是你们念书好啊”，这个“啊”字是一声长叹，包含着三叔很多思绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时光倒回二十年，三叔对于念书的态度并非一个“好”字，而是有他自己的判断。他自身是个能人，力气大，脑子灵，各种农活手拿把掐不在话下，到城里打工也能立刻适应，从技能到人际，游刃有余，既赚钱，也赚人缘。因此，他家的日子在本村最殷实，称得上“首富”，属于“村东头跺跺脚，村西头颤三颤”的人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他常说，自己没读几天书，没接受过啥高深的教育，但日子过得比别人都强。上学念书，最终还是要过日子，只要日子过得好，受不受教育不要太在乎。因此，在别人家都为孩子成绩不好着急的时候，三叔很淡然，对堂弟的成绩不关心，考了100分不表扬，考个不及格也不打骂，并告诉自己的儿子，挣多少分不算本事，关键是会挣钱。三叔对于学校教育是这个态度，对于家庭教育是这样灌输——只要掌握了挣钱的本事，你就赢了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三叔对那些在教育上投入太多钱和精力的家庭很不屑，尤其是对我家。那个时候的学费虽不算高，但对于农村家庭仍是不小的负担，每到开学前，很多父母都为学费犯愁，甚至开学后好长时间，才会凑齐。三叔对凑学费的做法表示不理解，既然没钱，为啥还要去上，上了小学，要上中学，还要上大学，毕业之后如果没找到工作或者工作不好，那投了十多年的钱不就打了水漂？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我中考发挥失常，觉得够不着录取线，很沮丧失落，亲戚朋友不好来安慰，只有三叔过来告诉我，别着急，大不了和他一起去学修车，比念书简单，还能挣钱。搞得我哭笑不得，好在只是虚惊，一个月后我成功进入高中读书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为有教育观念的分歧，父亲和三叔的关系很微妙，兄弟二人经常会在吃饭喝酒时，为了这个分歧吵起来，闹个不欢而散。父亲开始是坚定的，也一直给我打气，说砸锅卖铁也要念书。但随着堂弟进入社会，父亲的心有些动摇了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;堂弟在三叔的不管之下，勉强挨到初中毕业，就再也不肯上学，想出去城市里闯一闯，三叔表示支持，并把他托付给一个做生意的亲戚照料。三叔给了堂弟一笔钱，让他自己去赚第一桶金。堂弟年纪不大，但继承了三叔的才干，不到18岁就已在城里混个风生水起，起码开始往家里拿钱了。而我那时还在大学里“烧钱”呢。每次放假回家，父亲总是说着堂弟致富的传奇，口气里都是惊羡，后来渐渐表达对我读书见效慢的责备，从叹息到抱怨，搞得我不敢和堂弟同时出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反转出现在我工作的第二年。堂弟开始欠债，他做生意喜欢猛进，加之很早进入社会摸爬滚打，有了固执的自信，对老人的劝诫当耳旁风。东处挪钱，西处洽谈，成了常态，渐渐入不敷出。开始三叔觉得家资雄厚，亏点本不算什么，等发现势头不对为时已晚，堂弟的债务横跨黑白两道，涵盖亲戚朋友，他无力偿还，就摊在了要强的三叔头上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;倾家荡产之后，债务只填上十分之一，已经当了爷爷可颐享天年的三叔决定从头再来，他把年轻时的手艺操持起来，同时打着两三份工，以惊人的毅力赚钱还债。亲戚的债务、银行的贷款……一笔又一笔，全靠他和三婶两个人支撑偿还。而习惯于在钱堆里打滚的堂弟，无法接受没钱的日子，在欠债之后直接躺平，天大的事情让父母顶着，就连他自己的儿子都是老人一边打工一边照料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的日子已持续十年，债务总算还得差不多。我没多大变化，就是亦步亦趋上班下班，变化的是父亲和三叔。父亲开始庆幸当年自己对于教育的投入，虽然我没挣什么大钱，但学会了稳重，不易“学坏”，对我也比从前多了肯定。三叔开始重复着说“念书多好”，教育是要花钱，但这个钱值得花，因为念了书的人就有“把门的”，做事就有东西拉着，不会一直“踩油门”，不管不顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我渐渐明白，教育固然不是万能的，可能无法直接解决就业、赚钱等这些很现实的问题。但没有教育是万万不能的，我们常常会将教育和社会想成因果关系，教育必须对进入社会能做什么负责，否则便是无用的。其实，教育的一大功能是对进入社会不做什么负责，不能只盯着“有所为”，还要注重“有所不为”。透过三叔的话，我想无论家庭教育、学校教育、社会教育，如果专注于将教育当成利禄的“油门”，那么注定会失控，越来越“快”的时代，需要教育作为“刹车”的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为长春媒体人）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[千年造像被“毁容”，只为他们还个愿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:29:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;近日，四川巴中南江县一处开凿于北魏晚期，距今1400多年的摩崖造像被人涂抹破坏，引发关注。网友看完图片后感慨：“令人欲哭无泪，文物保护任重道远。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;被涂抹造像为2021年新发现&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;网友发布的图片显示，造像被涂抹得花花绿绿。一些造像的莲座、衣服、头饰、手中器物分别被涂上了不同的色彩。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;773&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;南江县一摩崖造像被涂抹后（图上）和被涂抹前（图下）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;相关考古调查报告显示，该处造像系2021年新发现。2022年2月，巴中市文物局、四川大学考古文博学院、西安碑林博物馆和南江县文物保护研究中心联合对该处摩崖造像进行调查工作，随后形成的报告认为：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“摩崖造像罕见地始凿于北魏晚期，在初唐&lt;span>;、武周和中晚唐又有续凿，开凿年代早，形成过程复杂，其整体将地表天然石包开凿为造像碑的特色做法，在四川地区属于孤例。这些材料在完善四川石窟发展序列，揭示四川地区和中原北方地区的佛教文化艺术交流领域具有十分重要的学术价值。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;当地另一处摩崖造像被涂抹后（图上）和被涂抹前（图下）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;文保人员发现后没来得及阻止&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;记者致电巴中市文物局，一位工作人员表示，事情是前两天发生的，当时通过监控发现就去制止了，“因为在荒山野岭，赶到时他们已经涂完了。造像&lt;/span>;是前两年才发现的，还没有纳入文保单位，我们已经建了文物棚和监控，但太远了在山里面，当地的保护力量也有限。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工作人员介绍，涂抹造像的都是些七八十岁的老太爷，说是为给菩萨“穿衣还愿”，“我们也不好处理，只能批评教育。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于造像能否恢复原貌，巴中市文物局工作人员说，涂抹造像的颜料主要是丙烯类，目前已经邀请相关专家论证，“应该是可以恢复的，我们也会加强文物保护宣传教育，也通过媒体呼吁大家提高文物保护意识。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;当地通报：公安机关已介入调查&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;15日凌晨，南江县文物保护研究中心发布关于“石飞河摩崖造像被涂色”的情况通报：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月13日，我县石飞河部分摩崖造像被涂色引发网友广泛关注。经初步调查，11月6日，四&lt;/span>;川省阆中市居民李某华委托巴中市南江县赤溪镇金银村村民王某国（李某华之母）请高塔镇射洪寨村民岳某邦对石飞河部分摩崖造像涂色“穿衣还愿”。事件发生后，当地立即对现场增加了保护措施，防止不当行为造成二次损害。同时，公安机关正在依法开展调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月14日，四川省文物局、文物考古研究院和巴中市文物局专家进行现场查勘，并研究制定保护修复方案。南江县文物保护研究&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;中心已联系具有文物评估资质机构对摩崖造像价值及因涂抹造成的损失进行评估。下一步，我中心将及时向社会公布调查处置和修复情况。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;一些“冷门”的文物正在褪色&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;其实，由于&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;基层文物保护&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;力&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;量较弱，全国&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;各地类似的文物损坏现象并不少见。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在故宫、颐和园、秦始皇陵兵马俑等著名景点之外，山林里的古墓、荒野中的长城、悬崖上的佛窟……在我们看不见的地方，一些“冷门”的文物，正在褪色、风化、坍塌、消失。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;696&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;B站UP主@遗产君对此深有感触。“2015年，我参观了近20处山西古建筑，大部分都很破败。一些宋元时期的木构建筑整个屋顶都是塌的，墙也是倒的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;也是从那时起，他决定做一名文物分享博主。8年来，他走访了全国2000多处文物古迹，发布了25000多条文物帖文。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;1244&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这些年，国家文物保护力度逐渐加大，“前两年我再去山西，看到情况改善了很多。只要是&#39;国保单位&#39;，基本都修复好了，我快认不出来了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“国保单位”，即全&lt;/span>;国重点文物保护单位，由国家文物局直接拨款保护，力度最大。然而，我国76.7万处不可移动文物里，能被国家重点保护的，只有5058处，不到0.7%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那些散落于乡村山野间的低级别文物，才是更让人担心的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在不久前，山西长城被挖上&lt;span>;了热搜：两名工人为了“抄近路”，竟然用挖掘机把一段明长城挖了个大缺口。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;463&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;山西明长城的悲剧并不是偶然。2018年，博主遗产君在敦煌旅游时，从阳关回市区的路上，看到私家车直直地从一段汉长城上碾过去。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;788&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“许多冷门文物都经历了类似的破坏。”厦门大学历史与文化遗产学院特任研究员朱展云表示，这几年大规模、有组织的文物盗掘少了，但“无心之失”还有很多。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;山西某清代探花府&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我们不禁要问，为什么这些本该被保护的文物遗迹，大多难逃衰败？&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品还是毒品？女子网上转售父亲遗留止疼药一审判贩毒罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73519&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70321&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3217.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年7月，廖华在病友药转群发布的药品照片。受访者供图&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258309&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年7月，廖华在病友药转群发布的药品照片。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近日，广州女子廖华（化名）因涉嫌贩毒遭遇山东警方跨省追捕事件引发关注。廖华一再陈述，她以260元转售的镇痛药品是父亲去世后留下的，她本着节约不浪费的想法，在病友群里转药，并不知道这是“毒品”。&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山东省阳信县法院一审认为，廖华违反国家对毒品的管理规定，以牟利为目的，贩卖国家规定管制的能够使人形成瘾癖的精神药品，其行为已构成贩卖毒品罪。一审判处其拘役两个月，缓刑三个月，并处罚金人民币一千元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廖华说，一审宣判后，她越想越委屈。此前她只想到自己售卖处方药违反法规，但没想到是“贩毒罪”这样重的刑事罪名，而她的工作是行政会计，犯罪污点将极大地影响她的职业发展。廖华选择上诉，2023年10月底，此案二审在滨州中院开庭审理，目前未宣判。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月13日，滨州中院该案的承办法官告诉南方周末记者，法院将会按法律规定进行调查，调查方向及进度在审判结束后才能公布。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;既是药品也是毒品&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廖华称，自己售出的药物均是父亲生前服用剩下的。廖华父亲因患直肠癌晚期，治疗期间经常骨折，疼痛得厉害，医院开具了不少止疼片，类型也很多。父亲病重逝世后，廖华不知如何处理余药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月，廖华通过病友介绍进入一个“病友交流余药转让群”，将父亲剩下的治疗新冠、关节疼痛等15种药物摆放到一起，拍照发到微信群。当时群里昵称“小王”的人很快加上廖华并私信，询问购买盐酸曲马林及泰勒宁这两种药品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廖华对南方周末记者说，出事后，她注意到群里虽然经常有人转药，但是大部分为抗癌、化疗药物，较少出现止疼药。而她以260元转售给小王的三盒盐酸曲马林及两盒泰勒宁，属于“国家规定管制的其他能够使人形成瘾癖的麻醉药品和精神药品”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月14日，小王收到这一快递后，便开车前往当地派出所，反映其在网上未经处方就买到了国家管制药品，“这些都是麻精药品，也可以算是毒品”。警方对其询问笔录显示，小王是山东阳信县的吸毒人员，以前“溜过冰”（吸过冰毒），想用这些药替代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京市京都律师事务所律师汤建彬长期代理毒品犯罪案件，他告诉南方周末记者，国家毒品管制对象除了海洛因、冰毒、大麻等传统毒品以外，还有一类“麻精药品”，兼具药用属性和毒品属性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;汤建彬介绍，在司法实践中判断是不是“毒品”，首先要看该物质在不在国家列管的麻精药品名录里，即国家药监局、公安部、国家卫生健康委最新发布的《麻醉药品品种目录》《精神药品品种目录》及《非药用类麻醉药品和精神药品管制品种增补目录》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者查阅发现，这些名录是动态更新的，例如咳嗽药水里的可待因是一种镇痛药物，但由于其成瘾性，早在2000年就出现了咳嗽药水滥用成瘾的情况。相关部门陆续出台了系列规定，要求“凭处方销售”“适量销购”“监控流向”；2015年，含可待因复方口服液体制剂被列入第二类精神药品管制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此次廖华转卖的盐酸曲马林是一种中枢性镇痛药，多用于各种术后止痛，癌痛、分娩痛等治疗。过量使用可引起心动过缓、抽搐、呼吸抑制及昏迷，具有成瘾性。2008年，曲马多（包括其盐和单方制剂以及可能存在的异构体）已被列入二类精神药品进行管制。但曲马多的复方制剂，则是在2023年7月1日才列入二类精神药品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廖华转卖的另一种药物泰勒宁（氨酚羟考酮片），属于羟考酮的复方制剂，也是临床上被广泛运用的止痛类药物，于2019年9月1日被列入第二类精神药品管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月1日后，国家管制的麻精药品和非药用类麻精药品品种已达456种和2整类（芬太尼类物质和合成大麻素类物质）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“列管”意味着盐酸曲马林和氨酚羟考酮具有毒品和药品双重属性。“首先是药品属性”，汤建彬解释，这些麻精药品被列管并不自动等同于毒品，只有流入非法的毒品市场或被吸毒人员吸食的情况下，才会变成“毒品”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;按照最高人民法院2023年6月26日印发的《2023全国法院毒品犯罪审判工作会议纪要》（昆明会议纪要）相关规定，明知是走私、贩卖毒品的犯罪分子或者吸毒人员，而向其贩卖国家规定管制的、具有医疗等合法用途的麻醉药品、精神药品的，以贩卖毒品罪定罪处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据昆明会议纪要，“确有证据证明出于治疗疾病等相关目的”，私自经营具有医疗等合法用途的麻精药品的，不以毒品犯罪论处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;因此，廖华是否在明知对方是吸毒人员的情况下，仍出售盐酸曲马林及氨酚羟考酮，成为该案的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73518&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70320&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3215.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;廖华与购药者的聊天记录。受访者供图&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258310&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;廖华与购药者的聊天记录。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;是否“钓鱼执法”？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在网购药物过程中，小王曾暴露自己是吸毒人员。双方聊天记录显示，小王曾说：“我是以前溜过冰，现在买不到了，用这些药代替！现在还有点瘾！太难戒了。”廖华没有立即回复，小王后续又提到：“我不是病了，我以前玩音乐抽大麻，现在不好找了！用这个药代替它！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;廖华辩称，她并不知道“溜冰”是什么意思，对于盐酸曲马林和泰勒宁，也一直停留在止痛药的认知层面。她并未在意小王说的成瘾、难戒等字眼。在寄出药品后，她还建议小王如果有疼痛，可以试一下中医的针灸，这是她此前照顾父亲时的止痛经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;湖北今天律师事务所律师付成晨认为，该案的关键在于能否认定明知“毒品”。廖华上述说法可以作为辩护理由，但客观上廖华实施了贩卖“毒品”的行为，且其转卖的是父亲自己使用过的药，她对药效是十分清楚的，甚至可能在医生开药过程中对管制处方药性质有一定了解。要认定其“不明知”是毒品，还需看进一步的证据材料，以及法官的裁量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据廖华提供的另一份聊天记录，她还给一位已手术的胃癌患者转赠了芬太尼止疼贴，对方表示感谢。廖华称自己本意是病友互助，不是专门卖药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而在该案案发一个月后，曾联系廖华买药的小王，再次在微信群中想要加转让药品的群友。廖华注意到，该群友转让的药物合照里也包含盐酸曲马林缓释片。她怀疑此人在“钓鱼”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;汤建彬分析，吸毒人员在转药群里购买替代药品时，主动表明自己吸毒的行为不大符合常理。而在本案中，这几句话恰恰构成了廖华犯贩毒罪的关键。需要考量这一做法是否有“犯意引诱”的嫌疑，即当事人本身没有这个犯罪意愿，特殊人员诱导其犯罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据昆明会议纪要，隐匿身份人员存在“犯意引诱”的情况下获得的证据材料应予以排除。排除上述证据后，在案证据达不到认定被引诱人有罪的证明标准的，应当依法作出证据不足、指控的犯罪不能成立的无罪判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但目前，廖华质疑的“钓鱼执法”并无确切证据。在相关笔录中，举报人是主动开车到派出所报案，并未提及是警方线人等身份。南方周末记者数次联系小王，未获回复。11月13日，阳信县公安局工作人员表示由于案件正在二审，相关信息不便透露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;付成晨提醒，没有取得药品经营许可证，是不允许私下转卖药品的；转卖管制药品涉刑，转卖一般药品情节严重也涉刑，数额未达到刑事立案标准的，也会面临行政处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在病友群里，有人转发了廖华的案件报道后，群公告上写到：“各位病友、病友家属，止疼药国家严格管控，含有毒品成分，私自交易买卖，属于违法犯罪，轻者拘留取保候审，重者判刑，敬请大家遵纪守法！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校准航向再出发——新华社五论中美关系如何重返正轨]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;应美国总统拜登邀请，国家主席习近平将于11月14日至17日赴美国旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。两国元首将就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，以及事关世界和平与发展的重大问题深入沟通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元首外交是中美关系的“指南针”和“定盘星”，中美各界和国际社会也因此对这次旧金山会晤倍加期待，期待中美关系在元首外交战略引领下尽快回到健康稳定发展的正轨。在此关键节点，新华社推出“推动中美关系回归正轨”系列评论报道，呼吁美方同中方相向而行，克服干扰、排除障碍、积累成果、营造氛围，共同推动中美关系重回健康稳定发展轨道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一论回归元首共识：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让对稳定和发展中美关系的期待成为现实，需要中美相向而行。行动路线图也很清楚，就是重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山，把中美元首巴厘岛会晤共识真正落到实处，扩大双边关系积极议程，减少消极议程，为旧金山会晤创造条件、排除干扰、积累成果、营造氛围。毫无疑问，重返巴厘岛、通往旧金山的路程，不会是一马平川，不能靠“自动驾驶”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有重返巴厘岛，才能通往旧金山，重返巴厘岛是基础、是前提。最近一段时间，中美关系之所以出现一些积极迹象，正是因为对两国元首巴厘岛会晤共识的跟进和落实得到了提速。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希望美方在近期中美互动中所展现的积极姿态不是政治算计和战术投机，所作出的口头承诺能够成为具体政策和实质行动。也希望美方能够不被国内党争羁绊和政客私利左右，同中方共同行动、持久努力，让中美关系中的好消息、好势头不断累积，推动两国关系真正稳下来、好起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为世界上最重要的一组双边关系，中美关系牵动着人类的前途命运。巴厘岛会晤时，习近平主席强调应从把握世界大势的高度看待和处理中美关系。世界大势是什么？是和平、发展、合作、共赢成为时代潮流，任何国家或国家集团都再也无法单独主宰世界事务；是全球南方全面开启“大觉醒”时代，人类社会加速进入多极化世界；是人类越来越成为你中有我、我中有你的命运共同体，同时也面临着诸多全球性挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二论校准关系航向：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;中美必须找到正确的相处之道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为两个世界大国，中美能否确立正确相处之道，攸关世界和平发展和人类前途命运。一段时间以来，两国关系的变化牵动世界人心，其跌宕起伏的曲折历程，一方面表明了中美关系的严峻性和复杂性，确立大国正确相处之道并非易事，其间会受到各种因素的影响扰动；另一方面，双方最终排除干扰达成“重返巴厘岛”“面向旧金山”的重要共识也再一次证明，只要本着对历史、对世界、对人民负责的态度，对彼此树立正确理性的认知，对改善关系抱持最大诚意，中美关系就能朝着积极的方向发展，真正实现稳下来、好起来，回归健康稳定发展的正轨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于中美如何正确相处，习近平主席早已给出了明确答案，那就是相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢。这三大原则，是审视中美关系半个多世纪风云跌宕得出的重要论断，是当今时代大国之间彼此交往的正确之道，是保证中美两艘巨轮不偏航、不失速、不相撞的重要航标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有尊重，就谈不上信任；没有信任，就无法避免冲突，也谈不上真正的合作。这是中美交往积累的重要经验，也是双边关系重回正轨的基本前提。守住和平底线，这是中美必须做出的正确抉择。合作共赢是中美关系半个世纪以来的真实叙事，也是双方应当继续争取的共同目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从巴厘岛一路走来，中美关系回暖来之不易，值得倍加珍惜。面向旧金山，双方应从过往汲取现实的启迪，汇聚相向而行的力量，共同探索构建新时代的中美关系，创造中美两国的美好未来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三论正确定义关系：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;竞争对抗不符合时代潮流&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系如何发展，归根到底取决于两个大国对于彼此的认知。以合作面主导认知，双边关系就能朝好的方向发展；以竞争面主导认知乃至以竞争定义全部关系，对抗性就会不断增强，就有滑入“新冷战”深渊的风险。当下美方理顺对华关系，关键是树立正确的对华认知，走出零和博弈思维，积累扩大合作面，持续推动中美关系稳下来、好起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为两个大国，中美在贸易、技术、外交等领域既有合作也有竞争，不是你输我赢、你死我活，而应当是你追我赶、共同进步。中国不回避竞争、不惧怕竞争，但竞争应该是公平、合理、良性的，有红线、有禁区，不能无视市场经济规则和国际关系基本准则，更不能将核心利益问题作为竞争工具、挑衅手段。中国认为的竞争，应该是田径赛，有赛道有规则，可以在你追我赶中提升各自成绩，就像运动员竞技追求的是不断提升自己、突破自我，取得更好成绩，而不是给其他运动员“使绊子”或恶意干扰，否则只会因为违规而被罚出局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竞争更不是中美关系的全部。中美经济互补性远大于竞争性，中美经贸合作的本质是互利共赢。当前形势下，中美共同利益不是减少了，而是更多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美作为两个大国，对人类繁荣发展担负着重要责任。通过合作共同开启人类发展的新纪元，还是滑入大国冲突对抗的深渊，是两国必须回答好的世纪之问。跳出谁赢谁输的狭隘视角，追求人类一起赢的高尚目标，应该成为新时代中美两国的共同追求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四论增进合作共识：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;地球容得下中美各自发展、共同繁荣&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近一段时间以来，中美正向互动趋势不断增强。美国一方面在“竞争”意识主导下继续推出对华科技、经贸合作限制措施，一方面也在各个渠道寻求与中国接触，出现了近年鲜见的“求同”苗头。究其根本，中美是全球最大的两个经济体，中美关系是全世界最重要的双边关系，两国经济关联既深且广，两国和世界都无法承受双方误判意图、对抗冲突之重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美双方的发展进步完全可以成为对方的机遇而不是挑战，两国经济互补性远大于竞争性，中美应该互利共赢而不是零和博弈，双方可以彼此成就，做大共同利益的蛋糕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美合作不仅有存量优势，还有增量优势。中美虽然互为重要贸易伙伴，每年有数千亿美元的贸易额，但双边贸易额仍然有增长空间，这是美国与其他国家双边经贸关系无法比拟的。合作将为双方开辟更多更宽广领域增长空间。 “碳中和”领域技术研发交流和联合投资将使双方受益；未来中美老龄化人群对医疗服务的需求将大幅增长，医疗技术和数据的交流将给双方带来巨大价值；中国超大规模中等收入人群为美国农产品提供难以估量的潜在市场；美中两国都受益于双向投资流，鼓励相互投资将多角度反哺两国经济……双方合作的单子可以拉得很长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宽广的地球完全容得下中美各自发展、共同繁荣。中国人民和美国人民一样，都是自尊自信自强的人民，都拥有追求美好生活的权利，两国之间存在的共同利益应该得到重视，各自取得成功对彼此都是机遇而非威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;五论夯实民意基础：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;汇聚中美交流合作的正能量&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258352&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美虽远隔重洋，但中美人民的交流合作源远流长。 “国之交在于民相亲”。追忆往昔，中美民间的友好交往从没有中断，两国人民也在交往中结下了深情厚谊，为中美关系发展发挥了重要作用。历史已经充分证明，中美两国人民完全可以跨越制度、文化、语言的差异，建立起深厚的友谊。中美民间交流互利共赢，不仅是两国人民做出的自主选择，更是不可阻挡的历史潮流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中美关系处于关键十字路口的当下，持续不断的民间交往和人文交流合作尤显珍贵，为两国关系的健康发展注入源源不断的正能量。横跨太平洋的航班越多、货轮越多、游客越多、学生学者越多，中美两国关系发展的民意基础就越厚实，空间就越广阔，动力就越强劲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美都应该本着对两国人民负责任的态度，从两国人民的福祉出发，处理好、管控好、发展好两国关系，为两国人民继承和弘扬珍贵友谊遗产创造有利氛围和条件，筑牢两国友谊与合作的民意基础。近期中美关系“大气候”回暖，越来越多的中美各界人士为两国扩大交往合作鼓与呼，为两国人民相知相亲四处奔走，传递出中美民间友好的积极信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系眼下仍面临不少困难和挑战，稳定和改善两国关系任重道远。所幸的是，从历史中走来的这些根基性民间纽带仍在，推动中美关系向前发展的正能量正在不断聚集。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“去中国躲一下”，缅北战区逃生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“我们老家打仗了，去中国躲一下。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月10日上午，缅甸“90后”阿兰在云南瑞丽口岸排队等待入境。相较于7天前，这一次的速度快了很多，“中国国门这边，一个小时就办好了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰家在缅甸掸邦木姐市贵概镇，祖籍中国云南。今年10月下旬，阿兰回老家短住时，意外遇到了突发的战火。“开始几天可以听到枪炮声，去中国的路也封了。”直到11月4日，阿兰才再次回到木姐口岸，在那里看到了很多像她一样排队去中国的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明清以来，大量汉族移民迁入缅甸北部，逐渐形成重要的华人聚居区。这里与中国云南密切相接，不少居民说汉语、写汉字，对中华文化有天然的亲近感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;缅北冲突爆发后，像阿兰一样“到中国躲难”的缅北华人不在少数。在上千公里的边境线上，他们或入境中国，或进入中缅边境难民营救点，期待在这里感受片刻的和平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73514&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70316&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;瑞丽.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;中国云南德宏州瑞丽国门。出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行者便利地跨境互市。（李春华/图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258311&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中国云南德宏州瑞丽国门。出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行证便利地跨境互市。（李春华/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;亲历交战，&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;四面八方都有枪声&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月27日凌晨，原属缅甸政府军控制的清水河兄弟桥响起枪声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据缅甸民族民主同盟军旗下媒体“果敢民族之声”披露，当日上午，同盟军成功占领兄弟桥。随后的29日，缅甸清水河国门升起同盟军的军旗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星的家是一栋四层小楼，距离清水河兄弟桥只有百米远。这座桥横跨缅甸果敢清水河特区与缅甸佤邦南邓特区，同时靠近中国云南耿马县孟定口岸，是一处交通要道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星说，平日里桥上能看到缅甸政府军的士兵巡逻、把守，而桥对岸则是佤邦的地盘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73515&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70317&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;兄弟桥.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10月27日凌晨，缅北果敢清水河特区发生武装冲突。清水河兄弟桥正是交火点之一。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1974&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258312&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月27日凌晨，缅北果敢清水河特区发生武装冲突。清水河兄弟桥正是交火点之一。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不知道是怎么打起来的，反正四面八方都有枪声。”吴星和丈夫亲历了这场交火。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和丈夫被惊醒时大约是凌晨3点多。从窗户往外望去，外面天还是黑的。她觉得，这次枪炮声跟以前不一样，听声音威力比较大。他们躲在楼道处避险，一墙之外就是交火的地方，“当时桥上打得很凶，听到有人在惨叫”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴星家附近的住着二十多户在此务工的缅族人。随着天光渐亮、枪声渐弱，一些工人来到街上探路，结果被占领此地的武装士兵发现。“那里还有一伙老缅！”吴星听到有人喊了一声，随后密集的枪声突然再次响起，她的心再次悬了起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在这里，很多华人把缅族人称为&#39;老缅&#39;。”吴星看到，在武装士兵要求下，这些工人双手抱头、男女分开，检查是否携带武器。发现他们是老百姓之后，工人们被放行。“没有真的开枪打人，应该就是&#39;吓唬他们一下&#39;。”吴星说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天亮后，穿军装的士兵处挨家挨户叫门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来到吴星家门口时，她赶忙解释说自己是本地老百姓。“他们让人快点离开，说等下可能有缅军飞机会来轰炸。”吴星和丈夫马上以最快速度动身。“一人一套衣服，再带上一些现金。其它的什么都没带了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冲突发生前，听到风声的吴星就把女儿和母亲提前送到了孟定，而自己和丈夫则抱着侥幸心理留下。惊险过后，吴星不禁感慨：“真没想到还能活下来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，吴星和丈夫在佤邦南邓暂时安顿下来。这里离家很近，开车回去仅需要10分钟。接连数日，吴星白天开车回家，下午再返回南邓特区。她说，家里基本上没有受到破坏，院子里停放着一辆汽车、一辆摩托车。回去的时候都还在原地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有几家房子被炸毁了，但大部分还是好的。”说完之后，吴星又补充道，“不知道以后会不会再炸。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;边境避难，&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;道路一度拥堵&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月9日清晨6时许，淡白色的雾气笼罩着缅甸果敢125难民救助点。深蓝、浅绿色的防水帐篷在泥地上一字排开，不远处高高地立着黄色小楼。“这个地方原来是作为经济合作区设计的，但没有发展起来。现在就留下了一些烂尾楼。”救助点志愿者阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据阿伟介绍，125难民救助点设在果敢125工业园，占地超过百亩。缅北冲突发生后不久，就有超过2000人涌入救助点。摄于救助点的图片显示，很多儿童和老人住在室外的简易帐篷中。在黄泥地上铺上席子就是床。一些家庭在门口搭土灶台生火做饭，拿彩色的塑料矮凳当餐桌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“来得早的难民，可以住进室内的铁皮大棚，来得晚的，就只能到外面搭帐篷。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73517&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70319&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; img-title=&quot;难民4.png&quot; alt=&quot;缅甸果敢125难民救助点内，很多缅甸老百姓只随身携带了少量行李。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1434&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258313&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;缅甸果敢125难民救助点内，很多缅甸老百姓只随身携带了少量行李。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;救助点的物资是按户发放，每家可分到50斤一袋的大米，两三天发一袋。不过，这无法满足难民需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“果敢不像中国，这里每家每户平均4-5个孩子。”阿伟说，有一些家庭冒领物资，救助点管理人手有限，常常上当。“有人叫儿子领一次，爸爸又领一次。还有人领取后高价转卖给别人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“储存的大米基本上都没有了。”阿伟11月9日告诉南方周末记者，救助点的物资来自外地爱心人士捐赠、本地购买、从中国境内进口等。受当地冲突影响，从下缅甸到老街的路不通，包括粮食在内的救援物资无法运入，帐篷、大米等物资告急。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;救助站靠近中缅125界碑，与中国的南伞口岸仅有一墙之隔。很久一段时间里，这里是果敢边民进入中国的主要通道。“从果敢到中国，最便捷的地方就是南伞。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，南伞口岸位于中国云南临沧市镇康县南伞镇，这里距离果敢首府老街仅有约10公里。然而，当前中国南伞口岸出入境临时关闭，很多持有通行证的果敢人也无法通过口岸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月13日起，镇康当地发布公告，推动边民互市贸易正常化。据公布流程，当日起，镇康内边民、企业等可提前申报，并在口岸做好车辆、货物的接收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国国门开了之后，物资可以从中国进来，物资短缺的情况应该会有所改善。但缅甸人员依然无法从南伞口岸出入境，目前还是只通货，不过人。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了中国边境，与果敢相邻的佤邦，也成为不少缅甸百姓的避难选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73516&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70318&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/05c118ff2b.png&quot; img-title=&quot;难民.png&quot; alt=&quot;10·27缅北冲突爆发后，缅北佤邦南邓特区涌入了大批逃难的百姓。（受访者供图）&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1766&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/05c118ff2b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258314&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10·27缅北冲突爆发后，缅北佤邦南邓特区涌入了大批逃难的百姓。（受访者供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;龚先生老家在云南曲靖，目前在缅北佤邦、小勐拉一带做衣服批发生意。缅北冲突爆发后，他在佤邦南邓特区现场目睹了很多缅甸老百姓从战区涌入。他向南方周末记者展示的视频中，大量民众聚集在位于南邓的救援点，等待物资发放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“27日早上战事开打，27日下午就有很多人跑到南邓。”龚先生称，逃难的民众被安置在一处开阔的广场上，佤邦军士兵负责登记人员、维持秩序、免费发放物资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有条件的开车来，普通人骑摩托车、走路。可能因为事发突然，很多人都是两手空空。还有的人只披着一张毯子出门。”龚先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为逃难人员众多，从果敢战区逃亡临近佤邦道路一度拥堵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“果敢民族之声”11月7日消息，连日来，石园子至厂街路段至少有400余辆车，约五六百民众欲前往邻邦地区避难却被困其中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其发布的图文资料中，宽约三四米的水泥公路上，一条蜿蜒的“车龙”正驶向佤邦方向。心情急切的人推开车门，三三两两站在道路上，伸着脖子向“龙头”遥望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样迁移到佤邦的吴星感慨，“幸亏我们走得早，要不然也要被堵在路上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“以后要给爸妈办通行证”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阿兰兄弟姐妹8个，在家中排行老二。小时候，阿兰父亲烧炭养活一大家子，常年住在山上。阿兰和兄弟姐妹们就帮父亲拿炭、背炭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么防护措施都没有。比如你先进去，把炭一块块递出来。你顶不住了，就换我进去。”阿兰记得，从炭窑出来的时候，整个人被炭灰染黑，“连咳出来的痰都是黑的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为家穷，阿兰的书只念到小学，16岁起就到瑞丽打工。在她的家乡，很多同龄小姐妹选择到中国打工。相较于缅甸本国如仰光、内比都等大城市，瑞丽“距离近、工资更高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，阿兰是整个家里唯一一个有中缅边界通行证的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一次入境后可在瑞丽停留七天；七天后，她要回到缅甸木姐，完成一次出入境后，又可以停留七天。通过不断地“续签”通行证，阿兰无需办理流程更麻烦的护照就可以跨境往来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国瑞丽国门和缅甸木姐国门之间仅有数十米距离，途中可以看到中缅81号界碑。对于阿兰来说，这条路再熟悉不过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“先过了中国国门，去到缅甸（国门）盖个章。然后再过来中国（国门）盖个章，就办好了。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在瑞丽打工的日子里，一开始阿兰在中国人经营的饭店里当服务员。因为认识汉字、会说汉语，她的工资总比其他同来的缅甸老乡高一些。十几年来，她的工资从每月200涨到了每月2000元。挣来的钱大部分都补贴家里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着近年来直播平台兴起，阿兰开始在社交平台分享生活，同时做电商带货。每隔一段时间，她都要把产自缅甸的茶叶、蜂蜜、土特产等订单发往全国各地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多中国的哥哥姐姐们支持我，特别感谢他们。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出入境通道开放时，中缅边民可以凭借通行证便利地跨境互市。缅甸的大米、白糖、橡胶、牛肉、茶叶等农副产品由此销往内地，商人们从中赚取价差。缅甸的翡翠原石等矿藏也由此集散。对于中缅边民来说，这里代表着无限商机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，办好一张通行证大约要花十几万到50万缅币不等，合计人民币几百到一千元。由于家里经济比较困难，阿兰家一直没有额外再办证件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因战火滞留在老家，阿兰感到非常煎熬。睡觉的时候都在担心，枪炮会不会突然落在自己头上。直到返回瑞丽后，她才能放心睡个好觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次缅北冲突发生后，阿兰坚定了要给爸妈办证的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我正在想办法，这次花钱也要办。”阿兰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“哪一方都得罪不起”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在1983年制定的缅甸民族表中，果敢族被缅甸政府列入135个民族之一。特指生活在缅甸掸邦北部与中国云南省临沧市的镇康和耿马两县毗邻的果敢地区的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国缅甸研究学者王士录在《缅甸的“果敢族”:族称、来历、状况及跨国互动》一文中指出,“果敢族”的称谓从民族学上来讲是很不科学的,这些被称为“果敢族”的华侨、华人,事实上应当是缅甸华侨、华人中的“云南帮”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在民间，不少缅北华人习惯性称自己是“汉族人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今阿兰的老家里，依然看到熟悉的汉族习俗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，房屋大门门框上贴着红底金字的对联，中堂里赫然立着“天地君亲师”的牌位，台前供有香炉。阿兰说，每逢农历七月半、春节等，全家人还要摆上贡品，在这里庄重地跪拜、祈祷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兰的爷爷去世很早，奶奶告诉阿兰，他们祖籍在中国云南保山的龙陵县。对于祖籍龙陵，阿兰没去过，也没什么印象。她说，最想去的中国城市是北京，有朝一日想去看天安门。“我们读的都是中文书，从小读书时就很向往”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1948年，缅甸脱离英联邦正式独立后，国内几十股地方武装在边境地区与中央政府长期武装对抗，寻求独立。而北部中缅边界的果敢、佤邦、缅甸克钦邦第二特区和缅甸掸邦东部第四特区则分别由四股强势的武装力量掌控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很长一段时间里，缅甸中央政府并不能真正控制该地区。在多重矛盾下，缅北地方武装势力轮番主政、地区战事不断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，缅甸政府对缅北民族地方武装展开打击，地区控制力逐渐增强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年3月25日，果敢地区正式更名为“缅甸掸邦北部果敢自治区”。2015年3月26日，缅甸军方宣布控制整个果敢地区，对果敢地区采取了融入缅甸的政策，大力引入缅语教师，采用缅语教学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们从小读的是中文书、说的也是中国话。但我们又是缅甸人，要听缅甸政府的。”吴星说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅仅8年后，果敢地区再次响起炮火。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“果敢民族之声”11月13日消息，“10·27军事行动”开始18天以来，联军已攻占清水河、勐古、滚弄等城镇，夺回大小军事据点141个，缴获一批武器弹药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;频繁的战事、变换的地方政权，让民众对各方力量讳莫如深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“果敢地区三年打一小仗，五年打一次大仗。”阿伟不到50岁，已经历了四五次战争。他希望媒体报道难民救助点时能保持中立，因为“哪一方都得罪不起”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在我们这个地方，死一个人像踩死一只蚂蚁一样，如果你没有势力、没有朋友，你什么都不是。”阿伟说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;【掸邦概况】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;掸邦位于缅甸东部，北与中国云南省西双版纳接壤，东面与老挝和泰国相接壤，西面与克钦邦、克耶邦、克伦邦、曼德勒省、实皆省相连。掸邦是缅甸境内面积最大、人口最多的一个邦，首府在东枝市。历史上，来自中国云南的华人移民大量移入，在此逐渐形成缅北华人聚居区。掸邦南部有主张独立的武装力量存在，东部与泰、老交界地带即有名的金三角地区，北部与中国接壤，是缅甸境内果敢族（汉族）主要的聚居地。1986年至1989年，原属武装统辖地一分为四，成为缅甸掸邦第一特区（果敢）、缅甸掸邦第二特区（佤邦）、缅甸克钦邦第一特区、缅甸掸邦东部第四特区（勐拉）。近年来，华人新移民大量涌入，社会生态变得更复杂。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不清剿电诈决不收兵”，揭秘中国警方通缉的缅北电诈家族]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At noon on November 12, the Criminal Investigation Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security issued a notice to publicly arrest Ming Xuechang, an important leader of a fraud group in northern Myanmar. , Ming Guoping, Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen have attracted great attention from domestic and foreign public opinion. The reason why this news is attracting attention is related to Ming Xuechang’s identity. According to public reports, Ming Xuechang is an &quot;old leader&quot; of the Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar. He has held important positions in Kokang for a long time. He once served as the county magistrate of Kokang. In 2011, he was appointed as a member of the Shan State Parliament, Vice Chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region, and the Daily Working Committee and Leadership Committee of the Kokang Autonomous Region. committee member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258337&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; Also wanted by the police this time are Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen, all children of Ming Xuechang. The Ming family is huge in Kokang and is said to be second only to the four major Kokang families (one theory One of the four major families). In the past few days, news about the Ming family has continued to ferment. It has been circulated on the Internet that multiple people were shot and buried alive in Kokang on October 20. The location was located in the Crouching Mountain Manor area controlled by the Ming Xuechang family in Laojie, the capital of Kokang. At the same time, photos of Ming Xuechang’s grandson Ming Guangzhong receiving the admission notice from Peking University and many celebration pictures of Ming Xuechang and Ming Guangzhong at the university entrance banquet were circulated online. The Publicity Department of Peking University responded on the 13th that Ming Guangzhong was not a Peking University student, and there was no record of his application to Peking University on the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ming Xuechang and the Ming family behind him&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar borders Yunnan Province, with a population of about 140,000, mostly Han. Historically, it has a deep connection with China. In 2011, the Kokang Autonomous Region was formally established as part of Shan State and is now controlled by the Myanmar military junta. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the 69-year-old Ming Xuechang followed the Kokang warlord Peng Jiasheng to join the Communist Party of Myanmar in his early days and participated in the founding of the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army. After Myanmar’s internal affairs changed, he was appointed by the Myanmar military government as the head of Kokang County. In 2011, he served as a member of the Shan State Parliament, Vice Chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region, and a member of the Daily Work Committee and Leadership Committee of the Kokang Autonomous Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the Chinese Ministry of Public Security issued the wanted order, Ming Xuechang attended a local meeting to deal with telecommunications network fraud as a senior leader in the Kokang area. According to local media reports on October 26, “In order to further implement work requirements and strengthen the crackdown on various derivative illegal activities such as telecommunications fraud, the autonomous region held a special working meeting. Autonomous Region Chairman Li Zhengfu, committee members Lieutenant Colonel Jue Juewu, Bai Yingneng, Wu Musuodan, Sheriff Nulunwu, and heads of departments at all levels, security units, and township/community heads attended the meeting. In addition, veteran regional leaders Ming Xuechang, Zhao Deqiang, and Liu Zhengxiang attended the meeting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;This was also the last time Ming Xuechang appeared in public reports. According to the arrest warrant issued by the Ministry of Public Security of China, three people from the Ming family are also wanted this time. 42-year-old Ming Guoping is the son of Ming Xuechang and is the captain of the militia squadron of Shiyuanzi Township, Kokang Autonomous Region. Ming Julan, who is the same age as Ming Xuechang, is the daughter of Ming Xuechang. There is also a member of the Ming family, 27-year-old Ming Zhenzhen. Some media reported that she is Ming Xuechang&#39;s granddaughter. It is worth mentioning that the registered residences of Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen are both in Lincang, Yunnan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;592&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258336&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ming Xuechang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Kokang area, the Ming family is very powerful. Local media in Myanmar reported that Ming Xuechang is One of the richest men in the area, the Ming family has close ties with the four major families. Kokang is known as the four major families, referring to the Bai Suocheng family, Wei Chaoren family, Liu Guoxi family and Liu Abao family. The Ming family is considered a &quot;rising star&quot;. Media reports stated that the mining, casino, and real estate operations in Kokang Old Street are all controlled by four major families, and the four major families are also the backers of electronic fraud groups in the Kokang area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The arrest warrant issued by the Ministry of Public Security of China directly pointed out that the criminal group headed by Ming Xuechang has long organized and opened fraud dens, openly armed fraud, and carried out telecommunications network fraud criminal activities targeting Chinese citizens. The amount of fraud was Huge, and also suspected of multiple serious violent crimes such as intentional homicide, intentional injury, and illegal detention. The notice urged him to recognize the situation clearly, step back from the brink, voluntarily surrender, and strive for leniency. The police wanted order also stated that a reward of 100,000 to 500,000 yuan will be given to those who provide effective clues and assist in the arrest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just after the wanted order was issued, it was circulated on the Internet that multiple people were shot and buried alive in Kokang on October 20. The location was located in the Crouching Mountain Manor area controlled by the Ming Xuechang family in Laojie, the capital of Kokang. At the same time, the confession clips of many arrested telecom fraud leaders have attracted attention on the Internet, including Wei Qingtao, the second son of the Wei family, a member of the four major Kokang families, Liu Zhengqi, Liu Abao&#39;s brother, and Bi Huijun, the son-in-law of Ming Xuechang, who all went abroad to confess and urged their families to voluntarily surrender. , saying that China “will never withdraw its troops until it eliminates telecommunications fraud.” The Information Bureau of Myanmar&#39;s Wa State responded to media reporters on the 13th and stated that the above three people were indeed members of electronic fraud and were currently under the control of judicial agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The civil war broke out in northern Myanmar and the situation was tense. The Myanmar authorities promised to completely eliminate e-mail fraud by the end of the year&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, some ethnic Chinese minorities in northern Myanmar Ethnic armed forces are fighting the military junta, and the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said that at least 6,000 people have been displaced since the conflict broke out on October 27. The leader of the Chinese ethnic minority armed forces, Peng Deren, is the son of Peng Jiasheng. He claimed that the war was to eliminate telecommunications network fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said that China is highly concerned about the conflict situation in northern Myanmar and urges all parties to immediately cease fire and end the war. &quot;Insist on resolving differences through dialogue and consultation through peaceful means to avoid escalation of the situation, and Take practical and effective measures to ensure the security and stability of the China-Myanmar border.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video circulated on the Internet, Wei Qingtao, the second son of the Wei family of the four major families, also said in his confession that war is currently breaking out in Myanmar and may cause disaster at any time. He suffered serious casualties and urged his family to seize the last opportunity to open the park and return the Chinese people in the park to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News, since February 2021, domestic tensions in Myanmar have intensified, providing more opportunities for telecom fraud groups to settle in northern and eastern Myanmar and form a &quot;community of interests&quot; with local forces. space. In Myawaddy on the Myanmar-Thailand border alone, there are hundreds of fraud parks. Including fraud groups entrenched in parts of northern Myanmar, there are at least 1,000 parks in total, and more than 100,000 people commit telecom fraud every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The areas where telecom fraud groups gather in northern and eastern Myanmar are only a very small part of Myanmar’s land area, and are mostly areas controlled by ethnic minority local armed forces. However, they have dealt a fatal blow to Myanmar’s national image. &quot;CCTV reported this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the Chinese government has continuously increased cooperation and carried out joint law enforcement operations with Myanmar, Thailand and other countries to severely crack down on telecommunications network fraud in accordance with the law. Especially since this year, China has been even more aggressive. Recently, the police of China, Thailand, Myanmar and Laos launched a special joint operation to combat gambling fraud groups, aiming to severely crack down on telecommunications network fraud and online gambling crimes in the region, and resolutely reverse the high incidence of human trafficking, kidnapping, detention and other crimes. According to incomplete statistics, since September this year, many batches of telecom fraudsters have been escorted back to China from Myanmar, Cambodia and other overseas countries. On October 14, 2,349 telecom fraudsters were transferred from Myanmar to China, setting a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the war broke out, on October 31, Min Aung Hlaing, Chairman of the National Governing Council of Myanmar, met with State Councilor and Minister of Public Security Wang Xiaohong in Nay Pyi Taw. Wang Xiaohong mentioned that the law enforcement and security departments of the two countries will strengthen cooperation in the fields of combating online gambling fraud, counter-terrorism, drug control, law enforcement in the Mekong River Basin, and the security of major projects, so as to safeguard the security and development interests of the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that this series of actions demonstrates China’s determination to crack down on telecommunications network fraud. Recently, Zaw Min Tun, spokesperson of the Myanmar National Governing Council, also stated that the Myanmar authorities are determined to completely eliminate online gambling and online fraud in northern Myanmar by the end of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>