<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[六名中国公民被绑架杀害？海外华人华侨要团结以自保]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 11, 2023, the Philippine police discovered multiple tools in succession near a construction site in Laihu Bay. The remains are suspected by the police to be the six Chinese citizens who were kidnapped on October 30: including Mr. Zeng and his wife who are presidents of local Chinese charity organizations in the Philippines, brother Zeng and his wife, and brother Zeng’s teenage son. son, and one person remains unidentified. On November 28, the Philippine police confirmed the identities of four corpses, including Mr. Zeng’s two brothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, vicious cases involving overseas Chinese have occurred in some overseas countries: In May 2023, a Chinese couple died naked in a Bali hotel; in 2023, a Chinese student was murdered in Thailand on &quot;3·31&quot;... …In addition to these brutal cases, the criminal system of the warlords in northern Myanmar is basically tailor-made for the Chinese people. The number of Chinese people they have killed and the seriousness of their crimes are really too numerous to describe. Recently, the &quot;Ming Family&quot; in northern Myanmar, which specializes in telecommunications fraud, has reached the end of its rope and is about to be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the country&#39;s economic development, foreign economic, trade and cultural exchanges have increased, and Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Opportunities are always accompanied by challenges, and contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure one&#39;s personal and property safety, as well as legal rights, has become increasingly important. Examples of self-security and collective security for overseas Chinese can be found in the Korean community living in North America and the Jewish community scattered around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea has a small population, and even fewer people live in the world. However, a small number of Korean immigrants (mainly immigrants from South Korea) became a bright spot in the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; in 1992: After the U.S. police temporarily gave up protecting communities of color, a small number of Korean immigrants united and armed themselves for self-defense , took up arms to defend the community, resisting the onslaught of thugs, and held on until the National Guard entered the city to quell the violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For decades, Koreans have deeply felt the importance of external unity. Their overseas immigrants have strengthened internal unity, taking advantage of North American citizens&#39; gun-carrying laws to arm themselves for self-defense and strengthen their martial spirit. Therefore, even though the 1.65 million Korean immigrants only account for 0.5% of the U.S. population, North American residents know that Koreans are not easy to mess with and they dare to use guns in critical moments. Therefore, the thugs of the &quot;Los Angeles Riots&quot; were unable to capture the strongholds held by Korean armed forces, so they looted Chinese stores because the Chinese generally lacked the ability to defend themselves at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before World War II, the Jewish community was known for being disunited, disorganized, shrewd and philanthropic, and gentle and cowardly. It is said that there are 12 branches of Judaism since ancient times. There are so many factions and small groups below. The Jews who run banks are greedy for money and are unwilling to help others. Therefore, few people are willing to help them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to better integrate into European society, the Jews not only accepted many Western living habits, but also tried to avoid confrontation when they had conflicts with the indigenous peoples. Therefore, various European ethnic groups have long scorned the military value of the Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During World War II, the Holocaust in Nazi Germany nearly annihilated European Jewry, which changed the spirit, character, and psychology of some Jews. After the war, some Jews reached several consensuses:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, they must build their own country and make it strong, rather than just being nomads in the world. When conflicts involving the Jewish community occur again, it cannot only rely on money, but also on the state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it is still necessary to maintain the simultaneous existence of Jews in various parts of the world to spread the risks of survival in case one country is defeated and the entire race is annihilated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, money alone is not enough. To survive, you must have the ability to defend yourself. The two words &quot;wealth and strength&quot; are indispensable. If we are not rich, we cannot afford advanced weapons and equipment and cannot build a strong army, so we cannot be strong; if we are not strong, we cannot maintain wealth for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, Jews have self-defense groups in many communities around the world. Especially in North America, we make full use of local laws and policies to conduct paramilitary training and have a considerable number of foreign reserve soldiers. On October 7, 2023, just hours after the war in Gaza broke out, a large number of Jewish young people from North America and Australia flew to Israel to join the war, with a total number of tens of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through arduous efforts, the Jews have changed to a certain extent the customs of their ethnic group, which were previously fragmented, fighting among themselves, and trying to undermine each other (but there is still a clear distinction between their modern factions and the &quot;ultra-Orthodox&quot;). It not only engages in &quot;hiding troops among the people&quot; around the world, but also forms an underground intelligence network connecting the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, Israel is a miniature country with a population of only a few million, and its intelligence agency &quot;Mossad&quot; does not have sufficient funds (like the CIA). Especially in the early stages of construction and development, it can be said that there is little money to be had, and even poverty can lead to poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1960, the Nazi war criminal Eichmann was captured; in the 1970s, the &quot;Black September&quot; terrorist organization was hunted around the world. &quot;Mossad&quot; can only send out a small range of troops, and the budget is tight. Each person only has a few dollars per day for food, and cannot afford to live in a hotel or buy a car. They move around the world and live in old houses provided by local Jews. Some of them don&#39;t even have beds and can only make beds on the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With that little activity fund, not only can’t I afford a restaurant, I can’t even afford takeout. I had no choice but to give the money to the local Jewish contacts, who would buy ingredients from the mall on their behalf and cook the food themselves. It is simply impossible for a &quot;Mossad&quot; agent to drive an Aston Martin sports car as elegantly as in spy movies. The vehicles used in many operations were all old cars borrowed from local Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the grass-roots teams in the early days when Koreans and Jews established their own power networks in the world, the number of Chinese people and wealth they have around the world is really much stronger. But it is a pity that Chinese expatriates with huge wealth cannot even effectively protect their personal safety and property safety. Malicious anti-Chinese and crimes against Chinese expatriates occur frequently around the world. As for the large number of violent crimes against Chinese people mentioned above, many Chinese gangsters were involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is really regrettable and heartbreaking. The reason is that there is still internal strife among overseas Chinese and there is serious internal friction in their strength. Some Chinese friends in North America vividly told me how they tried to undermine each other in business, criticized each other culturally, and even colluded with &quot;Ghost Cap&quot; (foreign police) to punish each other. The speaker was very excited, beaming, and dancing. When he was excited, his saliva sprayed into my face. This is really heartbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, Chinese people at home and abroad have more and more interactions with the world. Contradictions, conflicts, and dangers are everywhere. How to ensure their personal and property safety, as well as their legal rights, has become increasingly difficult. The more important it is. The basis of all this is first of all the unity of the ethnic group. In this regard, we should really think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[甘肃酒泉市肃北县发生5.0级地震]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:17:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China Seismological Network officially determined: December 01, 22:55 in Subei County, Jiuquan City, Gansu Province ( A magnitude 5.0 earthquake occurred at 39.30 degrees north latitude and 97.27 degrees east longitude, with a focal depth of 9 kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height= &quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/1025/process/3ec8970a6e864b58b291bb70ede4aeb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1701443803135-0&quot; data-mce-width =&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔚来“朋友圈”再扩容，车企为何统一换电？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261667]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 battery swap stations around the world .Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/c93d06ff6e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of November 28, 2023, NIO has built 2,184 power swap stations around the world. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Following Changan Automobile (000625.SZ), NIO (09866.HK, NYSE:NIO) has made another success with its battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023, Zhejiang Geely Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Geely Holding) and NIO officially signed a strategic cooperation agreement on battery swapping in Hangzhou. The two parties will work on battery swapping standards and battery swapping technology. , carry out comprehensive cooperation in various fields such as battery swap service network construction and operation, battery swap model R&amp;D and customization, battery asset management and operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the agreement, in the future, the two parties will create two major battery swap standard systems for &quot;private cars&quot; and &quot;commercial vehicles&quot; through the &quot;co-investment, co-construction, sharing, and co-operation&quot; model to promote vehicle-end , station end, battery end, and operation end are connected and coordinated to expand the scale of the battery swap network to meet users with different needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, NIO founder Li Bin revealed in an internal speech to all employees that in addition to Changan Automobile, there are 4-5 potential partners currently being negotiated. In other words, more car companies may join NIO&#39;s &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei, the expert committee of the China Automobile Dealers Association, told Southern Weekend reporters that the expansion of the &quot;circle of friends&quot; for battery swapping has a strategic significance higher than the practical level, and it will have a limited effect on improving their respective revenue in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the initial cooperation between the parties is exploratory and may start with operating vehicles such as online ride-hailing. &quot;If the results are good, it may be upgraded to more important models or high-value models.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are only two roads in front of you&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news &quot;NIO lost 76.4 billion in five and a half years&quot; appeared on Weibo&#39;s hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2018 to 2022, NIO’s net profits attributable to the parent company were -23.328 billion yuan, -11.413 billion yuan, -5.611 billion yuan, -10.572 billion yuan and -14.559 billion yuan respectively. In the first half of 2023, NIO&#39;s net profit attributable to its parent company continued to suffer a loss of 10.926 billion yuan, with a cumulative loss of 76.4 billion yuan in 5.5 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although at the recent Guangzhou Automobile Industry Development Conference, NIO co-founder and president Qin Lihong emphasized that &quot;NIO will never go bankrupt, and it is impossible for it to go bankrupt.&quot; But it is undeniable that Weilai has invested too much in “peripheral products” and its sales have declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Li Bin’s internal speech to all employees was also on the hot search. He said that the road to battery replacement is very difficult, but it is difficult and the right thing to do. &quot;Everyone thinks of battery replacement as Amazon doing cloud services in 2003, as well as Alibaba, Tencent, Microsoft, etc. They have suffered losses for many years. Only then did we finally achieve success.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NIO and NIO’s battery swap are always accompanied by controversy. The construction of a service system with power exchange as the core is regarded as the main reason for NIO&#39;s losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, NIO will deploy a total of 2,300 power swap stations in 2023. As of November 28, NIO has built 2,184 power stations around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the cost of each generation of NIO&#39;s three generations of power swap stations is slightly different, if based on a rough calculation of the 3 million yuan cost of each power swap station stated by Qin Lihong at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show, NIO&#39;s power swap performance will be The cumulative investment has exceeded 6.5 billion yuan. This does not include additional expenses such as venue rental, personnel operations and electricity expenses. Based on NIO’s goal of adding 1,000 battery swap stations in 2023, the cost of building the stations alone will be as high as 3 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Fei, NIO’s vice president in charge of NIO Power, revealed at a press conference in March that the battery swap station had to serve 50-60 orders per day to achieve breakeven. At that time, NIO’s battery swap station averaged 35 orders per day. -36 orders. The implication is that Weilai is still in the loss-making stage when it comes to battery replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei believes that NIO positions itself as a luxury brand and provides services such as battery replacement and user rights to make up for the lack of product and brand power. It has indeed played a very good role in brand building in the early stage. However, as investment increased, its sales volume did not increase significantly, but instead became a huge burden. &quot;Keeping it has limited use, just throw it away. It&#39;s a pity.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only two ways in front of Weilai, either to sell more cars and dilute the power exchange network construction from within. or introduce more car companies to participate in NIO’s power swap network to create a scale effect and alleviate financial difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Weilai has already had clues about opening up the battery swap business. At the China Electric Vehicles 100 People Forum held in April 2023, Li Bin said that &quot;the battery swap service has reached the stage where it can be exported to the outside world.&quot; He hoped that other companies can share and build charging and swap infrastructure with NIO, and revealed that there are already Car companies are discussing this matter with NIO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu, honorary chairman of the Society of Automotive Engineers of China, told Southern Weekend reporters that as the current battery swap model has not yet found a profit model, there are only more battery swap stations and a more convenient energy replenishment experience. Only then can more users be willing to buy battery-exchange models, thus forming a positive cycle. NIO&#39;s cooperation with Geely, Changan and other automobile manufacturers will help promote the battery swap model on a larger scale, improve the overall operating efficiency of the battery swap model, and may solve the commercialization problem of battery swap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Or start from online car-hailing services&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The battery swap model laid out by NIO does have many advantages. For example, it only takes less than 5 minutes for car owners to replace the battery at the battery swap station. However, the disadvantage is that the battery swap model still faces problems such as high website construction costs, uncertain commercialization models, and inconsistent industry standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, there are several companies on the market that are trying to lay out the power swap model, but the construction of power swap stations is independent of each other. Since 2020, relevant national departments have continued to promote the formulation of standards for battery swap stations and battery packs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 World Power Battery Conference, Xin Guobin, Vice Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, revealed an important signal. Currently, a battery replacement technology standard system is being studied and compiled to promote battery replacement battery size, battery replacement interface, Standards such as communication protocols are unified. At the same time, relevant departments have also entered into the inspection process for the national battery replacement station standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Yuwu believes that each car company has different models and batteries. In the context of cooperation, battery swapping may require a transition period to improve the versatility of the battery swapping network. &quot;However, it can force companies to make better efforts in standardization, which is of key significance to the structural adjustment of the battery swap model.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some people question that unified battery swap operation management may affect Wei Come to the battery swapping experience of existing users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike NIO’s battery swap model, most car companies are betting on high-voltage fast charging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 800V high-voltage fast charging platform is currently regarded as the most likely technology path. In 2019, Porsche launched the Taycan, the world&#39;s first 800V high-voltage platform model. Automobile manufacturers such as BYD, Xpeng, Great Wall, Geely Jikrypton, etc. have all begun relevant layouts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the long term, 800V will be an opportunity to reshape the battery industry,” Li Bin said at the 2023 Shanghai Auto Show. “But no company has yet been able to reduce the cost of 800V to close to that of the current 400V. or a slightly higher level.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei also believes that high-voltage charging costs are high and is currently mainly used in relatively high-end models. It is unlikely that the technology will be transferred to low-end models in the short term. In addition, the layout of high-voltage charging piles is still imperfect, and an absolute advantage over the battery swap model has not yet been established in the short term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Liu Jinliang, CEO of Yiyi Internet Technology Co., Ltd., signed the power exchange cooperation with NIO on behalf of Geely Yifang this time. He has led Geely&#39;s travel business in recent years, and has been responsible for Caocao Private Car, Yao Travel and other sectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yanwei said that online car-hailing may be the first area of ​​cooperation between the two parties. Due to cost control, operating vehicles such as taxis and online ride-hailing vehicles mostly use lithium iron phosphate batteries. The batteries are used frequently, so the demand for battery replacement will be higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海底捞“科目三”爆火，有创意还是“辣眼睛”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chatting is not as good as dancing. Making oneself feel comfortable is everyone&#39;s talent...&quot; In Haidilao, watch Dancing seems to be more important than chatting and eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Haidilao has made a splash again with the launch of the &quot;&lt;strong>;Subject 3&lt;/strong>;&quot; dance service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;Subject Three&quot; is not the &quot;Subject Three&quot; of the driver&#39;s license assessment, but a dance that mainly consists of waving hands, twisting hips and half-crotch feet. The music above, the magical dance steps, and the exciting scenes have made the business of many Haidilao stores become booming. Some customers enjoy it: &quot;The fatigue of the day is healed here&quot; &quot;Haidilao can cure social fear&quot; &quot; The boys are so handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &lt;strong>;&quot;Dance&quot; must be reversed&lt;/strong>;, and Haidilao&#39;s &quot;Subject Three&quot; has also caused a lot of controversy. Some customers complained that &quot;the dancing is tacky and noisy&quot; and &quot;it feels uncomfortable to bring children here to eat.&quot; Accompanying the controversy are the feelings of Haidilao employees themselves: “There is no reward commission”, “It’s hard to refuse customers’ requests”, “It’s really embarrassing inside”, “It’s meaningless”, and even a young man from a store in Changxing County, Zhejiang&lt; strong>;I was admitted to the hospital with a bone bruise due to skipping &quot;Subject Three&quot;&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating with atmosphere, singing and dancing to entertain is not Haidilao’s exclusive program. For example, Chongqing Hot Pot Factory is called “Sheniu Hot Pot Restaurant” by customers. Behind the &quot;local flavor social shake&quot;, &quot;fancy decoration&quot; and &quot;grandstanding&quot; is the fierce competition in the catering industry. While trying to acquire customers at a low cost, they also want to speed up breaking out of the circle. However, no matter what, service comes first, and the core of a restaurant should be Still taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Under the sea &quot;Subject Three&quot; became a hit, what do you think? Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数据安全榜：谁在尽心倾力守护您的金融隐私？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:07:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In today’s digital age, financial privacy security is greatly testing everyone’s A financial institution also affects everyone&#39;s most sensitive nerves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But accidental events often produce extraordinary panic and associations. In November 2023, some financial institutions experienced successive risk incidents at home and abroad, and even encountered hackers, and their core data was leaked or hijacked. The incident triggered deep thinking in the financial and technological circles: How can we do our best to protect users’ financial privacy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, regulators attach great importance to the security of national financial data and personal financial information, and have successively introduced a series of regulatory specifications aimed at establishing a system that covers all financial data. Life cycle safety management system mechanism. Among them, the protection of personal financial information has become an important part of the security management of financial data life cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively evaluate the data security strength of the banking and life insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a survey on 20 systemically important commercial banks and 9 mainstream life insurance companies. Conduct systematic evaluation. Consistent with the construction logic of the indicator evaluation system of the wealth management list, green finance list, and digital finance list, the quantitative and qualitative indicators of the data security list account for 70% of the weight, and external expert review and media factors each account for 15% of the weight. In view of the differences in relevant information disclosure rules and actual disclosure situations between banks and insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed quantitative and qualitative indicator systems for data security in the banking and life insurance industries based on the key disclosure points of each bank and insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the strict data security standards of each bank and insurance institution under evaluation, and the rare data security accidents so far, this list focuses on the above-mentioned bancassurance institutions’ The strategic importance of data security, the transparency of information disclosure and the effectiveness of data security work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bank ranking indicator system: the most important performance in four dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banking industry data security ranking The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the evaluation indicator system are divided into four dimensions: organizational construction, institutional processes, technical tools and effectiveness, and include five secondary indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1151&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the banking industry data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Organizational construction&lt;/strong>; refers to the organizational structure of commercial banks in terms of data security. The research team of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center considered the number of relevant responsible departments disclosed by commercial banks. The weight of this indicator accounts for 10%, reflecting the importance commercial banks attach to data security and information protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;System process&lt;/strong>; refers to the degree of standardization of the process of building a data security system for commercial banks. Standardized institutional processes are an important cornerstone and guarantee for commercial banks to build data security systems. Under this dimension, we mainly examine the number of relevant systems and normative documents on data security of commercial banks, divided into two secondary indicators: the number of its own relevant systems and the number of normative documents related to supplier management, with a total weight of 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among them, supplier management refers to when a commercial bank collects, transmits, stores, filters, analyzes, exchanges, and shares all data belonging to the bank. , a management mechanism for effective risk identification, assessment and effective control of relevant external partners. At present, most commercial banks do not pay enough attention to data security when conducting annual reviews of various suppliers. For suppliers who have access to sensitive bank data, once the supplier has security vulnerabilities or misbehaves, it is likely that the information security and data security of commercial banks will be threatened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to encourage commercial banks to pay more attention to the management of suppliers in terms of data security, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has disclosed the relevant supplier management systems disclosed by commercial banks. The number of documents is included in the indicator system, accounting for 10% of the weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Technical tools&lt;/strong>; are a core part of the network security system. This indicator directly reflects the commercial bank&#39;s ability to protect data and privacy and the effectiveness and reliability of data security protection. In view of the fact that the research and evaluation of relevant technical tools in the data industry has been very systematic, we use the number of certification systems disclosed by each commercial bank to determine the bank&#39;s technical strength in data security. The weight of this indicator is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Performance indicators&lt;/strong>; account for 30% of the weight, which is the largest single indicator dimension and the only qualitative indicator to fully reflect the Results-oriented data security ranking evaluation logic. This indicator has a significant impact on the data security evaluation results of commercial banks. For commercial banks that have information security incidents, customer personal information leaks, major IT system failures and other incidents in 2023, we will warn the relevant commercial banks by reducing their scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It needs to be emphasized that in order to encourage commercial banks to increase the transparency of information disclosure in the field of data security and reduce information asymmetry, we have not disclosed relevant information for some banks. In the case of indicator data, the relevant indicator will be given the lowest score. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Data Security&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Big banks dominate the top three&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank data security list shows that Agricultural Bank of China ranks first, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. . The comprehensive scores of the three major banks all exceed 70 points, showing significant advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China has obtained 51 various certifications related to data security, far more than any other bank. The bank was the first among major state-owned banks to issue the &quot;Data Security Management Measures (Trial)&quot; and established a comprehensive data security management system based on this. At the same time, the bank adheres to the &quot;minimum necessary&quot; principle, conducts mining and applications within the scope and authority of reasonable use of data, and encrypts sensitive customer information to maximize data security and privacy and avoid leakage and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking of Banks (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2273&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among joint-stock banks, Ping An Bank and China Merchants Bank ranked fourth and fifth respectively on the list, performing relatively well. Ping An Bank insists on using safe and available tools and technologies for data integration, including using security umbrella technology to automatically desensitize data and automatically protect sensitive groups, and ensure the independence and security of analysis scenarios through data safe houses. The bank&#39;s credit cards use a self-developed privacy computing platform to accurately identify external and debit card customers, effectively reducing customer acquisition costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance ranking indicator system:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Three dimensions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;7&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Sub-indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance is a typical data-intensive industry, with a large amount of personal information, market information and transaction information. Regulators attach great importance to data security in the life insurance industry. Since 2023, regulatory agencies have issued regulatory documents such as the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Consumer Rights Protection in Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Network and Data Security Management in Third-Party Cooperation&quot;, requiring life insurance institutions to establish a consumer personal information protection mechanism. And carry out self-examination and rectification of data risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How is the performance of life insurance institutions? Based on public information such as financial reports, ESG or CSR reports, official announcements, and public reports disclosed by the nine life insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a quantitative analysis of the nine life insurance companies from the three dimensions of data security, internal governance, and external review. and qualitative evaluation, and set up 7 sub-indicators, each with a weight of 10%, and the total weight of quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center integrated expert review scores and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) to build a life insurance data security ranking indicator system . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of data security ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1379&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Life Insurance Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the data security dimension, the emphasis on data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by the number of times &quot;data security&quot; or &quot;data privacy&quot; is mentioned in ESG reports, and the effectiveness of data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by whether major information security incidents occurred in the past year. . The judgment of this indicator is based on the description of major information security events in the annual report or ESG report. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the internal governance dimension, life insurance institutions are qualitatively evaluated based on three indicators: whether to set up an independent data security department, whether to formulate a data security protection system, and whether to conduct an annual information security review. Implementation of internal data security work. The total weight of the above three indicators accounts for 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The external review dimension qualitatively evaluates the acceptance of life insurance institutions in the professional field of data security based on two indicators: whether the App has violated user privacy issues and whether it has obtained ISO/IEC27001 certification. Level of recognition. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Insurance ranking: China Life wins the championship, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;AIA Taikang ranks among the top three&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance data security list shows that China Life leads AIA Life to take the first place with an advantage of 1.59 points, and AIA Life ranks second. The comprehensive scores of both life insurance companies exceeded 80 points, 8 points ahead of the third place Taikang Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1186&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Looking at the scores of quantitative and qualitative indicators, China Life, China Pacific Insurance, AIA Life and Taikang Life all scored over 60. This shows that they perform better overall in multiple dimensions such as data security, internal governance and external review. In the end, China Life won the championship due to its high scores in both external judges&#39; scores and media factor scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life proposed a comprehensive &quot;Technology China Life&quot; strategy as early as 2012, and has continued to increase investment in data security for 11 years. As one of the first batch of pilot financial institutions, China Life took the lead in the industry to migrate and put into production the Xinchuang database of key business systems, achieve 100% distributed architecture transformation of key business systems, and successfully build a new self-controlled distributed cloud architecture digital base. The company also proposed and built the first data center in the domestic life insurance industry and a high-standard underground computer room that obtained T4 certification. In addition, the company has also successfully developed a safe, green and elastic China Life Hybrid Cloud using internal private cloud and external public cloud resources, which integrates computing, storage and containers to significantly improve data security and computing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also found that although the life insurance institutions at the bottom have not yet experienced major information security incidents, they have shortcomings in internal governance and external review obvious. For example, 4 institutions under evaluation did not set up independent data security departments, 2 institutions did not conduct annual information security audits, and the apps of 3 institutions were accused of infringing on user privacy, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that life insurance institutions at the bottom of the list urgently need to pay more attention to the construction and improvement of data security systems, and at the same time adopt more stringent and transparent policies. In the face of public concerns, the public&#39;s information disclosure standards should be strengthened through practical and effective measures to enhance public trust in the data security of life insurance institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的多重面孔：一轮夜空悬，千片秋江月]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261635]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In history, there are few Chinese poets like Li Bai. It attracted much attention during the era in which he lived. Topics, legends, and stories about him were widely circulated when he was alive, and they did not decrease with his death, but became more abundant and mysterious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A scholar did not take the imperial examination, but was recruited to the Jinluan Palace; a commoner did not have the merits of building a large scale, but was favored by the emperor; a person who intended to clarify the troubled times, He was killed by Changliu Yelang; a man who once scattered more than 300,000 yuan a year ended up with nothing in his later years; a poet fought with people in Chang&#39;an City; a Hanlin scholar who was waiting for an imperial edict, drank freely with his craftsmen; A man with lofty ideals who is &quot;willing to serve as the Prime Minister&quot; is keen on refining elixirs and collecting herbs; a madman who looks down on the powerful is excited when facing the common people&#39;s wild rice...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Faced with this prototype that combines many contradictions, people are puzzled and determined to &quot;understand&quot; him. People not only want to understand him, but also &quot;use&quot; him, either to support themselves, to self-explain, to self-comfort, to self-liberate, or to use the past to satirize the present, or to make use of topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does Taibai look like? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No photos or videos can answer the question of Li Bai&#39;s true face. For guessing about Li Bai&#39;s appearance, we can only rely on sporadic descriptions in historical materials and the poet&#39;s autobiography to seek clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The senior poet He Zhizhang exclaimed that Li Bai was &quot;relegated to a fairy&quot; when he first met him. Taoist master Sima Chengzhen commented on Li Bai that &quot;the Jun family has immortal Taoist bones, which can travel with the gods to the eight extremes&quot;. There are many documents written about Li Bai&#39;s contemporaries like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed in &quot;Books with Han Jingzhou&quot;: &quot;Although the body is less than seven feet, his ambition is ten thousand.&quot; The ancients said that tall people are like Zhuge Liang and others are all &quot;eight feet long&quot;, and the seven-foot-long man is only of average height. Even though Li Bai was majestic and magnificent, he was not tall and mighty. He should be a small man. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s fanboy Wei Hao described Li Bai in the preface to &quot;The Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; as having &quot;bright eyes, trembling like a hungry tiger, sometimes belted, The romance is brewing.&quot; His friend Cui Zongzhi&#39;s poem &quot;Gift to Li Twelve Bai&quot; also described Li Bai&#39;s &quot;eyes that illuminate people&quot;. It can be seen that Li Bai&#39;s eyes are indeed bright and special. Li Bai calls himself a &quot;savage&quot;, and the &quot;hungry tiger&quot; is seeing his state of breaking through the restraints, which is in sharp contrast with the &quot;or time belt&quot; below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Tang Dynasty, there have been many portraits of Li Bai left. Although Li Bai&#39;s true appearance has disappeared with history, some characteristics of Li Bai&#39;s image can be directly appreciated from the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the poems of Song Dynasty poets Rao Jie and Chen Shidao, we can know that the Tang Dynasty painter Zhou Fang once painted the image of Li Bai. In Zhou Fang&#39;s writings, Li Bai is a scholar wearing a black gauze hat and a white silk robe, which is highly consistent with the dress of most scholars in ancient times. Wusha was originally a skullcap commonly worn by the people, but it was not until the Ming Dynasty that it became an official hat. The white silk robe, made of white ramie, became the mainstream of fashion in the mid-Tang Dynasty, and people even became obsessed with this kind of clothing. Li Bai&#39;s own description is different from the image in the painting: &quot;The grass is wrapped in black scarves, and the purple Qi Qiu.&quot; He said that he often wore &quot;Ziqi Qiu&quot;, unlike the &quot;white robe robe in Zhou Yan &quot;. However, among many paintings that portray Li Bai&#39;s image in later generations, most painters have chosen the characteristics of &quot;Wu Sa Bai Yan&quot;. It can be said that Zhou Yan&#39;s &quot;photo&quot; to Li Bai has become the &quot;sample&quot; of Li Bai&#39;s image created by later generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The monument corridor of the Sichuan Jiangyou Li Bai Memorial Hall, with the &quot;Kuangshan Taibai Stele&quot; and &quot;Li Bai Xiang Stele&quot; painted by the famous Northern Song Dynasty painter Li Gonglin. The former painted Li Bai, a cloth, a bamboo stick when he was studying in the mountains, and he was in full swing. After that, many young Li Bai&#39;s image originated here. The latter&#39;s prosperity Li Bai opened his face round, his ear beads were thick, his expression was realized, and he was happy and peaceful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Tai Bai Xing Yin Map&quot; is the most representative Li Bai image painting, which is the painter Liang Kai hand in the Southern Song Dynasty. Liang Kai has the willfulness and unrestrained personality of &quot;Golden Belt Hanging Wall, Leaving the Office&quot;, and his preference for wine, which can be described as Li Bai. In the painting, Li Bai is wearing a wide clothes similar to the robe. The bun described by Jiao Mo is slightly leaning backwards, which seems to be expected to chant the poem. Almost in one go. Modern painter Zhang Daqian has painted many Li Bai, and most of them are based on the form in the form of Liang Kai&#39;s &quot;Li Baixing Yin Map&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28db5ac1.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 2874 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28F6db5ac1.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 260278 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The &quot;Li Baixing Yin Map&quot; of the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai is now hidden in the Tokyo National Museum. Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Qing dynasty painter Su Liupeng used the &quot;Taibai Drunk Map&quot; to express his spirit. In the painting, Li Bai is supported by two insiders. Internal servants&#39; clothing is dark, her eyes are beautiful, and their gestures are hidden. Li Bai wore a bachelor&#39;s scarf, wearing a white bachelor&#39;s clothes, cinnabar boots and belts. The color tone was fast, with a nobleness; This portrait is reminiscent of Li Bai who &quot;tastes the drunk temple and leads Gaolishi to take off the boots&quot;, revealing all the free and elaboration of the emptiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 2376 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260279 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The &quot;Too Drunk Map&quot; of the Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng is now hidden in the Shanghai Museum. Data diagrams &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is said that in the Ming and Qing database houses of the Forbidden City in Beijing, there are more people in the Nanxun Hall, including Li Bai and Du Fu&#39;s statues. These figures do not know where to paint. The people in the painting are far from the inherent impression. Du Fu also sees the image of dry and thin, but a black fat man. Although Li Bai looks fair, there is not much beard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Taibai Hall in the Li Bai Memorial Hall is located in a bronze statue, created by Li Xiangqun, a professor at the School of Fine Arts of Tsinghua University. The poet&#39;s slender body stands upright, with his head to the sky, the raised beard fluttering, his lips are slightly open, the most special thing is that the eyes are blurred. After the statue is exhibited, it is recognized by the cultural and art circles, and young people can accept it, but the elderly over 60 years old have expressed great puzzles for the treatment of no eyes and freehand methods, and some even protested. It can be seen that the folks in Tai Bai&#39;s hometown are not easier to emotion in Li Bai. The image of Li Bai, which is traditional, has become popular. It seems that he should be like people&#39;s imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1283 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580Deb4ef.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259842 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Li Bai&#39;s bronze statue in Taibai Hall, author Li Xiangqun. Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Axian&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Kong Qiu. &quot;&quot; Lifetime is not harmonious in life, and Ensu Media is more and good. &quot; this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai claims to be &quot;An Neng can destroy the eyebrows and the waist, so that I can&#39;t be happy?&quot; The Song of the Song Dynasty &quot;Rat&quot; said: &quot;Tang people said that Li Bai couldn&#39;t bend, and there was proud bones in the waist.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The &quot;proud bone&quot; in the body cannot be changed, which pushes Li Bai&#39;s arrogance to absolutely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; People believe that Li Bai&#39;s bones are anti-world and are different times. From the leading order to take off the boots, to let the prime minister grind the ink and the concubine, from riding a donkey to the county to fishing at the sea, all kinds of extreme deeds, ancient and modern China and foreign countries, are unparalleled. sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Tang Five Dynasties Note novel &quot;Tang Guo Shi Bu&quot;, &quot;Puyang Miscellaneous&quot;, &quot;Song window miscellaneous records&quot; all record this story, the difference is that &quot;Song Wind Miscellaneous Records&quot; records that Li Bai was retaliated with Gao Lishi&#39;s words. In &quot;The History of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and &quot;Puyang Miscellaneous&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s behavior of calling Gaolishi to take off the boots was severely denied by Xuanzong. The person asked Gaolish to take off the boots and be criticized by the emperor&#39;s &quot;this person&#39;s solidity&quot;. The previous statement was almost forgotten except for the adoption of &quot;Old Tang Book&quot;. In the future story, Gaolishi took off his boots to become a established fact. Perhaps, the depressed people want to take this opportunity to produce the foreign appearance of the Gaoli, and spit out the blocks in the chest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the notes novels related to Li Bai in the Song Dynasty, some fictional stories have almost exaggerated but vivid stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai in Zhao Lingchou&#39;s &quot;Hou Yilu&quot; is like a famous Wei and Jin Dynasty: &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: Kai style_ GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Li Bai opened the prime minister in the middle of the middle, sealed one board, and said:&quot; Fishing on the sea, Li Bai. &quot;The prime minister asked:&quot; The gentleman is facing the sea, fishing in the giant Said: &quot;The storm is happy, Qian Kun is indulging in its ambitions. Taking Hong Ni as the line, and the moon as the hook.&quot; And said: &quot;What is a bait?&quot; Bai said: &quot;Taking the unwillingness of the world as a bait.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Liu Ax &quot;Green Trouble&quot; wrote Li Bai to ride a donkey to hit the county: &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: Kai style Kaita_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Zai said:&quot; Who is it, peace and no rude? &quot;Taibai said:&quot; Begging the confession. &quot; The royal hand adjusts the sprout, Luxi wipes the boots, and the concubine holds it; I still take the horse in front of the gate of the emperor, and I don&#39;t allow me to ride a donkey in Huayin County? &quot;Jae saw that he was shocked and said ashamed:&quot; I don&#39;t know Hanlin so far. &quot;If you want to stay, he is too white and go away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the Ming Dynasty Feng Menglong&#39;s novel &quot;Li Yixian Drunk Book&quot;, Li Bai dared to ridicule the adulterer in public: &quot; Lishi and Chen took off their boots and set up socks. &quot;Ping Yan and Mo Mo, here are all from Yang Guozhong, and Yang Guifei as a&quot; king &quot;is fulfilled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Obviously, people&#39;s imagination of Li Bai has not stopped in the image of the &quot;madman&quot;, which is more thorough than describing the arrogant people. &quot;Sitting down, let him come up from the sky and return to heaven again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; About Li Bai&#39;s life and death, from the legend of &quot;Chang Geng&#39;s Dream&quot; to &quot;Catching the Moon and Riding Whales&quot;, has a profound impact on later generations of creators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;The Story of Wind&quot; blurred the story of the story film and the boundaries of the documentary, is the last work of the Dutch director Yiwenzi. course. Ivins came out of Merry&#39;s love moon and strolled on the surface of the moon. In addition to chatting with Chang&#39;e, he also saw Li Bai on the earth from a small hole. Li Bai was lying drunk on a leaf flat boat, thinking that &quot;the king is not seen, Gao Tangming&#39;s mirror is sad and white, and it is like a green silk to become snow.&quot; Suddenly the large moon shadow appeared on the surface, Li Bai wanted to hug with both hands and turned over into the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 643 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260280 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Li Bai, who carries the liquor in the moon and night in the Irings movie &quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;. Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Historical materials recorded that Li Bai died of illness, and Bai Juyi had a &quot;Li Bai Tomb&quot;. &quot;A sentence is quite fascinating. By the evening of the Tang Dynasty and the Song Dynasty, he had talked about Li Bai&#39;s death. For example, Hong Mai&#39;s &quot;Rong Zhai Essay&quot;: &quot;The worldly says that Li Taibai is applying the stone, because he is drunk in the river, he sees the Yue Ying&#39;s prince, and then drowns. Therefore, there is a grab of the moon. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Xingyue interdependence, Li Yangbing&#39;s&quot; Caotang Collection &quot;said that Li Bai was born because of his mother&#39;s dream of Chang Geng, hence the name White, the word is too white. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the contemporary writer Zhang Dachun, Taiwan, the origin of this naming is his devotion to Li Bai. Knowing that he is a star in the world, it depends on his parents, but heaven is to cultivate his body, and you have to borrow it; from this, the brothers are just a dozen years. Children&#39;s spring and autumn, accompanying partners. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; As a star, send it as a fairy sound, there is no guest heart, the rest of the heart will not. &quot;Zhang Dachun In this sentence, Li Bai&#39;s awareness is a character like a guest like a guest. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Fake Tao True Confucianism? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some Li Bai&#39;s story is in Xianhua Li Bai, and another part of Li Bai&#39;s story is increasingly highlighting his mortal characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The inspirational legend of &quot;iron pestle grind into a needle&quot; was recorded by the Song people Zhu Mu in &quot;Fang Gong Shenglian&quot;. This story shows that Li Bai&#39;s talent is not born, It was not a dream pen, but accumulated through hard learning. The genius in the eyes of the Tang Dynasty was so grounded in the eyes of the Song people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Ming people Tu Long wrote Li Bai&#39;s family life into the legendary &quot;Color&quot;, describing his wife Xu Xiang&#39;e and his son Biao, showing Li Bai as a husband On the side of his father, he put the high poetry fairy into worldly life. This was unheard of in the Yuan Dynasty opera, and the theme of opera in the Qing Dynasty did not appear again, and contemporary literary and artistic works have portrayed the relationship between Li Bai and their hometown and loved ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Interestingly, emphasizing that Li Bai&#39;s entry into the WTO, highlighting the image of his succession, almost showing a background in today&#39;s literary works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Li Bai stood at the entrance of the French altar, and broke up yesterday and broke yesterday. Pursuing: &#39;Wish to support the auxiliary, so that Guotai Min&#39;an is clear at home.&#39; He wants to be Guan Zhong, Lu Zhonglian, Zhuge Liang, Xie An, Jiang Ziya ... &#39;Abandoned World&#39; means abandoning it all. &quot;Jiangyou writer Wang Huiqing blossomed In 18 years, she completed more than 700,000 -character novels &quot;Li Bai&quot;. She attributed Li Bai&#39;s reasons to the reason to avoid Li Linfu&#39;s minions. It was purely helpless. Li Bai felt pain in his heart before the ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Master Tai Xuan who presided over the ceremony quoted the famous sentence of &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; to warn Li Bai: &quot;The husband wants to avoid being a prisoner, so as not the world.&quot; What is difficult to do is abandon the world. In the novel, Li Bai said to Cao Sheng Zhang Xu when he was a teenager: &quot;Confucius said &#39;Tian Xingjian, gentleman should be self -improved&#39;, I don&#39;t believe it is not coming.&quot; It is completely Confucian background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Li Bai: Gambler&quot; in the northern catfish novel &quot;Li Bai: Gambler&quot; is more straightforward. The scene is the realistic life view of Taoism &#39;for me. In order to realize his ideal of being a big official, there is nothing to do. But old, but more and more nostalgic for Confucian pursuit. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai promised to be the Pengbird in Zhuangzi when he was young. Not help. Yu Feng was stimulating all the time, and he traveled to help the mulberry. The descendants of the descendants were passed on, and Zhong Ni died. Bei Maoyu sighed: &quot;He has believed in this big bird who is flying from the eight -descent and Yu Fengsheng since he was young. Flying is good, it is good to fold, and it is folded. However, Li Bai thought of Confucius in such a tragedy .... Li Bai asked for a lifetime, and he was about to die, but found that he was still in harmony with Confucius stood together. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; Li Bai &quot;premiered in 1991. It performed for more than 30 years and was called the classic of Beijing Renyi Drama. From the life of Li Bai for more than 60 years, the play has selected the background of the drama in the past five or six years in his old age. It is also more manifested by the vulgar side between Li Bai&#39;s hesitation on the &quot;仕&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;. The screenwriter Guo Qihong said in the introduction of Li Bai&#39;s character: &quot;&#39;Floating too white&#39; seems to be the consensus of people&#39;s past, Yu Guanzhi, not all.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/3d10fddddd14.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/3d10fdd14.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 260281 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Beijing Renyi art The drama &quot;Li Bai&quot;, Xi Cunxin plays Li Bai. Visual China &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The opening of the show is that Li Bai came out of the mountain for Yongwang, Li Bai took &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; and &quot;Li Sao&quot; with him. It is not the same to complete Qu Yuan&#39;s tragic career with the free mind of Zhuangzi. Li Bai responded with a smile: &quot;The north is from the head, and the north is the south!&quot; After the experience of Ye Lang, Li Baiben had to enter the way with his wife, but he met Guo Ziyi to visit the day before. , Li Bai, 60, suddenly changed his mind and joined His Majesty Guo Ziyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai related works launched in 2023, represented by the animated film &quot;Changan 30,000 Miles&quot; and the musical &quot;Will into the Wine&quot;, all chose not to be in the poem Xian Taibai&#39;s high and easy stay, but pushed a lonely and frustrated Li Bai to the eyes of the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/730e64747a.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/730e64747a.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 260282 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In the musical &quot;Will into Wine&quot;, Zheng Yunlong plays Li Bai. Photo of the player &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After Li Baijin in &quot;Will into the wine&quot;, he did not see the emperor. Instead, he saw Gao Lishi and Yang Guifei. The ground told Li Bai, Mo Dangzhen, he and her are just play things in this palace. The show left Chang&#39;an with Li Bai&#39;s losses and returned to his hometown to make a knot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In-depth attention to Li Bai&#39;s inner world and the pursuit of life, and was born in the miscellaneous drama &quot;Shijiji&quot; of the Qing people. Earlier, the songs of each dynasty paid more attention to the description of Li Baipin. In this regard, Jiang Shizhen was very dissatisfied. He was eager to be Li Bai&#39;s name. This dissatisfaction is also a kind of dissatisfaction with his identity. The two have experienced it very much. Going down, they are all old as literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Jiang Shizhen once expressed in the article that when he read his own works, he would say that this is an excellent poet. How short it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, what does Li Bai think of himself? I am afraid this biggest mystery will not have a clear answer. Only the historical horselights continued to rotate, and gradually illuminated him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (&quot;>; ( Part of the content of this article refers to: &quot;Born My Materials: Biography of Li Bai&quot;, &quot;The basis and trajectory of the evolution of Li Bai&#39;s image&quot;, &quot;Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s image in painting works&quot;, &quot;Research on the Story of Li Bai in the Tang and Song Note Novels&quot;, &quot;Yuan Ming and Qing Li Bai&#39;s theme opera opera Study &quot;) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href =&quot; https://feedx.net &quot;style = &quot;COLOR: Orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_ blank&quot; >; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国考连续6年“扩招”，大专生可报考岗位减少106个丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261673]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-01 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;November 26, 2023, test site in Wuhan Wenhua College, Hubei Kao District, Hubei, Many candidates are reviewed at lunch breaks. (People&#39;s Visual Pictures) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989b.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;596&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989b.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;260330&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>; On November 26, 2023, at the test site of the Wuhan Mandarin College of the Hubei Examination Area in Hubei Examination Area, many candidates reviewed the lunch break. (People&#39;s Visual Pictures) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 26, 2023, the central authorities and its direct institutions in the 2024 examination were officially held in public subjects in public civil servants, and the test was officially launched in 237 cities and 87682 test rooms across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the State Civil Service Bureau, a total of 3.33 million people passed the recruitment unit&#39;s qualification review. The number of applicants exceeded 3 million for the first time. Among them, 2.613 million candidates performed registration before the exam. 2.252 million people actually took the exam with a reference rate of about 86.2%. The &quot;National Examination&quot; plan recruited 39,600 people, and the ratio of the number of people participating in the test to the number of recruitment plans was about 57: 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is not difficult to find historical data, and the scale of the &quot;National Examination&quot; recruitment is rising as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In August 1993, the State Council promulgated the &quot;Interim Regulations on the National Civil Service&quot; to establish and implement the civil service system at the state administrative agencies at all levels. In June 1994, the former Ministry of Personnel issued the &quot;Interim Provisions on the Recruitment of State Civil Service&quot;, which marked the formal establishment of the national civil servant examination system and organized the first central state administrative organs civil servant recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the first time, the &quot;National Examination&quot; provided 490 places of more than 30 national organs, and the 4,400 people officially applied for the exam, equivalent to 9 people competing for 1 position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since then, the number of &quot;national examinations&quot; has continued to increase. From 2019 to 2024, the number of recruits was 14,500, 24,100, 25,700, 31,100, 37,100, and 39,600, respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cheng Lianchang, the former executive deputy minister of the Ministry of Personnel and the leading group leader of the national civil servant system, has personally experienced the process of establishing and implementing the civil service examination system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has recalled that the previous hiring system was in the form of recommendation, delivery, introduction, and transfer. In his opinion, this lack of openness, justice, and science, often causing the situation where the people they want by the state government cannot find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 29 years after the first &quot;National Examination&quot; was held, civil servants recruited the requirements for their degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Youzhen, chief researcher at Huatu Education, noticed that there were 56 posts in the 2024 National Examination College students, which was 106 from the previous year. The number of positions and recruiters who require the master&#39;s degree to increase significantly, and the postgraduate graduate degree and above are required to have 246 posts, an increase of 814 from the previous year; there are 24 posts requesting a doctoral degree, an increase of 14 over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Grassroots positions are still recruiting big testors. The &quot;National Examination&quot; has nearly 27,000 plans to supplement directly to the county (district) level and below, and properly adjusts the qualifications, majors, working years and experience of grass -roots positions in difficult and remote areas according to the actual situation. Further enrich the grass -roots civil servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another thing worth noting is that &lt;span>; 2024 The State Administration of Finance and Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration for the first time &lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Reform Plan for Party and State Institutions&quot;. It was decided to set up the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration on the basis of the Bank of China Insurance Supervision and Administration. On May 18, the State Administration of Finance and Administration was unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The State Administration of Finance and Administration has a total of 1,166 positions this time. It is planned to recruit 1,660 people, and the number of recruits is ranked fifth in the system in each system. As of one hour before the end of the registration, the total number of applicants exceeded 80,000, with the largest competition ratio of 591: 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, the Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission recruited and other positions in the national examination at the same time, but it was actually a public institution managed by the Civil Service Law. The post was essentially a career establishment. However, after the reform, the State Administration of Finance and Administration has become a direct institution of the State Council, and the post is already administrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Liu Youzhen, this year Huatu Education has opened 22 custom -made classes at top universities such as Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China to provide special training for students dedicated There are more than 2,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that while the number of &quot;national entrance examinations&quot; reached a record high, the number of postgraduate applicants in 2024 decreased by 360,000 after 8 years in a row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Liu Youzhen&#39;s view, in the severe employment situation, seeking stability is still the primary factor for most candidates to choose to take the test. &quot;To test the public, simply avoid the increasingly difficult postgraduate entrance examination, and directly join the test of the army. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Personnel movement &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Hu Jinglin as the Party Secretary of the State Administration of Taxation &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body_GB2312, simkai, simkai, simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The State Administration of Taxation, on November 28, 2023, the relevant responsible comrades of the Central Organization Department attended the meeting of the State Administration of Taxation and announced that Hu Jinglin was appointed Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation eliminates the position of party secretary of the State Administration of Taxation of Wang Jun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hu Jinglin, born in June 1964, is a doctor of economics. He served as the first director of the National Medical Security Bureau in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Tang Fangyu no longer serves as the chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body_GB2312, SIMKAITI; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the official website of the Chongqing CPPCC&#39;s official website showed that Tang Fangyu served as the chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC from January 2023 to October 2023, and he has no longer served. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tang Fangyu, male, Han nationality, born in August 1963, graduate student, member of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that Tang Fangyu has successively served as Deputy Director of the Party Construction Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, director of the Political Research Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, Director of the Research Office of the Central Office, Deputy Director of the Central Office, and the Central Office of the Central Office The director of the office and other positions, as chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC and secretary of the party group in January this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Zhang Chunlin as Deputy Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /Strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the &quot;Shanxi News Broadcasting&quot; of Shanxi Satellite TV, recently, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China approves: Zhang Chunlin serves as a member of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee, a member of the Standing Committee, and deputy secretary. Earlier, Zhang Chunlin served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that Zhang Chunlin, male, Han nationality, born in February 1965, Sichuan Deyang, joined the work in August 1986, joined the Communist Party of China in January 1986, the population of the School of Economics and Management of Xinjiang University, the population of the School of Economics and Management of Xinjiang University, He graduated from resource and environmental economics, has a postgraduate degree, and is a doctor of economics. He is a member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Welcome to the new vice governor &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the afternoon of November 30, the second plenary session (closing party) of the sixth meeting of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of Shaanxi Province was held. It was decided to appoint Chen Chunjiang as deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. Chen Chunjiang had previously served as assistant to the Minister of Commerce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, the Standing Committee of the Hebei Provincial People&#39;s Congress decided to appoint Zhao Dachun as the deputy governor of the People&#39;s Government of Hebei Province. Zhao Dachun had previously served as the deputy general manager of China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the WeChat public account &quot;Hubei People&#39;s Congress&quot;, on the morning of December 1st, the sixth meeting of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of Hubei Province was approved by the Sixth Session of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Hubei Province. Governor. Previously, Weishengbin was a member of the party group of the Hubei Provincial Government and Secretary -General of the Provincial Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Deputy Minister of Science and Technology Zhang Guangjun returned to college &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 29, 2023, Huazhong University of Science and Technology held a meeting of teachers and cadres and announced that Zhang Guangjun was the secretary of the Party Committee of Huazhong University of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Guangjun, born in March 1965, academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering. He used to be the vice president of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, and the president of Southeast University. In November 2021, Zhang Guangjun became the deputy minister of the Ministry of Science and Technology and a member of the party group until this adjustment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; 15-year-old admitted to the University of Science and Technology of the University of Science and Technology, Anhui 80s Hall Officer Performs a new job &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti, stkaiti, stkaiti, stkaiti ; &quot;>; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the official website of the Anhui Forestry Bureau has been updated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Mi was born in September 1982. Anhui has nothing to do, doctorate in Confucianism, and post -doctoral economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September 1997, at the age of 15, he was admitted to the Junior Class of the University of Science and Technology of China and studied in the university. After graduating in 2006, he served as the director of the Comprehensive Division of the Anhui Provincial Government Development Research Center (Research Office). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2011, the 29 -year -old Zhou Mi served as deputy secretary of the Anhui Provincial Party Committee of the Communist Youth League. According to the Beijing News, he became the youngest office cadres in the country at that time. At the end of 2019, he went to Xinjiang to participate in the work of aid in Xinjiang. In January of the following year, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Hetian Committee of Xinjiang, the member of the Xuancheng Municipal Committee, and the headquarters of the headquarters in front of the Anhui Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Anti-corruption Chronicle &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; former deputy mayor of Chongqing Xiong Xue was arrested &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI , Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The former deputy mayor of Chongqing Xiong Xue was suspected of accepting a bribe. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Xiong Xue on suspicion of bribery. The case is under further processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 13, 2023, the website of the State Commission of Discipline Inspection of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Xiong Xue lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original mission, and was indifferent to political consciousness. Division, distorted political performance, formalism, false reports of fraud, confrontation of organizational review, and great superstition activities. Xiong Xue was also accused of incorrect family style, regardless of taught spouses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 【&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In the first round of the financial regulatory system for more than a month, the former director of the Shenzhen Insurance Regulatory Bureau fell off &lt;/span>; &lt; Strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 27th, according to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection Commission, According to the news, Zhang Huiyi, the secretary of the Party Committee and Director of the Shenzhen Insurance Regulatory Commission&#39;s Shenzhen Supervision Bureau, is suspected of serious disciplinary violations and is currently being reviewed and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that from October 10th to October 12th, the Party Committee of the General Administration of Finance Supervision held a 2023 inspection mobilization and training meeting. The meeting pointed out that the inspection was the first inspection of the system after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China and the establishment of the General Administration of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Sixth-level professional and technical personnel who lost virtue after drinking are dismissed, and many people are punished &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: Kai style, regular body_GB2312, simkai , Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hunan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection reported on November 29 that on the evening of August 18, 2023, the Hunan Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition held in Xiangxi Prefecture After the semi -finals of the Biomedical Medicine, the results of the results of the Hunan Provincial Department of Science and Technology and the Deputy Director of the Regional Division, the job of the job &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tang Songbo, deputy director of the Management Committee of the Xiangxi High -tech Zone and Weng Lizhi, deputy director of the Xiangxi State Bureau of Science and Technology, invited Li Yangbao (trial period) and professional and technical staff Liu Jian (level 6), director of the Provincial Torch Entrepreneurship Center guided by the Sai Organization, and others at a restaurant in a restaurant in Jishou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After dinner, Weng Lizhi contacted the high -speed railway Jishu East Station to send 6 people such as Li Yangbao, Tang Songbo, Liu Jian and other 6 people into the VIP room. During the waiting period, Liu Jian lost his state of ethics and harassed two female waiters many times, causing a bad impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In November 2023, Liu Jian was severely warned within the party (two years of affected periods), government affairs removal, Tang Songbo and Li Yangbao were severely warned and dismissed within the party. The party was severely warned, and the rest were dealt with by warning or admonition of the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Ministerial information &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; National Bureau of Statistics: There is no end to the extreme harmfulness of statistical fraud. , Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, 2023,&quot; Statistics WeChat &quot;WeChat public account announced the National Bureau of Statistics 2023 Special 2023 The first inspector of the Statistics Inspector to the special statistical inspector to Shaanxi. The inspection found that some cadres and government leaders in Shaanxi Province have not yet deeply understood the extreme harmfulness of statistical fraud and the extreme importance and urgency of statistical counterfeiting. The assessment pressure boost statistical fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; National Health and Health Commission: acute respiratory diseases continue to rise, strive to increase the clinic &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 26, a spokesman for the National Health and Health Commission Mi Feng introduced at a press conference that recently China&#39;s acute respiratory diseases have continued to rise, with various types Related to the hyperplasia of the respiratory pathogens. All localities should strive to increase the relevant clinic and treatment areas, appropriately extend the service time, and strengthen the protection of drug supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; People&#39;s Bank of China: Continue to increase the tilt of monetary policy on private small and micro enterprises &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The People&#39;s Bank of China issued a report on November 27. The People&#39;s Bank of China will continue The annual service goals of private enterprises, the weight of the relevant business of private enterprises in performance assessment, etc., increase financial support for private enterprises, and promote the reduction of comprehensive financing costs of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Rule of rule of law &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最高法发布反家暴典型案例，精神暴力也属家庭暴力&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月25日是“国际消除对妇女暴力日”，最高人民法院在当天发布一批反家庭暴力典型案例，进一步明确精神暴力也属于家庭暴力。在审判实践中，除了经常性谩骂、恐吓等精神侵害外，用喝农药、跳楼等自残自伤方式威胁也属于精神侵害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2022年以来共侦破黑客类犯罪2430起&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月30日，公安部召开新闻发布会。公安部网络安全保卫局副局长李彤在发布会上介绍，2022年以来，全国公安机关共侦破黑客类犯罪案件2430起、抓获犯罪嫌疑人7092名，重拳打击非法抢占火车票、医院挂号、景区及演唱会门票等社会资源，侵犯家庭及个人隐私生活的黑客犯罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前十月起诉电诈犯罪3.4万余人，文化程度较高人员涉罪上升&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月30日，最高人民检察院发布检察机关办案工作情况。 From January to October 2023, procuratorial organs across the country prosecuted more than 34,000 people for telecommunications and network fraud, a year-on-year increase of nearly 52%.犯罪人员低龄、低收入、低学历特征依然明显，但文化程度较高人员涉罪呈上升趋势。 In the first three quarters of 2023, procuratorial organs nationwide prosecuted more than 4,400 people with a college degree or above (including bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree, and doctoral degree), more than 5,900 people, and more than 7,600 people among the three categories of criminals: telecommunications network fraud, trusting, and concealment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;科教动态&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;雷军个人向武汉大学捐13亿现金，创全国高校纪录&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月29日，武汉大学130周年校庆日。 1987级计算机系校友、小米集团创始人雷军个人向武汉大学捐赠13亿元，刷新武大建校以来单笔最大捐赠额，这也是全国高校收到的最大一笔校友个人现金捐赠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;【&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;北京市教委：学生患病期间作业一律不做硬性要求&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月25日，北京市教委微信公众号“首都教育”发布消息称，北京市进入呼吸道传染病高发期，儿童感染人数增多，学校对学生患病期间的作业一律不做硬性要求，不建议患病期间赶、补作业，一切以孩子身体为重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;首批疏解四所高校雄安校区全部开工建设&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月28日，首批疏解的在京部委所属高校雄安校区集中开工动员会在雄安新区召开，标志着北京交通大学、北京科技大学、北京林业大学、中国地质大学（北京）等4所高校雄安校区全部开工建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;地方政情&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;云南：从源头减少会议经费开支，压减会议会期与参会人数&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，云南省财政厅网站发布消息称，会议将实行分类管理、分级审批，从严控制会议数量、会期和参会人数规模，各类会议会期不超过1天，一、二、三、四类会议分别以每人每天600元、500元、400元、300元为开支上限。同时提倡各单位在符合保密和网络信息安全要求的前提下采用线上会议形式，优先选择单位内部电视电话、电子政务内网等现有应用系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;浙江丽水发放购房消费券，最高可抵扣4万&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月28日，浙江省丽水市宣布分三期向购房者发放有效期60天、总额度1800万元的购房消费券，“促进合理住房消费”。这是近年浙江首个发放可抵扣购房款消费券的地级市。根据使用规则，在当地报名参加活动的42个楼盘购房，市区楼盘购房款300万以上或开发区楼盘购房款150万以上可抵4万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;福建：65周岁及以上台胞可免费乘坐城市公共交通工具等&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月27日，福建省委台办、省发展改革委等部门举行新闻发布会，公布福建省贯彻落实《中共中央国务院关于支持福建探索海峡两岸融合发展新路建设两岸融合发展示范区的意见》首批15条政策措施，其中包括65周岁及以上台胞可免费乘坐城市公共交通工具等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;声音&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;毛伟明：“他乡纵有当头月，不及家乡一盏灯”&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体,楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;】&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月27日，湖南省委副书记、省长毛伟明在北京走访调研部分湘商企业. “他乡纵有当头月，不及家乡一盏灯”。毛伟明表示，家乡永远是广大湘商的坚强“后盾”和温暖“港湾”。我们将秉持“让广大湘商在湘更吃香”的理念，引导支持有资源互补优势、符合湖南发展需要的企业向家乡转移，在双向奔赴中实现互利共赢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（综合自澎湃新闻、极目新闻、每日经济新闻、中国新闻网、财新网、湖南省委监委网站、中国青年报、新京报、央视新闻、“武汉大学”微信公众号、“首都教育”微信公众号等）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉56项违规行为，中信银行被罚没超2.24亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:40:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;国家金融监督管理总局行政处罚信息公开表显示，中信银行被罚没2.24亿元，涉56项违规行为。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1102&quot; height=&quot;3895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260389&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[基辛格，时代纵横者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK6BbyenF3EB9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK6BbyenF3EB9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;基辛格&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间2023年11月29日，美国前国家安全事务助理、国务卿，深刻影响了20世纪美国对外政策以及地缘政治发展的著名外交家、政治家、学者，亨利·基辛格逝世，享年100岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;基辛格与弟弟沃尔特&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1923年，海因茨·阿尔弗雷德·基辛格（Heinz Alfred Kissinger）出生在德国巴伐利亚省菲尔特（Fürth）的一个德裔犹太人家庭，父亲是教师，母亲是家庭主妇。 A year later, a younger brother was added to the family, Walter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿时的基辛格热衷于踢足球，一度加入了菲尔特足球俱乐部的青训。 But with Hitler coming to power in 1933, the Nazi regime&#39;s oppression of the Jewish community intensified. Because he broke into the stadium to watch games in violation of Jewish segregation regulations, Kissinger was often scolded and beaten by guards, and he was also kicked out of the team. Later, Kissinger&#39;s father was also dismissed from his teaching position without reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一切变得更糟糕前，基辛格一家于1938年移民美国，此后他改名为亨利·基辛格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;627&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1971年2月10日，美国总统理查德·尼克松（左）和国家安全顾问基辛格在白宫的办公室交谈&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1969年，尼克松任命基辛格为国家安全事务助理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从政前，基辛格已是颇有名气的国际政治学者，并曾在多个有美国政府背景的机构或智库任职，三次担任纳尔逊·洛克菲勒（Nelson Rockefeller）竞选总统时的外交政策顾问，期间曾尖锐批评尼克松是“最危险的总统竞选者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在尼克松成为总统后，二人却戏剧性地成为了一对默契十足的搭档。 Faced with the turbulent global situation in the 1960s, Nixon gave Kissinger great room for action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1971年7月，基辛格在访问巴基斯坦期间秘密飞往北京，并促成了尼克松在1972年震惊世界的访华。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1972年2月25日，北京，美国总统尼克松和夫人出席晚宴并合影留念，前排右一为基辛格&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1974年7月3日，莫斯科克里姆林宫，在为期七天的首脑会议期间，美国总统尼克松（中）、国务卿基辛格（左）与苏联领导人勃列日涅夫（右）敬酒&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1972年2月21日，美国总统尼克松抵达北京，开始访华行程。 2月28日，《中美联合公报》发布，宣布中美两国关系走向正常化。后来的研究普遍认为，中美关系的正常化极大影响了苏联的外交策略考量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在基辛格推动下，尼克松访华后不久，就于当年5月访问莫斯科，与苏联领导人勃列日涅夫会面，促成了《苏美联合公报》、《苏美相互关系原则》等9个文件的发布。此后几年里，美苏领导人来往频繁，在进攻性战略武器使用、核武器试验等领域取得了积极的共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美、美苏关系的改善直接带动了全球整体局势走向积极，基辛格关于大国平衡均势实现本国利益与国际和平的外交思想，在这一过程中得到了充分体现. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1973年1月23日，法国巴黎，越南民主共和国代表团特别顾问黎德寿（前排右二）和美国国家安全顾问基辛格（后排左二）在《巴黎和平协约》上签字&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基辛格于1965至1966年曾两次前往越南.走访期间，他意识到美国“既不知道如何赢得战争，也不知道如何结束战争”。而最终这场将美国拖入泥沼的战争，也正是在他手里结束的。尼克松上台后，基辛格和南北越领导人开展过一系列艰难的谈判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美关系的正常化极大推动了中南半岛局势的缓和。 1972年10月，基辛格与越共领导人黎德寿在巴黎举行的秘密谈判上取得了决定性突破，基辛格宣布“和平近在咫尺”，正在进行总统大选的尼克松民望大涨，最后以49 州的压倒性优势当选连任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1973年1月，各方签署《巴黎和平协约》。南北越停火，美国撤出在越南的所有部队，北越释放所有美国战俘。 Kissinger and Le Duc Tho were also awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Le Duc Tho refused to accept the award, and Kissinger announced that he would donate the prize money to the children of American servicemen killed or missing in the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;651&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1975年9月1日，基辛格在耶路撒冷的酒店眺望风景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1975年9月6日，在埃及和以色列之间的往返航班上，基辛格正在阅读报纸，妻子南希拍了拍他的头&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1973年“赎罪日战争”（即第四次中东战争）爆发，基辛格再次奔走在调停的First line.出于美国政治利益和他本人的血统，他曾试图拖延停火，让以色列军队获得更多的时间扩大战果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战后，基辛格却一度试图推迟美国对以色列进行的军火物资补偿，并致力于推动联合国安理会第242号决议实现和平。以沙特阿拉伯为首的中东产油国对美国实行石油禁运后，基辛格下场多方斡旋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从1973到1975年，基辛格来往于埃及、沙特阿拉伯、叙利亚和以色列的各路领导人之间，开展“穿梭外交”，成功取得了包括埃及总统萨达特等人的信任，以承诺出售武器换取沙特阿拉伯解除石油禁运，促成关于西奈半岛问题的两项协议——以色列将从西奈部分领土上撤走并放弃了结束战争状态的要求，埃及则同意对以色列的非军事物资开放苏伊士运河，这被认为是美国在福特政府时期取得的为数不多的外交成就之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260340&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1995年12月11日，左起：基辛格、戴安娜王妃、科林·鲍威尔与新闻主播芭芭拉·沃尔特斯出席第41届世界脑瘫联合协会颁奖晚会。戴安娜王妃在晚会上荣获UCP人道主义奖&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基辛格在尼克松因水门事件丑闻被迫辞职后，继续在福特总统政府担任国家安全事务助理和国务卿。但促成西奈半岛协议达成后没多久，在1975年11月被称为“万圣节大屠杀”的内阁改组中，基辛格的国家安全事务助理职务就被布伦特·斯科克罗夫特所取代.福特于1976年的总统大选落败后，基辛格辞去了国务卿的职务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后基辛格游走于政商学三界：成立了中国风险投资公司，担任董事长和首席执行官；担任过&lt;span>;费利浦·麦克莫兰&lt;/span>;（Freeport-McMoRan）的董事会成员；做过美国恐怖袭击国家委员会主席……此外还包括校长、各种机构的政治顾问或董事会成员，有些职位甚至还颇具争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时他还发行了至少7本书，内容包括自己的回忆录、政治评论，甚至还有一本关于人工智能的观察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2000年7月12日，美国得克萨斯州州长、共和党总统候选人小布什（左）和美国前国务卿基辛格在奥斯汀州长官邸的门廊上向记者挥手致意&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017年5月10日，美国总统特朗普（右）在白宫与美国前国务卿基辛格会面&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为美国历史上有过杰出贡献、经验丰富且在政商界拥有广泛人脉的老牌政治家，基辛格基本成了尼克松以来每一任美国总统都曾请教或拜会过的“山头”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年11月17日，基辛格与当选总统唐纳德·特朗普会面，他们对全球事务进行了一番讨论，次年他们又见过一次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来在2017年8月17日的一次采访中，基辛格谈到那位全世界都琢磨不透、时常剑走偏锋的总统时无奈地说：“我希望（特朗普）有一个奥古斯丁的时刻。对于圣奥古斯丁来说……他早年行径跟后来完全不同，但他有一天忽然受到神启，成为了后来的那个圣人。人们当然不指望总统能成为那样，但总是可以想想的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260339&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1985年，基辛格参观广州清平街市场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（安哥/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2005年5月12日，河南许昌，美国前国务卿基辛格来到邓庄乡许庄村七组村民梁书华家，感受当地农户的家庭生活&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，美国前国务卿基辛格在纽约举行的美中关系全国委员会年度颁奖晚宴上讲话&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直至走上政坛前，基辛格都未曾表现出对中国的太多兴趣，但因为工作而对中国进行深入了解后，他开始对中国有了一个全新的认识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;决定推进中美关系发展后，基辛格认真学习了中国文化、历史和政治等国情，并密切关注中国的政治经济发展。从1971到2023年，基辛格先后访华一百多次，这个记录在西方政治家中绝无仅有。他曾表示，“中国是我交往最久、最为深入的国家。中国已经成为我生命中非常重要的一部分。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基辛格逝世后，中国外交部发言人汪文斌表示，基辛格博士是中国人民的老朋友、好朋友，是中美关系的开拓者和建设者。 &quot;He has long been concerned about and supported the development of Sino-US relations, and has visited China more than a hundred times, making historic contributions to promoting the normalization of Sino-US relations. The Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger&#39;s sincere feelings and important contributions to Sino-US relations.贡献。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“电玩捕鱼”涉赌案：矛盾的时间点，反转的证词]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;一款名为“大富翁电玩捕鱼”的游戏被广西苍梧公安认定为赌博。（人民视觉供图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260322&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;一款名为“大富翁电玩捕鱼”的游戏被广西苍梧公安认定为赌博。 （人民视觉供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大富翁电玩捕鱼”是一款游戏，由北京一家游戏公司开发、运营。两年多时间内，玩家充值总额约1.57亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在广西苍梧县的公安机关看来，这个“捕鱼”不是游戏，而是赌博。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年2月18日，该游戏公司实控人宗超、钟柳青以及7名员工因涉嫌开设赌场罪被苍梧县公安局逮捕。 2023年10月23日，苍梧县法院一审判决，宗超被判有期徒刑6年10个月，钟柳青被判有期徒刑5年半，其余7人获刑2年到2年11个月不等. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;判决书中说明，苍梧县公安局根据在工作中发现的线索，经初查确认涉案游戏部分玩家属苍梧县籍，报案人和3名证人也是苍梧籍，他们的证言证实涉案游戏涉嫌赌博，苍梧县属犯罪地，具有管辖权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从参加庭审人士处获悉，巧合的是，其中有两名证人与被告人关押在同一监室。一审庭审期间，被告人提交的情况说明显示，两名证人均表示自己在公安机关工作人员安排下完成笔录，做笔录前，自己并未接触过这款游戏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这两名证人随后在接受看守所询问时，又推翻了在情况说明中的说法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宗超、钟柳青不服判决，已向梧州市中级法院提交上诉状。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;灰色地带和侥幸心理&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;涉案人员宗超、钟柳青和游戏公司的初创员工之前都是一家互联网大厂的同事。 2018年，他们从原单位离职，成立北京四海互娱科技有限公司，合伙运营捕鱼游戏。 2019年下半年，游戏上线运营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;捕鱼游戏的玩法是，用户充值人民币获得游戏金币后，消耗金币开炮捕鱼，打鱼成功后按倍率赢取金币。同时，用户在“福豆场”模式中，捕鱼时可以获得“福豆”，“福豆”能用来兑换话费、实物、京东购物卡等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一审判决书中引用了一名被告人的供述。他同宗超、钟柳青等人以及律师有一个线上群，专门讨论过这款游戏是否会触碰法律红线。律师给出的意见是，这款游戏玩法处于灰色地带，没有法律说可以这样干，也没有说不能这样干，所以当时就抱着侥幸心理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在被告人和他们的律师看来，这款游戏不能被认为是赌博的理由是，通过捕鱼赢得的金币虽与“爆率”“倍率”成比例关系，但是金币不能用来兑换人民币。而能兑换成人民币的福豆有其生成机制，同“爆率”“博大小”“倍率”无关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此案在&lt;/span>;2023年3月28日、6月25日至6月29日公开开庭审理。宗超的辩护律师为其做无罪辩护。律师在庭上指出，赌博的本质在于实现“以小博大”。游戏运营者为确保运营游戏不落入开设赌场罪的范畴，游戏附赠的福豆，有充值金额比例上的限制，且运营者通过设置黑名单的方式，将试图“以小博大”的玩家拦截在游戏之外。因此，这款游戏不能实现“以小博大”，故不是赌博。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而法院一审判决认定，玩家在捕鱼时使用消耗金币越多、倍数越大的大炮打鱼，能量条就会增长越快，对应就能产生不同等级的福豆，故存在“以小博大”。具有提现功能，属赌博游戏，予以认定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;“一时疏忽”？多个时间点出现矛盾&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2022年1月2日15点50分，当地人潘建峰到苍梧县石桥镇派出所报案称自己在家下载了“大富翁电玩捕鱼”App。实名注册后，发现这款游戏可以线上充值，之后通过玩游戏赢取“福豆”，“福豆”可以兑换成人民币提现。他告诉民警，自己已经充值36元，提现2元，因此认为这是款赌博游戏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据一审判决，在潘建峰报案前13天，2021年12月20日，苍梧县公安局已经注意到这款App，并进行初查，经核查发现有苍梧籍会员41人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苍梧县公安局于潘建峰报案当日对此立案侦查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此案在2023年3月28日、6月25日至6月29日公开开庭审理。庭审时，多名被告人的辩护律师提出了对潘建峰注册游戏、提现、报案时间过于接近的疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游戏后台数据显示，潘建峰在报案当天15时15分56秒注册游戏。他提供的提现界面截图则显示，他在15时49分17秒提现。也就是说，他在接受询问前25分钟刚注册游戏，且提现时距接受询问仅相差43秒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除潘建峰外，被告人的辩护律师认为证人王凯、覃军、陈涛从游戏中提现和接受警方询问的时间存在矛盾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王凯、覃军、陈涛分别从2022年1月7日10时25分、2022年1月7日12时10分、2022年1月10日10点30分开始在石桥派出所接受询问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王凯在接受询问时说，自己在游戏中已充值54元，提现2元；覃军说自己充了36元，提现2元；陈涛也称自己充值36元，提现2 yuan.三人均在询问中表示可以提供提现页面截图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审中，律师指出，三人提供的截图中，王凯、覃军提现时间都是1月8日21时31分，陈涛则在1月10日13时27分提现.也就是说，他们的提现时间均晚于接受询问的时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于律师提出的上述时间问题，公诉人出具了一份苍梧县公安局的情况说明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份文件解释，潘建峰在家先玩游戏，1月2日15时左右到石桥派出所报案，现场操作演示后提现，派出所受案接报时间15时50分。被告人辩护律师又指出时间线上的问题：潘建峰在下午3点左右抵达派出所，那么游戏应当是在派出所内注册的。庭审时，控辩双方对这一问题展开辩论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;情况说明中还指出，办案人员制作王凯、覃军的询问笔录时，使用了1月7日的笔录版本，忘记修改询问时间，实际时间是1月9日；制作陈涛笔录时，也“一时疏忽，粗心大意”，把询问时间写错，准确时间是1月10日14时30分至15时40分，按照这一解释，陈涛在接受询问前1小时完成提现. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;证人说法反转&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;巧合的是，证人覃军、陈涛后来因涉嫌寻衅滋事也被羁押在苍梧县看守所，分别同被告人宗超、钟柳青关押在一个监室。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两名证人都曾表示在公安机关工作人员安排下完成笔录，甚至连笔录内容都没有看过就签了字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审时，宗超提交了一份覃军手写的情况说明，描述了报案经过：2021年年底，同镇好友王凯打电话给他，让他带人去石桥派出所配合玩个捕鱼游戏。他带着潘建峰去了派出所。王凯微信给他们分享游戏下载链接，之后他们注册、充值并提现，再将相关游戏截图发给民警，全部完成后签字离开。他称，事前自己并没有接触过这款游戏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈涛则同钟柳青等3名被告人羁押在同一监室。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审时，3名被告人都提交了自己手写的说明。一名被告人称，第一次开庭前四天，他在监室内收到传票，陈涛注意到上面写着游戏公司的名字，说了句“我好像举报过”。该被告人就问陈涛为什么举报，陈涛的回答是“没玩过，就是被叫到派出所签笔录”,并表示没看过笔录内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，二人的说法又都在看守所给他们做的谈话记录中发生反转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年5月15日的记录中，陈涛表示，3月底开庭结束后，钟柳青找过他，让他写书面证明或出庭作证，证明他去公安机关反映网络赌博的情况是假的，不是主动反映事实。他没有答应，因为他之前说的都是事实。之后钟柳青写了书面材料叫他签字，提出只要其答应出庭作证，推翻他之前在公安机关的笔录，可以给他5万元、10万元甚至50万元，他都没有答应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;覃军则在3天后的谈话中表示，自己的情况说明是“糊里糊涂写的”，“他们说话好有艺术、好有文化，我也不知道怎么的就被洗脑了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苍梧县法院一审判决认为，潘建峰、覃军、王凯、陈涛4人的证言客观真实，与案件具有关联性，予以认定。而被告人提供的上述情况说明等材料，与案件查明的事实不符，不予采信。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中潘建峰、陈涛、覃军、王凯均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西检察机关依法对李东涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 15:04:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate today (1st) that former party members of the National Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd. The case of deputy general manager Li Dong suspected of accepting bribes was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Yichun City, Jiangxi Province. Recently, the Yichun City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Yichun City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Dong of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Li Dong, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecution charged: The defendant Li Dong used his position as deputy secretary and manager of the party committee of Shenhua Zhungeer Coal Company, deputy secretary and chairman of the party committee of Shenhua Group Zhungeer Energy Co., Ltd., deputy chief engineer of Shenhua Group Co., Ltd., Shenhua Group Members of the party group and deputy general manager of a limited liability company, members of the party group and deputy general manager of China Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd., seeking benefits for others and illegally accepting property from others for the convenience of their positions, and the amount is particularly huge, they should be prosecuted for the crime of accepting bribes according to law. criminal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>