<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[儿童友好公园，一米高度看世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257792]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Guangzhou in September, the highest temperature is still close to 39°C, and the pool in the park has become the most lively place. At the Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, children walked through marine life and played under dolphins and octopuses. However, the colorful colors at the bottom of the pool do not represent the colorful underwater world, but the oil spill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few months ago, the pool was still monotonous marble white. After taking an environmental protection class, a dozen children painted the bottom of the pool colorfully with paint, implying that after an oil spill, under the reflection of light, What the ocean looks like. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FoWhvc8K5DwpYMePAmES4M92IuwIUMBKZfTh5TqE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FoWhvc8K5DwpYMePAmES4M92IuwIUMBKZfTh5TqE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, the colorful paddling pool is painted for children to symbolize the luster of the ocean after an oil spill. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more and more parks that are tailored for children and allow children to participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou has the largest child-friendly park system in the country, including 1 municipal-level + 12 district-level children&#39;s parks. In 2023, &quot;Promoting the continuation of the municipal children&#39;s park project&quot; was included in the work report of the Guangzhou Municipal Government for the first time. Since 2001, Shenzhen has released two rounds of ten-year plans for children&#39;s development, incorporating child-friendly city construction into the top-level design for the first time. Currently, Luohu and Pingshan Children&#39;s Parks have been opened, and Longgang Children&#39;s Park will also be completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being friendly to children means being friendly to the future of the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Promoting the Construction of Child-Friendly Cities&quot; by 23 departments including the National Development and Reform Commission, child-friendliness refers to providing appropriate conditions, environment and services for the growth and development of children, and effectively protecting children&#39;s right to survival and development. rights, rights to protection and rights to participate. Guangdong and Shenzhen were selected into the first batch of national child-friendly cities. In March 2023, 23 departments including the Guangdong Provincial Development and Reform Commission issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for the Construction of Child-Friendly Cities in Guangdong Province&quot; to promote the construction of child-friendly parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we invite an environmental engineer to give a class, we will leave after reading the slides in the classroom. In the park, we let the children think about what humans have gained from the ocean and what they have given.&quot; Children in Guangzhou Yu Mingjie, deputy director of the park, told Southern Weekend reporters that the children understood that humans have also caused damage in the process of obtaining materials from the ocean. Even after the paddling pool was painted colorful, some children thought, &quot;Should we destroy or create?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a8jsOp74iGWTKdgd0Gc5eE5xTaQYkmWNp90suhEi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a8jsOp74iGWTKdgd0Gc5eE5xTaQYkmWNp90suhEi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the water in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;See the world from a height of one meter&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What do children love to do in the park? Play with water and sand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Weikai, a senior engineer at the Guangzhou Urban Planning, Survey and Design Institute, and others once calculated the regional heat of Guangzhou Children’s Park. From 9 a.m. to 5 p.m., the pool and sandy areas are the most densely populated with children. The place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Water and sand are ever-changing and full of infinite creativity. In the eyes of children, they are &quot;magical toys&quot; given by nature. Studies have shown that playing with water and sand can not only stimulate touch, vision and physical perception, but also cultivate children&#39;s curiosity and imagination and promote brain development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c3gHbcJUo1ASiicWsf8kRmMG9Tb1xEImoiIjIC0f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c3gHbcJUo1ASiicWsf8kRmMG9Tb1xEImoiIjIC0f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the sand in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When designing children&#39;s parks, they pay attention to the needs of children to play with water and sand. Shenzhen local standard &quot;Children&#39;s Park (Park) Design Specifications&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Shenzhen Design Specifications&quot;) requires that even small parks with a minimum area of ​​2 hectares should have sandy areas. When the park area reaches more than 10 hectares, a paddling pool can be installed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2gl3VcyI6uFvyqjyunpGcxZR7jQaPiQxU13H9Tfv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2gl3VcyI6uFvyqjyunpGcxZR7jQaPiQxU13H9Tfv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children playing in the water in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the sandpit and pool being exclusive for children, the plant brands in the children&#39;s park are also different. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The introduction of lychee trees in parks usually includes the Latin name, family, genus, species, character, etc., but in Shenzhen Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, the title of the explanation board is: &quot;How many lychees should you eat in a day?&quot; &quot;Pieces?&quot; It reminded many children in Guangdong of their experience of being scolded by adults for eating less lychees because of &quot;heat&quot; (a Guangdong term used to mean &quot;getting angry&quot;). Adults are also easily attracted, &quot;a bit like the headlines of public accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nan Fangfang, head of the direction ecology team, introduced that these interpretive signs are designed according to the &quot;3-30-3&quot; rule: 3 seconds for children to become interested; 30 seconds to have a simple understanding of things; scan 2D code to gain more in-depth and detailed knowledge in 3 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Explanatory signs in other scenic spots are only maintained once every 3-5 years. Pingshan Children&#39;s Park wears out much faster and needs to be updated every year. He is very happy, &quot;There are many people using the explanation, which is better than being deserted.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to sum up the design idea of ​​the children&#39;s park in one sentence, it would be &quot;seeing the world from a height of one meter&quot;. When adults walk into the children&#39;s park, they feel as if they have entered the &quot;Land of Dwarves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adults have to bend down to see the maps and guidance signs clearly; soft rubber mats are laid in each play area, and rounded corners are designed in places that are prone to bumping. The &quot;Shenzhen Design Code&quot; also requires that: trash cans can be shaped like lively cartoons, and the height of the input port should not exceed 80 centimeters; the operating height of children&#39;s drinking fountains should not exceed 70 centimeters; both men&#39;s and women&#39;s toilets in public toilets should be equipped with children&#39;s toilets and men&#39;s toilets The proportion of inner low-level urinals in the total urinals should not be less than 50%, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/x1CfgQNQR5H1mBnOx4SuBDTq0J9nklGOU1EHjjWy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;1692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/x1CfgQNQR5H1mBnOx4SuBDTq0J9nklGOU1EHjjWy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Adults have to bend down to see the signs in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, the open lawn surrounded by the big banyan tree is the Guangzhou Park The largest inner area. Children can set up tents, run, jump and enjoy the sunshine without any scruples, but cannot play football - refer to the &quot;Guangzhou Park Lawn Opening Management Guidelines (Draft for Comments)&quot;. Failure to play football on the open lawn of the park may seriously damage the lawn vegetation. activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lEjU7wrVqVwxVjMNANvCf94M41eek3fOG3vdSdrm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lEjU7wrVqVwxVjMNANvCf94M41eek3fOG3vdSdrm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The large lawn in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The park has also been thinking of solutions and plans to open a dedicated sports area to build There are football fields, basketball courts, tennis courts and a model car park for children to have more fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The needs of parents should also be considered. Children are enjoying themselves in the park, and parents cannot just sit there and watch their phones overheat and shut down under the scorching sun. Moreover, many parents are elderly. Yu Mingjie has also noticed this. He is making barrier-free renovations in the park and adding some new rest areas so that &quot;parents can drink tea and coffee indoors while seeing their children.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mBlzN0nt4MP4f0zR3uwXt0LoHqfjmcz5VHSF4jSH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mBlzN0nt4MP4f0zR3uwXt0LoHqfjmcz5VHSF4jSH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252539&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A parent is giving water to his child in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Experience danger safely&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Children are lively and active. Compared with ordinary parks, children&#39;s parks have greater pressure on safety. A UNICEF survey of 35,000 children in 65 countries found that a quarter of children would feel unsafe in parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yafei works as an operations manager in Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, and has to &quot;fight&quot; with children climbing trees multiple times every day - there is a crooked tree next to the swing, which is the children&#39;s favorite. Preventing children from climbing trees has even become a key task for the park management staff. &quot;We will try to coax them a little at the beginning, and then we will be more stern. If it doesn&#39;t work, we will contact the parents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each project in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park is equipped with staff. The number is slightly larger than that of other parks, with 60-70 people on duty every day. The park is also equipped with more than 40 emergency devices. Children can talk to the park alarm center by pressing a button. &quot;It is normal for children to get lost and look for their mother, 20 to 30 times a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To ensure safety, age or height restrictions on facilities are the most common methods. In Pingshan Children&#39;s Park, stainless steel slides and swings are suitable for those aged 4 and above, while more complex balance beams and climbing nets require those aged 6 and above 12 years old respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the regulations, it cannot stop children under age. In a net-climbing project, if you are not tall enough, it will be difficult to climb up to the last climbing point. There are often children who are half-climbed and their hands and feet are weak and dare not continue, so they have to be carried down by their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ziFDpqTKiUXj6dva8kdTe4msE9ocnzFWrypOyi3w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ziFDpqTKiUXj6dva8kdTe4msE9ocnzFWrypOyi3w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The net-climbing slide in Pingshan Children&#39;s Park is difficult for children with insufficient physical strength and height to climb up. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children&#39;s parks will also receive contradictory complaints from parents. On the one hand, they want their children to play More facilities mean more experiences; on the other hand, there are worries about safety. This contradiction is also a question that Liu Yuelai, associate professor at the School of Architecture and Urban Planning of Tongji University, has been thinking about - should we just encircle the railings and make them the safest? He feels that how children overcome dangers and difficulties also needs to be taken into consideration. Child-friendliness is more important than caring for and taking responsibility for children, creating conditions for children to experience, practice and grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, adults often prevent children from stepping into puddles. If all puddles are eliminated, children will be bored. If some difficulties are designed, children can realize that they can overcome them, which is &quot;more important than adults eliminating all dangers.&quot; While ensuring safety, the water depth, slope, etc. comply with national regulations, which can enrich the park&#39;s landforms and provide more fun for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the research, Nan Yishan also found that when it comes to snakes, children and parents are not curious, but afraid: there are no snakes in the park, right? Therefore, the commentary they designed begins with a child&#39;s voice saying: &quot;Snakes and humans have very deep misunderstandings about each other. When humans see snakes, they are nervous and afraid; when snakes see humans, they are frightened and frightened.&quot; The popularization of science focuses on how to communicate with snakes. What to do if you get along and get bitten by a snake. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Let&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;children participate in the construction of the park&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Few people know that the Nanyue King Museum is the former site of the Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou Children’s Park was first built in 1958. During the expansion in 1995, cultural relics of the Nanyue King were unearthed and moved to the junction of Renmin South Road and Yide Road not far away. Later, Guangzhou Baiyun Airport was moved and built in 2014. In 2006, it moved to the old Baiyun Airport land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;Brief History of the Park&quot; inspired artist Chen Zhou. He taught at the Guangzhou Academy of Fine Arts and later focused on children&#39;s nature education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park has an &quot;Art in the Park&quot; planning project. The purpose is not to hold an Internet celebrity exhibition, but to present the original intention, concept, process and results of children&#39;s art production. Chen Zhou took the children to visit the Nanyue Palace, imagining what the palace looked like more than two thousand years ago, and let the children build the kingdom in their hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The children found that the passages of the Nanyue Palace resembled an underground maze, so they designed passages using environmentally friendly materials to imitate the maze. Some passages can only be entered by children. Who is the King of South Vietnam and what does he look like? They thought they were ducks and birds, so they painted these patterns on the palaces they made. Some patterns even had the style of ancient house tiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With multiple express boxes connected in series, the children built a time and space maze that connects the history and present of the children&#39;s park - the &quot;Growing Palace&quot;. After the palace was on display, Chen Zhou often received WeChat friend requests. Later, he discovered that a child posted his WeChat QR code on the palace. &quot;It was a child&#39;s prank. Some parents also added me and told me that the child was real.&quot; I really like this work.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EzScAI2eA58ShksvdvX8CIxhUaCXBnHPTHgSs73O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EzScAI2eA58ShksvdvX8CIxhUaCXBnHPTHgSs73O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After visiting the Nanyue Palace, the children designed their own &quot;Growing Palace&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The children&#39;s art exhibition attracted many professional artists to visit, and some hope to participate next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child divides children&#39;s rights into three categories, one of which is the right to participate. However, according to the aforementioned UNICEF survey, only 26% of children said that the local government heard their voices. Opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children&#39;s parks have a similar dilemma. The stereotype of children&#39;s parks is that they are cartoony and colorful, even the bathrooms are colorful. Liu Yuelai has a different opinion. Sometimes there are colors everywhere, which is stimulating to children. Color is important, but the most important thing is the color of nature. &quot;For example, by observing how the colors of butterflies and sunflowers change, and immersing yourself in them, children will become more friendly to nature.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the construction of children&#39;s parks, children have a say and can even become the protagonists. Liu Yuelai found that children in fourth grade and above already have a very strong willingness to assert themselves and express themselves, and they have relatively strong spatial modeling abilities. In the process of participating in the construction of children&#39;s parks, children change from consumers to producers. “This kind of self-organization with order and endogenous dynamics is also an important experiment in civic education.” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As users of children&#39;s parks, how children play game facilities determines the functions of the facilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aerial net bed in Pingshan Children&#39;s Park was originally used for children and parents to sit and relax, but children prefer to use it as a trampoline. At first, park managers advised everyone not to jump, but many people wanted to jump. After consulting the equipment manufacturer, moderate jumping is allowed on the premise of controlling the age and number of children and ensuring safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a4U7H4gQyVegtGpOVo45wGZUctJ1cmroXTCSVHJk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/a4U7H4gQyVegtGpOVo45wGZUctJ1cmroXTCSVHJk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Under the big banyan tree in Guangzhou Children&#39;s Park, the artist led the children to weave a &quot;Klein cocoon&quot; imitating the &quot;Klein bottle&quot; for everyone to hide and seek in it. The children Not only are they the creators of &quot;Klein&#39;s Cocoon&quot;, but they are also users. These works remain permanently in the park and become amusement facilities for children. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The park has become&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;a part of life&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The city is so big, where is the best place to “walk your baby”? This question bothers parents. Behind the increased importance of children&#39;s parks is the reduction of children&#39;s activity space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Houses in big cities are getting smaller, and even living rooms are getting smaller. “People don’t have much need to entertain guests, and children have even less space at home, so they can only go outside to play. .&quot; Wang Yafei observed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before coming to Shenzhen Pingshan Children&#39;s Park to work as an operator, Wang Yafei had been working in operations and management in residential and commercial institutions. After arriving at the Children&#39;s Park, his mentality was &quot;much younger.&quot; &quot;Children talk lively and cutely, which makes people feel relaxed. After being together for a long time, they feel a little childish.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many residential areas around Pingshan Children&#39;s Park. Some children have become regular visitors to the park and come to play in the park almost every day after school. Over time, Wang Yafei and them have also become friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FH0H73nDVXyLBmzgeslarsG4DpJiHqSKuCy1VCn2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FH0H73nDVXyLBmzgeslarsG4DpJiHqSKuCy1VCn2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingshan Children’s Park Children’s Bookstore. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children will inevitably get bumped when playing in the park, and band-aids are always available in children&#39;s parks. At first, a box of 100 band-aids was enough for a month, but later it became less and less. At the fastest, it could be used up in half a month. Wang Yafei accidentally discovered that many children took away three or four band-aids at one time. Even when they were injured at home, the first thing they thought of was: There are band-aids in the park, so they went to the park to get them. Children&#39;s parks have become part of their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Expanding the supply of public services for children&quot; is exactly the requirement of the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Promoting the Construction of Child-Friendly Cities&quot; issued by 23 departments including the National Development and Reform Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Liu Yuelai found that the &quot;appearances&quot; of children&#39;s parks are becoming more and more similar. &quot;It&#39;s a bit like houses built by developers. The apartments are all of the same type. The equipment used is nothing more than stainless steel, aluminum alloy or other durable plastics. There is no local expression.&quot; For example, park facilities in the northwest can have local characteristics and train children. The balanced tree stump does not need to purchase the same industrial products in the product catalog, but uses local elm trees, which can not only save costs, but also reflect the local culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Shenzhen Design Code&quot; also mentioned that plants should reflect the characteristics of Shenzhen. No less than 70% of the plants should be produced within 500 kilometers of the park and should be selected from plants with low maintenance, strong weather resistance, and resistance to pests and diseases. There are few native tree species, and an appropriate amount of exotic landscape tree species adapted to Shenzhen’s climate are selected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tailored for children, it avoids &quot;competition&quot; for resources among different user groups. There are almost no other adults in the children&#39;s park except parents. Deng Xiaofei, a master&#39;s tutor at the School of Architecture and Urban Planning of Guangzhou University, believes that Guangzhou will build special children&#39;s parks in various districts with clear and professional functions, clear target service groups, and can better meet the needs of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &quot;small&quot; and &quot;far away&quot; are the feedback Wang Yafei hears most from parents. The first phase of Pingshan Children&#39;s Park covers an area of ​​57,000 square meters, which is equivalent to 8 football fields, but it is only larger than the required area for a comprehensive park. Half of it is bigger. The small area will naturally make parents feel that their children are not having enough fun - an hour&#39;s drive from Futian is not enough to play. Why not drive 20 minutes more to the larger Huizhou Daya Bay Children&#39;s Park? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if Guangzhou has the largest cluster of children&#39;s parks, it is still not dense enough. Deng Xiaofei has done research on the children&#39;s park system in Guangzhou. If they only travel for half an hour, only a few people will be able to access children&#39;s park resources. Only if they travel for one hour can the children&#39;s park resources cover the vast majority of children in Guangzhou. This is inconsistent with There is still a gap in Guangzhou’s three-level child-friendly living circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Guangzhou Planning Guidelines for Building a Child-Friendly City&quot; proposes to build a child-friendly living circle that can reach the entire area within 30 minutes by public transportation; relying on streets and residential areas, build a child-friendly life that can be reached at street level within 15 minutes&#39; walk. circle; relying on residential communities, we will build a child-friendly living circle that can be reached within a 5-minute walk at the community level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Xiaofei suggested that Guangzhou could increase the number and area of ​​children&#39;s parks in densely populated old urban areas and northern fringe urban areas. For old cities with a shortage of space, you can consider using idle or inefficient land resources, such as abandoned factories, to rebuild or expand the original children&#39;s parks, and set up children&#39;s play facilities in existing parks, squares, streets and other public spaces. , create children’s activity venues, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first batch of Guangzhou&#39;s child-friendly series pilot lists released in August 2023, in addition to children&#39;s special parks, Liuhua Lake Park, Yuexiu Park, etc. were also selected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen also has similar ideas. The &quot;Shenzhen Action Plan for Building a Child-Friendly City (2021-2025)&quot; proposes to build more community parks and small-scale amusement parks, and expand sufficient children&#39;s game venues in city parks and community parks. By 2025, more than 100 child-friendly parks will be built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高标准对接国际经贸规则，“应聚焦数字经济领域的制度型开放”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6t2GGa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/eOTBZFyizbruWq2svzV7bbVkt4RNFmNubK6 t2GGa. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai Yangshan Deep Water Port is also an important part of the free trade zone. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The top priority this year is to align with international high-standard economic and trade rules and promote high-level and comprehensive Institutional opening. It is necessary to test the system for the country and steadily promote the pressure test of institutional opening such as rules, regulations, management, and standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 30, 2023, Gong Zheng, Deputy Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee and Mayor Said this at the meeting of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone Promotion Leading Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June, the State Council issued &quot;Several Measures on Piloting Conditional Free Trade Pilot Zones and Free Trade Ports to Align with International High Standards and Promote Institutional Opening&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Several Measures&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the Shanghai Municipal Government issued an implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;, stating that &quot;in one year, we will focus on promoting trade in goods, trade in services, digital trade, temporary entry of business personnel, and optimizing Various pilot measures in the business environment and other aspects have been implemented.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone align with international high-standard economic and trade rules? What progress has been made? What are the current obstacles? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to this topic, Southern Weekend reporters exclusively interviewed Peng Delei, dean of the School of Law at East China University of Science and Technology and researcher at the Lingang-East China University of Science and Technology Free Trade Zone Innovation Research Institute. He has been paying attention to related topics since 2019, and Published many articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is still room for institutional innovation in the digital economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The State Council will issue &quot;Several Measures&quot; in June 2023. What is its importance? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In September and November 2021, China formally applied to join the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) and The Digital Economic Partnership Agreement (DEPA) demonstrates China’s determination to further deepen domestic reforms and expand high-level opening up to the outside world. The introduction of &quot;Several Measures&quot; marks the beginning of my country&#39;s formal alignment with international high-standard rules such as CPTPP and DEPA in terms of substantive content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thirty-three articles of &quot;Several Measures&quot; are mainly based on the CPTPP rules. Some provisions are also reflected in the content of DEPA, such as DEPA Article 2.6 for six-hour customs clearance of express cargo, etc. Trade facilitation measures. This shows that the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has relatively mature conditions to apply these rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that in practice, Shanghai has been at the forefront of the country in terms of facilitation of trade in goods. Recently, Shanghai has also highlighted this in the implementation plan for the implementation of &quot;Several Measures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once mentioned that compared with international high standards such as CPTPP and DEPA According to the rules, there is still room for further expansion in the scope of the digital economy content in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;. How should we understand it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are two rules related to digital trade in the &quot;Several Measures&quot;, one is about online consumer protection, and the second is about Software source code disclosure issues. However, CPTPP Chapter 14 E-Commerce (Digital Trade) covers 18 items, and each item also contains different amounts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;non-discriminatory treatment of digital products&quot;, that is, any Party grants digital products created, produced, published, contracted, represented or first commercialized in the territory of another Party. Treatment of products, or treatment of digital products whose authors, performers, producers, developers or owners are persons of another Party, shall not be less favorable than the treatment it accords to other similar digital products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, there is a rule in the CPTPP regarding the &quot;location of computer facilities&quot;: No Party shall require a covered person to use or set up computing facilities in the territory of that Party as part of carrying out activities in its territory. Conditions of business. Each party will also consider the issue of data security, so the CPTPP adds exceptions to this rule, that is, nothing in this article shall prevent a party from achieving legitimate public policy objectives, which leaves a certain amount of time for each party to policy space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the premise of protecting national security, more systematic considerations are needed on how to further align with international high-standard rules on non-discriminatory treatment of digital products and the location of computer facilities in the future. These provisions are also key provisions in DEPA, and they have an important impact on digital economic activities such as digital trade. Of course, this also provides space for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to be implemented first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is in line with international high standards in the field of digital economy , what are the advantages? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with other domestic free trade pilot zones, at present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone mainly undertakes the function of institutional innovation. We should take the lead in aligning with international high-standard rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there are many high-standard international rules. Taking CPTPP as an example, it covers 30 chapters including investment, e-commerce, and environment. If the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone wants to benchmark every chapter at this stage, I think it will be difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the conditions of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, it is more advantageous to actively benchmark DEPA and focus on institutional opening up in the field of digital economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the industrial foundation for the development of digital trade in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is unmatched by other pilot free trade zones. Shanghai is an international economic center, financial center, trade center, shipping center and technological innovation center. Trade The foundation is mature, and the newly established Lingang New Area in 2019 is also actively exploring the construction of an international data port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Article 84 of the newly revised &quot;Legislative Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Congress and its Standing Committee shall, in accordance with the authorized decision of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, formulate the Pudong New Area &quot;Regulations, implemented in Pudong New Area&quot;, which also provides a legal basis and guarantee for the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone to carry out pilot trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone should promote China’s accession in the field of digital economy High-standard economic and trade agreements provide practical support. What are the main obstacles faced at this stage? How to break through? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone actively benchmarks against DEPA, which has overall significance for China to join DEPA. The extent to which the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has adapted to DEPA and the problems it has encountered can provide an experience reference for China in subsequent negotiations to join DEPA. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is still in the exploratory stage in the process of connecting with CPTPP and DEPA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in terms of cross-border data flow, national security must be taken into consideration, and risk assessment and prevention and control must be done when aligning with international high-standard rules. What risks are faced by the free flow of data, how big the risks are, and what impacts they will bring, definitely require more detailed and systematic consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can break through from two entry points and gradually expand the scope of docking. First, we can consider learning from the negative list approach and research and develop an important data catalog. If this type of data is in the directory, the management specifications need to be stricter; otherwise, they can be relatively loose. Secondly, some qualified companies can also be allowed to pilot cross-border data flows. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“We attach great importance to the construction of a digital trust environment”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the establishment of the Lingang New Area, some explorations have been completed in promoting institutional opening up in digital trade. What are the highlights? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Peng Delei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, the &quot;About Supporting Lingang New Films&quot; issued by the Lingang New Area Management Committee and the Shanghai Municipal Commerce Commission on August 30 Implementation Plan for the District to Deepen High-level Institutional Opening and Promote Innovative Development of Trade in Services (hereinafter referred to as the “Implementation Plan”). This is a comprehensive plan for the development of service trade in the Lingang New Area and has breakthrough significance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; proposes specific measures for the safe and orderly flow of data and the innovative development of digital trade. For example, a data supervision sandbox pilot was launched to promote the implementation of a number of cross-border data cooperation projects such as electronic invoices and digital identities. The data supervision sandbox is equivalent to piloting some supervision measures on a certain subject in a region, and then judging whether it is suitable for promotion based on feasibility and effect. The implementation of electronic invoices and digital identities can improve trade efficiency and reduce business operating costs. These measures are actually the content of DEPA and are also the specific actions for Lingang New Area to align with international high-standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Lingang New Area is also relatively advanced in the construction of digital infrastructure, such as the layout and construction of international communication submarine cable facilities, as well as the new National (Shanghai) Internet Exchange Center and international Internet dedicated channels. Construction etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the field of digital trade, Lingang New Area can take the lead in the future What international high-standard economic and trade rules should we try? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pendre: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In terms of benchmarking DEPA, there are two aspects that can be tried first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen cooperation among digital enterprises. DEPA’s chapter on “Small and Medium Enterprise Cooperation” mentions that “Parties shall engage in digital SME dialogue. The dialogue may include the private sector, non-governmental organizations, academic experts and other stakeholders from each Party”. It is recommended to establish cooperative organizations or conduct regular forums to promote exchanges between small and medium-sized enterprises and Chinese and foreign-funded enterprises, and the demands of foreign-invested enterprises in China can also be reflected through this mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the cross-border data flow issues that digital investors are concerned about, on the premise of ensuring national security, it can also solve the worries of foreign investors investing in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to strengthen mutual recognition of digital enterprises. Article 4.2 of DEPA stipulates that “Parties shall endeavor to mutually recognize the data protection trust marks of other Parties as an effective mechanism to facilitate cross-border information transfers while protecting personal information.” After mutual recognition of information and security is completed, if both parties need to conduct data flow or transactions, many procedural requirements can be reduced and costs can be saved, which is equivalent to establishing a white list for each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Chinese-funded companies have previously been awarded the Data Protection Trust Mark (DPTM) by the Singapore Infocomm Media Development Authority.它用于认证已部署数据保护措施的企业，以证明其业务遵从新加坡个人数据保护法。类似地，我国个人信息保护法第十二条也有相关表述，即促进个人信息保护方面的国际交流合作，推动与其他国家、地区、国际组织之间的个人信息保护规则、标准互认。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;数据跨境流动被认为是开展数字贸易的基本前提，目前上海自贸试验区在这方面的实践情况如何？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;彭德雷：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;上海自贸试验区的数据跨境流动总体上是在数据安全法、国家安全法和个人信息保护法的框架下操作的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和实务界交流时，感觉到他们很重视数字信任环境的建设。数字信任环境包含网络安全、个人隐私保护等内容。比如，在数字贸易过程中，要保障不能发生大规模的数据泄露或网络袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海在发展数字贸易方面做了很多努力。比如，《实施方案》就提到，临港新片区要打造全国首个数字信任试验区。另外，今年7月，上海市第十六届人大常委会公开发布《上海市促进浦东新区数据流通交易若干规定（草案）》全文，向社会征求意见。这份征求意见稿的总体脉络和价值理念是加强对数据的利用，过去很多政策强调对数据的保护。如果数据能够得到充分利用，有助于促进数据经济的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;营商环境评估指标对标国际标准&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;过去十年，上海自贸试验区先行先试，取得了许多成果。在您看来，最重要的成果是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;彭德雷：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为最重要的是对外商投资实行“准入前国民待遇加负面清单管理制度”。这一概念的提出具有一定的背景，主要是基于当时中美双边投资谈判时，美方就投资准入提出的一些诉求和范式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最初大家也不知道能否落实这两个制度，就先拿到上海自贸试验区试点。 2013年，上海自贸试验区试点运行第一张外商投资准入负面清单。此后经过多年尝试，提供了许多有益的经验。所以到2019年《中华人民共和国外商投资法》颁布，“准入前国民待遇加负面清单管理制度”正式被写入法律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两个制度从试点到以法律的形式确定下来，在全国范围内实施，达到了自贸试验区经验可复制可推广的效果，体现了上海自贸试验区先行先试的使命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;商务部印发的《自贸试验区重点工作清单（2023—2025年）》中，特别要求上海自贸试验区着力打造国际一流营商环境，这方面可以怎样做？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;彭德雷：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;上海自贸试验区非常重视营商环境建设。例如，临港新片区正在积极对标世界银行在今年5月新发布的营商环境项目概念文件，即B-READY项目。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据我了解，临港新片区每年都会请会计师事务所做营商环境的评估。就在不久前，我和同事到临港新片区参与了一场关于营商环境的研讨会，给大家讲B-READY的争端解决、破产和劳工这三个章节的内容，比如可以通过网上仲裁便利化，改善营商环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，世界银行新版的营商环境评估指标里纳入了有关数字贸易的内容，即数字贸易限制指数。未来国内也有可能会把对数字贸易的限制作为营商环境评估的内容之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年是上海自贸试验区成立十周年，接下来将大力实施自贸试验区提升战略。您认为应如何提升？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;彭德雷：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现阶段，我国对自贸试验区提升战略的总体目标要求，可以归纳为三个方面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是在对接国际高标准经贸规则上要提升，目前主要是对标DEPA和CPTPP；二是市场准入水平要提升，重点在投资和服务贸易领域加大压力测试；三是改革系统集成、协同创新要提升，重点加强跨部门、跨领域、跨行业统筹协调，增强先行先试的系统性、整体性和协调性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海自贸试验区十周年：对接世界，做制度创新的“试验田”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ym9V0eOEVtB8W8Mp6J8VBf5GzLP7xxL36fZFJcT3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海自贸试验区金桥开发区金京路2095号是沃尔沃建筑设备投资（中国）有限公司的办公地，这一片区域聚集着众多汽车制造及零部件公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本世纪初，金桥作为第一个国家级出口加工区，吸引了沃尔沃在此开设一家装配厂。到2012年，沃尔沃建筑设备与上海市政府签署了建立中国地区总部备忘录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在办公室里，沃尔沃建筑设备的董事詹旭向南方周末记者回忆，当时对公司来讲，就像一位年轻人开始做人生规划，他有很多想法，却遇到了一个瓶颈。“自己待的地方是一个电子厂，难道一辈子只能当厂弟厂妹？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;詹旭形容，上海自贸试验区的设立解决了“这位年轻人”的彷徨，“告诉了所有的企业，浦东、上海乃至中国要发展成什么样子”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年4月，上海自贸试验区扩容，在外高桥保税区等四个海关特殊监管区域外，纳入了陆家嘴金融片区、金桥开发片区、张江高科技片区。2019年8月，全国唯一一个自贸试验区新片区又在上海临港地区揭牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月29日是上海自贸试验区运行满十周年。十年来，上海自贸试验区先行先试，为国家试制度、探新路，也成为上海经济发展的重要动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《中国（上海）自由贸易试验区建设10周年白皮书》，截至2022年底，浦东新区累计新设外资项目18691个，累计外资注册资本2172.74亿美元，累计实到外资749.94亿美元。浦东新区2022年实现地区生产总值1.6万亿元，以全国1/8000的面积创造了1/74的GDP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入新的阶段，上海自贸试验区面临着新的期待。党的二十大报告提出要“实施自由贸易试验区提升战略”。与此同时，中国正在申请加入《全面与进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》（CPTPP）和《数字经济伙伴关系协定》（DEPA）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据新华社2023年9月26日消息，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平近日就深入推进自由贸易试验区建设作出重要指示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平强调，新征程上，要在全面总结十年建设经验基础上，深入实施自贸试验区提升战略，勇做开拓进取、攻坚克难的先锋，在更广领域、更深层次开展探索，努力建设更高水平自贸试验区。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;有求必应，无事不扰&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“如果没有自贸试验区的支持，很多业务可能就被丢在海外做。有自贸试验区后，我们就多了一条路，既然自贸试验区要搞创新，那企业就会觉得不妨来找政府谈一谈。”詹旭说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年7月，沃尔沃建筑设备成为自贸试验区内第一家实现离岸贸易跨境结算的企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者向金桥管委会了解到，当时客户向沃尔沃建筑设备订购两台韩国生产的工程设备，交易和运输均在海外发生，资金结算（从海外客户收款，向韩国工厂付款两个流程）在自贸试验区内进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;詹旭早年间跑过工商窗口，和政府打交道很久。“以前我们参加的是政策宣讲会，现在更多的是调研会。自贸试验区的制度创新，很多想法是从企业端产生的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，以前企业去找政府多是咨询政策，现在是企业遇到问题后，政府帮忙把相关人士拉过来，大家坐下来一起探讨解决办法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈起上海自贸试验区带来的变化，詹旭对商事制度改革给予了很高的评价。“所有的审批环节都简化了，一件事跑一趟，有时候一趟都不用跑，不仅为企业节约了人力、费用，而且对激发企业活力、提升企业信心有很大作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据上海市政府于2023年9月15日举行的新闻发布会，过去十年，上海自贸试验区围绕企业全生命周期深化商事制度改革，创新开展“证照分离”“照后减证”“一业一证”等试点，已在31个行业发放行业综合许可证5000多张，平均审批时限压减近90%，申请材料压减近70%，填表要素压减超60%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，上海自贸试验区还率先实施注册资本认缴制、经营主体登记确认制、市场准营承诺即入制，创新简易注销等经营主体退出机制，持续降低制度性交易成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有求必应，无事不扰。”星北集团CEO吴海侠在回忆公司打造上海自贸壹号生命科技产业园的过程时，表达了与詹旭类似的感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴海侠向南方周末记者表示，上海自贸试验区正式挂牌时，公司刚到外高桥保税区拿完地。作为外高桥保税区内第一家生物医药创业园，会遇到不少新情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自贸壹号目前规划建设了三期园区，一期二期园区已入驻约150家企业。吴海侠说，生物医药企业对楼房层高的要求与其他企业不一样，在管委会的帮助下，从一期园区的层高最高只能24米，到三期园区时，已能达到50米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，当时上海自贸试验区在外高桥保税区实行了综合用地改革试点。这项改革对生物医药行业也有很大吸引力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年11月20日起施行的《关于中国（上海）自由贸易试验区保税区域综合用地规划和土地管理的若干意见》（有效期至2021年11月19日），鼓励地块用途兼容，用地类型实行两种或两种以上用途混合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《若干意见》表示，应当综合考虑空间布局、产业融合、建筑兼容和交通环境等因素，提出自贸试验区保税区域综合用地功能引导要求，明确综合用地允许混合的规划用途类型、比例等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生物医药企业的用地一般是按1/3办公、1/3研发、1/3生产的比例。但严格来讲，办公和研发是不能落在工业性质用地上的。有了综合用地改革，更能适应生物医药行业的需求。”吴海侠说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;制度创新能为企业降低成本&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;詹旭进入外资企业已有27年。在他看来，跨国公司是否选择留在一个地方发展，一是看能不能做更多的业务，市场好不好；二是看经营有没有风险，规则是不是清晰；三是看有没有制度创新，这是促进企业高质量发展的重要因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从上述新闻发布会上了解到，在国家层面复制推广的302项自贸试验区制度创新成果中，近一半源自于上海首创或同步先行先试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海泓明供应链有限公司是一家成立近30年的企业，2006年以来，逐步从传统的物流企业转型成数字化供应链企业，目前主要为集成电路、医疗器械等产业提供供应链服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在浦东新区丹桂路899号，走进泓明的办公室，能看到两排无人的工位，智能机器人正在完成运单识别录入、报关单自动归档等动作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在旁边的办公室里，泓明关务管理部的高级经理白沥向南方周末记者表示，公司的转型受益于海关监管制度的诸多创新举措。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白沥举例称，国内一家工厂从国外购买了一台设备，当这台设备的一块屏幕出现故障，过去的做法是工厂向海外下订单，经过清关缴税、国际运输等过程，新屏幕可能要一周才能到工厂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在成熟的制造流程里面，流水线机器是一台排着一台，这一台坏了，后面的就全部断掉了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006年开始，泓明就在外高桥等区域开立了保税仓库，相当于把这一块屏幕放到了“家门口”，节约了原来“从海外下订单”模式产生的时间成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但随着交易规模增大，企业需要一个更节省成本的方法。“企业为了服务全国十个地方的工厂，它需要放10块屏幕，就产生了10块屏幕的成本。那么，能不能只放5块？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海自贸试验区推出的海关特殊监管区域间保税货物流转监管模式，就解决了产业供应链最头疼的保税货物全国流转问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在自贸试验区之间的保税货物可以快速地自由流转，通过企业发送的数据流、信息流给到监管部门，取代传统的两地监管部门之间纸质资料流转。”白沥说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泓明在全国14个城市建立了24个产业供应链物流中心，现在这一模式已覆盖其全部物流中心，有效降低了库存成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述新闻发布会介绍，上海自贸试验区及临港新片区的制度创新成果主要体现在聚焦产业发展所需创新制度供给、增强高质量发展新动力等四个方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，在生物医药产业，上海自贸试验区于2017年12月率先试点医疗器械上市许可持有人制度（MAH），自贸试验区内符合条件的医疗器械注册申请人可以单独申请医疗器械注册证，然后委托给有资质和生产能力的企业生产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自贸壹号是国内首家符合MAH要求的生物医药创业园。吴海侠表示，自贸壹号建造了全国范围内第一个具有产业园区属性的CDMO平台，搭建了6条生产线。该CDMO平台能为企业提供研发、⼩试、中试、动物实验、人体试验、注册报批等流程的服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴海侠表示，通常来说，一条生产线的投入在1000万元以上。以前企业从申请到最后拿到证，大概要等2年，其间生产线是闲置的。企业的经济投入没有得到最大化利用，也浪费了时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他介绍，在MAH制度下，企业可以共享生产线，“能降低成本，提高利用率，释放巨大红利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年7月5日，上海市药监局发布公告“将本市医疗器械注册人制度改革试点扩大至全市范围”。2021年6月1日起，修订后的《医疗器械监督管理条例》正式施行，全国全面实行医疗器械注册人制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴海侠也建议，应进一步推动、完善生物医药研发用品、特殊进口物品白名单制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表示，作为生物医药研发用“原材料”，微生物、人体组织、生物制品、血液及其制品等特殊物品，这几年计划进口量随着产业发展逐渐增多。但是，特殊物品可能存在各类传染病风险，上海口岸对相关进出口慎之又慎。而生物医药产业的快速发展对特殊物品进境快速通关又提出了更高需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关制度从2020年开始，上海在陆续实施，但对此开放的部分仍然偏少，希望自贸区能够加速推动这一块制度的落地。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;用好用足浦东新区法规立法权&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与其他自贸试验区相比，上海自贸试验区设立时间最早，而且浦东新区具有“法规立法权”的独特优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年6月10日，十三届全国人大常委会第二十九次会议表决通过了《关于授权上海市人民代表大会及其常务委员会制定浦东新区法规的决定》，授权上海市人大及其常委会根据浦东改革创新实践需要，遵循宪法规定以及法律和行政基本规则，制定浦东新区法规，在浦东新区实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在泓明参与上海自贸试验区的一项制度创新时，这一独特优势就发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，泓明联合浦东集成电路行业协会反馈了企业免予办理强制性产品认证证明（即“CCC免办”）申请耗时长，导致设备零部件无法及时送达半导体生产厂的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时泓明遇到的难题是，正常CCC免办需要2个工作日左右才能出具，但供应链售后维修服务需要365天里24小时不停歇提供，原来政策的支持力度已满足不了产业需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白沥举起一只笔，在桌上比划了几下。“比如保险丝，很小一根，但一旦熔断了，整个机器就停了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，传统CCC免办都是产业上下游企业，其中的供应链企业本身没有开发申请权限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白沥认为，作为链主的供应链企业不但熟悉货物产品，且对整个供应链流向最为清楚。如果创新链主单位可以申请，那监管将从点式监管升级为链式监管，整个货物流，从哪里来到哪里去将清晰可见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在浦东市场监督管理局的推动下，泓明进行了CCC免办便捷通道的率先试点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;试点的主要内容包括允许通过“自主申报、自动发证、诚信监管”方式快速获证；通过流程再造，将5个工作日的人工审批转变至“零等待”系统自动放行。同时，物流贸易企业不能作为CCC免办申请主体的限制被打破，拓展了CCC免办主体范围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年至2022年，泓明和监管部门不断完善流程和体系。“到2023年，公司和协会觉得可以结合浦东新区的立法权，让试点的政策固定下来，推广起来。”白沥说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月1日，全国首部CCC免办管理措施《上海市浦东新区免予办理强制性产品认证若干规定》正式实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浦东市场监管局描述，管理措施的主要创新点之一是原来根据相关规定，物流贸易企业不能作为CCC免办的申请主体。经总局批复授权浦东，明确为重点产业提供服务的供应链企业可作为CCC免办的申请人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年7月24日举行的上海市十六届人大常委会第四次会议上，市发改委提到，以用好用足浦东新区法规立法权为契机，立足自贸试验区及临港新片区改革创新实践需要，在做强创新引擎、高水平制度型开放、改革系统集成、城市治理现代化等方面，再研究制定一批政策措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;创新知识产权保护&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在知识产权领域推进制度创新，也是上海自贸试验区对接CPTPP、DEPA等国际高标准经贸规则的重要方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在9月15日上海市政府举办的上海自贸试验区十周年新闻发布会上，市商务委副主任申卫华表示，上海自贸试验区正在商务部等国家部委的指导和支持下，聚焦CPTPP、DEPA中的货物贸易、服务贸易、数字贸易以及知识产权、政府采购等边境后管理制度等方面的规定，研究改革举措。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浦东新区常务副区长杨朝在发布会上介绍，上海自贸试验区建设10年来，完善了高水平知识产权保护制度，包括推行专利快速预审、专利实施调查等“快保护”制度，发明专利授权周期从3年缩短至3个月，探索实施知识产权侵权惩罚性赔偿制度，率先构建国际知识产权保护高地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年底，上海临港新片区知识产权维权互助基金落地，这是全国首个市场化运作的知识产权维权互助基金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后，临港市场监管局牵头成立了非营利性社会组织“临港新片区知识产权交流促进中心”，并以该中心为平台运营基金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临港新片区知识产权交流促进中心主任冯振华向南方周末记者表示，基金在临港新片区落地，主要是因为新片区有制度创新土壤，加之前沿技术和重点产业集聚，有知识产权保护需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他指出，随着新片区企业参与国际经济贸易程度的深入，面临的国际知识产权竞争愈发激烈，许多企业由于在人才、资金、信息等方面基础薄弱，在国际竞争中往往处于劣势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在此背景下，基金的落地完善了临港新片区多元化知识产权维权体系，有助于在临港新片区形成长效的市场化运作维权互助机制，为产业创新发展保驾护航。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前基金成员单位达到近180家，覆盖临港新片区重点产业领域，资金规模近130万。2022年启动了基金扩充计划，根据理事会年费管理办法进行管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，所谓市场化，就是在政府引导下，坚持企业“自发组织、自主管理、自治运营”，基金的募集、管理、使用等都通过市场化机制解决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为全国首创，基金没有成熟的经验可供借鉴。冯振华说，遇到问题、调查研究、解决问题，这个循环一直伴随着基金成立和运行的整个过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“临港新片区企业的真实需求就成为了基金成立的最重要标准。”该中心介绍，筹备小组在密集调研了近50家企业后，确定了基金成立和运行的基本思路，即“公益性与市场化相结合，知识产权与重点产业相链接，体系建设与纠纷应对相平衡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立以来，基金帮助临港新片区企业成功应对知识产权纠纷并提供维权资金支持案例2起，提前介入知识产权纠纷提供咨询超过15次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临港新片区一家从事创新型医疗器械研发和生产的公司在上市过程中，遭遇了全球医疗器械行业巨头的专利狙击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心介绍，除了企业自身积极应对之外，基金发挥了重要的维权援助功能，协调多方专家智库资源予以纠纷应对指导，提供维权资金支持，同时也为公司提供知识产权咨询，帮助其进一步完善知识产权布局，降低经营风险，最终在专利无效案中胜诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冯振华看来，未来自贸试验区在知识产权方面还可以关注以下问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是让企业了解国际经贸规则，提前做好准备以便应对潜在的知识产权风险；二是主动融入国际高标准经贸规则体系，甚至通过先试先行探索经验来影响经贸规则；三是平衡中国技术创新和产业发展与国际规则中知识产权相关规定适用的关系；四是关注新技术、新业态为知识产权相关规则适用带来的挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大胆试、大胆闯、自主改&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月18日，南方周末记者在沃尔沃建筑设备的仓库里看到一台大型的绿色的再制造发动机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在场的工作人员介绍，这台发动机是全国首单“重点行业再制造产品进口试点”货物，是公司向瑞典订购的，于9月1日抵达仓库，后续将交付客户用于售后。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了让货物快速到达工厂，浦东海关提供了门到门查检服务。现场查检主要是确保单货相符，以及进口机器设备的相关参数、性能等是否与申报内容相符，确保商品既通得快、走得顺，又管得住。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，中国在政策层面对进口再制造产品按照旧机电产品进行管理。“如一缔约方采取或维持措施禁止或限制旧货的进口，则该缔约方不得将这些措施适用于再制造货物。”詹旭现场念了一段CPTPP关于再制造产品的内容。他表示，从国际规则来看，再制造产品是允许进口的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6月1日，国务院印发《关于在有条件的自由贸易试验区和自由贸易港试点对接国际高标准推进制度型开放的若干措施》，第一条就是“支持试点地区开展重点行业再制造产品进口试点”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在詹旭看来，这次针对再制造产品的制度创新产生了多赢的结果。企业拓宽了业务空间，自贸区增加了贸易种类，同时与国际高标准规则接轨。此外，对打通国内国际双循环，达成低碳减排目标等也有重要意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“浦东发布”，为了保障首单试点进口货物顺利通关，上海海关提前介入，全程参与，研究制定了专项监管方案和应急预案。由企业所属地浦东海关负责联系企业，做好企业的事前指导、再制造产品的通关监管等工作，通过专窗受理申报、“门到门”查检等服务措施，确保重点行业再制造产品进口高效、安全通关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么叫做制度创新？因为这个改变不是领导批个条子，而是要讲出个所以然，要大家坐下来研究。”詹旭说，改变这条规则涉及哪些部门、各自要做出怎样的变化、规则改变后的监管和推广要怎么处理等问题都要研究清楚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年来，詹旭对自贸区的理解也在发生变化。他最初觉得，自贸试验区是在上海出台税收优惠等方面的政策。过了一段时间，他开始理解，设立自贸试验区不是在一个地方搞特殊化，而是针对一些特殊的问题进行试点，然后全面铺开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其实原来没想到那么宏大的层面。过去觉得，自贸试验区是不是在解决招商引资的问题？后来我慢慢体会到，自贸试验区是要对接国际标准，把解决方案放在国际视野去综合考虑。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“浦东发布”介绍，上海自贸试验区提早谋划落实上述《若干措施》试点任务，目前已取得了积极进展，初步形成了一批制度创新成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了率先开展再制造产品进口试点，成果还包括持续优化金融创新业务审批服务，瑞士再保险集团子公司瑞再企商保险申请增资支持个人保险业务拓展，10日内即获批准等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月30日，上海市委副书记、市长龚正在中国（上海）自由贸易试验区推进工作领导小组会议上说，“十年来，上海自贸试验区大胆试、大胆闯、自主改，充分发挥了开路先锋、示范引领、突破攻坚的作用，彰显了全市经济增长极和发动机作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来，要更好发挥高水平改革开放&#39;试验田&#39;作用，在制度创新上取得更大突破。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会：赛场内外，同样精彩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257774]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至2023年9月27日17时，中国代表团在杭州亚运会奖牌榜上遥遥领先，奖牌总数124块，其中69块金牌、39块银牌、16块铜牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，获得女子1500米自由泳决赛冠军的李冰洁在展示奖牌。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，获得女子1500米自由泳决赛冠军的李冰洁在展示奖牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杭州第19届亚运会于2023年9月23日至10月8日举行，共有15个比赛日。本届亚运会的竞赛项目有40个大项，61个分项，481个小项，是设项规模最大最多的一届亚运会。值得注意的是，非奥项目作为亚运区别于奥运会的标识，大多起源于民间传统体育活动，具有深厚的民众基础和浓郁的地域特色。本届亚运会更是新增了滑板、霹雳舞、电子竞技等非奥项目，不仅增加了比赛的观赏性，也展示了亚洲体育文化的多样性和包容性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，杭州亚运会电子竞技项目在中国杭州电竞中心开赛。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/edbca512b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，杭州亚运会电子竞技项目在中国杭州电竞中心开赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;每一场比赛、每一枚奖牌的背后，都凝聚着选手们的汗水和努力。杭州亚运会给亚洲地区带来了无限的激情，在全球范围内展示了亚洲体育的风采。然而亚运会值得关注的不仅仅只有奖牌，赛场内外同样精彩纷呈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月22日，中国香港代表团出席欢迎及升旗仪式，正式驻杭州亚运村。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/c0c0d7c38e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月22日，中国香港代表团出席欢迎及升旗仪式，正式进驻杭州亚运村。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月22日，中国香港亚运代表团团长霍启刚在欢迎及升旗仪式上接受媒体采访。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/7cbd514ecd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月22日，中国香港亚运代表团团长霍启刚在欢迎及升旗仪式上接受媒体采访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月23日，东道主中国代表团在《歌唱祖国》的音乐声中入场。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/16b0743b90.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月23日，东道主中国代表团在《歌唱祖国》的音乐声中入场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杭州亚运会是继成都大运会之后，中国再次举办国际体育盛会，同时又是一次展示新时代中国形象的重要窗口。与成都大运会一样，国内外的体育观众可以进入场馆，近距离观赏激烈的竞技项目。游泳、篮球、乒乓球等是开赛第一周最热门的项目，南方周末记者在场馆现场看到，有不少热情观众会提早两三小时就到检票口等候入场。而在网络上，运动员们竞技技术、身材乃至颜值、气质，讨论热度在亚运相关类别中居高不下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月20日，每天晚上钱塘江边都会上演亚运会主题灯光秀。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/d3f4a4cf5f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;每天晚上钱塘江边都会上演亚运会主题灯光秀。图片摄于2023年9月20日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，一位游泳运动员汪顺的粉丝在游泳馆展示她为汪顺加油助威的海报。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/044e764b59.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，一位游泳运动员汪顺的粉丝在游泳馆展示她为汪顺加油助威的海报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，亚运游泳项目在杭州奥体中心游泳馆激烈进行。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/df4b53b699.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，亚运游泳项目在杭州奥体中心游泳馆激烈进行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为第19届亚运会的主办城市杭州，也竭尽所能，让远道而来的运动员和观众感受到主办方的热情。钱塘江畔的亚运主题灯光秀每晚准时亮起，都吸引众多游客前来观看。亚运村的整体环境、住宿条件以及饮食安排让运动员们和亚运技术官员们赞不绝口，媒体中心的饭堂也让外国媒体工作者在连线直播时称赞连连。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月25日，乌兹别克老将丘索维金娜在完成跳马动作后右手抚心向观众致意。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ff734d3fb1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月25日，乌兹别克斯坦老将丘索维金娜在完成跳马动作后右手抚心向观众致意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;来自沙特阿拉伯的媒体人伊麻德丁说，这次亚运唯一的遗憾就是“眼看10月8日就是闭幕式了，亚运的日子结束得太快”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月26日，中国乒乓球男团与韩国队选手在赛后接受媒体采访。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/e4704d51f6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月26日，中国乒乓球男团与韩国队选手在赛后接受媒体采访。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“三星堆”在香港]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 22:34:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[多家企业放弃，森林碳汇为何不香了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/UBXtPOqKCGqqORVOY0LYq9xP53SFURKTDpdBA5nv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;869&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/UBXtPOqKCGqqORVOY0LYq9xP53SFURKTDpdBA5nv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;购买森林碳抵消曾经是企业实现碳中和目标的“快车道”，但最近不少企业宣布放弃这条途径，更关注自身的碳减排。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（农健/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“森林已经不再是人类减碳的朋友了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月初，美国著名的气候报道记者大卫·华莱士·威尔斯在一篇有关森林山火的评论文章里哀叹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今夏肆虐加拿大全境的山火，烧掉的不只是森林，还有它们背后的森林碳抵消项目。伴着浓浓黑烟，通过光合作用汇集的碳被释放，森林变成了巨大碳源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;森林碳抵消项目是重要的碳信用，通过购买碳信用来抵消自身的碳排放，曾经是企业实现碳中和目标的“快车道”，尤其受到“减排困难户”如石油业、航空业等青睐。然而这几年，碳抵消项目特别是林业碳抵消项目受到越来越多的质疑甚至“漂绿”指责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，国际石油公司壳牌宣布放弃其每年投入1亿美元的碳抵消计划，因为当前的“碳抵消”项目，没能达到公司的质量标准。彭博新能源财经在其《长期碳抵消展望》报告中指出，由于担心购买到低质量的碳信用而遭遇声誉风险，2022年在全球范围内，企业碳抵消的额度比2021年下降了4%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么森林碳抵消项目越来越不受欢迎了？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;二氧化碳并不是“一等一”互换关系&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;质疑的根本原因在于森林“减排原理”的局限性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林业碳汇吸收的二氧化碳和化石燃料燃烧排放到大气中的二氧化碳并不是“一等一”互换的关系。政府间气候变化专门委员会（IPCC）特别区分了两种“碳循环”模式：长碳循环（或称慢速碳循环）和短碳循环（或者快速碳循环）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长碳循环的碳主要储存在岩石圈，也就是经由千万年被固定下来的化石燃料中。这部分碳如果不被开采燃烧，一般情况下不参与大气中的碳循环，因为将碳化合物储存在地下的过程缓慢，“长碳循环”可能需要数千年到数万年才能完成一个循环。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;短碳循环的碳储存在植被和土壤里，碳的循环利用期短，时间取决于植物的寿命，一般在100年内：植物光合作用吸收二氧化碳——植物死亡或被动物、真菌或微生物分解——碳回到大气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然界中“短碳循环”和“长碳循环”少有交集，并不交叉。使用“植树吸碳”来吸收经由化石燃料开采和燃烧所释放的碳，则是人为地在两种系统间进行了等量替换，并不符合数学逻辑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;植树吸碳的原理就是光合作用，但值得注意的是，只有处于生长阶段的森林才有较强的吸碳能力，树木逐步成长为老龄树后，代谢慢甚至枯死，将不再适用于碳汇项目。因此，一般造林碳汇项目的周期是20-60年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，这期间的碳汇也不稳定。在树木生长期，森林可能会因病虫害、火灾或采伐等原因而受损甚至死亡，森林就会由“碳汇”转变为“碳源”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最为突出的是山火问题。自2015年以来，美国加州的山火已经破坏了6个森林碳抵消项目，将570万至680万吨的二氧化碳重新排回大气。在2021年的大火中，微软和英国石油公司购买的森林抵消项目也被烧毁，给公司的“气候表现”带来了不少压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，一篇发表在《自然》杂志上的研究结果甚至显示，在采伐和森林火灾的双重影响下，亚马孙东南部的热带雨林已经成为碳源，不再是碳汇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在全球变暖背景下，林业碳汇项目的山火风险进一步增加。WRI的分析显示，过去20年间，全球森林的失火率几乎翻了一番。联合国环境规划署在2023年早些时候预测，到2050年，全球范围内极端山火的数量将增加30%，到本世纪末将增加50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便人们可以保证森林碳汇项目不会中断，全球可能也找不到那么多的土地。例如，瑞士最近与秘鲁和加纳达成了碳补偿协议，即使像瑞士这样小的国家也可能需要几乎相当于整个波多黎各岛的土地来种植树木。而四大石油和天然气公司——英国石油公司BP、埃尼、壳牌和道达尔能源若要实现2050年净零目标，需要在相当于英国面积两倍多的土地上植树造林。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一份乐施会的报告估计，要实现如今各企业承诺的碳减排计划，所需要的土地面积大概是印度面积的五倍，超过地球上全部农田面积的总和。类似的，另一份2022年由多国共20位科学家发布的“土地差距”报告（Land&amp;nbsp;Gap）显示，要实现各国政府的气候承诺，需要的面积相当于四个印度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大量的土地需求也可能会引发对生态系统的负面影响。IPCC的土地利用报告指出，“造林活动如果在天然无林地上部署，则可能加剧生物多样性、水和粮食安全的风险”。最近，一家位于阿联酋迪拜的bluecarbon公司传出将购买利比里亚10%的国土，用以开发碳抵消项目，引发国际社会对于当地居民生计的担忧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些企业已经意识到碳抵消项目的风险，并承诺放弃这一路径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年9月，英国易捷航空作为首家宣布放弃碳抵消方案的公司，宣布将增加投入、开发直接减排技术，如开发氢燃料、优化运行效率等。易捷航空表示，预计到2050年，这些直接减排技术可以将公司的碳排放减少78%，而剩余22%的碳排放将依靠碳捕获技术处理。2023年6月，法国雀巢公司宣布将不再采用碳抵消方式来实现公司设定的碳中和目标，未来将“致力于投资可以真正为供应链和运营带来减排的项目”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;保护好森林，让当地人受益&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月15日，生态环境部审议通过了《温室气体自愿减排交易管理办法（试行）》，意味着全国温室气体自愿减排交易市场即将重启，这其中也包括林业碳汇等项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2022年中开始，生态环境部围绕CCER（中国核证自愿减排量）项目的一系列表态表明，CCER审批被按下了重启键，也随之激发了国内碳信用的开发。近一年来林业碳汇呈现了爆发式增长，自2023年2月以来，至少有30个林业碳汇项目落地。很多企业提前布局，在林业资源丰富的地区与当地林业公司签约，将林地开发成碳汇，以期CCER一旦重启，即可进行交易（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;详见南方周末报道《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/230498&quot; title=&quot;“空气也能卖钱”：过热的林业碳汇&quot;>;“空气也能卖钱”：过热的林业碳汇&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长远来看，森林碳汇是否获得了“额外”的减排效应，保证减碳效应的持久性、经得起第三方的验证，仍是核心问题。低碳智库益科双碳中心近期发布的报告《是机遇也是风险，碳抵消对企业意味着什么？》就企业如何选择合适的碳抵消项目提出了建议：尽量去保护完好无损，或基本完好无损的森林，以保护林地及周边的生物多样性和生态系统为主要任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新版的CCER方法学中，也对森林碳汇项目的减排量核定、审定与核证机构等作出了更新规定，更加强调项目的可核验属性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述“土地差距”报告作者也提到，森林碳信用开发的重点应放在阻止砍伐古老、原始森林，并使当地居民和社区受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放弃森林碳抵消的话题背后，是一场旷日持久的有关“碳移除”（Carbon&amp;nbsp;Dioxide&amp;nbsp;Remove，CDR）的争论。CDR包括了广义上从大气中去除二氧化碳的措施，现阶段主要指的是传统的方法如森林碳汇等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未来，CDR的技术可能会扩展到直接从空气中捕获碳，并将之长期储存在陆地、海洋或岩洞里。IPCC在最近一次的第六次评估报告中，第一次就CDR作出了政策建议，认为如果要实现全球升温控制1.5℃的目标，大规模的CDR应用将无可避免。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但“种树”之外的CDR技术，争议更大。所以，IPCC也强调，任何的碳移除手段都不能替代深度减排。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[双节有奖征集丨归与游，我的城市印记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:58:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;中秋遇上国庆，又是一年双节相逢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;难得的双节长假让我们可以归家团圆，也可以结伴出游。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从乡县小城到繁华都市，从故乡家园到旅行胜地；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;都曾给您留下过难忘的回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是孩提时流连的湖边？或是下班后时常光顾的街边小店？抑或是旅行时难忘的街景？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参与双节话题讨论，与我们分享您的城市印记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们为您准备了&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南周文创“一个月亮”中秋礼盒、“在场”T恤、南方周末APP会员&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;等周边好礼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;评论区留言即可获得抽奖机会，&lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com/iJC2nEr1/&quot;>;点击这里立即参与抽奖&lt;/a>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如何获取抽奖机会？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1、活动期间下方评论区发表评论可获得1次抽奖机会（每日一次）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2、优质用户评论被精选展示可获得1次抽奖机会（精选评论每日更新哦）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;3、参与APP双节签到活动也可获得抽奖机会，签到活动时间：9月29日至10月6日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;4、分享&lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com/iJC2nEr1/&quot;>;抽奖活动页面&lt;/a>;可获得1次抽奖机会（每日一次）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[民政部派出调查组对中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会开展全面调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257780]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:30:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;针对群众举报和媒体反映的中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会“9958儿童紧急救助项目”及其他有关问题，民政部高度重视，约谈督促中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会切实负起责任，依法依规维护所涉家庭的正当权益。近日，民政部已派出调查组入驻该基金会开展全面调查，坚决查处和纠正违规违法问题。调查处理情况将及时向社会公布。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运电竞首金的夜晚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257770]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of September 26, 2023, at the Hangzhou E-sports Center, the first gold medal in the e-sports event of the Asian Games is about to be Birth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/l55WaYzpvo4oY49Bk4ggdvshvJ6j6U1gU216Ynp2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/l55WaYzpvo4oY49Bk4ggdvshvJ6j6U1gU216Ynp2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yang Yiqing was interviewed by the media while holding a banner to support the players&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Afternoon 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;6&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;00&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are still 3 hours left before the game, and the media box is already half full , everyone knows what this gold medal means - the first gold medal in the Asian Games e-sports event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There seems to be no suspense about the outcome of the competition. Since the Honor of Kings World Champions Cup was held in 2019, no team outside China has won the championship. Experienced reporters come to the scene not to watch the game, but to see the status of the players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of a reporter from an e-sports magazine, among the seven e-sports events in the Asian Games, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; is not very competitive, but it has the largest number of domestic players among the seven events. The most well-known game was the first to reach the finals in the schedule, so this game has a deeper historical significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games, the Chinese team won the championship in the &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; event, but it was an exhibition match. Today&#39;s gold medal is legal.&quot; Two-time Asian Games winner The gap is reflected in his experience. In 2018, he could not go through the media channel, but this year he can. &quot;It&#39;s just a different channel, but the feeling in his heart is different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mtxJzBlptUba9tQDzUY2CxCjyQJtOJtAGhyJVYRV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mtxJzBlptUba9tQDzUY2CxCjyQJtOJtAGhyJVYRV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 26, 2020, in the final of the Asian Games version of the e-sports e-sports King of Glory in Hangzhou, Chinese team player Luo Siyuan (middle) competed in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Hta0j2IyEs9mbBDeSefhhvw88OzzOuJ2YaogipQK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Hta0j2IyEs9mbBDeSefhhvw88OzzOuJ2YaogipQK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, in the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports King of Glory Asian Games version finals, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team 2-0 and won the championship&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1pm&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;7&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;00&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Inside the venue, the rehearsal for the finals has begun. Outside the venue, the official licensed merchandise retail store of the Hangzhou E-Sports Center is taking final orders before the audience enters. In addition to mascot items like other projects, souvenirs surrounding e-sports projects also include categories co-branded with game IPs, which “sell out very quickly.” When faced with the question of why there are so few e-sports souvenirs in e-sports venues, the young The counterman replied, &quot;Mascot badges are basically hard to buy. There are hundreds of them a day and they are sold out in the morning. The popular character badges were sold out two days ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prepare for the finals, the warehouse I urgently restocked the goods the night before and replenished a batch of souvenirs through all the channels I could find, including the Gongsunli badges of &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; that had already been sold out, but I couldn&#39;t wait for the final audience to enter. &quot;Before the third place match in the afternoon. It’s all sold out.” Brother Cabinet’s tone was filled with regret, “We are not fully mentally prepared.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are not many e-sports peripherals left for the final audience, “The badges are sold out, the magnetic books The irons are sold out, the keychains are sold out, the card sets of Li Bai and Shangguan Wan&#39;er are sold out, and Gongsunli&#39;s are sold out. This character is very popular, and there are only two of her bookmarks left.&quot; The cabinet brother thinks they belong to the contestants. Hobbies drive consumption. He heard from the audience that the character commonly used by contestant Xu Bicheng (ID: Yinuo) is Gongsun Li. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Brother Cabinet’s job is to sell goods, he was also puzzled by the purchasing power of the audience. He opened the stationery gift box on the shelf nearby, “The gift box contains 4 items, notebook, pen, Exclusive bookmarks and sticky notes are priced at 208 yuan. I thought no one would buy them at first, but they have almost sold out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/27/cD1FMIJlvjfDI1M24YTRNBk6a04y1YojTNWhkdRM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;724&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/27/cD1FMIJlvjfDI1M24YTRNBk6a04y1YojTNWhkdRM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 26, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games Electronics The final of the Asian Games version of Honor of Kings, players from the Chinese team (right) and the Malaysian team in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;PM 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;7&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;30&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The audience is about to enter. Without enough time to wait for the store manager&#39;s reply, another counter girl in the franchise store went to the warehouse and moved the remaining seal keychains, which belonged to the characters Da Qiao and Xiao Qiao. As soon as they were put on the shelves, a male spectator took away all the three Daqiao keychains. Seeing this, the counter girl stuffed the Xiaoqiao keychains she wanted to put on the shelf back into the box, &quot;Hide some first, otherwise there will be no more.&quot; Things are sold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More spectators crowded into the hall at the entrance. Seven cosplay game character actors were invited to stand in the center of the hall for a group photo. People waiting for the group photo volunteered at the venue. There was a long queue behind the audience, and almost every audience member who came through the door stopped to identify the characters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gathered crowd made it easy for media reporters to find the people they wanted to interview. A media from Hubei wanted to interview fans of the Wuhan eStarPro team. Two players from this team were selected for the national team, namely Luo Siyuan (ID: Huahai) and Sun Linwei (ID: Tanran). Young girl Yang Yiqing was chosen as the interviewee from the crowd. She was easily identifiable as she was wearing the uniform of the eStarPro team and carrying a bag of support materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the camera, Yang Yiqing enthusiastically praised the positive value of the players, &quot;I want to say something about Luo Siyuan. He has taken on the responsibility of captain and has always been very responsible, very determined, and very diligent in training.&quot; , led the team members to help the team win so many championships, I think they represent the spirit of perseverance and hard work.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eStarPro team has won 8 championships in previous competitive competitions. Regarding tonight&#39;s championship, the mentality of fans is much better than that of the media. Yang Yiqing said: &quot;Player Sun Linwei has just celebrated his 20th birthday. I am also here to wish him the first gold medal at the age of 20.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The support materials brought by Yang Yiqing include banners and small flags, which are spontaneously produced by the players or their team&#39;s fan clubs. A few days before the finals, each support club chose to distribute the materials at the Intime Department Store at the intersection away from the e-sports center. The materials with the personal photos of the players were to express their stance, and all the players of the national team were printed to show the pattern. The biggest one is Xu Bicheng’s (ID: Yinuo) Zebra Paradise Support Club. They set up a display area directly in the atrium on the first floor of the shopping mall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the game started, each company’s support materials competed in a round. When the venue’s cameras scanned the auditorium, the fans held up their banners high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/sBFZOTT3mdSIpJs8yAHJQQbm0uApeUfFLuBic1qZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/sBFZOTT3mdSIpJs8yAHJQQbm0uApeUfFLuBic1qZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;E-sports souvenir shelves in Hangzhou E-sports Center&#39;s licensed merchandise retail store&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Yangxin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;In the evening 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;8&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;30&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The auditorium is filling up one after another , the warm-up music before the game was played loudly on the field, and the DJ chose a RAP version of &quot;Good Luck&quot;. In fact, the spectators who can come to the game are very lucky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tickets for the Asian Games e-sports events will go on sale on August 14, 2023. It is the only event where ticket purchase qualifications are determined by drawing lots, and it is also the most expensive event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no statistical data on the winning rate of single-game tickets, but according to the official blog of the Hangzhou Asian Organizing Committee, there are at least 5 million users who apply to purchase tickets for e-sports events, and the maximum number of spectators for each game is no more than 4,000 people. Among them, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot;, &quot;League of Legends&quot; and &quot;Dota2&quot; are particularly popular. On September 23, the official ticket purchase system released some tickets again, and the tickets for these three projects were almost sold out in seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/dcoHGEW6YFq4faY2Qrf8rKvKsntTDWLjJTae8Xbu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/dcoHGEW6YFq4faY2Qrf8rKvKsntTDWLjJTae8Xbu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hangzhou E-sports Center licensed merchandise retail store, spectators waiting for the replenishment of e-sports souvenirs&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Yangxin/Picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Night&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;19&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;47&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Live broadcast , the just-concluded 19th Asian Games Hangzhou Honor of Kings Asian Games version finals, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team and won the Honor of Kings Asian Games version championship, winning the first gold medal in e-sports. It was also the Chinese sports team’s first victory in this Asian Games. The 48th gold medal won. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final between the Chinese team and the Malaysian team lasted two rounds, and each round was won with an absolute advantage, taking about 15 minutes each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the award ceremony, the faces of several Chinese contestants appeared on the big screen one by one, with tears faintly flashing. When the emcee picked up the medal and hung it up for Lin Heng (ID: Nuanyang), Chi Xiaoming (ID: Ming) next to him lowered his head in misunderstanding, then stood up quickly, revealing a trace of his nervousness. Xu Bicheng also showed nervousness. Facing the cheers of the audience, he raised his right hand and scratched his head unconsciously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After exiting, the six contestants passed through the mixed interview area. The long passage was filled with reporters and volunteers. A small blackboard was erected at the media entrance, &quot;The mixed interview area is full.&quot; Several young people who had just won the award dispersed and expressed their excitement at the moment to the microphones and cameras swarming in front of them. Jiang Tao (ID: Adou) finished his speech and was about to leave when he was stopped by a bunch of voices. Dozens of reporters immediately surrounded the place where he stopped. Only the one with the loudest voice could get the right to ask questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last question was grabbed by a female reporter: &quot;What do you want to say to our audience?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I did it, and I believe you can do it too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After saying this, Adou walked towards the exit accompanied by the team manager. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[减持“新规”从严落实！沪深交易所进一步明确破发、破净、分红不达标条件]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257772]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 19:37:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the China Securities Regulatory Commission launched the &quot;new regulations&quot; on shareholding reduction, the market is in urgent need of detailed rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued relevant notices, clarifying some of the constraints in the new regulations on shareholding reduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission’s requirements for share reductions on August 27 show that controlling shareholders and actual controllers of companies whose shares are broken, broken, or whose dividends do not meet the target are not allowed to reduce their shareholdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the requirements were issued, many listed companies announced the early termination of their shareholding reduction plans. Taking the Shanghai Stock Exchange as an example, the controlling shareholders, actual controllers, directors, supervisors, and senior executives of 35 companies terminated their shareholding reduction plans in advance, and the &quot;key minority&quot; personnel of 18 companies voluntarily promised not to reduce their shareholdings in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the market has also raised through various channels a series of implementation standards issues such as how to judge relevant conditions and what methods to limit shareholding reduction. To this end, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges have conducted systematic and in-depth research to refine relevant implementation standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice issued by the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges clarified the standards for breaking the issue, breaking the net or failing to pay dividends, clarifying the scope of the secondary market holding reduction, clarifying whether the conditions are met during pre-disclosure, etc., responded to market concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;You can reduce your holdings only if you cannot break the stock price or break the net price for 20 consecutive days&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As we all know, a stock price break means the stock price is lower than the issue price when it was first issued. To avoid artificial manipulation, a break here means that the closing price of the stock on any of the 20 trading days before the announcement of the shareholding reduction plan is lower than the stock issuance price at the time of the initial public offering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the Shanghai and Shenzhen exchanges require that the stock price does not break for 20 consecutive trading days before they can reduce their holdings. This article is applicable to the controlling shareholders, actual controllers and persons acting in concert at the time of the initial public offering of the listed company; if the issuer discloses that it has no controlling shareholder or actual controller, it applies to the largest shareholder at the time of the initial public offering. and its actual controllers and persons acting in concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Net-breaking means that the stock price is lower than the net assets per share. The notice shows that the so-called net loss here refers to the closing price of the stock on any of the 20 trading days before the announcement of the shareholding reduction plan is lower than the net assets per share at the end of the most recent fiscal year or the most recent financial accounting report period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Senior market insiders pointed out, “In order to improve the accuracy and timeliness of judgment, two comparison benchmarks are set (for the net breaking situation), namely the latest financial report and the audited annual report for the most recent year. , the holdings can be reduced only if the net is not broken. Same as the break, twenty trading days are also selected, and the holding can be reduced only if the net is not broken.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order to ensure the comparability of prices, the net is broken and the net is broken. All adopt the backward re-weighting calculation method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market participant said, &quot;This notice strictly identifies the circumstances in which holdings cannot be reduced. For example, for breaking the stock and breaking the net, it is not simply that the stock is not broken or the net is not broken on a certain day as the conditions for reduction, but It is required to not break the stock price or net profit for 20 consecutive trading days. This can prevent controlling shareholders and actual controllers from manipulating the stock price to cooperate with the reduction of holdings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Excluding fiscal years with negative net profits&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Dividends that do not meet the standard include two types of situations: one is that there is no dividend for three years; the other is that the accumulated amount of dividends over the three years does not reach 30% of the three-year average annual net profit. The year of judgment is the fiscal year for which the audited annual report is disclosed. It is worth noting that fiscal years in which net profits are negative are not included. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some special circumstances in the calculation of whether dividends meet the standards. For example, if there are losses for three consecutive years but profits are distributed because the accumulated undistributed profits are positive, if according to the natural algorithm, the average annual net profit for three years is negative, a small amount of dividends can meet the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, one or two years in the past three years have been profitable, and the remaining years have suffered losses and the losses have been huge, resulting in a negative average annual net profit in the past three years. According to natural calculations, a small amount of dividends may be appropriate. Achievable standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid such a situation, this time it is stipulated that the loss-making years will be excluded from the calculation standard, and only the dividend amount and average annual net profit of the profitable years will be calculated. According to this standard, if there are losses in the last three years, there are no years that can be calculated, and the standard cannot be met, and the shareholding cannot be reduced; if the cumulative net profit in the last three years is negative, the loss-making years will be eliminated, and the dividends for the remaining profitable years will reach 30%. Only then can we reduce our holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of industry insiders, in fact, the elimination calculation method and standards are more stringent, basically achieving the effect that controlling shareholders and actual controllers of loss-making companies are not allowed to reduce their holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Block transactions are included in the scope of secondary market holding reductions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges pointed out that according to general understanding, the secondary market refers to centralized bidding transactions and block transactions. If other methods of reduction are achieved through the above two methods or are similar to them, they should also be implemented with reference to the same standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This notice also adds pre-disclosure requirements for large transactions. The current holding reduction rules do not force major shareholders to disclose in advance before reducing their holdings in large-scale transactions. In order to prevent controlling shareholders and actual controllers from reducing their holdings through large-scale transactions without meeting the conditions, new rules for large-scale transactions have been added this time. The pre-disclosure obligation requires them to pre-disclose 15 trading days in advance with reference to the regulations on centralized bidding, and to make disclosures during and after the event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysts believe that &quot;this move further improves the transparency of shareholding reduction and facilitates small and medium-sized investors to understand the holding reduction arrangements of controlling shareholders and actual controllers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of disclosure requirements , when the shareholding reduction plan is disclosed in advance during the start-up stage of the shareholding reduction, the controlling shareholder and actual controller should determine whether the conditions that prohibit the shareholding reduction are met. If it is met, it cannot be disclosed; if the conditions for shareholding reduction are met, the shareholding reduction plan can be disclosed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Strengthen supervision of violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What will be done if relevant entities violate relevant regulations? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that exchanges can take self-regulatory measures according to their rules, including self-regulatory measures, disciplinary sanctions, trading restrictions, etc. The China Securities Regulatory Commission may impose administrative penalties or take regulatory measures in accordance with the Securities Law and the Certain Provisions on the Reduction of Shareholdings by Shareholders, Directors, Supervisors and Senior Management of Listed Companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from past cases, the exchange has taken disciplinary actions and restricted trading measures for serious violations. The China Securities Regulatory Commission also imposed severe fines and heavy penalties. For example, Shanghai Yingyi violated pre-disclosure requirements and reduced its holdings of WuXi AppTec shares and was fined 200 million yuan; Yu Fanyi and others violated regulations by reducing their holdings of Wole Home shares, and their illegal gains were confiscated and severely punished. A fine of more than 30 million yuan was imposed; the Shenzhen Stock Exchange issued a notice of criticism and disciplinary sanctions to the shareholders of Xtest Testing on the day they announced the illegal reduction of holdings. The company&#39;s shareholders promised to repurchase the excess reduction of shares and hand over the illegal gains. The relevant measures have been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in recent cases, parties that have illegally reduced their holdings have repurchased the shares that have been illegally reduced. It is expected that stock repurchases will also become one of the important measures to punish violators and will never be allowed. The offender benefits from the violation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, the Shanghai Stock Exchange will further strengthen the supervision of shareholding reduction behaviors: First, it will improve the transparency of information disclosure of shareholding reductions. For pre-disclosure announcements of shareholding reductions, it is required to fully explain whether the conditions for shareholding reductions are met. The second is to strengthen the monitoring of holding reduction behaviors, strengthen transaction supervision, and promptly discover illegal holding reduction behaviors. The third is to do a good job in rule consultation and policy interpretation, and guide listed companies to ensure the first compliance level in the disclosure of information on shareholder reductions; the fourth is to take regulatory measures in a timely manner, and in the case of suspected violations, send letters to inquire, Telephone reminders and other measures will be taken to verify that violations are involved, and disciplinary sanctions will be implemented quickly and strictly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shenzhen Stock Exchange stated that it will also further strengthen supervision work: First, improve the supervision of information disclosure of shareholding reductions. For pre-disclosure announcements of shareholding reductions, it is required to fully explain whether the conditions for shareholding reductions are met. The second is to improve the functions of the shareholding reduction monitoring system, strengthen transaction supervision, and detect violations in a timely manner. The third is to take regulatory measures in a timely manner. For suspected violations, measures such as sending letters to inquire and calling reminders will be adopted as soon as possible to verify that violations are involved, and disciplinary sanctions will be implemented quickly and strictly. maintain behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中共中央政治局召开会议 审议《关于二十届中央第一轮巡视情况的综合报告》 中共中央总书记习近平主持会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257776]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 19:46:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on September 27 to review the &quot;About the First Round of Inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China&quot; Comprehensive Report. Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting held that the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core attaches great importance to inspection work, regards inspections as a strategic institutional arrangement to promote the party&#39;s self-revolution and comprehensively and strictly govern the party, and has made a series of major decisions and arrangements. The first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China adhered to integrity and innovation, promoted the concreteness, precision and normalization of political supervision, and released a clear signal that comprehensive and strict governance of the party is always on the road, and the party&#39;s self-revolution is always on the road. Practice has proved that inspections are an effective way to discover and promote solutions to problems, and we must continue to make efforts and advance in depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting pointed out that from the inspection, party building and comprehensive and strict party governance in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance, and sports have been strengthened, and new results have been achieved in various tasks, but there are also some problems. It is necessary to pass on the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere to the end, urge the inspected party organizations, especially the main responsible comrades, to take on their responsibilities, carry out rectifications strictly and practically, and implement the inspection rectification and learning in the new era of Xi Jinping The education on the theme of socialism with Chinese characteristics should be combined to deeply understand the decisive significance of the “two establishments” and resolutely achieve the “two maintenances”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting emphasized that we should take the inspection and rectification as an opportunity to further strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership, urge the inspected party organizations to improve their political positions, conscientiously perform the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Party Central Committee, and continuously enhance the core functions and functions of state-owned enterprises. Core competitiveness, consolidating the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, increasing the efforts of financial enterprises to serve the real economy and national strategies, and promoting high-quality development. It is necessary to coordinate development and security, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, take effective measures to prevent and resolve major risks, and firmly maintain the bottom line of safety. It is necessary to promote the in-depth development of comprehensive and strict party governance, tighten the responsibilities of the party committee (party group) secretary as the first responsible person, the members of the leadership team with &quot;one post and two responsibilities&quot;, and the supervision responsibilities of the discipline inspection and supervision agencies, and highlight the strengthening of the &quot;top leaders&quot; at all levels. We will strengthen the supervision of corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, in-depth rectification of the &quot;four styles&quot;, deepen the use of cases to promote reform and treatment, and promote the integrated promotion of those who do not dare to corrupt, those who cannot corrupt, and those who do not want to corrupt. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. It is necessary to make full use of the inspection results, deepen reforms, improve systems, promote source control, and promote treatment of both symptoms and root causes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other matters were also considered at the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>